<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
              <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, 1 THURSDAY, OCTOBER 12 1905.</head>
                    <div type="item">       
<head>AMERICAN INSURANCE.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>Astounding D’sclosures</head>
                        <div type="item">                        
<head>A PRISIDENTS ENORMOUS
SALARY.</head></div>
                        <div type="item">
<p>New York, October 11.
At the investigation into the affairs of
the American life insurance companies, Mr.
McCurdy, President of the New York Mutual,
stated that his salary was £30,000 per annum.
He also gave explanations showing that large
sums were drawn from a company with which
he has business relations, by members of his
family.	</p>
<p>Mr. Qjyphant, Chairman of the Expenditure
Committee of the Mutual Life, stated that the
company maintained a confidential fund for
legal expenses, of which the total amounts are
only known to the trustees. Mr. Gillette, the
Vice-President of the company, testified that
the solicitor of the company could get £5,000
whenever he pleased, without disclosing the
destination of the money. Mr. Gillette men-
tioned that the company contributed £8,000
to the Republican Campaign Fund in 1904.
(Reuter)</p>
                        </div>
<div type ="item">                         
<head>ANGLO RUSSIAN RAPPROCHEMENT</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<head>STRONGLY ADVOCATED BY FRANCE</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<p>London, October 11.</p>
<p>The "Times” learns from Paris that there is
reason to believe that the Anglo-Russian
rapproachemedt, which is being strongly advo-
cated by France, is being favorably considered
in Russia, and further that there is no likeli-
hood of a Russo-German alliance, which is
strenously opposed in Russia	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type ="item">  
<head>Jays Seize German Steamers.</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<head>Contraband of War Alleged</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<p>Tokio, October 11.</p>
    <p>The Japanese have seized the German 
Steamers Struve and Hans Wagner, bound for
Vladivostok, alleging that they were laden
with contraband of war.          (Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type ="item">  
<head>THE “MATIN’S” ARTICLE.</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<head>M. DELCASSE NOT RESPONSIBLE</head></div>
                        <div type ="item">                         
<p>Paris, October 11.</p>
    <p>The editor of the "Matin" says that M.
Delcasse is in no way responsible for the state-
ments of the paper regarding the question of
Morocco.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type ="item">                          
<p>Berlin, Octobor 11.</p>
   <p>The German press is disp'aying irritation
because the British Government has not denied
the statements made by the "Matin.” (Reuter)</p>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>THE RUSSIAN STRIKES.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<head>MOVEMENT SPREADING.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<p>St. Petersburg, October 11.
The strike movement is beginning here and
growing worse at Moscow.	(Havas)</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>DUKE OF SAXE COBURG’S
MARRIAGE.</head>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
<p>Berlin, October II.</p>
        <p>The Duke of Saxe Coburg was married to 
the Princess Adelaide cf Schleswig Holstein at
Gluecksburg. The Emperor was present at the
simple ceremony.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
<p>Glucksburg, October 11.
The Kaiser was present at the marriage of
the Grand Duke of Saxe Coburg. (Havas)</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>PRINCE FRIEDRICH ENGAGED</head></div>
<p>Berlin, October 11.
    The engagement is announced of Prince
Kitel Friedrich of Prussia to the Duchess
Sophie Charlotte of Oldenburg. (Reuter)</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<p>  By kind permission of Lieut. Colonel R C.
C. Cox commanding and Officers 2nd Royal
Iniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will perform
the following selection of music in the Esbekih
Gardens to-morrow, Friday, commencing at
9 p.m.</p>
<p>1. March-The Hero’s Call-Leitmann</p>
<p>2. Mdrocari- Die Tangende Muse- Stratum</p>
<p>3. Overture- Paragraph III- Strause</p>
<p>4. Polka Vocal- The Three Jolly Cobblers- Lutr</p>
<p>5. Fantasia- Gipsy Life- Le Thiere</p>
<p>6. Valse- Amoretten Tanre- Gung’l</p>
<p>7. Selection- Tosti’s Songe- arr. Pougher</p>
<p>8. Caprice- A Coon Band Contest- Prior.</p>
       <p>Regimental Marceli.- Khedivial Anthem</p>
               <p>God Save the King</p>
                            <p>R. Watson Ramset,</p>
                                      <p>Bandmaster.</p>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
<head>Local And General</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
	<p>Stray and ownerless dogs found in the
Shoubra district of Cairo during to-morrow
night and at dawn of the 14th inst. will be 
poisoned by the police.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
       <p>Sudden Death.- Mustafa Mohamed el
Deep, a native butcher of 50 years of age,
suddenly fell dead in a tramcar yesterday.
His death is reported to have been caused by
heart failure.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
    <p> Nussf-Shaaran.- To-morrow evening the
religious ceremonies of “Nusst-Shaaban” will
be held in all mosques. H.H. Prince Mohamed
Ali will represent the Khedive at the ceremony 
at the Saidna el Hussein mosque, Cairo.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
   <p> A Generous Gift- H.E. Ahmed Mazloum
Pasha has endowed the Orwat el Waska Society
with a plot of land 642 square metres in area
situated at Bab el Sharia, Cairo. The Pasha
has evidently not forgotten his Alexandrian 
associations.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
    <p>Quarrel Between Arabs. -Three natives
of Moharrem Bey, being on bad terms with
each other, came to blows to-day, and one of
them named Saad Mohamed El Deeb sustained 
some injuries which require medical treatment
for from 15 to 20 days.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
         <p>  Victoria House and Nurshing Home.-
We learn that the registry office of Victoria
House and Nursing Home is now open from
10 a.m. to noon and 3 to 4 p.m. (Saturdays 
and Sundays excepted), Miss Walker, the
Matron, having returned from leave.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
	   <p>Walker and Meimarachi, Limited, notify
holders of bearer warrants that interest coupon
No 12 for the sixteenth 6 1/2 per cent. Cumula-
give preference dividend, due on the 1st inst.,
is payable, less income tax, at the anglo-
Egyptian Bank, Limited, 27, Clement’s Lane,
London, E.C.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
	<p>Diphtheria at Luxor. -The official journal
of yesterday, contains a notice issued by the
moodier of Keueh province, giving orders for
the notification of cases of diphtheria in Luxor
district, where a number of cases have occurred
lately, and for the disinfection of houses and
huts where cases have occurred. The decree
will come into force on Saturday, the 14th inst.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
	<p>Burglars in Egyptology -Having made
the realms of art his own, the burglar has
now burrowed his darkling way amid the films
of archaeology. It is an American Egyptologist,
Dr. Zimmerman, staying in Paris, who has 
made this discovery. But he has made it un-
der painful circumstances. He arrived a few 
days ago with numerous packing cases cram-
med full of valuable medals, rings, coins, and
dainty if minute objects of art gathered among 
the tombs of the Pyramids. One day he was
away from the room for some hours, and real0
used with amazement on his return that all
his precious memorials of the Pharaohs had
vanished. One man has been arrested with a
few of the stolen objects in his possession, but
of the great bulk of them there is no trance.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
	<p>British Chamber of Commerce.- We would
draw the attention of manufacturers and mer-
chants to the work of the British Chamber of
Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in
1896 with the whole object of assisting British
trade in this country. The services of the 
Chamber are always at the disposal of any
member desiring information on trade matters
generally, including the question of appoint-
ing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for
such advice, it is obviously in the interests of
all British traders here to become members,
especially when it is remembered that the
annual subscription is merely the nominal one
of $1. The latter payment also includes a copy
of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber.
Home enquirers can obtain further particulars
from out London office, 36, New Broad-street,
which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
     <p> H. H. The Khedivah Mother leaves Monta-
zah to-day by special Khedivial train at 3 p.m.
tor Ko bbeh les Bains where she will arrive
at 8 pm. Mr. Hilpern will be charge of the
train.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
     <p> Princess Kazimah, daughter of H.H. Prince
Huesein Pasha Kamel, arrived here this
morning and left for Cairo by the 9 a.m. train
in a special saloon carriage.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
     <p> Mr. P. W. Machell arrived at Port Said
yesterday morning by the Osiris, and proceeded
to Cairo by the midday train.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
   <p>Mr. J.D. Wallich, inspector general of Tele-
graphs arrived this morning with his wife and
laughter from Europe, and left for Cairo by the
9 a.m. train in a special saloon carriage. We
are glad to hear that Mr. Wallich looks much
the better for his holiday.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
  <p> Mr. Monller, the French Commissioner to the
Caisse de la Dette, and family also left for
Cairo by the 9 a.m. train to-day.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>The Daira Sanieh Case</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
<head>The Court’s Decision</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
	<p>As we briefly mentioned in our issue of
yesterday, the hearing of the motion brought
by the Egyptian Government to set aside the
opposition made by the Princes of the late
Khedive Ismail’s family to the payment by the
Daria Sanieh Company of nearly $2,000,000
to be made on the 16th inst., took place at the
Cairo Mixed Tribunals, Judge Somerville Tuck
sitting in Chambers (audience de Refere).</p>
	<p>Melter Molten, avocat du Contentieux,
appeared for the Government and, after ex-
plaining the claims brought by the Princes
against the Government, moved that the inhibi-
ion contained in their citation be removed, as
being neither made in virtue of a deed proving
a legal claim nor sanctioned by the authorization
of the judge. He quoted numerous precedents
to show that a judge in Chambers had jaris-
diction to remove an illegal obstacle, such as
the inhibition. </p>
	<p>Matter Carton de Wiart, representing the
Daria Sanieh Company, replied to the Princes’
advocate and supported the Government’s 
motion. He explained some of the decisions 
which Maltre Linant had cited and in which
the apparently adverse views taken were justi-
find by the fact that in those particular cases
there was no urgency and the attachment was 
not made on sums of money but on securities.</p>
	<p>The Judge them closed the hearing, announc-
ing that his decision would be given later.</p>
	<p>This case of the Princes, who are treating
the Government as if it were an insolvent 
debtor, was regarded with great interest, and
the small hall of the Refere was inconveniently
crowded.</p>
<p>(By Telephone)</p>
<p>Cairo, Thursday.</p>
	<p>The Court has decided that it is competent
to receive the application of the Government
and to try the case. It annuls the inhibition
made by the Princes on the monies of the
Daria Sanieh and the Daira Sanieh Company
and has ordered these sums to be paid over
to the Government on the 16th inst. and
condemned the Princes to pay the costs of the
hearing. </p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                      
  	<p>H.H. the Khedive psased yesterday in
inspecting his Mariout properties. We under-
stand that he will arrive at Mansourah
early on the 20th inst., when he will attend
prayers at the Mahmoudieh Mosque, and will
then preside at a banquet given in his honor
by the Municipality, before opening the Agri-
cultural Show.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>SIDI GABER STATION.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
    <p>We are pleased to see that the Railway
Administration has at last improved the Sidi
Gabor station hy erecting a special 3rd data
booking office separate from the let and 2nd
claw offices, and by opening a waiting room
exclusively reserved for third-class passengers.
We hope that the stationmaater'R offioe will
next be enlarged, aa at present there is co
separate telegraph office, and space is, in con-
sequence, extremely limited.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>THE GREEK SCHOOLS.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
     <p>Early this summer three or four cases of
diphtheria took place among the pupils of
the boys and girls' schools of the Hellenic Com-
munity of Alexandria. Two little girls died
of the disease, and the governing Board
promptly disinfected the schools, and closed
them at an earlier date than usual, with a
view to preventing any epidemic breaking
out among the children. The Board, we hear,
is not altogether pleased with the action of
the Municipality, which has installed a
public convenience within a few yards of the
windows of the Boys’ School. It seems to us
that no worse site could have been chosen
for this structure. Its presence must cause
considerable discomfort and inconvenience to
a large proportion of the 1,500 pupils of the
schools, which are close together, and may
disseminate disease among the children during
the hot weather.</p>
    <p>The Hellenic Schools were formally opened
for the winter term at 8 p.m. to-day by his
Beatitude Mgr. Photius I., Orthodox Patriarch,
who pronounced the benediction at the close
of a short religious service. A large  number
of well-known members of the Hellenic com-
munity were present at the brief but impres-
sive ceremony.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>Steamer Movements</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
    <p>The Messageries Maritimes mail boat se-
legal, which left Alexandria for Naples and
Marseilles last Friday, arrived at the latter
port yesterday morning.</p>
   <p> The S.S. Scottish Prince left London on 
Wednesday with passengers and general cargo,
and is due to arrive at Alexandria, via Malta 
on or about the 28th inst. </p>
  <p> The S.S. Trojan Prince from Manchester,
with passengers and general cargo, left
Malta on Wednesday, and is due to arrive at
Alexandria on Saturday evening.</p>
	<p>The S.S. Cyprian Prince from London left
Malta, with passengers and general cargo, on
Wednesday, and is due to arrive at Alexandria 
on Sunday.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>Hamburg-Amerika Line</head></div>
                                    <div type ="item">                                      
<head>Amalgamation With Anglo-
American.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
   <p> We learn from a reliable source that the
negotiations between the Anglo-American Nile
Steamer and Hotel Company and the Hamburg
America Steamship Company have concluded
in an amalgamation under terms which are in
every way satisfactory to both parties con-
cerned.</p>
    <p>It is some time ago since Egypt learnt that
the Hamburg America Steamship Company was
desirous of starting a Nile steamer service and
at first it was understood that the venture
would be made independently of the com-
panies already established, notably Messrs.
Thomas Cook and Son, and the company with
which they have just come to terces. Some
agitation was evinced and the opinion was
expressed in some quarters that German enter-
price should not be allowed the opportunity of 
ousting those companies which had a prior right.
The matter was taken up in London, and quest-
tions were asked in Parliament, but, as is so 
often the case, no definite answer either satis-
factory or otherwise was vouchsafed. </p>
	<p>Shortly afterwards it was rumoured that
the conditions under which Nile traffic is
carried on were about to be changed, and that
the exchange would in all probability deter any
would-be interloper from entering into com-
petition with the established companies. Then
we learnt that negotiations for the amalgama-
ion of the Hamburg-America line with the
Anglo-American were pending, and later that
arrangements had been made for meetings
between the directors of the two companies at
Paris or Berlin. We have more than once 
prophesied the result of these negotiations, and
our anticipations now appear to have been
well-founded.</p>
	<p>It cannot, of course, be said with certainty
what will be the result of this amalgamation,
but it has certainly prevented any serious
competition. The Anglo-American line is well-
known and is yearly making rapid strics ;
strengthened by the valuable support of the
strengthened by the valuable support of the
Hamburg-America company, with the con-
combatant addition to its capital and conse-
quent increase of its fleet, it cannot fail to
progress still more rapidly. What with the 
yearly increase of Nile traffic there is plenty
scope for two such lines as Messrs. Thomas
Cook & Son and the new amalgamation, and
we have every hope of seeing a continued im-
provident in the already excellent services,
without either party suffering from the inevit-
able but healthy competition of its rival.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>ACCIDENT AT BAB-EL-GEDID.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
   <p> On Tuesday evening at 8 o’clock Abdon
Effendi Girgis, assistant stationmaster of
Alexandria, whilst on duty, mounted an engine
with the intention of descending at the
north end of the yard to give instructions with
regard to the next train which would pass
and jumped off before the complete stoppage
of the engine, catching his left foot in the
wheel. The fore part of his foot was crushed,
and he was carried into the station, conscious
but b’eeding terribly. Medical assistance was
sent for at once and an outside doctor arrived
at the same time as the two railway doctors.
The rushed part of the foot was immediately
amputated while the patient was under the
influence of anesthetic. After the operation
the injured man was taken to the German
hospital, where he is progressing favorably
under Dr. Morrison’s care. It is believed that
he will be able to walk on the heel of the
injured foot.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN
EGYPT LTD.</head></div>
    <p>The manager in the Oases reports, in regard
to the water supply of the Khargeh and Dakhla
Oases, as follows:- The underground artesian
supply being practically inexhaustible, the
output at the surface may be almost inde-
finitely augmented, provided the wells are
suunk in suitable localities and kept sufficiently
far apart to avoid any appreciable reduction
of the hydrostatic pressure. The 0ases lands
have one great advantage over those of the
Nile Valley in that they are not dependent on
the time, volume, and duration of the Nile
flood. With proper care and attention the
output of wells remains constant,and in several
instances wells sunk thousands of years ago by
tho Romans and early Egyptians are still
yielding over 500 gallons a minute.</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>SAVOY HOTEL, PORT SAID.</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
  ,<p> Several improvements and alterations have
been effected at this hotel during the summer,
which will add greatly to the comfort of
visitors. The whole of the shops facing the
quay have been removed and in their place a
fine dining saloon and bar have been erected,
opening on the see front. At the back of the
bar winter garden, measuring 21 metres by
24 metres, is being laid out. The additions
include 32 newly built bedrooms, which will
bring up the total to 74. Mr. Kingler, the
proprietor, who is also the well known manager
of the Grand Continental Hotel, in Cairo, has
spared no expense in making the Savoy at
Port Said a thoroughly up-to-date hotel. He
has just obtained an extension of the lease
from the Messsengeries Maritimes, who are the
owners of the whole block of buildings in
which the hotel is situated.</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>Notes From Port Said</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<head>HARBOUR NEWS.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                             
<p>(From-our Correspondent).</p>
<p>Port Said, Wednesday.</p>
    <p>The P. & 0. Osiris arrived this morning
soon after dawn and transferred her mails to
the waiting Marmora which goes direct through
the canal, whereas last week, the mail steamer
was obliged to remain some few days, though
arrangements had been made for sending on
the mail bags as quickly as possible by train.
One may say now that the passage of vessels
through the canal either way has reached
practically a normal condition. To-day ten
vessels came up close together and it was
somewhat difficult to find berths for them.
A few ships have been obliged to tie up
further down the canal on account of the
strong breeze which has prevailed all night
and to-day ; these, with the residue of the
third and last fleet, which was in the Bitter
lakes yesterday waiting the passage of the
outward bound vessels, will, all being well,
arrive at this end shortly. Two small British
second class cruisers arrived from seaward
yesterday and tied up in the Dutch Basin
and Rive Asie respectively,having their pilot
flags hoisted soon after noon to-day for the
canal. The Bibby liner Cheshire, which, owing
to the great movement in the harbour early
this morning was ordered to anchor in the
roads, came in at eleven, and disembarked
Mr. Yeilding who had taken passage on the
ship from home.</p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>BRITISH ASSOCIATION HOMEWARD-
BOUND.</head>
 <p>The Castle liner Durham Castle came out of
the Canal to-day soon after ten, and remained
for some hours to take in coal, water, and
provisions. Those members of the British
Association I had the pleasure of seeing spoke
most highly of the pleasant time they have
had during their enforced stay in Egypt
Several of them have been to Cairo and further
afield, as was told in the "Gazette” on Monday.
Great regret is expressed by several of them
that they did not have the oppotunity of
seeing anything of Kibendini and the other
equally interesting environs of Mombasa, as
their stay was so short in that port, but a
party appear to have made a considerable tour
around the harbour and bays of Mombesa,
and all declare that they have had a most
interesting and enjoyable time.</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<head>REGATTA.</head>
<p>The following, is the result of yesterday's
regatta :-</p>
           <p> Class I.</p>
<p>Boat	Start	Finish Sailed by
1 Minnie 3.03 28 4.45.05 N.W.deCourcy
2 Sans Pareille 3.20.03 4.45.17 H. de Techudi
3 Tier-el Mina 3.00.32 4.51.40 Capt. Borg
Celtic	3.08.30	4.56.10 Major Gamble</p>
            <p> Class II.</p>
<p>1	Jessica 3.22.12  4.49 30 Grafton Bey
2	Cattelaya 8.24.50	4.50/5 Mr. Barnard
3	Akraba	3.23.40 	4.53.05 Sagh. Phillips</p>
   <p>The wind came up about 2 p.m. very strong
from the N.E., which no doubt accounts for
such a poor attendance at the sailing races.</p>
   <p> At about 4.30 p.m, the representative pairs
of the "Club Nautique Francais" and the
"Club Internationale Canottieri” started from
the breakwater elbow buoy ; the day, on
account of the high wind, was not at all an
ideal one for rowing races, there being at the
starting buoy quite a high sea for such boats.</p>
     <p>The Canottieri went away in fine style, and
from the first had it all their own way, the
Francais suffering very much from the inex-
perience of their cox, who did not line them
up at the start, and during the whole race
steered a very bad course. They gave up
after going about two-thirds the length of the
course, having shipped a good deal of water.</p>
   <p> The umpire’s launch then took them in
tow, but the line appears to have been made
fast not to the bow but to one of the seats
of the boat. The cox left his post without
fixing the rudder, and the boat, getting broad
side on to the direction of the tow; promptly
filled and capsized ; the crew were rescued by
the launch. </p>
   <p> As the boat was full of water when brought
in and had also lost its two sliding seats, the
second heat of the competition could not be
rowed off, and will therefore take place at
5 p.m. this afternoon.</p>
  <p> The following is the handicapped programme 
of the events for to-tomorrow when his Highness
the Khedive will visit the Club.</p>
 <p>  1st Race for the challenge cup of his High-
ness the Khedive.</p>
<p>Boat	    Time of Start</p>
<p>Jessica        2.30</p>
<p>Akraba </p>
<p>Cattelaya 2.32</p>
<p>Tantah	2.38</p>
<p>Gumrook	2.40</p>
<p>Masr	2.43</p>
<p>Calipso	2.45</p>
<p>Laurea	2.56</p>
<p>Course 0</p>
<p>2nd Race of native rigged open boats.</p>
<p>3rd Race between six oared gigs of his
Highness Prince Aziz and the Coastguard
Aministration.</p>
<p>4th Final of tho four Rowing Clubs of Alex-
andria. </p></div>
                                <div type ="item">  
<head>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB (ALEX.).</head></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<p>Owing to the interference of military arran-
cements, there will be no shooting next
Saturday, 14th inst. Notices will be published
as to when the next shoot will take place.</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>A.S.C</head></div>                                
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>OCTOBER SKYE MEETING.</head> 
 <p>There will be no lotteries at the Cercle
Kbedivial on Friday the 20th October for the
Skye Meeting on the following day and start-
ing declarations must be made in writing
before 6 p.m. on Friday the 20th October 1905
at the office of the Hon. Secretary, 6 Boulevard
de Ramleh.</p></div>
                            <div type ="item">  
<head>Egyptian Share Market</head></div>
                                <div type ="item">                                  
<p>(From our Financial Correspondent) </p></div>
                            <div type ="item">                              
<p>Londen, October 5</p>
<p>The money market bag again dominated all
Stock Exchange values since our last. It is
generally recognised that the Bank return
during the first days of October, usually shows
the reserve to be the smallest of the whole
twelve months, and this is accounted for,
under normal conditions, by the autumn de-
mand for cash throughout the country. This
year, however, the heavy foreign withdraw-
also of gold and the detaining of large amounts
in Egypt have brought the reserve to below
21,000,000 and the proportion of liabilities 
down to 37 5/5 %. This has had a disquieting
effect and has produced a state of nervousness
throughout the week, especially as the Bank
of Berlin has put its Bank rate up to 5 %. It
is felt that unless the Bank rate here is
made effective a further advance in the 
near future will be necessary. There are
those who are of opinion that in any ease,
owing to the further demands of gold for
Egypt and South America, we shall certainly
see such an advance before the end of the
year. Those who hold this view put forward,
in support of their opinion, in addition to
the reasons already stated, the fact that Ame-
rica is still buying bar gold in the open
market here.</p>
<p>The above reasons have naturally had a
weakening effect upon investment stocks
last we wrote, and Conso’s, which on Tuesday
were only a shade under 89, close today at
88 3/4 for the s/c and 88 1/2 for cash. At the
same time, this renewed falling away in prices
this afternoon is attributed to some heavy 
liquidation which is going on, and the low
prices touched today are not alone due to
the monetary position. The foreign market
also has been dull throughout the week,
Russians having declined a full point to 94
since our last and the whole list of Japanese
stocks having shed 1/8 from last Friday’s
quotations. News from Paris seems to con-
firm the report of the proposed new Russian
loan of £72,000,000, which, it is stated, will
be issued simultaneously in England, France,
Germany, America, and, possibly, one of the
smaller countries, provided the difficulty
arising out of the difference in prices, in the
various international markets can be overcome
so as to permit a common price of issue. Failing
this the idea is that the total loan will be
reduced to £40,000,000; a 4 % loan at 90.</p>
       <p> Referring to our remarks above on the
money market it is being pointed out that the
strong position of Paris, which, in view of this
proposed Russian loan it is to the interest of
the Paris Bankers to maintain by permitting,
if necessary, gold to be sent to London, is an
element which should allay the fears of those
who anticipate a higher Bank rate.</p>
<p> Home rails, although some companies have
had most excellent traffic for the past week,
have suffered from the prevailing depression
owing to the money outlook. Reports from the
iron and steel districts are of the most satis-
factory and cheerful description. Trade is
active and prosperous, all of which means
better business for the, railways, especially
those in the north which carry heavy minerals.
Americans have likewise been scared by the
possibility of dearer money, though not to the
same extent as home securities. New York
anticipated a 4 1/2% rate yesterday, but as soon
as it was known that the Directors had made
no change prices hardened up all round in the
Yankee market. Canadian Pacific shares were
on offer, especially after the meeting of the
company, with the result of which he share-
holders were apparently disappointed, as they
had anticipated some reference would be made
to the land scheme which, in a large measure,
has been the cause of the recent rises. The
shares close today at 178 1/2.</p>
  <p>Egyptian Land and Financial shares remain
steady but firm,with very little business doing.
Both National and Agricultural Banks main-
tain their level, and are quoted to-day at 27 3/5
and 9 respectively.</p>
	<p>In the mining market the public still keep
everely aloof from, South Africans, and Rho-
desians are being affected by the general
drooping tendency of Kaffirs.</p>
 <p>There has been little business done, to
Egyptian mines. Nile Valleys have weakened
somewhat and dose today at*lA a Mpon the
week of 1/8. United Africans are 1 9/15 The amount
realised by the shipment of gold from the Um
Rus mine for the month of August was
£1,185, end the Mysore rWt shipment for the
same month was sold for £69,280, not includ-
ing the value of gold contained in copper bars.</p></div>
CARLTON HOTEL,
 
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
