<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>ENGLAND, FRANCE, AND GERMANY. </head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>ALLEGED OFFER TO FRANCE.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>AUTHORITATIVE             
                CONTRADICTION.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>BERLIN, October 13.
                It is understood here that Great Britain has informally assured Germany of the baselessness of the report published by the  "Matin," but the tone of the semi official press indicates that Germany is not satisfied, and wishes an official repudiation. This, however, is generally regarded in England and in France as being Unreasonable. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <P>LONDON, October 13.
                The Government does not intend to make a statement regarding the revelations of the "Matin," but Reuter's Agency is enabled to state authoritatively that the Government has informed Germany that France never asked nor did Great Britain offer any assistance, as the question never arose. (Reuter)</P></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>THE KARLSTAD AGREEMENT.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>APPROVED BY THE RIKSDAG.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>STOCKHOLM, October 13.
                The Swedish Riksdag has approved the convention of dissolution.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>STOCKHOLM. October 13.
                The Riksdag has approved the Karlstad agreement. (Havas)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>ENGLAND'S RECEPTION IN JAPAN. </head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>OFFICERS RECEIVED BY THE MIKADO.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>TOKIO, Ootober 13.
                Admiral Noel and staff have been received by the Mikado. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>TOKIO, October 13.
                Admiral Noel has lunched with the Empe-      ror. Cordial toasts were exchanged.  (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>ASSASSINATIONS IN RUSSIA.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>ST. PETERSBURG, October 13.
                The Chief of Police at Krasnoyarsk was killed while returning from the theatre yester¬day evening. The Sub-Chief of Police at Kisbi- neff has also been assassinated. He was largely responsible for the massacres of 1903, and the recent anti-Jewish disturbances. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>THE MOSCOW STRIKES.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>BARRICADES ERECTED.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>Moscow, October 13.
                The strikers in Moscow having erected barri-cades to-day, the Cossacks charged and broke them down. There are sevoral injured. (R.)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>DEATH OF PRINCE TROUBETZKOI.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>ST. PETERSBURG, October 13.
                Prince. Trobetrkni, the leader of the mo¬derate reformers, died suddenly at the close of a spirited speech before a special Government Commission regarding the troubles at Moscow University.     (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>Moscow, October 13.
                Prince Trubetzkoi, rector  of the University, has died suddenly.                     (Havas)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>M. DELCASSE’S RETIREMENT</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>JAPANESE RUMOURS INCORRECT.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>PARIS, October 13.
                A note from the Havas Agency declares that the Japanese rumours concerning the retir¬ement of M. Declasse are not correct.  (H.)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>THE RUSSO-JAPANESE TREATY.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>WASHINGTON, October 13.
                Ratifications of the Russo-Japanese treaty will be exchanged here to-morrow. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>LORD CROMER SAILS.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>LONDON, October 13.,
                Lord Cromer has left for Egypt. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>DEATH OF SIR HENRY IRVING.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>LONDON, October 13.
                Sir Henry Irving died suddenly of syncope at Bradford after having performed in the theatre.    (Reuter)</p></div>
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the Boulac district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 16th inst. will be poisoned by the police. Those found in the Gamalieh district on Monday night and at dawn of the 17th inst. will be dealt with in the same way.</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>COAL IMPORTS.—During the period from the 1st of January to the 12tb of October 842.530 tons of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 457,203, Newcastle 194,487. Scotland 98,112, Yorkshire 61,225, and other places 31,503 tons. In the same period of last year 814,430 tons were received.</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>THE AHIAMHIU THEATRE. — The Della Guardia Dramatic Company will represent II Suicidio at the Alhambra Theatre to-night and for the unusual weekly matinee at 4 15 p.m. to-morrow LA Famiglia Pont Biquet is billed and at the evening performance Madame Sans- Gehe will be staged. From to-morrow the prices at this theatre are reduced as follows:— Boxes P.T. 60, Front Seats P.T. 10.</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>PRO CALABRIA. — The Cairo Musical and Dramatic Society have arranged for a grand concert to be given at the Khedivial Opera House on Thursday, the 26th October, com-mencing at 9 p.m., in aid of the victims of the recent earthquake in Calabria. The concert will be under the distinguished patronage of H.H. the Khedive, the Earl of Cromer, the Diplomatic Agents of Italy, America and Spain, General Bullock, C.B.. and H.E. the Sirdar. By kind permission of Lient. Colonel Markham and the officers of the 1st King’s Royal Rifle Corps the band of that regiment will attend.   A verv attractive programme, which we shall publish later, is being drawn up.</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <p>HORRIBLE SUICIDE IN CAIRO. — A native woman who learnt recently that her husband was not faithful to her, resolved to commit suicide and for this end poured a quantity of petroleum on her clothes, and then applied a lighted match. Just as she had committed this insane act her husband appeared on the scenes and tried to save the woman, but the flames caught hold of his clothes. A cavass of the Greek consulate, who was passing at the time heard the shrieks of the poor couple and rushed in and did all that he could to save the two lives and the flames were finally extinguished. The woman, however, died almost immediately, but it is hoped that the man will recover from his serious burns.</p></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head></div>
                    <div type ="item">
                <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head></div>
                <div type ="item">
                <head>VISIT OF H.H. THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                <p>Yesterday was a great day in the annals of the Khedivial Yacht Club. At an early hour in the forenoon all the merchantmen in the harbour had dressed ship in honor of the occasion.</p>
                <p>At about 3 p.m. the club began to present a very animated spectacle, as the members with their guests began to arrive. The club build- ing had been very tastefully decorated with flowers and plants and looked very charming.</p>
                <p>Punctually at 4 p.m , as previously arranged, His Highness the Khedive with his suite arrived at the club. The Egyptian Army band played the Khedivial Hymn and the Khedivial standard was broken at the club’s mast. This was a signal for all the government ships and departmental buildings to dress with their bunting. His Highness was received at the Club steps by his Highness Prince Aziz Pasha Hassan, Commodore of the Club, and Admiral Sir Maasie Blomfield K.C.M.G, RN. Vice-Commodore, and the members of the committee.</p>
                <p>His Highness then proceeded to the reserved portion of the_verandah, whence he watched the races, taking a great interest in all the contests of the regatta.</p>
                <p>The first event of interest apart from the event of the day, was the race between native sailing boats. These were all made fast to a rope by their sterns, with canvas stretched, and at a given signal all cast off and  sailed away. The nine boats pre¬sented a very pretty sight, and his Highness the Khedive expressed great pleasure at the scene. Soon after this came the finish of the sailing race, for the challenge cup of his Highness the Khedive for which the entries were as follows :— 
                    Boat                     Time of Start
                    Jessica \                   2.30
                    Akraba )                    2.32
                    Cattelaya                   2.38
                    Tantah                      2.40
                    Gumrook                     2.43
                    Mssr                        2.45
                    Calipso                     2.56
                    Laurea</p>
                    
                
                <p>Prince Aziz’s magnificent cutter Laures first crossed the finishing line in fine style, with every stitch of canvas stretched, pre¬senting a fine spectacle which was greatly admired by the spectators watching from the club verandah. She was sailed for the Prince by Sagh. Phillips of the Coastguard Administration.</p>
                <p>Then came the six-oared gig race, when, as usual, the gig of Prince Aziz came in an easy first, with the coastguard Harbour Depart- ment’s boat second, the Aida boat third, and coastguard training ship's gig fourth.</p>
                <p>The last race was the final of the Rowing Club competition ; when the Canottieri easily best the German Sport Verein, drawing away from the start and gradually increasing their lead until they crossed the line six lengths ahead, although the Germans put on a very plucky spurt at the finish.</p>
                <p>The Khedive then presented the prizes to the winners, each of whom he congratulated  on his individual success. He then expressed to Prince Aziz and Admiral Blomfield the pleasure which his visit to the Club had afford- ed him, and wished it every success.</p>
                <p>The Alexandria city police rendered great service in keeping the road clear, and the coastguards had formed a cordon entirely round the club, thereby ensuring the place being kept free from intruders.</p>
                <p>The Egyptian Army band played during the afternoon. The detailed times, etc. of the vari-   
                ous races will be published on Monday.</p></div>
                           
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                <head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAYS.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">
                <head>PURCHASED BY ANGLO-BELGIAN
                COMBINATION</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The above company, which was constituted by Khedivial Decree in May, 1897, with a capital of LE. 200,000, has passed into new hands by the purchase by Messrs. Lambert and Ralli, on behalf of an Anglo Belgian group, of the interest possessed in the concern by the Witta Boctor family, and amounting to more than three-fourths of the total share capital. It is not yet known whether the local group represented by Mr. George Eid, whose option expired on the 20th Ultimo, will form part of the new combination. The new board will be entirely European, most probably half of the members will be English and the other half Belgian. Maltre Carton do Wiart, through whom the negotiations have been brought to a successful issue, will sit on the Board. It is intended to considerably increase the original capital, with the view of extending the present line of 164 kilo¬metres and introducing many improvements. The company also intends taking advantage of the falls in the town of Fayoum by uti- lising their motive  power of 4,000 horse power for driving the machinery of the differ¬ent factories by electricity. </p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>NEW BUILDINGS IN CAIRO.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The Societe Belge-Egyptienne de l'Esbekieh in conjunction-with the Daira Khassa have decided upon demolishing all the small tem¬- porary buildings now existing on the property purchased from the Djellal family some three years ago and situated behind Shepheard’s Hotel and in their place the company will erect nine immense blocks of residences similar in size to the one just completed at the corner of the Boulac road. The cost of these new buildings is estimated at £250,000 and it is expected that they will take between two and three years to construct.  The foundations of the first are now finished and building operations will commence at once.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>THE NEW TURBINE CUNARDER.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The new turbine propelled Cunard liner Carmania sails from Liverpool to New York on December 2, and her voyage is arousing considerable interest on both sides of the Atlantic. The passenger accommodation of the Carmania is in the same sumptuous style as that of the Caronia. By the addition of these two huge vessels, the Cunard Company has increased its tonnage during 1905 by 40,000 tons.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>THE DIPHTHERIA EPIDEMIC.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>Some of the local papers have stated lately that diphtheria is largely on the increase in Cairo, whilst our contemporary Le Phare d'Alexandrie contradicts the statement, and further avers that the Sanitary Department denies the existence of the disease. From enquiries made by our Cairo correspondent yesterday it seems that the number of daily cases is greatly exaggerated. From the returns issued by the statistical office we find that there were 11 new cases and 14 deaths reported during the week ending 30th September, and that the weekly average during the past four or five weeks does not exceed ten cases. Assuming the correctness of these records there is nothing to cause any alarm or to justify the statement that the disease exists in an epidemic form at present. </p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>BANK OF EGYPT, LTD.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>Mr. A. Zanneti Polzi has resigned his post as submanager, and the Board of Directors has appointed Mr. Vittorio G. Gallichi in his place. He is empowered to sign in conjunction with Messrs. Strong. Smith, or Jennings on behalf of the Bank of Egypt, Ltd., during the absence of the General Manager, Mr. A. Luzzatto.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>THE BANK OF SALONICA.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The Cairo branch of the Bank of Salonica will be opened on Monday under the manage- ¬ment of Mr. Singer, formerly of the Credit Lyonnais. The offices are situated in the immeuble Mosseri, rue El Manakh.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The following is the programme of the Bra- cale orchestral concert to be given to-morrow morning at the Casino at 10 a.m. :-
                1.	Marelie-Nuptaile-Mendelssohn
                2.	Ouverture- La Sirene- Arber
                3.	Valse- La Charmeuse- Rene Maggier
                4.	Ballet-Sylvia- Delibes
                5.	Suite tire du ballet casse Neisette-Tsaichowsky                                  Dause Russo- Arbe- Chinoise    
                6.	Ouverture- Saul-Bazzini. </p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>The Khedivial express mail steamship El Kahira will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for Piraeus, Smyrna, Mitylene, and Constanti¬nople.	</p>
                <p>The Ellerman S.S. Avon from Liverpool arrived yesterday with general cargo and passengers.</p>
                <p>The Ellerman S.S. Sardinia sailed to-day from Liverpool for Gibraltar, Malta, and Alex¬andria:</p>
                <p>The S.S. Egyptian Prince left Manchester on Friday with passengers and general cargo and is due to arrive at Alexandria via Tunis and Malta on or about the 27th inst.</p></div>
                
                
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>RAISING OF THE PHARAON II.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                <p>Port Said, Friday.</p>
                <p>During the last few days, great efforts have been made to get the salvage material for raising the Pharaon II into working order. It will be remembered by your readers that this large sucking dredger was sunk one night over five months ago, in the Dutch Basin owing to the carelessness of those who were responsible for the night watch ; and that, whilst bunkering sho quietly filled and sank. Subsequently the collision between the Congal and a Harrison boat occurred, which resulted, in the sinking of the former vessel, and which entailed many weeks of hard and difficult work, resulting in the successful refloating of the ship. All this, followed again by the general upset canned by the Chatham, greatly delayed the salvage operations on the sunken dredger, and to cause more worry, at the trials of the raising plant shortly before the Chatham caught fire, one of the doable lighters collapsed and had to undergo con¬siderable repairs and modifications.</p>
                <p>However, all’s well that ends well, and the ffour pairs of lighters, each pair having a dis¬- placement of 250 tons, were yesterday placed in position, two-pairs on each side of the dredger (which by the way lay in 29 feet of water) and were all lashed with heavy chains to the cradle and each other, in such a manner that the air pipes, of which there were eight, protruded some few feet above the surface.</p>
                <p>All being ready, soon after midnight, the pumping was started by several centrifugal and Grindl pumps under the supervision of M. Dormay, who has been in charge of this work since the day on which the Pharaon sunk. About seven o'clock this morning, the dredger and her four "attendants” suddenly rose more than two feet, and she has steadily continued to risen since ; till, at the time of writing she lies almost at her normal water line level. The salvage pumps of the Canal Company’s Progres were got to work on the water in her hold and engine room about noon, and she will go into the floating dock probably to-day.</p>
                <p>Like the Congal, she now resembles nothing so much as a rock strewn coast after the tide has fallen ; festoons of yards of seaweeds hang from every point about her decks ; she is covered with slime and ooze, rusty, one mass of barnacles and dirt; a truly desolate and pitiable sight ; as for possibilities of future work with her I should fancy there are none. She is so covered with dirt and all manner of weeds that I would be surprised indeed it she can be made anything of, after her five and a half months’ submersion.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>NOTES FROM THE-SUDAN.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">
                <head>LOCUST SWARMS.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                <p>Wad Medani, October 2.
                I informed you in my last letter the locusts were not expected to do ranch harm to the crops owing to the heavy rains which had fallen. Unhappily they are now more numerous than ever, and may yet do considerable harm. It is very difficult to persuade the natives to take any measures against them, for the Arabs of this district leave everything to Providence.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>DEVOURED BY A CROCODILE.</head>
                <p>While Bimbashi Nickerson, Inspector of the Mudirieh of Senaar was proceeding on a tour of inspection on the Dinder River one of his servants was carried away by a crocodile before the eyes of his comrades on the steamer. A sailor who witnessed the terrible sight, threw himself into the water and tried to save the wretched boy, but the reptile escaped with its  prey. The generous Bimbashi on his return gave the mother of the boy a large sum of money. The sailor, who risked his life to save his friend will, I hear, be generously rewarded by the Government.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                <head>FEVER PREVALENT.</head>
                <p>Miralai Dickenson Bey, Governor of the Blue Nile Province, has been rather seriously ill and great sympathy is felt for this energetic official, who has been taken to hospital at Khartoum. Fever has been very prevalent in the Southern Provinces. Mr. Marsden, Deputy inspector of Singa, who worked up to the last, was finally compelled to go on leave for three months.</p>
                <div type="item">
                <head>MEDANI SCHOOLS.</head>
                <p>The Government School built at Wad Medani will open very shortly. The masters are now on their way from Khartoum. The school will prepare pupils for the Gordon College and the funds for its maintenance are levied from the natives at the rate of five milliemes per ardeb, taken in the Uskur tax. Traders and well-to-do persons , will each have to pay L.E. 1 per annum for their sons’, education.</p></div>
                    <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                        <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                        <p>BREMEN.</p>
                        <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the Sudan.</p>
                        <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                        <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                        <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                    </div>
                
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                <head>OBITUARY.</head>
                <div type="item">    
                <head>SIR HENRY IRVING.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
                <p>John Henry Brodribb, who assumed the name of Henry Irving, was born on February 6,1838, at Keiton near Glastonbury, and educated at Dr. Pinches’ school, in George Yard, Lombard Street, London. He made his first public ap-  pearance at the Sunderland Theatre, Sept 29, 1856, and after a series of engagements at Edinburgh, Glasgow, Manchester, and Liverpool, extending over nine years, he was engag- ed on July 30,1866, to play, with Miss Kate Terry, at Manchester, by Mr. Dion Boncicanlt, in an original play of his, entitled "Hunted Down.” This led to a London engagement,  when he came out at the St. James’s Theatre as Doricourt in the "Belle’s Stratagem." He sub- sequently played at Drury Lane, the Hay- market, and the Gaiety theatres.  In May, 1870, he transferred his services to the Vaudeville Theatre, playing Digby Grant in Mr. Albery’s comedy of the “Two Roses”, which character he sustained for 300 conse- cutive nights. His representation of “Hamlet” at the Lyceum Theatre (October 31, 1874) produced a great sensation among the play- going public, and opinion was at first much divided as to the merits of the performance, but it is now generally admitted that by his rendering of this and of other Shakespearian parts, Mr. Irving has placed himself at the head of English tragedians. "Hamlet” was played for 200 nights, the longest run of the play on record. He appeared in ''Macbeth’’  Sept. 18, 1875 ; in “Othello" in 1876 ; and next as Philip in Tennyson's drama of "Queen Mary”  One of the parts in which he made his work and by which he will be best remem- bered by many, was that of Matthias in "The  Bells” a powerful drama which had a long run at the time of its production, and has been fre- quently reproduced. Afterwards Mr. Irving  played his Shakespearian parts in the provinces, in Scotland, and in Ireland. When in Dublin, he  played "Hamlet" by the request af the Univer-  sity, he having been presented with an address  in the Dining Hall of Trinity College. In Jan., 1879, he added to his Shakespearian repertory by playing "Richard III." at the Lyceum. The withdrawal of Mrs. Bateman from the Lyceum gave Mr. Irving supreme control over the theatre, of which he had long been the mainstay. It opened under his management on Dec. 30, 1878, when he again played ''Hamlet" for 100 nights. The most remarkable incidents of Mr. Irving's manage- ment have been the production of “Othello" (in which he alternated the parts of the Moor and lago with Mr. Edwin Booth), "The Mer- chant of Venice," 'Much Ado about Nothing," The Cup," "Twelfth Night,” and "Faust," all which have been played in conjunction with Miss Ellen Terry. A public banquet was given to Mr. Irving at St James’s Hall, on July 4, 1883, shortly before his departure with the Lyceum company for a theatrical tour in the United States. A second visit to America was made in 1884, and before its close Mr. Irving delivered an address to the students of Harvard University on the art of acting. He also delivered an address by the invitation of the Vice Chancellor (Prof. Jowett) at Oxford, on June 26, 1886, On May 5, 1887, Mr. Irving was elected a life trustee of Shakespeare’s birthplace. On June 1 he produced Byron’s  "Werner" at the Lyceum Theatre for the benefit of Dr. Westland Marston, with the fine result of giving over £800 to the distressed  dramatist. On October 17 he visited Stratford- on-Avon for the purpose of making the dedica- tory speech at the presentation of a public fountain by Mr. G. W. Childs, of Philadelphia, and the next day left Liverpool for a third tour in America, lasting until March 24 1888. During his stay in the States he was given, on March 15, a reception by the American Geethe Society, and on March 19, by special desire :of the War Department, he took his company to the Military Academy at West Point where, with Miss Ellen Terry, he gave "The Merchant of Venice" in Elizabethan dress and without scenery of any kind. On March 12 the great blizzard occurred which paralysed New York for a week, and on that evening the Star, there Mr. Irving was performing, was the only theatre open. After a short season at the Lyceum he took "Faust” on tour, and at Bolton laid the foundation-stone of a new theatre. On Nov. 28 he was entertained at a publio banquet 5 in Birmingham. On'. Dec. 29 he produced ' Macbeth at tho Lyceum, with Miss EUeo v Terry as Lady Macbeth, andran it until the following surnmor, nearly 200 nights, which  is the longest run of the play on record. In April of the year 1889 he visited Germany, where "Julius Caesar" and “The Merchant of Venice” were presented for him at the Berliner Theatre by Herr Barnay ; and on his return home he played, with Miss Ellen Terry, before the Queen at Sandringham. On Sept. 28 he revived at the Lyceum Watts-Philips’ play “The Dead Heart." The play ran the whole season, ending in the summer of 189-, after which, with Miss Ellen Terry, he made a short provincial tour, giving recitals of "Macbeth” with the accompaniment of Sir Arthur Sulli- van’s music. On Sept. 20, 1890, he produced “Ravenswood,'' by Herman Merivale, founded on Sir Walter Scott’s "Bride of Lammermoor." This was followed in 1891 by a revival of "Much Ado." "The Lyons Mail,”' and  The Corsican Brothers.” During the season of 1892  Mr. Irving’s company played "Henry VIII.,"
                a notable revival, at the Lyceum, the great actor taking the part of Cardinal Wolsey.  His next part was not dissimilar to this, for he appeared as "Becket” in the late Lord Tenny son’s great play of that name. At the end of 1893 Mr. Irving gave numerous revivals of familiar pieces in his repertoire. He then took his company to America, and, on his return to the Lyceum in the spring of 1894, revived “Faust.”  In September 1894, he appeared at Bristol in a little play by Dr. Conan Doyle, in which be figures as a Waterloo veteran. In 1899 he withdrew from the management of the Lyceum Theatre and has since made several tours in America, and also frequent visits to the provinces.  He was knighted in 1895 and received the honorary degrees of LL.D. of Dublin, Cambridge and Glasgow Universities.</p></div>
                
                <cb n="6/>"
                    <div type="item">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE</head></div>
                        <div type="item">
                    <p>Vendredi 13 Octobre
                    La situation monetaire nes’est pas ameliordes ioi plus qu’en Europe, oul’on parle d’aug- menter encore le taux d’escompte. Aussi les affaires sont-elles peu importantes sur notre marche, en depit d’une fermete relative: sur les fluctuations qui ont en lien depuis ven- dredi dernier deux tiers indiquent une hauses et un tiers une.baisse ; mais on peut dire d’une facon generale que le calme a prevalu sur toute la ligne, exoepte en National Bank, Agricole, Markets, Anglo-American Nile et Behera.</p>
                    <p>On espere une amelioration a la suite du versement de 10 £ par action que doit faire la Daira Sanieh lu-di prochain. Ce versement auquel les princes khediviaux avaient fait op- position vient d’etre autorise par, le juge de refere du Caire devant lequel le Gunvoroemant prptien avait porta Io differend. L- Somme considerable que ce paiement va mettre en circulation faciliters surement les operations de notre place.</p>
                    <p>Les Sucreries sont en pleine debandade a 30 francs. La direction du Caire a ferme les usines de Rodah, Magaga et Bibeh par raison d’eco- nomie, et M. Willcocks est en tonrnee d’ins- pection dans la-Hante-Egypte. </p>
                    <p>Une bonne operation a ete dernierement conclue par l’Egyptian Land and General trust a Alexandrie. II a’agit de l’achat des terrains Gourbal a des conditions avantageuses pour la Societe.</p>
                    <p>Le personnel venu d’Angleterre pour l’ex- ploitation des Oasis est arrive au Caire d’oh'il se rendra prochainement a ses divers portes de destination. Eu parlant des Oasis le directeur a dit que le sous-sol contenait des nappes d’eau inepuisables. II suffit de creuser les puita artesiens a des distances suffisantes les uns des autres pour maintenir la pression.</p>
                    <p>Un heureux envenement pour les porteurs d’Anglo American Nile e’est l’entente inter- venue entre cetta compagnie et la Ham- burg America pour le service fluvial a orga- niser en Egypte. Le cours de l’Anglo-American est monte de ce chef de 5 9/ a 5 15/16 et 6,et la tendance est toujours pour la hausse.</p>
                    <p>Un autre evenement de la semaine qui est
                    digne de remarque e’est l’achat de la Fayoum Light Railways par un groupe de financiers anglo-belge qui se propose d’augmenter de beaucoup le capital initial (L.E. 200,000) en vue d’une extension considerable du reseau et d’autres amelierations.  La Compagnie se pro- po¬se egalement d’utiliser les chutes d’eau de Fayoum dont la force atteint 4,000 chevaux vapeur comme force motrice des diverses usines de la localite.</p>
                    <p>La National Bank gagne 1/8 sur le cours de vendredi dernier et cioture a 27 5/16.</p>
                    <p>Il en est de meme de I’Agricole qui clotere a 9 3/4. </p>
                    <p>Le cours du Behera, qui avait flechi au com- mencement de la semaine, reprend vers la fin a 43, a la nonvelle de l’emission des 25,000 actions de l’Union Fonciere d’Egypte offertee aux por- teurs de Behera au prix de £5 et a raison d’une actions de l’Union Fonciere d’Egypte pour deux actions ordinaires de la Societe du Bedhera.</p>
                    <p>Les Markets a’avancent de 25/3 a 26 a cause naturellement de la prochaine reouverture des marches, ear l’etat des recettes ne justifie en rien cette hausse.</p>
                    <p>De 1/8 la Ramleh Railway monte a 7 3/16.</p>
                    <p>Les Dividendes Tramway monte egale- ment de 328 a 332, taudis’que les Priviledgies restent stationnaires a 162. </p>
                    <p>En Brasseries nous assistons au meme monvement: Les Privilegiecs a Alexandrie et au Caire restent sans changements, pendant que les Dividendes haussent respectivement de 10O a 105 et de 62 a 63.</p>
                    <p>En hausse encore la Salt and Soda de 33/6 a 34, l'Obligation Credit Foncier de 315 a 318 la Bauque d’Athenes de 135 a 135 1/4 et la Delta Light de 2 1/2 a 2 9/16. </p>
                    <p>Les valeurs qui au con^ ire ont faibli sont: la Delta Light de 13 1/16 a 12 15/16, l’Alex- andria Water de 15 /16 a 15, les Cotton Mills de 5/9 a 5/6, la Nungovich de 10 15/16 a 10 13/16 et la Land Bank de 9 7/8 a 9 3/4.</p>
                    <p>Les Estate, l’Investment et le Trust, si actifs naguere, restent sans transactions appreciables, queique soutenus aux cours respectifs de 1 7/32, 1 5/16 et 1 9/32, ainsi que l'Urbaine a 5 3/8. </p>
                    <p>Le prix de la Daira n'a pas sensiblement varie-e’est toujours 28, mais plutot acheteurs. </p>
                    <p>Somme toute, la semaine qui vient de se- couler n’a gu’ere ete plus active que les deux
                    qui l’out precedee, mais les cours ont ete plus fermes .</p>
                            <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head></div>
                            <div type="item">
                    <p>(Auiourd’ hui midi et demie)</p>
                    <p>Comme un digne corollaire de la semaine, le marche a fait prevue sujourd' hui d’une inaction a peu pres complete. La corbeille a ete delals- see durant la plus grande partie de la matinee.</p>
                    <p>Aussi n’est il guere possible d’asrigner des variations aux cours des valeurs.</p>
                    <p>LA National Bank est toujours demandee a
                    27	5/16.</p>
                    <p>Mais l’Agricole flechit legerement a 9 3/4.</p>
                    <p>On achete la Behera a 43 1/8, soit au meme prix qu’hier.</p>
                    <p>L’Union Fonciere dont il est question dans notre chronique fait £ l ll/l6 de primp sur le prix d’emission. On l’achete a 6 11/16.</p>
                    <p>La Comptoir est stationnaire a 4 9/32.</p>
                    <p>Une reaction se produit sur la New Dairs don’t le cours flechit a 27 15/16. 
                    <p>La Ramleh Railway est au contraire plus ferme a 7 1/4.</p>
                    <p>Il ne serait guere possible d’assigner un prix aux Sucreries, car on n’a pas traite d’affaires ce matin. Tontefois, la valeur nous vient de Paris en reprise a 35 francs.</p>
                    <p>Le reste du marche est absolument calme of sans  variations.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
