<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hank Thompson</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-04">November 4, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, SSTRUDAY, NOVEMBER 4, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIA’S PLIGHT.</head>
                    <head>HORRORS FORESHADOWED.</head>
                    <head>ARMED RISING PROBABLE.</head>
                    <head>DEFECTION IN ARMY.</head>
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                    <dateline>London, Friday, Nov. 3.</dateline>
                    <p>There is no improvement to record in the terrible condition of Russia. The
                        revolutionary leaders foreshadow horrors eclipsing any yet recorded. They
                        have ordered the suspension of the general strike for a period of 30 days,
                        and are employing the interval in making the final preparations for an armed
                        rising, unless complete satisfaction is given to the national demands. </p>
                    <p>There are symptoms of defection in the army, and that the troops are prepared
                        to use their arms on the popular side. </p>
                    <p>Reports from the provinces show that there is nothing but turmoil and
                        bloodshed, there being frequent slaughters of Jews. Martial law has been
                        proclaimed at Odessa, and the Press censorship has been withdrawn. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Odessa, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The troops are re-assuming control of the city and clearing off the mobs.
                        (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>8t. Petersburg, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The railway men are continuing the strike in order to prevent the despatch of
                        troops to Finland. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>An Imperial ukase proclaiming an amnesty was signed to-day at Peterhof. </p>
                    <p>The general situation throughout Russia is unchanged. Anti-Jewish
                        disturbances and massacres continue at Kishineff, Rostoff, Kieff, Poltava,
                        Sevastopol, and elsewhere. Communications by wireless telegraph have been
                        established between the Prussian port Memel and Peterhoff, by means of a
                        German cruiser and torpedo-boats. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The Tsar has signed an amnesty. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL TOUR.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARRIVAL AT ADEN.</head>
                    <dateline>Perm, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The Renown and Terrible passed here at midnight. (Reuter) </p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <dateline>Aden, November 3.</dateline>
                        <p>The Prince and Princess of Wales have arrived. The Fox and Proserpine
                            have returned and will proceed to Bombay in company with the Renown.
                            (Reuter) </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CRETE.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ACTION BY CONSULS.</head>
                    <dateline>Canea, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The Consuls, on behalf of their Governments, have summoned the revolutionary
                        chiefs to lay down arms, promising them a general amnesty and the assembly
                        of a commission of enquiry to examine the necessity of reforms. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COTTON CONFERENCE.</head>
                    <dateline>New Orleans, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The President of the Southern United States Cotton Association announces a
                        conference, the date of which is not yet fixed, of representatives of
                        Manchester, Continental, and American spinners, to establish doner
                        relations, and stable prices. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MADAGASCAR.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW GOVERNOR GENERAL.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>The appointment of the deputy M. Augagneur as Governor-General of Madagascar
                        has been signed. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>M. Augagneur has been appointed Governor-General of Madagascar. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORWAY.</head>
                    <p>FIRST BRITISH MINISTER. </p>
                    <p>London, November 3. Mr. Arthur James Herbert, Charge d’Af faires at
                        Darmstadt, has been appointed first British Minister to Norway. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR CLAUDE MACDONALD.</head>
                    <dateline>London, November 3</dateline>
                    <p>Sir Claude Macdonald. K.C.B., has been promoted ambassador. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH CHAMBER.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, November 8.</dateline>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies passed simply the order of the day in the debate on
                        an interpellation concerning the Lonywy strikes. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE.</head>
                    <dateline>Vienna, November 3.</dateline>
                    <p>Demonstrations in favor of universal suffrage have taken place at Prague and
                        Grata. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Legislative Council will meet on December 1 next </p>
                    <p>All Saints’, Cairo.— The Rev. Professor Sayce will preach at All Saints’
                        Church, Cairo, on Sunday, 12th inst., and not to-morrow. </p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—During the month of October 312 vessels passed through the Canal,
                        the does from which amounted to frs. 8,903,400 31. </p>
                    <p>Reunion des Familles. -This excellent Alexandrian society has organised a
                        series of balls during the winter season at the New Khedivial Hotel. </p>
                    <p>The Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Co. has opened a temporary office next door
                        to Messrs. Rosseli and Kerr in Maison Chawarbi Pasha, Kasr el-Nil-atrest,
                        Cairo. </p>
                    <p>Irrigation Department.—Abdel Latif Bey el Moweilihi, son of Abdel Salam
                        Pasha, has been appointed chief engineer of the teftish in charge of the
                        Second Circle of Irrigation in the Gharbieh Province. </p>
                    <p>Murder at Cairo.—A quarrel took place on Thursday between two natives of the
                        Sayeda Zenab quarter of Cairo, and one of them became so excited that he
                        thrust a knife into the other’s heart, killing him on the spot. The murderer
                        was arrested. </p>
                    <p>Our Commercial Review.—From to-day we will publish a special early edition of
                        our Commercial Review in order that it may be despatched to Europe every
                        Saturday afternoon by the Austrian Lloyd mail. The subscription to this
                        review is P.T. 50 per aunum. </p>
                    <p>Coal Imports.—During the period from 1st January to 2nd November, 919,9 96
                        tons of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 495,416, Newcastle
                        214,545, Scotland 1[]0,924, Yorkshire 64,303 and other places 34,708 tons.
                        Daring the same period last year 889,464 tons were received. </p>
                    <p>Alexandria Pickpocket Case. - Yesterday a European lady was passing near
                        Santi’s Restaurant at Alexandria when a pickpocket seized her purse and made
                        off The lady, who declared that the purse contained £50, fainted. The thief,
                        though hotly pursued, made good his escape. </p>
                    <p>A Record.—An American importer at Alexandria has received a quantity of goods
                        from New York within fourteen days. The goods were transhipped to the S 3.
                        Schleswig at Naples. Fourteen days from New York to Alexandria is a record,
                        the average time for mails being sixteen days. </p>
                    <p>The Union Artistique Francaise give their eighth performance at the Eden
                        Theatre to-night, when a triple programme will be presented, viz., Frangois
                        Coppee’s 1-act comedy Le Luthier de Cremone, the drama La Dernire Idole, and
                        the comedy Un jeune Homme presse. The curtain will rise at 9 p.m. </p>
                    <p>Alhambra Theatre.—The Gardet French comedy company is meeting with great
                        success at the Alhambra. This evening the company will present Le Sursis, a
                        military vaudeville in 3 acts. This will be preceded by an operetta entitled
                        Les Charbonniers. To-morrow a matinee performance will be given of La
                        Cagnotte, the legendary vaudeville from the Palais Royal. In the evening,
                        one of the Palais Royal’s greatest successes, Cheri, will be produced </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LIST.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARRIVAIS.</head>
                    <p>Le paquebot “Moulouya” des Messageries Maritimes arrivé de Marseille le 4
                        Novembre avait à bord : </p>
                    <p>M. Kress et ami, M. Marietti, Mlle Floridal, Mlle Mariette, Mlle Beau regard,
                        M. Viannay, M. Leboox et 3 enfants, M. Bernard, Mlle Bougier, Mlle V. Zahar,
                        Mlle Hoohstrasse, Mme Petit, M. Âlessandri, M. Délavai, M. Belonole. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>Le paquebot “Senegal” des Messageries Maritimes parti poor Marseille le 3
                        Novembre avait k bord:</p>
                    <p>M. et Mme Ronillot, M. Ibrahim Fehime M. Dibbina, M. et Mme Leoerf, M.
                        Ballatiano, M. A. Buoau, M. et Mme Poutrel et fils, M. Combe, M. Rioha, Mile
                        Miranda, Frdre Xenophon et 47 passagers de Sme olasse. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Bestaorant</head>
                    <p>ARISTON AERATED WATER8</p>
                    <p>Guranteed Distilled</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA J</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>Oppoctto tk Trump Co. forb, BWio kkl, iMMl-lt</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COTTON IN KOREA.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EXTENSIVE CULTIVATION</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                        <dateline>London, Friday, Nor. 3.</dateline>
                        <p>We understand that, though nothing has been definitely settled, the new
                            lunatic asylum will probably not be constructed near the desert edge
                            west of Damanhour, in the Behera Province, as was previously expected.
                            The Behera site had certain disadvantages, chief among them the absence
                            of stone quarries which would have greatly increased the cost of
                            construction,a brick building costing at least twice as much as one
                            constructed of local building stone, many good varieties of which are
                            available and abundant, especially near the edge of the Eastern
                            (Arabian) desert </p>
                        <p>The choice of a site at Khanka, a lew miles beyond Khanka, is now being
                            discussed, and we understand that Sir Horace Pinching Pasha, Dr.
                            Warnock, and Mr. Courtenay Clifton, the first two representing the
                            Sanitary Department and the latter the Ministry of Public Works, will
                            proceed next week to the spot from Marg and examine the proposed site.
                            The new asylum will probably be built in the hard desert fairly near
                            Khanka—if built in the neighbourhood of Cairo at all—where there are
                            water wells which yield a good supply, and abundance of building stone
                            is within easy reach. The climate of Khanka is good, and the town, which
                            was at one time a fairly important centre, but is said to have been
                            declining recently, may well benefit by the construction of‘the asylum,
                            especially if the Marg-Matarieh railway, as was formerly proposed, is
                            prolonged from Marg to Khanka. The embankments for part at least of the
                            intervening distance were laid down and rails and embankment alike reach
                            Alag some two miles N. E. of Marg and a little less than one-third of
                            the way to Khanka. </p>
                        <p>Sir Peroy Girouard, it will be remembered, at one time contemplated the
                            extension of the Cairo-Marg line through Khanka to the well-known
                            Abou-Zaabel stone quarries. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW LUNATIC ASYLUM.</head>
                    <p>The fine new hotel in the Sharia Soliman Pasha, one of the largest and most
                        up-to-date in. Cairo, will be formally inaugurated on Thursday next, when a
                        concert, and later a ball, will be given. </p>
                    <p>The building, which can accommodate 200 guests, has been furnished throughout
                        by Messrs. S. Davis and Sons, of London. It is lighted throughout by
                        electricity and possesses lifts and all the very latest sanitary
                        improvements. There are also a restaurant and grill room, bar and
                        billiard-rooms, eta The whole of the rooms have already been retained for
                        the middle of next month. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NATIONAL HOTEL</head>
                    <p>The Japanese Government is taking active steps to secure cotton culture on a
                        large scale in Korea. Experiments which have been made have proved that the
                        soil is suitable for its cultivation. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN.</head>
                    <p>The season at Helouan is beginning under the best auspices. There are already
                        many visitors at the different hotels, and the Grand Hotel, which opened its
                        doors on the 1st inst, has began with a goodly number of guests. We notice
                        among them Mr. and Mrs. von Wedderkop, Mrs. P. Koop, Miss Koop, Mr. S.
                        Manuel, Dr. O. Hobson, Messrs. J. H. and S. R Charles worth, Mr. P. S.
                        Barlow, Mr. John L. Oliver, and Mr. Geo. Patterson.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BUILDING SITES AND SANITATION.</head>
                    <p>Our attention has been called by some of our readers to one of the most
                        unpleasant accompaniments of building activity at Cairo. </p>
                    <p>To put the matter plainly, in far too many cases, no conveniences of any sort
                        are supplied for the use of the workmen, with the result that an amount of
                        filth is allowed to be spread broadcast in the neighbourhood of these
                        buildings, which is bound to have a prejudicial effect on the health or at
                        least on the comfort of the neighbourhood Dead dogs and cats and other offal
                        are frequently thrown into these sites and may remain there for two or three
                        days, festering and horrible, to the disgust of passers-by. Would it be
                        impossible for the Sanitary Department to force contractors to provide
                        latrines, eta, for the use of the workmen, which could be cleared out from
                        time to time by carts? A rule of this sort has long been applied to all such
                        cases in the British Islands, and has proved a decided success from the
                        point of view of the comfort and health of all concerned. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS.</head>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo for the Nile trip yesterday by the P. S.
                        Hataaoo Mrs. H. Halsey Vail, Miss M. Vail, Mr. H.H. Worthington, Mr. Rollo
                        Worthington, Mrs. Worthington, Miss Knight, Rev. Dr. and Mrs. Watson, Mr.
                        and Mrs. W. Brand, Miss Brand, Mrs. Stevens, </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF GRAND MUFTI.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>APPOINTED TWO DAYS AGO.</head>
                        <p>The new Grand Mufti of Egypt, Sheikh Abdel Kader El Rafei, died in Cairo
                            at 8 o’clock yesterday evening, it is believed, from heart failure. </p>
                        <p>The deceased, who was appointed only two days ago to the Grand Muftiship,
                            in place of the late Sheikh Mohamed Abdou, was of the Hanafi sect and
                            enjoyed a great reputation for piety and learning. His death is greatly
                            deplored among Moslem circles, which had been greatly pleased by his
                            recent appointment </p>
                        <p>The statement of one of our contemporaries, that the late Grand Mufti was
                            found dead in his carriage on returning from a visit to the British
                            Agency, is not correct Sheikh El Rafei’s last visit to the British
                            Agency took place two days ago, immediately after his nomination. </p>
                        <p>It is of course too early for discussion as to who will succeed him in
                            the Grand Muftiship. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WEDDING AT ST. MARK’S.</head>
                    <p>A marriage took place on the 1st inst. at St Mark’s Church, Alexandria,
                        between Mr. Denys Goldney Birch and Miss Lucy H. B. Burton. Canon Ward and
                        the Rev. R. Wormell officiated. The bride wore a pretty dress of white crepe
                        de Chine trimmed with Bruges lace and orange blossom, and a tulle veil with
                        sprays of same. Her cousin, Miss Sepsi, attended her as bridesmaid. She wore
                        a white silk dress, white hat and pink roses. The bride was given away by
                        her uncle, Mr. Sepsi, and Mr.,Hirsch acted as “best mao.” Numerous relatives
                        and friends ware present at the church, many of whom went on afterwards to
                        Mr. and Mrs. L. H. Birch's house at Ramleh to wish good luck to, and drink
                        the health of, the newly-married couple. The presents were numerous, among
                        them </p>
                    <p>being ;—bride to bridegroom, antique silver electric lamp-candle sticks and
                        accessories for writing table; bridegroom to bride, red Morocco leather
                        silver dressing case, gold watch and chain; Mr. and Mrs. L. H. Birch,
                        oheque; Mr. and Mrs. A. H. Payton, furniture; Mr. and Mrs. A. Sepsi, silver
                        tray with and and tea service ; Mr. I. Sepsi, two crystal and silver
                        decanters, with cake dish ; Miss S. Sepsi, silver card tray ; Mrs. M. Biroh,
                        oheque; Mr. C. H. Biroh, Gladstone bag; Mr. L. G. Biroh, brass bowl; Mr. and
                        Mrs. C. J. Choremi, gold soent bottle set with ruby and brilliants; Mr. W.
                        F. Peel, 2 silver vases ;Mrs..Braddyil, oheque; Mr.A.F. Hirsoh, silver rose
                        bowl; Mr. and Mrs K. P. Birley, silver pepper pots. Handsome presents were
                        also reoeived from Mr. R Gteutilii, Mr. H. Heraolt, Mia Buffer, Mr. and Mrs.
                        R G. C. Moss,' Mr. a R C. Moss, Mr., Mrs. and Miss Bell, Mr. R. Remanda, Mr.
                        A. Remanda, Mr. and Mrs. G. A. Williams, Mr. D. Anastasiadis, Mr. M. A.
                        Caloyanni, Mr. L. Vivante, Mr. 8. Emmens, Miss Demech, Miss A Demeoh, Mr. a
                        Blattner, Mr. R.Blattner, Mrs.VveF.Giglio, Mr. 0. Barany, Mr. A. H. Mieli,
                        Mr. Pandelidis, Mrs. Terlendi, Mr. F. Leveaux, Mr. C. Peel, Mr. W. A Biroh,
                        Mr. Oswald Gorra, Mr. A. M. Giglio, Mr. Pegna, Mr. A. Bassiliadis, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Kelham, Miss L. J. Peel, Mr. and Mrs. L. J.Peel, etc., eto. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>H.H. Prince Leopold of Battenburg, wife is leaving Marseilles for Port Said
                        on the 24th instant by the orient-pacific steamer Ormuz, will stay a week in
                        Cairo before proceeding to Assouan. A suite of apartments has been retained
                        for his Highness at the Hotel d’Angleterre. </p>
                    <p>Immediately on his arrival at Constantinople the Grand Cadi of Egypt was
                        summoned to a private audience with the Sultan. </p>
                    <p>Adly Pasha Yaghen, Governor of Cairo, will probably arrive from Europe on
                        Monday next, and will resume his functions on the following day. </p>
                    <p>Mat. fi M Pasha is expected to return from leave next Monday </p>
                    <p>Judge H. W. Halton is returning by the P. &amp; 0. steamer Mooltan, due at
                        Port Said on the 14th November. </p>
                    <p>Col. Aylmer has returned to Cairo from England. </p>
                    <p>Mr. Howard Carter has resigned his inspectorship under the Antiquities
                        Service. </p>
                    <p>Dr. Murison has returned to Cairo from England. </p>
                    <p>The many friends of Dr. Hayes, who was compelled to leave Egypt several
                        months ego on account of serious illness, will be pleased to hear that he is
                        completely restored to health, and will soon be returning from England to
                        resume his duties at the Quarantine office in Suez. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM FAYOUM.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE NAZLEH WATERFALL.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
                        <dateline>Fayoum, Nov. 8.</dateline>
                        <p>The Ministry of the Interior and the Public Works Department have granted
                            a concession for working the Nazleh waterfall to the Mixed Tribunal of
                            Fayoum, in order that it may be used for the benefit of the inhabitants
                            of Medinet el-Fayoum. There are, however, no public funds available for
                            the purpose, and it is proposed to offer the concession to capitalists,
                            who, after supplying the necessary power for Lighting Fayoum by
                            electricity, could apply, the surplus to commercial purposes. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>IRRIGATION DEPARTMENT.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Clowes left Fayoum yesterday for Wasta. Mr. Ireland is in Beni Souef
                            province. Mr. Box is expected to leave Fayoum shortly, much to the
                            regret of the fellaheen, who have always found him mindful of their just
                            rights in the matter of water supply. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MINISTRY OF THE INTERIOR.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Major Elgood arrived yesterday, but without an assistant, his late
                            assistant having been appointed secretary to the Adviser. Major Elgood’s
                            district now comprises the provinces of Fayoum, Beni Souef, and Ghiseh,
                            known sometimes as Middle Egypt. The Major knows the Fayoum well, and
                            frequently is called upon to settle disputes between village sheikhs.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NATIVE TRIBUNAL.</head>
                        <p>Boutros Girgis, a clerk in Beni Souef Tribunal, who is charged with
                            disposing of official documents, some of which he is said to have sold
                            to Madame Astireh, is to be tried by the Native Court on the 7th inst.
                            Much public interest is manifested in the case. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EAST INDIES SQUADRON v. E.T.C.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>(SUEZ).</head>
                        <p>A match was played at Suez between the above teams on Thursday, 26th
                            ulto., resulting in a somewhat easy win for the E.T.C. Meet. The E.T.C.
                            batted first, but were soon out for the small score of 55, thanks to the
                            bowling of Mansell and some excellent fielding by the members of the
                            E.T.C. Lt. Wolfe-Murray, the captain, was the only one to reach double
                            figures, playing a steady innings. The E/T.C. found no difficulty in
                            knocking off the required number owing to the batting of Mansell and
                            Toms, and were able to declare at 109 for 5. The Squadron, going in a
                            second time, ran up a total of 72 for 5, a very pleasant game thus being
                            won by the RT.C. on the first innings by 54 runs.,Scores </p>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>East Indies Squadron.</head>
                            <p>Lt. Jones c. Templeman, b. Mansell ... 2 </p>
                            <p>Lt. Linteny b. Battiscombe ........... 1 </p>
                            <p>Sub.-Lt Kennedy b. Mansell............ 5 </p>
                            <p>Cb. Stwt Stewart c. and b. Mansell.... 8 </p>
                            <p>Lt. Wolfe-Morray a Templeman,b.Mansell 22 </p>
                            <p>Lt Stockwell o.Le Rongetel,b.Battisoombe 2 </p>
                            <p>Lt Bevan o Harris, b. Mansell ........ 5 </p>
                            <p>Ass. Pay Organ o. Harris, b. Mansell ... 2 </p>
                            <p>Staff. Surgeon Jeremy ran out... _ ... 3 </p>
                            <p>P. 0.2. Harley h. Williams ....... _ 0 </p>
                            <p>Sub.-Lt Drake not out ................ 8 </p>
                            <p>Byes 1, Leg Byes 1, Wides 4....... _ 6 </p>
                            <p>Total ... 55 </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>E.T.C.</head>
                            <p>Massey c. Bevan, b. Stewart ......... 7 </p>
                            <p>Mansell c. Wolfe-Murray, b. Harley ... 49 </p>
                            <p>Carpenter b. Stewart .................. 10 </p>
                            <p>Toms b. Kennedy ..................... 24 </p>
                            <p>Williams b. Kennedy ................... 4 </p>
                            <p>Le Rongetel c. Stockwell, b. Harley ... 3 </p>
                            <p>Battiscombe not out.................... 1 </p>
                            <p>Harris not out....................... 2 </p>
                            <p>Brans ] Did not bat. </p>
                            <p>Dogmore ] Did not bat. </p>
                            <p>Temp’eman ] Did not bat. </p>
                            <p>Byes................................... 12 </p>
                            <p>Total ... 109 </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>East Indies Squadron. </head>
                            <p>2nd Innings. </p>
                            <p>Jones c. Harris, b. Williams ... 21 </p>
                            <p>Beran b. Harris ... ... 4 </p>
                            <p>Linberry b. Mansell ... 14 </p>
                            <p>Kennedy c. Mansell, b. Battiscombe ... 10 </p>
                            <p>Wolfe-Mnrray not out ... 10 </p>
                            <p>Stockwell c. Harris, b. Mansell ... 6 </p>
                            <p>Organ not out ... ... 3 </p>
                            <p>Byee 3, Wides 1 ... 4 72 </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. Roman Prince, with passengers and general cargo, left Manchester on
                        Friday and is due to arrive at Alexandria on or about November 19 via Tunis
                        and Malta. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck &amp; Co’s Pilsener-Beer.</head>
                    <p>BREMEN. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA.</head>
                    <p>Constituted with limited LUbfitty wafer Khedivial Decree dated 80th of May
                        1905. </p>
                    <p>Board of Directors.</p>
                    <p>President: The Governor of the National Bank of Egypt </p>
                    <p>Vice-President : The Governor of the Bank of Abyssinia. </p>
                    <p>S.E Boghos Pasha Nubar, Director of the National Bank of Egypt. </p>
                    <p>Baron J. De Menaace, Director of the National Bank of Egypt </p>
                    <p>Raphael Suares, Director of the National Bank of Egypt </p>
                    <p>H.H. Ras Makunan, Governor of Harrar and its dependencies. </p>
                    <p>H.H. Has Walda Giorgis, Governor of Kaffa and its dependencies. </p>
                    <p>F. Monvoirin, director of the Societe Generale de Credit Industrial et
                        Commercial, Paris. . </p>
                    <p>M. le Commr. Francesco Varvaro Projero, Director tor of the Banca d’ltalia,
                        Rome. </p>
                    <p>Wilhelm Pelizaeus, Cairo. </p>
                    <p>The Head Office of the Bank of Abyssinia will be at Adis Ababs </p>
                    <p>The Registered Offices of the Bank will be at Cairo. </p>
                    <p>The National Bank of Bgypt having obtained a Concession from H. M. The
                        Emperor Menelak for the constitution of a Company with liability limited to
                        the nominal amount of the Shares under the name of the Bank of Abyssinia,
                        and the said Bank having been founded under Egyptian Law and authorised by
                        Khedivial Decree on the 80th May, 1905, the National Bank of Egypt offer for
                        sale, on account of themselves and other parties entitled, the above
                        mentioned 100,000 shares (£1. 5s. paid) at the price of £7 per Share (of
                        which £2 is premium and £t.5s. already paid up on the shares) payable to the
                        vendors as follows </p>
                    <p>£9. 10s. Od. on Application, </p>
                    <p>15s. Od. on Allotment. </p>
                    <p>The Balance of £8 15s. Od. per Share, making them fully paid, will be payable
                        to the Bank of Abyssinia as required by it, an, interval of at least two
                        months elapsing between the calls. </p>
                    <p>The Lists will open on the 7th November, 1905, and will close the same day. </p>
                    <p>Applications will be received:— </p>
                    <p>In Adis-Abaha. </p>
                    <p>In Cairo and Alexandria, at the National Bank of Egypt- </p>
                    <p>In London, at the Agency of the National Bank of Egypt, 4 &amp; 5, King
                        william Street In Paris, at the Societe Generale de Credit Industrial et
                        Commercial, 66, Rue de la Victoire. </p>
                    <p>In Rome, Genoa and Milan, at the Banoa d’ltalia, at la Banca Commerciale
                        Italiana, at the Credito Italiano, and at the Societe Bancaria Italiana
                        &amp; Banca di Roma. </p>
                    <p>In Berlin, at the Bank fur Handel &amp; Industrie. </p>
                    <p>In Vienna, at the Creditanstalt fur Handel and Gewerbe. </p>
                    <p>In New York, at Messrs. Baring, Magonn &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>The Warrants will be to Beaver, and will be issued as £1 5s. paid. </p>
                    <p>Dividend payments will be effected at the Companies Offices, the National
                        Bank of Egypt, and at the other establishments above mentioned.
                        ____________________ </p>
                    <p>The work of economic progress for Abyssinia, to collaborate in which this
                        Bank is formed, and by which it should benefit, is one requiring time for
                        development. </p>
                    <p>In accordance with the Statutes, the object of the Bank of Abyssinia is to
                        carry on all Banking, commensal, financial and industrials operations,
                        especially in Abyssinia. </p>
                    <p>The following eight privileges are,granted exclusively to the Bank of
                        Abyssinia, beginning on the day on which it is constituted and lasting
                        daring the 50 years forming the term of the Concession and of the Statutes - </p>
                    <p>1. The Emperor will not allow any other Bank to be established in his
                        Kingdom. </p>
                    <p>2. the Bank of Abyssinia will have the sole right to issue Bank notes. The
                        notes of the Bank of Abyssinia shall be legal tender in Abyssinia and will
                        be exchanged for the beam in gold or silver at the Head Office of the Bank
                        of Abyssinia. </p>
                    <p>3. The Government will not mint any coin. All minting will he done in
                        consultation with the Government by the Bank of Abyssinia, who have the
                        profit resulting therefrom. </p>
                    <p>4. All the Government public funds shall be deposited with the Bank of
                        Abyssinia and Government payments shall be made by cheques drawn on the
                        Bank. </p>
                    <p>5. Preference will be given to the Bank of Abyssinia tor all issues of
                        Government loans. </p>
                    <p>6. The Bank of Abyssinia is given permission to build warehouses, wherein
                        merchants may deposit their goods against loans from the Bank. </p>
                    <p>7. The Government of Abyssinia will give a free grant to the Bank of
                        Abyssinia of all the lands necessary for the establishment of the Head
                        Office, its Agencies and warehouses. </p>
                    <p>8. The Bank of Abyssinia shall have transport for its specie by rail in
                        Abyssinia at Government rates. </p>
                    <p>With regard to the division of profits, Article 89 of the Statutes determines
                        that the net proceeds will, after deduction of all charges, constitute the
                        profits, which will be divisible as follows: — </p>
                    <p>1. Ten per cent, is to be set aside to form the ordinary Reserve Fund. </p>
                    <p>2. A sum shall next be set aside sufficient to pay to the Shareholders seven
                        per cent interest on the Amount paid upon the Shares. </p>
                    <p>3. After then deductions the remaining profits shall be divided in the
                        following manner) </p>
                    <p>As to twenty per cent. to the National Bank of Egypt, to be applied in
                        conformity with the Act of Concession. </p>
                    <p>As to the remaining eighty per cent to the Shareholders. </p>
                    <p>Copies of the Concession, of the Khedivial Decree, end of the Statutes site
                        be seen by intending Subscribers at tha Offices of the London Agency of the
                        National Bank of Egypt, 4 and 5. King William Street London, K.C. </p>
                    <p>Prospectuses and Application Forms can be obtained at the offices of the
                        national Bank of Egypt, 4 &amp; 5, King Willima Street, Lonthon, E.C. 26
                        October 1906 </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
