<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2021-07-29">July 29, 2021</date>
                    <gloss>3</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1882-08-18/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1882-08-18">Friday, August 18, 1882</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="4">4</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" status="verified">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <head>The Egyptian Gazette</head>
                    <p>By Decrees of the Court of Appeal for Egypt, the Tribunals of Alexandria and
                        Cairo, <hi rend="italic">The Egyptian Gazette</hi> has been named an
                        Official Journal for the insertion of any Notices, Decrees or Orders issued
                        by that Court. <lb/>Par diverses ordonnances de la Cour d'Appel
                        d'Alexandrie, et des Tribunaux de Première Instance d'Alexandrie et du
                        Caire, le journal <hi rend="italic">The Egyptian Gazette</hi> a été désigné
                        pour la publication des Insertions et Annonces Judiciaires.</p>
                    <table cols="3">
                        <row>
                            <cell>No. <measure quantity="277">277</measure>.]</cell>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, AUGUST 18, 1882.</cell>
                            <cell>[PRICE: P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>ABONNEMENTS. <p>ALEXANDRIE........ 40 francs par an </p><p>LE
                                    CAIRE et INTERIEUR...... 50 ,, ,, </p><p>ETRANGER</p><p>... ...
                                    ... 60 ,, ,,</p><p>ANNONCES. </p><p>Pour cinquante mots ou
                                    au-dessous, Fr. 10.</p><p>Annonces régulières, de gré à
                                gré.</p></cell>
                            <cell>
                                <p>Le Propriétaire-Directeur:– A. V. PHILIP.</p>
                                <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE PRINTING OFFICE, BOULEVARD DE RAMLEH,
                                    ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                                <p>P. O. Orders and Cheques payable to A. V. PHILIP.</p>
                                <p>Mandats-Poste et autres valeurs à l'ordre de A. V. PHILIP.</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>SUBSCRIPTION.<p>ALEXANDRIA ...... .. .. 40 francs per year
                                    </p><p>CAIRO &amp; INTERIOR .. ... 50 ,, ,,</p><p>OTHER
                                    COUNTRIES .. ... 60 ,, ,,</p><p>ADVERTISEMENTS. </p><p>Eight
                                    shillings for fifty words; contracts entered into for standing
                                    advertisements.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="2"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>FIRE, LIFE &amp; MARINE INSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>C. F. MOBERLY BELL, </p>
                    <p>MAISON ANTONIADIS, BOULEVARD DE RAMLEH,</p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="4" cols="2">
                            <row>
                                <cell rows="4">AGENT :</cell>
                                <cell>ROYAL INSURANCE COMPANY,</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>PHOENIX FIRE OFFICE, </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>UNION MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>SCOTTISH AMICABLE LIFE ASSURANCE SOCIETY.</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>JAMES HEWAT</head>
                    <p>(HEWAT &amp; CO.) </p>
                    <p>PUBLIC ACCOUNTANT ACCREDITED at the "COURTS OF THE REFORM,"</p>
                    <p>AGENT FOR EGYPT TO </p>
                    <p>GUARDIAN ASSURANCE COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>Capital £2,000,000, </p>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL UNION ASSURANCE COMPANY,</p>
                    <p>Capital £2,500,000.</p>
                    <p>RISKS ACCEPTED AT TARIFF RATES. </p>
                    <p>AGENT FOR THE CHEQUE BANK, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, St. Mark's Buildings.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE UNIVERSAL MARINE INTRANCE COMPANY LIMITED,</head>
                    <p>CAPITAL £1,000,000. </p>
                    <p>COMPANY'S OFFICES :– 31, Cornhill, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>CHAIEMAN : SIR JOHN LUBBOCK, Bart., V.P., F.R.S., D.C.L.</p>
                    <p>UNDERWRITER : T. H. WELLS. Esq. </p>
                    <p>SECRETARY : ALFRED TOZER, Esq.</p>
                    <p>AGENTS FOR EGYPT :</p>
                    <p>R. J. MOSS &amp; Co., ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE FIRE INSURANCE ASSOCIATION, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>Capial $1,000,000. </p>
                    <p>RISKS ACCEPTED AT TARIFF RATES BY THE AGENT FOR EGYPT,</p>
                    <p>F. J. Harding, </p>
                    <p>Maison Canelli, behind the Egyptian Telegraph Office.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>PENINSULAR &amp; ORIENTAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>Under Contract for Her Majesty's Mails to India, China, Australia,
                        &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>REDUCED RATES OF PASSAGE MONEY.-SPECIAL RETURN TICKETS. </p>
                    <p>Weekly Departure for BOMBAY. | Fortnightly Departure for CHINA and JAPAN. </p>
                    <p>Fortnightly Departure for CEYLON, MADRAS and CALCUTTA. | Fortnightly
                        Departure for AUSTRALIA and NEW ZEALAND. </p>
                    <p>Under the accelerated service now in force, the Company's steamers generally
                        leave PORT SAID every Thursday for MALTA, GIBRALTAR &amp; LONDON
                        (Gravesend), calling at PLYMOUTH. </p>
                    <p>Occasionally the steamers may leave earlier than Thursday.</p>
                    <p>PLYMOUTH.– Coupon Railway Tickets for London by Great Western Railway are
                        issued at all the Foreign Stations of the Peninsular and Oriental Steam
                        Navigation Company.</p>
                    <p>In addition to a great saving of expense, these Coupons ensure special
                        advantages to passengers landing from the Company's Steamers at
                        Plymouth.</p>
                    <p>They pass the passengers' Baggage through the Docks and into the Train free
                        of Dock Dues and porterage; they are available for Seven days from the day
                        of landing; and they also admit of the journey being broken at any Main Line
                        Station, provided it is completed within that period, and that application
                        is made to the Booking Clerk at the Docks for the necessary authority.</p>
                    <p>Orders obtainable from the Company's Agent boarding the Steamer will also
                        enable Passengers proceeding by the Great Western Railway to Stations other
                        than London to obtain Tickets covering all Dock and Porterage Dues.</p>
                    <p>Convenient Warehouses for the clearance and labelling of Baggage, and
                        well-appointed Waiting Rooms, with Railway Booking and Postal Telegraph
                        Offices attached, are provided close to the landing-place on the premises of
                        the Great Western Company's Docks.</p>
                    <p>Compartments in the splendid First-class carriages of this Line are specially
                        reserved for Saloon Passengers landing at Plymouth from the Company's
                        Steamers, in order that they may proceed on their journey without being
                        inconvenienced by other travellers.</p>
                    <p>These Carriages will be stationed in front of the Baggage Warehouse at the
                        Docks, so that Passengres may take their seats as soon as their Baggage is
                        cleared, and avoid the necessity of walking or hiring a cab to the Milbay
                        Railway Station.</p>
                    <p>This Station and several first class Hotels, are within easy distance of the
                        Docks. </p>
                    <p>GRAVESEND.– When, on account of the tide, the Steamers anchor off Gravesend
                        occasional opportunities are afforded to Passengers to land and proceed to
                        London from thence. </p>
                    <p>LONDON.– Every facility will be afforded at the ROYAL ALBERT DOCKS to those
                        Passengers who prefer to proceed to London in the Steamer. A frequent Train
                        Service is kept up between the Docks and the Termini at Fenchurch Street and
                        Liverpool Street. </p>
                    <p>For further particulars apply to</p>
                    <p> GEORGE ROYLE, </p>
                    <p>Agent P. &amp; O. S. N. Company, </p>
                    <p>PORT SAID.</p>
                </div>
                <cols n="4"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET,</head>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>CARTE D'OR and EXTRA DRY... Fr. 7</p>
                    <p>CARTE BLANCHE..... ,, 6</p>
                    <p>SILLERY MOUSSEUX.... ,, 5</p>
                    <p>Sold at above prices from stock by</p>
                    <p>G. MARCUS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Agents for Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Palestine Independent Tours. </head>
                    <p>ALEXANDER HOWARD, proprietor of Howard's Hotel, Jaffa ; Howard's Hotel,
                        Jerusalem and Howard's Universal Hotel, Latroon, valley of Ajalon, (half-way
                        to Jerusalem) has the largest and best supply of tents and equipage for
                        Syrian Travel. Efficient dragomans and escort provided. Greatest advantages
                        given to all classes of travellers visiting the Holy Land, by direct
                        engagement at Jaffa, or by contract made at my Cairo branch office, in the
                        Esbekieh, opposite Shepheard's Hotel, during the winter season.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>The Anglo-Egyptian Banking Company, Limited. </head>
                    <p>CAPITAL................£1,600,000 </p>
                    <p>Represented by 80,000 Shares of £20, fully paid up. </p>
                    <p>RESERVE FUND................. £160,000</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE: </p>
                    <p>27, Clement's Lane, Lombard Street, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES: </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, PORT SAID, PARIS, LARNACA.</p>
                    <p>AGENCIES: </p>
                    <p>MALTA, NICOSIA, LIMASSOL, and the villages of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Accounts current opened. </p>
                    <p>Deposits received for fixed periods and at call.</p>
                    <p>Letters of credit issued. </p>
                    <p>Payments made by telegraphic order. </p>
                    <p>Purchase and sale of stock and shares on commission. </p>
                    <p>Money advanced against deposit of approved securities and against cotton,
                        cotton seed, bread-stuffs, &amp;c. </p>
                    <p>Every other description of commercial Banking business transacted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>The Crédit Lyonnais</head>
                    <p>Société Anonyme </p>
                    <p>CAPITAL............200,000,000 Francs</p>
                    <p>RESERVE............80,000,000 Francs</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Cairo &amp; Port-Saïd Agencies.</p>
                    <p>Advances made on Egyptian and Foreign Securities.</p>
                    <p>Securities received on deposit and Coupons encashed.</p>
                    <p>Orders executed on the Alexandria and Foreign Stock Exchanges.</p>
                    <p>Purchase and Sale of Securities with Drawings.</p>
                    <p>Encashment of Securities drawn.</p>
                    <p>Issue of cheques, telegraphic remittances and Letters of Credit on all
                        countries.</p>
                    <p>Deposits received for fixed terms.</p>
                    <p>of 1 year, bearing interest at 3 % </p>
                    <p>,, 1½ ,, ,, ,, 3½ %</p>
                    <p>,, 2 ,, ,, ,, 4 %</p>
                    <p>Interest payable every six months.</p>
                    <p>Advances made on merchandise.</p>
                    <p>Deposit, Consignment and Sale of merchandise.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Crédit Foncier Egyptien</head>
                    <p>Société Anonyme </p>
                    <p>Au Capital de Francs 40,000,000.</p>
                    <p>Siège Social au Caire. </p>
                    <p>Prêts hypothécaires à long terme remboursables par annuités calculées de
                        manière à amortir la Dette en 10 ans au moins, 50 ans au plus.</p>
                    <p>Prêts hypothécaires à court terme, remboursables avec ou sans amortissement. </p>
                    <p>Ouvertures de Crédit sur hypothéque. </p>
                    <p>Prêts sur nantissement. </p>
                    <p>Dépôts de fonds en compte-courant. </p>
                    <p>Dépôts de valeurs sans frais.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>The Land &amp; Mortgage Company of Egypt, Limited,</head>
                    <p>Incorporated under the Companies' Acts, 1862 to 1879, with limited liability. </p>
                    <p>CAPITAL £1,000.000 </p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE : 27, Clement's Lane Lombard Street, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>For EGYPT </p>
                    <p>CHIEF OFFICE:– Rue Adib, Alexandria. </p>
                    <p>AGENCIES:– Cairo, Maison Heller, Avenue d'Ismaïlia. </p>
                    <p>TANTAH, Rue de la Gare. </p>
                    <p>MANSOURAH, Messrs. Russi Frères. </p>
                    <p>ZAGAZIG, Mr. Ernest Camilleri.</p>
                    <p>DAMANHOOR, Mr. E. F. Mercier. </p>
                    <p>Loans on mortgage for long terms, repayable by annuities calculated to cover
                        the interest and sinking fund.</p>
                    <p>Loans on mortgage for short terms, repayable with or without sinking
                        fund.</p>
                    <p>Credits and accounts current opened against mortgages.</p>
                    <p>Purchase and sale of land and buildings with option to the buyer of freeing
                        himself by annual payments.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>NOTICE. </head>
                    <p>Under instructions from H. E. the Commander in Chief an Intelligence
                        Department has been opened in the Port Office under the direction of Major
                        General Sir F. Goldsmid.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p> NOTICE TO TRAVELLERS.– I the undersigned PIETRO PAULICEVICH, have the honour
                        to inform my patrons and the public generally, that I will open the Victoria
                        Hotel at Aley (Mount Lebanon) on the 1st of June 1882.</p>
                    <p>Those who may honour me with their patronage may depend on finding every
                        comfort provided. The services of the best medical man in Syria are
                        available. The hotel is situated on the highest part of the mountain and the
                        locality is specially recommended by the faculty as being the healthiest in
                        the Lebanon.</p>
                    <p>A diligence of the Ottoman Company of the Beyroot and Damascus Road, leaves
                        Beyroot every day (Sundays excepted) at 4 p.m. making the jonrney from
                        Beyroot to the door of the hotel in three hours, the fare being 4 francs for
                        each passenger.</p>
                    <p>The following is the tariff :– </p>
                    <p>For one person in one room 10 francs per day.</p>
                    <p>For two persons in one room 16 to 18 francs per day.</p>
                    <p>These prices include board, wine and lights.</p>
                    <p>Further information can be obtained from the undersigner at BEYROOT.</p>
                    <p>PIETRO PAULICEVICH, </p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR. 31782</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head> Law, Commercial, Banking or the Press. </head>
                    <p>AN ENGLISHMAN, aged 29, a VERBATIM SHORTHAND WRITER and experienced
                        COMMERCIAL CORRESPONDENT, writing &amp; good and rapid hand, is open to an
                        engagement in Alexandria … Cairo at a moderate salary. The Advertiser, who
                        is at present resident in Constantinople, is furnished with excellent
                        references and testimonials and will pay his own expenses from
                        Constantinople if a personal interview be asked for with a view to a
                        subsequent appointment. Address, in the first instance, “Steno" at the
                        office of this paper. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Khédivieh Mail Steamers.</head>
                    <p>ACCELERATED SERVICE BETWEEN </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA and CONSTANTINOPLE. </p>
                    <p>Viâ the PIRAEUS and SMYRNA in 4 1/2 days.</p>
                    <p>Direct Line for ATHENS in 2 days. </p>
                    <p>THE S.S. BEHERA, 1,500 Tons, will sail Wednesday next at 10 a.m. for
                        CONSTANTINOPLE, touching at the Piræus, SMYRNA, MYTELENE and
                        DARDANELLES.</p>
                    <p>Passengers may break the journey at any intermediate Ports. A discount of 10
                        % will be allowed to families of not less than three persons.</p>
                    <p>Return tickets are issued at a reduction of 10%. The reduction will be 15 %
                        on return tickets for families.</p>
                    <p>European Doctor and Stewardess on board each Steamer.</p>
                    <p>Apply for tickets to the agency at the Marina.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivieh Steamers in the RED SEA leave SUEZ every alternate Friday for
                        JEDDAH, SUAKIN, MASSOWAU, HODEIDAH, ADEN, TADJURA, ZEILA and BERBERA.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>R. GERARD </head>
                    <p>Civil Engineer, Architect &amp; Contractor.</p>
                    <p>Designs and Estimates for works of all kinds carefully prepared.</p>
                    <p>Contracts executed. </p>
                    <p>RUE DE LA POSTE FRANÇAISE. 12.10</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>AVIS </head>
                    <p>IL PARVIENT a la Commission Sanitaire Centrale le bruit qu'elle aurait trouvé
                        des germes de maladies dans les eaux de la ville.</p>
                    <p>La Commission déclare que ce bruit n'est pas fondé ; qu'il n'existe, en ce
                        moment à Alexandrie aucune maladie pourant être attribuée à la qualité des
                        eaux, et que la santé publique est bonne.</p>
                    <p>La Commission a dû s'occuper de cette question et elle prend, d'accord avec
                        M. le Directeur de la Cie. des Eaux, les mesures nécessaires pour les
                        maintenir dans cet état satisfaisant.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>AVIS </head>
                    <p>L'ETUDE de Me. Cesar LUNEL BEY sera ouverte à partir du ler Septembre
                        prochain, Maison de Madame Veuve Abet, rue Cléopatre derrière l'agence des
                        Messageries Maritimes au ler étage. </p>
                    <p>1725-15-1</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AVIS.</head>
                    <p>The Commercial Bank of Alexandria Ld. a l'honneur d'informer ses clients et
                        le public en général que ses bureaux sont réouverts dès aujourd'hui.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 17 août 1882. </p>
                    <p>6--2 1720 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE. </head>
                    <p>F. Mellor begs to inform her friends that she has re-opened her business
                        behind the German Church and hopes to receive a liberal share of their
                        patronage and support.</p>
                    <p>J. G. GERMAIN, </p>
                    <p>Manager.</p>
                    <p>16982 1721 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>To Let.– A furnished House on the Boulevard de Ramleh. For further
                        particulars apply to W. The Egyptian Gazette office.</p>
                    <p>3-2 1723</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Palloni's Café &amp; Restaurant</head>
                    <p>REOPENED. FRENCH AND ITALIAN CUISINE.</p>
                    <p>Service à la Carte. </p>
                    <p>EVERY attention will be paid to the manner in which the cuisine and catering
                        department will be conducted.</p>
                    <p>The beautiful situation of the diningrooms, which are situated at the baths
                        on the sea shore, behind the Offices of the Sanitary Council will prove an
                        attraction to the public.</p>
                    <p>L. PALLONI, </p>
                    <p>Proprietor. 3-1-1724</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RÉOUVERTURE du Café et du Restaurant Palloni</head>
                    <p>(Derrière le Bureau Sanitaire.) </p>
                    <p>CUISINE FRANÇAISE ET ITALIENNE,</p>
                    <p>Service a la Carte. </p>
                    <p>LE plus grand zèle sera déployé par le soussigné pour satisfaire ses clients
                        surtout dans le choix parfait des mets et dans le soin qui sera apporté à la
                        cuisine.</p>
                    <p>La situation délicieuse de ce Restaurant qui est placé entièrement sur la
                        mer, et par conséquent bien aéré invitera certainement l'honorable public à
                        y faire une visite.</p>
                    <p>L. PALLONI, </p>
                    <p>Propriétaire. 3-1-1723</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>S'ADRESSER ...</p>
                    <p>et annonces au bureau un journal, Rue Debbane, Maison Dahan, Alexandrie. </p>
                    <p>Le journal The Egyptian Gazette est en vente:</p>
                    <p>A ALEXANDRIE. </p>
                    <p>Au bureau du journal,</p>
                    <p>AU CAIRE. </p>
                    <p>Chez Messrs. FRATELLI PENASSON, </p>
                    <p>Chez Messrs. DRACATOS &amp; Cie., L'Esbékieh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <p>FRIDAY, AUGUST 18, 1882.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL NOTES. </head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sir Garnet Wolseley, accompanied by his staff, made a minute inspection
                            yesterday of the positions at Ramleh. The Commander-in-Chief is staying
                            on board H. M. S. Salamis.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lieutenant General Sir Edward Hamley K.C.M.G., C.B., R.A., has taken over
                            command of the 2nd. Division.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>H. M. S. Euphrates arrived yesterday as well as the chartered transports
                            Pelican, Nevada, Capella and Egyptian Monarch.</p>
                        <p>The chartered transports Marathon and Empusa arrived this morning.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The S.S. Capella had on board H. S. H. the Duke of Teck and the Staff of
                            Sir Garnet Wolseley, the total number being 37 officers, 80 men and 57
                            horses. The principal officer was Col. Goodenough R.A.; and Col.
                            Schreider, Major Alleyne R.A., and Captain Maurice, R.A., were amongst
                            the number.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A considerable movement of troops has taken place to-day and considerable
                            activity prevails in the harbour. Various guesses are being made by the
                            public as to the object of these movements and every person has the
                            satisfaction of believing that he has been specially favoured and that
                            he alone knows the precise intentions of the Comnander-in-Chief. Some of
                            the guesses that have been made will probably turn out correct, although
                            we do not suppose <cb n="2"/> the military authorities have disclosed
                            their intentions.</p>
                        <p>However we may say that important events are now imminent and Araby and
                            his fellow rebels will soon have cause to rue the day when they defied
                            the power of the British Empire.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The troops being embarked to-day consist of the 1st Division and the 60th
                            Rifles from the 2nd. Division.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The total strength of the army of Egypt sent from England, exclusive of
                            seamen and Marines, is 15,239 officers and men. For this force 5,741
                            horses have been shipped from England, and others, together with mules,
                            will be forwarded to Egypt from abroad. To comply with the requisitions
                            of the War Office, 43 transports have been chartered to convey 740
                            officers, 54 warrant officers, 14,445 non-commissioned officers and men,
                            and 5,741 horses. The Cavalry numbers 15 squadrons, the Artillery 8
                            batteries, the Infantry 10 batteries, the Royal Engineers 4 companies, 1
                            pontoon train, 1 telegraph troop, 1 field park, the Commissariat and
                            Transport 10 Companies, bearer companies 4 and field hospitals 10,
                            besides general, divisional, brigade and regimental staffs. In the
                            course of next week every man should have landed in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Her Majesty's Government has chartered not less than 34,000 tons of the
                            steamers belonging to the British India Steam Navigation Company.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Commandant of the Damietta garrison, the notorious Abdel Al Pasha,
                            has written to the Assistant Governor of Port Said requesting him to
                            send him the latest European papers, in order that he may know the
                            opinion of the Press on recent events in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>As we are aware that Abdel Al receives The Egyptian Gazette regularly, we
                            will summarise the opinion of the European Press for him.</p>
                        <p>Araby, Mahmoud Samy, Toulbé, Abdel Al and Company are looked upon as a
                            gang of thieves and assassins devoid of all sense of honour or shame.
                            They do not deserve the honoured name of soldier for, under cover of a
                            flag of truce, they pillaged and burnt Alexandria and committed other
                            crimes which we will not sully our pages by detailing.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>We hear from Port Said that the submarine telegraph is working regularly.
                            All telegrams have to be taken on board the telegraph ship which lies
                            outside the western jetty. </p>
                        <p>Messrs. Bazin intend establishing a service for sending messages on board
                            at the cost of one shilling per message.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Being desirous of ensuring a supply of fresh water at Suez, the British
                            authorities arranged for the dry dock to be filled. It appears that the
                            necessary precautions had not been taken and the residents at the
                            Terre-Plein ran short of water.</p>
                        <p>The dry dock has since been taken possession of by British troops.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The newly appointed Assistant Governor of Ismailia, Aly Effendi Zulficar,
                            has prevented provisions from being supplied to British men-of war.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>We learn from El Akhram (Les Pyramidss) that news has been received from
                            Cairo announcing that Toulbé Pasha was severely wounded on the 5th
                            instant and that Lieut. Colonel Ahmed Iffat was killed in the same
                            engagement.</p>
                        <p>According to our confrère, the following is the proposed composition of
                            the forthcoming Cabinet :</p>
                        <p>Cherif Pasha, President and Minister of Foreign Affairs.</p>
                        <p>Riaz Pasha, Minister of Interior,</p>
                        <p>Omar Pasha Loutfy, Minister of War and Marine.</p>
                        <p>Ismail Eyoub Pasha, Minister of Justice. </p>
                        <p>Haidar Pasha, Minister of Finance. </p>
                        <p>Sabet Pasha, Minister of Public Instruction.</p>
                        <cb n="3"/>
                        <p>Talaki Pasha, Minister of Wakfs.</p>
                        <p>Aly Pasha Moubarek, Minister of Public Works.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>Reuter's Telegrams.</head>
                    <p>By arrangement with Mr. J. Sehnitzler, General Agent for Egypt of Reuter's
                        Telegram Company Limited, the sole right to republish the telegrams issued
                        by him to his subscribers is acquired by the Proprietor of The Egyptian
                        Gazette. Any other newspaper republishing these telegrams will be proceeded
                        against.</p>
                    <div type="cable">
                        <dateline>LONDON, 18th August. </dateline>
                        <p>The rumour that Holy War had been proclaimed in Morocco is unfounded.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                        <dateline>MARSEILLES, 18th August. </dateline>
                        <p>H. E. Riaz Pasha has left for Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Havas Telegrams.</head>
                    <div type="cable">
                        <dateline>LONDON, 17th August. </dateline>
                        <p>The Bank rate has been raised to 4%.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                        <dateline>LONDON, 18th August. </dateline>
                        <p>The House of Commons has adjourned till the 24th August. (?)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ. </head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT.) </byline>
                    <p>(Delayed in transmission.)</p>
                    <p>SUEZ, 1st August. </p>
                    <p>Some inquietude is felt to-day by the two or three Europeans still left in
                        this almost deserted town of Suez. Cut off from free communication with the
                        outer world, the Bazaar is now our chief source of information and rumours
                        of the most extraordinary description seem to increase inverse ratio with
                        the supply of our comestibles, which is daily becoming more meagre and
                        costly. For every fresh egg we have a score of <hi rend="italic">on
                        dit</hi>, as though the very hens had taken to politics to the neglect of
                        their domestic duties; whilst the goats of Suez, that supply our milk appear
                        to have gone over en masse to the "national party" scarcely one responding
                        to the matudinal call of my almost distracted soufragee. These rumours have
                        had but little apparent effect as yet on the remaining native population,
                        whose occupations being gone, spend their days in sleep and their nights in
                        gossips according to the good old custom during the month of Ramadan. Some
                        little stir was however caused yesterday by an interchange of messages which
                        took place between the British Admiral, Wiliam Rewett, K.C.B; V.C., and our
                        Governor, his Excelleney Hussein Pasha Soury, as the naval officers landed
                        and passed to and fro through the town. The object of these visits was to
                        obtain an assurance from the Governor that he would receive the Commander
                        in-chief, and return this visit officially, with a view to ulterior
                        arrangements. Unfortunately the Khediye's authority does not as yet extend
                        much beyond the walls of Alexandria. … proclamanations have not been
                        communicated to the district Governors, who continue to receive their
                        instructions from the rebel chief as member of the Ministry and from the
                        “Mallieh" at Cairo. Even our telegraphic communication with Alexandria
                        passes through Cairo and is controlled by Araby and his myrmidions. The
                        position of our Governor is therefore one of great difficulty and it is not
                        surprising that no definite result was obtained from yesterday's
                        negotiations when the last deputation returned on board at 10 p.m. Two hours
                        later a special train arrived with a peremptory summons to his Excellency to
                        present himself at Cairo. Shortly after his departure a report spread like
                        wild fire through the town that Araby Pasha had telegraphed his desire that
                        all true believers should quit Suez "as the English were about to bombard."
                        In consequence of this and of an idea that the sweet-water Canal would be
                        cut, the greatest agitation prevailed and to-day the excitement has
                        increased to be panic. The people are flocking from all directions to the
                        Railway station only too glad to obtain standing room on the trains which,
                        since 5 o'clock this morning have been running between this place and Faïde,
                        crowded with native refugees-men, women and children, who are deserting
                        their homes to seek safety, from they know not what in the interior.</p>
                    <p>2nd August.– The sun rose this morning on a scene of desolation with the
                        ruined character of the place greatly inhanched. The trains have been
                        running continuously and what is still left of the population is congregated
                        at the Railway station and its neighbourhood awaiting the opportunity to get
                        away; whilst the streets and Bazaars are almost deserted. Last night the
                        Mosques were not illuminated and there was no call to prayers from the <hi
                            rend="italic">madnehs</hi>. The train which was expected at 10 p.m. did
                        not come in until 1 o'clock this morning.</p>
                    <p>It was melancholy to see the throngs of poor people, entire families, waiting
                        patiently during the long hours, watching over their goods and chattles. The
                        cackling of fowl and the bleating of goats were heard in all direction and
                        it was difficult to move about without stumbling over objects both animate
                        and inanimate amid the heterogeneous mass which strewed the station and
                        environs. It these people expected to find room in the train for their
                        miscellaneous household goods, they were destined to disappointment. Owing
                        to the immense concourse of people on the platform, the train did not come
                        into the station, but stopped some two hundred yards up the line. Where it
                        became known that the <cb n="4"/>train was in a general rush ensued, and the
                        race was to the strongest. "Diel tak the hindmosti" was the cry and in a
                        moment there was a general stampede down the line in which human beings,
                        cocks, hens, goats and water-melons seemed inspired with the common impulse
                        of sauve qui peut. The latter were ralling about under our feet as though
                        imbued with the power of perpetual motion, whilst the goats, having regained
                        their freedom were to be seen in the moonlight careering widly back to theer
                        old haunts among the gum-bags. Three more trains have since left and I fancy
                        the town will be pretty well cleared of inhabitants before sunset to-day.
                        The last to leave will be the Deputy Governor Rachid Bey and the soldiers. I
                        believe the former has no desire to leave, but he has no choice. The latter
                        openly express their intentions of breaking open the provision stores before
                        starting, and as it is unlikely their depre.ations will be confined to this
                        limit, I, in common with others, have decided not to wait until the last,
                        but to slip down to the docks before it is too late and leave our property
                        and the town to their fate, which seems now to be sealed.</p>
                    <p>Among the first to fly from imaginary danger were the employés of the
                        Custom-house, who had earned for themselves the reputation in the town of
                        being among the foremost of Araby's partisans. They were, they averred,
                        prepared to defend the town against all christian invaders, and in token of
                        their zeal went through a course of instruction "in the noble art of war"
                        under the native commandant. The crews of the six Khedivial steamers have
                        just deserted en masse to "join Araby," not even a watch being left on
                        board; the English engineers remaining alone, in charge of the ships. Other
                        government departments have suffered equally from the scare.</p>
                    <p>8th Aug.– Half an hour after writing the above I noticed from my balcony a
                        great commotion among the soldiers at the neighbouring caricole and looking
                        round to discover the cause saw the whole lenghth of the Suez Creek studded
                        with man of war's boats in tow of steam launches approaching the town, the
                        men's arms flashing in the bright sunshine. In a very short time landing was
                        effected by Flag Captain Hastings of H. M. S. Euryalux opposite the P. &amp;
                        O. Company's offices. The advance party marched straight for the Railway
                        Station and the "Gouvernorat" was speedily surrounded.</p>
                    <p>Meantime another party were landing on the beech and before 1 p.m. the town
                        was quitly occupied by the Naval Brigade; the native garrison having fled at
                        our approach. The main camp is now established at the Victoria Hospital
                        under command of the Flag Captain. A strong position is held by Commander
                        Hulton of H.M.S. Dragon on the hill. The town of Suez is guarded by the
                        marines of the Fleet under Captain Baldwin R.M.L of the Euryalue; pickets
                        being stationed at various points in the tow to preserve order. On the
                        landing of the Naval Brigade, Brigadier General O. V. Tanner C.B. was
                        appointed "Commandant of Suez" by the Commander-in-Chief; the services of
                        Mr. A. K. Tuson, Assistant Paymaster of H. M. S. Mosquito being placed at
                        his disposal to assist in organising his department. The 72 (Seaforth)
                        Highlanders are expected to arrive tomorrow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</p>
                    <p>VENDREDI, 18 AOUT 1882</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>Dépêches Télégraphiques.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>(AGENCE REUTER.)</p>
                        <p>Par une convention passée entre le propriétaire de l'Egyptien Gazette et
                            M. G. Schnitzler, agent générale en Egypte de la Cie Reuter, le seul
                            droit de republier les dépêches données par lui a ses abonnés est acquis
                            par le propriétaire de l'Egyptian Gazette. Tout autre journal
                            reproduisant le dépêches sera poursuivi conformément à la loi.</p>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>LONDRES, 18 août. </dateline>
                            <p>Le bruit que la guerre sainte a été proclamée au Maroc est dénué de
                                fondement.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>MARSEILLE, 18 août. </dateline>
                            <p>S. E. Riaz pacha s'est embarqué pour Alexandrie.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>(AGENCE HAVAS.)</p>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>LONDRES, 17 août .</dateline>
                            <p>La Banque d'Angleterre a élevé son escompte à 4 pour cent.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>MARSEILLE, 17 août (soir), </dateline>
                            <p>Riaz pacha s'est embarqué pour l'Egypte, sur l'Ebre des Messageries
                                Maritimes.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>LONDRES, 18 août. </dateline>
                            <p>Le Chambre des communes s'est ajournée au 24 août.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le Gouvernement de S. M. B. a affrété à la Compagnie de Navigation
                            British India un nombre de navires dont le tonnage réuni s'élève à
                            34,000 tonnes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sir Garnet Wolseley accompagné de son Etat-Major a fait hier une
                            inspection minu. tieuse des lignes de Ramleh. Le Général en Chef réside
                            à bord du Salamis de la M. R. B.</p>
                    </div>
                    <pb n="3"/>

                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le forces de l'armée Britannique envoyées en Egypte, non compris les
                            marins et les soldats d'infanterie de marine, sont de 15,239 hommus,
                            officiers et soldats</p>
                        <p>Pour ces troupes on a expédié d'Angle terrecht chevaux ; il doit en être
                            expé. die de l'étranger d'autres encore avec des mulers.</p>
                        <p>D'après les ordres du ministère de la vuerre ou a dû affréter 43 bateaux
                            transports où se sont embarqués 740 officiers, 54 officiers superieurs,
                            14,445 hommes de trou. pe et 5,7 +1 chevaus. La cavalerie se compose de
                            15 escadrons, l'artillerie de 8 batteries, l'infanterie de 10
                            bataillons, les Roral Engineers de 4 compagnies ; on compte 1
                            train-ponton, 1 compagnie té. légraphiste ; le commissariat et le
                            nouvement furment 10 compagnies ; il y a 4 compagnies de braucardiers,
                            et 10 ambulances.</p>
                        <p>Il y a en outre les Etats- Majors, général, divisionnaire et
                            régimentaire.</p>
                        <p>Dans le courant de la prochaine semaine l'armée d'expédition d'Egypte
                            doit être entièrement débarquée.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Les troupes embarquées aujourd'hui comprennent la lre Division et le 60me
                            des Tirailleurs de la 2de Division.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le Lieutenant Sir Edward Hamley a pris le commandement de la 2me
                            Division.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>L'Euphrate de la M. R. B. est arrivé hier ainsi que les transports le
                            Pelican, le Nerada, le Capella et l’Egyptian Monarch.</p>
                        <p>Les transports Marathon et Empusa sont arrivés ce matin.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le vapeur Capella avait à son bord le due de Teck et l'état-major de Sir
                            Garnet Wolseley se composant de 37 officiers avec 7 soldats et 57
                            chevaux.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>D'importants mouvements de troupes ont eu lieu aujourd'hui et une grande
                            aetivité règne dans le port. Le public s'ingénie à deviner l'objet de
                            ces mouvements, et chacun à la fatuité de croire qu'il est spécialement
                            renseigé, et que lui seul connaît les intentions précises du général en
                            chef.</p>
                        <p>Il peut se faire que quelques uns des paris qui ont été tenus soient
                            réalisés, bien qu'il soit inadmissible de supposer que les autorites
                            militaires sent fra denne ture sans véritables intentions. Orque nous
                            pouvons dire c'est que de grand évènements sont imminents et qu'Araby et
                            sa bande, auront bientôt sujet de reguiter d'avoir osé défier la
                            puissance de l'Empire Britannique.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Les funerailles de M. Henry Gaillard, supérieur des Zazaristes à
                            Alexandrie aumont lieu main samedi à 8 heures du matin, Hôpital
                            Européen.</p>
                        <p>Les personnes qui n'auraient pas reçu de lettrbs de faire part sont
                            priées de considérer le présent avis comme une invitation</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le colonel Chaillé Long bey qui, à l'heute du anger, s'était offert
                            généreusernent pour grer le consulat des Etats-Unis, vient de donner sa
                            démission aujourd'hui qu'il n'y a Slus de services à rendre et que tout
                            dange a disparu.</p>
                        <p>Le Gouvernement Egyptien ne laissera certainement pas échapper l'occasion
                            d'utiliser les services du colonel lors de l'organisation du) Soudan,
                            contrées que M. Chaillé Long a longtemps parcourues et qui, en grande
                            partie, ont été réunies par lui à la couronne khédiviale.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Nous lisons dans El Akhram (Les Pyramides) que l'on a reçu des nouvelles
                            du Caire d'après lesquelles Toulbé pacha a été grièvement blessé dans la
                            journée du 5 courant et le lieutenant-colonel Ahmet Iffat a été tué dans
                            le même engagement.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>D'après notre confrère voici quelle serait combinaison projetée pour le
                            futur cabinet:</p>
                        <p>Cherif pacha, président et ministre des affaires étrangères;</p>
                        <p>Riaz pacha, ministre de l'intérieur ;</p>
                        <p>Omar pacha Loutfy, ministre de la guerre et de la marine;</p>
                        <p>Haidar pacha, ministre des finances;</p>
                        <p>Sabet pacha, ministre de l'instruction publique;</p>
                        <cb n="2"/>
                        <p>Talaki pacha, ministre des Wakfs;</p>
                        <p>Aly pacha Moubarek, ministre des travaux publics.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Les anglais voulant assurer à Suez la provision d'eau douce, ont fait
                            remplir le bassin de radonb, d'accord avec le directeur de l'usine. I
                            paraît que les précautions nécessaires à ce travail n'ayant pas été
                            prises, les employés du Terre-Plein ont manqué d'eau.</p>
                        <p>Les Anglais ont depuis occupé militaire ment l'usine.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le nouvean sous-gouverneur d'Ismailia Aly effendi Zulfikar a empêché le
                            passage des provisions de bouche destinées aux frégates anglaises.</p>
                        <p>La situation se tend de plus en plus.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le télégraphe fonetionne à Port-Said depuis quelques jours. Chaque
                            dépêche doit être portée à bord du bateau qui se trouve en dehors de la
                            jetée-ouest.</p>
                        <p>La maison Bazin a l'intention de créer un service pour envoyer des
                            dépêches à bord moyennant un schelling par dépêche.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>MM. Rousseau bey, Adrien bey et d'autres personnes encore vont arriver de
                            PortSaid par le bateau autrichien.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. Talmo, magasinier du Mont-de-Piété du Caire est arrivé à Port-Said.
                            Après bien des difficultés et des démarches incessantes auprès de Yacoub
                            pacha, il a pu obtenir un train spécial jusqu'à Ismailia emportant pour
                            un million environ d'objets de valeur de toutes sortes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Un train spécial est parti du Caire le 14 août emmenant 250 personnes
                            environ, sujets grecs et italiens.</p>
                        <p>Un Français se trouvait dans ce train, M. Boisson, da Ministère des
                            Travaux Publics.</p>
                        <p>Ce n'est qu'après huit jours de demandes et de prières continuelles que
                            l'autorisation de quitter le Caire leur a été accordée par Arabi.</p>
                        <p>Les trains locaux ne prennent plus de voyageurs.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Le commandant en chef des troupes del Damiette, le général Abdel Al
                            pacha, a écrit au commandant Aboul Ata, sous-gouverneur de Port-Said,
                            lui demandant de lui envoyer des journaux européens pour connaître
                            l'opinion de la presse au sujet des événements d'Egypte.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sachant qu'Abdel Al reçoit et lit régulièrement l’Egyptian Gazette, nous
                            en profiterons pour lui résumer l'opinion de la presse européenne et lui
                            dire qu'Arabi, Mahmoud Sami, Abdel Al, Toulbé, Aly Fehmy et les autres
                            ne sont considérés que comme des voleurs et des assassins, incapables
                            d'aucun sentiment d'honneur et de pudeur. Ils sont indignes du titre de
                            soldat attendu que sous l'abri du drapeau parlementaire ils ont pillé et
                            incendié la ville d'Alexandrie et commis d'autres crimes tellement
                            horribles que notre plume se refuse à les retracer.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Ce matin à cinq heures et demie est mort à l'hôpital Européen le
                        Très-Reverend Père GAILLARD, Supérieur de la Mission et du Collège des
                        Lazaristes de notre ville.</p>
                    <p>M. HENRY GAILLARD s'était rendu à l'hôpital Européen le 10 juillet et il a
                        traversé les funestes journées des 11, 12 et 13 avec une heroïque
                        résignation, un calme admirable. Hélas, il devait payer de sa vie les
                        terribles émotions qu'il a éprouvées et qu'il cachait si bien aux autres
                        qu'on a pu presque le croire indifférent.</p>
                    <p>Le convoi et le service funèbre auront lieu demain matin à huit heures : on
                        se réunira à l'hôpital Européen.</p>
                    <p>Tous les Français, tous les Européens résidant à Alexandrie ne voudront pas
                        laisser aller à sa dernière demeure ce héros modeste, martyr de son
                        devonement, sans lui rendre un dernier devoir.</p>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <p>M. HENRY GATLLARD n'était âgé que de 37 ans.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTRE DE SUEZ. </head>
                    <byline>(DE NOTRE CORRESPONDANT SPÉCIAL.)</byline>
                    <p>Malgré le retard subi par cette lettre, nos lecteurs, nous l'espérons, n'en
                        liront pas moins le contenu avec intérêt.</p>
                    <p>SUEZ, I Aout. </p>
                    <p>Aujourd'hui une certaine inquiétude s'est répandue parmi les quelques
                        Européens qui se trou. vent encore dans la ville de Suez. Toute
                        communication avec le reste de l'Egypte étant coupée, notre unique ressource
                        est le Bazar et c'est là que nous courons aux informations et de là que par.
                        tent les nouvelles les plus extraordinaires, qui chaque jour augmentent,
                        tandis que les vivres diminuent chaque jour et deviennent plus cher.</p>
                    <p>Pour un oeuf on est obligé de se liver à des discussions infinies, comme si
                        les poules elles-mêmes s'étaient adonnées à la politique au détriment de 1
                        leurs devoirs domestiques.</p>
                    <p>Il en est de même pour les chèvres de Suez qui nous fournissent le lait;
                        elles semblent avoir pas. sé en masse au "parti national." A peine en
                        restet-il une qui réponde à l'appel matinal de mon bar. barin qui parait
                        être devenu fou.</p>
                    <p>Ces rumeurs jusqu'à présent n'ont selon toute apparence produit aucun effet
                        sur les indigènes restés à Suez. Ayant perdu leurs travaux, ils passent la
                        journée à dormir et la nuit à jouer suivant l'antique usage pendant le mois
                        de Ramadan.</p>
                    <p>Toutefois hier il est survenu un peu d'agitation causée par un échange de
                        messages entre l'amiral anglais, Sir W. Hewett K.C.B., et notre gouverneur,
                        S. E. Hussein pacha Soury, au moment où les officiers debarquaient et
                        traversaient en tous sens la ville. L'objet de lenr visite était d'obtenir
                        l'assurance que le gouvernenr recevrait le commandant en chef et lui
                        rendrait la visite officielle. ment, dans le but d'arriver ensuite à des
                        arrangements. Malhewreusernent l'autorité du Khedive ne s'étend pour le
                        moment pas bien au-delà des murs d'Alexandrie. Les proclamations de Son
                        Altesse n'ont pas été communiquées aux gourer neurs des districts et ceux-ci
                        continuent à rece. voir leurs instructions du rebelle Arabi, comme membre du
                        ministère et de la Mallieh au Caire. Notre ligne télégraphique avec
                        Alexandrie passe par le Caire et les messages sont contrôlés par Arabi et
                        ses "mirmidons." La situation de notre gouverneur est par conséquent
                        excessivement dif. ficile, et on ne doit pas être surpris qu'aucun résultat
                        définitif n'ait pu être obtenu dans les négociations d'hier. La dernière
                        députation est revenue à bord à 10 heures du soir. Deux heures après, un
                        brain spécial arrivait avec ordre péremptoire pour S. E. d'avoir à se
                        présenter au Caire. </p>
                    <p>Peu après son départ, le bruit se répandait en …. ….. avait exprimé
                        télégraphiquement le désir que chaque croyant quittât la ville de Suez, car
                        les Anglais allaient la bombarder. A cette nouvelle et surtout à l'idée que
                        l'eau douce allait être coupée, une grande agitation éclata, qui
                        aujourd'hui, est devenue une paniqne réelle. La foule accourt de tous côtés
                        dans la direction de la gare du chemin de fer, avec l'espérance de pouvoir
                        trouver un wagon de inarchandise et s'y blottir. Depuis cinq heures du matin
                        en se presse dans les rues et sur les places, celle dite Taide est remplie
                        de réfugiés indigènes, hommes, femmes, enfants qui, dans la crainte de ce
                        qui va arriver, abandonnent leurs habitations pour se sauver à l'in
                        térieur.</p>
                    <p>2 août.– Le soleil s'est levé ce matin sur une scène de désolation que
                        l'aspect ruiné de la place rendait encore plus navrante. Les trains ont été
                        toute la nuit en mouvement et ce qui reste de la population est entassé à la
                        gare ou dans les envi. rons dans l'attente d'une occasion favorable pour
                        partir; les rues et les bazars sont presque entièrement déserts. La nuit
                        dernière les mosquées n'ont pas été illuminées et les dervisches n'ont pas
                        apelé les croyants à la priere.</p>
                    <p>Le train qu'on attendait à 10 heures du soir n'est arrivé qu'à 1 heure du
                        matin. Il était triste de voir cette quantité de pauvres gens, de familles
                        entières qui attendaient là, de longues heures, faisant la garde de leurs
                        haillons et des quelques vivres qu'ils avaient avec eux. Les cris des
                        enfants mariés aux bélements des chèvres s'entendaient dans toutes les
                        directions. Il était bien difficile de se mouvoir au millen de ce monde,
                        sans tomber sur des objets animés et inanimés répandus entre les tables, les
                        chaises et mille autres objets qui obstruaient entièrement le pas. sage. Si
                        tous ces gens-là ont cru trouver de la place dans le train pour leurs
                        marcbandises de toutes sortes, ils ont dû être bien désappointés.</p>
                    <p>En raison de la foule énorme agglomérée sur la plate-forme, le train n'est
                        pas entré en gare, mais s'est arrêté à 200 mètres sur la voie. Lorsque I'on
                        sut que le train était arrivé, ce fut un péle. mèle indiscriptible, une
                        course précipitée. "Dil tak te bindmost!" Tel était le cri que chacun
                        poussait. En un instant, une longue colonne s'é branla sur la voie ferrée,
                        colonne formés d'hommes, portant des melons, des poules, de coqs, de
                        chèvres, en un mot on royait que le sentiment général était celui d'un
                        véritable sauve qui peut.</p>
                    <p>On aurait dit par moment que les melons eux aussi étaient animés ils
                        roulaient à terre et étaient en mouvement perpétuel, tandis que la liberté
                            <cb n="4"/> étant rendue aux chèvres, on les voyait au clair de la lune
                        sauter et s'en retourner à leurs vielles étables an milieu des sacs de gomme
                        abandonnés.</p>
                    <p>Depuis ce moment trois trains sont partis, et je crois que la ville sera bien
                        dégarnie de ses habitants avant le coucher du soleil. Les derniers à la
                        quitter seront le gouverneur-député Rachid bey et les troupes. Je crois que
                        le premier n'a pas envie de s'en aller, mais il n'a pas le choix. Les autres
                        expriment ouvertement leur intention de pil. ler les magasins avant de
                        partir. Quelques Européens et moi, nous avons décidé de ne pas attendre ce
                        moment et de nous acheminer vers les docks avant qu'il ne soit trop tard,
                        nous résignant à abandonner nos propriétés et la ville à leur sort, qui
                        paraît maintenant être décidé.</p>
                    <p>Les premiers à fuir un danger imaginaire ont 6té les employés de la douane;
                        ils s'étaient attirés dans la ville la triste répntation d'être des
                        partisans d'Arabi. Ils parlaient d'etre prêts à défendre la ville contre
                        tout envahisseur chrétien, et pour prouver leur zèle ils donnaient an penple
                        des leçons sur l'art ri noble de la guerre.</p>
                    <p>Les équipages des six bateanx de la compagnie Khedivieh ont déserté en masse
                        pour rejoindre Arabi, et pas une sentinelle ne fut laissée à bord ; les
                        mécaniciens anglais restent seuls à bord de ces bâtiments. Les bureaux du
                        gouvernement ont aussi souffert de cette désertion générale.</p>
                    <p>8 août.– Une demi-heure apres avoir écrit ce qui précède j'ai remarqué de mon
                        balcon une gran. de animation parmi les soldats dans les caracols voisins,
                        et en regardant à droite et à gauche pour en découvrir la cause j'ai aperçu
                        des soldats tout le long de la plage et je vis la mer couverte de ca. nots
                        et de chaloupes à vapeur qui s'approchaient de la ville, chargés de soldats
                        dont les armes étiu. celaient au soleil.- En peu de temps le débarque. ment
                        fut effectué sous les ordres du capitaine Hastings du Euryalus de la M. R.
                        B. et les troue pes se placerent devant les bureaux de la Comp. Peninsulaire
                        &amp; Orientale.</p>
                    <p>L'avant-garde des troupes mareha droit sur la gare du chemin de fer, pris le
                        gouvernorat fut vite cerné. En même temps une autre partie de soldats
                        débarquait, et, avant une heure de l'après-inidi In ville était eomplètement
                        occupée par la brigade navale; la garnison indigène avait fait à l'approche
                        des Anglais. Le quartier-général est main. tenant établi à l'hôpital
                        Victoria sous le comman. dement du capitaine Hastings. Le commandant Hulton
                        occupe une forte position sur la colline. La ville est gardée par les marins
                        de la flotte commandés par le capitaine Baldwin du bateau Eryalus de la M.
                        R. B. Des piquets sont placés sur plusienrs points de la ville pour
                        maintenir l'ordre. Au débarquement de la brigade navale le briga.
                        dier-général 0. V. Tanner fut nommé commandant de Suez; on mit à sa
                        dispositiun M. Tuson, payeur à bord du Mosquito; ce fonctionnaire l'us.
                        sistera dans l'organisation de son bureau.</p>
                    <p>Le 72me des Highlander est attendu demain.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN SAITAIRE</head>
                    <p>D'ALEXANDRIE.</p>
                    <p>Du 17 Août 1882. </p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="15" cols="2">
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">
                                    <p>Mortalité générale.</p>
                                </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Hommes </cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Femmes </cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Garçons </cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Filles</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>
                                    <p>Total </p>
                                </cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">
                                    <p>Causes de décès. </p>
                                </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Maladies ordinaires</cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">
                                    <p>Naissances (indigènes). </p>
                                </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Garçons</cell>
                                <cell>4</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Filles</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Total</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">OBSERVATIONS</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Indigènes </cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Européens.</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Total</cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <dateline>Alexandrie, le 17 Août 1882.</dateline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DÉPARTS DES MALLES POUR L'ÉTRANGER</head>
                    <p>Du 14 au 20 Août 1882.</p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="15" cols="7">
                            <row>
                                <cell rows="2">
                                    <p>PAQUEBOTS.</p>
                                </cell>
                                <cell rows="2">VOIES. </cell>
                                <cell rows="2">JOURS.</cell>
                                <cell cols="2">OBJETS</cell>
                                <cell cols="2">MANDATS.</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Ordin. </cell>
                                <cell>Recom.</cell>
                                <cell>Jours.</cell>
                                <cell>Heures.</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>heures</cell>
                                <cell>heures</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Autrichien </cell>
                                <cell>Corfou </cell>
                                <cell>Mardi </cell>
                                <cell>3 soir </cell>
                                <cell>2½ soir</cell>
                                <cell>Mardi</cell>
                                <cell>Midi</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Autrichien </cell>
                                <cell>Leros </cell>
                                <cell>Mardi</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Messageries </cell>
                                <cell>Naples </cell>
                                <cell>Mardi </cell>
                                <cell>8 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>7½ mat. </cell>
                                <cell>Lundi </cell>
                                <cell>6 soir</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Anglais </cell>
                                <cell>Chypre</cell>
                                <cell>Jeudi</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Anglais </cell>
                                <cell>Beyrout </cell>
                                <cell>Jeudi</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Autrichien </cell>
                                <cell>P.-Said </cell>
                                <cell>Vendr. </cell>
                                <cell>10 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>9½ mat.</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Russe </cell>
                                <cell>Smyrne </cell>
                                <cell>Vendr.</cell>
                                <cell>11 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>10½ mat.</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Russe </cell>
                                <cell>Syra </cell>
                                <cell>Vendr.</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Italien </cell>
                                <cell>Catane </cell>
                                <cell>Samedi </cell>
                                <cell>8 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>7½ mat.</cell>
                                <cell>Vendr.</cell>
                                <cell>6 soir</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Khédivié </cell>
                                <cell>Pyrée </cell>
                                <cell>Merc. </cell>
                                <cell>9 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>8½ mat.</cell>
                                <cell>Mardi</cell>
                                <cell>6 soir</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Messageries </cell>
                                <cell>P.-Said </cell>
                                <cell>Samedi</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fraissinet </cell>
                                <cell>Malte </cell>
                                <cell>Diman.</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>
                                    <p>Russe </p>
                                </cell>
                                <cell>P. Said </cell>
                                <cell>Diman </cell>
                                <cell>11 mat. </cell>
                                <cell>10½ mat.</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" status="verified">
                <cols n="2"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>SOCIÉTÉ GÉNÉRALE DES TRAVAUX EN EGYPTE.</head>
                    <p>(THE PUBLIC WORKS COMPANY OF EGYPT.) </p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE :-MAISON ZOGHEB, ABDIN STREET-CAIRO. </p>
                    <p>THE COMPANY is prepared to undertake, on account of third parties, the
                        cleansing, digging and maintenance of Canals, the Construction of Houses,
                        Factories, Bridges, Dikes, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>AND, GENERALLY SPEAKING, ALL PUBLIC AND PRIVATE WORKS. </p>
                    <p>Work can be paid for, as may be agreed either in cash, or by payments spread
                        over a term of years.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN MINERAL OIL OLÉONAPHT.</head>
                    <p> V. I. RAGOSINE &amp; Co. of PARIS and MOSCOW.</p>
                    <p>CAPITAL 14,000,000 FRANCS. </p>
                    <p>OLEONOPHAT is a pure MINERAL OIL with a greater degree of glutinousness than
                        animal or vegetable oils. It gives more economical and regular greasing
                        while the machines and their different parts are kept in a perfect condition
                        without wear and tear. </p>
                    <p>OLEONAPHT is not inflammable and bears a temperature of 322 degress with
                        perfect safety. </p>
                    <p>OLEONAPHT does not cause any swarf, does not dry and is free from smell.</p>
                    <p>Further, besides two gold medals obtained at Paris in 1878 &amp; 1879, the
                        use of Ragosine's Oleonapht is ordered in board all steamers of the French
                        Government. </p>
                    <p>The undersigned receives orders, and will give any further information
                        required. </p>
                    <p>ALCIDE BLETON, PLACE DES CONSULS-ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>GENERAL AGENT FOR EGYPT.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE CITY OF LONDON</head>
                    <p>FIRE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>CAPITAL: £2,000,000. RESERVE FUND: £50,000.</p>
                    <p>CLAIMS PROMPTLY &amp; LIBERALLY SETTLED. </p>
                    <p>ALDERMAN HENRY E. KNIGHT, CHAIRMAN. LIGHTLY SIMPSON Esq., DEPUTY
                        CHAIRMAN.</p>
                    <p>L. C. PHILLIPS, GENERAL MANAGER. </p>
                    <p>CHIEF OFFICE:-101, CHEAPSIDE, LONDON. </p>
                    <p>Agents : - Messrs. BARR GETTY &amp; Co., ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>NORTHERN FIRE AND LIFE ASSURANCE COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>BRITISH AND FOREIGN MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>The undersigned are authorized to issue policies on behalf of the above
                        Companies at moderate rates.</p>
                    <p>DIXON BROTHERS &amp; Co., Agents.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED,</head>
                    <p>20, OLD BROAD STREET, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>(Established 1836.) </p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIBED CAPITAL £1,000,000.– RESERVE FUND £370.000. </p>
                    <p>The undersigned are authorized to issue policies from SUEZ and RED SEA PORTS. </p>
                    <p>Agents at JEDDAH and SUAKIM, Messi'S. WYLDE BEYTS &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>At Suez and Massowah, apply to</p>
                    <p>G. BEYTS &amp; Co., Agents.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE Egyptian Gazette Printing Office</head>
                    <p>A. V. PHILIP, Proprietor.</p>
                    <p>Letter &amp; Note Headings</p>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL &amp; FINANCIAL CIRCULARS</p>
                    <p>BROKER'S NOTES, MEMORANDUM FORMS</p>
                    <p>INVOICE HEADINGS, BILL FORMS, RECEIPT FORMS, DELIVERY ORDERS</p>
                    <p>Bills of Lading, Charter Parties</p>
                    <p>PROSPECTUSES, REPORTS, BALANCE SHEETS &amp;C. OF PUBLIC COMPANIES</p>
                    <p>PRODUCE CONTRACTS, HOUSE CONTRACTS &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Prescription Forms</p>
                    <p>VISITING CARDS </p>
                    <p>Ball Programmes, Concert Programmes, Playbills, Menus &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>BOOKS; PAMPHLETS; NEWSPAPERS</p>
                    <p>FUNERAL NOTICES</p>
                    <p>&amp;c. &amp;c.  &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Orders for the above or any other description of plain or ornamental
                        printing, in any language, will receive prompt attention.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>FIRE INSURANCE. </head>
                    <p>Norwich Union Fire Insurance Society, </p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED IN 1797) </p>
                    <p>AMOUNT INSURED:– £125,000,000. </p>
                    <p>Unquestionable Security.– Large Reserve Funds.– Losses settled with
                        promptitude and liberality. </p>
                    <p>PRINCIPAL OFFICES :–LONDON, 50, FLEET STREET, NORWICH, SURREY STREET. </p>
                    <p>Agents for Egypt: R. J. Moss &amp; Co., ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>At CAIRO apply to Messrs. SCHNEIDER &amp; ZAHN.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>R. J. MOSS &amp; Co.</head>
                    <p>THE MOSS STEAM-SHIP Co., Limited (Messrs JAMES MOSS &amp; Co., Managers,
                        LIVERPOOL).</p>
                    <p>Weekly departures for LIVERPOOL calling at Malta, taking Goods at throngh
                        Rates for London, Hull, Glasgow, Hamburg, Rotterdam, Cronstadt, New-York,
                        Boston &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>S.S. OSIRIS, now in Port, to sail in a few days, followed by the</p>
                    <p>S.S. THEBES.</p>
                    <p>First Class Passage to Liverpool £15. </p>
                    <p>THE BRITISH INDIA STEAM NAVIGATION Co., Limited (P. MAC-NAUGHTON, Esq.,
                        Secretary GLASGOW).-Regular communication with Ports of the Red Sea and the
                        East Coast of Africa, Persian Gulf and India (See advertisement below). </p>
                    <p>THE STAR LINE OF STEAMERS, Limited (Messrs. RATHBONE BROTHERS &amp; Co.,
                        Managers LIVERPOOL), trading between Liverpool, Calcutta, Colombo and
                        London. </p>
                    <p>THE OCEAN STEAM-SHIP Co. (ALFRED HOLT, Esq., Manager, LIVERPOOL).—To and from
                        the Straits and the Ports of China and Japan, </p>
                    <p>Messrs. H. BRIGGS, SONS &amp; Co.'s HULL LINE OF STEAMERS. </p>
                    <p>THE ORIENT LINE OF STEAMERS (Messrs. ANDERSON ANDERSON &amp; Co., Managers,
                        LONDON) to and from Australia. </p>
                    <p>Agents to Messrs. Geo. W. Wheatley &amp; Co.-Goods forwarded to all parts of
                        the world. </p>
                    <p>The Standard Marine Insurance Company, Limited. | The Universal Marine
                        Insurance Company, Limited. </p>
                    <p> Messrs. Forwood Brothers &amp; Co., London, Underwriters. </p>
                    <p> The Liverpool Underwriters Association. </p>
                    <p>The Norwich Union Fire Insurance Society. </p>
                    <p>Lighters on hire.– Towage by S. S. MOSQUITO.– Coals always in stock afloat
                        and on shore. </p>
                    <p>For information in CAIRO, apply to Messrs. SCHNEIDER &amp; ZAHN, Strada della
                        Chiesa Cattolica.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>BRITISH INDIA STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANY LIMITED. </head>
                    <p>MAIL AND PASSENGER STEAM SHIPS.</p>
                    <p>SAILING FROM SUEZ </p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="2" cols="2">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell>FORTNIGHTLY TO</cell>
                                <cell>FORTNIGHTLY TO</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>KURRACHEE &amp; PERSIAN GULF, (Monthly ZANZIBAR) carrying
                                    Portuguese Govt. Mails.</cell>
                                <cell>COLOMBO, MADRAS, and CALCUTTA, in connection with Co.'s Indian
                                    Mail Lines.</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Homeward.-S.S. KHANDALLA.................25th August</cell>
                                <cell>Outward. – S.S. REWA...................24th August</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Outward. -S.S. AGRA...................23rd August</cell>
                                <cell>Homeward.S.S. INDIA................29th August</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>These Steamers call at ALGIERS and LISBON.</cell>
                                <cell>These Steamers call at MALTA. </cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>Queensland Royal Mail Line between London and Brisbane.</p>
                    <p>MONTHLY CONTRACT SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>SAILING FROM SUEZ </p>
                    <p>Calling at ADEN, BATAVIA, COOKTOWN, BOWEN, ROCKHAMPTON, Outward -and
                        PORT-SAID, Homeward</p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="2" cols="2">
                            <row>
                                <cell>Outward.– S.S. CHYEBASSA ..........13th Sept.</cell>
                                <cell>Homeward.– S.S. CAMORTA.........28th August</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>,, – S.S. COMPTA ..........11th Oct.</cell>
                                <cell>,, – S.S. ROMA ..........25th Sept.</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>REMARKS.-Surgeons and Stewardesses carried. Ice rooms, Pukahs and every
                        comfort for a tropical climate. Passengers and Cargo booked through, to
                        Continental and American Ports and to all impoitaut Ports on Coast of INDIA,
                        PERSIAN GULF, BURMAH, STRAITS SETLEMENTS, EASTERN ARCHIPELAGO PORTS, BATAVIA
                        and QUEENSLAND PORTS to BRISBANE and ZANZIBAR and EAST AFRICAN PORTS to
                        DELAGOA BAY. Rates of Passage money, as below, include table for First and
                        Second class Passengers only, but not wines or spirits, which may be had on
                        board for payment. Return tickets available for Six Months from date of
                        landing are issued to Passengers at a reduction of one Fifth, and for Twelve
                        months of one Tenth on the Return passage money. Passengers are allowed to
                        break the voyage at any intermediate Port and proceed by following steamer
                        in which there may be accomodation.</p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="7" cols="4">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell cols="4">FIRST CLASS RATES OF PASSAGE MONEY FROM SUEZ TO
                                </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>
                                    <p>Jeddah ... £ 8 –</p>
                                </cell>
                                <cell>Bagdad… £ 60 –</cell>
                                <cell>Rangoon … £ 40 –</cell>
                                <cell>Rockhampton…  £ 57 15</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Hodeidah … ,, 12 –</cell>
                                <cell>Zanzibar… ,,  40 – </cell>
                                <cell>Penang… ,, 45 –</cell>
                                <cell>Brisbane… ,, 58 17</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Aden … ,,15 –</cell>
                                <cell>Mozainbique.… ,,  45 –</cell>
                                <cell>Singapore … ,,50 –</cell>
                                <cell>Naples … ,, 10 10</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Kurrachee … ,, 31 10 </cell>
                                <cell>Delagoa Bay… ,, 50 – </cell>
                                <cell>Batavia … ,, 50 –</cell>
                                <cell>Malta … ,, 8 –</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bombay … ,, 31 10 </cell>
                                <cell>Colombo … ,,  30 – </cell>
                                <cell>Cooktown … ,,54 10 </cell>
                                <cell>Algiers… ,, 15 –</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>
                                    <p>Bushire … ,, 50 –</p>
                                </cell>
                                <cell>Madras… ,,  35 –</cell>
                                <cell>Townsville … ,, 55 11</cell>
                                <cell> Lisbon … ,, 15 10</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bussorah… ,, 52 –</cell>
                                <cell>Calcutta … ,, 37 –</cell>
                                <cell>Bowen… ,, 56 13 </cell>
                                <cell>London… ,, 15 15</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>Second Class, Two thirds,and Deck Passengers, One fourth of First Class
                        Fares. </p>
                    <p>AGENTS IN LONDON, Messrs. GRAY DAWES &amp; Co., 13, Austin Friar's E.C. </p>
                    <p>MANAGING AGENTS IN INDIA, Messrs. MACKINNON MACKENZIE &amp; Co.,
                        CALCUTTA.</p>
                    <p>AGENTS AT PORT SAID, for the London, Calcutta and Persian Gulf Lines, Messrs.
                        WORMS JOSSE &amp; Co., </p>
                    <p>AGENTS AT PORT SAID, for the London and Queensland Line, Messrs. WILLS MANCHE
                        &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>AGENTS AT CAIRO, for all Lines, Messrs. THOS. COOK &amp; SON. </p>
                    <p>AGENTS AT ALEXANDRIA, for ditto, R. J. MOSS &amp; CO. </p>
                    <p>For further particulars Freight or Passage apply to</p>
                    <p>G. BEYTS &amp; Co., SUEZ.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Anchor Line Steamers</head>
                    <p>HENDERSON BROTHERS, GLASGOW. </p>
                    <p>Fortnightly sailings between GLASGOW, LIVERPOOL &amp; BOMBAY.</p>
                    <p>First Class Passenger Steamers carrying Surgeons and Stewardesses. </p>
                    <p>Booking Passengers and Cargo through to CONTINENTAL and AMERICAN PORTS.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE from SUEZ.-Outward. </p>
                    <p>S.S. .................., on or about the 21st August, direct for
                        BOMBAY.-First Class Fare 30 Guineas.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE from SUEZ.-Homeward. </p>
                    <p>S.S. .................., on or about the 21st August., for LIVERPOOL.-First
                        Class Fare to NAPLES 10 guineas, MARSEILLES 12 guineas, LIVERPOOL 15
                        guineas.</p>
                    <p>Agents at ALEXANDRIA, Messrs. HEWAT &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>For further particulars freight or passage apply to</p>
                    <p>G. BEYTS &amp; Co., SUEZ.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>CLAN LINE STEAMERS.</head>
                    <p>CAYZER IRVINE &amp; Co., LONDON, LIVERPOOL and GLASGOW</p>
                    <p>REGULAR FORTNIGHTLY SAILINGS BETWEEN GLASGOW LIVERPOOL &amp; BOMBAY. </p>
                    <p>First Class Passenger Steamers specially built for the trade, carrying
                        Surgeons and Stewardesses.</p>
                    <p>Passengers and Cargo booked through to EUROPE CONTINENT and AMERICA </p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE FROM SUEZ.– Homeward.</p>
                    <p>SS ..........., on or about the 22nd August, for LIVERPOOL.-FARE: £15. </p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE FROM SUEZ.– Outward. S.S. </p>
                    <p>S.S. CLAN FORBES, on or about the 25th August, direct to BOMBAY.-FARE: €30. </p>
                    <p>S.S. CLAN DRUMMOND, on or about the 8th Sept., for COLOMBO, MADRAS &amp;
                        CALCUTTA.</p>
                    <p>Agents at ALEXANDRIA :-Messrs. HEWAT &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>,, PORT SAID:-Messrs. BAZIN &amp; Co. </p>
                    <p>For further particulars, freight or passage apply to</p>
                    <p>G. BEYTS &amp; Jo., SUEZ.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
