<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, JANUARY 2, 1905.</head>
<div>
<head>PORT ARTHUR
NEW TOWN ABANDONED.
More Forts Stormed and Captured
DEFENSIVE POWER WEAKENING.</head>
<p>London, December 31.</p>
<p>The Daily Telegraph learns from Chifu that a messenger from Dalny states that the Russians have abandoned the new town at Port
Arthur, which was destroyed.by the Japanese
fire. The Japanese are unable to occupy the
same for tear of mines which may be there.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<p>Tokio, January 1.</p>
<p>The Japanese have taken by assault the
Forts of bung shu shau and Ptduug-shan and
the heights to the south of Huasantigyantao.</p>
<p>(Havas.)</p>
<p>Tokio, January 1.</p>
<p>The Japanese yesterday, after exploding a
series of minus, stormed and captured Sung-shu-shou, one of the most important of the remaining forts at Port Arthur. The Russians exploded mines as they were retreating. A portion of the garrison was buried under the
debris but rescued by the Japanese, who
captured some guns. The Japanese losses were
small. There is every indication that the
defensive power is weakening.</p>
<p>The Japanese to day captured H fort and
the new Palung-shan fort, together with the
heights south of Huasantigyantao. </p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>ADDRESS TO THE SPIRITS.</head>
<p>Tokio, December 31.</p>
<p>On the occasion of a naval funeral, Admiral Togo delivered an eloquent and touching address in the spirits of his comrades fallen a Port Arthur. He declined a reception by the Tokio municipality on the ground that the
time is not yet ripe for such a ceremony.
Admiral Togo is busily engaged in conferring
with his naval staff as regards his future plans.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
<p>Port Louis, December 31.</p>
<p>It is rumored that the two Russian squadrons will join each other north of Majunga.</p>
<p>(Havas)</p>
<head>DUTCH NEUTRALITY.</head>
<p>The Hague, January 1.</p>
<p>The Dutch battleship "De Ruyter” has been
ordered to the East Indies.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>DEPARTING RUSSIAN TROOPS.
REVIEWED BY TSAR.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, January 1.</p>
<p>The Tsar is visiting South Russia in order
to bid farewell to the troops who are  departing for the Far East. The Tsar, held a review at Birsula and urged the soldiers to win fresh glory. The men responded with enthusiastic cheers.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<p>KOREA
DIFFICULT POLITICAL SITUATION.</p>
<p>Seoul, December 31.<p>
<p>The political situation here is very difficult.
There have been several political meetings
lately. A serious riot, caused by the pro-Japa-
occurred in front of the Palace. Twelve
persons were shot by Korean guards. Further
rioting is expected. The streets are filled with
Japanese gendarmes.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>RUSSIAN REFORM MOVEMENT.
REPRESSIVE MEASURES.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, December 31.
The provincial authorities are taking mea-
sure to prevent banquets which cloak reform
meetings.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<p>St. Petersburg, January. </p>
<p>M. de Witte, President of the Committee of
Ministers, is actively preparing material in
order to study the reforms indicated in the
Tsar’s manifesto. The first meeting of the
Committee will take place on the 3rd inst.</p>
<p>(H.)</p>
<head>FINLAND.
A PETITION TO tHE TSAR.</head>
<p>Helsingfors, January 1.</p>
<p>The four Estates of the Finnish Diet have
decided to present a petition to the Tsar asking
for the withdrawal of the Russification decree
of 1903, in order to re-establish a legal order
of things in Finland.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>Anglo American Nile Steamer
& Hothl. COMPANY.
RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA & CAIRO
Three Sailings a Week.
Agents at Alexandria
Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co</head>
<head>VIOLENT GALE IN BRITAIN.
NUMEROUS CASUALTIES.</head>
<p>London, December 31.</p>                                                                   <p>A violent gale swept the British Isles yesterday causing numerous casualties on land and sea. Considerable telegraphic interruption
occurred. There was an extraordinarily high
tide in the Thames and, Medway. The Victoria
Embankment is inundated, and Cleopatra’s
Needle is surrounded by water.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<head>INTENSE COLD IN RUSSIA.
38 DEGREES BELOW- ZERO.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, January 1.</p>
<p>Intense cold prevails in Russia. The trains
are delayed. All the schools in Moscow are
closed. The thermometer marks 38* below zero
Fahr.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>ADEN HINTERLAND.
IRADE WHOLLY UNSATISFACTORY.</head>
<p>London, January 1.</p>
<p>The Irade concerning the Aden hinterland
proves to be wholy unsatisfactory, as it widely
modifies the British proposals.</p>
<p>(Reuter.)</p>
<head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO.</head>
<p>Paris, December 31.<p>
<p>The Sultan of Morocco has declared to the.
French Minister that he is disposed to continue
to have recourse to the aid of the counsels ui
France. The crisis is considered as being
happily at an end.</p>
<p>(Havas.)</p>
<head>THE PROGRESS OF ARBITRATION.</head>
<p>Paris, January 1.</p>
<p>At the New Year’s Day reception of the
Diplomatic Corps, M. Loubet, replying to
Count Tornielli, spoke of the progress of the
idea of arbitration in the minds of the peoples
and governments.</p>
<p>(Havas)</p>
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
<p>The ancona Court has acquitted Mr.
Sciplini, accused of having accidentally killed
the late Mr. Rossetti, the Cairo advocate.</p>
<p>The Nile Cold Storage Company, Ltd.
has obtained the contract for supplying meat
to the British Army of Occupation in Cairo.</p>
<p>Embezzlement at G. P.-O.—It has been
discovered that some embezzlement has occurred
in the funds of the Postal Benevolent Society
at Alexandria, and an enquiry has been
opened.</p>
<p>Fatal Accident.—On Saturday afternoon a
Copt who was crossing the junction at Ataba
el Khadra, Cairo, was struck by a tram and
sustained injuries which have since proved
fatal.</p>
<p>A. L. M.,& D. S.—We are asked to remind
members of the choral union that the practices
will be resumed to-morrow: at the Rudolph
Asile at 6.15 p.m. In the future rehearsals sill
be on Monday evenings, at that hour.</p>
<p>Cotton in Cyprus.—The question of ex-
tending the cultivation of cotton in Cyprus
has lately been occupying much attention, and
last season some quantity of Egyptian cotton
seed was imported and sown.</p>
<p>Suez Canal.—On Thursday 29th December,
11 vessels passed through the canal, 10 of
which were British and 1 Austrian. The
receipts for the day were trs. 166,789.56. The
total receipts from 1st to 29th December were
9,478,611.37.</p>
<p>Motor Accident. — We hear that H.H.
Prince Hussein Kamel’s motor car ran down
and injured a carter at the corner of the
Sharia el Madabegh The Arab seems to have
lust his head completely, and to have rushed
in front of the motor instead of getting out.
of the way.</p>
<p>“The Cyprus Journal’’ for December contains, as usual, a variety of interesting contributions more especially dealing with the agriculture of the island. Among other things we find articles on the manuring of cotton, sheep scab, the boar, the sow, poultry notes, archeological notes, etc.</p>
<p>Coal Imports.—The imports of coal into
Alexandria from the 1st January to the 29th
ulto. amounted to 1,050,460 tons, as compared
with 1,005,482 tons during the corresponding
period last year. Of this total, Newcastle sent
240,694 tons, the Welsh coaling district*
594,774 tons, tho Scotch districts 108,810 tons,
and Yorkshire 58,375 tons, while the imports
of other qualities came to 48,307.</p>
<p>Gymkhana—We publish to-day the programme of the Gymkhana to be held at Mena House next Friday. There are nine interesting events. The sixth is an open pony race to ridden in colors. The band of the Inniskillings will play during the afternoon. In the evening there will be a dance. Trams will run frequent that day to the Pyramids, the last car leaving the Pyramids at midnight. Entries for the races can be made at Mena town office. Tables l\for luncheon at Mena-House should be ordered beforehand.</p>
<head>ROYAL VISIT TO EGYPT.
ARRANGEMENTS FOR
DUKE OF CONNAUGHT.</head>
<p>We hear that the Duke and Duchess of
Connaught will probably arrive in Egypt on
the 26th inst, and will leave again on the
27th February.</p>
<p>Their Royal Highnesses, While at Cairo, will stay at Abdeen Palace, as the guests of H. H. the Khedive.</p>
<p>All the arrangements for the stay of the
Duke and Duchess in Egypt have been placed in the hands of George Nungovich Bey.</p>
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<p>The Khedive has arrived at Montazah from
Cairo. His Highness will return to the Capital
in a few days.</p>
<head>QUARANTINE IN TURKEY.</head>
<p>Pera, Dec. 31.</p>
<p>Since the departures of the 28th, pilgrim
ships from Aden are subject to 10 days quarantine, ships without pilgrims five days, with disinfection and destruction of rats.</p>
<head>CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
<p>During the week ending on Saturday last
57 deaths from bovine typhus were reported
throughout Egypt During the corresponding
period last year, 7,169 deaths were reported.
A slight recrudescence of the disease is noted
daring the last week, but this is entirely of a
local character, confined to the provinces of
Gharbieh and Ghizeh.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the outbreak the
cattle of the localities infected and neighbouring villages have been inoculated with
serum. This has always checked the development oI the disease. The quantity of serum at the disposal of the Sanitary Administration is
amply sufficient for inoculation in case of
local outbreaks, and a constant supply is
furnished by the Serum Farm. The Administration baa every ground for the hope that
the disease will have disappeared by the end
of this year.</p>
<p>The serum seems to have little or no protective effect with animals coming from
Cyprus, many of which, though inoculated,
have succumbed to the disease. Similar
experiments have been dumJc in India on
animals coming from the mountains and from
the plains. The cattle of the plains are protected by the serum, which, however, has little
or no effect on the mountain cattle, even when
employed in strong doses. Under these conditions the Sanitary Administration considers
die importation of Cypriote cattle, as long as
the epidemic lasts, to be a mistake, as these
animals are sure to be infected sooner or later.</p>
<head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
<p>On Saturday two new cases of plague were
reported, with a death outside hospital, at
Suez, and one new case with two deaths
outside hospital at Kafr el Fokaha, in the
Toukh Markaz.</p>
<p>During the week ending the 31st December,
15 cases of bubonic plague occurred throughout
Egypt. An increase appears in the number of
cases occurring at Suez last week. It appears
from the report that I have received from
Dr. Cresswell and from my own observations,
(says Sir H. Pinching in his report) that
these cases are due to infection conveyed by
rata, which had been infected themselves by
goods coming from India or Upper Egypt.
One of the persons attacked by plague at
Suez is an assistant in a shop, which contains
large quantities of indigo coming from Calcutta
and tea from Madras. In moving the cases
containing these goods the dead bodies of rats
were found. Large quantities of beans have
also been imported from Upper Egypt, where
cases of plague occurred this year, the last of
which was reported on July 31.</p>
<head>AN INTERESTING AUCTION.</head>
<p>Maitre Privat, of the Cairo Mixed Court,
has issued notice of the sale by public auction
of the furniture of Mr. Reich, a British subject, which was seized on the application of Mustapha Ahmed, a coachman and local subject The sale will take place early in January. This announcement has aroused some interest in Cairo, as Mr. Reich was up to a few weeks ago in association with another gentleman, Mr. Bernie Mansfield, under the style of Reich and Mansfield. A short time back the partnership between these two gentlemen was dissolved. The sale will begin at 10 a.m. on the 6th inst at the Old Continental Hotel buildings, where are the offices and residence of Mr. Reich.</p>
<head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
<p>By kind permission of Lient-CoL G. M.
Mackenzie, commanding, and officers, 2nd
Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will play
the following programme on the Terrace, Grand Hotel, Helouan, tomorrow afternoon from 3.15 to 5.15 p.m. :—</p>
<p>March- The Bride Elect—Sousa.</p>
<p>Overture—The Village Festival—O’Kufe.</p>
<p>Song—Killarney—Balfe.</p>
<p>Selection—Veroniqne—Messager.</p>
<p>Valse—Friedens Palmen—Keler Bela.</p>
<p>Polacca— Picaroon—Gran.</p>
<p>Selection—The Toreador—Monckton.</p>
<p>Polka—Ionian—Mrs. Wardroper.</p>
<p>Regimental March.</p>
<p>Khedivial Anthem.</p>
<p>God Save the King.</p>
<head>RAMLFH ELECTRIC RAILWAY.
THE NEW TARIFF.</head>
<p>The new tariff which came into force yesterday on the Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Company's line has aroused a considerable
amount of indignation among the inhabitants.</p>
<p>Mr. IL II. Birch sends us the following communication on the subject:—</p>
<p>The directors of tho Ramleh Railway Company, Ltd., have issued a notice that no further contract tickets will be issued after 31st December, 1904, end that in place of them “carnets,” or books of tickets, will be provided at a price which more-than doubles the cost of the yearly contract. The reasons given for this new departure are-</p>
<p>I “That many contract holders refuse to
show their tickets to the conductors when
called upon to do so, and abuse and even
assault them." The remedy for this is to send
the offenders before tho Tribunals, and exac
the penalty for their misconduct.</p>
<p>II“The company is now a tramway company and no such companies in Europe issue contract tickets.” To this the reply is that it was a railway company when the concession was obtained from the Egyptian Government, and if it has suited the direction to convert the railway into a tramway for their own benefit, it is no reason why the public should be sacrificed.</p>
<p>The Government, having granted a monopoly
to the company, should take care that this
monopoly is not abused. The contract holders
are mostly old residents, and it is not only
the proceeds of their tickets that benefit the
company, but also a further benefit accrues
from the members of their households and
guests who visit them and who do not hold
contracts. What is to be the result of this
new regulation? The increased charge is
altogether immensurate to the service rendered by the company. Numbers of people will have to leave Ramleh, and rents, house property, and land will all decrease in value. It behoves everybody to protest energetically against this regulation, which is unjustifiable from ad points of view.</p>
<p>This morning we interviewed one of the
members of the board of the company, Mr.
Lumbroso, who gave us the following exposition of the directors’ standpoint:—</p>
<p>In no country in the world are there season
tickets for electric trams, but only books of
tickets. After the electrification of the line,
and out of consideration for the public’s demands, season tickets were issued on the condition that every season ticket holder should have his photograph in the ticket case and
should show it whensoever asked by the company’s servants. But, continued Mr. Lumbreso,
this system has been rendered impossible
owing to the "mauvaise volonte” of the public
and of the tricks played upon the company by
-false season ticket holders, who insulted and
attacked the employees when asked to show
their tickets. The directors have had to stop
issuing season tickets, and have reduced the
price of packets of 50 tickets for the first
class from P.T. 38 to P.T. 75 and for the
second class from P.T. 4.7 to P.T. 37J. This,
said Mr. Lumbroso, was a sacrifice made by
the company for the sake of the public, since
on a total of about L.E. 50,000 the amount
realized from season tickets was only L.E. 8,000.
On the other hand, tho above must take into
consideration the fact that if the present price
of the books of ticket appears to be higher
than the season ticket rate, the new system
has the advantage of allowing them to give
away the tickets in the books to their families
and servants if they wish to.</p>
<head>PASSENGERS’ LISTS.
arrivals.</head>
<p>Le paquebot “Sirio” de la Cie Florio-Rubat-
tino arrive hier de Genes avait 4 bord :
M.M. Lionel Sutro et fam., Bartlett et Whip-
ple, Trukenburg, Crumm, Postorino, Amali, D.
Hessen, Johnswood et Comp, H. Boidinaun et
Comp., Padovani, Cemmosky, Fergusson et fam.,
Johnston et fam., Huff Sohley et Comp., Fou
quet, M. et Mme S. As tom, Meyer, Adams, P
Levi et Comp., Vanda Hermes, E. M. More,
A. Merolli, Comte Perigord, Malvano, Rava, J.
Neille, Com.- Angelini et Benucci, Gossart et sa
mfcra, Aziz Aboud et Comp, et 26 passage ra de
3me classe.</p>
<p>Le paquebot "Cleopatra" da Lloyd Autri-
chien, arrive ce matin de Trieste avait a bord:
M. et Mme Frappier, M. et Mme Donnet,
FAliansky, M. et Mme C. Elmgren, R. Mgr.
Lynch et 3 comp., M. et Mme Ranking, Baron
V. Frerich, Mmo Nilsen, Kubler, John, Zamia-
trian, VegK, Florkovsky, Nicoloivich, Hover,
Kumar, Metzler, Lemberg, Kristen, Blaskle,
Schmelzer, M. et Mme Hilzheimer, Gotz, Zab-
stnik et 2 de fam., Homko, Rotter, Pried, Jago-
vies et fils, Gera to et 8 passage™ de 3me classe.</p>
<head>DEPARTURES.</head>
<p>La paquebot "Semiramis" du Lloyd Autri-
chien parti samedi poor Trieste avait a bord :
M.M. H. Axisa, Karl Wollanka, Ed. Heini-
mann, Cap. A. Forsberg, R. Jenisch, ministre plenipotentiaire et consul general, D.A.J. Hamilton, Dinean Stewart, Mme D. Stewart, E. P. Mitchell, F. Mitchell, Guido Kleinchuster, M. de la Bouglise, A. Brasi, E Debourg, F. Buxbaum, M. et Mme A. Barber, av. B. A. Findall,
A. Trobridge, M. et Mme Napoleski, Mme I.
Monti Baldini, A. L. Lamas, R. Mordo, Chalikiopoulos, J. A. Fattersall, G. H. Pattison, Ernest Brod, Macdonald, E Mattatia, Isidoro Salto, Weiglaas, R. Abdela, Tattwall, F. Fleisched et 10 passage de 3me classe.</p>
<p>Per Ellerman S. S. "City of Cambridge,’
sailed for Liverpool Saturday : — Dr. Ruth-
erford, Mia Schofield, Mia Brenn, Mia Cameron, Mr. Whitehead, Mr, Mend’s.</p>
<head>BIG FAILURE AT ALEXANDRIA
LIABILITIES £180,000.</head>
<p>The heavy fail in American cotton has led to the failure of one of the leading Syrian capitalists in Egypt, Mr. Selim Tawil, who belongs to a family which is well known at Alexandria, and whose business connections were very extensive. His speculations were chiefly directed to American cotton, and on Friday last he found himself unable to pay his differences. The amount he has failed for is said to be £180,000. As the Bourse and all the banks are closed today it is impossible for us to obtain complete details of the failure.</p>
<p>Mr. Tawil was arrested on Saturday but was at once released on the guarantee of Mr. Gorra, late of the Imperial Ottoman Bank at Alexandria.</p>
<head>SAVOY SMALL DANCE.</head>
<p>Saturday evening’s small dance at the Savoy was a huge success, and seldom, even in the very height of the         season,        has        there been a more enjoyable one. Nearly all the officers of the Army of Occupation and of the Egyptian Army were present, as wall aa the. usual habitatues of Savoy Saturday’s dances. The restaurant was crowded both for dinner and supper. Dr. Milton gave a big dinner party. His guests numbered 18, including the Misses Coles, Dr. Tribe, Mr. McGillivray, Mr. Greville, Dr. Hayward, Mrs. Pidgeon, Mr. Russell, Miss Gabriel, Miss Ball, Miss Cox, Miss London, Miss Joseph, Mr. Mussell, and Mr. Scott Moncrieff. Mr. and Mrs. Bell entertained a party of 10, amongst the guests being Mr. and the Hon. Mrs. Home, Major and Miss Petre, Capt. the Hon. A Stanley, and Miss Hurley. Dr. and Mrs. Page-May entertained 11 guests at dinner, Mrs. Simon had a party of 4, Capt. C. H. Garrat a party of 8, and Mr. P. W. Stout a party of 4. Mr..and Mrs. Berners entertained Sir John and Lady Rogers, .and- CoL Sir Henry Oldham dined with Major-General Ralph Allen, while Mr. Sheldon Amos had a party of 5.</p>
<p>Among others at the dance we observed Mrs. and Mias Koyle, Col. Matchett, Mr. P. ‘W. Machell, Sir Edward and Lady Zohrab Pasha, Mr. Vinoent Corbett^ Dr. and Mrs. Maddeu, Mr. Mitchell lnnee, CoL and Mrs. J. K. Watson, etc.</p>
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
<head>FOOTBALL</head>
<head>R.M.A. v. D. Coy. R. Berks Regt.</head>
<p>An exciting game between these two singularly well-matched teams took place at Mustapha on Saturday last. The game was a very fast one, the ball traveling swiftly from goal to goal, and there was not a dull moment
throughout. Result: a pointless draw.</p>
<head>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB.</head>
<p>The following are the weights for the
Paddock Handicap, to be run on the second
day of the Cairo Second Winter Race Meeting (January 25 and 27) :—</p>
<p>Sirur 8.9, Abou Arkoub 9.12, Ide 10.7, Siham 9.8, Sadik 10.9, Lariff 9.13, Klondyke 9.12, Parhan II. 11.2, Saber 10.12, Rioe 10.6, Royalist 10.12, Fantasia 10.11, Eclipse 10.5, Petit Due 8.13, Agrib 10.5, Hardcase 10.2, Sans Pared 10.8, Vandal 10.6, India 9.7, Pahr 9.0, Caprice 11.9, Viking 9.6, Amory 9.7.</p>
<head>GYMKHANA</head>
<head>To BE HELD AT MENA HOUSE
ON FRIDAY, 6th JANUARY, 1905.</head>
<head>Entrance to Grand Stand and Enclosure :
Gentleman P.T. 10—Ladies P.T. 5—
Children Free.</head>
<head>Tea will be served on the ground free of charge.</head>
<head>Prizes will at given for all the events.</head>
<head>A Band will play during tie afternoon.</head>
<head>FIRST RACE AT 3 P. M.
Events.</head>
<p>1. Donkey Race for Gentlemen.
2. Hack Race, Ponies and Galloways.
3. Egg and Spook Race, Ladies on donkeys.
4. Hack Race (Horses), for Gentlemen.
5. Cigarette and Umbrella Race on donkeys.
6. The Mena Cup. 1/2 mile straight, For all Arabs 14.2 and nnder. Open race to be ridden in colors. 1st horse P.T. 1000, 2nd P.T. 200, 8rd P.T. 75.
7. Ladies’ Hack Race.
8. Lloyd Lindsay Race, on Ponies.
9. Affinity Stakes, on Hones.</p>
<p>There will be a dance at 9.80 p.m.</p>
<head> STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
<p>The Moss liner "Seti" sailed from Liverpool
on Friday afternoon and is due here about
the 18th int, with passengers, mails, and
general cargo.</p>
<p>The Moss liner "Menes" arrived at Liver-
pool on Saturday morning.</p>
<p>The Ellerman S. S. "City of Cambridge”
sailed on Sunday morning direct for Liverpool
with passengers and a full cargo, including
5,169 hales cotton.</p>
<p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Niger,"
from Marseilles, passed the Straits of Messina
on Saturday and is due here tomorrow morning</p>
<head>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES
(From our own Correspondent).
JUDGE SAUSMAREZ’S DEPARTURE</head>
<p>Constantinople, December 27.</p>
<p>Judge and Mrs. de Sausmarez left Cons-
tantinople for London last Tuesday. Their
departure is a cause of general regret, end
the very large gathering of friends At the
station to see them off bore testimony to
their greet popularity in this city. It is not
only a learned judge that the Constantinople
and Egyptian Bar loses in the person of Mr.
de Sausmarez, but also one who, during his
tenure of office, bee displayed merits of
a high order in the cause of justice end in
the interests of litigants.</p>
<head>GREEK-CATHOLIC PATRIACH.</head>
<p>On Friday last, after the ceremony at the
Selamlik, H. B. Mgr. Cyril, Greek Catholic
Patriarch at Alexandria, was received in audience by the Sultan, to lay the expression of
his homage end devotion at the foot of the Imperial throne and to take leave on the occasion of his return to Alexandria. The departure of the Patriarch will take place in a fortnight.
Last Saturday, Mgr. Cyril paid e visit to
Mgr. Ermaian, Armenian Patriarch at Constantinople. He also visited, with his suite, the Armenian Cathedral at Couin-Capu.</p>
<head>PERSIAN MISSION.</head>
<p>Aly Elder Khan, brother of the Persian Ambassador here, Futhollah Khan, military attache, and Aly Aagher Khan, attache of the Persian Embassy, arrived here last week from St Petersburg. They are the members of the special mission sent by the Shah of Persia to the Tsar, and will proceed very shortly to Cairo on a visit to H.H. the Khedive. They are awaiting the arrival of the Persian Ambassador at Constantinople, who will be the bead of the mission.</p>
<head>PERSONAL</head>
<p>The betrothal is announced from Smyrna of Miss Effie Charnaud, daughter of Mr. Edwin Charnaud, chief inspector of the Ottoman Public Debt, with Mr. Henry Williamson, of Cairo. The bride is the niece of Mr. Charnaud, director of the Tobaooo Regie here.</p>
<p>The news of the death of Mr. Hicks, manager of the Imperial Ottoman Bank's agency at Cairo was received here with much regret, Mr. Hicks having been very popular. His successor has not yet been appointed.</p>
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
<p?The rush of well-known people to Egypt
after the New Year promisee to be exception-
ally heavy. Plans are already being disarranged and rearranged, owing to the difficulty of
scouring berths on steamers. The Earl and
Countess of Deltrousie, who are going up the
Nile, accompanied by Miss Margaret Fraser,
have had to postpone their departure from
England for this reason.</p>
<p>The Earl of Cromer will probably return
from his Nile trip on the 20th inst</p>
<p>Lady Arthur Russell and Miss Russell are
expected at Cairo from the Fayoum in the
course of the week.</p>
<p>M. and Mme Maximoff are leaving for the
Upper Nile about the middle of this month.</p>
<p>M. and Mme. Bouliniere will also visit the
Upper Nile and perhaps the Sudan in February.</p>
<p>The celebrated American artist, Mrs. Anna
Louise Blanchard, of New York, arrived in
Cairo yesterday. The wife of one of the most
prominent members of the Diplomats Corps
has arranged to give sittings to Mrs. Blanchard
for a portrait in oils.</p>
<p>Mr. Charles Betts, the well-known, stock-
broker at Alexandria, has entered into partner-
ship with Mr. Otto Schmidt, the son-in-law of
the late Mr. Micallef.</p>
<p>The Darmanin family thank all those who
attended the funeral of the late Antonio
Darmanin, or who in other ways showed sym-
pathy in their bereavement, as well as Messrs.
Allen, Alderson & Co. and the whole of tbs
firm's staff.</p>
<p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy
Hotel, Port Said, we notioe Miss von Goldacker,
Dr. Baissler, Mr. R Colebrooke and Miss
Colebrooke, Mr. Melas, Dr. B. Moritz, Mr. H.
Schwesle, Prof. Dr. H. Bitter, Vicomte de Fontarce, Mr. Reynolds, Commandant Schwanck,
Baron Oppenheim, Mr Anders, Mr. Morgan,
Mn. Collins, Mrs. Schailk, Messrs. Lemarche.</p>
<head>NOTICE</head>
<p>IS HEREBY GIVEN that all persons
having any claims or demands upon or
against the Estate of EDMUND KELLY
DE WILTON BEY, late of Suez, Egypt,
deceased (who died at Cairo on 26th March, 1903) are required to send in particulars
of their claims or demands to the undersigned Leon Carton de Wiart, Advocate, Cairo, Attorney for the Executrix under the will of the deceased, on or before
the 31st day of January, 1905, after which
date he will proceed to distribute the
assets of the deceased and will not be
liable for the assets or any part thereof
so distributed to any person of whose
claim he shall not then have had notice.
Dated this 29th day of December, 1904</p>
