<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!-- Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-10-30">October 30, 2023<!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 0000-00-00 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-22">Tuesday, November 22,
                        1905<!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p1.jpg">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"  
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p2.jpg">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
             <div type="item">
                    <p>The Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Limited, 15, Gerrard St., Soho,</p>
                    <p>undertakes every description of banking busines</p>
                    <p>on the most favourable conditios.:</p>
                    <p>Current accounts opened with commercial ha ises</p>
                    <p>London, W.</p>
                    <p>and private individuals in conformity with th-ND AT BIRMINGHAM &amp;
                        MANOHESTER</p>
                    <p>castom of Banker</p>
                    <p>Fixed deposits for one year certain received at à per cent per annum.
                        Depo-its at interest for shorter periods are also received at mates to be
                        agreed upon. Letters of Credis for the use of travellers are isted payable
                        in al parte of the World. Approved hills discounted.</p>
                    <p>Bille, documentary invoices, eto, collected. Deaf and singapoio transfers
                        inued pay- able all over the World.</p>
                    <p>Foreign exchange bought and sold. Advsners made upon approved securities and
                        upon cotton, cotton-seed, sugar and other mer abandies.</p>
                    <p>The parchaee and sale of stocks and shares on the London Stock Exchange and
                        on the loesl and Continental Bourses, undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Customers osa deposit their valuables, bonds, , for le enstody in the Bank's
                        fire-proof strong-rooms, and the Bank will attend to the collecuen of the
                        coupons and drawn bonds deposited as they fall due</p>
                    <p>Mercentile credits issued.</p>
                    <p>Annaides, pensions, dividends, eto, collected. All farther particulars and
                        information can be oblained on application.</p>
                    <p>The officers and olerke, of the Bank are pledged to secrecy as to the tran-
                        sactions of customers.</p>
                    <p>Brus<add>
                            <note>
                                <p>The George Nungovich Hotels.</p>
                                <p>Grand Hotel, Heleuan.-Finest and most luxurious Hotel near Cairo.
                                    Patunised by Royalty. Moderate charges. Special terms for
                                    resident Hotel des Bains-Most comfortable hotel, opposite the
                                    Baths. Pension from P.T. 4. Attached to the above hotels and
                                    specially roved for their clients are the Golf Links (18 holes)
                                    with English Professional. Own Golf House in the desert. Sulphur
                                    Bath Establishment-Sulphur water stronger than any in Europe.
                                    Eight European Masseurs and ose Every modern sprovement.</p>
                                <p>THE WORLD'S MEDICINE.</p>
                                <p>BEECHAM'S PILLS</p>
                                <p>Care all Billous and Nervous Disorders, Sick Headache,
                                    Constipation, Impaired Digestion, Wind and Pains in Stomach,
                                    Disordered Liver and Female Allments. They act like Magie on the
                                    Vital Organs, Regulating the Secretions, restoring the long-lost
                                    Complexion, bringing back the keen edge of Appetite, and
                                    arousing with the Rosebud of Health the whole physical energy of
                                    the human frame..</p>
                                <p>BEECHAM'S PILLS are the most popular English family Medicine, and
                                    are composed entirely of Medicinal Herbs. They cleanse the
                                    stomach, and bowels, purify the blood, invigorate the nervous
                                    system, and give tone and energy to the Muscles. BEECHAM'S PILLS
                                    have the largest sale of any Medicine in the World.</p>
                                <p>Sold at all Drug Stores In Egypt, is boxes, 4 plastres and 6
                                    plastres.</p>
                                <p>MELLIN'S</p>
                                <p>4-31-405</p>
                                <p>For Infants FOOD</p>
                                <p>and Invalids.</p>
                                <p>Prepared as directed is rich in those sub- stances which nourish
                                    and sustain children and sick persons.</p>
                                <p>Always uniform, easily prepared, speedily digested and
                                    absorbed.</p>
                                <p>MELLIN'S FOOD WORKS, PECKHAM, S.E.</p>
                                <p>Representative in Egypt, Max Fischer, Cairo and-Alexandria.</p>
                                <p>CIGARES</p>
                                <p>CHAMPAGNE</p>
                                <p>de la HAVANE GEORGE GOULET.</p>
                                <p>de provenance directe</p>
                                <p>et de toutes les meilleures marques</p>
                                <p>Nicolas G. Sabbag</p>
                                <p>IMPORTATEUR GENERAL OUREMSEUR DE 3. A. LE KHEDIVE de less les
                                    grasie Clube Hotele Rypla Rue de in Gare du Caire9 ALEXANDRIE
                                    Adres Taligraphions: Babbag Alexandrie Telephone No. MS</p>
                            </note>
                        </add></p>
                 
                </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p3.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A NEW RUSSIA!</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>WAR.</p>
                    <p>JAPS BLOWN UP.</p>
                    <p>ALL QUIET IN. MANCHURIA..</p>
                    <p>DAWN OF NEW ERA.</p>
                    <p>CONSTITUTION DEMANDED.</p>
                    <p>ST. PETERSBURG, November 21. As a result of Prince Mirskis appointment the
                        Government gave permission for a public ST. PETERSBURG, November 21. from
                        the Zemstvos throughout the country, but conference to be held here of
                        representatives General Kuropatkin reports that, during at the last moment
                        deslined to sanction the the night of the 16th inst., four volunteers with
                        same, though allowing the delegates to meet pyroxyline bombs blew up a
                        Chinese building privately. The Government forbade the news on the Russian
                        left, which was occupied by 25 papers to mention the matter. The delegates
                        Japanese. The latter were all killed or wounded, met last Saturday
                        privately, and adopted and were buried in the debris. With this radical
                        resolutions demanding a constitution, exception, all is quiet in Manchuria.
                        (Reuter.) an elective legislative assembly, together with liberty of
                        conscience, press, speech, and educa (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PORT ARTHUR.</p>
                    <p>ERHLUNG-SHAN FORT.</p>
                    <p>tion.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904.</p>
                    <p>THE KHEDIVE</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is still on his estates at Mon- tazah.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been graciously pleased to bestow the following ranks on the
                        under mentioned officials:</p>
                    <p>Sanich Nicolas Sawaya Bey, ex-postmaster of Tantah.</p>
                    <p>Salissah Salib Nakhla Effendi, ex-chief accountant of the province of
                        Sharkieh, and Iskandar Khalil Effendi, ex-station-master at Suez</p>
                    <p>THE GREEK FLEET.</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAL AT PORT-SAID. have been made to welcome and entertain the Port Said,
                        Sunday. Great preparations where it is due to arrive to-morrow morning Greek
                        Squadron during its visit to Port Said, from Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>members being Messrs. Coroni, Roidis, Smyr A reception committee has been
                        formed, the niadis, Pneumaticos, and Kantaris.</p>
                    <p>According to the programme drawn up at Rabea: Maximos Youssef Effendi,
                        ex-chief present, on Monday evening Commodore Coun- accountant of the
                        province of Gharbieh. douriotis, his staff, and principal officer will be
                        officer (4th class) of the Imperial Order of the His Highness has conferred
                        the rank of entertained at dinner by Mr. Coroni. de bureau at the Alexandria
                        Post Office, and attended by the officers and men Medjidick on M. Giuseppe
                        di Giorgio, ex-chef celebrated at the Greek Church, which will be On Tuesday
                        morning a "Te Deum" will be the rank of Chevalier (5th class) on M.
                        Gio-banquet will be given to the Commodore and vanni.Cortessi, ex chet de
                        bureau at the Alex officers at the Continental Hotel in the evening, A grand
                        andria Post Office. eovers being laid for 100.</p>
                    <p>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS. The Council of Ministers, under the pre- sidency of H.
                        H. the Khediver will meet on Saturday afternoon at Abdeen Palace, to discuss
                        the provisions of next year's Budget. The modifications in the ranks of the
                        engineers in</p>
                    <p>The fleet may possibly leave on Wednesday or at the latest on Thursday. There
                        is a report the departure of the Greek Squadron, that the Russian Fleet will
                        not arrive till after</p>
                    <p>THE BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</p>
                    <p>Prince Humain Path</p>
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL PASSAGE. for Chino yosterday af</p>
                    <p>LIKELIHOOD OF ATTACK IN LOCAL</p>
                    <p>WATERS</p>
                    <p>We regret to of the Maldives locomotor ataxy</p>
                    <p>to this affiction. The readers are aw, father-in-law; Rabe lady of Suer last
                        year,</p>
                    <p>dan Bay,</p>
                    <p>Principe Camille Baapoli and Conte de la</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Sunday-It is now understood that the Baltic Fleet will reach Port
                        Said on Wednesday next at dawn. The Fleet, which is under the command of
                        Vice Admiral Volker Penne have left Naples on a trip to Egypt sahm, will
                        number 20 vessels, comprising 2 of the Volunteer Fleet, and 4 German
                        colliers Controller-General of the Port battleships, 2 cruisers, 7
                        destroyers, 5 steamers Bose Admiral Sir Matie supply of coal, water, and
                        provisions, suficient yesterday from Cairo. to carry them to the next port
                        of call. Arrangements have been made for a prompt Administration, and
                        Lady</p>
                    <p>KONG</p>
                    <p>During their stay at Port Said a police patrol will be drawn round the
                        vessels, defining Rembold, son of Sir Horace Rambold The St. James's Gazette
                        states the limit beyond which all unauthorised persons the composer of the
                        entr'acte music for will not be allowed. The Flute of Paa". week's
                        production in London of Milk Craigie's</p>
                    <p>The Canal authorities are quite confident that they can pass the fleet
                        through to Suer merchant traffic. Fleet without great hindrance to the
                        ordinary It is very necessary to emphatically deny</p>
                    <p>Port-Said, Monday. arrived at Port-Said about 10 o'clock this -The Greek</p>
                    <p>ghter Heary</p>
                    <p>The marriage of Mile Bea Ammy of M. and Mme Emin Anny Bey, to Guarino will
                        take place at the Church of the</p>
                    <p>the Ministry of Public Works will also be orning and saluted the port, the
                        salute being the ridiculous reports which have been Nativity, Bacos, on
                        Saturday next</p>
                    <p>LOCAL AND GENERAL. considered.</p>
                    <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the Ramleh and Moharrem Bey districts, on
                        the COUNTERSCARP OCCUPIED. 23rd inst. will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    <p>inst.</p>
                    <p>THE RUSSIAN SORTIE.</p>
                    <p>Arthur on the 19th inst.</p>
                    <p>A. L. M. &amp; D. S.-The next practice of the choral union of the A.L.M.
                        &amp; D.S. will take place at Kudolph's Asile on Friday at 6.30 p.m. BRITISH
                        RECREATION CLUB, CAIRO.-Parents who have not already done so are kindly
                        asked to send in names and ages of their children.</p>
                    <p>THE PILGRIMAGE-Dr. Hayes, of the Qua- rantine Service, has arrived at
                        Alexandria from Suez on important duty connected with the forthcoming
                        pilgrimage.</p>
                    <p>stalls in the. Zazinis Theatre for the coming OPERA SEASON.-The drawing for
                        boxes and operatic season will take place at the Khe- divial Bourse st 6.15
                        p.m. to-day.</p>
                    <p>HEDJAZ RAILWAY. Marshal Kiazim Pasha, director of the works of the Hedjar
                        Railway, has telegraphically communicated to the High Commission for that
                        line a summary of the contents of the chief engineer's report on the work
                        done during this report, the work is making good progress the past month,
                        beyond Maan. According to both as regards the earthworks and the build- ing
                        of bridges and tunnels. The boring of tunnels Nos. 1 and 5 is very shortly
                        to be taken in hand. Tunnel No. 2 has been bored, No. 3 has been commenced,
                        No. 4 is practically finished, and No. 6 is completely finished.</p>
                    <p>returned by the battery.</p>
                    <p>As soon as the vessels were signalled the Greek colony made holiday, and
                        assembled in thousands on the breakwater and along the Quai François Joseph,
                        to welcome their com patriots. Several crowded launches, on the largest of
                        which (the Ibis) was the reception committee and a band playing national
                        airs, went out to meet the ships and accompanied usual official calls were
                        paid. them to their moorings Shortly after, the</p>
                    <p>Greek flags and decorations are in evidence</p>
                    <p>circulated by mischiet-makers from time to time, respecting a probable attack
                        upon the Russian Fleet in Egyptian waters by the Japanese or their
                        emissaries, such having not the slightest foundation in fact.</p>
                    <p>official sources fixed the arrival of the fleet for Port Said, Monday. On
                        Sunday, last even the following Monday. A space on the Asiatic side of the
                        canal was cleared of all shipping, so that the nerves of the fleet might not
                        be un- everywhere, Port-Said possessing a large or other formidable craft.
                        Special pilots duly strained by the presence of felucas, barges, Greek
                        community. were also warned for duty. It is now reported that the Russian
                        Consal has advised the Canal Company officials that the fleet will not
                        arrive until Saturday next. It has struck more than one, that it is a good
                        deal safer for this fleet, composed as it is of old ships (barring the dan
                        troyers) to await the arrival in the Indian Ocean of the main fleet before
                        venturing past Aden alone.</p>
                    <p>GREEK FLEET LOTTERY.</p>
                    <p>The Hellenie Minister of Finance has sent 50,000 tickets to Egypt for the
                        Greek Fleet Lottery. It is believed that more than 100,000 tickets will be
                        taken in Egypt</p>
                    <p>TORIO, November 21., The Japanese mined and occupied the counterscarp of
                        Erhlung-shan Fort on the 19th (Heuter.) SHEIKH BARGHUT. TOKIO, November 21..
                        The Japanese have mined and occupied, the THE SANGANEB REEF. counterscarp of
                        Erblung-shan Fort at Port ward of Sheikh Barghut harbour, and it is The
                        Sanganeb reef. lies about 13 miles east- MOTORS FOR EGYPT. (Havas.)
                        essential that a lighthouse should be erected Prince Djemil Toussoun has
                        ordered a LONDON, November 21.. on this reef, if Sheikh Barghut is to be the
                        double phaston body, to be sent to Egypt for The Daily Telegraph understands
                        from chiet harbour on the Egyptian side of the Red his Panhard "chassis,"
                        from Botiaux, of be Shanghai that a steamer from Chi-tu reports andra last
                        night and inspected the Bab-elton have decided, therefore, to erect a light-
                        THE RAILWAY COMMISSION arrived at Alex Sea. The Ports and Lagushouses
                        Administra-vallois. the news that four Russian destroyers, incluuhedid
                        station this morning. It is expected house on the southern portion of the
                        reef. It eight, horse power three-cylinder Panhard Comte Michel de Zogheb
                        has purchased an ing the Rastorpny, carrying identical des patches, left
                        Port Arthur at the same time, the quays will be visited this afternoon. is
                        to be an open iron-work tower and the height sutomobile, with landaulet body
                        by Labour The Japanese stopped two. The fate of the of the focal time above
                        high water will be 165 dette. feet. The light is to be of the first order,
                        showing third is unknown. Their orders were to deliver all round. The type
                        of lamp is to be petroleum the despatches at Chi-fu at any cost. (Reuter)
                        barung. Quarters for four hightkeepers are to JAPS SEIZE GERMAN STEAMER.
                        Tokio, November 21. The Japanese have seized and taken to marez returued
                        from Cairo yesterday. A Mal- SUPREME CONSULAR COURT-Judge de Saus- CATTLE
                        EXPORTS, TO EGYPT. Sasebo the German steamer Batelan, whichse maintenance
                        case was heard before him Our Constantinople Correspondent states was waking
                        for Port Arthur with a cargo of this morning in the Supreme Consular
                        Court..that the reason why the Ottoman Government water clothing, blankets,
                        medicines, and has decided to temporarily prohibit the export corned beef.
                        The captain declared that the Jael was bound for Nighwang (Heuter. THE
                        BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>OUTRAGES AT CANEA.</p>
                    <p>OFFICERS AND MEN RUN AMOK</p>
                    <p>The ASILE RUDOLPH gratefully acknowledges with thanks the receipt of a
                        quantity of bread and sandwiches for the use of the poor from Messrs. Walker
                        and Meimarachi, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>be constructed.</p>
                    <p>PUBLIC WORKS</p>
                    <p>the Suez Canal, the London Morning Pt Referring to the passage of the ships
                        through</p>
                    <p>says</p>
                    <p>Lady Low has arrived at the Grand Con tinental Hotel, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Marquis Salvago-Raggi amived at Cairo on Sunday from Italy.</p>
                    <p>yesterday. Dr. Leigh Canney left Cairo for Assousn</p>
                    <p>Chitty Bey, Director-General of Customs on business connected with his
                        Administration, left Alexandria yesterday afternoon for Cairo,</p>
                    <p>Drs. Ward R. F. Campbell and Takvorian Arshag have been authorised to
                        exercise their profession in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will short- ly take place, between Misa
                        Bother Kamer and Mr. Henry Margosches, of Cairo</p>
                    <p>Mr. Carl Otto Montan, Judge at the Mixed transferred in the same capacity to
                        the Alex Tribunal of 1st Instance, Mansourah, has been andria Mixed Tribunal
                        of 1st Instance.</p>
                    <p>OMDEH MURDERED Tahta, November 20. The omdeh of El-Agbanneh, a wealthy</p>
                    <p>Russian Baltic Fleet, of which there are now a Egyptian authorities to permit
                        vessels of the In regard to the reported resolution of the number off Crete
                        or approaching the Levant, to take provisions and coal at Port Said suffi-
                        cient to "enable them to reach the next port," man, held in high esteem in
                        Tahta district, it is to be remarked that this is wholly at while on his way
                        home on the evening of the variance with the Suez Canal regulations. The
                        first 18th inst, accompanied by another omdel The adjudication of 1st
                        instant-relative to the annual works of repairing, etc., to be three clauses
                        of those regulations relate to the and the sarraf of El-Aghannah, was
                        sudden- carried out in the canals and drains of the passage of men of war in
                        what may be termed y accosted by three armed men. They Behera province has
                        been approved in favour the question of such warships' stay in the Cand
                        Tema, where he had been attending ordinary circumstances. The next three
                        bear on met him nearly half way between his village of the following
                        contractors :- Markaz. an assembly, presided over by the police nal. But the
                        seventh clause expressly provides Abou-Hommos, Mohamed El-Mahallawi 2,930
                        shall embark "warlike stores, supplies, or equip rushed towards the omdeh
                        and stabbed him in that no vessel belonging to a belligerent Power officer.
                        One of the three armed men, STABBING AFFRAY-in the course of a brawl of
                        cattle to Egypt owing to the enormous Kafr El-Dawar Mohamed El-Maballawi
                        2,150 ment" in the Suez Canal or "any of its ports the face. His: two
                        companions were threatened known afterwards to be Bakit Hassein, between
                        four natives in a coffee shop in Mo-rise in the price of seat consequent on
                        these harrem Bey yesterday, two were seriously exports, especially in the
                        vilayet of Aidin. stabbed. They were conveyed to hospital, and the two
                        others arrested.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</p>
                    <p>GAMBLING HELL RAID. The Alexandria The Khedive has been most graciously</p>
                    <p>Rosetta... Assad Hanna...</p>
                    <p>Damanhour... Attia El Sayed Chibrakhit... Attia El Sayed... Hoche Issa...
                        Saied Khalil.. Teh El Baroud Aly Ghonem... Kom Hamada Aly Ghonem.....</p>
                    <p>LE</p>
                    <p>3,090 of access," meaning Port Said or Suez, and</p>
                    <p>2,260</p>
                    <p>3,922 perhaps Ismailia. Obviously the Suez Canal with the same fate should
                        they utter any ery 4,440 authorities will infringe their own regulations or
                        give help. One of the two companions knew in adopting the course towards the
                        Baltic the first assailant by name and, being unarmed, 3,200 Fleet which
                        they are reported to have in con- the last. The first blow he received clean
                        alieed both took to their heels. The victim resisted to ... 3,280
                        templation. As for Egyptian ports other than off his nose, the second out
                        away four fingers,</p>
                    <p>police, with the aid of the Hellenje Consulate,pleased to approve of the
                        following promotions, Khatatbah... Mustapha Azmi...... 1,003 those of access
                        to the Saez Canal, they are the last broke his skull. The post-mortem</p>
                    <p>made a raid on a gambung-bell in Nubar Pasha-street on Sunday night and
                        arrested the owner, the cards and money being seized.</p>
                    <p>HOSPITAL SUPPLIES The adjudication for</p>
                    <p>the supply of provisions to the Kasr el-Aini Hospital, the infectious
                        diseases hospital, and the lunatic asylum, not having given satis factory
                        results, it will be renewed on the 10th</p>
                    <p>FIVE PERSONS MURDERED. December next.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>The Daily Expres learns from Cabes that</p>
                    <p>tron dates stated:-</p>
                    <p>Local Kaimakam St. C. M. G. MacEwen Bey, Sudan Civil Administration, to be
                        Kaimakam, 2-7-04</p>
                    <p>Officer for Supplies, Sudan South, to be Kai El Bimbashi H. G. A. Garsia,
                        D.S.O., Staff</p>
                    <p>makam, 1-10-4.</p>
                    <p>to be Local Kaimakam, 1-11-04. El Bimbashi S. L. Cummins, Medical Corps,</p>
                    <p>THEFTS AT LUXOR</p>
                    <p>covered by another regulation which prohibits SILVAIN IN CAIRO any
                        belligerent resorting to any such Egyptian ten serious blows before he was
                        slain. examination shows that the victim received Papa Lebonnard is not a
                        great drama, but port or roadstead for the purpose of obtaining it was
                        admirably performed on Saturday night, any facilities for warlike
                        equipment." If The ghaffir belonging to the victim's owa house gave the
                        veteran actor, M. Silvain, a it will be impracticable for the Baltic Fleet
                        to but he had slackened pace and could not keep at the Khedivial Opera
                        House, Cairo, when the Egypt chooses to enforce her own regulations village
                        was in Tama together with the omdeh very warm welcome. Comparisons are
                        always coal in her waters, and it is above all to be up with his master.
                        When he did reach the odious, especially when two such different borne in
                        mind that the intention of the law is spot where the victim lay, he found
                        him dead schools of acting as those represented by Mnot in any case that
                        coal should be supplied and saw Bakit Hassanein erasing the canal Coquelin
                        Ainé and M. Silvain are discussed, wherewith to continue the voyage Eastward
                        in with two other men unknown to him.</p>
                    <p>but the difference in the style of the two men hostile expedition against a
                        Power friendly News of the occurrence reached here, and is very remarkable.
                        M. Silvain is a master of to Egypt, but to enable the vessels to reach Hilmy
                        Bey Issa, the Substitut du Parquet, EGYPTIAN STATE RAILWAYS-The Board of In
                        the course of his recent lecture at the declamation, his utterance of verse
                        always ore the nearest Russian port. The expedition is together with the
                        medical inspector, proceeded Administration informs us that, from Thursday,
                        Egyptian Institute on the discoveries at Karritundo, and his interpretation
                        of the title role bound away from, not towards, its own coun- to the spot.
                        They were joined by the Ing- daily to No. 5 train leaving Shellal for Luxor
                        petrated at Luxor. The inspector of the Aati seems to us to exaggerate a
                        little the human Russia among the Powers which may have the An inquiry was
                        opened, and Bakit Hassanein, 1st proximo, a dining car will be attached nak,
                        M. G. Legrain dealt with the theft per- is thoroughly human, but in Louis he
                        try's shores. Egypt appears to be classed by pector for the Interior and the
                        Bab Moudir. at 9.10 am, and to No. 6 train leaving quities Service informed
                        his hearers that; weakness of the king threatened by the dagger will but
                        have not the strength to refuse aid, the suspected perpetrator of the crime,
                        has nxor for Sheilal at 10 am. thanks to the mossures taken, the two fine of
                        Nemours. It is possible to argue that in though it should constitute a
                        breach of been arrested. statues had been recovered. The thieves were this
                        moment the king is only a frightened ani- neutrality. But there is a Power
                        that stands run to earth and punished. All had been pre mal, but it is
                        equally permissible to contend behind Egypt, and that Power has given proof
                        district as a most brutal character. He has The man arrested is known
                        throughout the MENAGERIR-The stay of Masserini's Mena: meditated in this
                        theft, and it was within their that even in such a moment of terror and dis
                        of its resolve that neutrality shall be observed; been brought several times
                        before the Courts (Reuter)gerie at Alexandria is, drawing to a close. No
                        knowledge who had paid the thieves £10 to carry may certain relics of the
                        kingly dignity would therefore the Japanese will take leave to doubt for
                        crime. one should miss seeing the serpentine dance, it out. The speaker
                        hoped that the Antiquities still enable Louis to present a more royal front
                        if the intention with which the Suez Canal executed by Mme Masserini in the
                        midst of Service would receive a certain amount of to his foe. a group of
                        lions. In other respects, also, the support from the native judges in the
                        adequate Company is credited will be carried out. show is well worth a
                        visit. punishuient of antiquity thieves.</p>
                    <p>some of the officers and men of the Baltic Fleet have roamed the streets of
                        the town in a state of wild.intoxication, insulting and assaulting the
                        inhabitants. During the drunken brawls, they murdered at least five persons.
                        Forty Russians have-deserted.</p>
                    <p>OUTRAGE ON HUNGARIAN PREMIER, ASSAILED WITH SNOWBALLS.</p>
                    <p>November 21.</p>
                    <p>ALBAMBRA THEATRE- The Castellano Ita- Count Tian, the Hungarias Premier,
                        whilst lian opars company commenced its return visit leaving a meeting at
                        which he had justified the on Saturday with Manon Lescaut, which was policy
                        of the Government, was received by a fully produced, as also were Hamlet ou
                        noisy crowd with cries of "Resign." He was Sunday and Gioconda laat night.
                        This evening ated with snowballs. The police dispersed Un Ballo in Maschera
                        will be given. the crowd with blank cartridges, and arrested forty
                        persons.</p>
                    <p>(Heuter)</p>
                    <p>DEVASTATING BORF. 30,000 PEOPLE HOMELESS</p>
                    <p>BATAVIA, November 21.</p>
                    <p>DELTA LIGHT BAILWAY. The committee of the London Stock Exchange has ordered
                        the following security to be quoted in the official List Egyptian Delta
                        Light Railways Com pang, further issue of £107,000 4. percent Debentures of
                        £100 each, Non, 3531 to 4,600</p>
                    <p>COTTON KING SOLD UP</p>
                    <p>It is not precisely that Japan apprehends danger from the continuance of the
                        voyage of The office furniture of Mr. Sully, the great the Baltic Squadrons,
                        or their possible reunion KORDOFAN TRADING COMPANY, LTD. York last week in
                        connection with his bank but because it would form &amp; bad precedent
                        cotton speculator, was sold by auction at Newsone Armada somewhere south of
                        the equator, This company has been registered with a ruptcy. It realised
                        only £1,580, although it were the Suez Canal to be made the scene of a
                        capital of £8,100 in 6,000 shares of £1 each must have cost twice as much.
                        and 2,000 shares of Is each, to carry on in the United Kingdom and in Egypt,
                        Kordofan, and the neighbouring provinces, or in any part of Africa, the
                        business of general mer chants, traders in, and purchasers of ivory, ostrich
                        feathers, rubber and other products, import and export merchants, etc. The
                        office of the company is at 46, Leadenhall street, London, C.E.</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE-The No-</p>
                    <p>GHEZIREH PALACE</p>
                    <p>ALDERSON'S GARDEN, BULKELEY.</p>
                    <p>GRAND VARMETY ENTERTAN Be Tis ROYAL TOOKEY FAMILY. CHEVALIER J. ODRESS Magle
                        Concluding with the Coach "THE BRIGANDS"</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable least attention. It would be nearer
                        the mark, Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the perhaps, if the vivid imagination
                        of Russian Central position. Under English management. spectacle of vast
                        fleets of Chinese junks men of war's men should prepare them for the
                        81-11.004</p>
                    <p>gross infringement of the obligations imposed on neutrals is impossible to
                        say what inter- national difficulties might not arise were the door to be
                        opened to systematic infraction of Shepheard's Hotel have decided, owing to
                        the observance of neutrality; &amp; Power like Egypt The inanagement of
                        Ghesireh Palace and the privileges which, in virtue of a strict large number
                        of applications for zooms, to enjoys. The idea of an organised attack by
                        re-open the Ghezireh Palace on December 13 Japanese desperadoes, if such
                        individuals are made at Ghezireh. The west balcony has been ships during
                        their passage through the famous We hear that many improvements have been to
                        be found in this heinisphere, on the Russian enlarged, and nothing has been
                        spared to make gyptian waterway is too absurd to merit the the park worthy
                        of its world-wide reputation. ATTEMPTED MURDER A Greek (local subject) A new
                        Trigane orchestra of, 12 performers, A bore has devastated the Taloet
                        archipelago fired at and seriously wounded a compatriot in vember issue of
                        the monthly Bulletin of the one of the best which Budapest possesses, has
                        Thirty thousand people are homeless. (H.) the Mir Ganeh quarter of
                        Alexandria. The British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt is, as been engaged by
                        the general management or would be murderer, on being arrested, stated
                        usual, full of interesting information. The both hotels for the season. that
                        he had fired in self-defence as his victim contenta include extracts from a
                        paper on PARTNER WANTED well-edited had attempted to kill him. No hope is
                        enter moisture in cotton and cotton yarn, re narrow Eastern channels-the
                        Straits of Sunda and with business ability, to establish tained of the
                        latter's recovery. cently read before the New England Cotton or the Formosa
                        Channel as. examples with The 8. 8. Bolders, of the Westcott and Japanese
                        torpedo craft dashing, forth from - semi-professional and wholesale business
                        Maiifacturers Association, summaries of the Laurance Line, left Malta
                        yesterday and is behind the shelter this afforded and sinking in Alexandris
                        and absquently in Cairo: VERDE THEATRE, CAIRO. The alterations consular
                        reports ised by H.M.'s representa due here on Friday with general cargo,
                        from their foes right and left. branch of London House, tapital required.
                        The Russians could £1,500, of which advertiser, who is the made in the Verdi
                        Theatre were completed tives at Alexandria, Port Said, and Sues and many
                        London. principal of a large and well-known London resterday, and the house
                        should now be perseful remarks and feofa in regard to exports, Japanese the
                        original idea as derived from the only thank themselves for having given the
                        BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER Firm, Will contribute share. Business will
                        feetly, secure against all danger of fire. The cotton, cotton seed, beans,
                        freights, company phantoms of the North Se be thoroughly taught. English
                        language Italian opera company now performing at the meetings, Egyptian
                        imports, traffic on the Mah necely. Write for appointment to Abbas Helmy
                        Theatre will go up to Cairo mondieh Canal, contracts, counie of exchange Mr.
                        F. Davidson, Hotel Abbate. shortly and give a series of performances there
                        stocks and shares, coal imports, dividends and 24920-24-2 till the end of
                        February reports, conversion tables, etc.</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman 8.8. Ararat sailed from Malta on Monday, and is due here with
                        passengers mails, and general cargo on Friday morning. The Khedivial Mail 8.
                        8. Prince Abbas will leave Alexandria on Wednesday, for Pir Smyrna,
                        Mitylene, and Constantinople..</p>
                    <p>Mocking the passage of the squadrons through EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round, ELECTRIC LIGHTLIFT.-BODERATE CHARGIN</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CRUISER AT SUEZ Sues Thesday-The British cruiser Fhe PL has arrived
                        here from Trinhomall</p>
                </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p4.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>
                    
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Par contre il y a hausse de l'Anglo Ame- rican Nile à 5 3/8, des Eaux
                            d'Alexandrie à 17, Le nombre de traites annuellement pro-des Eaux du
                            Caire à 1100 et des Privilégiées testées au tribunal d'Alexandrie est de
                            Tramways à 147 1/2. 2,500 à 8,000, sans compter les effets pro- testés
                            aux divers consulats de la ville et au tribunal indigène. Sur ce
                            chiffre, deux cents traites seulement ont des suites en justice et le
                            nombre de poursuites en décla ration de faillite est bien plus faible
                            encore 14 novembre Indreasmha; vap. ang. de New-York p. Manills Pourquoi
                            dons cette habitude de 1.isser Le paquebot Sénégal de la Cie Messageries
                            Fri: vap. norv. de New-York p. Java protester des billets qu'on a
                            l'intention de Maritimes arrivé hier de Marseille avait à bord:
                            Britannia; vep. ang. de Sydney p. Londres payer ensuite? Le motif en est
                            bien simpl Mme Campana et fils, M. Hancel, Mme et rnia; vag. ang. de
                            Bombay p. Marseille Yes kinoor; vep. ang de Kuarachee p. P. 8. po. at
                            les commerçants qui sont à court d'ar- Mlle Linant de Bellefonds, Mme
                            Reboul, Mlan Cumming; vap. ang. de Chittagong p. Londres gest le
                            comprendront tout de suite. Les R. G. André, M. Raybaud, Mile Mariatte,
                            M.Zold; vap. ott. de Constantinople p. Djeddah formalités du protét.
                            sont fort longues; sor Gison, Mlle Rougier, M. Backer, M. P. Vlasto,
                            Camaran; yap.ott. de Constantinople p. Camovan enregistrement, son
                            retrait par la Banqu M. Pergentin, Lieut. Col. Campbell, Mlle Maud
                            Nabis; vap, ang, de Caloauts p Londres chargée de l'encaissement, son
                            envos aux Smith, Mile Kingsford, Mile Hansard, M. Meltokefala; vap. all.
                            de Karmobee p. Hambourg fabricants d'Europe, son renvoi par eni à
                            d'Astagne, Mile M. N. Hainworth, M. Boulinier, Beckenham; vap ang. de
                            Calmans pene Botterdam leurs représentante ou à leurs avocats en Mile
                            Poster, Mme Sivade et fillette, Mme Knight Bachelor; vap, aug. de
                            Calcutta p. Hall Egypte, le temps que ceux-ci metient paret fillette, M.
                            Azzi, Mlle Brantis, M. de Debourg, Mme Pillafort, Mme J. de Zogheb Fes.
                            4,405,088.04. fois à encaisser, tout cela prend souvent la Boaglise, M:
                            et Mme Brissac, M. de Historia; vap. ang. de Calentia pour Londres
                            jusqu'à six mois. On comprendía que pou Peretti, Mme Fleurent, M. et Mme
                            Pangalo, City of Asbens; vap. ang. de Liverpool p. Calcutta un négociant
                            ayant besoin de disponibiMme Atkinson, Capt. D. G. Poole, M. Tousoby
                            lusvep. all. de Breuen pour Yokohams lités le moyen le plus économique
                            d'essaint Caneri, Mme Mathieu, M. J. Aghion, M. Kaighs Erant; vag ang de
                            Calents pone Hall Clan Fraser; vap ang. de Maire pour Londres avoir à sa
                            di-position est de laisser pro- Sacazan, M. et Mme J. Aghion, fillette
                            et gou- Ehrenfels; vap. all. de Calenta pur Hambourg tester ses traites:
                            Moyennant 58-P.T. dvernante, M. Pados bey, Hon. Reginald Walsh, Assas:
                            vap. sag de Karesches pour Bickoshesd protat et quelques menus frais, il
                            opère M., Mme et Miles Jackse, M. et Mme Chakour City of Visnns; vap.
                            ang. Liverpool pour Bombay pendant des mois sur des sommes de 10 bey et
                            enfants, Mme B. Gandur, M. A.Tawil, M. Berwick Castle; vap. ang. de
                            Calenta p Hambourg 200 livres qui, s'il eft du les emprunter, G.
                            Gauthier, Mme H. Ebrard, M. et Mme Jullien, Aspern: vapaase. d'Aden pone
                            Pola lai eussent euáté un intérês bien supésars Hinmanuel, Gertrude,
                            Marie, Henriette, Kank; vap, norv. d'Emden pour Kianteshao rieur... M.
                            J. W. Hogg, M. et Mme Ancelin et enfant, Umberto I; vap, ital. de Gènes
                            pour Ma swal doambawa: vap. hoil d'Amsterdam pode Batavis Voilà pourquoi
                            des négociants égyptiene M. et Mme J. Keill, Mile C. Fourlany, Mile R.
                            Bergedorf; vap. allem d'Adelaide pour Ma-seille continueront à laisser
                            protester leurs trai-A. Work, Mile M. E. Moore, M. Osmond, M. Nordbora
                            vap dancia de Glass pou Kurmohes tes et qu'il n'y a pas lieu, pur les
                            fortes et Mme Borghetti, M. Lahlo, M. Binshiman, Fr. 4,817,900.60.
                            sommes du moins, de réduire le prix du M. Senli, M. Tabat, M. Davet, M.
                            Marulli, M. protét. Pavaron, Mme Trompette, M. P. Gonot, M. E Abel, M.
                            G. Hiertz, M. et Mme Avon, Père
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        15 novembre
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Nourrit, M. Jacob, M. Beller, et 35 passagers STOCKS AND SHARES
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        de 3me et 4me classe,
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Municipalité d'Alexandrie
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        AVIS
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        dea. teresis des Fortifiestions par 1 ts de 400 &amp; Is Porte
                            Roseste, d'ans quantité de pierres extraites 10rma Les sahateirs devront
                            payer le drois d'en chère de 1 0/0 et époser le 10 0/0 de is valene de
                            marchandise aché an moment de la vente et mer le paiement intégral &amp;
                            là Caises Mani aipale, le lendemain. da jur de l'adja lination.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Shares 418 518 24 1/8 For. 483
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        New-York: coton simér.: Fatars jan: :, manque, mai:
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        GRADIES DE COTON. Récolte nouelle: On n'a pro-qne rien fait dane toate
                            l'après midi, mais la dose est restée forme par suite du tanque de
                            vendeurs.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        5,40:
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour for-mare P.T. 61-/--/ pins bas
                            pour fv.-mare P.T. 60 85/40&amp;-- Dans l'après-midi, prix plus hant
                            pour février murs P.T. 81 -/- plae bas pour février-ses P.T. 61-1--1-
                            N.B.-Les autres livraisons syee reports irréguliers. FaVES-SAIDL Récolte
                            actuelle: Marché nal. Alexandrie, le 31 novembre 1904.
                    </p>
                </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p5.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CANAL DE SUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Par contre il y a hausse de l'Anglo Ame- rican Nile à 5 3/8, des Eaux
                        d'Alexandrie à 17, Le nombre de traites annuellement pro-des Eaux du Caire à
                        1100 et des Privilégiées testées au tribunal d'Alexandrie est de Tramways à
                        147 1/2. 2,500 à 8,000, sans compter les effets pro- testés aux divers
                        consulats de la ville et au tribunal indigène. Sur ce chiffre, deux cents
                        traites seulement ont des suites en justice et le nombre de poursuites en
                        décla ration de faillite est bien plus faible encore 14 novembre Indreasmha;
                        vap. ang. de New-York p. Manills Pourquoi dons cette habitude de 1.isser Le
                        paquebot Sénégal de la Cie Messageries Fri: vap. norv. de New-York p. Java
                        protester des billets qu'on a l'intention de Maritimes arrivé hier de
                        Marseille avait à bord: Britannia; vep. ang. de Sydney p. Londres payer
                        ensuite? Le motif en est bien simpl Mme Campana et fils, M. Hancel, Mme et
                        rnia; vag. ang. de Bombay p. Marseille Yes kinoor; vep. ang de Kuarachee p.
                        P. 8. po. at les commerçants qui sont à court d'ar- Mlle Linant de
                        Bellefonds, Mme Reboul, Mlan Cumming; vap. ang. de Chittagong p. Londres
                        gest le comprendront tout de suite. Les R. G. André, M. Raybaud, Mile
                        Mariatte, M.Zold; vap. ott. de Constantinople p. Djeddah formalités du
                        protét. sont fort longues; sor Gison, Mlle Rougier, M. Backer, M. P. Vlasto,
                        Camaran; yap.ott. de Constantinople p. Camovan enregistrement, son retrait
                        par la Banqu M. Pergentin, Lieut. Col. Campbell, Mlle Maud Nabis; vap, ang,
                        de Caloauts p Londres chargée de l'encaissement, son envos aux Smith, Mile
                        Kingsford, Mile Hansard, M. Meltokefala; vap. all. de Karmobee p. Hambourg
                        fabricants d'Europe, son renvoi par eni à d'Astagne, Mile M. N. Hainworth,
                        M. Boulinier, Beckenham; vap ang. de Calmans pene Botterdam leurs
                        représentante ou à leurs avocats en Mile Poster, Mme Sivade et fillette, Mme
                        Knight Bachelor; vap, aug. de Calcutta p. Hall Egypte, le temps que ceux-ci
                        metient paret fillette, M. Azzi, Mlle Brantis, M. de Debourg, Mme Pillafort,
                        Mme J. de Zogheb Fes. 4,405,088.04. fois à encaisser, tout cela prend
                        souvent la Boaglise, M: et Mme Brissac, M. de Historia; vap. ang. de
                        Calentia pour Londres jusqu'à six mois. On comprendía que pou Peretti, Mme
                        Fleurent, M. et Mme Pangalo, City of Asbens; vap. ang. de Liverpool p.
                        Calcutta un négociant ayant besoin de disponibiMme Atkinson, Capt. D. G.
                        Poole, M. Tousoby lusvep. all. de Breuen pour Yokohams lités le moyen le
                        plus économique d'essaint Caneri, Mme Mathieu, M. J. Aghion, M. Kaighs
                        Erant; vag ang de Calents pone Hall Clan Fraser; vap ang. de Maire pour
                        Londres avoir à sa di-position est de laisser pro- Sacazan, M. et Mme J.
                        Aghion, fillette et gou- Ehrenfels; vap. all. de Calenta pur Hambourg tester
                        ses traites: Moyennant 58-P.T. dvernante, M. Pados bey, Hon. Reginald Walsh,
                        Assas: vap. sag de Karesches pour Bickoshesd protat et quelques menus frais,
                        il opère M., Mme et Miles Jackse, M. et Mme Chakour City of Visnns; vap.
                        ang. Liverpool pour Bombay pendant des mois sur des sommes de 10 bey et
                        enfants, Mme B. Gandur, M. A.Tawil, M. Berwick Castle; vap. ang. de Calenta
                        p Hambourg 200 livres qui, s'il eft du les emprunter, G. Gauthier, Mme H.
                        Ebrard, M. et Mme Jullien, Aspern: vapaase. d'Aden pone Pola lai eussent
                        euáté un intérês bien supésars Hinmanuel, Gertrude, Marie, Henriette, Kank;
                        vap, norv. d'Emden pour Kianteshao rieur... M. J. W. Hogg, M. et Mme Ancelin
                        et enfant, Umberto I; vap, ital. de Gènes pour Ma swal doambawa: vap. hoil
                        d'Amsterdam pode Batavis Voilà pourquoi des négociants égyptiene M. et Mme
                        J. Keill, Mile C. Fourlany, Mile R. Bergedorf; vap. allem d'Adelaide pour
                        Ma-seille continueront à laisser protester leurs trai-A. Work, Mile M. E.
                        Moore, M. Osmond, M. Nordbora vap dancia de Glass pou Kurmohes tes et qu'il
                        n'y a pas lieu, pur les fortes et Mme Borghetti, M. Lahlo, M. Binshiman, Fr.
                        4,817,900.60. sommes du moins, de réduire le prix du M. Senli, M. Tabat, M.
                        Davet, M. Marulli, M. protét. Pavaron, Mme Trompette, M. P. Gonot, M. E
                        Abel, M. G. Hiertz, M. et Mme Avon, Père</p>
                    <p>15 novembre</p>
                    <p>Nourrit, M. Jacob, M. Beller, et 35 passagers STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>de 3me et 4me classe,</p>
                    <p>Municipalité d'Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>dea. teresis des Fortifiestions par 1 ts de 400 &amp; Is Porte Roseste, d'ans
                        quantité de pierres extraites 10rma Les sahateirs devront payer le drois
                        d'en chère de 1 0/0 et époser le 10 0/0 de is valene de marchandise aché an
                        moment de la vente et mer le paiement intégral &amp; là Caises Mani aipale,
                        le lendemain. da jur de l'adja lination.</p>
                    <p>Shares 418 518 24 1/8 For. 483</p>
                    <p>New-York: coton simér.: Fatars jan: :, manque, mai:</p>
                    <p>GRADIES DE COTON. Récolte nouelle: On n'a pro-qne rien fait dane toate
                        l'après midi, mais la dose est restée forme par suite du tanque de
                        vendeurs.</p>
                    <p>5,40:</p>
                    <p>Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour for-mare P.T. 61-/--/ pins bas pour
                        fv.-mare P.T. 60 85/40&amp;-- Dans l'après-midi, prix plus hant pour février
                        murs P.T. 81 -/- plae bas pour février-ses P.T. 61-1--1- N.B.-Les autres
                        livraisons syee reports irréguliers. FaVES-SAIDL Récolte actuelle: Marché
                        nal. Alexandrie, le 31 novembre 1904.</p>
                </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p6.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL, by the 8.8. Meeris, miled</p>
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS LIVERPOOL, November 21, 1.0 gm</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER, 22, 1904</p>
                    <p>A. &amp; J. MAIN &amp; Co., Ld., Glasgow.</p>
                    <p>CLYDESDALE IRONWORKS.</p>
                    <p>Structural Engineers.</p>
                    <p>Manfacturers of, ima and steel framed buildings, Agri- cultural sholding,
                        granarien Bungalows, etc. Iron fencing and mailing.</p>
                    <p>HELOUAN RAILWAY.</p>
                    <p>HORAIRE DES TRAINS A PARTIR DU 3 NOVEMBER. 1904 DEPARTS DE BAB-EL-LOUK</p>
                    <p>BOER</p>
                    <p>55</p>
                    <p>SIMPSON STRICKLAND &amp; Co., Dip... 6.50 8.05 9.10 110 12.10 1.15 2.10 3:10
                        4.10 5.15 6.15 7.15 8.30 10.10 12 39 7.45 9-10-11-12.55 1.50 3. 355 4 5.55
                        455 750 9.30 11. 1.20</p>
                    <p>LIMITED. DARTMOUTH. ENGINEERS, STEAM TACHT &amp; LAUNCH BUILDERS. SUITABLE
                        FOR THE NILE AND CANALS POR INFORMATION APPLY TO</p>
                    <p>Arr</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; XOLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Messrs. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin.</p>
                    <p>red and Port and OIL gr</p>
                    <p>Paten Tibbes-making 2</p>
                    <p>king Booktans</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Platt Brothers &amp; Co., Limited, Oldka. Messrs. John Fowler &amp;
                        Co., Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>the 6th November:</p>
                    <p>alm of the day</p>
                    <p>bales 8,000</p>
                    <p>-Peal &amp; Co..</p>
                    <p>974 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>400</p>
                    <p>Birds &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>850</p>
                    <p>Spot</p>
                    <p>Toriel es file,</p>
                    <p>107</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>8. Tawil,</p>
                    <p>407</p>
                    <p>American fatares</p>
                    <p>5.19</p>
                    <p>Bold &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>145</p>
                    <p>5.26</p>
                    <p>7.C.Baines&amp;Co.,.</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>6.28</p>
                    <p>B. &amp;0. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>Egyptian fally</p>
                    <p>X. Constantinidin,</p>
                    <p>(Nov.) (Dea.)</p>
                    <p>8 19/64 81/04</p>
                    <p>39613</p>
                    <p>Ms. W. E. KINGSFORD, SHARIA KASR-EL-NIL, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Barelli &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>Papopandalides fr</p>
                    <p>(Jan) 7 60,64 (March) 7 58/64</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 1,266</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Brown fair per lb.</p>
                    <p>G. Becken,</p>
                    <p>good f</p>
                    <p>(brown notinal 6/16</p>
                    <p>7. Andres,</p>
                    <p>good</p>
                    <p>J. Plante &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>fully good fair</p>
                    <p>G. Frange &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Beans new (per 480 lbs.) to 25/3</p>
                    <p>A. Arbib e figli,</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>H. bindernagel,</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>insole (December)</p>
                    <p>W. Gony &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>111</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Unified...</p>
                    <p>88 7/8 105-1/4</p>
                    <p>B. J. Conry &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>79</p>
                    <p>Privats Discount m bill</p>
                    <p>.8%</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd, 112</p>
                    <p>New-Yoax, November 21.</p>
                    <p>Carrer Beos.&amp; Coy. Lad, 1,459</p>
                    <p>Spot Coston...</p>
                    <p>10-</p>
                    <p>Bank of Egypt Lad,</p>
                    <p>74</p>
                    <p>Amerionn Futures</p>
                    <p>-9.59</p>
                    <p>Imp. Out. Bank,</p>
                    <p>169</p>
                    <p>9.70</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fender,</p>
                    <p>249</p>
                    <p>9.87</p>
                    <p>Moura Bros,</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>9.94</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 1/3</p>
                    <p>6,748 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>3,016 ardebs beans</p>
                    <p>1.000</p>
                    <p>260</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>162</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy, Lid,</p>
                    <p>Tedros Ghirghis &amp; Co., Anglo-Egyptian Bank Lod.</p>
                    <p>8. Taw,</p>
                    <p>B. Minoto, 1,628 ardebs beans, 908 boxes Private dissous (mansh bille)</p>
                    <p>oranges</p>
                    <p>Batterworth &amp; Balley, 317 bales ragas</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Lad, 48 bales wool</p>
                    <p>B: Beown &amp; Co., 10 packages mixed-manila roper</p>
                    <p>Fiz &amp; David, 176 angos ogge</p>
                    <p>B. Attal, 66 mese egge</p>
                    <p>G. M. Adei, 94 cases eggs</p>
                    <p>Bar Bilver (per os d.)</p>
                    <p>Jossan dayle reeipts Ports</p>
                    <p>69,000</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, November 21.</p>
                    <p>American fasares (December Jantiary)....</p>
                    <p>6.91</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>8%</p>
                    <p>27 1/16.</p>
                    <p>Jonsole (December)</p>
                    <p>88 8.8</p>
                    <p>Bio Tinto...</p>
                    
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>PARIO</p>
                    <p>PARMAN PLOW &amp; Tee DRY BAG Benass</p>
                    <p>LANGANO &amp; Cerise</p>
                    <p>DAVEY PAXMAN &amp; Co.'s Trip-Geared Engine given off a fall horse- Dynamon,
                        Motort and Mectric Machtpary of a power for one hour at 1 lbs. of fuel. At
                        the great trial of Com</p>
                    <p>deseriptions.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Chubb &amp; Son's</p>
                    <p>Lock &amp; Safe Company Limited Makere to the Bank of Hagland Chubb's soal
                        tes of all elses on hand. Building of Strong Booms undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Gee: Angus &amp; Co., Ltd. Machino balting of every descripilon anther,
                        rabber, hair, cotton and Balato Specialities 1-TANGYES OIL ENGINES, supplied
                        to the Government Administrations, and suitable for driving, pumping,
                        electrical installations, four mills, workshops, etc.</p>
                    <p>98 10 Tangyes' Marine Type Petrol Launch Engine which has won four first
                        prises open to the whole world-1903. Tangyes' Alcohol Engines up to 37
                        BHP.</p>
                    <p>28 15</p>
                    <p>13781</p>
                    <p>488 5/16</p>
                    <p>Escomptes-Parie 8, Londree 8, Berlin 5.</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>ORARY PRIOR PER TOR FARE ON WARDS</p>
                    <p>Best quality</p>
                    <p>Bethal</p>
                    <p>Cowryon</p>
                    <p>Dorlion</p>
                    <p>Tangyes' Suction Producer Plants for Driving Gas Engines. Telegraphie Addres:
                        GEER, OAINGINER, ALEXANDRIA." Works Office in town, Sharia Bab-El-Hadeed
                        (Calro),. Alexandria Ofee and Stores. Aba Dirdar S. No. 19</p>
                    <p>NOUVEAU REMEDE PURGATIF IDEAL</p>
                    <p>Conte: Constipation, Congestion, Hemorrhoides, Migraine, Obenite, . Conserve
                        le teins frais es la mille valse; d'ane effimisé abeolae agit ans douleurs.
                        Il out sonseillé par toutes les sommitée mées. Le pergatit le plus
                        dennemique.</p>
                    <p>PURGEN</p>
                    <p>Defodral so e UELBERG, barmion, Alexandria</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>Bhg. 1/1 19&amp;18 이 6,0</p>
                    <p>66</p>
                    <p>Cardig Howport</p>
                    <p>Per Ton Best quality</p>
                    <p>Shgs. Shgs. 24/24 6 23 6 24 18 186 18,3 18,6 18</p>
                    <p>18 6</p>
                    <p>Varions, 18 hoge 00, 48 packagee henna, 1,817 package wandries</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>Okefalos</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Woat Hor</p>
                    <p>Toartea...</p>
                    <p>Gesinae de acous</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL, by the 8.8. Roumelia, miled on</p>
                    <p>Beotak</p>
                    <p>18 3</p>
                    <p>Oignone</p>
                    <p>the 9th November 1</p>
                    <p>Bairde</p>
                    <p>A. Arbibi figli,</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>N. G. Casali,</p>
                    <p>Moursi Beos.</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>G. Rincken,</p>
                    <p>Yorkshire torpool</p>
                    <p>Doslogs Beat Hamilton B Michigbord</p>
                    <p>183 18 3</p>
                    <p>Nominal</p>
                    <p>LONDARE</p>
                    <p>Best Lasiathing</p>
                    <p>3. Bishes &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>fnd quality</p>
                    <p>Ofefales.. Tourmax Gaines Olgnens</p>
                    <p>1/1, 1/2 &amp; 18</p>
                    <p>8/6</p>
                    <p>Borond Lancashiri</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIE</p>
                    <p>Ascher</p>
                    <p>Orows</p>
                    <p>Stor</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>AGENTS IN EGYPT</p>
                        <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                        <p>Messrs. HASSABO BEY MAHOMED &amp; Co. Who have a big stock of engines and
                            boilers always on view. as Khedive's Street. (Telephone 995.)</p>
                        <p>CLEAN WALLS AND</p>
                        <p>23-11-904</p>
                        <p>WHITE CEILINGS</p>
                        <p>ARE ALWAYS POSSIBLE AT A MINIMUM COST, PROVIDED YOU USE</p>
                        <p>FRESKEL</p>
                        <p>(REGD.)</p>
                        <p>Credit Lyonnais THE GREAT SANITARY WATER PAINT.</p>
                        <p>Société Anomyise</p>
                        <p>Capital 960.000.000 de Francs</p>
                        <p>ANTIEREMENT VERSES</p>
                        <p>AGENCES DEGYPTE ALEXANDRIN-LE CAIRPORT-SAID</p>
                        <p>90-10/ L OBRNIT LYONNATS Sale toutes opérations de banque, telles que
                            :</p>
                        <p>(NANTES DUNKERQ Graines de eos. (Dankoges) Pr. (Na)...</p>
                        <p>MARSEILLE</p>
                        <p>DESTINATIONS. DIVERERS Opters Odeon, Talents, Van</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
</div></body></text></TEI>