<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Ryan Schefstad</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-09-29">September 9, 2023</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1904-11-21/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-21">Monday, November 21, 1904</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Peninsular & Oriental S. N Company. -->
                <div type="advert"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE</head>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>CORFAST, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>This Company's item of saltare graph cables the most direct and quickest of
                        conication from Egypt to Eampe, North and South America, East, South and
                        West Aries, India, Aptir New Zealand, Chine and Japar</p>
                    <p>To secure quick tration, telegrams should be marke Vid Eastern</p>
                    <p>For latest aerage time to London, set daily bulletin to</p>
                    <p>this paper.</p>
                    <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT A, Cairo, Sues, P Teek, Port-Said, Skin Head Office,
                        London.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>No. 7,051]</p>
                    <p>ALEXA YOBIA, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904.</p>
                    <p>[SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</p>
                    <p>THE EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>onits</p>
                    <p>Le. &amp; cfbles tégraphiques sous-marinis constitue le moyen de
                        communication le plus direct et le plus Egypte pour TEurope, TAmérique</p>
                    <p>du Nord et du Sad, Afrique orientale, méridionale occidentale, e Indes,
                        FAustralia: la Nouvelle-Zélande, Chine et le Japon</p>
                    <p>Pour carer ene t</p>
                    <p>rapide,</p>
                    <p>doivent porter Findication Via Eastern</p>
                    <p>Voir le tempe moyen</p>
                    <p>Londres a bulletin</p>
                    <p>STATIONS EN EGYPTE Part-T</p>
                    <p>le plus</p>
                    <p>Peninsular &amp; Oriental S. N Company. British India S. N. Company, Limited.
                        Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Coy.</p>
                    <p>The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the</p>
                    <p>MONGOLIA"</p>
                    <p>following dates:</p>
                    <p>MALACA</p>
                    <p>9,516 Tona 11 November 5,045</p>
                    <p>SUMATRA"</p>
                    <p>4,807</p>
                    <p>POCKANA</p>
                    <p>4,610</p>
                    <p>7,913</p>
                    <p>&amp;December</p>
                    <p>MATILA"</p>
                    <p>4.310</p>
                    <p>HARDINIA"</p>
                    <p>6676</p>
                    <p>23</p>
                    <p>MACEDONIA"</p>
                    <p>20,518</p>
                    <p>MARMORA</p>
                    <p>30,809</p>
                    <p>7,0</p>
                    <p>4,874</p>
                    <p>PRRA</p>
                    <p>SUNDA</p>
                    <p>Marelli, Plymouth and London Malts and London. Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Marion, Plymouth and London. Marseilles, Plymouth and London. Malta and
                        London,</p>
                    <p>Malts sod London.</p>
                    <p>Marseille, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>Marsel Jes, Pigmonth and London, Yarles and. London. Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Port-Said to London via Brindisi.</p>
                    <p>The BRINDISI atomer leaves POBT-BAID ser arrival of Indian Mail. Combined
                        steamer and sleeping one fare from PORT-BAID to LONDON vis BRINDISI or vis
                        MABSEILLES 25.9.11.</p>
                    <p>To the East</p>
                    <p>The Mail Beamers leave BUEZ for ADEN and BOMBAY every Wednesday, and for
                        AUSTRALIA and CHINA every sisarnase Wednesday. Aster leaves for CALCUTTA,
                        formighaly, and snosher for JAPAN. Pengers can embark sa PORT-BAID.</p>
                    <p>For all farther information apply to the Company's Agents, Mesars. Teos. Coon
                        &amp; Box (Rgypt) Lad....</p>
                    <p>GRoses BOTLE, Beq......</p>
                    <p>Morers. HASBLOWN &amp; Co....</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>PORT-BAID ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>/81-19-90</p>
                    <p>F. G. DAVIDSON, Superintendens P. &amp; O. 8.-N. Company in Bgypt BUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Orient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p>B.M.B. Orotava will leave Bass about Croya</p>
                    <p>Dea. Deo.</p>
                    <p>9</p>
                    <p>MAIL AND PASSENGER</p>
                    <p>Calling at Apass, Copenso Fry Service in OUTWARD-8.8. Muttra</p>
                    <p>SAILINGS FROM TEAM SHIPS. London and Calcutta Line.</p>
                    <p>Chief Omce: Sharia Boulae, Grand Continental Hotel Buildings Brack Offer
                        Uppite Savoy Hotel Daire Regular weekly Tourist Steamer Departures between
                        CAIRO and AssoUax by the following steamers :-</p>
                    <p>and Mapas Outward, and MaILLES (GEOL and PLYNOTE optional) Homeward. noction
                        with the Ce's Indian M Lines and monthly with the East African Mail Line
                        between Anay, Mom and ZAIDAL November 26- HOMEWARD: S.S. Mombassa Nov. 28
                        MAYFLOWER... PURITAN</p>
                    <p>Queensland Line of Steamers between London and Brisbane. MAYFLOWER...</p>
                    <p>Calling at Cosest, BATATA, CooTOWN, TOVILLE, Bows, and RocKRANTOR 8.8.
                        "ITIA," will mil from Bus or abous the 14th December. REMARKS-Bargets snd
                        Stews and Cargo booked Graff, Bast Afric Below</p>
                    <p>on board for paymen donmer in which shere</p>
                    <p>Aden</p>
                    <p>81.10 31.10</p>
                    <p>From Port Said :</p>
                    <p>Agents in LONDON, M Managing Agents in INDIA Agias PlanT SAID, PORT BAID Moms
                        Thos Cook For further</p>
                    <p>Amerions Ford to all Straits Setti Bomers Arolipelago, Fins and Becond Clase
                        Pre gers are allowed to break the voyage My LASS BAT OF PASSAGE MONEY</p>
                    <p>tropical elis</p>
                    <p>Two Thirds of a Clo Par</p>
                    <p>and Extraches.</p>
                    <p>CAIBO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>BYTS &amp; Co., Age, Bues. 81-13-904</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE, Limited.</p>
                    <p>(HENDERSON BROTHERS), LONDON, LIVERPOOL, AND GLASGOW. First class passenger
                        steamers,</p>
                    <p>1904</p>
                    <p>December 9th</p>
                    <p>281d 30th</p>
                    <p>VICTORIA PURITAN MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p>1905</p>
                    <p>Weekly SECOND CATARACT SERVICE by, the First Class Tourist Steamer "INDIANA"
                        AGENTS FOB PRINCIPAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANIES Through Bookinge to Khartoum
                        and Gondokare. RAILWAY TICKETS TO ALL PARTS OF EGYPT. FREIGHT SERVICE by
                        steam barges between ALEXANDRIA and CAIRO SAVOY HOTEL Elephantine island,
                        Asonas, Company's Property.</p>
                    <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.</p>
                    <p>Fortnightly Service from ALEXANDRIA Passengers and Freight). Commencing on
                        abe 16se of Noystube.</p>
                    <p>To NAPLES and MARSEILLES, with the Twinsrow-beloon zo Schleswig 7,100 ton)
                        leaving ALEXANDRIA every alemate Wednesday na 3 pm.: 18 &amp; 80 Nov., 14
                        Des., 11 Jan, a Jan., 8 Yok The following steamers are intended to leave
                        PORT SAID:</p>
                    <p>BONNWARD: for Bremen or Hamburg v NAPL, GOA, (GENNALTAR), SOUTHAMPTO</p>
                    <p>ZETEN</p>
                    <p>OLDENBURG</p>
                    <p>PRINU ALIUR 1091 BUKARABORT</p>
                    <p>Novem.</p>
                    <p>Pa. Ras, LAVDOLD BARKASUBBA PRAUSSEN</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD for China and Japan v Bu ADEN, UOLOMBO, PREANG, SINGAPORN</p>
                    <p>BUON</p>
                    <p>Booking Passengers and Cargo through to Porta in INDIA, EUROPE &amp; AMERICA
                        Sailings Fortnightly from Bues. For LONDON S.S. Bohemia Dec. 10 For CALCUTTA
                        S.S. Agria...... December 7 BRYDLITZ For MARSEILLES 16 ALIVERPOOL 8.8.
                        Marilia Nov. 24 For BOMBAY S.S. Circassia... Saloon Pares: from Port-Baid,
                        in Ghentar 49, Marsellen Liverpool (all rente) 815 London (all son rente)
                        413, Lendon November 26 BAYERN Marsellie 10 Pages embarking at Ismailie 21
                        mors et Soomers 1000 reduction allowed to of the Army of Opatient and
                        Government employs Through siekted to New-York (vil Gow). Fares on Agutta i
                        Oniro, Mars THOMAS COOK &amp; BON, Pans-id, Mars CORT BROTHERS &amp; 0, ta
                        For further partieniars of Freight or Page apply to G. BEYTS &amp; Co.,
                        Sues.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY B.M.B.
                        Ortona will leave. Pors-Bald about... Dée. 5 19</p>
                    <p>Oricaba</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>8.B-Homeward ouers are sometime before their advertised, dassa. Passengers
                        landed and embarked at Ismallia, Quarantine Regulations permitting, free of
                        an expense. Port-Bald to Naples..................... 1st Class; 411-nd
                        Clais, 47 8rd Class, &amp; 4 8 to Marseilles....</p>
                    <p>FARES</p>
                    <p>10 Gibraltar.***********</p>
                    <p>16 18.</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>81-18-006</p>
                    <p>10- MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>8 18-</p>
                    <p>Established 1888. Capital 41,000,000. Beserve Fund 4835,000.</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>ZIETAN</p>
                    <p>For Austraile BUNK</p>
                    <p>GNKISENAU</p>
                    <p>BRAIN</p>
                    <p>Dea</p>
                    <p>FKINDRICH D. GR. 1005</p>
                    <p>BREMEN</p>
                    <p>FOR FURTERE FABRIQUAM APPLE TO FER AGENTS OF SER NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD at
                        Caire, Alexandria, Part Sald and Suez. OTTO STERZING, AGT Caire, Oran
                        BDARE</p>
                    <p>C. H. SCHOELLES, AGENT IN ALEZARDNIA, Cleopatra Lase</p>
                    <p>M THOR 000 a BOL CARL STANENS BASTURBAU are thorised to sell bole CAIRO and
                        ALEXANDRIA 30-11-004</p>
                    <p>Elevur tickets no longer insted, bas pengers paying the fall, fee in one
                        direction are allowed on THE IMPO oad Burse, LONDON, Riebling 1008 Al Fando
                        Band 10,00,00 Co.,L. Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation.</p>
                    <p>to- Prymonth or Tilbury. sissemens of one-third of their fare beck if the
                        rern voyage be made within four months of arrival, or so sbasement of 20% af
                        rara voyage be made wishin six months of armval. Agents, Cairo-THOMAS COOK
                        &amp; Bow. Alexandra B. J. Moss &amp; Co. - For all information apply to Wm.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Port-Said and Port-Tewalk Suez), 81-13-904</p>
                    <p>BIBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>SPECIAL BEDUCED RATES DURING THE SUMARE SEASON.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS to GOLOMBO. TUTICORIN, to, and RANGOON b. Yor kahere is tons will
                        have Bues abou, November 28.</p>
                    <p>6.8 Warwickshire, toss, will leave suas abous December 7.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS MILLE and LONDON.</p>
                    <p>B. Worcestershire, 1,60 tons will leave Port-Baid about November 29.
                        Shropshire 7.0 will leave Port-bald abous Deco</p>
                    <p>FARES from tersid to Marsillee $12.6.0, London $17.0, bo 433.10.0, Rangoon,
                        437.19.0; Fitted with Refrigerators, Electric Light, Electric fans and all
                        recent improvemente Experienced Stewardesse and burgeons carried. Agente in
                        Cairo's Messre, Tao COOK &amp; SON For si particulars apply to W. STAPLEDON
                        &amp; SONS, Port-Bald &amp; Port-Tewak (sues).</p>
                    <p>81-18-906</p>
                    <p>81-13-904</p>
                    <p>1,-Old Street, 1808-Total exceed Polisis/ined a BUEZ by G. BEYTS &amp; Co.,
                        Agate.</p>
                    <p>22nd inst.</p>
                    <p>Deutsche Levante-Linie. Wying with Vien pres (re-senda</p>
                    <p>Mail and Passenger Beamships. Begur three-weakly Service froua HAMBURG, VIA
                        ANTWERP &amp; MASTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice ver, goods from all the
                        principal GERMAR BARWAY BRATORS on direst of Lading to ALEXANDRIA and all
                        the principal port of Berre, BrazIAN COAT, ., the favoumble through mise of
                        the DETROS VAR (bag).</p>
                    <p>EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>8.8. Siegfried, now on the berth loading will sail for Botterdam and Hamburg
                        on the S.S. Thasos now in port will sail for Beyrons on the 28rd inst.
                        Lesbos from Answerp will seil for Beyrout on the 28rd inst.</p>
                    <p>For ride and partediars apply to ADOLPHESTROSS, Alexandria,
                        Agent-18-9-905</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE. Messageries Maritimes.</p>
                    <p>FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Greed-Turkey' Line;</p>
                    <p>Express songs leave Alexandria every Wednesday 6p.m. for PIRBUS (Athens),
                        SMTSHA MITYLENE, and CONSTANTINOPLE. In sonadon with the Outers agrees
                        tants-de-luze for Belgrade, anos, Paris, and London,</p>
                    <p>Palestine-Syria Ligg</p>
                    <p>Futurs leave Alesandria every day p.m., and For Sold every Sunday at 8p.m.,
                        fo JAFTA (for Jertale), CALFYA (for Naresh), BETBOUT (for Dam), TRIPOLI,
                        ALEX ANDARTTA, MAKINA, onasing in alumna wesks to LARNACA and LIMARMOL
                        (Cyprus).</p>
                    <p>Red Sea Lind</p>
                    <p>Beamery leave Buen every Thursday spm for JRDDAR, alling alred TOR (for Mount
                        Steal and TAMBO, and sonstosing in aberse woks to BUAKIM, MARKOWAH, HODIDAH,
                        and ADEN.</p>
                    <p>H.B. Dock chairs provided for the ses of poengers, szalons saisins and table
                        wins tree. mer plans may be seen and page booked as the Company's Agmales at
                        Alexandria, Cairo, Pore Bad, and Bees or as Thos. Cook &amp; on or other
                        Touris Aganay</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>The Moss S.S. Company, Limited.</p>
                    <p>P LAVERPOOL ning si MALTA, O JAM MORU,, JB, Levers, MAARJ -7.M. &amp; BAA</p>
                    <p>Bacond glass 416 Retur</p>
                    <p>ummodation only,</p>
                    <p>Thrones</p>
                    <p>From Alossadria For Marsellles direct Friday 4 Nor, as noon Sinigal</p>
                    <p>Sallings from Antandria ta November, 1904,</p>
                    <p>Rate of panoge money</p>
                    <p>From Alexandria</p>
                    <p>To Naples</p>
                    <p>Wednesday</p>
                    <p>Cap. Vincensi Conge Galett Niger Portugal Rignier For Pot Bels Jaffa and
                        Bayreuts Nov. Conge Osp Galottl Portugal Riquier Conge Galet For Part Sald
                        and Beyrouth Wednesday Capt. Camngli Through Wckets for London vs Marsalles
                        (Unials Denys Senegal Vincenti Trough sekass Parts (vi Marellon return lekte
                        with the Arian Lloyd Oy,</p>
                    <p>Now</p>
                    <p>For Marsailles Direct:</p>
                    <p>To Part Ha To Jalta To Beyreath</p>
                    <p>1.18.10</p>
                    <p>-1.7.10</p>
                    <p>Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste Venice Line. Weekly Express Mail Bervice. Be
                        leave Alexandria every Barily at Brindis, arving Today morning in aime for
                        axpraece so Paris, London, Naples, prese Imly and Germany. No. 19 4pm.
                        Cleopatra Capt. A. Ivallich. " Semiramis Nov. 264 pm. Semiramis Ongs,
                        Marsinolieb. Marinoboh Deo. 8 Cleopatra Alexandria-Patras-Brindisi-Trieste
                        Line. Ivalligh Sommer lowres Alexandra os or about serd November, Tsh and
                        31st December, Far East Line.</p>
                    <p>from Bus) To Aden, Bombay, Colombo, Pang bama, Kobe about Dep. 5. To Aden and
                        Bobay</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Colombo, Madma, Rangoon and Onleata abos November 20.</p>
                    <p>East African Line.</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Morabam, Zanzibar, Batre, Dalagon Bay, Daban about December 4.</p>
                    <p>Syrian-Caramania Line.</p>
                    <p>Steamer leaves Alexandria on or about November 14 and $8, Decembar 13 and
                        96.</p>
                    <p>Syrian-Cyprus-Oaramanian Line.</p>
                    <p>Beamer avee Alexandria on or about November 31, Dececaber 5 and 19</p>
                    <p>For all, informaalom spply to the Company's Agros. And, Fore-ald and Bass,
                        Box, La., Laon Hassas, Oniro Agons, Saria Maghaky (Telephone 198), Onde
                        Tunaso, Helowan Special passage rates granted to Egyptian Government
                        officials, of the Army of Occupation and their families.</p>
                    <p>CUNARD LINE.</p>
                    <p>Trieste-New York. BLATONIA Sept. 80 LUCANIA... PANNONIA. Oes 14 CAMPANIA...
                        USTONIA... Nor. After t 16I 18 SLAVONIA... PANNONIA...</p>
                    <p>Gregort</p>
                    <p>returning from China Australia</p>
                    <p>Ballings from Port Said In November 1904. Probably on Thursday 10 Nov.
                        Salarie Bunday Dupl, Nigre Caledonien Sailings from Seas In November, 100%
                        19 Nov.</p>
                    <p>For Aden, Olombo, ingspers, Balgon, Hong-Kang, Shan- ghel, Robe and
                        Yokohama</p>
                    <p>Tamatave, La Bunten sod Manrie</p>
                    <p>Braint-Simone Cap Bourdon Schmita</p>
                    <p>ghal, Kobe and Yokohama</p>
                    <p>PRI</p>
                    <p>8,100 lot. 814 Bingia, 46 Bern, Rod Begle Hose &amp; Co., Aissandris, Agents
                        ous Babarday, November so be followed by BA SETI fork and her UA as be
                        bented us einaive of Railway fare through to and from Cairo. Partieslars on
                        application. -11-004</p>
                    <p>or Dinent, Aden, ah, Da-doares, its Marte, Tame La Banion and Maurice Hethay,
                        Oelembe, Fremantle, Adelaide, Mel- beros, Bydney and Nemes...</p>
                    <p>Gaire Agency</p>
                    <p>Wednesday 14. Thursday 1 Dec Monday Not. hopheard's Hetal.J</p>
                    <p>Melbourne X</p>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO.'s LINE.</p>
                    <p>Bleetris des</p>
                    <p>Base &amp; Pors-Said formigasly tur London or Liverpoos direes</p>
                    <p>BALOON (A) FARE $12.</p>
                    <p>8.8 AMARAPOORA 6600 Tone will leave PORT-BAID abons Nov. MARTABAN 780</p>
                    <p>#Kanooo</p>
                    <p>B060</p>
                    <p>97 for Liverpool.</p>
                    <p>9 for Liverpool,</p>
                    <p>25 for Liverpool.</p>
                    <p>Due in Leadun or Liverpool 18 days thereafter 6., Port de THOS. SOOK &amp;
                        SON. Kara L., 6. J. GRAGE &amp; B... Asdr</p>
                    <p>A WORMS</p>
                    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p>(ROYPT), LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE-LUDGATE CIRCUS-LONDON, CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE-CAIRO, near
                        SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL Alexandria, Port-Said, Ismailia, Suez, Luxor, Assouan,
                        Halfa &amp; Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>TOURIST AND GENERAL PASSENGER AGENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>Baggage and Forwarding Agents. NILE STEAMER SERVICES.</p>
                    <p>TOURIST SERVICE. The large and spendidly sp. pointed S.S. Rameses, will leave
                        Cairo on Tuesday, November 29th, for Luxor, Assouan and Phile. Other
                        sailings Dec. 6, 13, eto..</p>
                    <p>EXPRESS SERVICE-Steamers will leave Cairo</p>
                    <p>Rivière</p>
                    <p>PRINCE LINE.</p>
                    <p>7,100</p>
                    <p>Tons, 8,000 WELSH PRINUS.. BLAUK PRINCE 2,000 SPANISH PRINUS (idg 7,000
                        NORMAN PRINCE 4,000 GEORGIAN PRINC</p>
                    <p>APRICAN PRINCE TUDOR PRINCE SWEDISH PRINCS (big- CHINESE PRINGS - ITALIAN
                        PRINCE MERCHANT PRINUR BOLDIER PRINCR</p>
                    <p>4000 SAILOR PRINCE</p>
                    <p>400 RUNBLAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>MAXICAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>A HIGHLAND PRINCE</p>
                    <p>BICELIAN PRINCE-</p>
                    <p>BRITISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>GRBUIAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>URBOLE PRINU</p>
                    <p>SYRIAN PRINUR - INDIAN PRINUR TUBUAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>8700 NEAPOLITAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>KI MOURISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>AT KARTERN PRINUS 8,060 CASIN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Koto ORANGE PRINCE</p>
                    <p>17M BUTTISH PRINCS 1,879 LOURAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Tona 8,000APORAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>1,000 BAXON PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Tons</p>
                    <p>7,000 BURMESE PRINOR (bg)-</p>
                    <p>4710 180JAS PRINCE</p>
                    <p>4000 CROWN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>AMO SOYPTIAN PRINUS 400 SPARTAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>8,000 DMPERIAL PRINCE</p>
                    <p>A70 PERSIAS PRINOR KIM CASTELGIAN PRINO 3,060 AREATIO PRINCE 3,000 KAFFIR
                        PRINUR 57 CYPRIAN PRINCE BOTAL PRINUS</p>
                    <p>Good Accommodation for Passengers.</p>
                    <p>Liverpeal-New York</p>
                    <p>Liverpool-Beaton,</p>
                    <p>19,95 sons. UMBRIA 8,197 tops BAXON... 14,390 o 13,960 STRURIA... 8,119
                        13,564.</p>
                    <p>AUZANIA 7,598</p>
                    <p>18 Embarking passengers at the Riverside Railway</p>
                    <p>Ivana... 14,088 SYLVANIA.. 8,598</p>
                    <p>on Tuesdays and Saturdays.</p>
                    <p>Deession, Prince's songs, Lavertongh mos rom gypt inned by</p>
                    <p>the Agente suuANAUMI&amp;US, Alexandria; NICULAB KIRSIS, Ustro, B. BROADBENT,
                        Pore-Baldy</p>
                    <p>ELLERMAN LINES, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>CITY LINE.</p>
                    <p>MALTA, LONDON, COLOMBO &amp; CALCUTTA</p>
                    <p>CITY &amp; HALL LINES.</p>
                    <p>Joure ESIC TO MARSEILLES, LIVERPOOL, BOMBAY &amp; KARACHT.</p>
                    <p>The undermentionat First Class Ponger will be dispatched trom Port d'on or
                        shoot the following dates her Malta &amp; Landen 8.8, CITY OF BEANS Nov. 3
                        Liverpeel Celembe &amp; Caleutte S.S. CITY Catcurta Nov. Bombay &amp;
                        Kareahl Oro Loco Nov. 20 Nov, 20 Baker Fass-Fers Paid to Malle A Man Lendin
                        or UORY BROTHERS &amp; On, Ltd., Agents for the City Line, Port sald; W.
                        STAFLEDON &amp; Box, Agense for For further parents wel the Hall Line, Port
                        Said or to TROS COOR &amp; NOR (gypt, Ltd. Oxire,</p>
                    <p>36788-38-3-908</p>
                    <p>Navigation Generale Italienne.</p>
                    <p>Societes Reunies Florie-Rubattino. Services Postaux. Departs de Novembre. Les
                        Jendis 8, 10, 17 et 24 à 8h. p.m. direct pour Messine, Naples, Livourne et
                        Gines.</p>
                    <p>Lee' Mardis 1 es 15 à 8h. p.m. direes pour Brindisi, Bari, Anedae et
                        Venise</p>
                    <p>Le Meroredi &amp; 10 h s.m. pour les escales de la Syrie es Larusque,</p>
                    <p>Le Land 14 à 4h. p.m. poqr Port-aid, Suse et Massawah.</p>
                    <p>Lee Landi 7 et March 24h. p.m. pour Port Bald.</p>
                    <p>BANK OF ATHENS, Limited.. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co..</p>
                    <p>Ephial 20,000,000 (Tally sad p</p>
                    <p>achter and Liverpool and ghy them werp a lot lessra and Syrian Coast. The
                        dates are approximate and Town PAL PERSIAN FRINUS due from Antwerp &amp;
                        Middlesbro Nov.13 GRECIAN PRINCE de frem</p>
                    <p>Railings ry 10 days from</p>
                    <p>KAFFIN PRENUR</p>
                    <p>ROWN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>OCEAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>Londo Fame &amp; Trieste Answerp</p>
                    <p>HABIATIC PRINOS</p>
                    <p>1 INDSN PRINUR SCOTTISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Manchester</p>
                    <p>Lendon Manchester Antwerp &amp; Tendon De</p>
                    <p>BOREWARD SHILINGK-The R8. alle Prince is weling her sad will be loved by the
                        &amp;&amp; Crown Pr For terms of freight or passage apply to O. J. Grace
                        &amp; Co., Alexandria, Agents. 31-12 904</p>
                    <p>THE PAPAYANNI LINE. (The Ellerman Lines, Ltd.)</p>
                    <p>Pank</p>
                    <p>ltakall banking bobate</p>
                    <p>ights N&amp; per</p>
                    <p>Despatch weakly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Malls
                        from ALEXANDRIA to CYPRUS and the STRIAN ODART and vice-varm For particolare
                        of freight, passage, st, apply to the Agent SD. A, MINUTTO 1099-9-9-906</p>
                    <p>SUDAN GOVERNMENT RAILWAYS. CAIRO-KHARTOUM SUMMER MAIL SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Watraday and Sunday</p>
                    <p>Dining set Dining sad Bleep</p>
                    <p>AR</p>
                    <p>part Catro</p>
                    <p>as also on train from Catro te Lamer on Mondaye psd from Jame to Onlyondage
                        Wall alivered Exart, Bunday and Wednesday evening and Ostre, Thursday and
                        Friday morning.</p>
                    <p>Pregnant Bailings from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL, also Begalar Services from
                        LIVERPOOL ALEXANDRIA and to ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT. BLACK SEA, and other
                        Mediterranean Ports and To Moderate Fares for single and return tickets
                        Excellent Passenger Accommodation. Stewardess carried. Liberal table and by
                        the 88. PARDINIA The CITY OF RUNDER, cow loading will leave for Liverpool in
                        a few days and will be followed SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY,
                        LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>INLAND TOWN ORRAT BRITAIN</p>
                    <p>CARGO when by special agreement only. Through Freight quoted for the UNITED
                        STATES and For passage or freight apply to the Agents, BARKER &amp; Co.,
                        Alexandria.. 9081-81-10-908</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT Says White Nile Tour Trip de Khartoum andar er plans may
                        be KHARTOUM AIRO OFFICE SHARIA KASB- ween sind gee ook at all list Agen of
                        goods undertaken so all pieces on SEBUTAL STRAM for private This and sa
                        Nther whhin navigation fai ENGINEERING DE TMENT Shipyard for construction of
                        rowheel, mar ai SOLE AGENTS FOR Dadbridge Of Engines from machinery,
                        buildings, brigacion Beat On, Lil</p>
                    <p>every Monday, and Friday during the season. First The Ellerman Lines Limited.
                        INTERNATIONAL SLEEPING AND RESTAURANT CARS COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>(Including Westcott &amp; Laurance Line.)</p>
                    <p>14</p>
                    <p>departure November 4, 19 days on the Nile for £22. SPECIAL COMMED BAKWAY AND
                        STEAMER BIKE TOURS AT GREATLY REDUCED FARER Hegular mailings from Liverpool
                        Glasgow Antwerp and London to Alisandra Frequent mailings from Alex Deer
                        BI-WERELY SERVICE TO HALFA ERARTOUM, BUDAN. W andzia to Liverpool and
                        London. Throngh freight rates to toland towns to Great Artain slao o the USA
                        SPECIAL STRAMESH AND DAHABRAHS FOR PRIVATE PARTIES S.S. Bolderss from Lendon
                        &amp; Mala Ellerman is due on or about Nov. 23 One Regular Service of
                        Freight Steamers between CAIRO and HALFA. Liverpo Bwana &amp; Malta- Westco
                        Antwerp &amp; London Cook's Interpreters in miform are present at the
                        principal Hailway Basions and Ianding plans in pssengers holding their kete.
                        10-18.004</p>
                    <p>Tours to Palestine, Byvin, and Demes. Best Canis egiptunk Lowest chan</p>
                    <p>Ellerman Westool</p>
                    <p>Flavian</p>
                    <p>Ararat Alisan</p>
                    <p>" R</p>
                    <p>Belgravian Grester</p>
                    <p>Liverpool &amp; Malte London</p>
                    <p>For para</p>
                    <p>M. TAMVACO, A</p>
                    <p>The 8 Athian, now on the bert for Liverpool, will be despatched to that pers
                        Ages</p>
                    <p>sandy</p>
                    <p>Vesil further wote the Tren Monday, Wednesday, and ap Supplement- Slots</p>
                    <p>ping and Barnt Care will re re e</p>
                    <p>4) Thebes all information ma be obed at Company's</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n1/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fixed deposits for one year certain received at à per cent per annum.
                        Depo-its at interest for shorter periods are also received at mates to be
                        agreed upon. Letters of Credis for the use of travellers are isted payable
                        in al parte of the World. Approved hills discounted.</p>
                    <p>Bille, documentary invoices, eto, collected. Deaf and singapoio transfers
                        inued pay- able all over the World.</p>
                    <p>Foreign exchange bought and sold. Advsners made upon approved securities and
                        upon cotton, cotton-seed, sugar and other mer abandies.</p>
                    <p>The parchaee and sale of stocks and shares on the London Stock Exchange and
                        on the loesl and Continental Bourses, undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Customers osa deposit their valuables, bonds, , for le enstody in the Bank's
                        fire-proof strong-rooms, and the Bank will attend to the collecuen of the
                        coupons and drawn bonds deposited as they fall due</p>
                    <p>Mercentile credits issued.</p>
                    <p>Annaides, pensions, dividends, eto, collected. All farther particulars and
                        information can be oblained on application.</p>
                    <p>The officers and olerke, of the Bank are pledged to secrecy as to the tran-
                        sactions of customers.</p>

                    <p>weakness in the step they had taken. The Russian Government first accedes to
                        a most important political step and then at the last moment withdraws ite
                        sanction. But instead of putting an absolute veto on the conference it
                        allows the representatives of the Zemstvos to meet in private. The
                        consequences were obvious Radical resolutions are adopted, a Constitution is
                        demanded, together with liberty of conscience, liberty of the Press, liberty
                        of speech, and liberty of education, besides an elective legislative
                        assembly. This private conference was only held on Saturday, but by Monday
                        the facts are known to the world and the ball has been set rolling which,
                        under the leadership of a Slavonic Mirabeau or Lafs- yette, may lead to the
                        ruin of militant auto- eracy throughout the Russian Empire:</p>
                    <p>At the same time, serious observers of the conditions of modern Russis, even
                        among those who sympathise with the aspirations of the Russian people for a
                        form of government which will give some legitimate scope for their ener
                        gies, entertain grave doubts as to the capacity of the Russians for
                        self-government. The mem- bers of the bureaucracy, indeed, base their claim
                        to govern Russia, when they condescend to argue the matter at all; on the
                        ground that acceptance of office the new Minister of the In- no other
                        government is possible. Soon after his</p>
                    <p>terior made a mendorable declaration." Abroad," said Prince Sviatopolk
                        Mirski, "people speak of a new Constitution for Russia: such a thing is,
                        impossible under present conditions.". It is not only abroad that people
                        speak of a new Constitu tion; it is in Russia itself that the demand is
                        being did not stop short at a repetition of the common made. But Prince
                        Sviatopolk-Mirski's declaration official formula. "But," he continued,
                        "there is such a thing as local self-government, as is exemplified in the
                        Zemstvos. I believe," he added, "in Zematvos." That is a declaration of
                        immense importance coming from such a quarter how important is demonstrated,
                        with singular appositeness in an article on "Self-government in Russia" in
                        the new number of the Empirs Review. For reasons which may readily be sur
                        mised, the writer of the article desires to pre- serve his anonymity; but
                        internal evidence renders almost superfluous the editorial as surance that
                        the writer is entitled to be listened to with respect when he seeks to
                        supplement Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's state- mont by giving a sketch of the
                        Zemstvo institution in Russia. The evidence which THEOFPTIAN GASETTE IS
                        PRINTED ON PAPER is adduced of the existence of the seeds of a
                        representative system of government throughout the greater part of
                        European</p>
                    <p>N.B-9ribecriptions commence trees the 1e or 10th of any month SUBSCRIPTIONS
                        and ADVERTISEMENTS at dne la advices P. O. Orders and Thayer t be made
                        payable to the Editor and Manager Bowland Snelling, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>appears to have taken root in Russian provin cial life, the success which has
                        on the whole attended it, and the possibilities which it presents of
                        preparing the people for the difficult. task of self-government. The Zemstvo
                        instita tion is a tiny plant, but if it be wisely tended it may yet grow
                        into a noble tree. Unfortunately Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's belief in the
                        Zemst vos is not a common article of bureaucratic</p>
                    <p>A very interesting telegram from St. Peters-faith, and there have been
                        indications that, if burg this morning announces that the Russian some of
                        the bureaucrats of St. Petersburg Government actually gave permission for a
                        could have their way' even this struggling public conference to be held at
                        St. Peters experiment in local self government would be barg, composed of
                        representativos of "Zems crashed beneath the heel of autocracy. But tvos"
                        throughout the country. At the last the fact that the delegates of the
                        Zemstvos moment, however, the courage of the autocracy Saturday last is an
                        historical event of the were allowed, even to confer in private on failed,
                        and the sanction for a public con utmost significance, and we may live to
                        reckon ference was withdrawn, though the delegates November 19, 1904, as one
                        of the cardinal were allowed to meet in privata A more dates in the history
                        of the human race. portentous step. in the history of the poli tical
                        emancipation of the human race has not occurred since the summoning of the
                        States General. The analogy can be pressed</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Royal Insurance Coy. Our Winter Season's Our Winter Season's Stocks THE
                        EGYPTIAN GAZETTE TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS.</p>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE. LABGEST FIRE OFFICE IN THE WORLD. BASELDEN &amp; Co., Agent,
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>B. VITERBO &amp; Co., 4, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>COMPRISING AN</p>
                    <p>Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver &amp; Plated Articles,
                        CUTLERY, LEATHER &amp; ATHLETIC GOODS &amp; GAMES.</p>
                    <p>TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS. CHOICE HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS. VINTAGE WINES.</p>
                    <p>SUBRO</p>
                    <p>Meypt (inploding</p>
                    <p>PT. 80 the three ma Portal Union P.T.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LD. PROVISIONS, CONFECTION RY AND TABLE
                        DELICACIES,VT 1.7.4</p>
                    <p>$1-8-906</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 17821</p>
                    <p>HABELDEN &amp; Co., Agonis, Alexandria. FEED. OTT &amp; Co., Se Agents,
                        Cairo.</p>
                    <p>"AL HAYAT" Helouan</p>
                    <p>First Class Health Resort</p>
                    <p>UNRIVALLED POSITION on the Mokattam Hills 96 metres above the level of the
                        Nile, surrounded by desert.</p>
                    <p>Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly moderate prices.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Supply Stores, (BRANCH WALKER &amp; Co.; CAIRO). WALKER &amp;
                        MEIMARACHI, Limited.</p>
                    <p>MENA HOUSE HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>IS NOW OPIEN.</p>
                    <p>24848-80-4-905</p>
                    <p>ALL ROOMS FULL SOUTH WITH SHELTERED VERANDAHS. GRAND CONTINENTAL.</p>
                    <p>PUBLIC SITTING ROOMS in separate Pavilions communicating by glass
                        corridors.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light-Steam-Heating - Lift. Bathing, Air and Diet Cures. Resident
                        Medical D rector. All kinds of Sports, Own Stables. Omnibus meets ali
                        Trains. ILLUSTRATED PROSPECTUS SENT FREE ON APPLICATION.</p>
                    <p>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER</p>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB,</p>
                    <p>Printers</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Stationers</p>
                    <p>Open all this year. Unrivalled position in centre of Cairo, opposite
                        Khsdivial Opera House and Babekish Gardens Magnificent Verandah. French
                        Restaurant and Grill-room Bars and Billiard Saloons open to non-residents.
                        Suppers after the theatre.</p>
                    <p>Bookbinders.</p>
                    <p>ASK FOR</p>
                    <p>Dealers in Fancy Goods.</p>
                    <p>7-8-905</p>
                    <p>VERY OLD SPECIAL</p>
                    <p>ASK FOR</p>
                    <p>"D.C.L Scotch Whisky Ce DisTLERS COMPANY E</p>
                    <p>EDINBURGH</p>
                    <p>Bole Agents for Egypt &amp; Budan G. G. DROSSOS &amp; CO. LATE PRAZZICA &amp;
                        DROSSOS. ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, FORT-SAID AND</p>
                    <p>91080</p>
                    <p>KHARTOUM</p>
                    <p>50-11-904</p>
                    <p>SPIRO CONDOLEON.</p>
                    <p>SMYRNA TURKEY-CARPETS. Made entirely of wool and regeiable colours</p>
                    <p>Tea Bay CARPETS IN THE WORLD.</p>
                    <p>EWED 47</p>
                    <p>WREXHA</p>
                    <p>ENGLAX</p>
                    <p>PILSENER</p>
                    <p>REGISTERED</p>
                    <p>AND 13 NOT SUPPLIED APPLY 10</p>
                    <p>.</p>
                    <p>JOHN B CAFFARI ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>:</p>
                    <p>GEORGE NUNGOVICH HOTELS.</p>
                    <p>24847-3.31.905</p>
                    <p>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL</p>
                    <p>PORT SAID. First Class Hotel Modern in all respects. Fire-proof, Drained to
                        the Sea. Lifte, Electric Light, English and French Billiards, Fresh and Bal
                        Water Baths.</p>
                    <p>The Coolest Summer Residence in Egyp</p>
                    <p>Special terms to Cairo Residents and their families desirous of enjoying the
                        cool air and sea bashing during the summer months</p>
                    <p>DRAGOMANS IN HOTEL UNIPORN MEN ALL TRAINS AND STRANE</p>
                    <p>BOLE PROPRIETORS</p>
                    <p>JOHN HAIG'S GLEN LEVEN Old Scotch Whisky. JOHN HAIG &amp; Co, Limited,
                        MARKINCH, SCOTLAND. ESTABLISHED PRIOR TO 1880. 32306-30-11-004 Boss AGENT
                        YOU BE R. CORBO &amp; G. PARIENTE, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>*</p>
                    <p>The Tosh</p>
                    <p>VISITORS AND RESIDENTS</p>
                    <p>KINDLY NOTE THAT</p>
                    <p>Whisky The Sphinx.</p>
                    <p>Established 1726.</p>
                    <p>MACKINTOSH &amp; C°</p>
                    <p>INVERNESS.</p>
                    <p>General Depot. JOHN ROSS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Marina,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Retailers.</p>
                    <p>E. J. FLEURENT, Square Halim Pacha, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>31837-14-8-006</p>
                    <p>"AU DE ROUGE." WHERE TO WINTER</p>
                    <p>General Drapery Establishment.</p>
                    <p>(Central Tramway Station), CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>SPIRO BUILDINGS, Sharia Kare Nd, Cam P. PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>90001-7-1-905</p>
                    <p>Magasins Victoria.</p>
                    <p>BOOLESTONE AND KEILL</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH DRAPERY.</p>
                    <p>Opposite Austrfan Consalate, near the Kininia Theairs. Gaialogues on
                        applleation.</p>
                    <p>NOTICE</p>
                    <p>Mr. W. Ernest Walton has arrived in Egypt and is now residing at Hotel du
                        Nil, Cairo. All retailers of post-cards should without fail see the
                        collection which be. hrow at his disposal for the Egyptior mukt. This
                        collection is unique in th world. No time nor expense has beer spa-ed in the
                        production of there pos eud, which are veritable reproductions?
                        quarelles</p>
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>Me. P. P. Greve the Correspondent of the</p>
                    <p>for him should be addressed</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>JUST ARRIVED LATEST DESIGNS IN LADIES' DRESS 9000S. 8-11-906</p>
                    <p>19.6</p>
                    <p>ORIGINAL DUNLOP</p>
                    <p>AUTOMOBILE</p>
                    <p>AND BICYCLE TIRES. REDUCED PRICES.</p>
                    <p>Bole Agents:</p>
                    <p>C LOUKAITIS &amp; Co., GOVERNMENT PURVEYORS, Garage Boulae Btreet, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>LOR</p>
                    <p>IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>TEWFIK PALACE</p>
                    <p>Telephone</p>
                    <p>No. 5, Helonan</p>
                    <p>HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>Tel. Address: HELOUAN</p>
                    <p>THWPIX</p>
                    <p>HELOUAN,</p>
                    <p>Half-an-hour from Cairo.</p>
                    <p>HOURLY TRAIN SERVICE</p>
                    <p>The TEE PLACE Horse is a first-class Residential Hotel standing by stiff past
                        outside the town is a beautiful healthy open to 3 feet above the Nile
                        Vallor. It contains In ons Incuriously funished, commantine mágnideat views
                        Long Deswing on and aged rom Ma', Body Photraphat dark rooms. All the bed o
                        have halomes, and 30 see separate fath</p>
                    <p>foes attached</p>
                    <p>It is the only Ring with extensive priesto gdon, Pan House, Grous or and
                        Tennis Court. Is is ind hewler of the Helman Sporting thich holds its Raco
                        Motins the Soares and Golf Links apon the rewis Palace Gard</p>
                    <p>Hallway Fation, and the 'phor Baths Ma Coma the Hotel Tephone to sapes,
                        Gronins Post is the l Pensson from 1 per</p>
                    <p>947918-4-5----</p>
                    <p>EMBOSSING PRESS. STAMPING OWN ADDRESS CHEST &amp; ENGRAVING OFFICE</p>
                    <p>J MARGOSCHES</p>
                    <p>CAIRO BLAC ROAD</p>
                    <p>Geral Moy</p>
                    <p>Aq</p>
                    <p>Date of Twos Coo&amp;or),</p>
                    <p>PHOTOGRAPHIE REISER</p>
                    <p>(Ren &amp; Broa). SPECIALITY:</p>
                    <p>'Childrens Photos.</p>
                    <p>High Class Portraits.</p>
                    <p>THE CAIRO WEEKLY NEWSPAPER,</p>
                    <p>Is Under Entirely New Management</p>
                    <p>AND WILL BE PUBLISHED AS USUAL</p>
                    <p>During the Season 1904/5.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTION</p>
                    <p>For the Season P.T. 20</p>
                    <p>PAYABLE IN ADVANCE</p>
                    <p>All Communications and Subscriptions to be addressed to the EDITOR,</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. P. GRAVES.</p>
                    <p>And for Advertising Space apply to Mr. W. E. WALTON:</p>
                    <p>10. No</p>
                    <p>P.I. 30 por line. Contrate and</p>
                    <p>10th of any month. SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS AN Jos in advanos. P. O.
                        Orders and Cheques to be made payable to the Editor and Manager, Sowind
                        Soulling, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>onde Offfese: 86, New Bed-str; B.C.</p>
                    <p>FEE" BYPTIAN GARETTE IS PRINTED OF PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY TEN
                        COMDGN PAPER KILLS EXTTRO (SALES OFFICE E, CANNON STREET...</p>
                    <p>BIRTH.</p>
                    <p>SCOTT-At Kar-el-Nil; on the 19th H. Scor, of a 100.</p>
                    <p>the wife of Mr. J.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>THE WAR.</p>
                    <p>RUSSIAN BOMBARDMENT.</p>
                    <p>JAPANESE REPULSE.</p>
                    <p>GREAT BATTLE IMMINENT,</p>
                    <p>MUKDEN, November 19.</p>
                    <p>A stiff artillery fire was opened on the Russian right at daylight, and
                        lasted for several hours. The fire continued at intervals during the day.
                        The Russians are expecting a general attack. All ranges have been carefully
                        marked, and whichever army attacks is likely to suffer severely..
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>MUXDEN, November 19. The Hussians expect a general attack. (H) ST.
                        PETERSBURG, November 20 The Russian artillery on the Sha Ho have compelled
                        the Japanese to fall back. (Havas.).</p>
                    <p>TOKIO, November 20. Friday's report from Marshal Oyama, detail- Fing the
                        various skirmishes and stating that the Russian bombardment of the Japanese
                        positions was resultless, seems to indicate the imminence of another great
                        battle, though, apparently, neither side has yet made any decisive move-
                        ment. The Russian feints were evidently (Reiter.)</p>
                    <p>An English Daily Newiper, tablished in 1880 Hiror &amp; Manngar: B. B Price
                        One Plastre Tarts.intended to draw the Japanese.</p>
                    <p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904.</p>
                    <p>TANZIM DEPARTMENT AND CAIRO. In our last issue we mentioned that the
                        inhabitants of Helouan, weary of the absolute contempt with which the
                        Tanzim, Department treated their just complaints, had determined to appeal
                        directly to Lord Cromer. But it is</p>
                    <p>ST. PETERSBURG, November 20. The attack on Putiloff, mentioned on 18th inst.,
                        was made in order to ascertain the strength of the Russian position. The
                        Japanese got within 30 yards of the trenches, but were finally repulsed
                        leaving 100 dead. (Beuter.)</p>
                    <p>not. Helouan alone which suffers from the THE UNITED STATES.</p>
                    <p>neglect and indifference of the Tanzim Depart ment. Cairo has also grounds
                        for complaint, and</p>
                    <p>it must be admitted that the maintenance of</p>
                    <p>the streets of the Capital is not carried out</p>
                    <p>PEACE CONFERENCE.</p>
                    <p>with such a regard for the convenience of the THE PRESIDENTS MESSAGE. public
                        as it would be only reasonable to expect. No one, who knows anything at all
                        of the conditions of life in the city and of the always increasing flood of
                        traffe that pours through its streets all day long, will deny that on the
                        whole this work is well done, for though it might, we should imagine, be
                        easily expedited when 'tis done, 'tis well done, but there is a want of tact
                        in the choice of time and place for the labours of the department in charge
                        that is not merely annoying to the</p>
                    <p>average man in the street, but a very serious</p>
                    <p>impediment to the business of the town. At the present moment Clot Bey street
                        has been</p>
                    <p>NAVAL AMBITION.</p>
                    <p>WASHINGTON, November 19.</p>
                    <p>It is understood that Mr. Roosevelt's message</p>
                    <p>pulled up from one end to the other and all will say nothing regarding tariff
                        reform, but traffic throughout it is completely stopped. In the party
                        leaders are carefully considering a fact this has been the case for more
                        than a revision which will be proposed next year. month past, with the
                        single qualification that the Tramway Company has continued to use its lines
                        through the street. These lines carry</p>
                    <p>Nearly all the European powers have indicat-</p>
                    <p>ed their acceptance in principle of Mr. Hay's invitation for a Peace
                        Conference, leaving the</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>NEW YORK, November 19. Mr. Morton, Secretary for the Navy, speaking</p>
                    <p>an immense amount of traffic, seeing that they details for future
                        negotiations. form part of the 'direct tramway routes to The United States
                        Naval Estimates for Abbassieh, Rod-el-Farag, and Shoubra, and form 1905
                        amount to 114,5000,000 dollars, which is the connecting link between the
                        milway an increase of 17,000,000. station and the Mousky, Nasrieb, and, in
                        short, all parts of the town. Fortunately for the ordinary carriage traffic
                        the closing of this street is not a great inconvenience inas much as the
                        alternative route by the Bab el here, declared that Mr. Roosevelt aimed at
                        Hadeed street adds but little to the distance having the best and strongest
                        Navy in the to be covered. With the tramways, however, world. the case is
                        different, for the whole of the traffic that usually goes through Clot Bey
                        has now to make a long detour passing by the Post Office, Continental Hotel,
                        and so on up 34865 9 the Boulse-road and thence along the new road to the
                        railway station. The consequence of this is that all day long a double
                        stream of DAILY WEATHER REPORI traimoars is passing right through the heart
                        of</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX O fices, Hotel du Nil, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>OFERTATION BY SURVEY DEPARTMENT</p>
                    <p>trection of wind. Force Daring</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Fresh</p>
                    <p>Max. Temp. In the shade..</p>
                    <p>Min</p>
                    <p>Relata</p>
                    <p>610</p>
                    <p>BRMARER From Saturday to yesterday the wind blew sality, from the W&amp;W.
                        with irringular fores and guety at times and rough continuous gosty wind
                        from the W. withough so, the The weather was clear throughout Fterday, there
                        was weather being fresh and cool. Barometer falling</p>
                    <p>OTHER STATIONS</p>
                    <p>(Router)</p>
                    <p>ANGLO-RUSSIAN CONVENTION. NEGOTIATIONS PROGRESSING.</p>
                    <p>E</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 19. The Anglo-Russian negotiations for the Con the town and
                        crosses, the heavy carriage vention are progressing. Russia desires to
                        traffic that is always in motion to and from exclude anything which would
                        imply that the the Sharia Kamel and the south and west</p>
                    <p>JAPANESE LOAN.</p>
                    <p>LONDON) November 19. The total subscriptions for the Japanese</p>
                    <p>parts of the town. Happily both the Boulac Russians are necessarily to blame.
                        (Reuter) Raber rough road and the. approaches to it from the east are wide
                        enough to easily meet the strain thus put upon them, or rather they would be
                        so if it had not been that just at this particular moment one half of the
                        Boulse road in the leisurely manner to which we are accust loan here amount
                        to £80,533,800. has been torn up and is being romacadamised omed. Why this
                        work, which most certainly was not pressingly needed, should have been
                        undertaken asactly at the time that the open- ing of the season brings a
                        rush of traffic to this spot, and that that rush is already spore or less
                        seriously incommoded by the abnormal tram- way traffic, is a question that
                        it would puzzle</p>
                    <p>For the 14 hours ending m. Terday.</p>
                    <p>Mm.</p>
                    <p>ert Baid..</p>
                    <p>#1</p>
                    <p>20 Waly Balta. 10 Berbe</p>
                    <p>Bunkfa</p>
                    <p>Kherteam. Wed Molant</p>
                    <p>PORNION STATIONS</p>
                    <p>700.1 Almon</p>
                    <p>185</p>
                    <p>Balber</p>
                    <p>Bra</p>
                    <p>8. Molar</p>
                    <p>OPPOSIN OTTOMAN BAN</p>
                    <p>ALMX ANDRIA O Bow CATRO</p>
                    <p>RIO JANEIRO TROUBLES.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>RIO JANEIRO, November 19. Colonel Sadre, the instigator of the troubles,</p>
                    <p>STRIKE DISTURBANCES AT HAVRE</p>
                    <p>any sane man to answer, unless the answer be, has given himself up to the
                        authorities. (H.) that the authorities are quite indifferent to the
                        convenience of the public or are, for some rea son or other, incapable of
                        judging its needs. It is really therefore to be hoped that some steps will
                        be taken to place some one in charge of the organisation and working of the
                        depart</p>
                    <p>HAVAR, November 20 Disturbances have taken place as a result of (Havas)</p>
                    <p>ment responsible who is competent to carry it the strike of port labourers,
                        on without exhibiting the utter indifference to! the convenience of the
                        public that is shown at present</p>
                    <p>Anglo-American Nila Steamer,</p>
                    <p>&amp; HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL, VERSE OF DOGE BETWEEN ALE ANDRIA &amp; CAIRO</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round.</p>
                    <p>A 180 Might ELEOBRIO LIGHT.-LIFT.-ODERATE CHARGER</p>
                    <p>Three Sallings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agente at Alesandriay</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA DONO WAREHOUSE CO., L</p>
                    <p>81.10.200</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n2/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <!-- page 3 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>THE WAR.</p>
                    <p>RUSSIAN BOMBARDMENT.</p>
                    <p>JAPANESE REPULSE.</p>
                    <p>GREAT BATTLE IMMINENT,</p>
                    <p>MUKDEN, November 19.</p>
                    <p>A stiff artillery fire was opened on the Russian right at daylight, and
                        lasted for several hours. The fire continued at intervals during the day.
                        The Russians are expecting a general attack. All ranges have been carefully
                        marked, and whichever army attacks is likely to suffer severely..
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>MUXDEN, November 19. The Hussians expect a general attack. (H) ST.
                        PETERSBURG, November 20 The Russian artillery on the Sha Ho have compelled
                        the Japanese to fall back. (Havas.).</p>
                    <p>TOKIO, November 20. Friday's report from Marshal Oyama, detail- Fing the
                        various skirmishes and stating that the Russian bombardment of the Japanese
                        positions was resultless, seems to indicate the imminence of another great
                        battle, though, apparently, neither side has yet made any decisive move-
                        ment. The Russian feints were evidently (Reiter.)</p>
                    <p>An English Daily Newiper, tablished in 1880 Hiror &amp; Manngar: B. B Price
                        One Plastre Tarts.intended to draw the Japanese.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904.</p>
                    <p>THE SABA-NAHAS WEDDING The Khedive was represented by Youssef</p>
                    <p>A SPLENDID CEREMONY...</p>
                    <p>FULL DETAILS</p>
                    <p>GREEK FLEET'S VISIT..</p>
                    <p>FAREWELL RECEPTION.</p>
                    <p>THE BALTIC FLEET</p>
                    <p>DATE OF ARRIVAL</p>
                    <p>THE ROYAL BERKS</p>
                    <p>NOTES FROM HELORAN</p>
                    <p>The Grand Hotel, Helaas is a apa lage number of disguised having arrived
                        there lately.</p>
                    <p>Amongst the guests staying at this we notice Lady Bisset and danch W. Bisset,
                        RE KCSL Calthorpe, M. HN.P. Mrs. Bixley M, S. G Berkshire Regiment, left
                        to-day for Aboakir, W. Niemaksa Mr. Two companies of the 2nd Battalion Royal
                        Alexandre Tilche M where they will camp out for a week's training and Mrs.
                        Spearman The three companies of the regiment which Mrs. Leetham, Mrs.</p>
                    <p>by the troop train which will have brought the Herr Schover Mr. 8.1 The
                        approximate strength of the three com 20th Hussars to Alexandris for
                        embarkation. Halifax, and MP. S Panies is 230 men. They will be quartered
                        at</p>
                    <p>Abbassieh</p>
                    <p>at the Grand Hotel, Helouan, and his te Rev. R. H. Longley arrived a few days
                        ago. held there yesterday over the chaplaincy of Helouan for the coming
                        winter. The first Anglican Church, service was</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL AGRICULTURAL SOCIETY between the Government and the K. A. S., we
                        and is in attendance at the golf links of the will shortly be submitted to a
                        meeting of the With regard to the agreement to be come to The golf
                        professional has arrived at Halquan society.</p>
                    <p>Pasha Dia, 1st Aide-de-Camp to his Highness. Among those present were Prince
                        Omar Pasha Toussoni, Brig. General Bullock, C. B., and The members of the
                        Hellenic Club organised his staff, Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of on
                        Saturday afternoon a farewell reception to Alexandria (who had returned from
                        Cairo that Commodore Coundouriotis and staff and the evening specially in
                        order to be presept), M. officers of the Greek Fleet at 5 o'clock. They The
                        ships of the Baltic Fleet are expected to Belinfante Ustberg, Diplomatic
                        Agent and were received by the president, Mr. M. Sins arrive at Port Said on
                        Wednesday next. Consul General for Sweden and Norway, M. dino, surrounded by
                        the other members of the The marriage of Miss Mary Saba, the von
                        Humboldt-Dachroeden, German Consul, community were present, including Mr.
                        and Girard, French Consul, and Mme Girard, Baron club. A great many members
                        of the Greek daughter of the popalar Postmaster-General of Chevalier
                        Pascarius, Austro-Hungarian Consul, Mrs. E. Benachi, M. and Mrs. M. Salvago,
                        Mr. Egypt, to F. Nahas Bey, the great Syrian Hassan Pasha Mohsen, Liegt.
                        Col. McCracken, and Mrs. Alex. Benachi, Mr. and Mrs. Delta, notable, was
                        celebrated on Saturday evening Major and Mrs. Gamble, Captain and Mrs. Mr.
                        and Mrs. N. Sinadino, Dr. and Mrs. Valas General Stoessel telegraphs that
                        all the neh an auspicions social event in the history officers of the 2nd
                        Battalion Royal Berkshire of the band of the Greek Philharmonic going to
                        Cairo, will leave on December 2, Mr. A. B. Middleton, Mza with all the
                        splendour and hospitality befitting Bingley, Captain, and Mrs. Finch, and
                        the sopoulo. Dancing took place to the strains of Alexandria. The ceremony
                        has been looked forward to for many weeks past by the inhaegiment, a number
                        of officers from the Hellenic Society and of the flagship Psara bitants of
                        Egypt's commercial capital, for the Squadron, Dr. Ruffer, Director-General
                        of the popularity of our worthy Postmaster General Quarantine Board, and
                        Mrs. Ruffer, Michalla proposing the health of the Greek Fleet, which The
                        proceedings opened by Mr. M. Sinadino widespread, and the magnificence of
                        the fete as Sub-Director General of the Customs was received with the
                        greatest enthusiasm. was fully in accordance with the high official broise
                        Ralli, Vice President of the Alexandria members of the club and the Greek
                        community Administration, and Mrs. Michalla, Mr. Am In his speech, Mr.
                        Sinadino, on behalf of the rank of the family, whose hospitality on this
                        Municipality, Mr. Chataway, Administrator of generally, wished the officers
                        and men God- occasion will long be remembered. The invitatie Alexandria
                        Municipality, and Mrs. Cha-speed on the continuation of their cruise. He
                        tions had been sent out for 9.30 p.m. and taway, Mr. Debbane, Consul General
                        for Brazil, asked Commodore Coundouriotis to convey to bourhood of that part
                        of Ramleh, where is the Alexandria City Police, and the Hon. Mrs. the
                        community for having sent the fleet to palatial residence of Saba Pasha, was
                        alive with a ceaseless procession of carriages bringing the Quarantine
                        Board, and Mrs. Zananiri, by one and all, that this pleasant visit would
                        Hopkinson, Zananiri Bey, Secretary-General of these waters, and expressed
                        the hope, shared invited came also from Alexandria, and cunt Mrs. Peake, Dr.
                        Szarvazy, Austro-Hungarisa the wedding guests. A large number of those Peake
                        Bey, Deputy Postmaster-General, and be the forerunner of others equally
                        pleasant. less tramloads of invités were despatched at Vice-Consul, Mr. Jas.
                        Hewat, American Consular minus of the line to Halt 1, which is con- Agent,
                        Mr. Borchgrevink, Procureur General, intervals of a few minutes from the
                        city ter veniently situated in proximity to the scene of Mr.Sootidis,
                        Hellenic Consul-General, Hafez Bey the festivities. Mohamed, Sub-Governor of
                        Alexandria, Dr. and Mrs. Morrison, Dr. Gottschlich, Beneducci Bey, Secretary
                        to the Gouvernorst, and Mrs. The road leading to the residence of the
                        Beneducci, Mr. and Mrs. G. B. and Miss Pasha was gorgeously illuminated and
                        bedeck Alderson, Mohamed Bey Said, Chief of the ed with prettily arranged
                        lamps, which gave a Native Parquet, M. Reiny, Belgian Consul, fairy like
                        aspect to the impressive surround Councillors of the Alexandria
                        Municipality, ings. Before the portal giving access to the Judges of the
                        Mixed and Native Tribunals mansion a great tent had been erected, draped and
                        a representative gathering of the crème de with tastefully-arranged
                        curtains, where a la crème of the English, Greek, Jewish, German, elak room
                        had been installed. The immediate and French colonies, besides all the
                        leading steps, leading to an entrance hall, through society in Alexandria.
                        approach to the house is by a staircase of marble representatives of Syrian,
                        Coptic, and native which the guests passed to the great balcony, where a
                        scene of enchanting loveliness met their astonished gaze.</p>
                    <p>Itis reported that the Japanese, after success shortly after that hour the
                        immediate neigh Miraisi Hopkinson Bey, Commandant of the H. M. the King of
                        the Hellenes the thanks of understand that ite terms are now drawn up and
                        Grand Hotel, which are now in splendid con</p>
                    <p>fal mining, have occupied the counterscarp of the Sang su-shan fort (Reuter)
                        Toxo, November 20. The Japanese Headquarters at Port Arthur report that
                        a</p>
                    <p>DINNER PARTY</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Em. Benachi subsequently gave dinner party at their residence in
                        the Greek splendid ceremony was the profusion and taste Geraadis, Hellenic
                        Diplomatic Agent, Mr. One of the most remarkable features of this and
                        officers. Amongst the guests were Mr. quarter to the departing Commodore of
                        the floral tributes. Throughout the salons N. Scotidis, Consul General, and
                        the leading</p>
                    <p>From the balcony to the extreme end of the garden there stretched one huge
                        pavilion, completely composed of Arabic curtains. and the flooring consisted
                        of innumerable The superficies, covered was very extensive Oriental rugs.
                        This vast expanse was relieved THE BRITISH YACHT Catarina left Alex-by
                        beautiful floral decorations, and numberless andria this morning. tables and
                        chairs had been set-out for the A POST AND TELEGRAPH OFFICE was opened end
                        of this pavilion thé supper buffets were convenience of the guests.
                        Throughout the at Geteins on the 3rd November. spread, and these were
                        concealed by aand included a vast quantity of jewellery and continued until
                        the early bours of the morning. ceremony had been gone through. gigantic
                        curtain until after the wedding</p>
                    <p>CLOT BEY STREET, Cairo, is now entirely blocked for the laying down of
                        asphalt.”</p>
                    <p>QUARANTINE restrictions against arrivals in Egyptian ports from Salaya have
                        been sup pressed.</p>
                    <p>AN INCENDIARY.The servant of Teufik Bey Abel el Kader, who is accused of
                        setting his asters house on fire, at Shoubra, and there by causing loss and
                        damage equivalent to L.Ez has been arfested.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA OPERA SEASON. The Italian opers company for the operatic season at
                        the Zania Theatre, and Khedivial Opera House arrived at Alexandria trom
                        Italy yesterday by the Fiorg Kufatto steamer. The first perform anos will
                        take place at the Zazinia on Monday</p>
                    <p>next</p>
                    <p>of</p>
                    <p>riage.</p>
                    <p>MASS ON BOARD.</p>
                    <p>start.</p>
                    <p>the Delta Railway Institute, kindly lent for After the, ceremony a banquet
                        was held in the occasion.</p>
                    <p>MIXED TRIBUNAL</p>
                    <p>The technical commission for the revision of</p>
                    <p>QUARANTINE Quarantine is imposed in Egyptian ports on</p>
                    <p>dition.</p>
                    <p>For golfers we recommend the combined. return first-class railway tickets
                        including lunch at the Grand Hotel, at P.T. 20 each. Company. They give free
                        socess to the gole the Anglo-American Nile Steamer and Hotel They are now
                        also to be had at the offices of links and golf house of the Grand Hotel</p>
                    <p>LETTER TO THE EDITOR We do not hold ourselves</p>
                    <p>to all, to</p>
                    <p>NILE BOILER EXPLOSION. TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GARTE journal a few days
                        ago of a boiler explosion, Dear Sir,-Having read in your esteemed. which
                        occurred on a steamer lying near Kar el-Nil Bridge, Cairo, which resulted in
                        the loss of several lives; I would like through the boilers and engines of
                        river steamers are not medium of this paper to enquire why the put under
                        compulsory inspection by the Pablic Works Department, seeing that boilet and
                        engines on land- are under compulsory super vision of the Department. To the
                        man in the street this appears a most</p>
                    <p>exquisite garlands and wreaths of flower were and Mrs. M. Sinadino, Mr. and
                        Mrs. M. Sal and reforms in the working of certain branches absurd
                        arrangement as it stands esity of the mansion, all round the walls, festoons
                        of members of the Hellenic community, viz., Mr. the Codes as applied to the
                        Mixed Tribunals, displayed. The effect was most enchanting. Mr. G. B.
                        Alderson let off fireworks about vago, Mr. and Mrs. 8. Delta, Mr. and Mrs.
                        of these tribunals, has begun its sittings at the To say nothing of the very
                        apparent necessity 10 p.m. in his garden in honour of the mardinner a
                        reception followed at which nearly Boutros Pasha Ghali, Minister for Foreign
                        river craft, it is a well known fade to engineers Alex. Benachi, and Mr. G.
                        Zervudachi: After Mixed Tribunals, under the presidency of for official
                        inspection of boilers and engines of The presents were both-costly and
                        numerous all of Hellenic society was present. Dancing Affairs. engaged in
                        repairing such steamers, that there Are a considerable number of steamers
                        (if snols gems. they can be called) working on the Nile, that are, with
                        respect to their boilers, a greater menage to those who are employed on them
                        and to any craft that come near them, than any floating mine yet designed.
                        The writer knows the existence of small craft on the Nile which are equipped
                        with boilers the age of which must be sought for in the long-forgotten past.
                        Surely our Government in Bapt can put their foot firmly down now and demand
                        the compulsory inspection of these craft by competent and responsible
                        officials.</p>
                    <p>SER W. WILLCOCKS EXPEDITION. mission from the Turkish Government to exa- As
                        Sir William Willcocks has received per- mine into the ancient irrigation
                        system on the Tigris and Euphrates, he is leaving to morrow for Bombay en
                        route for Basra and Bagdad, where he hopes to make a preliminary examina
                        tion of the ground this winter.</p>
                    <p>NILE COLD STORAGE CO. PROGRESS AND PROSPECTS.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday morning, Mass was celebrated on board the Spetzai, at which about a
                        hundred civilians assisted. These were afterwards enter ships having left
                        Aden since the 13th inst. tained by Capt. Caloyanni and his officers.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE OF FLEET andria, on the occasion of the departure of the Yesterday
                        afternoon, the harbour of Alex- fleet, was the scene of unwonted movement
                        and animation. Early in the afternoon large numbers of people collected on
                        the quay and sailed out</p>
                    <p>PASSENGER LISTS</p>
                    <p>ARRIVALS</p>
                    <p>tino arrivé hier de Gènes avait à bord Le paquebot Tabe de la Cie Florio
                        Rubat</p>
                    <p>THE BRIDAL PROCESSION. arrived and the scene, was animated, in the At 10
                        o'clock the guests had nearly all extreme. The uniforms of the officers of
                        the Army of Occupation and of the naval officers of the Greek Squadron, the
                        exquisite dresses of the ladies, and the general diversity of the gathering,
                        contributed to make the spectacle most brilliant and entrancing. The most
                        in- in small boats to witness from near the teretting moment of the evening
                        was when the bridal procession issued from the house and departure of the
                        ships. A small steamer be M. et A. Miani, D. d'Anton, Quartars, Bondi, La
                        marquis Salvago Raggi, E. Isnardi, Pacho, advanced slowly along the spacious
                        balcony, longing to Mr. Minotto was also kindly lent to cap. Schneider,
                        Wernon et son fils, Sheppard, According to statements appearing in the while
                        Professor D'Ambra's string band struck carry the members of the committee of
                        re- Parkes et Lang, Ryan, Birdwood, M. et Mme local papers since the
                        disaster, the boiler which up the entrancing strains of the Wedding ception,
                        besides a quantity of other people and R. Zecheri, Uggetti, Mile Eminente,
                        Anderson, exploded recently had been subjected to an March from Lohengrin.
                        This impressive cor Company have had a most successful issue. 3.30 p.m. the
                        Hydra weighed anchor and Dikran et sa mère, A. Monti, Mathilde Nando away
                        with the necessity for inspection. I The reserve shares of the Nile Cold
                        Storage the band of the Philharmonic society. At about Bevalls, Casossi,
                        Morters, A. Viola, Zoughton, overhaul a short time before, but this does not
                        ge was headed by gorgeously caparisoned They were, in fact, largely over
                        applied for commenced to steam slowly out of the harbour. et Co., Ugo
                        Lombardo et 2 saurs, Lat. Bamard, think I may say that the owners of river
                        Ravasses, who were followed by a group The object of this issue was in order
                        to Her departure was greeted with loud and E. Figari et son fils, A.
                        Bensilum, Lusi et fam, steamers themselves should be the first to wel the
                        high pontiffs of the Syrian Greek Catholic Melchite rite. comply with the
                        desires of the principal share prolonged cheers, the band of the
                        Philharmonic Anna Cuzzer, Torella et fam., Figari, Palla come official
                        inspection, and morally speaking FIRES-A fire broke out at 1 o'clock yester
                        The magnificent vestments and elaborately holders-who are the largest
                        consumers of playing the Greek Anthem, as well as the vigine, av. A.
                        Mortera, et 50 passagers de 3me so they should do both for their own
                        interests day morning at an Armeniais tababonist's in decorated robes of
                        these ecclesiastics presented perishable goods in this country. band of the
                        warship. As the Hydra steamed classe.. and the interests of those employed
                        on them Bourse street. The Alexandria Fire Brian admirable coup d'ail.
                        Immediately behind the The capitalists requested that the company's towards
                        the entrance of the harbour, she was Le paquebot Bofors, arrivé hier de
                        Venise and who travel on them. de promptly extinguished the conflagra
                        Vicur-General, the archimandrites, and the operations should be extended,
                        and that it followed by Mr. Minotto's steamer and in- avait à bord: tion.
                        The dange is estimated at £20. The priests, the bride followed, leaning on
                        the arm of should deal in all perishable provisions, and numerable small
                        sailing boats, crammed with M. et Mile N. Syrigo, M. et Mnie C: Pardo, means
                        of drawing public attention and the I sincerely hope this incident will be
                        the soitents of the shop were insured for 12,000 her father. She looked
                        charming and her dress not in meat alone. The company therefore enthusiastic
                        and excited crowds, who greeted baron &amp; de Merope et fam, Me Manusardi,
                        attention of the Government to the immediate fs. Another fire broke out last
                        night in a house elicited general admiration. made the above mentioned issue
                        in order to the departure of the vessel with continued A. Liuni, Fannal,
                        Comp. Gianoli, Emma Co necessity of placing river steamers under com Her
                        long at Kate Ashri, but was soon put out also. traiti was borne by a lovely
                        little child, garbed extend its sphere of operations to meet the and
                        repeated cheers. On the steam launch louna, baron A. de Menasca, Mme
                        Acavalos, pulsory inspection. wishes of these gentlemen. we remarked,
                        besides the Diplomatic repre- De Hanghy et sa dame, K-Figari, Vogel, Marta
                        The bridegroom followed, leaning on Ma The Board of the Nile Cold Storage
                        Com-sentative of Greece, M. Gennadis, and the Lindemann, Mme Sinmoth, Herr
                        Woolf, Amelia Yours truly, BEZ CASAL On the 17th inst, 15 vessels dame Saba
                        Fasha's arm. That lady's dress was pany has also decided to erect a cold
                        store at Consul-General, M. Scotidis, all the leading Kommel, Me Rossi et sa
                        fam, Silvio Fabbris, were British, I French, I Austrian, 1 Spanish, creation
                        in ivoire chiffon with appliques. Alexandris on a much larger scale than the
                        members of the Greek colony here, M. E. Colucci et sa dame, Cie Dame
                        Viennes, Thorn Turkish, Egyptian, German, and I Danish bevy of bridesmaids,
                        exquisitely dressed, follow-use ready approaching completion at Port
                        Benachi, M. M. Sinadino, M. S. Salvago, M. et tam, C. Monni et sa dame,
                        Silvio Ramazzotti, The transit and passenger dues for the day dark beauty in
                        a pale blue dress. The cortège that the company will import and yet will
                        still enthusiasm and excitement manifested on the arrivé ce matin de Trieste
                        avait à bord ed, led by Mr. Saba and Miss Tagher, a Said. This Alexandria
                        cold store will be suffi-G. Zervudachi, M. J. Cartalis, and many others, G.
                        Zuccani et 80 passagers de 3me classe Muted to 40,683,30 frs. The total
                        transit advanced down the steps, while the guests have a large space which
                        can be let out to launch were great. Mr. Minotto himself climb ciently
                        extensive to store all the provisions most also with their wives and
                        children. The Le paquebot Habsburg du Lloyd Autrichien and passenger des
                        colected from the 1st to silently and respectfully fell back to make way
                        merchants, hotel proprietors, eto. that date on 209 vessels amounted to
                        5,08,201.04 for M. Gelse, Mme Schriffes, Mme Rundt, for them. As the bridal
                        procession came to ed on to one of the masts and saluted from Brioni, Mme
                        Constantinidis, is fille et Nico- wards the spot where the sacred ceremony
                        was The cold store at Cairo will be completed thence the departing ship.
                        When the Hydra aidi, Sehway et 1 comp, de Montag, Orninger, to take place, a
                        startling and beautiful effect this week, and already the first of a weekly
                        reached the entrance of the harbour, the Tamarky, Dragits, Caravopoulos,
                        Havodynsky THE KHEDIVE. was produced by the sudden illumination of series of
                        shipments of game, poultry, fish, accompanying steamer and boats returned.
                        Klenier, Metzer, Mme Ruppa et sa sear, of numberless electric lamps, which
                        were arranged butter, eggs, etc., is en route and will arrive and in like
                        manner escorted the warship Spetsai Fischer, Agilla et 1 bébé, Mme Baila, 2
                        comp, The Khedive left Cairo, this morning for in festoons. before the end
                        of this month. out of the harbour. The flagship Para was et 1 bébé, Cap-
                        Gelletich, Spitzer, Fowler, Mine and author of "Sight Testing for the
                        Mastazah, where he is, spending the day. The capital of the company is only
                        £50,000, the last to leave, amidst an uproar of cheers Steinbach, Mme Stein,
                        Paravicini, Hehske, Medical Practitioner "Befraction Work," aded by IE the
                        Governor of Alexandria. The actual ceremony was performed in that the return
                        on this small capital should shouting, waying of hats, and, the playing of
                        Molteul, Dr. Faller, Mme Hanson, Gessler,te.. May be consulted for the
                        Khedive gave audience at Abdeen accordance with the quaint and solemn rites
                        be large, especially in view of the fact that the music. Pale on Saturday
                        morning to Herr von of the Syrian Greek Catholic Melchite Churche largest
                        consumers are interested as share Blow, Sir William Willocks, the Archbishop
                        The rubric of this ritual has been handed down</p>
                    <p>gased thigh the Suez Canal. Of these, s</p>
                    <p>of Mount Sinai, and the new Cadi Sheikh Abd el Balan Fods, and in the
                        afternoon to Abd Hamid Abaza Effendi and Sheikh Bakri Ahgar and his son.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday afternoon the Earl of Cromer printed to His Highness the mearbers
                        of the Railway Commission</p>
                    <p>On Sunday afternoon His Highness gave dience to HE Ismail Sabri Fashs and Sir
                        Will Garstin, K.C.M.G.</p>
                    <p>AF on Sunday HRH Prince George Duke of Brunswick Laneberg and the Bart of
                        Cromer visited tiss Khedive at Aldeen Palace 46-3.30 pm- His Highness
                        returned the visit, paling upon H.R.H. Prince George at Shepherd's
                        Hotel.</p>
                    <p>The Khave has bestowed the following ranks on the undermentioned officials
                        Moutamais Malmond Choukry Bay, Chiet</p>
                    <p>in blue</p>
                    <p>THE MARRIAGE RITE</p>
                    <p>from the Byzantine epoch, and the curious chants and elaborate ceremonial are
                        survivals from the earliest era of the Eastern Church.</p>
                    <p>holders.</p>
                    <p>RAILWAY COMMISSION</p>
                    <p>Cairo, November 20.</p>
                    <p>BOILER TENDER.</p>
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. E. DAVIDSON 140, Great Portland Street, London, Ophthalmic Optician, 9
                        eacher of Sight Testing</p>
                    <p>SPECTACLES</p>
                    <p>dom. et 1 bébé, Pantaleo, Ehrlich, Mme Heller, The beautiful weather added to
                        the bright Squarding, Muller, Thomoe et sa fille, M. ness and animation of
                        the scene, and it being Holzner, K. Reiber-Stieglitz et 2 enfants, A. at the
                        HOTEL ABRATE for a a Sunday afternoon, large numbers of the Denners, Mie,
                        Kingham, 2 enfants et dom, working classes also had collected to witness A.
                        Maller, Dr F. Bagel Bey, M. et Mme Kyan, Mr. DAVIDSON in the inventor of
                        many Short Time Only.</p>
                    <p>Defective Vision</p>
                    <p>the departure. It may be remarked that the Carlo Waiter, M. et Mme Weekes, M.
                        et Mme</p>
                    <p>In the absence of the Patriarch of the Syrian morning to examine the line
                        between Zagazigions, also manifested on this final one that Bay, Prince
                        Ibrahim Hilmi et 8 de fam, Mine The Railway Commission left Cairo this Greek
                        colony, as-on all preceding ecca Revel, Mme Cattani bey et sa fille, M.
                        Cattail of the latest appliances for dealing with Greek Catholic Melchite
                        Church, His Holiness and Dessouk. The members will afterwards go patriotism
                        and enthusiasm regarding their fleet Weyermann et 2 de fam, M. et Mme A and
                        cordially invites all medical men to Kyrillos Goha, who is at present at
                        Rome, the to Tantali, whence they come on to Alexandria, which cannot but
                        impress the observer and Cattani, Kaufmann, Dr Wengler, M. Weil, marriage
                        ceremony was conducted by the Right arriving here at 8.20 p.m. Reverend
                        Kyrillos Risk: Vicar General of the Patriarchate.</p>
                    <p>THE SUPPER</p>
                    <p>After the ceremony the bride and bride grooms and Saba Pasha and his wife
                        received the heartiest congratulations of all present. Ices and sweets were
                        then handed round.</p>
                    <p>prove to him the close and powerful ties which Schmidt, Vogel, M. et Mme
                        Pittack, Mayer, exist between the mother country, Greece pro- bébé et gouv.,
                        Liepmann, sa dame et 3 enfants per, and the rich and powerful Greek colony
                        Johnson Pacha, Spreafico et 2 de fam et 46 in Bgypt. passagers de 3me
                        classe.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURES</p>
                    <p>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE Last night, Hamlet, the French composer Thomas's most
                        substantial production, and Mignon, his most genial, were given at the whole
                        stay of the fleet here, there has not been It may be remarked that
                        throughout the Alhambra and Abbas Helmy Theatre, respect conduct among the
                        Greek sailors when in the cited a single example of disorderly or bad ively.
                        The performance of the latter was town, a fact which reflects the highest
                        chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait à bord: Le paquebot Semiramis, du
                        Lloyd Autri The bonbons were lavishly distributed among frantically
                        applauded. The representation was credit on the discipline and good conduct
                        both the guests, elaborately arranged in Japanese trom every point of view
                        excellent. Signs of the officers and men. MM. Rud. Patienhofer, Mma
                        Goldslees, time paper tied with pink silk Javours. At Monti-Baldini fully
                        justified the celebrity Aram d'Ambro, Gewinner, B. Springer, Wiese,
                        Yesterday evening, at the Greek Club here C. Moeri, Blao, Frita Pam, Miles
                        Kaisler,</p>
                    <p>11 o'clock the supper buffets were thrown open</p>
                    <p>THE GUESTS</p>
                    <p>them and to teak their practical utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 19.30 and 2 to 6.</p>
                    <p>Mr DAVIDSON'S latest invention bsolutely prevents any of the effects of
                        patented) is a new SUN GLASS, which Sun Glare.</p>
                    <p>Bulkalay, Ramlah Newly is</p>
                    <p>9401984-1</p>
                    <p>which she lisa sequired on the European stage, most of the leading members of
                        the Greek Paul Biso, Marco Mattatia et 22 passagers de CARLTON HOTEL, and an
                        exquisite repast was partaken of by all it would be dithout indeed to find a
                        more colony met and discussed the means of raising 3me classe. Clerk to the
                        Khedivial Deligstion at Constan present tinople graceful and perfect Mignon.
                        The prinsa donna the sum which is to be contributed towards was well
                        seconded by the tenor Tomiani; who the fleet. Banich Aly Pound Effendi,
                        attaché to the Two thousand invitations had been issued made his debut last
                        night and met with con same delegation. for the marriage; and the throng of
                        wedding derable success. The other artistes were all Gamal Nagin Effendi,
                        second clerk to the gooit was very grist, but owing to the good in their
                        respective roles, while the or enormous available space there was no eresh
                        chestra worked wonders</p>
                    <p>same</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAL AT FORT SAID. has arrived. The ships were welcomed by Port Said,
                        Monday-The Greek Squadron GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, enthusiastic crowds on
                        launches and on the breakwater</p>
                    <p>ALMEANDRIA 8. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED,</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <!-- page 4 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DERNIERE HSURE</head>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                    <p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL. qui en feront la demande pourront accom</p>
                    <p>The widows of the late Khedive Ismail arriv. ed at Cairo yesterday morning
                        from Constanti nople.</p>
                    <p>The correspondent of the Times at Rome writing on the 9th inst., pays the
                        following</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER, 21, 1904</p>
                    <p>pagner le Mabmal. Les pèlerins qui suivront e tapis sacré se trouveront dans
                        les meilleures conditions de confort, d'écono- mie et de sécurité
                        désirables.</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui voudront accompa gner le Mabmal et profiter de ces avants-
                        ges devront en faire is demande à leur 4ouvernorat ou mon lirich an mois
                        su</p>
                    <p>21 novembre</p>
                    <p>Trieste et Brindisi; 61 h, vapaute. Habsburg, esp. Klaneberger, son: $42, an
                        Lloyd Antishies. Newle: 16j 1,2 ap. ang. Heldswell, cap Willes, ton. 1609,
                        &amp; Barber &amp; Son. Manchester es Malte4j. 1/3vap sog Grecian Prince,
                        cap Claridge, tom. 1405, &amp; Grace &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>moins avant le départ, c'est-à dire avant le STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>tribute to Sir Bennell Rodd: "Very great regret is felt in all quarters here
                        at the depart 31 décembre prochain et effectuer un dépôt ure of Sir Rennell
                        Rodd, the new Minister at te L.E. 25 en première classe, 22 en deu-
                        Stockholm, who leaves Rome to-morrow. Dur xième classe, 18 en troisième
                        classe. Ce ing his three years' service as Secretary of the arif est convenu
                        poar i chamead seale- Embassy, he has gained, not only the respectment. La
                        location de tout chameau supplé bat also the affection of all who have come
                        in mentaire sera comptée en plus à raison de contact with him; and this has
                        been partien L.E.13 1/2 en première classe. Ea troisième, larly the case
                        with the Italian official world, deas pèlerina s'arrangent pour voyager who
                        have always had for him a very high and vee un seul chameau, ils psieront
                        chacun 12 L.E. Si ces sommes n'ont pas été inté- alement dépensées pour le
                        compte da pèlerin, le surplus lui sera remboursé après soa retour.</p>
                    <p>marked esteem.</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. Hashim, chef de bureau of the Public Security Department at the
                        Alexandria Gou vernorat, has been promoted to the post of chef de bureau at
                        the Ministry of Interior.</p>
                    <p>QUESTIONS MUNICIPALES</p>
                    <p>Cloring Friese, to-day at 1 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Debenture</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>COPER DE LA DEPECHS DE L'ALEXANDRIA GENERAL PRODUCE</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL COTTON A880CIATION.</p>
                    <p>(Coare pentiquée se jour à la Bourse Khódiviale 108.15's m.)</p>
                    <p>-5 15 21.83 Livesison Novembre</p>
                    <p>$ 15 2/89</p>
                    <p>$15 25/32</p>
                    <p>Marché quist</p>
                    <p>Janvier Marn</p>
                    <p>Krivage d'oier et la ce jour, à Minet-el-Bassal .85,786</p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khédiviale 19h.45 p.m.)</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>BANKS Imperial Ovomen Beak... Nations! Bank of Egypt... New Insas 28
                        15:16</p>
                    <p>$ 15 1/3</p>
                    <p>$15 21/33</p>
                    <p>Marché quiet</p>
                    <p>24 5/16 Fos. 488 L.E. 1 ex Fos. 295</p>
                    <p>Fem. 1000</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui suivent le Mahmal LE. 56 et effectuent les dépôts ci-dessus
                        sont dis- pensées des autres formalités, excepté pour-518 sant du passeport
                        qui est toujours de igueur.</p>
                    <p>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demi).</p>
                    <p>Le marché des valeurs se maintient ferme et en hausse.</p>
                    <p>A</p>
                    <p>Il manquait à notre Municipalité, pour être complète, un corps de police
                        spécial Cette lacune, à peine signalée, vient d'être comblée. Déjà la
                        Délégation et le Gouver- norat se sont occupés da nombre et du salaire de ce
                        noavesa personnel. Il ne reste plus qu'à soumettre la proposition à la La
                        Banque Nationale atteint en clôture Commission Municipale. Quelles vont être
                        les attributions de cette police indépen- 24 5/16, la Wardan 7 7/8, la
                        Brasserie des dante, de cet Etat dans l'Etat, nous avons Pyramides 182, les
                        Markets 27, les Eaux en soin de le demander. Si nos informa d'Alexandrie 16
                        15/16, les Eaux du Caire tions sont exsictes, ce corps est destiné à 1090,
                        les Privilégiés Tramways 146 1/2 prêter main forte sax percepteurs munici-et
                        les Dividendes 385. psax, en ce qui concerne en particulier Is Saxe du 20/0.
                        Cet impôt que le contribu- able sisé paie sans difficulté, le pauvre est
                        obligé quelquefois de le refuser. C'est à quoi va servir la nouvelle police.
                        Les dé</p>
                    <p>bria de meubles de es malheureux seront vendus séance tenante et toutes les
                        mesures de rigueur qui sont permises par la loi, impitoyablement
                        appliquées.</p>
                    <p>Après avoir décroché de nouveau le prix de 40, la Salt &amp; Sods est
                        retombée in elóture à 39/6.</p>
                    <p>La Bébéra fléchit légèrement à 56, les Press Libres à 28 1/2,
                        l'Anglo-American</p>
                    <p>Nile à 5 1/4, et la Delta Light à 15 5/16.</p>
                    <p>Comme à ce trait on reconnait bien Anglo-Egyptian Spinning &amp; Weaving
                        Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>l'esprit qui anime notre Municipalité! Bi</p>
                    <p>cette conduite odieuse pouvais augmenter</p>
                    <p>de façon notable les recettes de la ville,</p>
                    <p>passe encore. Mais cette armée de pereep-</p>
                    <p>'ASSEMBLEE GENERALE ORDINAIRE.</p>
                    <p>th. 8916 F. 108 #1716.</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Grece...</p>
                    <p>Banque Industrielle Crédit Foncier Egyption Lottery Bonda</p>
                    <p>Sis 19 82 Livaison Novembre Janvier Mors</p>
                    <p>21 novembre:</p>
                    <p>EXTERIEUR</p>
                    <p>Déplebee parienes de 19 novembre 1904 PRODUITS GYPTIONS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOG Coton: Bial da Marahi-Satan Disponibis: Berde: iame sure Pature
                        déoscabre :8 9/84 (4/94 de baie) LIVERPOOK</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton-Sano changement Frus-Peu d'affaires</p>
                    <p>Grainas de coton-Mane cours Frees-Calme</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Fermes</p>
                    <p>Graine de colon From-Harebé nal</p>
                    <p>COTON.AMERICAIN LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Fates janvige-févrise: 5.21 (1 point de bias)</p>
                    <p>msi-jain: 5 31 (1 point de baisso Disponible: 5.82 († points de paises)</p>
                    <p>NEW YORK</p>
                    <p>Middling Upland: 1301 mm 001 Fame Jeur-$45,6 poias de baisse)</p>
                    <p>Marché de Minet-el-Bassal</p>
                    <p>21 novembre 1904-(11h.56 a.m.) Cotons: Cloare da marché da 19 novembre: Moins
                        d'affaires</p>
                    <p>BRUKERS</p>
                    <p>Fair. Fally Fair, Good Fair, Fully Good Pai- et Good: Très calme</p>
                    <p>ZAUTH-RAPPTE E FATOUM</p>
                    <p>Fair et Fully Fair: Bien. Good Pair, Fally Good Pair of Good: Très calme</p>
                    <p>Sme quali 6,Ire qualité, Extra: Calme JANNOVION</p>
                    <p>me quali, Ire qualité, Extra: Calme</p>
                    <p>Bu da marebé de ce jour, cot: Moins de demande prix faible..</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages d'hier et de ce jour se chiffren par mamare 69,149 coatre mème
                        jour l'année précé- dente canters 78,088.</p>
                    <p>LONDON STOCK EXCHANGE</p>
                    <p>8 13 Government</p>
                    <p>ABARST</p>
                    <p>EXCHANGE QUOTATION</p>
                    <p>London abeque</p>
                    <p>Bin-back paper Shogun papee</p>
                    <p>Paris obeque</p>
                    <p>8m. bank 8- hoge Switzerland Germany</p>
                    <p>Imlian cheque pape</p>
                    <p>Vienne &amp; Priva Joarantinople obeque..</p>
                    <p>479</p>
                    <p>SHARE LIST</p>
                    <p>ISSUED BY THE "ASSOCIATION DES COURTIE VALNUSS D'AGETANDRIN".</p>
                    <p>Lai: 11-</p>
                    <p>agypian Del Bul. exo... 51,4</p>
                    <p>#11-</p>
                    <p>Agris. Bank</p>
                    <p>LAND, &amp;c. Agris-Industrielle Beypt Fond</p>
                    <p>420 900</p>
                    <p>4-834</p>
                    <p>Behera Company... Egyptian Deln Land Co.</p>
                    <p>7.78</p>
                    <p>Wardan Briate Ocy.</p>
                    <p>61/4</p>
                    <p>Mai: 990 &amp; pointe la asissa Arrivages du jour: bile 43030 Contre m4ms in
                        Pen - 16 Pointer: balles 525,00 contre balles 335,000</p>
                    <p>Coons Oricines</p>
                    <p>83.11</p>
                    <p>Closure d'aujourd'hui</p>
                    <p>1a. 45 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Agria. Bank of Beyps</p>
                    <p>Land &amp; Morgage..</p>
                    <p>Nat Back Bype</p>
                    <p>21 5/8</p>
                    <p>80 1.</p>
                    <p>498 1/3</p>
                    <p>56</p>
                    <p>Pes. 238</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>151</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>New Daira Banish Fond. COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL Alex. Bonded Storse Pref.
                        Anglo-Egypt.Spinning Co. Boures Kaldivials pref. Cairo Sewage Trans- [port
                        Ord. Cr. Brewery, Alex., Fond. do 8%. Deba. do Cairo Fond.</p>
                    <p>129</p>
                    <p>Baalen sailway</p>
                    <p>frainwaye d'Alexandrie Fos. 45 1/2</p>
                    <p>147</p>
                    <p>41</p>
                    <p>div. 885</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>Alersadria Water</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>61 185 600 72</p>
                    <p>Prices on Tuesday, November 15, 1904, Console a/e...</p>
                    <p>Lais 15 15/16</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>dex da chire</p>
                    <p>Fe-: 1085-</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Dala sanish</p>
                    <p>Lot 31 58</p>
                    <p>Console Cash...</p>
                    <p>88 19 93 14</p>
                    <p>G</p>
                    <p>-113 -Sp</p>
                    <p>décem</p>
                    <p>LK. 55-8/4</p>
                    <p>514</p>
                    <p>dourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>Let 23 1/3</p>
                    <p>Egyptian 4% Uaifel 105-</p>
                    <p>&lt;-13</p>
                    <p>Byptian Markets.</p>
                    <p>871</p>
                    <p>4 114 Seats....</p>
                    <p>Sh. 7/9 Sh. 17</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton Mills</p>
                    <p>Angio Egyptina Spinning</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>Domain -104-</p>
                    <p>105-</p>
                    <p>do Markete</p>
                    <p>dière d'Alexandre Priv. Fos.: 33</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>Di</p>
                    <p>do Salt and Boda Fond</p>
                    <p>Prof. D -99 48</p>
                    <p>100-13</p>
                    <p>Ciments d'Egypte</p>
                    <p>da Uaire</p>
                    <p>Priv.</p>
                    <p>www www</p>
                    <p>34 Ias ribed</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>Div.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Syndicate... B.</p>
                    <p>4% Dairs 1980. xD 100</p>
                    <p>101</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>9 7/16 82</p>
                    <p>Kafr-el-Zayst Coston Coy. 109 New Bgyptian Company... Nangovich Hotels</p>
                    <p>Tarlosh 4% Uni-d</p>
                    <p>85 914</p>
                    <p>98.1</p>
                    <p>Sat &amp; doda</p>
                    <p>Granos de coton.-Pea de demande</p>
                    <p>Anerine God. 4.99 19</p>
                    <p>100 It</p>
                    <p>Promage</p>
                    <p>Disponible</p>
                    <p>Ticket</p>
                    <p>French 8% Banter...</p>
                    <p>87-</p>
                    <p>Presses Libe</p>
                    <p>Bouidé des Hailerice at</p>
                    <p>Mit-A-Baisse 10/40</p>
                    <p>Bian</p>
                    <p>German 3% 1898-</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>Oong. Uréfis Foncier</p>
                    <p>[Savon.</p>
                    <p>Haute-Brypto-Bisse 10,40</p>
                    <p>Bign</p>
                    <p>Greek 5% 1881</p>
                    <p>46 12</p>
                    <p>47-1</p>
                    <p>2612 18 13</p>
                    <p>Ind. de Karmons Presenge at Dépôte 102 Prosse Labres...</p>
                    <p> 5%</p>
                    <p>Fes. 94-</p>
                    <p>Blés-Petite demande</p>
                    <p>Italian 5% 188</p>
                    <p>118 84</p>
                    <p>104:1</p>
                    <p>Lum Paros et talon</p>
                    <p>125-</p>
                    <p>Qualité Satdi: Cond. Sahs P.T. 118 &amp; 180</p>
                    <p>Besan 4% Oon, 1889</p>
                    <p>93 114</p>
                    <p>438</p>
                    <p>109</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS.</p>
                    <p>Bihira Fives-Néant</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>n</p>
                    <p>116 139</p>
                    <p>Japan 5%</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>fja</p>
                    <p>#8-114</p>
                    <p>16 16 16 For..1090</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amer. Nile &amp;c. Co. Khedivial Mail S.S. ho. [Co. Fonds. 14/6 Alex.
                        Water Company Cairo Fonds. Tanish " "Fonds. BAILWAYS &amp; TRAMWAYS</p>
                    <p>Baldi-Bien</p>
                    <p>United States 4% 1945 x D 18: Daira Shaish</p>
                    <p>Saqas In laasrielle</p>
                    <p>184-</p>
                    <p>Jasa di socato</p>
                    <p>LS. 14 Fos.247</p>
                    <p>244</p>
                    <p>814</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amaha Nole</p>
                    <p>La 55-16</p>
                    <p>198</p>
                    <p>183-</p>
                    <p>of dam</p>
                    <p>For 181 3/4</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>National Bank.</p>
                    <p>112</p>
                    <p>Jeferred Dela</p>
                    <p>Let 17 14</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>Now...</p>
                    <p>718</p>
                    <p>938</p>
                    <p>650</p>
                    <p>88/4</p>
                    <p>Agricultural Banks</p>
                    <p>8% Bonds 73 pd 103</p>
                    <p>P.- #15 5/16</p>
                    <p>Basse Egypt, Fonds..... Delta Light..</p>
                    <p>195</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>COTON</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>do do Def.......</p>
                    <p>17 88</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>Cond. Baba P.T. 70 &amp; 78</p>
                    <p>Delta Leads 5-paid...</p>
                    <p>Cairo-Helona...</p>
                    <p>07</p>
                    <p>Exportation du mois d'octobre 1904.</p>
                    <p>Deferre...</p>
                    <p>Fayoum: disponible: Rin</p>
                    <p>Qualité Baldi: Cond. Baba P.T. 97 &amp; 92 Lentilles-Stationnaires</p>
                    <p>Disponible: Bien</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saba P.T. 82 &amp; 95</p>
                    <p>Orges: Bant ohangement</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. 50 &amp; 54 Mate: Mome allure Disponible: Bian</p>
                    <p>Delta Preference</p>
                    <p>Deferred......</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>Preferred..... 9718</p>
                    <p>104</p>
                    <p>igypting Joston Mille Lat</p>
                    <p>Banque Nat de Grice az.o... 482</p>
                    <p>Nangorina Hol</p>
                    <p>Dele Land</p>
                    <p>teurs civile, flu quée d'une armée de poi</p>
                    <p>Fayoum... Keach-Assocan.</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>480</p>
                    <p>do Foods 985</p>
                    <p>Messieurs les actionnaires sont convoqués. siers, occasionners des frais plus
                        considé-en Assemblée Générale Ordinaire le Lundi.98 814 rables que le
                        produit des taxes même. N 12 Décembre prochain à 5 h. de relevée. 148 1/3
                        Alexandria Trans... serait-il pas plus économique en me ne dans les locaux
                        de la National Bank of temps que plas humanitaire, sinon d'exo-Egypt à
                        Alexandrie. nérer de la taxe ces malheureux payant un faible loyer, du moins
                        de laisser les choars en l'état où elles sont ?</p>
                    <p>Nous connaissons trop malheureusement les tendances de nos conseillers pour
                        douter un moment qu'ils ne snetionnent Is me- sure proposé par la
                        Délégation. Ils ont tonjours déployé beaucoup de cèl pour la perception des
                        impôs et s'ils avaient montré la même rigu ur dans l'adminis- tration des
                        dépenses, ils ne mériteraient que des éloges.</p>
                    <p>ORDRE DU JOUR:</p>
                    <p>Rapport du onseil d'Administration, Approbation des comptes,</p>
                    <p>Election des censeurs.</p>
                    <p>Les porteurs d'actions devront, pour prendre part à l'assemblée, déposer
                        leurs actions 3 jours au moins avant la réunion dans une des Banques
                        ci-après désignées au Caire ou à Alexandrie.</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Egypt, Crédit Lyon nais, Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ld., Banque
                        Impétale Ottomane, Bank of Egypt Ld, on an Siège de la Compagnie à
                        Liverpool, 17, Sweeting Street.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 21 Novembre 1904 Le Président,</p>
                    <p>Nous aurons done une police municipale C'est une affaire entendae et qui sera
                        décidée à l'unanimité comme l'a été l'exelu- sion de la presse des séances,
                        comme va l'être bientôt le renvoi de la question des maisons ouvrières aux
                        calendes grecques. Au moins nous sera-t-il permis de suggérer A notre
                        Municipalité une oeupation plas utile pour cette police que la poursuite de
                        malheureux, nous voulons dire la mise en The Khedivial Mail Steamship
                        vigueur d'un système de poids et meenree</p>
                    <p>24931-8-1</p>
                    <p>ELWIN PALMER.</p>
                    <p>poinçonnés, fabriqués par l'Etat et délivrés and Graving Dock Company,
                        Limited.</p>
                    <p>aux marchands contre le prix de facture, Ce serait rendre aux pauvres un peu
                        de NOTICE IS HEREBY GIVEN that the cette justio qui leur est cons'amment re-
                        fusée que d'obliger ainsi los détaillants à Seventh Ordinary General Meeting
                        of the lede livrer le poids exact. Les bacals, les above Company, will be
                        held at Winchester marchands de légumes et de poissons, les House, Old Broad
                        Street, London, E C., boulang ra, las boashses, eta on, en eff, on Monday,
                        28th day of November, 1904, des poids inférieurs de 15 20 0/0 su paid at
                        noon; to receive and pass the Directors' 16gal. Ainsi le pauvre n'est pas
                        seulement Report and Accounts, to elect Directors vistime de la négligence
                        des autorités on ad Auditors, and to transact the ordinary ee qui regarde le
                        servies des quartiers, business of the Company.. l'embelissement et
                        l'assainissement, il est ensors volé sur la qualité et la quantité de s
                        nourriture et cela par la coupable in- carie de la Municipalité.</p>
                    <p>La elese aiség mit et peut faire res-</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, the 21st November, 1904. 24,935-1</p>
                    <p>peeter ses droits, andis que le pauvre reste MOUVEMENT MARITIME</p>
                    <p>Impaisant; et la Municipalité, sa ieu de lui venir en side dans ce qu ses
                        reven li estions peuvent avoir de légitime, s'on- cupe uniquement de le
                        pres-arer pour en obtenir jusqu'à la dernière piastre.</p>
                    <p>Le pelerinage de 1905 Le ministère de l'Intérieur vient de pablier la
                        circulaire relative su pèlerinage</p>
                    <p>de 1905.</p>
                    <p>En voidjan court sparça</p>
                    <p>DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p>ARRIVERS</p>
                    <p>19 novembre</p>
                    <p>Anvers it Malte; 4j..vsp ang Osa Prines, cap. Kirkwood, ton 1,074. &amp;
                        Grace &amp; Co. Smyrne et Pirie: #j, vap. hall. Byzantion, cap Mas romatio,
                        ton. 400, &amp; Kuchayas. 20 novembre</p>
                    <p>Alexandreite: vap. ang. Mariont, op. Silvestri, son 880, à la Kh4divial Mail.
                        Constantinople es girde: 40 h., vap ang. Prines Abbas, cap, Anderlich, tom.
                        861, à la Khedivial Mail.</p>
                    <p>Hambourg et Malte: 4) 11), vap all. Thissos, esp. Starke, ton. 1,80 &amp;
                        Bross.</p>
                    <p>Tries 73 84. vap ang. Crown Prince, a Thomas,</p>
                    <p>ton 16:16, &amp; Grace &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Les prix suivants ont été pratiquée ce jour</p>
                    <p>85/8 Bamleh Railway... Furnished by Baid &amp; Barnard 10, S. Marka
                        Vaildings, Alexandria, a haris Kural-Nil Damanhour... iro, who underks the
                        esle and purchase of oke and darsa, on the lossl Boarse ant also of he
                        London Brook Exchange.</p>
                    <p>BOURSE KREDIVIALS</p>
                    <p>Remarques sur le marché da disponible et Contrasts. Samedi, le 19 novembre
                        1904. Coton: ion a été bonne et elle été favorisée par le fait Disponible-La
                        demands de la part de l'exporta que maig 4 los afforis des détenteurs elle
                        n'a pas complètement anivi la hausse des contrats.</p>
                    <p>Les qualités laissent à désirer et ceste circonstance sendrait à donner
                        maison à ceux qui disent que la deolte a pent-être plus souffert qu'on ne le
                        préten- dis. Mentionnons aussi l'opinion qui eommence à révaloir que
                        l'Alexandria General Produce Associs- tion se trouvera probablemens dans la
                        nécessité de rédaire quelque pen en précédente e-timation</p>
                    <p>Kar-Zaysi... Tromb......</p>
                    <p>Coton G.M.B.</p>
                    <p>(BASER RETPTH) Province Bébér De P.T. 290 Provines Garbish</p>
                    <p>De P.P. 815</p>
                    <p>820-625-</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 165-270-</p>
                    <p>(HAUTH-ROYPTS)</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 872 1/3 &amp; 375</p>
                    <p>Dairs Sugar</p>
                    <p>Sals &amp; Sode</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Market...</p>
                    <p>34</p>
                    <p>Ingleterre</p>
                    <p>33/8</p>
                    <p>France</p>
                    <p>9,18</p>
                    <p>Russie</p>
                    <p>atricha</p>
                    <p>Italie</p>
                    <p>Allemagne</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES A MINER-EL-BASS&amp;L.</p>
                    <p>Espagne</p>
                    <p>Balles 4</p>
                    <p>Balles 74</p>
                    <p>Suède</p>
                    <p>Turquie, Grèce et Boumanie</p>
                    <p>Pesant cantars 564,65.60</p>
                    <p>N.B.-Dans les expéditions pour l'An orre aout comprises balles 4,97 à dest
                        tion des Etats-Unis.</p>
                    <p>Sile Valley</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>par Cantar</p>
                    <p>800-</p>
                    <p>835</p>
                    <p>du mois de novembe 903</p>
                    <p>Suisse</p>
                    <p>Da</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Graines de outon</p>
                    <p>Faver</p>
                    <p>(MOYENNE-GYPTA)</p>
                    <p>Belgique</p>
                    <p>1, b.</p>
                    <p>8827</p>
                    <p>ardeba 8.276</p>
                    <p>Province Fayoum</p>
                    <p>Hollande</p>
                    <p>4-12</p>
                    <p>25,810</p>
                    <p>Fayoum Baai-Sogef...</p>
                    <p>Indea</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>6707</p>
                    <p>25.310</p>
                    <p>674</p>
                    <p>24,973</p>
                    <p>Japon</p>
                    <p>8525</p>
                    <p>26,389</p>
                    <p>6-17</p>
                    <p>26,168</p>
                    <p>7.</p>
                    <p>871</p>
                    <p>19343</p>
                    <p>523</p>
                    <p>SECTION DES GRAINES ET CEREALES PRIE FRANOO-STATION: DISPONESAR Graines de
                        colon AAA P.T. 68- Pause Saili Haute-Bgypte Fayoumi</p>
                    <p>24,'91</p>
                    <p>7,40</p>
                    <p>164</p>
                    <p>TIONWT</p>
                    <p>10,</p>
                    <p>8,094</p>
                    <p>&amp;P.T.</p>
                    <p>11.</p>
                    <p>1085</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>56 1/3</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>5,738</p>
                    <p>21791</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>35.71</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>14.</p>
                    <p>8139</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>499</p>
                    <p>99</p>
                    <p>8,165</p>
                    <p>24156</p>
                    <p>1,353</p>
                    <p>8583</p>
                    <p>93 355</p>
                    <p>65</p>
                    <p>7023</p>
                    <p>3123</p>
                    <p>657</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>541</p>
                    <p>2670</p>
                    <p>91</p>
                    <p>90,</p>
                    <p>8.-11</p>
                    <p>28.177</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>31.</p>
                    <p>7.659</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>Association."</p>
                    <p>16,707</p>
                    <p>571</p>
                    <p>CHEMINS DE FAR 8/B 698</p>
                    <p>13,</p>
                    <p>.6 103</p>
                    <p>37,91</p>
                    <p>717</p>
                    <p>1535.</p>
                    <p>24,</p>
                    <p>1,816</p>
                    <p>2,384</p>
                    <p>941</p>
                    <p>Ominee de coton. Show 97718 Be Saldi.**** Béhárs... Fives Saldi</p>
                    <p>4:47</p>
                    <p>16,620</p>
                    <p>11283</p>
                    <p>30</p>
                    <p>26,</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>14,795</p>
                    <p>467</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>829 461 12</p>
                    <p>6,325</p>
                    <p>35,414</p>
                    <p>1/32</p>
                    <p>230</p>
                    <p>80-7</p>
                    <p>881</p>
                    <p>7,574</p>
                    <p>8.411</p>
                    <p>5,891</p>
                    <p>78</p>
                    <p>289</p>
                    <p>9-71</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES</p>
                    <p>des dimanche 10 et lundi 21 novembre 1904- Documente de "Alexandria General
                        Prodne</p>
                    <p>Les embargaments sont bons et l'on crois que Cotons wax de décembre aussi ne
                        seront pas inférieure à ceux de l'année dernière.</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages ne s'améliorent pas, co qui, d'aprie quelques-uns, pourrait
                        bien atre attribué an Bas dnes sit bien être de l'Ag ieulture qui loi
                        permet</p>
                    <p>d soutenir la marchandise. Franeo-gare.-Sans affaires pour les raisons déjà
                        expliquées.</p>
                    <p>Bibers...</p>
                    <p>Orge...... Malt....** Lentillee</p>
                    <p>Tol des arrivages depuis le 1er septe bre 1904 Jasqu'à ce jour Canaire
                        9,101,011. Contre même jour en 1908</p>
                    <p>......</p>
                    <p>Contrats.-Récolte seinelle. Les haussiers ont continné dominer et pour un
                        moment les cours Of ont épousede janga'à al. 18 14 pour le mars. Anjourd'hui
                        nous elörene &amp; tal 18 7/8 ce qui fait que la réaction an foud n'a pas
                        été importante Tont fais il y a un désir marqué de réaliser, es qui prodoit
                        de l'incertit de dans l'allare du marché. La troisième filière de novembre a
                        atteint cantire 65 000 minis elle a été antée par ni groupe de pienlstears
                        ont-iders eo qui a eu pour unigne eff-s d'inspirer pour un moment un pea
                        plas do courage atix haneriers.</p>
                    <p>Le cottes Américaines is flasheent ui pen grand nombre de faseurs, leur
                        importanos ayant l'apparar ce d'ane.eonfirmation des estimations lancées en
                        dernier lieu os donoant is risolte Améri eine somme devant atteindre les
                        18,000,000 balles Nouvelle résolta. La nouvelle delte ne donnent presque pas
                        lieu à des affaires et is ea et absoln. ment desblia d'après l'oest da
                        marché pour la récole sourelle</p>
                    <p>Dans le austinée Prix plus hango marslaris 15 81/82&amp;1 plas bas pour murs
                        16 15 818/</p>
                    <p>Grain de eatin</p>
                    <p>Disponibles disponible a's off et rien d'inté reemant et toutes les
                        ductussions sont restdes confl nées intre PT. 69 at P.T. 58, aveo PT. 68
                        10-0 somme dernier cours. Les ex sortations sont mold et als évite at marché
                        de l'empressement de la part du commerce. Frano gare-Nalité somplète
                        Contrats-Béla semella-Affaires insigni.</p>
                    <p>Venise et Brindisi 67 h. vapital. Boafor, pants et fastsations is importance.
                        La marond Milasso, ten 1518, &amp; la Cia Florio Rabauino. Gleet Mes ios 8
                        h, vsp. ital. Tbe, cap., Mancini, on 19:8, &amp; Is Cis Plorio
                        Rabkinino.</p>
                    <p>Le passport est de rigueur et ne pint être délivré que sur production: 1' d'a
                        billet d'aller et retour délivré par le Khe divial Mail, 9° d'an certificat
                        constatan que ie pàterin a les moyens pécanisirea de faire le voyage 8 d'an
                        réépissé de dépúerine et Jaffa: 40 h. vap ang Bravo, &amp; Mes de P:B. 186.
                        L palerias étrangers son soumis aux mms conditions.</p>
                    <p>La madirish ou le gouvernorat degr tenir un registre de tous le passeporte
                        qu'elle délivre. et noter avee soin le nou des pålerine qui sont de retons.
                        Moyanna les conditions el-dessus toutes les personnes</p>
                    <p>Laren, to 694, &amp; Minotto</p>
                    <p>04 Naple:5j, vp ital. Moreo Minghatti, sp. Deo, ton. 1816, &amp; la Cis Flo
                        lo Rabst</p>
                    <p>Ost Blade: 1) 13, vap ve Tes,</p>
                    <p>Eame isti, ton. 1424, &amp; la Cle</p>
                    <p>chypre et Port-Haid 19 b, voy ang. Bar,</p>
                    <p>Chiasmaro, son. 1894, &amp; Minotto</p>
                    <p>p</p>
                    <p>et pusat soutes paste du pon de ven-leare Dans le mannée, plas aos pour
                        fem</p>
                    <p>P.7 61 10/40 18,40 pe bar your février-mes</p>
                    <p>61 8,40%-/-</p>
                    <p>Pro-Baldi:</p>
                    <p>BARQUNS AT ONEMINS DO FR 8/B 9555 Show 43994</p>
                    <p>199</p>
                    <p>www www</p>
                    <p>428</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>747</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>Gesines de coton Bia Saldi... vee Shidi. Báhára.</p>
                    <p>Bébérs</p>
                    <p>Onge Mate ... Lentilles... etons-Toesl des arrivages deptis le 1er engtou-
                        hes 1008 jusqu'à ce jour Cantare 2 101 011</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS, (1,88 a.m.) Cours de la Bourse de Minet-el-Baral Oelen
                        F.G.F.Br.</p>
                    <p>sb 1:7, ardebe 7-0098</p>
                    <p>N.8 Cette liste est relevée de registre de PAlex ndri General Pdece
                        Association"; mons aplions ada qa on passe la o aparera eo ar arrivages du
                        sos de nove eb é de deste ann'e</p>
                    <p>Alexandria General Produce Associat</p>
                    <p>No. 177.</p>
                    <p>SECTION COTONNIERE</p>
                    <p>Les différences de pris pour livraison Contrats de Coton, "de novembre" 1904,
                        on</p>
                    <p>inées comme suit:</p>
                    <p>BROWN.</p>
                    <p>ter</p>
                    <p>Sintre Fair et Fully Fair. Fully Fair et Good Pair Good Fair et Faily God
                        Fair, 72 E Fally Good Fair et Good... HAUTE-EGYPTE ET FLYOUM antre Fully
                        Fair et Good Fair</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>...P.T.</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>www.</p>
                    <p>Good Fair et Fully Good Fair Fally Good fair et Good Alexandrie, le 31
                        octobre 1904. Pour le comé, Le Président,</p>
                    <p>C. DE ISOHUDI</p>
                    <p>ADMINISTRATION</p>
                    <p>DES DOMAINE DE L'ETAT</p>
                    <p>Enchères de jeudi 17 novembre 1904, à 11h a.m.</p>
                    <p>A8SOCIATION DES COURTIERS EN MARCHANDISE (Service Special)</p>
                    <p>DEPROBE D'OUVERTUR</p>
                    <p>A.adrinin</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, 10b. &amp; m</p>
                    <p>Pasare: Janviar Povciae: 8.21</p>
                    <p>Paesi Mai-Jain 1-</p>
                    <p>Seconde Diplohe, 10h. 5</p>
                    <p>Pature: Janvier-fiveiae: 5.91</p>
                    <p>Fature: mai jain: 8.87</p>
                    <p>Boarea Ebédiviale, 21 novembre 190</p>
                    <p>Aosson D'ALEXANDRIN</p>
                    <p>Low 161, Dsqér, 18 Beshaishe, 41 134,</p>
                    <p>Bailes Cantre</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>984</p>
                    <p>947</p>
                    <p>Prix 18 11/18 15 8/4</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>283</p>
                    <p>18 34</p>
                    <p>156, Rowiach, 40</p>
                    <p>gat</p>
                    <p>15 3/8</p>
                    <p>151, 189, Mieir</p>
                    <p>810</p>
                    <p>15 8/4</p>
                    <p>23</p>
                    <p>145</p>
                    <p>18 5/8</p>
                    <p>161, Sasha, 44.</p>
                    <p>968</p>
                    <p>18 18/16</p>
                    <p>168, Doquées, 25</p>
                    <p>168</p>
                    <p>18,7 16</p>
                    <p>168, Sant</p>
                    <p>88</p>
                    <p>919</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.B. 5 14 3/8: Novembre... Janvier...... Yo Mare Mai</p>
                    <p>166,</p>
                    <p>44</p>
                    <p>985</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>16:95/81</p>
                    <p>187,</p>
                    <p>69</p>
                    <p>409</p>
                    <p>15.5/16</p>
                    <p>www18 11/18</p>
                    <p>181.</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>15-></p>
                    <p>18 27/32</p>
                    <p>169,</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>208</p>
                    <p>16 9/16</p>
                    <p>16 1/32</p>
                    <p>170,</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>Praise de solem Nov. Die Jan.... vrier More... Avril...</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>18, 1/4</p>
                    <p>178,</p>
                    <p>...P.T. 89 90/40 a</p>
                    <p>170</p>
                    <p>18 7/8</p>
                    <p>180,</p>
                    <p>Nov, Die-Jan.... Févrige Mars</p>
                    <p>62 8:40 P.T. 78- 78-</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>993</p>
                    <p>17 11/18</p>
                    <p>174,</p>
                    <p>89</p>
                    <p>959</p>
                    <p>18-</p>
                    <p>&amp;90/40 175, 10/40 177.</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>17 8/8.</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>Novembre...</p>
                    <p>Javier</p>
                    <p>Cotons : Nouvelle récole. Calme.</p>
                    <p>Les los ontéé sons adjagia à l'Anglo-Egyptia Bank Cay Lal.</p>
                    <p>1800 Mai</p>
                    <p>N.B-Aliens de l'eoshare il ones proofdé à l</p>
                    <p>Pvrier Avril...</p>
                    <p>Poves Soldi</p>
                    <p>-Les 13 premiers sont de qualid add, 8 d'abbaas, 8 de nabari, les derniere de
                        joanovich.</p>
                    <p>Bicole stalls. Ora onvers &amp; tal, 18 97/89 pone Disponible.-Point
                        d'arrivages, poins d'affaires et te mare pour tomber &amp; al. 16 1/18 apur
                        Bominang J. 18 8/4 &amp; 96/89. La tenne set fuble et il y a peuvente dee
                        denx lots' da smo sivant d'affaires, en grande partie des ré-lisations.</p>
                    <p>Feno-gars Bien.</p>
                    <p>Contra-Bdeofte acinelle. La one est le máme pour los contrass es la cote
                        afflande, on bases on on wt parement nominale.</p>
                    <p>de den Bose annalle. In eines ouvert &amp; P.E. 61 pour le février-mart
                        Pro-Betdi Bolte natualle dans</p>
                    <p>Ior ios Us no de dak, baller 28 are 188 P.T. 181 &amp; Abdel Maghid</p>
                    <p>Bose let Usine de tot, ballee 11- 88 F.T. 140 &amp; Abiel Moghi</p>
                    <p>8 1/3</p>
                    <p>17 16</p>
                    <p>DERNIERE HSURE</p>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.B. 5 14 3/8: Novembre... Janvier...... Yo Mare Mai</p>
                    <p>166,</p>
                    <p>44</p>
                    <p>985</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>16:95/81</p>
                    <p>187,</p>
                    <p>69</p>
                    <p>409</p>
                    <p>15.5/16</p>
                    <p>www18 11/18</p>
                    <p>181.</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>15-></p>
                    <p>18 27/32</p>
                    <p>169,</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>208</p>
                    <p>16 9/16</p>
                    <p>16 1/32</p>
                    <p>170,</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>Praise de solem Nov. Die Jan.... vrier More... Avril...</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>18, 1/4</p>
                    <p>178,</p>
                    <p>...P.T. 89 90/40 a</p>
                    <p>170</p>
                    <p>18 7/8</p>
                    <p>180,</p>
                    <p>Nov, Die-Jan.... Févrige Mars</p>
                    <p>62 8:40 P.T. 78- 78-</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>993</p>
                    <p>17 11/18</p>
                    <p>174,</p>
                    <p>89</p>
                    <p>959</p>
                    <p>18-</p>
                    <p>&amp;90/40 175, 10/40 177.</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>17 8/8.</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>Novembre...</p>
                    <p>Javier</p>
                    <p>Cotons : Nouvelle récole. Calme.</p>
                    <p>Les los ontéé sons adjagia à l'Anglo-Egyptia Bank Cay Lal.</p>
                    <p>1800 Mai</p>
                    <p>N.B-Aliens de l'eoshare il ones proofdé à l</p>
                    <p>Pvrier Avril...</p>
                    <p>Poves Soldi</p>
                    <p>-Les 13 premiers sont de qualid add, 8 d'abbaas, 8 de nabari, les derniere de
                        joanovich.</p>
                    <p>Bicole stalls. Ora onvers &amp; tal, 18 97/89 pone Disponible.-Point
                        d'arrivages, poins d'affaires et te mare pour tomber &amp; al. 16 1/18 apur
                        Bominang J. 18 8/4 &amp; 96/89. La tenne set fuble et il y a peuvente dee
                        denx lots' da smo sivant d'affaires, en grande partie des ré-lisations.</p>
                    <p>Feno-gars Bien.</p>
                    <p>Contra-Bdeofte acinelle. La one est le máme pour los contrass es la cote
                        afflande, on bases on on wt parement nominale.</p>
                    <p>de den Bose annalle. In eines ouvert &amp; P.E. 61 pour le février-mart
                        Pro-Betdi Bolte natualle dans</p>
                    <p>Ior ios Us no de dak, baller 28 are 188 P.T. 181 &amp; Abdel Maghid</p>
                    <p>Bose let Usine de tot, ballee 11- 88 F.T. 140 &amp; Abiel Moghi</p>
                    <p>8 1/3</p>
                    <p>17 16</p>
                    <p>DERNIERE HSURE</p>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <!-- page 5 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN MINING ACTIVITY.</head>
                    <p>eting activity in Egyptian Mining, the Directors of the London and Paris
                        Pechenge have retaled the service of a competiat tag Engineer, whose regents
                        on the present patties of the varices proportios is of the we Importance.
                        This feforms Jon le at Egyptian Mining ng with the Exchange before doing ded
                        the veld the locs of capital lurred by the purchase of worthless,
                        securities.</p>
                    <p>The Landen &amp; Parte Mining Securt</p>
                    <p>Cerrespondents centereglating investment</p>
                    <p>the purchase or sale of an London Break Ephango asid Continental Bourson:</p>
                    <p>Drafts Issed on PARIS, BERLAN, AMSTERDAM, ANTWERP, HEW YORK &amp;
                        MONTREAL</p>
                    <p>LONDON &amp; PARIS EXCHANGE,</p>
                    <p>LANGITON</p>
                    <p>GENERAL BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>Head Ofen BALDON HOUSE, BAIK, LONDON, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>Codes:</p>
                    <p>ZUBAIR PASHA.</p>
                    <p>HIS AUTOBIOGRAPHY.</p>
                    <p>(Concluded.).</p>
                    <p>EGYPT EXPLORATION FUND. APPEAL FOR SUPPORT.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904</p>
                    <p>Dionysios knows," the teacher receiving in all the premium of a hundred and
                        twenty drachme. This is dated about A.D. 100. Someprivate letters are
                        interesting, and an invitation of á decurion to his party on the sixth day
                        before the Kalends, at eight o'clock," has a distinctly modern flavour.</p>
                    <p>MODERN AND ANCIENT EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer, in his report on Egypt for1903, had alluded to their
                        publications, which, he said, showed that many of the abuses which until
                        lately existed in Egypt almost in their original form were of very ancient
                        date.. "For instance, plentiful allusions, are made to the system of
                        tax-farming, which it is well known prevailed in Egypt, as elsewhere, from
                        time immemorial, and which appears everywhere to have given sise to abuses
                        very similar in chs- tacter." Lord Cromer then pointed out that with the
                        recent fishery reforms almost the last restige of this iniquitous and
                        oppressive sys- tem would disappear. He noted with some in- terest that in
                        the days of Domitian the system -though without doubt equally oppressive to
                        the taxpayers seemed hardly, to have been so lucrative to the tax-farmers as
                        in those of Abbas II. These have bean of recent years mak- ing an annual
                        profit of over £30,000, whereas from the</p>
                    <p>OXYRHYNCHUS PAPYRI</p>
                    <p>68 89-10988</p>
                    <p>Libby's</p>
                    <p>Luncheons</p>
                    <p>Put a variety into living and use Libby's</p>
                    <p>Cooked Corn Beef, Vienna Sausage, Lunch Tongue, Veal Loaf, Pot- ted Turkey,
                        Deviled Ham, Ox Tongue, Etc. quickly made ready to serve.</p>
                    <p>Send today for the little booklet. "How to Make Good Things to Bat." fall of
                        ideas on quick funch serving. Libby's Atlas of the World mailed free by
                        Pietre stampe</p>
                    <p>Libby, McNeill &amp; Libby, Chicago, U. S. A.</p>
                    <p>Calendar of Coming Events.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA:</p>
                    <p>it appears that on certain taxes being put November. up to auction those who
                        had previously held Mon. 91 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Il Trovators, the
                        concession not only refused to bid bat seemed likely to abscond, "as they
                        had incur Alhambra Thairs, Gioconda 3.15pm Place des Consale. Masseria's
                        Mon- red sufficient. loss already." In the case of gario. 9 p.m. slavery,
                        which is still not altogether unknown</p>
                    <p>Fri. 25</p>
                    <p>International Employés Society.9p.m. Alderson's Garden. Vanery Masera ment. 4
                        p.m.:</p>
                    <p>Abbat Hotel. A. L. M. &amp; D. 8 Concert 9p.m.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Masonic Hall, Boalse-road. 9 p.m. Khadivial Open House. M. Silvain. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>It is in the Darfur campaign that Zubair's The eighteenth ordinary, general
                        meeting of career gets mixed up with those events that the Egypt Exploration
                        Fund was held in the have led to the interest of England in the rooms of the
                        Royal Society, Burlington House, Sudan. While Zubair was conquering Darfur,
                        on the 11th inst, when the president, Sir the Governor of Khartoum, Ismail
                        Pasha John Evans, took the chair. Ayyoub, was sent to Darfur by the Khedive
                        to After some formal business the Treasurer assist in the conquest;
                        probably, as some of read his report, expressing regret that it was Gordon's
                        biographers assert, to prevent Zubair the most unfavourable he had had to
                        deal with being too independent. The latter asserts that In regard to the
                        Exploration Fund the total on the upper waters of the Blue Nile, Lord Thurs.
                        74 Abbas Helmy Thesire Aida, in aid of be had achieved his work when Ismail
                        proffer expenditure was £3,084, whereas the receipts Cromer compared a
                        recent purchase of a lad ed his assistance; that nevertheless he wel were
                        £1,806. As to the archaeological survey of fifteen for £12 with that of a
                        woman, aged comed the Khedive's emissary at Fasher, the £553 was spent sa
                        against £422 received; thirty-five, for £7 2s. 6d, and inquired whether
                        December. capital of Darfur, and discharged a hundred while on the
                        Greco-Roman branch £1,325 was a slave really cost more on the Abyssinian Ba
                        guns in his honour; that he handed over the spent and £931 received. There
                        was, there frontier in 1903 than was paid in Egypt in the government of the
                        conquered countries to fore, a serious deficit. In the case of the fand year
                        86. In conclusion, the chairman referred proper this arose from the
                        necessity of sending to the irrigation works in Egypt, and hoped Ismail
                        Ayyoub, proceeding himself with a picked force to deal with the relics of
                        the out two expeditions and from the falling off of that all possible
                        precautions would be taken November. defeated armies. With these be easily
                        receipts from America. The second expedition for the preservation of
                        monuments within the Mon. 31 Meeting of Ragheb Lodge No. 51, a esme to
                        terms, but a dispute broke out as necessary because the right of priority to
                        area of the extended reservoir should the on his return to Fasher between
                        himself excavate outside the temple of Queen Hatshepu Assouan dam be
                        heightened. and Ismail Ayyoub with respect to a propo and then they would
                        not through Dr. Naville would have otherwise had to be abandoned,. sition
                        that the son of the late Sultan of Darfur have found the remains of a temple
                        built prior should be made governor of the province, subject to the Khedive,
                        and to pay £100,000 to that of Queen Hatshepu. The diminution of annually, a
                        proposal favoured by Zubair. but- RECEIPTS FROM AMERICA rejected by Ismail
                        Ayyoub. Zubair, was, was serious, and was due to the fact that however,
                        entrusted with the command of an the Americans were now undertaking inde
                        expedition to quell a rebellion got up by a son pendent excavations. As to
                        the Grieco-Roman of the deceased Sultan; and in this, his last branch it had
                        been intended to send out an expedition, he advanced as far as Wadai,
                        expedition every other year, but the success of whence, however, he was
                        summarily recalled. the discoveries at Behuesa put many other He then asked
                        leave to return to Cairo to searchers in the field and an annual expedition
                        interview the Khedive, and received in reply became necessary. Last year Dr.
                        Grenfell and an invitation to do so, accompanied with the Dr. Hunt, among
                        most important papyri, un- title Pasha. He brought as a sent to his earthed
                        the new Logia, and the epitome of master 1000 Sudanese soldiers, completely
                        Livy, and next year's work, for which enough armed, 100 Arab horses, 8 tons
                        of ivory of the money was available, would, it was hoped, finest quality,
                        four lions, four panthers, and twelve parrots." But in spite of his
                        munificence he was not allowed to return to the Sudan, and the defence of
                        his kingdom passed to his son Suleiman, whom Gordon some years after catight
                        and shot.</p>
                    <p>produce something of equal importance. It was pointed out that the ordinary
                        subscription of a guinea, after payment of the expenses of the publications
                        and the, office dues, only left about three shillings for the purposes of
                        excavation, and an urgent appeal was therefore made to all subscribers to
                        double their sub- scription at least for the current year, or to make a
                        substantial donation, else the small capital of the fund would have to be
                        drawn on. The accounts were adopted without discussion.</p>
                    <p>PRESIDENTIAL ADDRESS.</p>
                    <p>Portions of this narrative certainly bear some resemblance to the adventures
                        of Sindbad the Sailor; yet in the main it corresponds well with the records
                        of Junker and Nachtigal, while it contains many details unknown to them.
                        Throughout Zabair appears as what Wingate (1) describes him, a born leader
                        Sir John Evans then delivered his address. of men. The reputation which he
                        enjoyed in After referring to the losses of the society the Sudan, and which
                        nine years after he had through the deaths of Dr. Stuart Murray, Mr. been
                        exiled froth it would have sufficed, in Edward Gilbertson, the Bishop of
                        Carlisle, Mr. Gordon's well-grounded opinion, to keep the G. F. Watts, R.A.,
                        the Rev. Dr. George Salmon, Sudanese from joining the Mahdi, was based and
                        Sir William T. Charley, K.C., he appealed on his marvellous success in war,
                        but also, it urgently for funds and then summarised the would seem, on the
                        strict justice of his rule, of work done in the past season. Professor which
                        he boasts, though he admits that his Flinders Petrie had excavated on the
                        site of punishments were occasionally severe, including hanging with the
                        head downwards. The</p>
                    <p>references to him in Gordon's later Journal do not contradict Zubair's
                        description of himself in these respects.</p>
                    <p>Herakleopolis, now Ehnass, sixty miles south of Cairo, and the principal
                        object of interest</p>
                    <p>LIGHT ON OLD CUSTOMS.</p>
                    <p>PLANS FOR THE FUTURE. Subsequently Professor Flinders Petrie and Dr. Bernard
                        Grenfell gave brief accounts of their work and plans for the coming year.
                        Pro- fessor Petrie intends to completely examine Sinai, if permission can be
                        obtained, and Dr. Grenfell will resume the search for papyri at
                        Oxyrhynchus.</p>
                    <p>OCTOBER'S CHILLS.</p>
                    <p>BRING MANY ILLS: THE CURE IS DR. WILLIAMS' PINK PILLS</p>
                    <p>WOULD you be warm! Look to your blood supply. Chills, Rheumatism, and
                        Sciatica, come from poor or bad blood. Dr. Williams' Pink Pills for Pale
                        People prevent as well as cure them: for these pills make new blood.</p>
                    <p>Theatre des Nouveautés. Variety Enter minment. 9.80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Troosdero. Variety Entertainment. 9.80 p.m</p>
                    <p>Wed 28 Masonic Hall. Idris Lodge No. 48 Sea. 20</p>
                    <p>Bon. 27</p>
                    <p>December.. Fri. 9 Sat. 10 Wed. 21</p>
                    <p>Fri. 88</p>
                    <p>Meeting f Ragheb Mark Lodge No. 510 1 at Masonic Hall, Boalse-road. 9 p.m.
                        Zoological Gardens. Performanes by Band of B. A. Infantry in afternoon,</p>
                    <p>Mens House. Gymkhana.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Horticultural Society's Show.</p>
                    <p>K 8. C. grounds. First Winter Races. p.m.</p>
                    <p>E. 8.0. grounds First Winter Baces. Sad day. 9p.m.</p>
                    <p>24 IMPORTANT NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>Mr. William Wright, a stonemason, Murano-street, Firhill-road, Glasgow, said:
                        "I contracted a chill, and a pain started in</p>
                    <p>my left ankle, and jumped to my hip. I was obliged to</p>
                    <p>give up work, and</p>
                    <p>AGENCY WANTED.</p>
                    <p>The Sole Agency in England and her colonies required by a syndicate</p>
                    <p>take to my bed. having its head office in London, for In spite of good a
                        REALLY FIRST CLASS EGYP. nursing, two doc</p>
                    <p>General Agent for Egypt and the Orient</p>
                    <p>AUGUSTUS VAN MILLINGEN</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL BUILDING, AVEROFF BraT, ALEXANDRIA, MOTPT.</p>
                    <p>SALE BY AUCTION.</p>
                    <p>DAVIES</p>
                    <p>BRYAN</p>
                    <p>&amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>CONTINENTAL HOTEL BUILDING CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>ST. DAVID'S BUILDINGS ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>ARD</p>
                    <p>MESSES. CONGDON &amp; CO. have been 35-37, Noble St, London.</p>
                    <p>instructed to sell by Public Auction the property and affects of the officers
                        20th Hussars. The sale will take place in the Mess-room, Cavalry Barracks,
                        Abbassieh, on Friday and Saturday, Nov. 95th and 26th, commencing at 9.30 on
                        each morning. The property will be on view on Tues day, Wednesday, and
                        Thursday afternoons up to 6 p.m..</p>
                    <p>94982.5-1</p>
                    <p>GREAT SALE</p>
                    <p>OF</p>
                    <p>Winter Novelties</p>
                    <p>COMMENCES NOVEMBER 12</p>
                    <p>AT.</p>
                    <p>Walker&amp;Meimarachi.</p>
                    <p>PASCHAL BRANCH.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>LATEST</p>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PARIS CREATIONS</p>
                    <p>94870-14-11</p>
                    <p>TIAN CIGARETTE. Only a really ex- CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>(Prepaid.)</p>
                    <p>the</p>
                    <p>Under this heading advare are Inserted following rales-18 wents anos, P.T. 5;
                        three tin, P.T. J werde: cn, P.T. # throw m alx times, P.P.</p>
                    <p>tors, poulticing, cellent tobacco with fine delicte aro- fomentation and ma
                        and made with the best paper pro- medicine, I felt as curable wil be
                        entertained. Address, bad after eight sending samples and naming weight
                        weeks as when I and price per ten thousand (carriage was first laid up and
                        duty forward), ASHLEY BROWN, T. 16 times, FT. B. For every 10 words or under
                        beyond my 182, Charing Cross Road, London, Stonemason, was cured of agony
                        that I scarW.C. If reference desired, apply, The "I read in the Imperial
                        Ottoman Bank, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Such was</p>
                    <p>Mr. William Wright, a Sciatica, by Dr. Williams cely slept. Pink Pille</p>
                    <p>Emisssion de 5,000 actions DE LA</p>
                    <p>Brasserie des Pyramides</p>
                    <p>(EX CROWN BREWERY OF CAIRO)</p>
                    <p>"SOCIETE ANONYME" Constituée par acte passé devant le notaire Belors &amp;
                        Brucelles, le 24 Mare 1889. publié an Moniteur Belge le 12 Avril 1889, oud.
                        N° 1663.</p>
                    <p>10 words, PS, three, P.T. ix, P.T.</p>
                    <p>The addre</p>
                    <p>DVERTISING AGENTE-The beet publie advert faing vite in Ostre belong to Violal
                        &amp; Co, Advert lelag. Agonte Chalet Parels Darbalhome Special too fat
                        parmaasut allant Moderate barma 109 Prompt despa</p>
                    <p>LEXANDRIA LENDING LIBRARY.-Over &amp; Co., Bae Cherif Paaba</p>
                    <p>A 1,000 volimas. Apply for catalogue to Borman</p>
                    <p>94908-6-6</p>
                    <p>AUBNISHED FLAT TO LET, &amp; rooms; bath rcom, ele, for about 18 months.
                        Plesearty situated near Ramlah Station, Alexandria Apply letter, "A. B.,
                        40-"Magnia Victoria</p>
                    <p>Conformément &amp; l'article 6 des Saints et vivant décision du Conseil
                        d'Administration du 88 Octobre 1904, la Brasserie des Pyramides émes 6,000
                        Aey tions de Capital portant le Capital de la Bocité de 1.500 000 franes
                        1.000.000. L'émissio est faite au prix de 108 franes l'action. Lee
                        Acionnaires ont un droir de préférence à mai son d'une setion pour &amp;
                        setions de Capital on 10 de dividende qu'ile pos den Les soions non
                        sonorites par les Actionnaires,</p>
                    <p>24907-8-6</p>
                    <p>JEUNE, DEMOISELLE antrichiens, chant instaurice on dame de compagnie.
                        Excellen bien l'Allemand et l'Italien, demande place certifiente et
                        référence sur place d'adresse: Mme Iorio, No. 1, rue Chérif Paoba,
                        Alexandris</p>
                    <p>94929-8-8</p>
                    <p>found was a golden statuette of a local divinity, Hershefi, bearing on its
                        base a dedication by a newspapers of a miner who had been cured of King of
                        the XXIVth Dynasty, of whom no acute Sciatics, or Rheumatism in the leg, by
                        On the other hand, the autobiography other relics are known, and a
                        magnificent triad Dr. Williams' Pink Pills for Pale People. A affords little
                        justification for the hysterical in red granite representing Rameses II.
                        between box was therefore got for me. Before I had got passage cited above
                        from Birkbeck Hill, the the gods Hershefi and Ptah, 11ft. high and 8ft.
                        through it my spirits were better, and the pain impression produced by which
                        on the British broad. At Thebes, close to the temple of Queen was leaving my
                        hip and leg. After a second public probably cost the gallant officer his
                        Hatshepu, Dr. Naville and Mr. Hall had found box, the Sciatica was entirely
                        cured. The pills life. Zubair's omission of all mention the mortuary chapel
                        of a King of the XIth gave me rich blood, for, chancing to cut my of the
                        slave trade in his account of his Dynasty, who reigned about 2500 B.c. Part
                        IV. finger, the blood that came from it was rich and life is doubtless
                        intentional, and his connection of the Oxyrhynchus Papyri had been
                        published, red, whereas when I was ill my blood was poor with it is too well
                        attested for us to attach mach end with it a small volume of the Logia of
                        and thin. The pills gave me a good colour. importance to the omission. But
                        the phrase Jesus. Some of the minor papyri were of much They sent me back to
                        work in three weeks." "eriminal of boundless wickedness" is as unanit
                        interest. Mrs. Wright added:-"Till my husband able as the terin "scoundrel"
                        for a man in the had Dr. Williams' Pink Pills he could not position of
                        Zubair, pursuing a form of traffic There was, for instance, a document
                        record- bear his left leg to be touched, even lightly. which his own
                        religion tolerated, and which, ing the emancipation of a slave, entering
                        into I noticed an improvement from the day he As Gordon admits, had been
                        discovered in Europe to be illicit only one generation before all the minute
                        particulars of a passport of the started taking them. I, too, have found
                        them From Baker's "Ismailia" it appears that it was middle of the last
                        century. In a deed by which a sure cure for the blinding headaches, from
                        fifficult to do business in the. Sudan without two brothers joined in the
                        manumission of the which I often suffered. " third part of a slave who as
                        regards the other In Chill October, need new blood, not becoming a slave
                        trader; and if Zubair con- tributed to the desolation of the Sudan, some two
                        parts had already been made free, one only to stave off Rheumatism and
                        Sciatica, credit should, on the other hand, be given him brother Achilleus
                        is described of middle height, but also to cure the many diseases resulting
                        for having in places arrested the process by the fair, having a long face
                        and asear on the middle from poor blood. Dr. Williams Pink Pills sont
                        estribuése az souseripters on proportion of his forehead while the female
                        slave, who for Pale People (genuine pills bear the full les souseriptions.
                        introduction of strong government. Nor can we is to become entirely
                        free-Apollonous, aged seven word title) cure Paralysis, Locomotor Pone
                        l'axreios de leur droit de préférens, les MISS MINA SHEPPARD will sentinne
                        her treat his conduct in fomenting a rebellion whigh about twenty-six, of
                        middle height, fair has a Ataxy, Kidney Disease, Scrofuls,
                        Rickets,stionnaires auront à fournir un Certificat de dépôt cember 1. A Camp
                        is to be inaugurated the might lead to the restoration of his sovereign long
                        face and a sear on the right foot. Her third Consumption, Aniemis, Loss of
                        Appetite, de lere titre dans une Banque d'Egypte on de Pyramids, where
                        patients and obere ma rights as very heinous. Having conquered some part
                        seems to have been worth three hundred Palpitationis, Neuralgia, Ladies'
                        Weaknesses, Les Ponporiptears auront à verser 35 frenon par provinces by his
                        own arm, he had then pre drachma of silver, say, £10. Some other and
                        Hysteria. These pills are not a purgative setion à la souseription, 30
                        franes à la répartitionTO LET.-Fice Ville, furnished or unfurnished. sented
                        them to the Khedive, who rewarded REMARKABLE DOCUMENTS They are sold at all
                        medicine shops, and le solde soit 88 frases, à la remise du sitre. with
                        garden and tables, enated on the Ghesireh hith for the gift by interning him
                        in Cairo. Les versaments devront se faire à la Banqna Promenade, Cairo, ing
                        the Khedivial porti ( Some sympathy is surely due to his son, "the were
                        bonds of apprenticeship. One witnessed by Dr. Williams' Medicine Co, at 2.
                        9d. that a boy named Thorus is apprenticed for per box, or six boxes for
                        13s. 9d. Impériale Ottomane, en Egypte on an Siège, Sonial &amp; Cimb, and
                        next to the second gate of the garden of City in his attempt to sage for his
                        family five years to learn the art of weaving from Sold in Egypt at all
                        chemists at P.T, 13 per Bretele 106, Hae Boyals of low bordereaux de the
                        Palace Hotal. Apply a "The Villa sonie relics out of his father kingdom. Had
                        Zubair been permitted to return to the Heraclas, who for the first your and
                        seven box or P.T. 70 per 6 boxes. Can be bought at seription sont déposés.
                        Sudan in 1876 or 1884, the history of that vast months is to pay the boy no
                        wages, but find the general depot: Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel region would
                        have been different, and much him in food and a stipulated quantity of du Nd
                        St, (1st floor), and Alexandrís, Roebre bloodshed would have been spared at
                        least clothes. After the term mentioned the boy is Stamboul, No. 8. for a
                        time. The course of events has provided to receive a gradually increasing
                        amount of it with a permanent soures of good govern wages and more expensive
                        clothes. Twenty ANTED byrgs firm (British) at Alex ment, which Zubair could
                        not have given it, holidays in each year are to be allowed on! His
                        autobiography, however; gives us the account of festivals, but there is no
                        mention The P. &amp; 0.8. N. Company's Yeaht Optoma laring formaliare and
                        ground for Gordon's anxiety for his services in of "week ends.". The date of
                        this bond is 4.D. Largest 1st ols and most comfortable VOTIS 6,000 tons,
                        will ve Alesandria od mradi 1884, just a Gordon's earlier Letters explain
                        183. Even more remarkable is the bond of the prejudice by which he was
                        deprived of apprenticeship of a slave for two years to the Hotel in
                        Alexandria. Facing the Friday, the 9th and 80s of December for Man Apple
                        them. (The Monthly Review) "semiograph, to be taught to read and write
                        Central position. Under English management, taking First Balon Png only, o
                        1001, 108 chorthand of "the signs that your to 81-11-006</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Brazellee</p>
                    <p>La soseription est ouverte le Vendrell 38 novem courant et close le lendemain
                        Samedi à midi.</p>
                    <p>Le Président du Conseil d'Administration 14980-98 30. CHAKOUR</p>
                    <p>the rel</p>
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>Swedish nerve treatment for ladies after De</p>
                    <p>secommodated.</p>
                    <p>94904-8-1</p>
                    <p>PHE UNION CLUB, Alexandria, invites applie sions for the following posts (for
                        European servante) Chef, Hind Walter, Barman, Hall porter. Appliantion to be
                        addressed to Briary Union Cink Alasandria 94018-04</p>
                    <p>NEW SEASON'S</p>
                    <p>GOODS</p>
                    <p>ARRIVING</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Calro &amp; Alexandria</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <!-- page 6 contents -->
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>Pour GENES, par le batean italien Adria parti le A novembre:</p>
                    <p>Behmid &amp; Co., 848 bailes coton</p>
                    <p>G. Franger &amp; Co.. 806</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Bensoni &amp; Co., 250</p>
                    <p>J. Plante Co, 692</p>
                    <p>Carver Beck &amp; Coy. Ltd, 80</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 128</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann, 881</p>
                    <p>Mobr &amp; Fender, 288</p>
                    <p>2,882 balles coton</p>
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER, 21, 1904</p>
                    <p>Lyzarnot, November 19, 13 80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sales of the day</p>
                    <p>6,000</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>400</p>
                    <p>Aimerion (new erop) Maize Spot per</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>Americns fatures (Dee-Jan)</p>
                    <p>5.22</p>
                    <p>(April-May)</p>
                    <p>5.29</p>
                    <p>Ameriona Middling...</p>
                    <p>6.89</p>
                    <p>Egyptian fally good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>8 32/64</p>
                    <p>(Dec.)</p>
                    <p>8 9/64</p>
                    <p>(Jan.)</p>
                    <p>84.64</p>
                    <p>(March) 7 68/6</p>
                    <p>nominal</p>
                    <p>good fair (browa) do "good</p>
                    <p>nominal</p>
                    <p>fully good-fir</p>
                    <p>8 12/16 8 10 16</p>
                    <p>Four FIREE et ODESSA, par le batean ere Egyptian Brown fair per lb. d. Ep.
                        Nicoles II, parti le 5 novembre :. Divers, 150 ce riz, 249 so is destes, 88
                        colis divers G. Pranger &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>1,322 ballow soton</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 260</p>
                    <p>S</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderi,</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>Behmid &amp; Co..</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>280..</p>
                    <p>G. Riecken,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines à Co.,</p>
                    <p>50</p>
                    <p>E Mallison &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>2,129 belles coton</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Besas now (per 480 lbs) to 25/8 1</p>
                    <p>Cotton Werkly total sales...</p>
                    <p>On speculation</p>
                    <p>For export</p>
                    <p>Total Import</p>
                    <p>Forwarded to consumers...</p>
                    <p>For BYBIA. by the S.S. Minich; sailed on the 5th November:</p>
                    <p>Varions, 184 bags Baden besos, 108 bags rics, 28 bags coffee, 87 bags beans,
                        14 begs lentila: 6 asses cigarettes, 18 ampsy maks, 10 packages sombae, 14
                        packages vegetables, 1,991 poeksgus aundries</p>
                    <p>For HULL, by the S.S. Tycho, miled on the 6th November:</p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Actual export</p>
                    <p>Block.</p>
                    <p>East India aflost</p>
                    <p>American sfloat...</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton On speculation</p>
                    <p>8. Tswil,</p>
                    <p>Bebrend &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank,</p>
                    <p>N. E. Tamvado,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>ORENSTEIN &amp; KOPPEL, Limited. STEINEMANN MABARDI &amp; C</p>
                    <p>Capital 10,000,000 Frs.</p>
                    <p>PURVEYORS TO H.H. THE KHEDIVE:</p>
                    <p>PORTABLE AND, PERMANENT RAILWAYS PASSENGER AND GOODS CARS</p>
                    <p>Tipping and Platform Waggons</p>
                    <p>FOR ALL PURPOSES. R</p>
                    <p>LOCOMOTIVES FROM 10-400 H.P.</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Engineering Stores. MERCHANTS CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY Bole
                        Agents for Egypt, Asia Minor and Byria for</p>
                    <p>IMPORTES ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Mos, Olayton &amp; Shuttleworth, Lincoln Portable &amp; fred Engines &amp;
                        Bollers</p>
                    <p>mille Threaking Strawbruising &amp; Outting Machines.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Galloways Ltd. Manchester. The Ungest Boller Works in the World. Walter
                        A. Wood, Mowing &amp; Bearing Hoshine Co. Roosick Falls N. T. (America)
                        Piguet &amp; Co., Lyons. French Steam Engines.</p>
                    <p>Bespers, Moore, Harvesters &amp; Babes</p>
                    <p>Aveling &amp; Porter Lim., Rochester. Steam Rollers and Stoom Ploughs. Les
                        Tanneries Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Falling. (CATRO: 24 Kar
                        el Nil Strees. B. Hindley, Barton, Dorset, Vertical Engines and Boilers,
                        specially designed for opposite the Bank of Egypt driving Ketrie Dynasce
                        &amp; Centrifugal Pumpa, sto, F.O B. 690 Telephone No. 39 Hillstret Hugueot
                        Park Bicions LEXANDRIA: 29 Cher f Pasha Damont. Paris: Centrifugal pumps.
                        Street, Telephone No 661</p>
                    <p>bales 50,000 Large Stocks of Rails, Trucks, and Locomotives always kept in
                        Alexandris. E. &amp; E. Turner Ltd. powish Flow Hills.</p>
                    <p>500</p>
                    <p>2,000</p>
                    <p>100,000 SIEMENS &amp; HALSKE, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>194,000</p>
                    <p>7,000</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING OFFICES: CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>450,000 Slectric Light Installations.-Transmission of Power-lestie Railways
                        and Tramways-</p>
                    <p>4,000</p>
                    <p>Telegraphic &amp; Telephonic Apparatas. DYNAMOS-MOTORS.</p>
                    <p>CAIBO: 94, Karr-al-Nil Blast, opposite Bank of Brypt, P.OB. 690 Telephone No.
                        189. ALEXANDRIA: 39, Chérif Pasha Street. Telephone No. 661. 81-19-004</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>870,000</p>
                    <p>75</p>
                    <p>Weekly sales</p>
                    <p>2,600</p>
                    <p>Buick</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>90,000</p>
                    <p>Forwarded to co-</p>
                    <p>somers...</p>
                    <p>18,000</p>
                    <p>Actual Export...</p>
                    <p>1,800</p>
                    <p>Import</p>
                    <p>91.000</p>
                    <p>NEW-YORK, November 19.</p>
                    <p>Spot Cotton...</p>
                    <p>-10</p>
                    <p>904 tons cotton seed</p>
                    <p>Amerionn Fasares (December)</p>
                    <p>956</p>
                    <p>1,550</p>
                    <p>(January)</p>
                    <p>9.65</p>
                    <p>676</p>
                    <p>1,027</p>
                    <p>(April)... (May)</p>
                    <p>9.82</p>
                    <p>9.90</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers</p>
                    <p>668</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 8,8</p>
                    <p>Como day's receipts at all U.-S. Parts</p>
                    <p>49,000</p>
                    <p>Kafr Zayat Cotton Coy. Led, 1,800 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>G. Brach &amp; Co., 871 begs gam</p>
                    <p>Aly Moh. Balsh, 150 bags onions</p>
                    <p>H. Bindernagal, 60 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>Pour TREBIZONDE, par le batean dujoman Alez- andros, parti le 8 novembre:</p>
                    <p>Divers, 1,8:6 now rix, 165 saos benné, 80 anos fèves da Boudan, 379 enis:
                        danses, 109 barile alcool, 6x barie vides, 28 colis zerabile, 38 solis
                        poeax, 18 colis divers</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</p>
                    <p>BOURS da 19 novembre 1904 COURS DES VALEURS A TERMS, CLOTURE</p>
                    <p>PARIS</p>
                    <p>Bense Française 8%...</p>
                    <p>Actions de Boss...</p>
                    <p>Lots Taros.</p>
                    <p>Ture Unifié,</p>
                    <p>Dete Egyptienne Unde......ex</p>
                    <p>Dairs denied.</p>
                    <p>Crédit Foncier Egyptien...</p>
                    <p>Extérieur espagnol...</p>
                    <p>Obligations Beaque Nar, de Grios..</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Athènes, nouvelles souons Mesropotiain</p>
                    <p>Basse consolidé...</p>
                    <p>Bosnowice</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Change ar Londres...</p>
                    <p>Bases 2o.&amp; disponible</p>
                    <p>Boers No. 8 livrable les 4 de</p>
                    <p>...balee LIVERPOOL, November 19. American fatures (December January)... 5.92
                        Egyptian fally good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>8-19/64</p>
                    <p>EM (Dec.) 8 6/64 (Jan.) 81.04 (March) 7 59 64</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 19,</p>
                    <p>Private discount (3 month balls) Bar Bilver (per on d.)</p>
                    <p>Jonsole (December) Bio Tinto... Band Mines Egyptian Unifled..</p>
                    <p>Bailway Domain</p>
                    <p>Ottoman Defence... Turkish Unified...</p>
                    <p>Ian Bente 4...</p>
                    <p>Onoman Bank shares</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Egypt...</p>
                    <p>4566- Monopole Gree</p>
                    <p>Dairs Banish</p>
                    <p>98 60</p>
                    <p>New Dairs..</p>
                    <p>138</p>
                    <p>Bente Ureoque 4$</p>
                    <p>88 16</p>
                    <p>107</p>
                    <p>Charterede of d. Africa...</p>
                    <p>Agrionitaral Bank...</p>
                    <p>101 15 Nile Valley Gold Mine</p>
                    <p>714</p>
                    <p>-8%</p>
                    <p>26 14/16</p>
                    <p>88 1,4</p>
                    <p>62 12</p>
                    <p>11 1/4</p>
                    <p>104 7/8</p>
                    <p>99 8/4</p>
                    <p>104 -1/9</p>
                    <p>108 '1/3</p>
                    <p>88 88</p>
                    <p>ww</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>94</p>
                    <p>104-</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>100 1/3 91.5/8</p>
                    <p>...87</p>
                    <p>2 1/16</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>DOW 1 8/4</p>
                    <p>Delta Light Railway (Boarer shares) 16 to 15 1/8</p>
                    <p>89 80gypa. dos seed to Hall (Nov.) 5 13/18 steady Jerman Best g (ovembe)
                        18/10</p>
                    <p>£100,000 were wishdrawn from the Bank to-day for Egypt</p>
                    <p>25 14 1/2 bots Turos</p>
                    <p>Jrédia Lyonnais...</p>
                    <p>Ostonian Bank...</p>
                    <p>Chegnes dis London</p>
                    <p>Sagar Whise No. 8: (November).</p>
                    <p>Crédit Foncier Egyption</p>
                    <p>... 88 1/4</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Consolidés anglais......</p>
                    <p>Hecomptes-Parie 8, Londres 8, Berlin 6.</p>
                    <p>OKATWOOD'S A MILAN AFE stock</p>
                    <p>LINITD</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Mesars. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin.</p>
                    <p>Pized and Portable Beim and OIL gl Gers</p>
                    <p>Faten Tibbon-making Thrashing Machines,</p>
                    <p>Mesars. Platt Brothers &amp; Co., Limited, Oldham.</p>
                    <p>Cettos Glaning Maklary</p>
                    <p>Messrs. John Fowler &amp; Co., Limited, Leeds. Broom Ploughing Machinery and
                        Bnadrier,</p>
                    <p>The Central Cyolone Co., Limited, London. Grinding and Palverling
                        Machinery,</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Charles Cammell &amp; Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p>Messrs.</p>
                    <p>Stest Halis, springs, ballers, As</p>
                    <p>Patent and hit Dos</p>
                    <p>Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                    <p>at and Manual Fire Engin</p>
                    <p>Messrs. F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld., Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Unmal Brand Belting ote, she</p>
                    <p>Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p>The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                    <p>Bikes Vortex Turbines,</p>
                    <p>Meears. Greenwood &amp; Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>The (Laval) Fatest Stories, Meetrial Dynamo &amp; Motors.</p>
                    <p>MoCormick's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                    <p>Planet Junior Agricultural Implementa</p>
                    <p>Hores Hoss, Beed Drills, sta, ete. OLIYER PLOUGHS.</p>
                    <p>Agent in Cairo: M. A. FATTUCCI</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>38-8-905</p>
                    <p>Agents or OXBARB</p>
                    <p>.</p>
                    <p>TARIF D'EXPORTATION</p>
                    <p>Pour le mele de Novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 19.</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>128-</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>1147-</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>294-</p>
                    <p>...35.14 1/2</p>
                    <p>Obefales..... Tourteenx Grainos de soson... Olgnons</p>
                    <p>Bhg. 1/1 194 18</p>
                    <p>6,6</p>
                    <p>DESIGNATION</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>40-3/8</p>
                    <p>724-</p>
                    <p>138-</p>
                    <p>Ofriales.....</p>
                    <p>Tourionax...</p>
                    <p>Oignons.</p>
                    <p>Pets de</p>
                    <p>mote</p>
                    <p>Pytx di</p>
                    <p>Nomine!</p>
                    <p>LONDAN8</p>
                    <p>Outon</p>
                    <p>Canlar</p>
                    <p>2:610</p>
                    <p>Shgs. 1/1 1/2 &amp; 18 6/8</p>
                    <p>Octon</p>
                    <p>435</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Athènes (nouvelle usanos)....</p>
                    <p>PRIMES DES CONTRATS.</p>
                    <p>Liv. Mars P.T. 18 80/40 à 15-</p>
                    <p>inse de scton. Fr.... 180/40 1 85/4</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton...</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIRECTS Graines de eosan.... Oriales....</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL Engs. 11/ 1,8</p>
                    <p>"SIMPLE FACULTE</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>"STELLAGE</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Liv. Mars P.T. 27 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 aminos de soton, Fr.-M. 8 90/40 8 80
                        40</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>Bhge. 9,6-10/ 1/9-</p>
                    <p>CEREAL MARKET..</p>
                    <p>Con</p>
                    <p>BOG HL FABAD MARKET.</p>
                    <p>NATIONAL BANK'S BROOWAR</p>
                    <p>INSTRADAY'S PRI</p>
                    <p>Coton... Céréales... 100 Tourleans... Graines de coton...... Oignons.....</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Wheat, Taga Midd</p>
                    <p>Ard..P.T. 136 to P.T. 197</p>
                    <p>128</p>
                    <p>182</p>
                    <p>"DOUBLE"</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>150</p>
                    <p>Beans, Tug</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>98 G</p>
                    <p>Lov. Mare F.Z. 9 18/40 &amp; 10</p>
                    <p>CONTINENT (NANTES.DUNENBQUE) Graines de cot. (Dankergus) Fr. 10-1 (Nantes)...
                        19 1/2</p>
                    <p>95</p>
                    <p>(old</p>
                    <p>106</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Oignons</p>
                    <p>Lane Tugar...</p>
                    <p>91</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Barley, Tagad</p>
                    <p>Zaws...</p>
                    <p>Dues Shemal</p>
                    <p>Helba</p>
                    <p>Hummor..</p>
                    <p>MARSEILLE</p>
                    <p>68 EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO, LTD Graines de soon...</p>
                    <p>DESTINATIONS DIVERSES Genes, Marseille... Fr. - Coton 1 Odes, Triose, Venise,
                        9.50 8.80 90.0&amp;99.80</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>(Between the hours of 10 am and 6 pm, Ontre time</p>
                    <p>Dunkerque Anvers Hambo</p>
                    <p>New York. Bombay Alexandri la 18 novembre 100s..</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>78</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>216</p>
                    <p>VERAGE TIME supled in tranmission Bevotion telegram from Byland te Almendra
                        Salurley, 19th November 1984</p>
                    <p>Le Havre</p>
                    <p>Baronione***#</p>
                    <p>Lale Crashed Kho</p>
                    <p>darl........</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS</p>
                    <p>Grashed Ta</p>
                    <p>ORRALS IN BOAT AT BARES.</p>
                    <p>What</p>
                    <p>Ard. 4030</p>
                    <p>FROM</p>
                    <p>85 0</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>1000</p>
                    <p>Dars banal..</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>960</p>
                    <p>206</p>
                    <p>Beans.</p>
                    <p>Lentils...</p>
                    <p>Farley</p>
                    <p>RANDED IN AT</p>
                    <p>Ris on paille</p>
                    <p>brus</p>
                    <p>(Parch</p>
                    <p>1.80</p>
                    <p>par 100 kilog.</p>
                    <p>poids.</p>
                    <p>andeb</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>21188-24-11-904</p>
                    <p>YOUNGS,</p>
                    <p>RYLAND STREET WORKS, BIRMINGHAM, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>LIFTING &amp; HOISTING APPLIANCES</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>HYDRAULIC TOOLS.</p>
                    <p>SCREW AND</p>
                    <p>HYDRAULIC RAIL-BENDERS.</p>
                    <p>Write for</p>
                    <p>Catalogue No. 73.</p>
                    <p>23694-4-4</p>
                    <p>Davey Paxman &amp; Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>COLCHESTER, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>Makers of high class steam engines and boilers for Brish, Colonial and
                        Foreign Governments, Celebrated for ECONOMY and DURABILITY.</p>
                    <p>PHILADELPHIA</p>
                    <p>SWEDEN</p>
                    <p>DENMARK</p>
                    <p>GERMANT eto., eto.. Awarded only Gold Medal, ever given by the Royal So. of
                        Arts and Gold Medals at the following Exhi sitions</p>
                    <p>LONDON VIRRA-1878 PARIS</p>
                    <p>PAXHAR FA</p>
                    <p>Teab Day Bace Bomam.</p>
                    <p>VERTICAS LARGASHION &amp; Cess BUSAN BOILERS,</p>
                    <p>DAVEY PAXMAN &amp; Oo.'s Trip-Geared Engine gives off a full horse- power for
                        one hour at 1 lbs. of fuel. At the great trial of Com found, Portable and
                        Single Cylinder Steam Engines by the Royal Agricultural Society at Newcastle
                        open to the whole world, Davey Paxman &amp; Co. took the only prises
                        offered, establishing a record which has not yet been equalled.</p>
                    <p>AGENTS IN EGYPT</p>
                    <p>Messrs. HASSABO BEY MAHOMED &amp; Co. ALEXANDRIA. Who have a big stock of
                        casinos and bollers always on view. 1st Khedive's treat. (Telephone
                        998.)</p>
                    <p>DINNEFORD'S</p>
                    <p>The Universal Remedy for Acidity of the Stomach, Headache, Heartburn,
                        Indigestion, Sour Brectations Bill</p>
                    <p>DINNEFORDS</p>
                    <p>Avotions</p>
                    <p>The Physician's Cure for Goot, Rheumatic dout and. Gravel..</p>
                    <p>Safest and most Gentle Medielne fot Infants, Children, Delicate Females, ad
                        the</p>
                    <p>Makness of Pregnancy</p>
                    <p>MAGNESIA MAGNESIA</p>
                    <p>99-11-904</p>
                    <p>Credit Lyonnals SHRAGER BROTHERS</p>
                    <p>Société Anonyme.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, CALCUTTA, ALEXANDRIA. SINGAPORE AND. OOLOMBO (UTION).</p>
                    <p>OURANY PRIOM FRA YON PAR ON WA Japital 350.000.000 de France Merchants in
                        Jute and Jute Fabries</p>
                    <p>Far Ton</p>
                    <p>Shgs</p>
                    <p>Cardi Newport Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Best quality Best quality</p>
                    <p>Bethal</p>
                    <p>24/ 23 6 18</p>
                    <p>24 6 24 186</p>
                    <p>Coupon</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>Davison</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>West Hartley Main</p>
                    <p>Joolak</p>
                    <p>Morry's</p>
                    <p>Bairds</p>
                    <p>Dunlops</p>
                    <p>Best Hamiltos B</p>
                    <p>L</p>
                    <p>Yorkshire Lavorpool</p>
                    <p>Michiedend</p>
                    <p>Best Lasashire</p>
                    <p>Bad quality</p>
                    <p>Besond Lancashire Anchor</p>
                    <p>Orown</p>
                    <p>Star</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN MINING</p>
                    <p>NAMN OF COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>Central Egypt Exploration.....</p>
                    <p>Wayptian Mines Explor. Bynd...****** Eyptian Badan Minerals......</p>
                    <p>Kayptian and Hodan Mining Bynd.</p>
                    <p>Osbait (dan Mining Hynd.</p>
                    <p>Hile Development Synd</p>
                    <p>Nile Goldfalds (10 paid)</p>
                    <p>Nile</p>
                    <p>Valley Block</p>
                    <p>Valley</p>
                    <p>North Mile Valay</p>
                    <p>MARKET</p>
                    <p>All shares are 21 Making up Prices. Latest Prices</p>
                    <p>Shares Issued.</p>
                    <p>and fully paid</p>
                    <p>sisted.</p>
                    <p>exceps where</p>
                    <p>144 www TVE</p>
                    <p>312</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>144</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>oposing Byndaf</p>
                    <p>here)</p>
                    <p>United Afrin</p>
                    <p>Budan Exploration (10</p>
                    <p>414 www</p>
                    <p>November 8-</p>
                    <p>November 11.</p>
                    <p>11,9 1/8</p>
                    <p>PILULES</p>
                    <p>BUDORTRA</p>
                    <p>DEHAUT</p>
                    <p>DE PARIS</p>
                    <p>a'hésitent pas-4 se parger, quand elles en ont besoin. Elles ne craignent at
                        le dégodt at la fatigue, parce que, &amp; l'opposé des autres purgatifs,
                        celui-ci n'epère bien que lorsqu'il est pris avec de bons alimenta et des
                        fortifiantes, telles que vin, café, the Chacus choisit, pour se purgar
                        Pheure et le repas qui lai conviennent ecenpations.La Patigue Ce in
                        purgation étant annulée par Pertel de la bonne alimentation,</p>
                    <p>as se décide aisément &amp; recom encer gatant de fois que</p>
                    <p>cala est nécessaire</p>
                    <p>L'EGYPTIAN GAZETTE est en vente</p>
                    <p>dans les rast du Caire tous les soirs, à</p>
                    <p>7h. 80, excepté les dimanches et jours</p>
                    <p>Heide. Ta journal at aussi vente our Patent Fuel Swansea Graigola 21/6 carse
                        du Caire, d'Al</p>
                    <p>de Dame , de Haft-Royal et de Baparie</p>
                    <p>Allontie Poundry Onbe 38 Cole</p>
                    <p>de Testal</p>
                    <p>ENTIREMENT VERSES</p>
                    <p>AGENCES D'EGYFTE</p>
                    <p>(@enny Bags).</p>
                    <p>Free all Pills</p>
                    <p>OOTTON PACKS.</p>
                    <p>(own and he </p>
                    <p>(11 by 11)</p>
                    <p>186 ALEXANDRIE-LE OAIBS-PORT-SAID</p>
                    <p>Avances sur Marchandises, Consignation.</p>
                    <p>(11 by 10)</p>
                    <p>by 10) (11 by 10</p>
                    <p># by 101</p>
                    <p>ONION POCKETS</p>
                    <p>OBEDIT LYONNAIS tale des avances (sewn and hewed) sur marenandices, telles
                        que t</p>
                    <p>COTONE, GRAINES DE COTON, CEREALES, SUCRES, ete.</p>
                    <p>Il reçoit également des marchandise</p>
                    <p>soit en dépos libre, avee droite de maner</p>
                    <p>104 on (40 by (by 10)</p>
                    <p>GRAIN BACKS</p>
                    <p>www and humal)</p>
                    <p>SUGAR BAGE</p>
                    <p>asgs, soit en consignation, pour la vente at (4 by by 38/ Barple on a
                        l'oran</p>
                    <p>41</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>11.</p>
                    <p>8-10-004</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
