<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!-- Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-09-29">September 29, 2020<!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 0000-00-00 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-21">Monday, November 21,
                        1904<!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p1.jpg">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Peninsular & Oriental S. N Company. -->
                <div type="advert"></div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"  
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p2.jpg">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
            <div type="item">
                    <p>Fixed deposits for one year certain received at à per cent per annum.
                        Depo-its at interest for shorter periods are also received at mates to be
                        agreed upon. Letters of Credis for the use of travellers are isted payable
                        in al parte of the World. Approved hills discounted.</p>
                    <p>Bille, documentary invoices, eto, collected. Deaf and singapoio transfers
                        inued pay- able all over the World.</p>
                    <p>Foreign exchange bought and sold. Advsners made upon approved securities and
                        upon cotton, cotton-seed, sugar and other mer abandies.</p>
                    <p>The parchaee and sale of stocks and shares on the London Stock Exchange and
                        on the loesl and Continental Bourses, undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Customers osa deposit their valuables, bonds, , for le enstody in the Bank's
                        fire-proof strong-rooms, and the Bank will attend to the collecuen of the
                        coupons and drawn bonds deposited as they fall due</p>
                    <p>Mercentile credits issued.</p>
                    <p>Annaides, pensions, dividends, eto, collected. All farther particulars and
                        information can be oblained on application.</p>
                    <p>The officers and olerke, of the Bank are pledged to secrecy as to the tran-
                        sactions of customers.</p>
            </div>
       
             <div type="item">                 <p>weakness in the step they had taken. The Russian Government first accedes to a
                    most important political step and then at the last moment withdraws ite
                    sanction. But instead of putting an absolute veto on the conference it allows
                    the representatives of the Zemstvos to meet in private. The consequences were
                    obvious Radical resolutions are adopted, a Constitution is demanded, together
                    with liberty of conscience, liberty of the Press, liberty of speech, and liberty
                    of education, besides an elective legislative assembly. This private conference
                    was only held on Saturday, but by Monday the facts are known to the world and
                    the ball has been set rolling which, under the leadership of a Slavonic Mirabeau
                    or Lafs- yette, may lead to the ruin of militant auto- eracy throughout the
                    Russian Empire:</p>
                <p>At the same time, serious observers of the conditions of modern Russis, even
                    among those who sympathise with the aspirations of the Russian people for a form
                    of government which will give some legitimate scope for their ener gies,
                    entertain grave doubts as to the capacity of the Russians for self-government.
                    The mem- bers of the bureaucracy, indeed, base their claim to govern Russia,
                    when they condescend to argue the matter at all; on the ground that acceptance
                    of office the new Minister of the In- no other government is possible. Soon
                    after his</p>
                <p>terior made a mendorable declaration." Abroad," said Prince Sviatopolk Mirski,
                    "people speak of a new Constitution for Russia: such a thing is, impossible
                    under present conditions.". It is not only abroad that people speak of a new
                    Constitu tion; it is in Russia itself that the demand is being did not stop
                    short at a repetition of the common made. But Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's
                    declaration official formula. "But," he continued, "there is such a thing as
                    local self-government, as is exemplified in the Zemstvos. I believe," he added,
                    "in Zematvos." That is a declaration of immense importance coming from such a
                    quarter how important is demonstrated, with singular appositeness in an article
                    on "Self-government in Russia" in the new number of the Empirs Review. For
                    reasons which may readily be sur mised, the writer of the article desires to
                    pre- serve his anonymity; but internal evidence renders almost superfluous the
                    editorial as surance that the writer is entitled to be listened to with respect
                    when he seeks to supplement Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's state- mont by giving a
                    sketch of the Zemstvo institution in Russia. The evidence which THEOFPTIAN
                    GASETTE IS PRINTED ON PAPER is adduced of the existence of the seeds of a
                    representative system of government throughout the greater part of European</p>
                <p>N.B-9ribecriptions commence trees the 1e or 10th of any month SUBSCRIPTIONS and
                    ADVERTISEMENTS at dne la advices P. O. Orders and Thayer t be made payable to
                    the Editor and Manager Bowland Snelling, Alexandria.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            
                <div type="item">                <p>appears to have taken root in Russian provin cial life, the success which has on
                    the whole attended it, and the possibilities which it presents of preparing the
                    people for the difficult. task of self-government. The Zemstvo instita tion is a
                    tiny plant, but if it be wisely tended it may yet grow into a noble tree.
                    Unfortunately Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's belief in the Zemst vos is not a common
                    article of bureaucratic</p>
                <p>A very interesting telegram from St. Peters-faith, and there have been
                    indications that, if burg this morning announces that the Russian some of the
                    bureaucrats of St. Petersburg Government actually gave permission for a could
                    have their way' even this struggling public conference to be held at St. Peters
                    experiment in local self government would be barg, composed of representativos
                    of "Zems crashed beneath the heel of autocracy. But tvos" throughout the
                    country. At the last the fact that the delegates of the Zemstvos moment,
                    however, the courage of the autocracy Saturday last is an historical event of
                    the were allowed, even to confer in private on failed, and the sanction for a
                    public con utmost significance, and we may live to reckon ference was withdrawn,
                    though the delegates November 19, 1904, as one of the cardinal were allowed to
                    meet in privata A more dates in the history of the human race. portentous step.
                    in the history of the poli tical emancipation of the human race has not occurred
                    since the summoning of the States General. The analogy can be pressed</p>
                </div></div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p5.jpg"> 
              <div type="item">
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p> THE WAR.</p>
                    <p> RUSSIAN BOMBARDMENT.</p>
                    <p> JAPANESE REPULSE.</p>
                    <p> GREAT BATTLE IMMINENT,</p>
                    <p> MUKDEN, November 19.</p>
                    <p> A stiff artillery fire was opened on the Russian right at daylight, and
                        lasted for several hours. The fire continued at intervals during the day.
                        The Russians are expecting a general attack. All ranges have been carefully
                        marked, and whichever army attacks is likely to suffer severely..
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p> MUXDEN, November 19. The Hussians expect a general attack. (H) ST.
                        PETERSBURG, November 20 The Russian artillery on the Sha Ho have compelled
                        the Japanese to fall back. (Havas.).</p>
                    <p> TOKIO, November 20. Friday's report from Marshal Oyama, detail- Fing the
                        various skirmishes and stating that the Russian bombardment of the Japanese
                        positions was resultless, seems to indicate the imminence of another great
                        battle, though, apparently, neither side has yet made any decisive move-
                        ment. The Russian feints were evidently (Reiter.)</p>
                    <p> An English Daily Newiper, tablished in 1880 Hiror &amp; Manngar: B. B Price
                        One Plastre Tarts.intended to draw the Japanese.</p>
                </div>  
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p6.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
