<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!-- Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-10-30">October 30, 2023<!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 1904-11-23 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-23">Wednesday, November 23,
                        1904<!-- 1904-11-23 --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p1.jpg">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Peninsular & Oriental S. N. Company. British India S. N. Company, Limited. Anglo-American Nile Steamer & Hotel Coy.
The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the following dates:-
Marseille, Plymouth and Lenden. Marseilles, Plymouth and London Malta sud London Malta and London.
Marseilles, Plymouth and London.
MALACCA" "HUMATRA
6,046 Tone
November
Malta and Landon Maits and Landco.
CRANA
4410
7,913
MANILA
December
4.210
SARDINIA"
574
MACEDONIA"
10,811
MARMORA
10,809
PERA
9,712
SUNDA
CHINA
 -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- 1,000 ROYAL PRINCE
Good Accommodation for Passengers.
Navigation Generale Italienne. Societes Rousies Flerie-Rabatties Services Postaux. Departs de Decembre
Les Jendis 1, 8, 16, 99 99 8h. p. direct pour Messine, Naples, Liveure et Génes.
Les Jendis 1 es 13 à 8h. p.m. direes poor Brindisi, Bari, Aneboe et Veniso
Le Mercredi 18 & 10 ham. pour les vales de la Syrie es Larnaque
Le Lundi 19 & 4 b. p.m. pone Port-Sald, Snes et Masen wah.
Le Mercredi 7 et Jeudi à 8h. p.m. pour Fort Said.
BANK OF ATHENS, Limited. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.
Failings hegy 10 days from Haste sal gel and beinghtly Awad Less to Aldra and Byrias Coast. The dates are apprinteri & Teeth Fasha ARIATIC PRING due trois Lende
Nov
INDEAN FRIZUR
Manhbester
Du
SCO TISH PAINOR
TROJAN PRINUR
Anwery & London Manchester
 -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p2.jpg"
                ><!-- Royal Insurance Coy
FIRE AND LIFE. LARGEST FIRE OFFICE IN THE WORLD. HAJELDEN & Co., Agents, Alexandria.
B. VITERBO & Jo., Agents, Cairo.
THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.
Our Winter Season's Stocks
COMPRISING AN
Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver & Plated Articles, CUTLERY, LEATHER & ATHLETIC GOODS & GAMES..
TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS. CHOICE HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS. VINTAGE WINES.
PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LD PROVISIONS, CONFECTION RY AND TABLE DELICACIES,
$1-8-906
ESTABLтеHED 17821
HASELDEN & Co., Agmis, Alexandria, FRED. OTT & Co., Sub Agents, Calro
GWYNNES, LIMITED.
(J. & H. GWYNNE, LTD., & GWYNNE & Co., UNITED.)
GWYNNE, LONDON
Onde
ABO, and th Baltions, Al. MORNING & MEALS.
Trade Mark- "INVINCIBLE."
MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT
Telephones
544 BANK.
Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly moderate prices.
The Egyptian Supply Stores, (BRANCH WALKER & CO., CAIRO). WALKER & MEI MARACHI, Limited.
MENA HOUSE HOTEL.
IS NOW OPEN.
Centrifugal Pumping Machinery CAIRO SAVOY
in the world, suitable for all purposes, including
RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE, IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING & FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, & ALL MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.
These Pumps can be driven by Bears, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other power, for Lifts of from 1. in 5008., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a Minnie Makers of the Mex Pamps. Results Guaranteed. Over 50 Years' Practical Experienos.
All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet Egyptian requirements.
London Omees
81, Cannon Street, London, E.O.
Works Hammersmith, London,
38369-11-13-904
BOEHME & ANDERER
NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB,
24848-80-4-905
HOTEL.
Will Open November 26.
31-8-905
EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL
PORT SAID. First Class Hotel. Modern in all respects. Fire-proof, Drained to the Ses, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French Billiards, Fresh and Salt Water Baths..
The Coolest Summer Besilence in Bgypt Special terms to Cairo Besidente and their families desirous of enjoying the cool air and ses bathing during the summe months. DRAGOMANS IN HOTEL, UNIFORM MENT ALL TRAINS AND STRAMERS,
23041-38-8-818
JOHN MOIR & SON,
LIMITED.
LONDON, ABERDEEN, AND SEVILLE. PURVEYORS TO THE KING.
MANUFACTURERS OF
THE SEVILLE ORANGE MARMALADE, WHOLE FRUIT JAMS, PURE PICKLES,&c.
Head Office: 9 & 10, GREAT TOWER ST., LONDON. Agents: D. A. VAFIADIS & CO., P.O. BOX 540, CAIRO,
DAILY WEATHER REPORT.
OBSERVATIONS BY SUBTY DEPARTMENT.
ALEXANDRIA
8.8.W. Eight
shade
130 1.0.004
REMABER
As noon yesterday the wind blew, strong from the NW. There was a rough a Howry, dark, travelling clouds pre- wind falling light. At midnight it became almost calm, with
allied and it was showery at times in the afternoon, the heavy continuous rim and qually weather from the 8.8.W.. the ses becoming smoother arometer rising slowly.
 --></div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p3.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>(FROM OUR FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENT.) Major R. G. Tallet D.S.O., ho tion joins the
                    2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade in London, November 22. Egypt, has worn the "green
                    jacket for Egyptian Bank (Limited) was held this after well as the medal with
                    five clasps in Bulle The annual general meeting of the Anglo- sixteen years and
                    earned his decoration and the dividend of 15% declared which, includ- Talbot,
                    who is a member of the ancient military noon. The report and balance sheet were
                    passed, fighting for the relief of Ladywith. Mo ing the dividend of 10% for the
                    first six and naval family of which the Bal of Shrews- On the table you will
                    find complete plans, months, made a dividend of 13 per cent on bury is the head,
                    at the with all details, for a block of 110, to cost, Colenso, Vaal Kats,
                    Montecristo, say, under L.E. 20,000. The Chairman, in the course of his speech,
                    Hill, Langs Nek, etc., etc.. "Also plan of the city, showing the lands at gave
                    some details as to the issue of the 20,000 present not used and belonging to the
                    Govern-new shares. The shareholders took up the quota Major G. C. L. Stockwell,
                    D.3.0., Highland ment and the city. to which they were entitled to the extent of
                    Light Infantry, has been appointed second-in- "Will the Municipality request the
                    Govern-Stock Exchange at £12 each nett to the bank, moyed from Egypt to Bengal,
                    18,000; the remaining 2,000 were sold on the command of the 1st Battalion, which
                    lately ment to cede plot marked A, or rather, say, or £2 premium on the issue
                    price, giving the 30,000 sq. m., on the following conditions: "1. This block to
                    be built according to plans deducted £1,000, the cost of issue (mostly the
                    province of Bahrel Ghaal, who commands bank a profit of £4,000. From this must
                    be Major W. A. Boninois, RA, Governor of presented, possibly in about a year. 2.
                    Apartments to be let at rents not to £3,000. This £3,000 is to be devoted to
                    paying of cannibalistic propensities known as Government stamps), leaving a nett
                    profit of the expedition destined to punish those gentary exceed 10% on actual
                    cost to workmen ap the staff a bonus of 10 per cent. on their "Nism Niams" in
                    the Upper Nile regions, is a proved, and who will be selected or balloted
                    salaries for the past year. This decision met very smart offer who has won a
                    fine reputa with the hearty approval of those presant. tion during his six
                    years' connection with the the capital of the bank was one million and in the
                    Nile Expedition of 1899, including the The Chairman then went on to state that
                    Khedive's Army. He served with distinction half, of which half a million is paid
                    up. The final rout of the Khalifa's forces (mentioned in reserve fund is also
                    half a million, equal to the despatches) and would have chastised the of the
                    Board in dealing with the profit. The cient forces at his disposal. paid-up
                    capital. He then sketched the policy Niam-Niams early this year had he had suffi
                    first charge on the profit will be £62,500,, or 12 per cent. dividend on the
                    capital of to staff provident fund £1,500; the third Sir C. J. Graves Sawla,
                    Bart, M.V.0.) took half a million; the second charge, subscription that the
                    first-class cruiser Aboukir (Captain charge, the very large amount of £30,000 to
                    first place in the recent long-range firing, par establish a pension fund for
                    the benefit of the ticulars of which were given some time ago in staff. This is
                    undoubtedly a very large sum, these notes. The battleship Montagu (Captain
                    equal, as it is, to 6 per cent, on the capital of T. B. 8. Adair) was a good
                    second. Indeed, alf the bank. The £30,000 will become the property the cruisers
                    and battleships shot well. of the staff, and the scheme for its appropria For a
                    considerable time shorter commisions</p>
                <p>for, of all nationalities.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p4.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>Pone MARSEILLE, par le batean français Congo, parti le LF novembre: VHA FOUR
                    MADRILLE</p>
                <p>$4966-11 Bolio, 24 colie vieux enivre 844 dolls vient lailon 517 pains sind
                    Buerories, 20 store Candiegión, 19 are willes Divers, 40 olive Behrend, 600 de
                    vi FC Baines &amp; Co, G. Franger &amp; Co.,</p>
                <p>NEW YORK COTTON MARKET. Telegram received to-day from New York by Moms Andres,
                    Chawarby &amp; Co., of Alexandria. the large somhsen oefers to sell, to the
                    weaknes The fall is due to the disappointed hopes of Bulle, of southern sharks,
                    to a good deal of operation</p>
                <p>Après Jure restés longtemps stationnaieston having seen thrown upon the market
                    and rés à 7 environ, les Cotton Mills viennent de monter subitement à 9/9
                    acheteurs. O a4changé ce matin 6 à 7,000 titres.</p>
                <p>En husse également la Ward an à 8 1/8 acheteurs, les Markets à 27/3 acheteurs,
                    les Esux d'Alexandrie à 17 1/8 et les Esax du Caire à 1125 achetears.</p>
                <p>Par contre on fléchit légèrement sur 1s Crown Brewery do 232 à 230, sot l'Anglo
                    Ameriein Nile de 5-3/8 5 5/16 acheteurs et sur les Privilégiées Tramwaya
                    d'Alexan- dris de 147 1/2 146 1/2 acheteurs. Lea Dividendes sont demandées à
                    386.</p>
                <p>ADMINISTRATION DES POSTES.</p>
                <p>AVIS</p>
                <p>L'Administration dos Poster met en sjufestion entreprise des transporte potent
                    dans la ville de Fort Baid,ans conditions stipndes dans le eshier des aharges
                    doped as de ostle Direction Gindrals (Parra da Sedarist) &amp; la Direction
                    Leals dea Postes de Port-id.</p>
                <p>pressed for sale, and in consequenes of large selling ont of parohsses for want
                    of margins.</p>
                <p>The heavy rossipts depress the market, The semens shows 9 more cotton giand shan
                    same time last year.</p>
                <p>vis. 1 sottod gianed up to the" 14th Nove aber, 1938. Bales 7,070,deo More 69%
                    4,171,000 Total ginned up to the 14th. November, 1934 Balos 11,741,000</p>
                <p>GUNNY BAG MARKET SCHRAGER BRO CALCUTTA MARKET REPORT FOR WEEK ENDING 10th Novexa,
                    1904.</p>
                <p>Monday and Tuesday were closed days and the Gunny market opened yesterday very'
                    strong, the firmness being due to the rather excited state of the loose Jate
                    market, both here and upcountry, and higher prices havo- been paid by Home
                    buyers and spinners for</p>
                <p>Jute</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p5.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>"I can recommend Perusa for dys- pepsia and stomach trouble. I have been using
                    your medicine for a short period and I feel very much relleved. It is Indeed a
                    wonderful medicine be sides a good tonic."--M. C. Butler.</p>
                <p>gained nothing by saying it-indeed, be would microbe of cancer, or a secondary
                    microbe; whe only have played straight into the hands of ther it will be
                    susceptible of inoculation, and enemies of the Church, who would have quoted
                    whether the animals inoculated will develop in his protest as unmistakable
                    evidence of Papal fections which can be treated for cure. All this hostility to
                    the Republic. They will do that will occupy months. as it is of course. But they
                    will not be able tot over the plain declaration of his Holi news that the
                    profession of Christianity can be in complete accord with a Republican form of
                    government. It can, no doubt; but, as French Christianity is learning, to its
                    cost, the anti- Christian influences which dominate the policy SAINT ANDREW'S
                    FOOTBALL CLUB. of France at the present time have no desire to This fixture was
                    brought off on the parade work in harmony with the Church. On the ground at
                    Mustapha Pasha on Saturday after contrary, it is their deliberate intention to
                    suppress Christianity, if they can. They will noon in lovely weather and before
                    a good turn- out of spectators. The Signallers started the made manifest without
                    grievous spiritual suffer early in the vicinity of Curtis &amp; Co.. Keill fail,
                    of course; but their failure will not be game with the wind at their backs and
                    were There are certainly two opinions as to the and clearing the Saints began to
                    gain ground. ing and spiritual loss. was soon in evidence, and through his
                    tackling expediency of the Channel tunnel, but 1 Neither team for a time could
                    claim any great imagine that if Paris were polled on the sub-advantage, the play
                    being pretty much of the ject of the Champs Elysées "tube" it would
                    give-and-take order. The Saints' forwards were return an emphatic "yes." It is
                    the latest pro- not displaying any brilliancy in their move- jeet to build
                    subterranean passages at the ments, and in this department certainly the The
                    ratification of the Anglo-French Agree-most important points beneath the
                    principal homesters were the superior lot. Cowie was ment having been voted in
                    the Chamber byennes of this great thoroughfare. For long their front-rank
                    warrior, and he, supported by 443 to 105, we may now take it that the the
                    pedestrian public have taken their lives in good half-back play, steadied the
                    attack.. The Sugate will follow suit, and that final success their hands in
                    attempting to "negotiate the Signallers defence, however, was not found will
                    crown the work upon which M. Delcassé formidable stream of traffic that sweeps
                    by at wanting, both New and Harper offering active sad Lord Lansdowne are to be
                    heartily con- certain hours of the day, almost without inter-opposition. The
                    first point of the game fell to gratulated. Nevertheless, it is to be regretted
                    lude, from the Place de la Concorde to the the Saints, and came from the foot of
                    Hutch- that, while the Agreement is accepted as a Arc de Triomphe. ings. That
                    player, taking up the ball close in Prance and England are happily very good and
                    lifting it over the heads of all, placed it whole, a resolution should have been
                    proposed and carried which affirmed that the Chamber friends, but as joint
                    administrators of the New just out of Quarterman's reach. The Signal- counts on
                    M. Delcassé to open negotiations Hebrides they can hardly be described as lers
                    tried hard to square before the interval with the British Government, as soon as
                    a success. One of the French papers in the and certainly their play deserved to
                    meet with possible, with a view to improving the New neighbouring island of New
                    Caledonia, re some success. Their efforts, however, were foundland Convention.
                    That Convention will, ferring to a recent massacre in the New Hebri- unavailing,
                    and the interval arrived with of course, when ratified by the Senate, be des,
                    describes the condition of this group as the score: Saint Andrew's 1, Signallers
                    0. binding upon the two Governments; bat M. "flagrant anarchy," and says neither
                    life The restart gave promise of a very fast Delossé is charged with the task of
                    getting it or property is safe there. Furthermore, moiety. The Signallers were
                    evidently bent altered to meet the requirements, real or both France and England
                    "incur a serious on penetrating the visitors' defence, but Keill aginary, of the
                    French fishing industry. I responsibility" in encouraging settlers to and
                    Fitzgerald were playing a sterling game, and am sorry that the Chamber has laid
                    that duty emigrate there under the present governing were well supported by the
                    halves. Curtis, too, up the Foreign Minister; I hoped that the arrangements.
                    French rights and interests in seemed to be in his element. Still the home-
                    troublesome question of the "French Shore" the New Hebrides are described as
                    "incon-sters persevered and reward at last attend would be settled once and for
                    ever; and the testably predominant," and the suggested solu-ed their efforts,
                    Saxton patting a beauty which fact that it will not be finally settled by the
                    tion of existing evils is the voluntary retire Curtis in clearing over-ran. This
                    gave the other present Convention constitutes a distinct draw-ment of England
                    from the scene and the part-forwards an opening which they were not slow back to
                    complete satisfaction. However, there nership. That remedy, however, would be
                    far to take advantage of, and the score stood one is no reason to fear that
                    England and France from popular either in England or in Australia all. From the
                    kick off play was pretty much That peculiarly Parisian institution, the confined
                    to midfield. The remaining twenty "revue," is more or less a standing dish in
                    the minutes was very finely contested, but no other music halls, but as the year
                    begins to wane, it scoring took place. The whistle sounded with It is a funny
                    country, this country of hair partakes more and more of the character of the
                    score. Signallers 1, Saint Andrew's 1 splitting and of duelling. Why M. Syveton
                    the English pantomime in its allusion to recent The following were the teams
                    smacked General André in the face has been and current events. The Alliance,
                    unfortun- Signallers: Quarterman, New, Harper, Hand- a mystery to everybody, but
                    a greater ately, forbids, but one can imagine the fun ley, Dovey, Austin,
                    Saxton, Limmer, Glee, one is why, as one of his officers has chosen that
                    sprightly French artists of the "Café Herbert, and Woodley. to make the insuit
                    offered to the Minister of concert would extract from the ludicrous Saint
                    Andrew's Curtis, Fitzgerald, Keill, War a personal matter, as Captain de Gail,
                    or story of the Russians in the North Sea. An- Bright, Clark, Nixon, Sweet,
                    Jones, Cowie, the 1leme. Cuirassiers, has done, he should other incident most
                    certainly to be seized upon Hutchings, and Halley. not be allowed to fight M.
                    Syveton and be is the escape and subsequent arrest of M done with it. After all,
                    he merely acted as Syveton. The escapade has little that is noble all, by 58
                    feet moulded breadth, and 36.6 feet deep to the tonnage deck, with a gross
                    tonnage an officer standing up for the Army, and is in it, but the "revue" lets
                    who will be moralist, not that what we are constantly inciting it simply amuses.
                    One has need of an extensive The Anchor Line have added to their fleet of 9,400
                    tons, and when fully loaded her dis ofhears to do! De Gail is an aristocrat
                    knowledge of "argot" and of all the ramifica- the steel twin-screw passenger
                    steamer Cale placement will be not less than 16,000 tons. The first-class
                    accommodation is situated by birth, and has always marked himself out tions of
                    French politics to thoroughly appre- donia, which was launched at Meadowsile,
                    amidships, with staterooms for 300 passengers as begg more of a thinker than
                    most of ciate the niceties of a Paris ""revue" where Parties, on theind Deprem
                    da, beristen on the main and bridge decks. The second- those of his class in the
                    Army. What he has parody is piled on parody, and paradox upon ing ceremony being
                    performed by her Grace class accommodation is also fitted amidships to done
                    in-challenging Syveton may be a rash paradox, often with a talent and a
                    brilliance the Duchess of Montrose, and the vessel will be wards the after end
                    of the vessel; with staterooms all ready and fully equipped in every particu-
                    for 400 passengers. The third class galley and a foolhanty act, but one cannot
                    help that are bewilderingly clever. The quality of lar to take her place in the
                    regular service of contains a most complete steam cooking plant. feeling glad
                    that some French officer should the jokes may be strained, but they generally
                    the company in good time for the spring and do such a thing after Friday's most
                    disgraceful drop in the right place.</p>
                <p>will quarrel over the matter, and we must be content with that we have got.
                    Perfection is not of this world.</p>
                <p>incident.</p>
                <p>Americans. have known how to turn the As to André, he is, it appears, very ill,
                    for theatres of London into a gold mine, and they M. Byveton's blow was a
                    thundering one; but are about to Americanise the theatres of Paris. I think it
                    is pure "méchanceté" that makes According to statements made in the local the
                    journalists talk about his "ratelier" having press, a powerful syndicate has
                    been formed, been deranged. They merely want to throw and it is proposed to
                    found as many as ten new ridicule upon him, and of that there is plenty theatres
                    in the French capital. Playwrights to throw, "Dieu le sait!" Meanwhile, he is
                    quake at the thought. At present they have a unmbtedly ill, and as far as it is
                    at present society strong enough to prevent managers known, both M. Syveton and
                    M. de Gait are from crushing them under the weight of com- under arrest. M.
                    Syveton was arrested just as petition. But in presence of a trust which can the
                    duel was about to take place, and there control ten theatres, a bitter struggle
                    against the was a rumour later to the effect that General power of capital is
                    feared. André had had his generous-defender "mis aux In Paris, at least, the
                    pawnshop has quaint, ariéts." Politics, and political manoeuvres, are
                    half-pathetic humours which it would probably always "tout puissant" in this
                    country, and be difficult to match in England. This is the in all probability
                    the general public will not time of year for renewals, and the expiry of the
                    know more of this affair until it is all over. date makes it possible to take an
                    inventory of En attendant, persons who are really indigold pledges remaining or
                    gone. This year a nant that the French Army should have small object pledged for
                    12s. 8d. in 1869 has contained spies, and others who have some been withdrawn,
                    after 36 annual renewals, in other reason, private or otherwise, for volving £1
                    138.-4d. Among the other "relics" showing up the methods General André still
                    remaining is a mantel ornament pledged for has employed in the carrying out of
                    58. 22 years ago, and regularly renewed. But what he doubtless considered his
                    duty, are the champion "relie" of the place is an ivory- busily exposing the
                    recent manoeuvres of the headed cane, on which the owner has paid 74d. Masonic
                    Lodges in the Army, and the Gaulois a year since 1859. and other papers are full
                    of revelations on the subject. This is, doubtless, quite right, and I because
                    the constant ringing of the bells and on only, imagine that good should come out
                    the call and protests of subscribers told so of the whole thing. That it will
                    bring about a severely on her nervous system that she was fresh Dreyfus
                    disturbance I can hardly believe compelled to leave her position, which she I
                    believed last year that such a thing as a had filled for nine years. revival of
                    that famous affair was not only An interview has taken place between the
                    possible, but even imminent. It is only fair Japanese Minister and M. Delossé
                    with that one should be allowed to change one's reference to "certain matters
                    relative to the opinions when one has a reason for so doing, observance of
                    neutrality," and the Tempe says and I now believe quite the contrary. I believe
                    that explanations are proceeding in an amicable that such a thing would be
                    considered by most way and there is very reason to hope for a infoential
                    Republicans as danger to the satisfactory result. In the present awkward
                    Republic, so great has been the prejudice position of France in the affixirs of
                    the nations, However, we shall in the utmost delicacy and tactfulness is
                    rendered Another series of duels has shaken Paris to necessary, and the country
                    has reason to feel its depths. In two pistols were used, and the grateful that
                    in M. Delcased it has a Minister seconds having apparently exercised the cus who
                    may be depended on to exercise the fomary care in loading them harmlessly
                    necessary quality of discretion. The progress there was, of course, no result.
                    One of the en of the Baltic Fleet is attended with the utmost counters was, that
                    postponed from Thursday danger to the Powers, and not until it has between M.
                    Syveton and Captain de Gait. The reached a destination, whether in the waters of
                    affair with swords was a thore serious matter, warfare or elsewhere, will they
                    be able to General Andre's son being distinctly pricked in breathe freely.</p>
                <p>A Paris telephone girl has committed suicide</p>
                <p>the wrist. The victim afterwards rode agay The Pasteur Institate of Paris is now
                    just on his bicycle, with much less inconvenience entering upon, the experiments
                    which it has than if he had taken part in a football match. undertaken for the
                    purpose of testing exhaus The language of the Papal allocation on the tively the
                    so-called-cancer serum of Dr., Doyen. ecclesiastical situation in France is
                    informeel by The experiments are under the care of Dr. &amp; spirit of dignity
                    and moderation. On this Metchinkoff, and have just reached the primary ocession
                    Plus X would seem to have derived stage of having ready two large
                    bladders-filled bie inspiration from the consummate states with Doyen cultures,
                    with which to propagate,</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p6.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>are an unfailing and reliable remedy for die of the important organe gout,
                    rheumatism, gravel pains in the bank and kindred silmante (nquired or
                    constitutional), Sold by prinetpal Chemite, not to loom quantities, but only in
                    boxes, price L bearing the British Government Bamp with th wonde Eugene Le.
                    Clero pred thereen</p>
                <p>The Biter of the Bgyption Gonette wil be pleased to resolve come nications
                    dealing with malies of local, interest, for yabletion. Notes of to covering in
                    (Between the hours of 10 am and 6pm. Outro time to protect the pable from frid
                    the Provinces are especially welcome. hould be sent to T by and Addres, not
                    nece</p>
                <p>Le Jeudi 24 Novembre conant pactis de 8h. pm., Man/elpalité groolders &amp; la
                    vente atten ahires jobliques pris de ontières Heropéens is &amp; is Porte
                    Rosene, d'ane quantité de pierres extraites der ersion des Forossions par de 400
                    1 100m Les betere devront par le droit d'an shore da 1020 époser le 10 000 de la
                    valore de la marebandise sehetés ant moment de la vante of soon Fon-M... 80/40.
                    Liv. Mare FT. 97 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 offener le paiement insigral &amp; Onlee
                    Mani. All come eipale, le leglessin da jour de l'etindiastion. Ile auront
                    sapporter le droise de carrière an prods de la Ville et devront enlever les
                    pierres ache tée dans un délai de dix jours, sone geins anah Are, pour compte de
                    l'adjudicataire. Alexandrie, le 21 Novembre 1904.</p>
                <p>"DOUBLE</p>
                <p>dv. Mare FT. 880/40 &amp; 10 .-M.</p>
                <p>10/40 1.18/40</p>
                <p>94044-8-9</p>
                <p>folle</p>
                <p>Writer's good faith The B</p>
                <p>1/Adminiralour W. P. CHATAWAY.</p>
                <p>THUM</p>
                <p>1:18</p>
                <p>Dr. LE CLERO'S SOAP. Molloal antiseptia used and recommended by ambent
                    dermatologists in the treatment of eos lepra, psoriaals, alourations, alta
                    eruptions: thehing and treating the bumours baby rashes ode, ale prophyte
                    against the risk of contmoting des and Infotions disordare generally. I healing
                    propension greatly minimise the bon ventence of shaving to use of phapes pote
                    ten La Tablete price / old by Cairo and Ale</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
