<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!-- Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-10-20">October 20, 2023<!-- October 20, 2023 --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 0000-00-00 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-23">Wednesday, November 23,
                        1904<!-- November 23, 1904 --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/mode/1up">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, CITED</p>
                    <p>This Company's: f</p>
                    <p>the stirect and quickes</p>
                    <p>Purp Zompe, North and</p>
                    <p>wipe telegraph calles is munication fres</p>
                    <p>Americs, East, Sout</p>
                    <p>and West Africa, India, Australia New Zealand, Chines</p>
                    <p>To</p>
                    <p>e quick transmission, telegrams should be marke</p>
                    <p>Vis Eastern</p>
                    <p>For et average fire to Lolo, see daily balletta, STATINS IN EGYPT Alex,
                        Cairo, Bags, P Tew Pors-Said, Saskin fead Office, Londen,</p>
                    <p>THE EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette,</p>
                    <p>No. 7,053]</p>
                    <p>ALEXAN BIA. WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>[SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, LINITED</p>
                    <p>La rées de cibles graphiques sous-marins de cetis compagnie enkelte le moyen
                        de communication le ple direct et le plus rapide d'Egypte pour Earepe
                        Amérique de Nord et do Sad, FAfriqa onentale, meridionale e Decidentale, Im
                        India TAstrabe à Nouvelle-Zélande, Chine et le Japon</p>
                    <p>Four serer one transmon rapide l elégra delrent porter Tindication VIA
                        Eastern Voir le tempe moyen de tranen le Londres a ballet journalier geblie
                        STATIONS EN EGYPTE Port-Tewik, Port- Senki Bare</p>
                    <p>Peninsular &amp; Oriental S. N. Company. British India S. N. Company,
                        Limited. Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Coy.</p>
                    <p>The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the
                        following dates:-</p>
                    <p>Marseille, Plymouth and Lenden. Marseilles, Plymouth and London Malta sud
                        London Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Marseilles, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>MALACCA" "HUMATRA</p>
                    <p>6,046 Tone</p>
                    <p>November</p>
                    <p>Malta and Landon Maits and Landco.</p>
                    <p>CRANA</p>
                    <p>4410</p>
                    <p>7,913</p>
                    <p>MANILA</p>
                    <p>December</p>
                    <p>4.210</p>
                    <p>SARDINIA"</p>
                    <p>574</p>
                    <p>MACEDONIA"</p>
                    <p>10,811</p>
                    <p>MARMORA</p>
                    <p>10,809</p>
                    <p>PERA</p>
                    <p>9,712</p>
                    <p>SUNDA</p>
                    <p>CHINA</p>
                    <p>Marselle, Plymouth soul Leidon. Waris and Lendon</p>
                    <p>Malta and Lendon, - Marsellies, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>Port-Baid to London via Brindisi. The BRINDISI steamer leaves PORT-BAID sher
                        arrival of Indian Mail. Combined steamer and giging me fare from PORT-SAID
                        to LONDON via BRINDISI or via MARSEILLES 25:9.11.</p>
                    <p>To the East</p>
                    <p>The Mall Bosses leave BUEZ for ADEN and BOMBAY every Wednesday, and for
                        AUSTRALIA and CHINA every alternate Wednesday. A same leavec for CALCUTTA,-
                        fortnightly, and another for JAPAN. Pagers en etabari PORT-SAID.</p>
                    <p>For all further information apply to the Company's Agents, Mors. Twoe. Coon
                        &amp; Bow (ayy) Lad.... Gueses BoTLE,</p>
                    <p>Moners. HARULDAN &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>MAIL AND PASSENGER STEAM SHIPS. SAILINGS FROM SUEZ London and Calcutta
                        Line.</p>
                    <p>Chiet-Office: Sharia Boulae, Grand Continental Hotel Buildings Br Ufice,
                        Upponte Savey Hotel, Caire Regular weekly Tourist Steamer Departures between
                        Carno and Assocax by the following</p>
                    <p>steamers --</p>
                    <p>Queensland Line of Steamers between London and Brisbane. MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p>1904.</p>
                    <p>December 9th VICTORIA 38ed PURITAN 80th MAYFLOWER.</p>
                    <p>1905.</p>
                    <p>Calling at Apes, Cososo and Mansas Outward, and MasILE (GENOA and Purour
                        dpsional) Homeward Fortly rice in connection with the Ce's Indian Mail Line
                        and monthly with the East African Mail Lane between Aass, Mo sod EATERAL
                        OUTWARD 8.8. Mutira. November 26 HOMEWARD: 8.8. Mombassa Nov. 38 MAYFLOWER
                        FURITAN Weekly SECOND CATARACT SERVICE by the First Class Tourist Steamer
                        INDIANA AGENTS FOR PRINCIPAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANIES Through Bookings to
                        Khartoum and Gondokare. RAILWAY TICKETS TO ALL PARTS OF EGYPT. FREIGHT
                        SERVICE by steam barges between ALEXANDRIA and CAIRO SAVOY HOTEL Elephantine
                        Island, Accap, Company's Property.</p>
                    <p>Calling at Cusco, BATAVIA, Coorowy, Towa, Bows, and RockArrow 8.8. "ITIA,"
                        will mail from Boes on or about the 14th December. REMARKS Surgeons and
                        Stewardes carried. Ice rooms, Funkata, and every comfort for stropical
                        climate. Passengers and Cargo booked shrough to Continental and American
                        Forte and to Gulf, East Africa, Burmah, Straits Settlements Eastern Archipel
                        important Porte on Cons of India, Persian may, so below, metode ble for Fint
                        acid Becond Cisas Pgly, bet not winds of spirit, which may be Jars and
                        Quomeland Perte. Bates of Pangs on beard for payment. Pengers are allowed to
                        break the reog my intermediate Parts probed by following FIRST GLASS BATH OF
                        PASSAGE MONEY FROM BURS AND IRMAT</p>
                    <p>Karmacha Bothbay Brshire</p>
                    <p>From Port Said # Agents in LONDON, Murs</p>
                    <p>Fonging Agent INDIA</p>
                    <p>CAIBO.</p>
                    <p>PORT-SAID. ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>81-19-90</p>
                    <p>F. G. DAVIDSON, Soprintendens P. &amp; O. B. N. Company in Egypt. BUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Orient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDE to AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p>B.M.B. Orotava. will leave Bass abous, Oroya</p>
                    <p>Orizaba</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Agence at PORT SAID,</p>
                    <p>Agmin M PORT SAID, Men Tho</p>
                    <p>For furth</p>
                    <p>Onlomb</p>
                    <p>Ola, Twe Thirds of 1st Cine T</p>
                    <p>and Karocbon</p>
                    <p>Company, GALNO &amp; ALARKANDRIA</p>
                    <p>G. BEXTS &amp; Co., Agents, Bues. 81-15-804</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE, Limited.</p>
                    <p>(HENDERSON BROTHERS), LONDON, LIVERPOOL, AND GLASGOW. First class passenger
                        steamers, Booking Passengers and. Cargo through to Ports in INDIA, EUROPE
                        &amp; AMERICA</p>
                    <p>Sailings Fortnightly from Buss.</p>
                    <p>Dec. 10 For CALOUTTA 8.8. Ayria...... Nov. 24 For BOMBAY 8.8.
                        Circassia...</p>
                    <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.</p>
                    <p>Fortnightly Service from ALEXANDRIA (Passengers and Freight). Commonning on
                        the 16 of Novetube.</p>
                    <p>To NAPLES and MARSEILLES, with the Twinsrow-baloon mer Schleswig (100)
                        leaving ALEXANDRIA Ovary aboca Wedomday at 2 pm.: 16 &amp; 80 Nov., 14 Des.,
                        11 Jan 6 Jan, 3 Fab The following steamers are intended to leave PORT SAID:
                        HORNWARD: for Bremen or Hamburg v NAPLE, GOA (ISBALTAR), SOUTHAMPTON, P.
                        Bas. LavyOL 300 2008 BARSABUSSA PRAUSSEN</p>
                    <p>ZIETEN OLDENBURG</p>
                    <p>84 Ton PRINCES ALICE 10911 SCHARNBORST</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD: for Chine and Japan sum, ADES, UOLOMBO, PARANG, SINGAPORS, December
                        7 SKYDLITZ BOUN November 28 BAYERN ZIXTAN</p>
                    <p>Dee.</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>For LONDON</p>
                    <p>Lee.</p>
                    <p>16</p>
                    <p>For MARSEILLES ALIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>8.8. Bohemia 8.8. Marilia</p>
                    <p>Dee</p>
                    <p>6</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>Baloon Farms: from Port-Baid, to Gibraltar 40; Marseille : Leverpool (alla
                        route) 818 London (all sea rente) 41311 vs Marvellion $16.16.0 Pangs
                        embarking at Ismailis &amp; more, 65 mars 10 00 reduction allows of the Army
                        of Occupation and Government employs. Through Hoke wed to New-York (v G).
                        Fares o Agentia in Oairo, Mons THOMAS,000K &amp; SON, Part-Bal, Mrs. CORY
                        BROTHERS &amp; OT For further particulars of Freight or Page apply to G.
                        BEYTS &amp; Co., Sues.</p>
                    <p>81-13-306</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY B.M.
                        Ortona will leave Port-bald about... NB-Homewarders are sometimes before
                        their advertised dates. Passengers landed and embarked at Ismailia,
                        Quarantine Regulations permitting, free of an expense 1 Class, 411 And
                        Clasi, &amp; 1 Brd Class, 44 81-</p>
                    <p>VARES</p>
                    <p>Pors-Hald to Nagles......</p>
                    <p>to Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>to Ginealta.....</p>
                    <p>18 18</p>
                    <p>10 10</p>
                    <p>10 MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED. Betablished 1888. Capital £1,000,000,
                        Bearve Fund 4035,000.</p>
                    <p>10-</p>
                    <p>8 16-</p>
                    <p>81-13-906</p>
                    <p>8000</p>
                    <p>-14 Nov De</p>
                    <p>GNEISENAU RHIN FRIEDRICH BREMEN</p>
                    <p>Zor Anetralla</p>
                    <p>FOR FURTHER PARTICULARS ARPAY TO TER ARNTS OF FER NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD at
                        Cairo, Alemandria, Port Said and Suen OTTO STERZING, A Cairo, Orena
                        BQUARE</p>
                    <p>C. H. SCHOELLER, AGA ALEXANDRIA, Oleopatra Lans</p>
                    <p>DALBO and AMBEANURIA</p>
                    <p>Hevur tickets so long tested, as per paying the full he in one duression are
                        allowed no Ola Broad Beroes, LONDON.-Hemblished 1908. Avial Funds exceed
                        $10,000,000, Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation.</p>
                    <p>to Plymouth or Tilbury. abstemens of one-third of their fars back if the rear
                        voyage be made within four monste of arrival, or An abotecons of so if
                        resten voyage be made within six months of armval. Ages, Cairo-THOMAS COOK
                        &amp; BOR. Alexandina B. J. Moss &amp; Co.- For all information apply to Wm.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Port-Said and Port-Tewik Sues), 81-18-904</p>
                    <p>BIBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>SPROIAL REDUURD RATES DURING THE SUMMER SHAUN</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS to 0OLOMBO: TUTICORIN, etc., and BANGOON</p>
                    <p>5. Yorkalere, 136 tons will have us abou. November 28,</p>
                    <p>8 Warwickshire, 19 tons, will leave bus; about December 7.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD MARSEILLE and LONDON,</p>
                    <p>Sa Worcestershire, 60 tons will leave Port-Said about November 29,
                        Shrupehors, 720 tons will leave Port-aid abous Desemoir</p>
                    <p>FARBS from Fortid to Marseilles 12.0.0, London 417.0.0 moo 632.100, Rangoon,
                        437.19.0. Fitted with Refrigerators, Bleonic Lights Electric fane and all
                        recent improvemente, Experienced Stewardesses and burgsons carried, Agents
                        in Cairo: Memes, THOS, GooR &amp; BON. Yor all particulars apply to W.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; SONS, Port-Said Port-Tewak (Sues).</p>
                    <p>81-18-904</p>
                    <p>1, Street,</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>2nd inst</p>
                    <p>Policies invoed at BUEZ by G. BEYTS &amp; Co., Agents.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste-Venice Line. Express Mail Hervice. Beam leave
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Deutsche Levante-Linie, in Today morning for agent to Paris, London</p>
                    <p>Weekly</p>
                    <p>Tneste We</p>
                    <p>Nov. 19</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>Mail and Passenger Beamships. Regular three-weekly serve from expresse
                        HAMBURG, VIA ANTWERP &amp; MALTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice vers, admitang
                        goods from all the prinelyal GERMAN BAILWAY STATIONS on diroos, Bill of
                        Lading to ASRXANDRIA and all the principal port of Bers, SYRIAN CHART,, as
                        she favourable through mana, of the Day Va (tm).</p>
                    <p>EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>8.8. Siegfried, now on the berth loading will sail for Rotterdam and Hamburg
                        on se 8.8. Thasos now in port will sail for Beyrout on the 28rd inst Lesbos
                        from Answerp will mail for Beyrons on the 23rd inst.</p>
                    <p>For tariffs and parstenars apply to ADOLPHE STEOB8, Alexandria, Agent,
                        18-9-905</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE. Messageries Maritimes.</p>
                    <p>FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Green-Turkey Liss,</p>
                    <p>Express momers vs Alexandria every Wednesday 6pm. for FIRMUS (Athens), SMTRNA
                        MITYLENE, and CONSTANTINOPLE. in sospesos wish the Ons greasin-de-lass for
                        belgrade, Vienna, Paris, and London.</p>
                    <p>Palestine-Syita</p>
                    <p>Fasters gre Alexandria very day gim., and For Bald every Bunday atp., for
                        JAVVA (for Jessie), CALFFA (for Bar), BYHOUT. (for Demeras), TRIPOLI, ALEX-
                        ANDRETTA, MENINA, sensing in wks so LANNACA and LIMANNOL (Cyprus).</p>
                    <p>Red Sea Line.</p>
                    <p>mer leave Sues every Thursday sp. for JMDDAR, alling as required at TOR (for
                        Mouns Stasy and XAMBO,, and sonatsing in abseness wo UAKIN, MANNOWAR,
                        HODEIDAR And ADEN.</p>
                    <p>H.B. Desk chairs provided for the mes of passengers, excellent enivine and
                        table wine free.. ms plant may be seen and poenget booked st the Company's
                        Against Alexandria, Cairo, Fors Bad, and Uses of a Thos. Cook a son or oshee
                        Touries Agacey,</p>
                    <p>31-18-904</p>
                    <p>The Moss S.S. Company, Limited.</p>
                    <p>For GAVERFOUL ng MALTA, JANE MUU, LA, MARGIN</p>
                    <p>Baillage from alexandria in November, 1904,</p>
                    <p>Rate of passage Including bis wine</p>
                    <p>nd Ola</p>
                    <p>From Aidonsdria! For Marseilles direct Friday Nov. noon</p>
                    <p>Cap. Vincenti</p>
                    <p>Galent</p>
                    <p>Prem Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Wednesday</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>For Part Said Jaffa and Bayrants 1 Nov. Portugal Conge For Port Said and
                        Beyrouth Wednesday Nov. at p... Senegal Trongh tickets for Paris (vi
                        Marellin</p>
                    <p>Camagit Riquier Owp Galett</p>
                    <p>To Naple</p>
                    <p>To Marsiline</p>
                    <p>Raquier</p>
                    <p>Galet</p>
                    <p>Capt. Camagit Fascents</p>
                    <p>To Pers Bald To Jaffo</p>
                    <p>L161</p>
                    <p>-47.10</p>
                    <p>To Bayreut</p>
                    <p>Through tickets for London (vis Maresiae) (Unials Donyres)
                        Ceningns-Polkestone) marchangable return deal with the Antrian Lloyd Oy
                        (available Marlitosen and on redom by Austrian Lloyd) er Tre) Sallings from
                        Port Said In November 1904 Probably on Thursday 10 Nov, Bolaria Okpt. Négre
                        Gregort</p>
                    <p>For Mareation Directi</p>
                    <p>For A, Chicho, Bingapore, Balgo, Hong-Kong, Shandy Robe and Yokohams For
                        Dibena Colombo, Singapore, Belgin, Yekobams</p>
                    <p>Caledonien</p>
                    <p>Sallings from Seen In November, 1904</p>
                    <p>Saturday Wednesday 18</p>
                    <p>19 Nov. Ernet- Tombin Melbourne</p>
                    <p>marile, Adelaide, Mal-Monday</p>
                    <p>1 Den 38 Nov.</p>
                    <p>X</p>
                    <p>For Dbons Bannibar, Mutamado, Mayotte, Magune</p>
                    <p>For Dribeos, Aden, Mabe, Dag</p>
                    <p>T.M.</p>
                    <p>8,000</p>
                    <p>TADOS</p>
                    <p>Send</p>
                    <p>modation only, ani aiya</p>
                    <p>apply</p>
                    <p>ES. NITOURIN</p>
                    <p>birth, will an</p>
                    <p>freight</p>
                    <p>Lancashire inland i</p>
                    <p>FAR TO LAverpool, la, la Bingia, Ben, Ind. Bingle, BOSS &amp; C, Alexandria,
                        Agents fallowed by B SETI other UJA. town on be obtained en Railway are
                        through to and from Ontro, Partieniars on application,</p>
                    <p>Bunton and Mearice</p>
                    <p>For A</p>
                    <p>30-11-004</p>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO.'s LINE.</p>
                    <p>Somers or Bass Port-basd rialgaly tos London or Liverpoos dire Mastrie Light
                        SALOON (A) FARE AIR. (later improvement 8.8. AMARAFOORA, 6600 Tone will
                        leave PORT-SAID about Nov. 97 for Liverpool. MARTABAN BANGOON 8000</p>
                    <p>750</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>A WORMS &amp; G., Part</p>
                    <p>for Laverpool 26 for Liverpool.. Dus in Leadon or Liverpool 18 days
                        thereafter. TMOS. GOOK A BON. EU La., 6. J. GRAGE &amp;. drie</p>
                    <p>Dee. "</p>
                    <p>31-18-40</p>
                    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p>(ROYPT), LIMIT.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE LUDGATE CIRCUS-LONDON,</p>
                    <p>CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE CAIRO, SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Port-Said, Iamallia, Suez, Luxor, Assouan,</p>
                    <p>Halfa &amp; Khartoum,</p>
                    <p>TOURIST AND GENERAL PASSENGER AGENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>bey, Gelembe, bearse, Bydiy and Neumen.</p>
                    <p>Gaira Agency Shepheard's Metal.)</p>
                    <p>returning from China</p>
                    <p>Anatralla</p>
                    <p>day noon conusong with Vienne pres (T-Ovende Imly and Germany. 4pm. Cleopatra
                        Capt. A. Ivallich. Nov. 284 p.m. Habsburg C Semiramis Marsinolich. Deo. 8
                        Ulkopatra Alexandria-Patras-Brindisi-Trieste Line. Beamer leaves Alexandra
                        on or about 3rd November, Tah and 21st December. Far East Line. (Departure
                        from Sun). To Aden, Bombay, Colombo, Fapang,</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Colombo, Madras, Hangoon and Calea abous November 90. East African
                        Line.</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Mombasa, Zanzibar, Beirs, Delagon Bay, Durban about December 4.
                        Syrian-Caramania Line</p>
                    <p>Steamer leaves Alexandria on or abous November 14 and 98, December 13 and
                        96.</p>
                    <p>Syrian Cyprus-Caramanian Line.</p>
                    <p>Beamer Laves Alexandria on or about November 23, December 5 and 10.</p>
                    <p>For all information apply to the Company's Age. And, Fort Bald and Soo, Te
                        &amp; Bon, L., Leon Hasan, Oniro Agent, 4 Sharia Maghaky (Telephone 198),
                        Cle Tapason, Heloman. Special passage rates granted to Egyptian Government
                        oficials, of the Army of Occupation and their families.</p>
                    <p>CUNARD LINE.</p>
                    <p>Trieste-New York. Liverpaal-New York BLAVONIA... Sept. 80, LecaMZA... 12,962
                        sons. UMBRIA PANTONIA Oct 14 CAMPANIA... 12,950 15,564</p>
                    <p>SLAVONIA... PANNONIA</p>
                    <p>Liverpool-</p>
                    <p>8,197 tone. Baxo</p>
                    <p>ErSURIA 8,119</p>
                    <p>AURANIA 7,526</p>
                    <p>16</p>
                    <p>18 Embarking passengers at the Riverside Railway Dec. 2 haion, Prince's age,
                        Liverpool, on Tuesdays and</p>
                    <p>the Agents UDUGANAUHI &amp; UB, Alandria; NICOLAS KIRSIS, Ore, B. BROADER</p>
                    <p>ELLERMAN LINES, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>CITY &amp; HALL LINES.</p>
                    <p>WARSHILLSS, LIVERPOOL, BOMBAY &amp; EARACHL</p>
                    <p>CITY LINE.</p>
                    <p>MALTA, LONDON, COLOMBO &amp; CALCUTTA</p>
                    <p>The undermentional First-Use Penger Steamere will be dispatched from Port bud
                        on or about the following Malta &amp; Landes 8.8. Cry OF BEARS Nov. 30
                        Liverpeet. Colombe &amp; Caloutte &amp; Cor Caters No. Bombay &amp;
                        Kareahl-</p>
                    <p>for</p>
                    <p>&amp; Pros</p>
                    <p>Nov, 1</p>
                    <p>Cery on Lecko BALOO FassPort Had to Malta, 441 Mar 200 London or Liverpool,
                        41164 Calho, Cal Bombay or Karachi, 100. peal rate for more bot carrying
                        Doctor or Steward For further person GORY BROTHERS &amp; Uo., Ltd., agents
                        for the City Line, Port Said; W. STAPLEDON &amp; SON, Agent for the Hall
                        Link Port Baldy or to Tros. Cook &amp; Bon (gypt, Ltd. Ostro</p>
                    <p>L</p>
                    <p>Nov. 30</p>
                    <p>apply to</p>
                    <p>Tone</p>
                    <p>PRINCE LINE.</p>
                    <p>AFRICAN PRINC TUDOR PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Tons 5,000 WALAH PRINUBE 7100 BLACK PRINCE</p>
                    <p>CHINESE PRINCS (bd).</p>
                    <p>SWEDISH PRINCE (bida)-</p>
                    <p>ITALIAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>MERORANT FRINGE.</p>
                    <p>BOLDIRK PRINCE</p>
                    <p>MEXICAN PRINUR SICILIAN PRINC BRITISH PRINCE. GRECIAN PRINCE ORBOLE PRINUR
                        SYRIAN PRINGR.. INDIAN PRINC TUBGAN PRINU</p>
                    <p>2000 SPANISH PRINCE (Olde NORMAN PRINCES GROBOTAN FRINGE</p>
                    <p>16 BAVIAR PRINCR RUSSIAN PRINC 4,490 HIGHLAND PRINUS 8,780 NRAPOLITAN PRINO
                        IM MOORISH PRINCE 307S BAUTERN PRINCE 8060 CARES PRINCE COBANOS PRINUS..
                        SCOTTISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>TOURAN PRINOR</p>
                    <p>Tona 1,000 | AFGHAN PRINC 2000 BURMESE PRINUS (dg). 7,000 BAXON PRINUR 4,000
                        CROWN PRINCR</p>
                    <p>4780 TROJAN PRINUS 463 BOYPTIAN PRINUS 4800 SPARTAN PRINCR 800 IMPERIAL
                        PRINCE 8,780 PERSIAN PRINUR 8.IM 33 CASTILLIAN PRINCE 800 AREATIO PRINUR
                        8,00 KAFFIB PRINCE..</p>
                    <p>3878 UTPRIAN PRINOR--</p>
                    <p>10 BOMAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>1,000 ROYAL PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Good Accommodation for Passengers.</p>
                    <p>Navigation Generale Italienne. Societes Rousies Flerie-Rabatties Services
                        Postaux. Departs de Decembre</p>
                    <p>Les Jendis 1, 8, 16, 99 99 8h. p. direct pour Messine, Naples, Liveure et
                        Génes.</p>
                    <p>Les Jendis 1 es 13 à 8h. p.m. direes poor Brindisi, Bari, Aneboe et
                        Veniso</p>
                    <p>Le Mercredi 18 &amp; 10 ham. pour les vales de la Syrie es Larnaque</p>
                    <p>Le Lundi 19 &amp; 4 b. p.m. pone Port-Sald, Snes et Masen wah.</p>
                    <p>Le Mercredi 7 et Jeudi à 8h. p.m. pour Fort Said.</p>
                    <p>BANK OF ATHENS, Limited. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</p>
                    <p>Failings hegy 10 days from Haste sal gel and beinghtly Awad Less to Aldra and
                        Byrias Coast. The dates are apprinteri &amp; Teeth Fasha ARIATIC PRING due
                        trois Lende</p>
                    <p>Nov</p>
                    <p>INDEAN FRIZUR</p>
                    <p>Manhbester</p>
                    <p>Du</p>
                    <p>SCO TISH PAINOR</p>
                    <p>TROJAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>Anwery &amp; London Manchester</p>
                    <p>CANTILLIAN PRINCE dee from Antwerp &amp; London Dee ROYAL PRINCS ARIB PRINOR
                        101RROLE PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Manchaster Antwerp &amp; London Manchester</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD SAILINGR-The &amp;&amp; Crown Prince is welding este sad will be
                        loved by the &amp; Asiátie Prinon For terms of freight or passage apply to
                        O. J. Grace &amp; Co., Alexandria, Agents. 31-12 904</p>
                    <p>THE PAPAYANNI LINE. (The Ellerman Lines, Ltd.)</p>
                    <p>Fregnant Sailingo from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL, aleo Begular Services from
                        LIVERPOOL ALEXANDRIA and to ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT. BLACK SHA, and other
                        Mediterranean Ports Excellent Passenger Accommodation. Stewardess carried.
                        Liberal table and</p>
                    <p>ap-Moderate Fares for single and return tickets by the 88. BARDINIA</p>
                    <p>Baggage and Forwarding Agents. NILE STEAMER SERVICES, TOURIST SERVICE. The
                        large and spendidly pointed P.S. Rameses, will leave Cairo on Tuesday,
                        November 29th, for Luxor, Assouan, and Phils. Other sailings every Tuesday
                        during the Season.</p>
                    <p>EXPRESS SERVICE-Steamers leave Oairó every</p>
                    <p>The BK CITY OF Dexos, cow loading will leave for Liverpool in a few days and
                        will be followed CARGO aken by spasial agreement only. Through Freight
                        quoted for the UNITED STATES and INLAND TOWNS in GREAT BRITAIN. For passings
                        or freight apply to the Agents, BARKER &amp; Co., Alexandria 8081
                        81-10-908</p>
                    <p>Monday and Friday during the season for Luxor, The Ellerman Lines.
                        Limited</p>
                    <p>ssouan, and Philae. 20 days on the Nile for £22. SPECIAL COMBINED BARWAY AND
                        STEAMER BE TOURS AT GREATLY REDUCED FARES. $1-WEEKLY SERVICE TO BALFA,
                        KHARTOUM, &amp; BUDAR. SPECIAL STEAMERS AND DAHABBAHN FOR PRIVATE PARTIES
                        Regular Service of Freight Steamers between GAIRO and HALFA. Cook's
                        Intergradere in miforts are prevent at the principal Bailway Batons and
                        Landing places in Boot Camp equipes. Lowest changes. 10-18-906</p>
                    <p>To to Palons,</p>
                    <p>(Including Westcott &amp; Laurance Line.)</p>
                    <p>Capital 28,000,000 (Fally paid a BANERS London, ha reet Within-Ales hent Gree
                        The Bank apdartakes all banking businem in gypt, Gre 6. Interests on caah
                        deposit</p>
                    <p>à per from Po P.P. 10,00</p>
                    <p>Despatch weakly a steamer with socommodation carrying Malls to Ceraus and the
                        SYRIAN OBART C For particulars of treight pa the Agent RDA, MINUTTO</p>
                    <p>SUDAN GOVERNMENT RAILWAYS. CAIRO-KHARTOUM SUMMER MAIL SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Dime</p>
                    <p>Dining and opting</p>
                    <p>Bunday and Wat</p>
                    <p>Lazee on Mondays, and from and Cairo, Tharaday and Friday more</p>
                    <p>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED. TRANSPORT DEPARTM et
                        goods anderskan to all coxon Whe ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT SOLE AGENDE FOR Digs
                        C Engine; from 1 Heat Co., Ltd, eto,</p>
                    <p>KHARTOUMAIRO OFFIC, SHARIA KASB--N NT day White Nile Tours Tripp Khartoum
                        Thotays Samar plasmay be Niles within navigation Shipyard he construin of
                        merwheel mit erection of all dies of machinery, bushings argon p B..Pplied
                        to Sudan Governan</p>
                    <p>Sheet</p>
                    <p>INTERNATIONAL SLEEPING AND RESTAURANT CARS COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>Depart</p>
                    <p>16.40</p>
                    <p>મા મને અચાનક પાછો દો</p>
                    <p>Alavambis</p>
                    <p>Regular sailings from Liverpool, Glasgow Antwerp and London to Alaxandris
                        Proquant sailings from Ales edria, to Liverpool sad des Throngh freight
                        rares to Inland towns in Great Aritate ale to the USA Work 8.8. Bolderaa
                        from London &amp; Mali is due on or about Nov. 98 Che Ararat Liverpool
                        Hwaneos &amp; Malta Antwerp &amp; Londos Liverpool &amp; "Malts London</p>
                    <p>Ellerman Westcott Ellerman. Wenteos</p>
                    <p>Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Flavian</p>
                    <p>Delgravian Crestes</p>
                    <p>The B. Athenian, now the berth for Liverpool, will be despatel</p>
                    <p>For parsiquiars apply. E. TAMVACO,</p>
                    <p>every</p>
                    <p>Cal ser notice the Trais de ese componed anusitely Soping and Tarsat Care
                        will Cole res Monday, Weinlay, and Baluniag Thursday, and day from LaWMAN
                        Supplemant for leaping On PT. 18 (1) Tubes and all information can be
                        obtained at Company's</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"  
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n1/mode/1up">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Royal Insurance Coy</p>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE. LARGEST FIRE OFFICE IN THE WORLD. HAJELDEN &amp; Co., Agents,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>B. VITERBO &amp; Jo., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Our Winter Season's Stocks</p>
                    <p>COMPRISING AN</p>
                    <p>Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver &amp; Plated Articles,
                        CUTLERY, LEATHER &amp; ATHLETIC GOODS &amp; GAMES..</p>
                    <p>TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS. CHOICE HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS. VINTAGE WINES.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LD PROVISIONS, CONFECTION RY AND TABLE
                        DELICACIES,</p>
                    <p>$1-8-906</p>
                    <p>ESTABLтеHED 17821</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; Co., Agmis, Alexandria, FRED. OTT &amp; Co., Sub Agents,
                        Calro</p>
                    <p>GWYNNES, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                    <p>GWYNNE, LONDON</p>
                    <p>Onde</p>
                    <p>ABO, and th Baltions, Al. MORNING &amp; MEALS.</p>
                    <p>Trade Mark- "INVINCIBLE."</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT</p>
                    <p>Telephones</p>
                    <p>544 BANK.</p>
                    <p>Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly moderate prices.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Supply Stores, (BRANCH WALKER &amp; CO., CAIRO). WALKER &amp;
                        MEI MARACHI, Limited.</p>
                    <p>MENA HOUSE HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>IS NOW OPEN.</p>
                    <p>Centrifugal Pumping Machinery CAIRO SAVOY</p>
                    <p>in the world, suitable for all purposes, including</p>
                    <p>RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE, IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING
                        DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                    <p>These Pumps can be driven by Bears, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other
                        power, for Lifts of from 1. in 5008., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a Minnie
                        Makers of the Mex Pamps. Results Guaranteed. Over 50 Years' Practical
                        Experienos.</p>
                    <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet
                        Egyptian requirements.</p>
                    <p>London Omees</p>
                    <p>81, Cannon Street, London, E.O.</p>
                    <p>Works Hammersmith, London,</p>
                    <p>38369-11-13-904</p>
                    <p>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER</p>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB,</p>
                    <p>24848-80-4-905</p>
                    <p>HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Will Open November 26.</p>
                    <p>31-8-905</p>
                    <p>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL</p>
                    <p>PORT SAID. First Class Hotel. Modern in all respects. Fire-proof, Drained to
                        the Ses, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French Billiards, Fresh and Salt
                        Water Baths..</p>
                    <p>The Coolest Summer Besilence in Bgypt Special terms to Cairo Besidente and
                        their families desirous of enjoying the cool air and ses bathing during the
                        summe months. DRAGOMANS IN HOTEL, UNIFORM MENT ALL TRAINS AND STRAMERS,</p>
                    <p>23041-38-8-818</p>
                    <p>JOHN MOIR &amp; SON,</p>
                    <p>LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, ABERDEEN, AND SEVILLE. PURVEYORS TO THE KING.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF</p>
                    <p>THE SEVILLE ORANGE MARMALADE, WHOLE FRUIT JAMS, PURE PICKLES,&amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Head Office: 9 &amp; 10, GREAT TOWER ST., LONDON. Agents: D. A. VAFIADIS
                        &amp; CO., P.O. BOX 540, CAIRO,</p>
                    <p>DAILY WEATHER REPORT.</p>
                    <p>OBSERVATIONS BY SUBTY DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>8.8.W. Eight</p>
                    <p>shade</p>
                    <p>130 1.0.004</p>
                    <p>REMABER</p>
                    <p>As noon yesterday the wind blew, strong from the NW. There was a rough a
                        Howry, dark, travelling clouds pre- wind falling light. At midnight it
                        became almost calm, with</p>
                    <p>allied and it was showery at times in the afternoon, the heavy continuous rim
                        and qually weather from the 8.8.W.. the ses becoming smoother arometer
                        rising slowly.</p>
                    <p>OTHER STATIONS For the 34 hours ending am. Yesterday</p>
                    <p>MAX</p>
                    <p>Min.</p>
                    <p>MAX.</p>
                    <p>STATIONS</p>
                    <p>STATIONS</p>
                    <p>Wady Halls Berber</p>
                    <p>Sunlight</p>
                    <p>Absolutely Pure &amp; Genuine.</p>
                    <p>The Great</p>
                    <p>English Laundry Soap.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                    <p>ERY OLD SPECIAL</p>
                    <p>Scotch Whisky O DISTILLERS COMPANY L</p>
                    <p>EDINBURGH</p>
                    <p>Bole Agents for Beypt &amp; Sudan G. G. DROSSOS &amp; CO. LATE PRAZZICA &amp;
                        DROSSOS. ALEXANDRIA, CATRO, PORT-BALD AND KHARTOUM</p>
                    <p>$1090</p>
                    <p>80-11-904</p>
                    <p>SPIRO CONDOLEON.</p>
                    <p>SMYRNA TURKEY-CARPETS. Made entirely of wool and vegetable onlons Tus Beer
                        CARPT p T WORLD. APIRO BUILDINGS Sharia Kaw-el-Hil; Ca</p>
                    <p>98501-1-1-006</p>
                    <p>The Tosh Whisky</p>
                    <p>Established 1720.</p>
                    <p>MACKINTOSH &amp; C°</p>
                    <p>INVERNESS.</p>
                    <p>General Depot. JOHN ROSS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Marina,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Retailers.</p>
                    <p>E. J. FLEURENT, Square Helim Pacha, CAIRO</p>
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>My P. P. Gre is the Correspondent of the</p>
                    <p>Gazelle as Cairo</p>
                    <p>Vales,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Printers</p>
                    <p>Stationers</p>
                    <p>Bookbinders.</p>
                    <p>Dealers in Fancy Goods.</p>
                    <p>7-8-905</p>
                    <p>ABK</p>
                    <p>FOR</p>
                    <p>WREXHAM</p>
                    <p>REWED A</p>
                    <p>WREXHAM</p>
                    <p>ENGLAND</p>
                    <p>AGER BEEPER</p>
                    <p>EXPORN</p>
                    <p>PILSENER</p>
                    <p>REGISTERED</p>
                    <p>AND IF NOT SUPPLIED APPLY TO</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. CAFFARI,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; GAIRO</p>
                    <p>THEMER</p>
                    <p>W</p>
                    <p>Humber ars &amp; Cycles</p>
                    <p>Beeston &amp; Coventry</p>
                    <p>ASK FOR</p>
                    <p>JOHN HAIG'S GLEN LEVEN Old Scotch Whisky. JOHN HAIG &amp; Co, Limited,
                        MARKINCH, SCOTLAND.</p>
                    <p>BOLE PROPRIETORS:</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED PRIOR TO 1880,</p>
                    <p>15284-36-11-004 Boss AGEX: ros Bay R. COREO &amp; G. PARIENTE, Caire.</p>
                    <p>"AL HAYAT" Helouan</p>
                    <p>First Class Health Resort UNRIVALLED POSITION on the Mokattam Hills 96 metres
                        above the level of the Nile, surrounded by desert. ALL ROOMS FULL SOUTH WITH
                        SHELTERED VERANDAHS. PUBLIC SITTING ROOMS in separate Pavilions
                        communicating by glass corridors.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light - Steam-Heating - Lift. Bathing, Air and Diet Cures. Resident
                        Medical Director. All kinds of Sports, Own Stables. Omnibus meets all
                        Trains. ILLUSTRATED PROSPECTUS SENT FREE ON APPLICATION.</p>
                    <p>THE ARTESIAN BORING</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PROSPECTING COMPANY. (SOCIÉTÉ ANONYME</p>
                    <p>CAIRO, 28, SHARIA EL-MANAKH,. (OPPOSITE IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK).</p>
                    <p>1.-Installation of complete Water supplies for drinking, agricultural, and
                        industrial purposes by means of artesian wells</p>
                    <p>Deep borings for prospecting purposes in all conditions of soil.</p>
                    <p>WATER SUPPLY INSTALLATIONS HAVE ALREADY BEEN SUCCESSFULLY CARRIED
                        OUT-FOR:</p>
                    <p>Abl-al-Maguid el Abd Bay Choubrah-el-Namleh, 4,000 enbie metres per day.
                        Société Anonyme des Moulins d'Egypte, Cairo: 700 enbie metres per day.
                        Brasserie des Pyramides, Cairo: 1000 enbie metree per day. Shakir Bay el
                        Khoury, Talbinh: 4000 enbid metres per day.</p>
                    <p>4. Leben, Icemanufacturing plant, Alexandria: 700 onbio metres per day,
                        ete.</p>
                    <p>Trisco</p>
                    <p>Malta</p>
                    <p>Brindis</p>
                    <p>Athena</p>
                    <p>Lammol</p>
                    <p>STATIONS</p>
                    <p>20</p>
                    <p>Khartoum Wad Modani</p>
                    <p>35</p>
                    <p>Fahrenheit in the shade. On the other hand, forty-nine below zero, or
                        eighty-one degrees of frost, is the lowest aqtually recorded in Man- churis.
                        Generally speaking, in the south the average winter minimum is not much
                        below zero Fahrenheit. But what the armies have chiefly to fear is the north
                        wind, which is the terror of Manchi When it blows no cover ing of furs is
                        sufficient to keep out the piercing cold, and life in the open will be
                        almost un- bearable, especially, for men doomed to outpost Barum Wind Temp.
                        and sentry work at night. Fortunately, this</p>
                    <p>FOREIGN STATIONS.</p>
                    <p>7063 calm 10.4 Calm 709 Very 130 Light 285,0 Light 6.8 704.3 Moder 261.7
                        Almost</p>
                    <p>Rough</p>
                    <p>THE SUN.</p>
                    <p>awful wind rarely lasts three days; and in its absence the winter sun shines
                        so Slight brightly that the dry cold is not felt. Stight When once the
                        country becomes ice-bound and Rather the rivers and streams are frozen over,
                        the 18.0 sight tactics and even the strategy of the opposing armies will be
                        greatly affected. The side adopting the defensive will find that the rivers
                        have completely disappeared as a calculable A factor, and can no longer be
                        reckoned upon as useful tactical obstacles to the passage of an assailant.
                        The lines, therefore, of the Tai-tse, the Sha bo, and the Hun will shortly
                        disappear from the nomenclature of the campaign as the THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE
                        special localities of great struggles. It is a</p>
                    <p>PHASES OF THE MOON. Nov. 1 Last Quarter 1.13. New</p>
                    <p>Lest quarter.</p>
                    <p>p.m.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS-Alexandria, Catro, and the Interior of Egypt (including
                        delivery in Alex andria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T 181 per
                        sanam. PT. 118 for six months. P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries
                        In the Postal Union P.T. 973 (43.166) per</p>
                    <p>andum.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS. P.T. 4 per line. Minimum sharge P.T. 90. Births, Marriages,
                        or Deathe, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 90, every addi Wonal Hiné P.T.
                        10. Noslees in new solone P.T. 90 par line. Contracts entered into for
                        standing advertimento.</p>
                    <p>N.B-Babartpalona commence from the 1st o 10th of any month.- SUBSCRIPTIONS
                        and ADVERTISEMENTS AN</p>
                    <p>complete transformation of the conditions of warfare, which will bestow a
                        unique interest upon this campaign, already so fruitful in sur Another thing
                        we may look for is.a great increase in mobility. As soon as the prises.
                        country roads and tracks have been worn down they acquire the smoothness
                        almost of an asphalt roadway in Alexandria. With the new possibility of
                        moving in all directions without let or hindrance, the scope of the cavalry
                        arm will be greatly enlarged. Accordingly, until April and May next we may
                        be on the lookout for many new features in the winter struggle between the
                        rival armies.</p>
                    <p>CRETE AND GREECE</p>
                    <p>struggle</p>
                    <p>A telegram from London this morning an</p>
                    <p>dos in advanes, P. O. Orders and Chieqnannounces that Prince George has made
                        another be made payable to the Editor and Manager Rowland Snelling,
                        Alemandrin</p>
                    <p>London Offo : 88, New Broad-er, B.O.</p>
                    <p>attempt to force the hands of the Powers in regard to Crete. No one
                        acquainted with Cretan politics can doubt that the union to Greece is bound
                        to come sooner or later; but the moment of its consummation must depend on
                        the goodwill of the four Powers. Turkey</p>
                    <p>THEOFPTIAN GARNTTIS PRINTED OF PAPER would hardly do more than formally
                        protest,</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY FR</p>
                    <p>for she has practically lost all hold over the island, which has no Turkish
                        garrison, such as</p>
                    <p>24,487-19-1-906 0DON PAPER MILLS C., LIMITED/BALES OFFICE the soldiers who
                        represent the Ottoman Suze</p>
                    <p>PAYMENT 10 and 11 MONTH WHERE TO WINTER ALDERSON'S GARDEN, BULKELEY.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN DEPOTI</p>
                    <p>C. LOUKAITIS &amp; Co. GOVERNMENT PURVEYORS Harage Bolae Street, Cara</p>
                    <p>NOTE PAPER STAMPED</p>
                    <p>ADORESS &amp;</p>
                    <p>J MARGOSCHES</p>
                    <p>BRASS PLATE ENGRAVER GENERAL SIGN WRITER S LETER MANUFACTURER: CAIRO</p>
                    <p>44</p>
                    <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round.</p>
                    <p>for bins should be addressed ELECTRIC LIGHT.-LIFT.-BODENATE CHANGES risal
                        Manakh.</p>
                    <p>IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>TEWFIK PALACE</p>
                    <p>Telephone</p>
                    <p>No &amp; Helona</p>
                    <p>HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Tel. Address: HELOUAN</p>
                    <p>HELOUAN,</p>
                    <p>SPECIAL FEATURES."</p>
                    <p>ARST-AND HEALTHIEST SITUATION IN RELOUAN PERFT SANITARY ARRANGEMENTS.
                        SEPARATE BALCONIES AND BATHROOMS TO MOST</p>
                    <p>OF THE BEDROOMS</p>
                    <p>MAGNIFICENT PRIVATE GARDENS, WARMED THEgitor BY A APRO AL SYSTEM BADIATOR</p>
                    <p>Some Optofone of the Press.</p>
                    <p>The Tits Palace Hol about known</p>
                    <p>Muree ades Hotal in stined to the north</p>
                    <p>the town</p>
                    <p>Omral Moj</p>
                    <p>&amp; AQUILERA Dale of Two Coes &amp;</p>
                    <p>Prid, Nober 15, at p</p>
                    <p>GRAND VARIETY ENTERTAINMENT</p>
                    <p>By Two</p>
                    <p>ROYAL TOOKEY FAMILY. CHEVALIER J. ophusa</p>
                    <p>Magician</p>
                    <p>Concluding with the Cole Sketch THE BRIGANDS</p>
                    <p>Bettiah Garrison with their families and offers of antile marins in barber
                        and permite are fo</p>
                    <p>CANNON STREET, &amp;</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>An English Daily Newspaper, Betabilahed in 188 disce &amp; Manager: B. Bas.
                        Petoe One Plastre Tarttt.</p>
                    <p>rainty over Samos. It is thought that France and Russia would not be
                        favourable to union in the near future; the relations between-Italy and
                        Greece are not particularly good, the Italians and the Greeks are rivals in
                        Epirus, and the compulsory recall of the Italian Minister from Athens last
                        spring did not improve the feelings of the two races: Great Britain has no
                        special interest, in hindering, or in hastening, the union, except that,
                        when once the Greeks have Crete, they will demand-Cyprus, which is always
                        regarded by them as an Hellenic island. The most formidable argument in
                        favour of the unión is that no one desires a fresh disturbance in Crete this
                        winter, which would certainly A dead calm appears to prevail for the time
                        call for the intervention of the 'Powers being in Manchuria, and a telegram
                        from Few will be so singuine as to pretend Mukden to-day states that owing
                        to the strength that the Cretans will find amalgama of the respective
                        positions, neither army ap- tion with the Greek Kingdom a complete</p>
                    <p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER, 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>THE CAMPAIGN..</p>
                    <p>Victoria pars inclined to attack, unless possessing such succeys, nor will
                        the Athenian politicians have</p>
                    <p>Magasins Victoria</p>
                    <p>WOOLESTONE AND EBILL.</p>
                    <p>a preponderance in numbers that they are able an easy task in governing the
                        warlike popul to make a flanking movement. It will be useful tion of the
                        island. Besides, certain Balkan during the present lull in the campaign to
                        study States will almost certainly put forward claims the climatic
                        conditions which must exercise a for compensation, as Greece herself did
                        when ENGLISH DRAPERY. In Manchuria the climate oscillates between two garia
                        in 1883. Meanwhile, wa cannot shut our. very large influence upon the course
                        of the war. Hastern Roumelia was united to North Bul extremes. In winter the
                        cold experienced is eyes to the fact that the Cretan question like a burning
                        copper diso, and the thermo- time when Europa bae many preoccupations very
                        severe, while in summer the sun shines has been once more reopened, and that
                        at meter rises to dearly one hundred degrees elsewhere.</p>
                    <p>Opposite Austrian Consulate, near the Batala Theatre. Onilogues on
                        application.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS. LOCAL AND GENERAL</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>WAR.</p>
                    <p>A STALEMATE.</p>
                    <p>MUKDEN, November 22. Owing to the strength of the respective positions,
                        neither army appears inclined to attack unless possessing such a
                        preponderance in numbers that they are able to make a flank ing movement.
                        The Japanese probably have the most available troops. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>THE GREEK Aseize COURT at Alexandria will begin its sittings on the 13th
                        December</p>
                    <p>THE BRINDISI MAIL will be distributed at the GPO, Alexandria, to-morrow
                        morning st 8 o'clock.</p>
                    <p>MARIOUT RAILWAY.-The Dairs Khasss has bought a large quantity of old material
                        from the Railway Administration for use on the Mariout line.</p>
                    <p>ter reunions of this society will commence on REUNION DES FAMILLES. The
                        series of win- Saturday, 17th December, with a ball and Xmas Tree.
                        Subsequent balls will be given on January 21, February 25, and April 1
                        respect ively, the last closing the season.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1004</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY. THE EVENING EXPRESS. In response to petition presented by
                        the inhabitants of Ram leh to the State Railway Administration, the latter
                        have arranged to stop the evening ex- press train from Cairo at Sidi Gaber,
                        com-</p>
                    <p>RESPONSIBLE OFFICER ARRIVES.encing from the 19th inst.</p>
                    <p>THE FRERES CASE-The appeal of M. Yayon against the judgment of the French
                        Consular ST. PETERSBURG, November 22. Tribunal at Cairo, which condemned him
                        to a It is stated that, at the request of Great month's imprisonment for
                        defaming the Con- Britain and Russia, the Emperor of Austria gregation of
                        the Frères, will be heard by the Aix will nominate the fifth member of the
                        Com-Court of Appeal on January 26: mission of Inquiry. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 22. It is stated here that, at the request, of Great Britain,
                        the Russian officer, of the transport Kamchatka, who first gave the order to
                        open fire on the trawlers, has been landed at Dakar. He will appear before
                        the Commis sion of Inquiry.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>GENERAL NEWS.</p>
                    <p>A RUSSIAN RUSE. DESTROYER BOUGHT IN ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22.</p>
                    <p>BLIND SCHOOLS-A "bazaar in aid of the blind schools at Alexandria and Tantah
                        will be held at the residence of Mrs. Coventry (which has been kindly lent
                        for the purpose), Mansourah, on Friday next, at 2 p.m. The sale is under the
                        patronage of Mrs. B. Dale.</p>
                    <p>THE BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS FOR PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>CANEA, November 22. A division of the Baltic Fleet has left for Port Said. It
                        consists of two battleships, three cruisers, six destroyers, and nine
                        transports. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>As we go to press, we learn that the Baltic morrow morning. Squadron is
                        expected to arrive at Port Said to</p>
                    <p>Russian Squadron is composed :- The following are the vessels of which
                        the</p>
                    <p>Battleships: Sissoi Veliki and Navarin Cruisers: Almas and Seietlana.
                        Besuprechy, Buistry, Byjedoci, Braci, Bodri, Torpedo boat destroyers:
                        Blestyaschtchy, and Buini</p>
                    <p>Volunteer Fleet steamers: Voronej, Tamboe, Vladimir, Kief, and Jarosla
                        Transports: Gortchakof, Juppiter, Kitai,</p>
                    <p>and Meteor</p>
                    <p>JAPS AND THE RED SEA. A nautical correspondent writes: in the Red Sea on the
                        look-out for the Russian If the Japanese are lurking about somewhere fleet,
                        the most likely spot for them to be lying Daedalus lighthouse, to the
                        north-east of in waiting is in the neighbourhood of the Berenice. The reefs
                        run out there in every direction and yet one cannot touch bottom in 300
                        fathoms with deep sea lead. The Japanese could place two torpedo-boats
                        there, one on the east and one on the west of the channel, and they could
                        knock the Russians into a cocked hat at this point.</p>
                    <p>THE HOUSING PROBLEM.</p>
                    <p>MR. ALDERSON'S SCHEME</p>
                    <p>The following is the text of a proposal which is to be placed before the
                        Alexandria Muni- cipal Commission by Mr. G.-B. Alderson on question in the
                        city: Wednesday next, in regard to the housing</p>
                    <p>"In answer to the locataires plea re more accommodation for artisans and
                        employés, I beg to submit the following suggestions:</p>
                    <p>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK</p>
                    <p>YESTERDAY'S MESTING.</p>
                    <p>the twelve months' working.</p>
                    <p>ARMY AND NAVY. (FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT</p>
                    <p>London, Novem</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENT.) Major R. G. Tallet D.S.O., ho tion joins
                        the 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade in London, November 22. Egypt, has worn the
                        "green jacket for Egyptian Bank (Limited) was held this after well as the
                        medal with five clasps in Bulle The annual general meeting of the Anglo-
                        sixteen years and earned his decoration and the dividend of 15% declared
                        which, includ- Talbot, who is a member of the ancient military noon. The
                        report and balance sheet were passed, fighting for the relief of Ladywith.
                        Mo ing the dividend of 10% for the first six and naval family of which the
                        Bal of Shrews- On the table you will find complete plans, months, made a
                        dividend of 13 per cent on bury is the head, at the with all details, for a
                        block of 110, to cost, Colenso, Vaal Kats, Montecristo, say, under L.E.
                        20,000. The Chairman, in the course of his speech, Hill, Langs Nek, etc.,
                        etc.. "Also plan of the city, showing the lands at gave some details as to
                        the issue of the 20,000 present not used and belonging to the Govern-new
                        shares. The shareholders took up the quota Major G. C. L. Stockwell, D.3.0.,
                        Highland ment and the city. to which they were entitled to the extent of
                        Light Infantry, has been appointed second-in- "Will the Municipality request
                        the Govern-Stock Exchange at £12 each nett to the bank, moyed from Egypt to
                        Bengal, 18,000; the remaining 2,000 were sold on the command of the 1st
                        Battalion, which lately ment to cede plot marked A, or rather, say, or £2
                        premium on the issue price, giving the 30,000 sq. m., on the following
                        conditions: "1. This block to be built according to plans deducted £1,000,
                        the cost of issue (mostly the province of Bahrel Ghaal, who commands bank a
                        profit of £4,000. From this must be Major W. A. Boninois, RA, Governor of
                        presented, possibly in about a year. 2. Apartments to be let at rents not to
                        £3,000. This £3,000 is to be devoted to paying of cannibalistic propensities
                        known as Government stamps), leaving a nett profit of the expedition
                        destined to punish those gentary exceed 10% on actual cost to workmen ap the
                        staff a bonus of 10 per cent. on their "Nism Niams" in the Upper Nile
                        regions, is a proved, and who will be selected or balloted salaries for the
                        past year. This decision met very smart offer who has won a fine reputa with
                        the hearty approval of those presant. tion during his six years' connection
                        with the the capital of the bank was one million and in the Nile Expedition
                        of 1899, including the The Chairman then went on to state that Khedive's
                        Army. He served with distinction half, of which half a million is paid up.
                        The final rout of the Khalifa's forces (mentioned in reserve fund is also
                        half a million, equal to the despatches) and would have chastised the of the
                        Board in dealing with the profit. The cient forces at his disposal. paid-up
                        capital. He then sketched the policy Niam-Niams early this year had he had
                        suffi first charge on the profit will be £62,500,, or 12 per cent. dividend
                        on the capital of to staff provident fund £1,500; the third Sir C. J. Graves
                        Sawla, Bart, M.V.0.) took half a million; the second charge, subscription
                        that the first-class cruiser Aboukir (Captain charge, the very large amount
                        of £30,000 to first place in the recent long-range firing, par establish a
                        pension fund for the benefit of the ticulars of which were given some time
                        ago in staff. This is undoubtedly a very large sum, these notes. The
                        battleship Montagu (Captain equal, as it is, to 6 per cent, on the capital
                        of T. B. 8. Adair) was a good second. Indeed, alf the bank. The £30,000 will
                        become the property the cruisers and battleships shot well. of the staff,
                        and the scheme for its appropria For a considerable time shorter
                        commisions</p>
                    <p>for, of all nationalities.</p>
                    <p>"3. Capital to bear 6% interest, and no more, balance for a sinking fund,
                        repairs, and</p>
                    <p>administration.</p>
                    <p>"4. These houses to be free of all taxes such as water, light, and 2%
                        tenant's tax.</p>
                    <p>15. Water to be supplied by Municipality free. dividend of 3% on the capital.
                        "6. Municipality to guarantee a minimum the necessary capital, build, and
                        when finished "On these terms I will undertake to obtain hand over to the
                        Municipal Council to admi- nistrats</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>News from the Mediterranean Fleet states</p>
                    <p>The Suez correspondent of the Daily Er for the first block, till finished and
                        handed over tion to individuals will be carefully drawn up abroad have been
                        strongly urged on in these</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN POSTAL ADMINISTRATION-It has been announced by some of our
                        contemporaries that Douglas Morice Bey has been appointed director of the
                        Port Said Post Office in succes-press wires to that paper on the 15th inst.
                        as sion to Mr. Mancantelli: The appointment has follows: not yet been filled
                        up, but it is vacant, as Mr. Mancantelli has been transferred to Alexandria.
                        vessels have arrived here with the intention of It is reported that
                        disguised Japanese war blowing up that portion of the Baltic fleet which
                        will go through the canal. The Russian admiral has cabled to the consulate
                        here to arrange about supplies. Four steamers of the Volunteer fleet which
                        are said to be flying the commercial flag are expected hourly at Port Said.
                        Their names are unknown.</p>
                    <p>INSURANCE. The "Fidelitas" Assurance Company of Brussels has authorised
                        Messrs. Alf. G. Buhagiar &amp; Co., of Alexandria, to repre- sent it
                        throughout Egypt. This company is one The Standard says that Messrs. Yarrow
                        of the leading assurance companies in Belgium, reported to the Admiralty
                        last September that and insures against maritime, fluvial, and fire a
                        destroyer had been bought from them by a risks. gentleman in Paris, who
                        wished to have it altered for yachting purposes. The Admiralty DAIRA SANISH
                        BONDS- The Committee of communicated with the Foreign Office, who the London
                        Sotek Exchange has allowed the made inquiries in Paris. Their suspicions
                        being following security to be quoted in the official aroused, they sent
                        Messrs. Yarrow instructions list: Egyptian Government, £1,264,820 Dairs to
                        retain the boat. It was, however, too late to Sanieh Bonds, 1890 "stamped
                        for exchange," It eventually reached Libeu, and joined the Baltic Fleet</p>
                    <p>do this, as the destroyer had left the Thames in lien of the same amount of
                        bonds unstamped</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>MACEDORIA EFFECT OF REFORM SCHEME</p>
                    <p>VIENNA, November 22. According to an official statement issued here, the
                        Austro-Russian reform scheme has greatly improved the general condition of
                        Macedonia. The population itself desires pence. (Router)</p>
                    <p>CRETE. CERTAINTY OF DISORDERS.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22, Cin a memorandum by Prince George, handed to the Powers,
                        he emphasizes the certainty of disorders in Crete, if the people's
                        aspirations for the union to Greece are again, rejected.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>GREAT GALE IN NORTH SEA PORTUGUESE ROYALTIES SNOWED UP.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22.</p>
                    <p>A great gale is raging in the North Sea There are several wrecks with loss of
                        life Blinding snowstorms are taking place in the North and Midlands of
                        England. The tele graphs are broken, and the trains delayed. The King and
                        Queen of Portugal were mowed mp at Chatsworth, where they are the guests of
                        the Duke of Devonshire.</p>
                    <p>FRENCH CHAMBER</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 22. The Chamber of Deputies has rejected the suppression of
                        secret funds. M. Combes had put the question of con</p>
                    <p>fidence</p>
                    <p>STRIKE AT LORIENT.</p>
                    <p>(Havas.)</p>
                    <p>LORIENT, November 29. The workmen at the powder factories have declared a
                        general strike, and the workmen at Brest areal are joining with them
                        (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>'AU DE ROUGE.'</p>
                    <p>now quoted.</p>
                    <p>THE AMERICAN ANNUAL NATIONAL THANKS- GIVING will be observed to-morrow
                        (Thursday). In recognition of this anniversary, &amp; service will be held
                        at 11 o'clock to-morrow in the American Mission Church, Cairo, near Shep-
                        heard's Hotel: Residents and visitors are cordially invited to participate
                        in this service.</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>SURZ CANAL-On the 19th and 20th inst. 33 vessels passed through the Suez
                        Canal. Of these, 24 were British, 2 French, 4 German, Dutch, 1 Austrian, and
                        I Portuguese. The transit and passenger dues for the two days amounted to
                        884,032.02 fra. The total transit and passenger dues collected from the 1st
                        to that date on 298 vessels amounted to 6,612,139.09 frs.</p>
                    <p>THE KHEDIVE.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is spending to day at Mariout, where he is inspecting his
                        estates. His Highness will return to Montazah in the evening.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN STATE DOMAIN.</p>
                    <p>Masar, M. M. Rothschild and fortune that Egyptian State Domain Mortgage bonds
                        to the amount of £20,220 nominal capital have been drawn for payment at par
                        on December 1. The drawing consists of all bonds (not pre- viously cancelled
                        by the operation of the sinking fand) comprised in the series of numbers
                        advert ised.</p>
                    <p>ELEMENTARY EDUCATION.</p>
                    <p>About a thousand children of the employés of the Egyptian Railway
                        Administration are without any means of obtaining any education whatsoever.
                        The Board has now decided in principle to pay a few fikis, who will begin
                        the work of instructing the progeny of platelayers</p>
                    <p>and others.</p>
                    <p>YACHTING</p>
                    <p>The British turbine yacht Emerald sailed from Alexandria harbour yesterday,
                        bound North The steam yacht Catarina is now at Port Said, and leaves for
                        Suez in a day or two</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner Moeris arrived at Liverpool 11 on Monday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>General Drapery Establishment. (Central Tramway station), CAIRO. P.
                        PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail 8.8. Dakaklich will leave Alexandria on Saturday and Port
                        Said on Sunday for Beyrout, Tripoli, Mersin, Alexandretta, Larnaca,
                        Limassol, Caiffs, and Jaffa.</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CRUISER AT SUEZ Suez, Tuesday-As wired to-day, H.M.'s second-class
                        cruiser. For arrived at Suez this morning from the East Indies.</p>
                    <p>She will change her crew with that brought</p>
                    <p>"I have visited the various quarters of the city and the artizans' dwellings,
                        and find it is a real want to avoid disease and discontent. "P.S. The
                        expenses of finding the capital to Council, will be my affair. "Shares will
                        be disposed of, say, £1 to £25 to hold to industrious artizans and £500 the
                        limit one</p>
                    <p>sure investment for the artizans.- "It is fay desire to create a profitable
                        and GEO. B. ALDERSON." IRRIGATION DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <p>The chairman then dealt with the general</p>
                    <p>affairs.</p>
                    <p>NUNGOVICH HOTELS CO.</p>
                    <p>outlines of the pension fund. The meeting notes, both in the interests of the
                        health of the ended without any incident, the shareholders officers and men
                        and the efficiency of our present expressing their general satisfaction
                        squadrons. The Admiralty has just announced with the prosperous position of
                        the bank's that in the future his Majesty's ships will be commissioned for
                        periods of two years instead of three. This will be a great boon to all
                        ranks, Another important point is that re- In regard. to the various rumours
                        as to the pairs will not be allowed to accumulate, Nungovich Hotels Co., we
                        understand that as we often the case under the three-years Mr. K. George
                        Veitch Murray is appointed Nungovich Bay has not resigned, but that rule.
                        The first ship to be commissioned under surveyor of contracts of the 3rd
                        class and is Sir Elwin Palmer, Sir John Rogers and Mr. the new conditions is
                        the first-class craiser attached to the service of the Assiout Barrage.
                        Cattaoui have sent in their resignations, as mouth on the 19th inst. for
                        service on the Mr. G. Parker is appointed surveyor of Sutlej, which will be
                        commissioned at Porte- to the 2nd Circle, and Mr. F.B. Jacomb to the
                        contracts to the 3rd Circle, Mr. L. R. Wallace 4th Circle.</p>
                    <p>The salaries of each of these officials will amount to L.E. 240 per annum.
                        The Govern- should it seem fit, to the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>matter will be amicably settled. members of the Board of that Company. It is,
                        however, fully expected that the</p>
                    <p>China station.</p>
                    <p>out by the Hermione, and then return to her ment reserves the right of
                        transferring them, PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.oldiers; it is much to be feared that
                        the ne</p>
                    <p>station. It it probable that the Four will remain at Suez with the Hermione
                        pending the arrival of the Baltic Squadron.</p>
                    <p>PUNITIVE EXPEDITION IN SUDAN. The War Office issued the following state- ment
                        to the Press yesterday:</p>
                    <p>On the 10th ult. a patrol left El Obeid for Rahad, under the command of
                        Miralai O'Con- sell Bey, to proceed against Abou Zeida of Kitra, who had
                        expelled the Mek appointed by the Moudir of Kordofan last April and usurped
                        his authority.</p>
                    <p>P. W. D. CONTRACTS.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has given out the contracts for the winter
                        cleansing works in</p>
                    <p>the canals as follows:-</p>
                    <p>Assiout-Mr. Sturgess Galioabieh.-1 and II. groups, Khalil Chahin. Chaker; 3.
                        Moh. Ali Wanis. Dakahlieh.-Group 1., Messrs. Bellini; 2. S.</p>
                    <p>Baldi; 3. Luca Lanitiche; 4. D. Cangos; 5. Charkieh.-1. Nasu Ghoraieb; 2. Mr.
                        F W. Cossena; 6. C. Cangos; 7. Youssef Gho- raieb; 8. Ibr. Khalil Chahim; 9.
                        Khalil Khoury.</p>
                    <p>Markas Abnoub-C. Passaris.</p>
                    <p>Assiout and Manfalout-Kamel Roufail. Minieh (West of the Nile).-MM. Th. Yanni
                        and B. Hanna; Minich (East of the Nile), J. Chasseand; Samalout, W.
                        Papadopoulo; Beni Mazar, W. Taylor; Fashn, D. A. Andenis. Beni Sonef-Beba,
                        MM. Liotto and Wour lich; Beni Souef and Wasta, Mr. E. Bramall. Fayoum, Moh.
                        Afifi.</p>
                    <p>While I am in hearty sympathy with the. appeal of the National Association
                        for the employment of Reservists and time-expired sponse will prove
                        disappointing. With all Colonel Younghusband, of Lhasss fame, labour are
                        compelled, by commercial stagna the good will in the world, most employers
                        of and his wife were passengers by the P. &amp; 0. tion, to reduce rather
                        than increase the 'nam- They disembarked at Suez early on Monday that they
                        are less able than when business is SS. Mongolia, homeward bound from
                        Bombay-ber of people in their service, with the result morning. brisk to
                        comply with such appeals But it is Lady Low also landed at Sues from the
                        Empire's gallant defenders, whether sailors an utterly vicious system which
                        makes the</p>
                    <p>same steamer.</p>
                    <p>or soldiers, dependent on such chances of subsistence after they retire.
                        Yesterday I Ronald Lechmere are among the passengers Time-Expired Tommy,"
                        illustrating from Sir Edmund and Lady Lechmere and Mr. came across a
                        striking letter from a by the P. and O. steamer Persia, which is due his own
                        experiences the ingratitude of the at Port Said on Tuesday next, Sir Edunnd
                        is State to his class. Of blameless character, The force arrived at Gebel
                        Daier on October 12, when Abou Zeida was ordered to come in proceeding to
                        East Africa on another big game and in possession of two war medals with six
                        by the 13th. He refused, and on the 14th the shooting expedition. clasps, he
                        served for a little over thirteen axpedition advanced, capturing the village
                        and years before passing back into civil life. With. some hills. Meantime,
                        the Meks of Feria and in Egypt in a few days' time by the steam to count on
                        receiving one of the many thou- An interesting party of tourists are
                        arriving such an excellent record, he had every right Kemla joined Abou
                        Zeids and desultory firing continued till the 18th, when the Camel Corps
                        yache Vectis, belonging to the P. and O. Steam-sands of berths which are in
                        the gift of the ship Company She has on board many well- State and artillery
                        captured the two villages. In the known passengers, including Sir William J.
                        both at the Army Clothing Stores and the But although he registered his name
                        afternoon of the same day, the Meks of Farla Dupree,, mayor of Portsmouth;
                        Mr. John Royal Laboratory nearly three years ago, he and Kimla came in and
                        received the "Amam." After the last skirmish Abou Zeida, with a Gordon, M.
                        P. for Elgin; Mr. B. Dosse, is apparently as far as ever from attaining his
                        few followers, took to the hills, but on October formerly courier to the
                        late Queen Victoria; desire. We are aware, of course, that something The
                        second performance of Thomas's Mignon, Mr. J. Lockwood Kipling, father of
                        the wall has been done during recent years, especially 21 he surrendered and
                        received the "Amam." No further trouble is expected in this part last
                        evening, proved again a very great success, known author, and also an author
                        himself, by the Post Office. But if recruiting for the of the country. The
                        following was the composi-signa. Baldini and Signor Tomisani being having
                        written a charming book on animals, Army is to be extended to classes which
                        now tion of the expeditionary force - frantically applauded throughout the
                        evening. Sir James Pelle, K.C.S.I.; Mr. H. W. Uloth, refuse to enlist, as
                        Mr. Arnold-Forster hopes, Artillery officers, 34 N.C.O.'s and men, Signa.
                        Baldini's interpretation of the title role director of the Peninsular and
                        Oriental Com the well-conducted soldier must be secured Was one deserving of
                        the highest commends pany, accompanied by his wife; Mr. Tristram reasonably
                        comfortable maintenance after he 3 guns. Camel Corps-6 officers, 200
                        N.C.O.'s and tion, and the many present who were moved Ellis, Mr. C. Martin,
                        Sir Acquin Martin, Mr. even to tears by her pathetic impersonation of G. J.
                        Ingram, with his daughter; Mr. R. E. 12th Sudanese-7 officers, 126 N.C.O.'s
                        and Mignon, is proof of the excellence of this very Craig, Jr., Mr. and Mrs.
                        Fletcher, and Mr. B. accomplished lady's performance. As Gugliel W. Knox,
                        with his wife and daughter mo, Signor Tomisani, who possesses a voice of</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                    <p>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE</p>
                    <p>good timbre and delightful freshness, was A marriage has been arranged, and
                        will take SOLAR MOTORS FOR EGYPT. eminently successful, and his delicate
                        handling place at the end of December, between Adrian, Egypt is shortly to
                        have what are called of the several charming romances falling only son of
                        the late Sir Adrian Dingli, G.C.M.G., "solar motors." The heat of the sun,
                        so long to his lot, brought him enthusiastic applause. C.B., Chief Justice
                        of Malta, and Lady Dingli, neglected as a practical factor in producing
                        Indeed, it is difficult to understand why this of 3, Strada Forui, Valetta,
                        and grandson of power as applied to industries, is being taken theatre is
                        not crowded to overflowing every William Henry Charlton, of Hesleyside,
                        North up seriously, and another generation (or our evening, when two such
                        artistes as those above umberland, and Geraldine, youngest daughter own)
                        will see the land dotted over with devices mentioned are included in the
                        caste of the late H.F. Curwen, of Workington Hall, of one kind or another
                        for gathering and con- This evening, Rossini's opera Il Barbiere-di
                        Cumberland, and Mrs. Curwen, of The Island, centrating the heat and power,
                        arriving at the Siviglia will be given, with the tenor Tomisani Windermere,
                        and 14, Manson place, Queen's earth from the sun, and heretofore absolutely
                        in the caste. To-morrow evening, a benefit Gate. wasted, so far as human
                        utility is concerned. performance of the ever popular deda will be One
                        development of the practical use of solar given for a very deserving object,
                        vis, the heat is the solar motor. This is so designed international Employés
                        Society of Alexandria. to automatically face the sun at all times of The
                        performance is placed under the patronage the day, and by the use of a steam
                        boiler in its of M. Pierre Girard, French Consul, and the focus, produces
                        steam at a high pressure, and two celebrated prime donne, Signe. Popovici
                        and Fabbri, will take part. in great quantity, for any use</p>
                    <p>One of these devious is to day in actual practical use in Arizona, at
                        Willoox, and is pumping all the water needed for irrigating very large farm
                        in that arid,country.</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>Others, according to a correspondent of the New York Herald (Paris), are
                        being sent to Egypt and South Africa</p>
                    <p>ALHAMBRA THEATRE</p>
                    <p>Un Ballo in Maschera was successfully given yesterday evening. Tonight,
                        Rigoletto, will be given, with the tenor Apostolou.</p>
                    <p>To-morrow Cavalleria Rusticana and I Pa gliacci will be staged, and on Friday
                        Verdi's</p>
                    <p>The native Press announces the death of Mohamed Bay lakander, son of Soliman
                        Pasha El Franssoni (Colonel Seves), late Minister of War. The deceased was
                        60 years of age.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Gottheil, professor at Columbia Univer sity, has left the Carlton Hotel,
                        Balkaley, and is now staying at Shepheard's</p>
                    <p>R. M. S. 8. Ophir for New Zealand on the Mrs. A. G. Harris left by the
                        Orient-Pacific</p>
                    <p>17th inst</p>
                    <p>The great economic problem solved by the Simon Bocanegra will be produced for
                        the CARLTON HOTEL, utilisation of the sun's heat is, of course, the first
                        time in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer, pretical production of power to any degres</p>
                    <p>&amp;HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH RIVER-TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN
                        ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>Three Sailinge a Week. Agents at Alepandria ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO.,
                        LB. 18-11-900 $3.10.004</p>
                    <p>JUST ARRIVED LATEST DESIGNS IN LADIES 31916</p>
                    <p>BASES 0000S</p>
                    <p>without cost of fuel.</p>
                    <p>That this will be developed more and more GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</p>
                    <p>as the years go by, producing power where fual</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>ie absent or its price prohibitive, seems now an Be. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED..
                        unquestionable fact. 0800-16.7.000</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh Nowly</p>
                    <p>retires; and that would be effected to a verg large degree by giving our
                        fighting men, whether in the Navy or the Army, a preferen tial claim to
                        employment in the lower non- combatant grades of the Civil Service, the
                        Admiralty, and the War Office</p>
                    <p>of</p>
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. F. DAVIDSON, Ophthalmic Optician, 140, Great Portland Street, London,
                        Teacher of Sight Testing and author of "Sight Testing for the Medical
                        Practitioner," "Refraction Work," eto. May be conanlted for</p>
                    <p>SPECTACLES At the HOTEL ABBATE for a Short Time Only.</p>
                    <p>Mr. DAVIDSON in the inventor of many of the latent appliances for dealing
                        with and cordially invites all medical men to Defective Vision see them and
                        to test their</p>
                    <p>practical utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 12.30 and 9 to 6. Mr DAVIDSON'S Intel Invention (patented) is a
                        new SUN OLA88, which absolutely prevents any of the ill effects of Sun
                        Glare,</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n3/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EGYPTIAN MINING ACTIVITY.</p>
                    <p>the dething setivity in Bgyptian Mining the Director at the thadon and Paris.
                        Exchange have reteled services of a competent Mining Engineer, whose reports
                        on the present on of Se variens proportie la of the utmost importance. This
                        Information is at Correspodents contraplating investment in Egyptian Mining
                        nag with the Exchange before doing s Sciered by the purchase of worthless
                        searities</p>
                    <p>The Landon &amp; Parie</p>
                    <p>Drafts feas</p>
                    <p>dertake the purchase or onte 2 all classes of the Landon Stock Exchange and
                        Continental Bourses. KIELEN ANSTRIDAN, ANTWERP, NEW YORK &amp; MONTREAL</p>
                    <p>LONDON &amp; PARIS EXCHANGE.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL BANKERS</p>
                    <p>BALDON BOULL, MIL, LONDON GLID</p>
                    <p>Délégation Municipale</p>
                    <p>(Communication officielle)</p>
                    <p>Calendar of Loming Events</p>
                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s'est réunie le November.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA:</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904</p>
                    <p>been unloading on terms most advantageous to MOUVEMENT MARITIME</p>
                    <p>themselves.</p>
                    <p>For local requirements fair quantities of E bags have been taken for
                        Jan./April, and with the Crops that will have to be handled, there should be
                        a big consumption of both E bags and 2 lb B Twills for Bombay and the up-
                        country markets. Heavy C bags were also largely takes at Rs. 25-6, both by
                        speculators and Burmah skippers, right on to Jute next year, and with the
                        Straits and Far East operating later the tendency is to a higher level of
                        prices. THESSIANS are firmer and do not look like giving way in value. Rs,
                        12-4 is the nominal quotation for wheat bags, with no sellers, while Rs. 10
                        has been paid for 40 10 jo eloth for Jan./June, and Rs. 7-14 for 40 8 oz.
                        Jan./March and Rs. 7-12 April-June. These are the last rates at which
                        business has been done, and mills are reluctant to go on. This and next
                        month's goods are at a premium, more</p>
                    <p>740</p>
                    <p>22 novembre 1904 9 h. p.m. soms la Wid. 28 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Il Barbiere
                        présidence de M. Amb. A. Ralli.</p>
                    <p>Présents: MM. E. Benschi, P. Fenderl, Mohamed Bey Said, Mansour Bey
                        Youssef,</p>
                    <p>di Biviglia. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>Albambrs Theses, Rigoletto. 9.16 p.m. Plaos des Consts Mini's Mens gerin. 9
                        p.m</p>
                    <p>EB, Soliman Bey. Abani, membres; Thars. 74 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Aida; in aid
                        of W.P.Chatsway, administrateur; I. Sedky, secrétaire.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 25</p>
                    <p>La Délégation désigne dans son sein un sous-comité spécial pour étudier,
                        d'accord avec les services, une règlementation pour. les tramways de la
                        Ville d'Alexandrie, en s'inspirant du règlement édicté par le Gouvernement
                        pour les tramways de la Sal a Ville da Caire.</p>
                    <p>International Employée Society.@p.m. Alderson's Garden. Variety Enermin ment.
                        4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Zizinia Theatre. M. Silvain in Iphigénie. 9pm. Mon. 28 Zizinis Theatre. Debat
                        of Italian opera company in Tristan of Isault. p.m. December. Abbat Hotel.
                        A. L. M. &amp; D. B. Concert, p.m.</p>
                    <p>Un autre sous-comité est chargé d'exa miner les propositions faites par les
                        services techniques et sanitaires en vae d'une November.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>réglementation sur les constructions et de Wed, 28 Masonis Hall. Idris Lodge
                        No. 48</p>
                    <p>lui faire rapport à ce sujet.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation 6mt en ce qui la concern et sous certaines conditions, an- avis
                        favo rable à une demande tendant à l'établisse- ment d'un bain de mer à
                        Chatby, son acceptation étant subordonnée aux auto- ridations nécessaires à
                        délivrer par le Gouvernorat.</p>
                    <p>Une proposition de M. Kempner ten dant à établir un service de transport pa
                        sutomobiles, est renvoyée à l'examen da comité da Contentieux.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide de vélocigraphier et de distribuer aux membres une nou
                        velle lettre de la Commission de défens der toestaires ainsi qu'ane note de
                        M. Alderson précisant sa proposition pour la construction de maisons à bon
                        marché. L'administration est chargée de pré enter ane notesar cette
                        question.</p>
                    <p>Bat. 36 Ban. 27</p>
                    <p>9p.m.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Opera House. M. Silvain. 9 p.m. Theaire des Nouveautés. Variety
                        Enter. mainment 9.80 p.m. Trocadero, Variety Entertainment. 9.80 p.m.
                        Meeting of Ragheb Mark Lodge No. 510, at Masonic Hall, Bonlae-road. 9 p.m.
                        Zoological Gardens. Performance by Band of E. A. Infantry in afternoon.</p>
                    <p>VISITORS AND RESIDENTS</p>
                    <p>KINDLY NOTE THAT</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX,</p>
                    <p>THE CAIRO WEEKLY NEWSPAPER,</p>
                    <p>Communication est donnée d'ane lettre Is Under Entirely New Management</p>
                    <p>du Miaisèrs désignant M. Williams, ing- peatear da 8me Cercle d'Irrigation,
                        comm deuxiè ne délégué du Gouvernement auprè de la Commission chargée de
                        déciler quels sont les travaux que l'entreprise Alma zik</p>
                    <p>AND WILL BE PUBLISHED AS USUAL</p>
                    <p>During the Season 1904/5.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTION</p>
                    <p>sars à exécuter pead ant la période d'en For the Season P.T. 20</p>
                    <p>tretien des qusis</p>
                    <p>Is Délégation prend note d'ane lettre minjatérielle donnant la comp wition de
                        la Commission chargée dea reatinations à faire à le délimitation de la
                        ville</p>
                    <p>Elle serête l'ordre du jo ir de la pro- ehaide séance de la Commission
                        Maniei- palé qui et réunira mercredi 30 novembre à 9 h. du soir</p>
                    <p>La séance est levée à minuit et demie.</p>
                    <p>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demi 1</p>
                    <p>Le marché est trèr forme et en reprise. La Banque Nationale remonte à 24
                        3/16, la Béhára à 55 8/4; l'Agricole est deman dée à 10 18/16, la Delts
                        Light à 15 3/16, et la Balt &amp; Sods à 39/3.</p>
                    <p>PAYABLE IN ADVANCE.</p>
                    <p>All Communications and Subscriptions to be addressed to the Eorron,</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. P. GRAVES.</p>
                    <p>And for Advertising Space apply to</p>
                    <p>Mr. W. E. WALTON,</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX Offices,</p>
                    <p>Hotel du Nil, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p>22 novembre</p>
                    <p>Syria et Port-Sald: 1j. vap gree Yorghios, op</p>
                    <p>Vashiaki, too. 755, &amp; Maonis. 23 novembre</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>COPES DE LA DEVICES DE VALEXANDRIA NIBAL PRODUC</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL COTTON ASSOCIATION altare d'hise soir à 6h.</p>
                    <p>Geavors: 5). 86, vapaa, Anna Goigh, expitaine Acton In dem a Van,</p>
                    <p>Tomish, ton. 1448, &amp; Giuransevich.</p>
                    <p>Salonique et Pitée;j., 13, vop hall. Vassilises Og cap. manos, tom. 919,
                        Nanopoulo Alexandreite: 33, 86, vip. ang. Milo, o. Barnett, ton: 689, &amp;
                        Minotto. Smyrns;j. 1, ap. kell. Costas, cap. Boutis, Odense et Caval; 4 J.,
                        84, v. russe Pani Spoliansky, ton: 851, &amp; Maquis.</p>
                    <p>Mersine od Port-Sald: 15h, raj. ang. Dakabliah, cap. Seemano, sou. 1868,
                        &amp; Msonis. oap. Findlay, ton. 644, 4 la Khedivial Mail.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS</p>
                    <p>93 novembre</p>
                    <p>especially nine-porter cloth, and nothing can Por t-aid; vap. ital. Bosforo,
                        op. Milazzo.</p>
                    <p>be had now at Re: 8 for Nov./Dec. Eleven- Pur-Said of Chypre ; vap. sing.
                        Bene, &amp; MacMaher. porter cloth is more easily obtainable in Candie; vap
                        hell. Byzantion, dag, Mavromatie. moderate quantities at Rs. 10-4 and Ra. 10
                        Maite et Hambourg: v. all. Siegfried, cap. Möller. respectively.</p>
                    <p>Closing quotations are as follows:</p>
                    <p>Glf. Spes</p>
                    <p>21/6 Freight</p>
                    <p>ALL Part -Preight</p>
                    <p>Nov. Dec. Jatt Jane Nov/Dec Janu Grain Backs 50 by 30 lbs. $100 $1,04 314 d
                        dbys -70/5 705 5 by 9:30 hp 14/1 369 45/11 48/7.</p>
                    <p>Hagar Bags 68 by 287 by 9345 45 Onion Pockets 40 by 1) 179ro 6 by sebys 3.
                        Twills 64 by 36)</p>
                    <p>EXPORT MANIFESTS</p>
                    <p>STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>Cloring Prices, to-day at 1 pm.</p>
                    <p>40/10</p>
                    <p>shares 18 5,8 #24 8/18 F. 438</p>
                    <p>BANKS Imperial Oba National Bank</p>
                    <p>For MALTA and MANJEESTER, by the 8.8. Spartan Prinos, sailed on the 10th
                        November: Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 1,848 bales cotton J. Planis &amp;
                        Co.,</p>
                    <p>Debenture</p>
                    <p>Boure Khivists)</p>
                    <p>More Mel</p>
                    <p>$ 15 9/16 Livraison Janvier 15 28.82 15- 29/ Marsbé quiat</p>
                    <p>45 m.) (Conte praalqués se jour à la Bourse Khédiviale</p>
                    <p>5 15 11/82 Livraison Janvier $18 17/89</p>
                    <p>Msi</p>
                    <p>$ 15 23/32 Marché quiet Arrivage de oe jour, &amp; Minet-</p>
                    <p>(Oours pestiqués ce jour</p>
                    <p>19h.45 p.m.)</p>
                    <p>$15 15/39</p>
                    <p>$15 516 Laynison Janvier</p>
                    <p>$ 15 21/59</p>
                    <p>v</p>
                    <p>BENANGURS</p>
                    <p>Ons ouvert à l 15 15 52 poo</p>
                    <p>prix &amp; 15 17/89; tour</p>
                    <p>on a dobé de sonic</p>
                    <p>&amp; 15 1/3.</p>
                    <p>Bieche notolle: Promine Maires insigni</p>
                    <p>cours P.T. 61 pour reise mars. factes.</p>
                    <p>Prom-Saidi: Bisole nie main</p>
                    <p>le: Oa</p>
                    <p>316</p>
                    <p>CULTURES COTONNIERE3</p>
                    <p>SUPERFICIE PAR PROVINJE</p>
                    <p>ANNER 1904</p>
                    <p>Basse Bgypte</p>
                    <p>Cationbish Faddans 38,812</p>
                    <p>Chardich 39,798 Dat.</p>
                    <p>188,218</p>
                    <p>237-368</p>
                    <p>Goacbish..</p>
                    <p>858,587</p>
                    <p>Bourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>admoufich Bébé</p>
                    <p>116,528</p>
                    <p>951,908</p>
                    <p>Faddaon</p>
                    <p>Mam</p>
                    <p>Feddons 1,193,298</p>
                    <p>Mai</p>
                    <p>Houts</p>
                    <p>Marebe quiet</p>
                    <p>Quizsh,</p>
                    <p>Feddens</p>
                    <p>N</p>
                    <p>$3 novembre</p>
                    <p>Baai-Sonef Fayoumi...</p>
                    <p>85,4-8</p>
                    <p>76.902</p>
                    <p>85.990</p>
                    <p>Assion.</p>
                    <p>35,457</p>
                    <p>Guingueb..</p>
                    <p>184</p>
                    <p>Kiceb.....</p>
                    <p>1,098</p>
                    <p>A-BOOM...</p>
                    <p>148</p>
                    <p>Feddens</p>
                    <p>Marché de Minet-el-Bassal</p>
                    <p>Bank... 23 novembre 1904 (11h.58 m.). Sept... Cotone: Cohé an' Sovembre New
                        Inne 35 1116 Pen d'ren. Lunca tür, da National Bank of Gre qane sobesedno so
                        tirée malgré les dipot de sue</p>
                    <p>sions des désantades</p>
                    <p>prix.</p>
                    <p>on 36</p>
                    <p>Fair. Fally Fair, Good Fair, Fully Good Hair Good: Faile</p>
                    <p>HAUTH-BOYPT ET FAYOUT</p>
                    <p>Fair et Pally Pelf! Blo: Good Fair, Fully Good Pair of Good: Faile</p>
                    <p>ABARET</p>
                    <p>6 1/4 me quali 6, Ire qualité. : Facile</p>
                    <p>10 15116 Agrio. Bank</p>
                    <p>For. 1000</p>
                    <p>LAND, be Agris-Industrielle Egypt</p>
                    <p>865</p>
                    <p>G. Riecken,"</p>
                    <p>565</p>
                    <p>F. C. Bain &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>487</p>
                    <p>L.B. 55 34 Bebars Company- 4811,16 Brian Del Land Co. 818 Wardan Site Coy...
                        21 5/8</p>
                    <p>900. 99</p>
                    <p>H. Bindecangel,</p>
                    <p>1,428</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Oo.,</p>
                    <p>2,977</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Lad, 1,705</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>Fireh &amp; Co,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>Schmid &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>125</p>
                    <p>F. Andres,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>438 1/3 86</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>W. Getty &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Few. 280</p>
                    <p>75</p>
                    <p>9.820 balee cotton</p>
                    <p>133</p>
                    <p>do do</p>
                    <p>New Dains Bad Fond. COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL Alex. Bonded Storia Pref.
                        Anglo-gypt Spinning Co. Bourse Khediviale... prel. Chiro Bewage Trans- Sort
                        Ord. Or. Brewery, Alex., Fond. do 6% Debe.</p>
                    <p>199</p>
                    <p>81 178 500</p>
                    <p>do Chiro Food</p>
                    <p>TE</p>
                    <p>Sh. 99</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton Mil</p>
                    <p>b. #7,8</p>
                    <p>do Market...</p>
                    <p>Sh. 89,8</p>
                    <p>Fos. 108</p>
                    <p>do Salt and Boda Fond Ciments &amp; Egypts...</p>
                    <p>41716</p>
                    <p>6814</p>
                    <p>9 1/16</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 50 osies cranges Chalom Attal, 75 ms eggs L. Heller, 200
                        barrels molasses Various, 6 packages stadries</p>
                    <p>Pour MESSINE et GENES, par le batean italien Singapore, parti le 10
                        novembrer</p>
                    <p>POUR DESTINATIONS DIVERSES</p>
                    <p>H. Fitari, 18 anos fèves et petits pois (Tripoli) Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co,
                        50 balles coton (Naples) 8. Albertini, 82 oilindres vides (Livourne) Divers,
                        94 colls divers</p>
                    <p>POUR GENES</p>
                    <p>Kraft &amp; Naggiar, 5 sans gomme Padova Rolio, 25 colis viens enivre look
                        &amp; Son, 7 elin trophées</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Syadioste... B.</p>
                    <p>Kafe-al-Zayas Cotton Coy. 102 New Bgyptian Company... Nangoviah Hotels...
                        Bode Baileries ot</p>
                    <p>NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS,</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amer.. Nile de Co</p>
                    <p>ZANNOVICH</p>
                    <p>Ame qualité, Ire qualité, Extra: Foole</p>
                    <p>Bas da marebé de ge joaz. eos: Malgré les con- coesione doe vandears, les
                        affaires sons peu nom breases</p>
                    <p>Lée rivage de ce jour se chiffrent par man. 44852 contre mèrite joué l'ammed
                        35850</p>
                    <p>Graines de ceton Moti sotive</p>
                    <p>Disponite</p>
                    <p>Mit-And-Baisse 10/40</p>
                    <p>Hoate-Hypo-Bsisse 10/40</p>
                    <p>Blis-8stionnaires</p>
                    <p>Qualité Saidi: Cond. Saba P.T. 115 à 180</p>
                    <p>Bhira:</p>
                    <p>Pre-Saas marché</p>
                    <p>Sort-Blob S</p>
                    <p>Fayoums: disponible: Bien</p>
                    <p>114129</p>
                    <p>Qualité Saidi: Cond. Baba P.T. 8592 Lentilles-Invariable Disponible Bieb</p>
                    <p>Cond. Baba P.T. 88 93</p>
                    <p>Orges: Sade obangement</p>
                    <p>Cond. Hahn P.T. 50 &amp; 55</p>
                    <p>Cond, Baba P.T. 70 &amp; 78</p>
                    <p>INFORMATIONS</p>
                    <p>2439 Foddane 948,409</p>
                    <p>Feddeos 1,488,706 N.BOe table est composé d'ap de les chiffres donnée par le
                        Ministère des Fiddes</p>
                    <p>EXTERIEUR</p>
                    <p>Déplonos paciaire da 2 novembre 1904 PRODUITS MAYPTIANS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOS</p>
                    <p>Ventes da joas, balles 20</p>
                    <p>Deponible Bearts: me tenne Puture décembre: 7 Galde (6/64 de baisee) GAINES
                        DE CO.ON EGYPTIENNES Liverpool: Mondation</p>
                    <p>Londres: Formes</p>
                    <p>Hall: soutenues, demande modérée FAVES BUYPTIENNES Liverpool: Onlus, ipsis
                        suasmaes Loadres: Nalued outplète H.MYes, sobesedes consérés YUTUN AMERICAIN
                        LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Oa a veada caballos 7,000 euses Javier-vene 0.20 (4 paias de baines) a-jain.
                        5.37 (3 pointe de onsse Disponible 339) Arrive du jour, baltes 8,000-
                        WWW-YORK</p>
                    <p>Asadons prochain rapport Barest timers récoles Audesque 12 millions.</p>
                    <p>adding up. (10 points de bainsa ani Jaar. 9413 poate de baisse) Mai, 963
                        poate de bainee</p>
                    <p>Arrivage du jour : bades 10,000</p>
                    <p>Con mode jour l'adané écoutes: baile- 104,000 Journal de Oomuneros New-York
                        anguente estima malton récolte 800,000 bailes soit</p>
                    <p>Domaines de l'Est, demain jeudi, 94 gonzant, il 11,600,000, n'y aura pas
                        d'onthères de coton.</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>36-13 w28 1pd</p>
                    <p>Ind. de Karmons Presange et Dépôt Presses Libree</p>
                    <p>10 10%</p>
                    <p>Maia Mame allure</p>
                    <p>: Bien</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderi,</p>
                    <p>140 balles soton</p>
                    <p>#5 516 14</p>
                    <p>Khedival Mail 8.8. e.</p>
                    <p>B&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>94 #</p>
                    <p>[Oo. Fonds. 4/6</p>
                    <p>P. O. Bain &amp; Co,</p>
                    <p>146</p>
                    <p>484</p>
                    <p>64</p>
                    <p>17 118 Fr. 1145 499 1</p>
                    <p>Alex. Water Onizo</p>
                    <p>Company Fonda Fonds.</p>
                    <p>650</p>
                    <p>94</p>
                    <p>Carrer Beds &amp; Coy. Ltd,</p>
                    <p>241</p>
                    <p>Schmid &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>155</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>Pour LE PIBEE</p>
                    <p>J. Plant &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>G. Petracahi,</p>
                    <p>W. Tropp &amp; Co,</p>
                    <p>1,544 balles coton ODESSA, par le batean rasse Reine Olga parti le 11
                        novembre y Divers, 800 mes ris, 56 sacs henné, 15 saos fares, 18 sace
                        lentilles, 80 mos noix de coco, 11 dolls divers Mohr &amp; Fender,</p>
                    <p>F: 0. Baines &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>108 balles coton</p>
                    <p>80 "</p>
                    <p>G. Franger &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>880</p>
                    <p>B. Mallison &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>215</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>ohmid &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Carvee Brow &amp; Coy. Ltd,</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>1,071 balles coton</p>
                    <p>Pone MARSEILLE, par le batean français Congo, parti le LF novembre: VHA FOUR
                        MADRILLE</p>
                    <p>$4966-11 Bolio, 24 colie vieux enivre 844 dolls vient lailon 517 pains sind
                        Buerories, 20 store Candiegión, 19 are willes Divers, 40 olive Behrend, 600
                        de vi FC Baines &amp; Co, G. Franger &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>NEW YORK COTTON MARKET. Telegram received to-day from New York by Moms
                        Andres, Chawarby &amp; Co., of Alexandria. the large somhsen oefers to sell,
                        to the weaknes The fall is due to the disappointed hopes of Bulle, of
                        southern sharks, to a good deal of operation</p>
                    <p>Après Jure restés longtemps stationnaieston having seen thrown upon the
                        market and rés à 7 environ, les Cotton Mills viennent de monter subitement à
                        9/9 acheteurs. O a4changé ce matin 6 à 7,000 titres.</p>
                    <p>En husse également la Ward an à 8 1/8 acheteurs, les Markets à 27/3
                        acheteurs, les Esux d'Alexandrie à 17 1/8 et les Esax du Caire à 1125
                        achetears.</p>
                    <p>Par contre on fléchit légèrement sur 1s Crown Brewery do 232 à 230, sot
                        l'Anglo Ameriein Nile de 5-3/8 5 5/16 acheteurs et sur les Privilégiées
                        Tramwaya d'Alexan- dris de 147 1/2 146 1/2 acheteurs. Lea Dividendes sont
                        demandées à 386.</p>
                    <p>ADMINISTRATION DES POSTES.</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>L'Administration dos Poster met en sjufestion entreprise des transporte
                        potent dans la ville de Fort Baid,ans conditions stipndes dans le eshier des
                        aharges doped as de ostle Direction Gindrals (Parra da Sedarist) &amp; la
                        Direction Leals dea Postes de Port-id.</p>
                    <p>pressed for sale, and in consequenes of large selling ont of parohsses for
                        want of margins.</p>
                    <p>The heavy rossipts depress the market, The semens shows 9 more cotton giand
                        shan same time last year.</p>
                    <p>vis. 1 sottod gianed up to the" 14th Nove aber, 1938. Bales 7,070,deo More
                        69% 4,171,000 Total ginned up to the 14th. November, 1934 Balos
                        11,741,000</p>
                    <p>GUNNY BAG MARKET SCHRAGER BRO CALCUTTA MARKET REPORT FOR WEEK ENDING 10th
                        Novexa, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Monday and Tuesday were closed days and the Gunny market opened yesterday
                        very' strong, the firmness being due to the rather excited state of the
                        loose Jate market, both here and upcountry, and higher prices havo- been
                        paid by Home buyers and spinners for</p>
                    <p>Jute</p>
                    <p>BAILWAYS &amp; TRAMWAYS</p>
                    <p>Bare Egypte, Fonds..</p>
                    <p>415 8/16</p>
                    <p>Dela Digh..</p>
                    <p>do do Def....</p>
                    <p>99 19</p>
                    <p>195 108 17 89 97</p>
                    <p>20 814</p>
                    <p>P. 146 1/3</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>88 7/16 Ramlah Bailway</p>
                    <p>Oniro-Helonan...</p>
                    <p>Укусия... Kenab-Assonan.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Tras... do</p>
                    <p>Foods</p>
                    <p>DOMAINES DE L'ETAT (AORNOS D'ALEXANDRIS) Coton-Balles 48-oantars 170 prov.
                        Sikhs Graines de coton-Arlebe 188 prov. Bakhs</p>
                    <p>Les prix suivants ont té pratiqués ce jour</p>
                    <p>(BASSE BOYPTR)</p>
                    <p>abour.</p>
                    <p>par Canar Provines Bébér ...De P. 88717 &amp; 800 Proving Garbie</p>
                    <p>Parnished by Bia Back 10, 9. Marke da sole</p>
                    <p>Bail has Alverdi tal-Niair-Zayat... De P.T. 818- Cairo, who undersks the sale
                        and parabste of Tomb... ... docks and Shares, ad the lossl Board and Web
                        of</p>
                    <p>the London dook sebange.</p>
                    <p>Cloture de la Bourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS</p>
                    <p>Cours de l'Association des Courtiers en Marohani.</p>
                    <p>a.N.B.,S 14 1/3-17/8</p>
                    <p>Menouf.....</p>
                    <p>Payoum Beai-Sonel...</p>
                    <p>815 820 Province Menoufich</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 297 1/3 &amp; 305 (MOYENNE OTPTA) Province Fayoum</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 255 959 1/9</p>
                    <p>...D P.T 105 &amp; 2:0</p>
                    <p>SEOTION DES GRAINES ET ORBRALES FREE FRANCO-STATION: DISPONIBAS TIORAT
                        Graines de eblon MP.T. 65 P.T. Haute-Hgypte</p>
                    <p>Coron F.G.F.Bs. Novembre..</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Javier...</p>
                    <p>16 17/82</p>
                    <p>9/16</p>
                    <p>Poose Saidi</p>
                    <p>MATE......</p>
                    <p>18 11/16</p>
                    <p>93/82</p>
                    <p>Mai</p>
                    <p>15 78</p>
                    <p>90 83</p>
                    <p>GRADES DE COTON</p>
                    <p>Dée. Jan.</p>
                    <p>64 balles coton</p>
                    <p>61 8/40</p>
                    <p>10/40</p>
                    <p>201</p>
                    <p>Avril ...</p>
                    <p>62 16/40</p>
                    <p>30/40</p>
                    <p>81</p>
                    <p>64</p>
                    <p>PAYES SAID Dée-Jan....</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Eindemans,</p>
                    <p>990</p>
                    <p>Sobrid &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>W. Geity &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>-60</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>M. hra Fenderl, d. Parsedh</p>
                    <p>Mallison &amp; Co... Choreini Benschi &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>937 balles coton POUR DESTINATIONS DIVE Peel &amp; Co., 41 ballen séfono (Da
                        K Nangiar, &amp; henn Carver Bros &amp; Co 180 balles coton Choremi Benachi
                        &amp; Co., 95</p>
                    <p>175 balles eoton</p>
                    <p>B Trabelsi, 19 balles enir 1 Borla, 100 balles hennes et Barki, 80 ballos
                        herid</p>
                    <p>vrier-Mare.</p>
                    <p>P.T. 78 90/40 &amp; 77-</p>
                    <p>78 20,40.</p>
                    <p>58 1/2</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES melord 3 novembre 1904"</p>
                    <p>SHARE LIST</p>
                    <p>ISSUED BY THE "ASSOCIATION DES COURTIERS EN VALMURS D'ALEXANDRIN",</p>
                    <p>Cocsa Orfictus</p>
                    <p>Closare d'aujourd'hui 10. 45 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Agrio. Ba of Bayp</p>
                    <p>bas Bank of Egyp</p>
                    <p>Bamien railway</p>
                    <p>Las 10 13/16</p>
                    <p>87/16</p>
                    <p>Egypuan Dela Bul. ato. 15 8/18 Tramwayatkode For .48 1/2</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Wasee</p>
                    <p>Hear da Cale</p>
                    <p>Datch dieh Béadr</p>
                    <p>Bourse Kholiviale Egyptina alacko</p>
                    <p>div. 886-</p>
                    <p>Lat. 17 119</p>
                    <p>For: 1.25</p>
                    <p>Les 21 916</p>
                    <p>L.B. 55 8/4</p>
                    <p>Lat. 23 1/4</p>
                    <p>97/3</p>
                    <p>Angio-gyptian Spinning</p>
                    <p>Budce l'Atatvadne Par. Fe-81</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Din</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>dia Unire</p>
                    <p>Priv</p>
                    <p>188</p>
                    <p>Div. 174</p>
                    <p>Beyptina Conon Mille Let</p>
                    <p>Sals &amp; dods</p>
                    <p>Pressage Press Labiren</p>
                    <p>Oody OB</p>
                    <p>pen</p>
                    <p>Vonoise re</p>
                    <p>.494</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>Lowe Pure</p>
                    <p>alon</p>
                    <p>Beade Na de Grao, 432-</p>
                    <p>doque Indaheidule</p>
                    <p>Audi Nale La 3 1/4</p>
                    <p>BARQUE</p>
                    <p>Jes de souaso</p>
                    <p>8/B 4384</p>
                    <p>1328</p>
                    <p>80/40</p>
                    <p>raines de son Shop 19951 960</p>
                    <p>8149</p>
                    <p>16. 100</p>
                    <p>P. 181</p>
                    <p>190</p>
                    <p>Jeferred De</p>
                    <p>La 17 18</p>
                    <p>509</p>
                    <p>Naagovien lovel</p>
                    <p>918</p>
                    <p>Dolan Land</p>
                    <p>REMARQUES Ooros-Nouvelle récolte Rien de changé dans la sisation et la cote
                        ost rhodifiée sur la barb to récolte setnelle.</p>
                    <p>Bicole melle: L'aprde-midi a été pea sotive, faible et en baisse, l'Amérique
                        6ant pea encoure gente di Tarente d'une flière ses importante pour dechain
                        ayant provoqes des offres e novembre qai quoique wynt dd 'tre 606, n'en
                        reste ga alons offers &amp; 1/4 deri sa do du med Dand instinde pet phi pote
                        1879-- ba pode me 1816 - Dane l'apre midi prie plas hat pour (Sfax) mare 15
                        35,894 plus bas pour mare 18 31/89 (Algory 11/16.</p>
                    <p>For ALGER HAMBOURO, par le batean alle mand Gun, part 11 novembre Divers,
                        1,420, sen ris, 88 oje, 06 oais. dattes, 199 harile vieux for, 311 colis
                        gomme, 28 Franger &amp; Co. eolis palmes, 80 eolis divers 108 balles coton
                        100</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros &amp; Co, P. Andre,</p>
                    <p>A good amount of inter basar. business was put through in Gunnies amongst
                        dealers during the holidays, and with some shippers covering J. Plants &amp;
                        Co up their requirements, prices have farther Mohr &amp; Fenderi, hardened
                        and the tendency is still upmaitis R&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>Mallison &amp; Op a Bain &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>90</p>
                    <p>102</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>199</p>
                    <p>416</p>
                    <p>117</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>Is demandes devrons tre adressées à E. te Direton Général des P&amp;Alaxedio
                        papier tim 4 de PT. es sons double antelope eid des porisot is nation "Offre
                        poor tros. Almost all consuming centres have been Cho eni Be sebi &amp; Co.,
                        pas dans la ville de Port-Haid alles putting in enquiries, such as were for
                        prompt A. Has (alog Dissabra prosbain shipment being met as far as possible
                        from Pela &amp;septer l'offre second hand holdings, while for forward de Bed
                        &amp; G. Bincken, Tedjudication. liveries, milla are quoting very
                        cautiously, and de, le 18 Neved 1004 14048-1 speculative bolders in some
                        instances have</p>
                    <p>السلوط</p>
                    <p>dernier 4414.</p>
                    <p>8.444 balles eelon</p>
                    <p>NB-Lo antree livraisons avee reporte irrigations Au moment de la dire les
                        nouvelles</p>
                    <p>Mame prix. Patore del 700/84 Every soon égyptien disponible: Begerds:</p>
                    <p>Liverpool, olen adelesin Future Janvier Mercier 6.90. Fuere sijain1 6.28</p>
                    <p>New York: ooton wide, Patues Jah. : 0.64</p>
                    <p>-mare</p>
                    <p>GRADES DE COro Récolte stelle, L'aprie midi à des bodo &amp; fhit nalle, mais
                        l anque d'offres hated phet milient for cours Dane la usinde prix pha láns
                        pour PT. 8 phies pour the 7.81/Dane Primi, priz pla pour Neder-ms PT. 61
                        8/40 10,401 be pour ferier-mare P.T. 61-8/40 &amp; ares livraisons ares
                        reports i</p>
                    <p>des arrivages depuis le 1er segben bre 1004 jusqu'à ce jour Canture 9,190,400
                        Centre même jour en 1908</p>
                    <p>eolon</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS</p>
                    <p>WY ONBEING DRY 8B-4987</p>
                    <p>8 180 20</p>
                    <p>908</p>
                    <p>Ooare de la Bours on F.G.K.Br. Novembre N.B. $ 14 8/18 @ Janrise w</p>
                    <p>Mars MA in</p>
                    <p>Die</p>
                    <p>Die-</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Sper rie of Raffinerie d'Egyp</p>
                    <p>858</p>
                    <p>Fm, 203 - 967</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>DES COURTIERS EN MARCHANDISES) (Service Special DEPECHE D'OUVERTUR</p>
                    <p>Adrionin t</p>
                    <p>Livanrook, 10h. 3 a..</p>
                    <p>Pasare: Janviar-Pivrine: 6.19</p>
                    <p>Pasare: Mai Juin</p>
                    <p>Seeon la Diploha, 10h. 5.</p>
                    <p>Future; janvier-fiveise: 3.14</p>
                    <p>Pasare mai jula: 8.29</p>
                    <p>Bourea Khadivala 24 novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>DAGNIESE BAURE (Odrod Khidivalt. p.)</p>
                    <p>Cours de l'Appolo de Oogniere on Marahan disee Olen</p>
                    <p>Novecobre...N.B. $ 14 8/18</p>
                    <p>Janvier</p>
                    <p>18 5/16 11/3)</p>
                    <p>16 1/9 18</p>
                    <p>M&amp; M</p>
                    <p>98/89</p>
                    <p>Die</p>
                    <p>ww</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Ave</p>
                    <p>15 41 81</p>
                    <p>8/9</p>
                    <p>18 8/10</p>
                    <p>11,89</p>
                    <p>18 18:31</p>
                    <p>13</p>
                    <p>11 18</p>
                    <p>80 88/40 &amp; 00</p>
                    <p>10/4</p>
                    <p>90/40</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n4/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Our Paris Letter. might certainly have said; but he would have whether the
                        microbe will prove to be the spécifie</p>
                    <p>manship of his illustrions predecessor. More be the Doyen microbe. The points
                        to be tried are</p>
                    <p>FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT) PARIS, November 7. We have taken so kindly to
                        English ways that, for two days this week, we were enjoying Landin
                        particular-almost. The fog was not quite of the yellowish hue that prevails
                        by the banks of the Thames, but it had sufficient sistency-and a sufficient
                        blackness to cause general fighting up at noon. I have just meta French
                        friend, who said, "I have come from London. Do you know-it is astonish ing
                        there was no fog there. The first I saw was at Havre, where the boat had to
                        remain half an hour outside the harbour because of it. The cold and the rain
                        and the fog are the usual heralds of the winter, in Paris. If wish for
                        another sign you have it in the you disconsolate crowd that besieges the
                        doors of the municipal, refuges. It says something for British prosperity
                        that of the fifteen hundred of all nationalities applying for relief last
                        month, only one spoke with the tongue of the Englishman.</p>
                    <p>SPORT AND PLAY.</p>
                    <p>FOOTBALL</p>
                    <p>ROYAL BERK'S SIGNALLERS F.C.</p>
                    <p>A UNITED STATES SENATOR</p>
                    <p>Used Pe-ru-na For Dyspepsia with Great Benefit</p>
                    <p>HON. M. C. BUTLER, Ex-United States Senator From South Carolina</p>
                    <p>AX-U. S. Senator M. C. Butler from that state for two terms. In a recent
                        letter from Washington, D. C.; he says:</p>
                    <p>E South Carolina, was Senator from</p>
                    <p>"I can recommend Perusa for dys- pepsia and stomach trouble. I have been
                        using your medicine for a short period and I feel very much relleved. It is
                        Indeed a wonderful medicine be sides a good tonic."--M. C. Butler.</p>
                    <p>gained nothing by saying it-indeed, be would microbe of cancer, or a
                        secondary microbe; whe only have played straight into the hands of ther it
                        will be susceptible of inoculation, and enemies of the Church, who would
                        have quoted whether the animals inoculated will develop in his protest as
                        unmistakable evidence of Papal fections which can be treated for cure. All
                        this hostility to the Republic. They will do that will occupy months. as it
                        is of course. But they will not be able tot over the plain declaration of
                        his Holi news that the profession of Christianity can be in complete accord
                        with a Republican form of government. It can, no doubt; but, as French
                        Christianity is learning, to its cost, the anti- Christian influences which
                        dominate the policy SAINT ANDREW'S FOOTBALL CLUB. of France at the present
                        time have no desire to This fixture was brought off on the parade work in
                        harmony with the Church. On the ground at Mustapha Pasha on Saturday after
                        contrary, it is their deliberate intention to suppress Christianity, if they
                        can. They will noon in lovely weather and before a good turn- out of
                        spectators. The Signallers started the made manifest without grievous
                        spiritual suffer early in the vicinity of Curtis &amp; Co.. Keill fail, of
                        course; but their failure will not be game with the wind at their backs and
                        were There are certainly two opinions as to the and clearing the Saints
                        began to gain ground. ing and spiritual loss. was soon in evidence, and
                        through his tackling expediency of the Channel tunnel, but 1 Neither team
                        for a time could claim any great imagine that if Paris were polled on the
                        sub-advantage, the play being pretty much of the ject of the Champs Elysées
                        "tube" it would give-and-take order. The Saints' forwards were return an
                        emphatic "yes." It is the latest pro- not displaying any brilliancy in their
                        move- jeet to build subterranean passages at the ments, and in this
                        department certainly the The ratification of the Anglo-French Agree-most
                        important points beneath the principal homesters were the superior lot.
                        Cowie was ment having been voted in the Chamber byennes of this great
                        thoroughfare. For long their front-rank warrior, and he, supported by 443 to
                        105, we may now take it that the the pedestrian public have taken their
                        lives in good half-back play, steadied the attack.. The Sugate will follow
                        suit, and that final success their hands in attempting to "negotiate the
                        Signallers defence, however, was not found will crown the work upon which M.
                        Delcassé formidable stream of traffic that sweeps by at wanting, both New
                        and Harper offering active sad Lord Lansdowne are to be heartily con-
                        certain hours of the day, almost without inter-opposition. The first point
                        of the game fell to gratulated. Nevertheless, it is to be regretted lude,
                        from the Place de la Concorde to the the Saints, and came from the foot of
                        Hutch- that, while the Agreement is accepted as a Arc de Triomphe. ings.
                        That player, taking up the ball close in Prance and England are happily very
                        good and lifting it over the heads of all, placed it whole, a resolution
                        should have been proposed and carried which affirmed that the Chamber
                        friends, but as joint administrators of the New just out of Quarterman's
                        reach. The Signal- counts on M. Delcassé to open negotiations Hebrides they
                        can hardly be described as lers tried hard to square before the interval
                        with the British Government, as soon as a success. One of the French papers
                        in the and certainly their play deserved to meet with possible, with a view
                        to improving the New neighbouring island of New Caledonia, re some success.
                        Their efforts, however, were foundland Convention. That Convention will,
                        ferring to a recent massacre in the New Hebri- unavailing, and the interval
                        arrived with of course, when ratified by the Senate, be des, describes the
                        condition of this group as the score: Saint Andrew's 1, Signallers 0.
                        binding upon the two Governments; bat M. "flagrant anarchy," and says
                        neither life The restart gave promise of a very fast Delossé is charged with
                        the task of getting it or property is safe there. Furthermore, moiety. The
                        Signallers were evidently bent altered to meet the requirements, real or
                        both France and England "incur a serious on penetrating the visitors'
                        defence, but Keill aginary, of the French fishing industry. I
                        responsibility" in encouraging settlers to and Fitzgerald were playing a
                        sterling game, and am sorry that the Chamber has laid that duty emigrate
                        there under the present governing were well supported by the halves. Curtis,
                        too, up the Foreign Minister; I hoped that the arrangements. French rights
                        and interests in seemed to be in his element. Still the home- troublesome
                        question of the "French Shore" the New Hebrides are described as
                        "incon-sters persevered and reward at last attend would be settled once and
                        for ever; and the testably predominant," and the suggested solu-ed their
                        efforts, Saxton patting a beauty which fact that it will not be finally
                        settled by the tion of existing evils is the voluntary retire Curtis in
                        clearing over-ran. This gave the other present Convention constitutes a
                        distinct draw-ment of England from the scene and the part-forwards an
                        opening which they were not slow back to complete satisfaction. However,
                        there nership. That remedy, however, would be far to take advantage of, and
                        the score stood one is no reason to fear that England and France from
                        popular either in England or in Australia all. From the kick off play was
                        pretty much That peculiarly Parisian institution, the confined to midfield.
                        The remaining twenty "revue," is more or less a standing dish in the minutes
                        was very finely contested, but no other music halls, but as the year begins
                        to wane, it scoring took place. The whistle sounded with It is a funny
                        country, this country of hair partakes more and more of the character of the
                        score. Signallers 1, Saint Andrew's 1 splitting and of duelling. Why M.
                        Syveton the English pantomime in its allusion to recent The following were
                        the teams smacked General André in the face has been and current events. The
                        Alliance, unfortun- Signallers: Quarterman, New, Harper, Hand- a mystery to
                        everybody, but a greater ately, forbids, but one can imagine the fun ley,
                        Dovey, Austin, Saxton, Limmer, Glee, one is why, as one of his officers has
                        chosen that sprightly French artists of the "Café Herbert, and Woodley. to
                        make the insuit offered to the Minister of concert would extract from the
                        ludicrous Saint Andrew's Curtis, Fitzgerald, Keill, War a personal matter,
                        as Captain de Gail, or story of the Russians in the North Sea. An- Bright,
                        Clark, Nixon, Sweet, Jones, Cowie, the 1leme. Cuirassiers, has done, he
                        should other incident most certainly to be seized upon Hutchings, and
                        Halley. not be allowed to fight M. Syveton and be is the escape and
                        subsequent arrest of M done with it. After all, he merely acted as Syveton.
                        The escapade has little that is noble all, by 58 feet moulded breadth, and
                        36.6 feet deep to the tonnage deck, with a gross tonnage an officer standing
                        up for the Army, and is in it, but the "revue" lets who will be moralist,
                        not that what we are constantly inciting it simply amuses. One has need of
                        an extensive The Anchor Line have added to their fleet of 9,400 tons, and
                        when fully loaded her dis ofhears to do! De Gail is an aristocrat knowledge
                        of "argot" and of all the ramifica- the steel twin-screw passenger steamer
                        Cale placement will be not less than 16,000 tons. The first-class
                        accommodation is situated by birth, and has always marked himself out tions
                        of French politics to thoroughly appre- donia, which was launched at
                        Meadowsile, amidships, with staterooms for 300 passengers as begg more of a
                        thinker than most of ciate the niceties of a Paris ""revue" where Parties,
                        on theind Deprem da, beristen on the main and bridge decks. The second-
                        those of his class in the Army. What he has parody is piled on parody, and
                        paradox upon ing ceremony being performed by her Grace class accommodation
                        is also fitted amidships to done in-challenging Syveton may be a rash
                        paradox, often with a talent and a brilliance the Duchess of Montrose, and
                        the vessel will be wards the after end of the vessel; with staterooms all
                        ready and fully equipped in every particu- for 400 passengers. The third
                        class galley and a foolhanty act, but one cannot help that are bewilderingly
                        clever. The quality of lar to take her place in the regular service of
                        contains a most complete steam cooking plant. feeling glad that some French
                        officer should the jokes may be strained, but they generally the company in
                        good time for the spring and do such a thing after Friday's most disgraceful
                        drop in the right place.</p>
                    <p>will quarrel over the matter, and we must be content with that we have got.
                        Perfection is not of this world.</p>
                    <p>incident.</p>
                    <p>Americans. have known how to turn the As to André, he is, it appears, very
                        ill, for theatres of London into a gold mine, and they M. Byveton's blow was
                        a thundering one; but are about to Americanise the theatres of Paris. I
                        think it is pure "méchanceté" that makes According to statements made in the
                        local the journalists talk about his "ratelier" having press, a powerful
                        syndicate has been formed, been deranged. They merely want to throw and it
                        is proposed to found as many as ten new ridicule upon him, and of that there
                        is plenty theatres in the French capital. Playwrights to throw, "Dieu le
                        sait!" Meanwhile, he is quake at the thought. At present they have a
                        unmbtedly ill, and as far as it is at present society strong enough to
                        prevent managers known, both M. Syveton and M. de Gait are from crushing
                        them under the weight of com- under arrest. M. Syveton was arrested just as
                        petition. But in presence of a trust which can the duel was about to take
                        place, and there control ten theatres, a bitter struggle against the was a
                        rumour later to the effect that General power of capital is feared. André
                        had had his generous-defender "mis aux In Paris, at least, the pawnshop has
                        quaint, ariéts." Politics, and political manoeuvres, are half-pathetic
                        humours which it would probably always "tout puissant" in this country, and
                        be difficult to match in England. This is the in all probability the general
                        public will not time of year for renewals, and the expiry of the know more
                        of this affair until it is all over. date makes it possible to take an
                        inventory of En attendant, persons who are really indigold pledges remaining
                        or gone. This year a nant that the French Army should have small object
                        pledged for 12s. 8d. in 1869 has contained spies, and others who have some
                        been withdrawn, after 36 annual renewals, in other reason, private or
                        otherwise, for volving £1 138.-4d. Among the other "relics" showing up the
                        methods General André still remaining is a mantel ornament pledged for has
                        employed in the carrying out of 58. 22 years ago, and regularly renewed. But
                        what he doubtless considered his duty, are the champion "relie" of the place
                        is an ivory- busily exposing the recent manoeuvres of the headed cane, on
                        which the owner has paid 74d. Masonic Lodges in the Army, and the Gaulois a
                        year since 1859. and other papers are full of revelations on the subject.
                        This is, doubtless, quite right, and I because the constant ringing of the
                        bells and on only, imagine that good should come out the call and protests
                        of subscribers told so of the whole thing. That it will bring about a
                        severely on her nervous system that she was fresh Dreyfus disturbance I can
                        hardly believe compelled to leave her position, which she I believed last
                        year that such a thing as a had filled for nine years. revival of that
                        famous affair was not only An interview has taken place between the
                        possible, but even imminent. It is only fair Japanese Minister and M.
                        Delossé with that one should be allowed to change one's reference to
                        "certain matters relative to the opinions when one has a reason for so
                        doing, observance of neutrality," and the Tempe says and I now believe quite
                        the contrary. I believe that explanations are proceeding in an amicable that
                        such a thing would be considered by most way and there is very reason to
                        hope for a infoential Republicans as danger to the satisfactory result. In
                        the present awkward Republic, so great has been the prejudice position of
                        France in the affixirs of the nations, However, we shall in the utmost
                        delicacy and tactfulness is rendered Another series of duels has shaken
                        Paris to necessary, and the country has reason to feel its depths. In two
                        pistols were used, and the grateful that in M. Delcased it has a Minister
                        seconds having apparently exercised the cus who may be depended on to
                        exercise the fomary care in loading them harmlessly necessary quality of
                        discretion. The progress there was, of course, no result. One of the en of
                        the Baltic Fleet is attended with the utmost counters was, that postponed
                        from Thursday danger to the Powers, and not until it has between M. Syveton
                        and Captain de Gait. The reached a destination, whether in the waters of
                        affair with swords was a thore serious matter, warfare or elsewhere, will
                        they be able to General Andre's son being distinctly pricked in breathe
                        freely.</p>
                    <p>A Paris telephone girl has committed suicide</p>
                    <p>the wrist. The victim afterwards rode agay The Pasteur Institate of Paris is
                        now just on his bicycle, with much less inconvenience entering upon, the
                        experiments which it has than if he had taken part in a football match.
                        undertaken for the purpose of testing exhaus The language of the Papal
                        allocation on the tively the so-called-cancer serum of Dr., Doyen.
                        ecclesiastical situation in France is informeel by The experiments are under
                        the care of Dr. &amp; spirit of dignity and moderation. On this Metchinkoff,
                        and have just reached the primary ocession Plus X would seem to have derived
                        stage of having ready two large bladders-filled bie inspiration from the
                        consummate states with Doyen cultures, with which to propagate,</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE</p>
                    <p>summer season of 1905.</p>
                    <p>The new steamer is 515 feet in length over</p>
                    <p>Peruns is not simply a remedy for dyspepals. Peruns is a catarrh remedy.
                        Peruns cures dyspepsia because it is generally dependent upon catarth of
                        the</p>
                    <p>stomach.</p>
                    <p>If you do not derive prompt and satie factory results from the use of Peruns,
                        write at once to Dr. Hartman, giving t full statement of your case and he
                        will be pleased to give you his valuable ad- vice gratis.</p>
                    <p>Address Dr. Hartman. President of The fortman Sanitarium, Columbus, O</p>
                    <p>For special directions everyone should read "The Ills of Life," a copy of
                        which surrounds each bottle. Peru- na is for sale by all chemists and
                        druggists at five shillings per botles or six bottles for twenty-five
                        shillingt</p>
                    <p>Those wishing direct correspond ence with, Dr. Hartman and can wait the
                        necessary delay in receiving a reply should address Dr. S. B. Hart man,
                        Columbus, Ohio, U.S.A.</p>
                    <p>The following wholesale druggist will supply, the retail drug trade in
                        Alexandria, Egypt</p>
                    <p>MAX FISCHER, Alexandria, Egypt.</p>
                    <p>The Caledonia is propelled by two sets of latest type. powerful triple
                        expansion marine engines of the</p>
                    <p>EST. 1847.</p>
                    <p>Allcock's</p>
                    <p>PLASTERS</p>
                    <p>Are a universal remedy for Pains in the back (so frequent in the case of
                        women). They give instantaneous relief. Wherever there is a pain apply a
                        Plaster. DIRECTIONS FOR USE.</p>
                    <p>For pains in the Kidneys,</p>
                    <p>We Back, the plaster should applied</p>
                    <p>Where there</p>
                    <p>in pain apply Alle's Plaster</p>
                    <p>Rheudration Paine in For Sore Throat, Cough, Shoulders, tib Bronchitis, for
                        Weak Lungs and fox-painful and sensitive parts of the-abdomen, apply as
                        indicated</p>
                    <p>Sutteess</p>
                    <p>Peet cor</p>
                    <p>Aching Shape equired and apply to part affected as dues above</p>
                    <p>Rheumatism, Colds, Coughs,</p>
                    <p>Weak Chest, Weak Back,</p>
                    <p>Lumbago, Sciatica, &amp;c., &amp;c.,</p>
                    <p>REMEN BERAllcock's Plasters are the original and genuine porous plaster and
                        have never been equalled as pain-curers. Furthermore, they are absolutely
                        safe as they do not contain belladonna, opium or any polson whatever,</p>
                    <p>firmaren Hospital Balhat</p>
                    <p>CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>(Prepaid))</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH PROFESSOR, well</p>
                    <p>How 2.2.</p>
                    <p>in English</p>
                    <p>subjecte, wanted in Cairo, for two to three hours daily; any part of day will
                        b Apply, stating qualifications and terms, to "M. E., Cairo.</p>
                    <p>DAVIES</p>
                    <p>BRYAN</p>
                    <p>&amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>94941-9-3 CONTINENTAL HOTEL BUILDI</p>
                    <p>TO LET-Fine Villa, furnished or unfurnishe with garden and sesoles, seated on
                        the Gheared Promenade, Caird; thing the Khedivial porting Cinb, and next to
                        the reccod gase of the gurdsn of the Palace Hotal. Apply at "The Villa.
                        "94889-1x-11</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>THE UNION CLUB, Alexandria, invite appli ST. DAVID'S BUILDINGS</p>
                    <p>tions for the following posts (for Europ servants): Chef, Head Water, Barman,
                        Hall- porter. Applications to be addressed to Becretary, Union Cimb,
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>91918-6-6</p>
                    <p>WANTED by a large firm (British) at Alexandria,</p>
                    <p>competent clark with thorough knowledge of Customs clearing formalises and
                        band ing of bags and merabandise; knowledge of English and Amb
                        indispensable; ommanding salary 415- pe month. Applications, which will be
                        treated as confidential, must slate previous experisoos Apply, P. O. Box No.
                        185, Alexandria. 91988-8-8</p>
                    <p>ESSONS-TURKISH, FRENCH Langu Seisnoes (experimental method of ching). Tanali
                        Bey, opposite Poss-offes, Abbessiah, Cairo. 24980-6-1</p>
                    <p>MISS MINA SHEPPARD will continue her</p>
                    <p>Swedish nerve treatment for ladies after De cember 1. A Camp is to be
                        inaugurated ear the Pyramids, where patients and others may be accommodated.
                        24984-8-8</p>
                    <p>W clerk, preferably having knowledge Type ANTED, for Khartoum, competent
                        English writing and Sboriband. Balary LE 16 per month. Apply, sting age,
                        experience, etc., No. 94949 alo Egyptian Gazette offoes. 94949-3-1</p>
                    <p>Sanitas</p>
                    <p>Unequalled Parifying Agent Indispensable In Hot Countries.</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>Sanitas" Disinfecting Flaid</p>
                    <p>general or personal use is thoreogbly vetive It completely disinfects the
                        house in which it is used, and administered internally prevents Cholers,
                        Typhoid Fever, Dysentery, etc.</p>
                    <p>"Sanitas "Disinfecting Powder</p>
                    <p>is the best air purifier known, and a stronger antiseptic and deodorant than
                        carbolic acid, besides being pleasant and refreshing "Sanitas" Eucalyptus
                        Soap</p>
                    <p>is specially recommended by the medical faculty for use in hot climates,
                        because of its Ene disinfecting qualities and its fragrance</p>
                    <p>Kingzott's Fumigating Candles apply the safest and most convenient mesh of
                        sulphur fumigation. For the disinfection of infected places beating,
                        clothing, etc. they are both dicacious and economical Destroy all
                        injects</p>
                    <p>THE "BANITAS" OG LTA BETHNAL GREEN, LONDON, E</p>
                    <p>CALLARD</p>
                    <p>&amp;</p>
                    <p>BOWSER'S</p>
                    <p>BUTTERSCOTCH</p>
                    <p>(The Celebrated Sweet for Children). Really wholesome Confectionern</p>
                    <p>his popular English Sofment can be obtained at r</p>
                    <p>Mr. CARONIS, ANGLO-AMERICAN EYOREs, Port-Bal DEMETRIADER,</p>
                    <p>Moss TANCRED BONNICI &amp; O</p>
                    <p>The PATISSERIE DE LA BOURSE, Rua Charif Paba, Alexandria,</p>
                    <p>Manufactory: London, England.</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management.</p>
                    <p>81-11-904</p>
                    <p>PATENT.</p>
                    <p>FOR FLAT ROOFS OF PERMANENT BUILDINGS.</p>
                    <p>VULCANITE ROOFING</p>
                    <p>Adopted by nearly all leading Arell Private</p>
                    <p>gets e Pabile</p>
                    <p>Hotels Schools</p>
                    <p>of Industrial</p>
                    <p>Repairs</p>
                    <p>Being</p>
                    <p>Root ware may be set as garden, any other pay</p>
                    <p>ention Committee</p>
                    <p>ASA IMPORTANT C</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>35-37, Noble St., London,</p>
                    <p>NEW</p>
                    <p>GOODS</p>
                    <p>SEASON'S</p>
                    <p>ARRIVING</p>
                    <p>Wills for fell partijalar tastes, detail shatakan, amples. Ps. to</p>
                    <p>VULCANITE, LTD., I CANNON STREET,</p>
                    <p>LONDON, EC, ENGLAND</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Cairo &amp; Alexandria</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n5/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, November 22, 12.66 pm</p>
                    <p>Baise of the day</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Amerion (new stop) Maise Bgot per</p>
                    <p>American fatares (Des-Jan.)</p>
                    <p>(April-May)</p>
                    <p>American Middling...</p>
                    <p>bales 7,000</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>6.19</p>
                    <p>5.26</p>
                    <p>5.28</p>
                    <p>8 12/64</p>
                    <p>(Dec.)</p>
                    <p>7 59154</p>
                    <p>(Jan.)</p>
                    <p>7-88.64</p>
                    <p>Reyptian fully good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Brown fair per lb, d.</p>
                    <p>(March) 7.47164</p>
                    <p>good fair (browajnominal 8 6/16 good</p>
                    <p>fully good fair...</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Besas new (per 490 lbe) to 25,8</p>
                    <p>Arrivals from Egypt 8.8. Moeris, 8,746 bales of</p>
                    <p>60sion</p>
                    <p>Spot Cotton...</p>
                    <p>American Futures (December)</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers Cotton day's receipts at all U.S. Porte</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904</p>
                    <p>BANKING FIRM "EL NASSIB," ORENSTEIN &amp; KOPPEL Limited</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Tewfik Pacha-Street, No. 12.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL AGENT OF THE ROYAL HUNGARIAN LOTTERY.</p>
                    <p>Telegraphic Address: EL NASSIB. - Telephone No. 1280.</p>
                    <p>We have succeeded, contrary to the general rule, in receiving from Budapest
                        by 1st Class of the 15th ROYAL HUNGARIAN LOTTERY. of which the drawing is
                        definitely fixed for the</p>
                    <p>the last mail a limited number of tickets for the</p>
                    <p>24th and 25th of this month.</p>
                    <p>Now it will be possible for us to satisfy the demands for tickets which we
                        have been obliged to refuse for several days.</p>
                    <p>For this reason we beg all those whose requests had to be refused kindly to
                        renew them and they shall be certain to receive the tickets by return of
                        post. Payments may be made in the following manner :-</p>
                    <p>1st from class to class as indicated in the Official Prospectus.</p>
                    <p>New York, November 22,</p>
                    <p>9.90</p>
                    <p>981</p>
                    <p>(January)</p>
                    <p>9.41</p>
                    <p>(April)...</p>
                    <p>(May)...</p>
                    <p>-- 9.60 9.66</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 5/8 bales 109,000 LIVERPOOL, November 22</p>
                    <p>Amerion fatores (December Janasry).... Egypsin fully good fair, delivery
                        (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>6.17</p>
                    <p>8 15/84)</p>
                    <p>(Dea.)</p>
                    <p>7 81/64</p>
                    <p>A WHOLE TICKET</p>
                    <p>A HALF TIOKST</p>
                    <p>(Jan.) 7 66 64</p>
                    <p>March) 7 49 64</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>A QUAQTER TIONET P.T.</p>
                    <p>AN EIGHTH TICKET P.T.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 29.-</p>
                    <p>Private dissonas (8 month bills)</p>
                    <p>Bar Bulver (per os d)...</p>
                    <p>27 4/16</p>
                    <p>1st CLASS.</p>
                    <p>50.5</p>
                    <p>25.5</p>
                    <p>13.-</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>Console (December)</p>
                    <p>89 3,8</p>
                    <p>2nd</p>
                    <p>84-</p>
                    <p>42-</p>
                    <p>21.</p>
                    <p>10.5</p>
                    <p>Bio-Tinto...</p>
                    <p>61 84</p>
                    <p>3rd</p>
                    <p>134.5</p>
                    <p>67.5</p>
                    <p>33.5</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>Band Mines</p>
                    <p>11 1/8</p>
                    <p>Egyptian United..</p>
                    <p>106 88</p>
                    <p>4th</p>
                    <p>168.</p>
                    <p>84.-</p>
                    <p>42,-</p>
                    <p>21.</p>
                    <p>カラ</p>
                    <p>Bailway</p>
                    <p>100-</p>
                    <p>5th</p>
                    <p>134-</p>
                    <p>67-</p>
                    <p>33.5</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>Domain</p>
                    <p>104 1/2</p>
                    <p>6th</p>
                    <p>101.-</p>
                    <p>50.-</p>
                    <p>25.-</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>Ottoman Defence...</p>
                    <p>108 1/2</p>
                    <p>Turkish Unibed.</p>
                    <p>88 58</p>
                    <p>Italian Bente 6s...</p>
                    <p>104-</p>
                    <p>Onoman Bank Shares</p>
                    <p>18 5,8</p>
                    <p>Nasional Bank of</p>
                    <p>Dairs Banish</p>
                    <p>101</p>
                    <p>New Dairs</p>
                    <p>91 5/8</p>
                    <p>Manopole Gree...</p>
                    <p>87-</p>
                    <p>Charterede of 8. Afri</p>
                    <p>95/16</p>
                    <p>Agricultural Bank...</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>Nile Valley Gold Mins</p>
                    <p>new 18/4</p>
                    <p>Beats Greoque 4*</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>672-</p>
                    <p>336.-</p>
                    <p>168.-</p>
                    <p>84.-</p>
                    <p>Delis Light Railway (Bearer share) 15 to 15 1/3 Egypt. dos seed to Hall
                        (Nov.) 5 19/16 nominel</p>
                    <p>German Best Bagar (November)</p>
                    <p>2nd. For all the 6 classes by one payment in advance: ie., for a whole ticket
                        672, for</p>
                    <p>a half 336, for a quarter 168, for a eighth 84 P.T.</p>
                    <p>3rd. In two equal payments of P.T. 336 for a whole ticket, P.T. 168 for a
                        half, P.T. 84 for a quarter, and P.T. 42 for an eighth. The first is payable
                        (with the order and the 2nd before the drawing of the 5th class.</p>
                    <p>4th. In 6 equal payments in advance of</p>
                    <p>Lote Taros</p>
                    <p>Crédit Lyonnais...</p>
                    <p>Om</p>
                    <p>Bank...</p>
                    <p>Cheques on London</p>
                    <p>18/11 1/3</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 23.</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>1149</p>
                    <p>598</p>
                    <p>35.16</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>722</p>
                    <p>Bar White No. 8 (November).</p>
                    <p>Crédis Foncier Egyptien</p>
                    <p>Beaque d'Athènes (nouvele nesnee). 128 1,1.</p>
                    <p>BOURSE. da 39 novembre 1904-</p>
                    <p>COURS DES VALEURS A TERMS, CLOTURE</p>
                    <p>Bense Française 3......</p>
                    <p>PARIS-</p>
                    <p>Actions de Snez</p>
                    <p>Los Tares.</p>
                    <p>Ture Unifié.</p>
                    <p>Deite EgyptienneUnifiés...</p>
                    <p>Daira Banish</p>
                    <p>98 40 4505 180-</p>
                    <p>Céréales.....</p>
                    <p>Touring</p>
                    <p>88 14</p>
                    <p>Graines de ecton...</p>
                    <p>105 40</p>
                    <p>Olgons</p>
                    <p>101 16</p>
                    <p>P.T. 112 per whole ticket.</p>
                    <p>56</p>
                    <p>22</p>
                    <p>28</p>
                    <p>14</p>
                    <p>25</p>
                    <p>half "quarter eighth</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>29</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>BANKING FIRM "EL NASSIB."</p>
                    <p>R. KRONFELD.</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>OUBARET FatoRS PER TON VREE</p>
                    <p>236 18'</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, Tewfik Street 12.</p>
                    <p>24</p>
                    <p>SALE BY AUCTION.</p>
                    <p>WASOS MESSRS. CONGDON &amp; CO. have been Shgs instructed to sell by Public
                        Auction the @ 246 property and effects of the officers, 20th Hussars. The
                        sale will take place in the 186 Mess-room, Cavalry Barracks, Abbassieh,on
                        186 Friday and Saturday, Nov. 25th and 26th, commencing at 9.30 on each
                        morning. The property will be on view on Tues day, Wednesday, and Thursday
                        afternoons 18 3 up to 6 p.m. 24982.5-4</p>
                    <p>186 -</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</p>
                    <p>24943</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>1/1 8/</p>
                    <p>18 66</p>
                    <p>Per Tom</p>
                    <p>Nominal</p>
                    <p>Cardi Newport Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Best quality Best quality</p>
                    <p>Shgs. 24</p>
                    <p>Bothal</p>
                    <p>Ordis Fonciar Egyptiens...</p>
                    <p>712-</p>
                    <p>Compou</p>
                    <p>Extérigne espagnol...</p>
                    <p>90 50</p>
                    <p>LONDAR8</p>
                    <p>Davison</p>
                    <p>183 18</p>
                    <p>29</p>
                    <p>Obligations Banque Nas, de Grice</p>
                    <p>Céréales.....</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Ashines, nouvelles actions</p>
                    <p>Touriesas</p>
                    <p>139</p>
                    <p>Métropolisain...</p>
                    <p>Grainse de sosed... Olgnone</p>
                    <p>Bhgo, 1/1 1/3 &amp; 18 7/0</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>-1</p>
                    <p>West Hartley Main-</p>
                    <p>Boolek</p>
                    <p>Merry's</p>
                    <p>179</p>
                    <p>Basse sonsolidé...</p>
                    <p>Bairds</p>
                    <p>17,9</p>
                    <p>Bosnowine...</p>
                    <p>Change ear Londres...</p>
                    <p>26 10</p>
                    <p>Dunlops</p>
                    <p>17,9</p>
                    <p>18 3</p>
                    <p>Beat Hamilton B</p>
                    <p>Boere No. 8 disponible</p>
                    <p>Graines de soton...</p>
                    <p>Buers No. 8 livrable</p>
                    <p>Forkshire Liverpool</p>
                    <p>Miebleford</p>
                    <p>Best Lancashire -</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>and quality</p>
                    <p>Consolidés anglale****</p>
                    <p>288 5/16</p>
                    <p>Besond Lancashire</p>
                    <p>Becomptes-Parie 8, Londres 8, Berlin</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Anchor</p>
                    <p>Crown</p>
                    <p>GERBAL MARKET.</p>
                    <p>Tourtesas... Graines de coton... Olgnens...</p>
                    <p>Star</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <p>Patent Fuel Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Swansea Graigola 22/6</p>
                    <p>Atlantic- Foundry Cobe கச Cake</p>
                    <p>38 34</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIRECTS Hhgo. 90-10/ 1/9-</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL ...Hogs. 11/ 1,8</p>
                    <p>CONTINENT (NANTES.DUNKERQUE)</p>
                    <p>BOG BL FARAD. (NATIONAL BAR' BHOOMAN) Grainse is ook (Dunkerque) Fr.</p>
                    <p>Olgnene...</p>
                    <p>Wheat, Tagarl Arl. P.T. 199 to P.T. 196</p>
                    <p>Middling Mawani...</p>
                    <p>188</p>
                    <p>MARGRILLE</p>
                    <p>146</p>
                    <p>Beans, Tugri</p>
                    <p>Gminer de soton...</p>
                    <p>-7.80</p>
                    <p>95</p>
                    <p>(old erop)</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>88</p>
                    <p>DESTINATIONS DEVERE</p>
                    <p>Lanule Tagad</p>
                    <p>Zaws</p>
                    <p>Amiawi..</p>
                    <p>Barley, Togari</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>Zawad</p>
                    <p>Dam Bhacal</p>
                    <p>Helbe</p>
                    <p>Bala</p>
                    <p>Lentils Orished Rho-</p>
                    <p>Orushe l</p>
                    <p>ORMAS IN BOAT AT BANNE</p>
                    <p>Ard. 8000</p>
                    <p>1400</p>
                    <p>1600</p>
                    <p>607</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>Coton : Odes, Trierts, Venies,</p>
                    <p>106 Gas, Marvellie... Pr. S</p>
                    <p>78 Barone</p>
                    <p>88 Le Havre</p>
                    <p>76</p>
                    <p>Dankerge</p>
                    <p>3.60 8.00</p>
                    <p>par 100 kille</p>
                    <p>નોરતાની વાતનો મહા કવિ કહ</p>
                    <p>Hambourg</p>
                    <p>186 P</p>
                    <p>210 New-Yo</p>
                    <p>Bombay</p>
                    <p>90.0 99.60</p>
                    <p>die, le 16 novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>PRIMES DES CONTRATS.</p>
                    <p>"SIMPLE VACULT</p>
                    <p>Ostos Tdy: Mare P. 18 80/40 &amp; 18: Gainer is set. 76. M... 1-a 38/40</p>
                    <p>LEGYPTIAN GAZETTE en vente dane les rues du Caire tous les soirs, à F 7h. 80,
                        cepté le dimanches et jours Hride. Le journal out at on wit aus Iris, de
                        Tantak</p>
                    <p>mire de jer, P.T</p>
                    <p>Pyle du</p>
                    <p>meg</p>
                    <p>"TELLAGE</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>GREAT SALE</p>
                    <p>OF</p>
                    <p>Capital 10,000,000 Frs.</p>
                    <p>PURVEYORS TO HH. THE KHEDIVE. PORTABLE AND PERMANENT RAILWAYS PASSENGER AND
                        GOODS CARS</p>
                    <p>Tipping and Platform Waggons</p>
                    <p>FOR ALL PURPOSES. LOCOMOTIVES FROM 10-400 HP.</p>
                    <p>(CATO: 24 Kaar el Nil Street opposite the Bask of Egypt</p>
                    <p>OFFICES OB. 690, Telephone No.39</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 29 Cher f Pasha Street. Telephone No. 661</p>
                    <p>Large Stocks of Rails, Tracks, and Locomotives always kept in Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>SIEMENS &amp; HALSKE, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING OFFICES: CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA Electric Light Installations.
                        Transision of Power Electric Railways and Tramways- Telegraphic &amp;
                        Telephonic Apparatze DYNAMOS MOTORS.</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>OHATWOOD'S and ILMER'S SAFES 2 steek</p>
                    <p>CAIBO: 34, Karl- Blest, opposite Bank of Bgypt, P.0.B. 600. Triophone No.
                        189. ALEXANDRIA: 29, Chéri Pasha Street. Telephone No. 867. 81-33-904</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Leers. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin. Palon T-mobing Kaisaking Hoshinas</p>
                    <p>Fixed and Fortable Bom and OIL Bags Oers</p>
                    <p>Mesars. Platt Brothers&amp;Co., Limited, Oldham. Messrs. John Fowler &amp;
                        Co., Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>Steam Panghing Machinery and Bandries,</p>
                    <p>The Central Crolone Co., Limited, London. Grinding and Pulering
                        Machinery.</p>
                    <p>Mers Charles Cammell &amp; Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p>Mors.</p>
                    <p>Bumi Halla, prigi, for as Patent mad at Dis</p>
                    <p>Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                    <p>Stoom and Maanal Fire Engin</p>
                    <p>F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld, Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Oarel Brands Baiting at, she</p>
                    <p>Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p>The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                    <p>Rik Vortes Turbines,</p>
                    <p>Mosers. Greenwood Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>Ths (a) Palent Bomb Batsriaal Dynamo &amp; Motors</p>
                    <p>McCormick's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                    <p>Planet Junior Agricultural Implements.</p>
                    <p>Borne Joan, Bood Dri, ate, st OLITER PLOUGES.</p>
                    <p>Agent in Cairo: MA. FATTUOOI.</p>
                    <p>38-8-805</p>
                    <p>Agents for amEENE Economisers.</p>
                    <p>STEINEMANN MABARDI &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>MERCHANTS,</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Engineering Stores. CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY</p>
                    <p>Bole Agenta for Egypt, Asia Minor and Syria for</p>
                    <p>IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Mears. Clayton &amp; Shuttleworth, Lincoln. Portable &amp; Exed Engines &amp;
                        Boffers, Cos</p>
                    <p>milla, Thrashing Strawbruising &amp; Cutting Machines</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Galloways Ltd. Manchester. The Largest Boller Works in the World Walter
                        A. Wood, Mowing &amp; Beaping Machian Co. Boorish Falla N. F. (Acarion)
                        Beapers; Mowers, Harvesters &amp; Bakes</p>
                    <p>Piguet &amp; Co., Lyons. French Steam Bagisan</p>
                    <p>Aveling &amp; Porter Lim., Rochester. Ste Bollers and Steam Ploughs Les
                        Tanneries Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Belting E.. Hindley,
                        Burton, Dorset, Vertical Engines and Bollars, specially designed for driving
                        estrie Dynamos &amp; Owntrifugal Pumps, sto, eta Hillafret Hagueot, Paria
                        Mectricians.</p>
                    <p>L. Dumont. Paris. Centrifugal pumps.</p>
                    <p>8. E. &amp; E. Turner Ltd. Ipswich. Flour Mille</p>
                    <p>31188-94-11-904</p>
                    <p>Winter Novelties Credit Lyonnais SHRADER BROTHERS.</p>
                    <p>COMMENCES</p>
                    <p>Société Anonym</p>
                    <p>22/9 NOVEMBER 12. Capital 250.000.000 de Franos</p>
                    <p>EXCHANGE QUOTATIONS</p>
                    <p>London cheque... 8m. bank paper Bai hege paper...</p>
                    <p>Parie cheque Cine</p>
                    <p>8m. bank paper...</p>
                    <p>Sm. hoe paper.</p>
                    <p>Banks Banks baying selling</p>
                    <p>rated 97 1/8 97 96</p>
                    <p>886 1/4 887 888 14 888</p>
                    <p>Bwitserland &amp; bank paper.. 881 1/4-</p>
                    <p>Germany chage......</p>
                    <p>Ben, bank-pape</p>
                    <p>mies</p>
                    <p>475 14</p>
                    <p>471 1/8</p>
                    <p>Italian sheque paper</p>
                    <p>888-</p>
                    <p>abaque</p>
                    <p>405. 1/3</p>
                    <p>888 1/4 406</p>
                    <p>88 1/8</p>
                    <p>88 8/8</p>
                    <p>Vienna &amp; Trie</p>
                    <p>Constantinopla cheque...</p>
                    <p>Municipalité d'Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>AT</p>
                    <p>Walker &amp; Meimarachi.</p>
                    <p>PASCHAL BRANCH.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>LATEST</p>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PARIS</p>
                    <p>ENTLERUMENT VERSES</p>
                    <p>AGENCES DEGYPTE ALEXANDRI LE CAIRE PORT SAID</p>
                    <p>Avamoos sur Marchandises, Consignation.</p>
                    <p>LE CREDIT LYONNAIS fait des avances Fur marshandises, telles que :,</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>GRAINES DE COTON, ORREALES SUORES, te</p>
                    <p>Il reçoit également des marchandisee soit en dépôt libre, avee droite de
                        magaal Rayole ou a l'airanger.</p>
                    <p>CREATIONS age, solé en consignation, pour la vente en</p>
                    <p>NOTICE</p>
                    <p>94870-14-18</p>
                    <p>8170004</p>
                    <p>LONDON CALCUTTA, ALEXANDRIA. SINGAPORE AND COLOMBO (Union). Merchants in Jute
                        and Jute Fabrios (Gunny Baga).</p>
                    <p>COTTON PACKS</p>
                    <p>and based)</p>
                    <p>(00 by 48′′) (11 by 11)</p>
                    <p>(11.by 10)</p>
                    <p>(11 by 10)</p>
                    <p>(by 10)</p>
                    <p>ONION POCKETS (own and homel</p>
                    <p>19) on (40 by 2 by 10)</p>
                    <p>(Swa</p>
                    <p>GRAIN BACKS (rown and hommel)</p>
                    <p>SUGAR BAGE</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>DR. LE CLERC'S</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>8.701.04</p>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO, LTD. Pills for the Liver &amp; Kidneys</p>
                    <p>VERAGE SIM m By from good to Aldria Ted Nebr</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS</p>
                    <p>are an unfailing and reliable remedy for die of the important organe gout,
                        rheumatism, gravel pains in the bank and kindred silmante (nquired or
                        constitutional), Sold by prinetpal Chemite, not to loom quantities, but only
                        in boxes, price L bearing the British Government Bamp with th wonde Eugene
                        Le. Clero pred thereen</p>
                    <p>The Biter of the Bgyption Gonette wil be pleased to resolve come nications
                        dealing with malies of local, interest, for yabletion. Notes of to covering
                        in (Between the hours of 10 am and 6pm. Outro time to protect the pable from
                        frid the Provinces are especially welcome. hould be sent to T by and Addres,
                        not nece</p>
                    <p>Le Jeudi 24 Novembre conant pactis de 8h. pm., Man/elpalité groolders &amp;
                        la vente atten ahires jobliques pris de ontières Heropéens is &amp; is Porte
                        Rosene, d'ane quantité de pierres extraites der ersion des Forossions par de
                        400 1 100m Les betere devront par le droit d'an shore da 1020 époser le 10
                        000 de la valore de la marebandise sehetés ant moment de la vante of soon
                        Fon-M... 80/40. Liv. Mare FT. 97 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 offener le paiement
                        insigral &amp; Onlee Mani. All come eipale, le leglessin da jour de
                        l'etindiastion. Ile auront sapporter le droise de carrière an prods de la
                        Ville et devront enlever les pierres ache tée dans un délai de dix jours,
                        sone geins anah Are, pour compte de l'adjudicataire. Alexandrie, le 21
                        Novembre 1904.</p>
                    <p>"DOUBLE</p>
                    <p>dv. Mare FT. 880/40 &amp; 10 .-M.</p>
                    <p>10/40 1.18/40</p>
                    <p>94044-8-9</p>
                    <p>folle</p>
                    <p>Writer's good faith The B</p>
                    <p>1/Adminiralour W. P. CHATAWAY.</p>
                    <p>THUM</p>
                    <p>1:18</p>
                    <p>Dr. LE CLERO'S SOAP. Molloal antiseptia used and recommended by ambent
                        dermatologists in the treatment of eos lepra, psoriaals, alourations, alta
                        eruptions: thehing and treating the bumours baby rashes ode, ale prophyte
                        against the risk of contmoting des and Infotions disordare generally. I
                        healing propension greatly minimise the bon ventence of shaving to use of
                        phapes pote ten La Tablete price / old by Cairo and Ale</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <!-- if necessary            
            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n6/mode/1up">
                
            </div>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n7/mode/1up">
                
            </div>
            --> 
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>