<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Ryan Schefstad</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-09-29">September 9, 2023</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1904-11-21/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-21">Monday, November 21, 1904</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Peninsular & Oriental S. N Company. -->
                <div type="advert"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE</head>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>CORFAST, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>This Company's item of saltare graph cables the most direct and quickest of
                        conication from Egypt to Eampe, North and South America, East, South and
                        West Aries, India, Aptir New Zealand, Chine and Japar</p>
                    <p>To secure quick tration, telegrams should be marke Vid Eastern</p>
                    <p>For latest aerage time to London, set daily bulletin to</p>
                    <p>this paper.</p>
                    <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT A, Cairo, Sues, P Teek, Port-Said, Skin Head Office,
                        London.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>No. 7,051]</p>
                    <p>ALEXA YOBIA, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904.</p>
                    <p>[SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</p>
                    <p>THE EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>onits</p>
                    <p>Le. &amp; cfbles tégraphiques sous-marinis constitue le moyen de
                        communication le plus direct et le plus Egypte pour TEurope, TAmérique</p>
                    <p>du Nord et du Sad, Afrique orientale, méridionale occidentale, e Indes,
                        FAustralia: la Nouvelle-Zélande, Chine et le Japon</p>
                    <p>Pour carer ene t</p>
                    <p>rapide,</p>
                    <p>doivent porter Findication Via Eastern</p>
                    <p>Voir le tempe moyen</p>
                    <p>Londres a bulletin</p>
                    <p>STATIONS EN EGYPTE Part-T</p>
                    <p>le plus</p>
                    <p>Peninsular &amp; Oriental S. N Company. British India S. N. Company, Limited.
                        Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Coy.</p>
                    <p>The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the</p>
                    <p>MONGOLIA"</p>
                    <p>following dates:</p>
                    <p>MALACA</p>
                    <p>9,516 Tona 11 November 5,045</p>
                    <p>SUMATRA"</p>
                    <p>4,807</p>
                    <p>POCKANA</p>
                    <p>4,610</p>
                    <p>7,913</p>
                    <p>&amp;December</p>
                    <p>MATILA"</p>
                    <p>4.310</p>
                    <p>HARDINIA"</p>
                    <p>6676</p>
                    <p>23</p>
                    <p>MACEDONIA"</p>
                    <p>20,518</p>
                    <p>MARMORA</p>
                    <p>30,809</p>
                    <p>7,0</p>
                    <p>4,874</p>
                    <p>PRRA</p>
                    <p>SUNDA</p>
                    <p>Marelli, Plymouth and London Malts and London. Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Marion, Plymouth and London. Marseilles, Plymouth and London. Malta and
                        London,</p>
                    <p>Malts sod London.</p>
                    <p>Marseille, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>Marsel Jes, Pigmonth and London, Yarles and. London. Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Port-Said to London via Brindisi.</p>
                    <p>The BRINDISI atomer leaves POBT-BAID ser arrival of Indian Mail. Combined
                        steamer and sleeping one fare from PORT-BAID to LONDON vis BRINDISI or vis
                        MABSEILLES 25.9.11.</p>
                    <p>To the East</p>
                    <p>The Mail Beamers leave BUEZ for ADEN and BOMBAY every Wednesday, and for
                        AUSTRALIA and CHINA every sisarnase Wednesday. Aster leaves for CALCUTTA,
                        formighaly, and snosher for JAPAN. Pengers can embark sa PORT-BAID.</p>
                    <p>For all farther information apply to the Company's Agents, Mesars. Teos. Coon
                        &amp; Box (Rgypt) Lad....</p>
                    <p>GRoses BOTLE, Beq......</p>
                    <p>Morers. HASBLOWN &amp; Co....</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>PORT-BAID ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>/81-19-90</p>
                    <p>F. G. DAVIDSON, Superintendens P. &amp; O. 8.-N. Company in Bgypt BUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Orient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p>B.M.B. Orotava will leave Bass about Croya</p>
                    <p>Dea. Deo.</p>
                    <p>9</p>
                    <p>MAIL AND PASSENGER</p>
                    <p>Calling at Apass, Copenso Fry Service in OUTWARD-8.8. Muttra</p>
                    <p>SAILINGS FROM TEAM SHIPS. London and Calcutta Line.</p>
                    <p>Chief Omce: Sharia Boulae, Grand Continental Hotel Buildings Brack Offer
                        Uppite Savoy Hotel Daire Regular weekly Tourist Steamer Departures between
                        CAIRO and AssoUax by the following steamers :-</p>
                    <p>and Mapas Outward, and MaILLES (GEOL and PLYNOTE optional) Homeward. noction
                        with the Ce's Indian M Lines and monthly with the East African Mail Line
                        between Anay, Mom and ZAIDAL November 26- HOMEWARD: S.S. Mombassa Nov. 28
                        MAYFLOWER... PURITAN</p>
                    <p>Queensland Line of Steamers between London and Brisbane. MAYFLOWER...</p>
                    <p>Calling at Cosest, BATATA, CooTOWN, TOVILLE, Bows, and RocKRANTOR 8.8.
                        "ITIA," will mil from Bus or abous the 14th December. REMARKS-Bargets snd
                        Stews and Cargo booked Graff, Bast Afric Below</p>
                    <p>on board for paymen donmer in which shere</p>
                    <p>Aden</p>
                    <p>81.10 31.10</p>
                    <p>From Port Said :</p>
                    <p>Agents in LONDON, M Managing Agents in INDIA Agias PlanT SAID, PORT BAID Moms
                        Thos Cook For further</p>
                    <p>Amerions Ford to all Straits Setti Bomers Arolipelago, Fins and Becond Clase
                        Pre gers are allowed to break the voyage My LASS BAT OF PASSAGE MONEY</p>
                    <p>tropical elis</p>
                    <p>Two Thirds of a Clo Par</p>
                    <p>and Extraches.</p>
                    <p>CAIBO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>BYTS &amp; Co., Age, Bues. 81-13-904</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE, Limited.</p>
                    <p>(HENDERSON BROTHERS), LONDON, LIVERPOOL, AND GLASGOW. First class passenger
                        steamers,</p>
                    <p>1904</p>
                    <p>December 9th</p>
                    <p>281d 30th</p>
                    <p>VICTORIA PURITAN MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p>1905</p>
                    <p>Weekly SECOND CATARACT SERVICE by, the First Class Tourist Steamer "INDIANA"
                        AGENTS FOB PRINCIPAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANIES Through Bookinge to Khartoum
                        and Gondokare. RAILWAY TICKETS TO ALL PARTS OF EGYPT. FREIGHT SERVICE by
                        steam barges between ALEXANDRIA and CAIRO SAVOY HOTEL Elephantine island,
                        Asonas, Company's Property.</p>
                    <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.</p>
                    <p>Fortnightly Service from ALEXANDRIA Passengers and Freight). Commencing on
                        abe 16se of Noystube.</p>
                    <p>To NAPLES and MARSEILLES, with the Twinsrow-beloon zo Schleswig 7,100 ton)
                        leaving ALEXANDRIA every alemate Wednesday na 3 pm.: 18 &amp; 80 Nov., 14
                        Des., 11 Jan, a Jan., 8 Yok The following steamers are intended to leave
                        PORT SAID:</p>
                    <p>BONNWARD: for Bremen or Hamburg v NAPL, GOA, (GENNALTAR), SOUTHAMPTO</p>
                    <p>ZETEN</p>
                    <p>OLDENBURG</p>
                    <p>PRINU ALIUR 1091 BUKARABORT</p>
                    <p>Novem.</p>
                    <p>Pa. Ras, LAVDOLD BARKASUBBA PRAUSSEN</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD for China and Japan v Bu ADEN, UOLOMBO, PREANG, SINGAPORN</p>
                    <p>BUON</p>
                    <p>Booking Passengers and Cargo through to Porta in INDIA, EUROPE &amp; AMERICA
                        Sailings Fortnightly from Bues. For LONDON S.S. Bohemia Dec. 10 For CALCUTTA
                        S.S. Agria...... December 7 BRYDLITZ For MARSEILLES 16 ALIVERPOOL 8.8.
                        Marilia Nov. 24 For BOMBAY S.S. Circassia... Saloon Pares: from Port-Baid,
                        in Ghentar 49, Marsellen Liverpool (all rente) 815 London (all son rente)
                        413, Lendon November 26 BAYERN Marsellie 10 Pages embarking at Ismailie 21
                        mors et Soomers 1000 reduction allowed to of the Army of Opatient and
                        Government employs Through siekted to New-York (vil Gow). Fares on Agutta i
                        Oniro, Mars THOMAS COOK &amp; BON, Pans-id, Mars CORT BROTHERS &amp; 0, ta
                        For further partieniars of Freight or Page apply to G. BEYTS &amp; Co.,
                        Sues.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY B.M.B.
                        Ortona will leave. Pors-Bald about... Dée. 5 19</p>
                    <p>Oricaba</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>8.B-Homeward ouers are sometime before their advertised, dassa. Passengers
                        landed and embarked at Ismallia, Quarantine Regulations permitting, free of
                        an expense. Port-Bald to Naples..................... 1st Class; 411-nd
                        Clais, 47 8rd Class, &amp; 4 8 to Marseilles....</p>
                    <p>FARES</p>
                    <p>10 Gibraltar.***********</p>
                    <p>16 18.</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>81-18-006</p>
                    <p>10- MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>8 18-</p>
                    <p>Established 1888. Capital 41,000,000. Beserve Fund 4835,000.</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>ZIETAN</p>
                    <p>For Austraile BUNK</p>
                    <p>GNKISENAU</p>
                    <p>BRAIN</p>
                    <p>Dea</p>
                    <p>FKINDRICH D. GR. 1005</p>
                    <p>BREMEN</p>
                    <p>FOR FURTERE FABRIQUAM APPLE TO FER AGENTS OF SER NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD at
                        Caire, Alexandria, Part Sald and Suez. OTTO STERZING, AGT Caire, Oran
                        BDARE</p>
                    <p>C. H. SCHOELLES, AGENT IN ALEZARDNIA, Cleopatra Lase</p>
                    <p>M THOR 000 a BOL CARL STANENS BASTURBAU are thorised to sell bole CAIRO and
                        ALEXANDRIA 30-11-004</p>
                    <p>Elevur tickets no longer insted, bas pengers paying the fall, fee in one
                        direction are allowed on THE IMPO oad Burse, LONDON, Riebling 1008 Al Fando
                        Band 10,00,00 Co.,L. Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation.</p>
                    <p>to- Prymonth or Tilbury. sissemens of one-third of their fare beck if the
                        rern voyage be made within four months of arrival, or so sbasement of 20% af
                        rara voyage be made wishin six months of armval. Agents, Cairo-THOMAS COOK
                        &amp; Bow. Alexandra B. J. Moss &amp; Co. - For all information apply to Wm.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Port-Said and Port-Tewalk Suez), 81-13-904</p>
                    <p>BIBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>SPECIAL BEDUCED RATES DURING THE SUMARE SEASON.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS to GOLOMBO. TUTICORIN, to, and RANGOON b. Yor kahere is tons will
                        have Bues abou, November 28.</p>
                    <p>6.8 Warwickshire, toss, will leave suas abous December 7.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS MILLE and LONDON.</p>
                    <p>B. Worcestershire, 1,60 tons will leave Port-Baid about November 29.
                        Shropshire 7.0 will leave Port-bald abous Deco</p>
                    <p>FARES from tersid to Marsillee $12.6.0, London $17.0, bo 433.10.0, Rangoon,
                        437.19.0; Fitted with Refrigerators, Electric Light, Electric fans and all
                        recent improvemente Experienced Stewardesse and burgeons carried. Agente in
                        Cairo's Messre, Tao COOK &amp; SON For si particulars apply to W. STAPLEDON
                        &amp; SONS, Port-Bald &amp; Port-Tewak (sues).</p>
                    <p>81-18-906</p>
                    <p>81-13-904</p>
                    <p>1,-Old Street, 1808-Total exceed Polisis/ined a BUEZ by G. BEYTS &amp; Co.,
                        Agate.</p>
                    <p>22nd inst.</p>
                    <p>Deutsche Levante-Linie. Wying with Vien pres (re-senda</p>
                    <p>Mail and Passenger Beamships. Begur three-weakly Service froua HAMBURG, VIA
                        ANTWERP &amp; MASTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice ver, goods from all the
                        principal GERMAR BARWAY BRATORS on direst of Lading to ALEXANDRIA and all
                        the principal port of Berre, BrazIAN COAT, ., the favoumble through mise of
                        the DETROS VAR (bag).</p>
                    <p>EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>8.8. Siegfried, now on the berth loading will sail for Botterdam and Hamburg
                        on the S.S. Thasos now in port will sail for Beyrons on the 28rd inst.
                        Lesbos from Answerp will seil for Beyrout on the 28rd inst.</p>
                    <p>For ride and partediars apply to ADOLPHESTROSS, Alexandria,
                        Agent-18-9-905</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE. Messageries Maritimes.</p>
                    <p>FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Greed-Turkey' Line;</p>
                    <p>Express songs leave Alexandria every Wednesday 6p.m. for PIRBUS (Athens),
                        SMTSHA MITYLENE, and CONSTANTINOPLE. In sonadon with the Outers agrees
                        tants-de-luze for Belgrade, anos, Paris, and London,</p>
                    <p>Palestine-Syria Ligg</p>
                    <p>Futurs leave Alesandria every day p.m., and For Sold every Sunday at 8p.m.,
                        fo JAFTA (for Jertale), CALFYA (for Naresh), BETBOUT (for Dam), TRIPOLI,
                        ALEX ANDARTTA, MAKINA, onasing in alumna wesks to LARNACA and LIMARMOL
                        (Cyprus).</p>
                    <p>Red Sea Lind</p>
                    <p>Beamery leave Buen every Thursday spm for JRDDAR, alling alred TOR (for Mount
                        Steal and TAMBO, and sonstosing in aberse woks to BUAKIM, MARKOWAH, HODIDAH,
                        and ADEN.</p>
                    <p>H.B. Dock chairs provided for the ses of poengers, szalons saisins and table
                        wins tree. mer plans may be seen and page booked as the Company's Agmales at
                        Alexandria, Cairo, Pore Bad, and Bees or as Thos. Cook &amp; on or other
                        Touris Aganay</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>The Moss S.S. Company, Limited.</p>
                    <p>P LAVERPOOL ning si MALTA, O JAM MORU,, JB, Levers, MAARJ -7.M. &amp; BAA</p>
                    <p>Bacond glass 416 Retur</p>
                    <p>ummodation only,</p>
                    <p>Thrones</p>
                    <p>From Alossadria For Marsellles direct Friday 4 Nor, as noon Sinigal</p>
                    <p>Sallings from Antandria ta November, 1904,</p>
                    <p>Rate of panoge money</p>
                    <p>From Alexandria</p>
                    <p>To Naples</p>
                    <p>Wednesday</p>
                    <p>Cap. Vincensi Conge Galett Niger Portugal Rignier For Pot Bels Jaffa and
                        Bayreuts Nov. Conge Osp Galottl Portugal Riquier Conge Galet For Part Sald
                        and Beyrouth Wednesday Capt. Camngli Through Wckets for London vs Marsalles
                        (Unials Denys Senegal Vincenti Trough sekass Parts (vi Marellon return lekte
                        with the Arian Lloyd Oy,</p>
                    <p>Now</p>
                    <p>For Marsailles Direct:</p>
                    <p>To Part Ha To Jalta To Beyreath</p>
                    <p>1.18.10</p>
                    <p>-1.7.10</p>
                    <p>Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste Venice Line. Weekly Express Mail Bervice. Be
                        leave Alexandria every Barily at Brindis, arving Today morning in aime for
                        axpraece so Paris, London, Naples, prese Imly and Germany. No. 19 4pm.
                        Cleopatra Capt. A. Ivallich. " Semiramis Nov. 264 pm. Semiramis Ongs,
                        Marsinolieb. Marinoboh Deo. 8 Cleopatra Alexandria-Patras-Brindisi-Trieste
                        Line. Ivalligh Sommer lowres Alexandra os or about serd November, Tsh and
                        31st December, Far East Line.</p>
                    <p>from Bus) To Aden, Bombay, Colombo, Pang bama, Kobe about Dep. 5. To Aden and
                        Bobay</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Colombo, Madma, Rangoon and Onleata abos November 20.</p>
                    <p>East African Line.</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Morabam, Zanzibar, Batre, Dalagon Bay, Daban about December 4.</p>
                    <p>Syrian-Caramania Line.</p>
                    <p>Steamer leaves Alexandria on or about November 14 and $8, Decembar 13 and
                        96.</p>
                    <p>Syrian-Cyprus-Oaramanian Line.</p>
                    <p>Beamer avee Alexandria on or about November 31, Dececaber 5 and 19</p>
                    <p>For all, informaalom spply to the Company's Agros. And, Fore-ald and Bass,
                        Box, La., Laon Hassas, Oniro Agons, Saria Maghaky (Telephone 198), Onde
                        Tunaso, Helowan Special passage rates granted to Egyptian Government
                        officials, of the Army of Occupation and their families.</p>
                    <p>CUNARD LINE.</p>
                    <p>Trieste-New York. BLATONIA Sept. 80 LUCANIA... PANNONIA. Oes 14 CAMPANIA...
                        USTONIA... Nor. After t 16I 18 SLAVONIA... PANNONIA...</p>
                    <p>Gregort</p>
                    <p>returning from China Australia</p>
                    <p>Ballings from Port Said In November 1904. Probably on Thursday 10 Nov.
                        Salarie Bunday Dupl, Nigre Caledonien Sailings from Seas In November, 100%
                        19 Nov.</p>
                    <p>For Aden, Olombo, ingspers, Balgon, Hong-Kang, Shan- ghel, Robe and
                        Yokohama</p>
                    <p>Tamatave, La Bunten sod Manrie</p>
                    <p>Braint-Simone Cap Bourdon Schmita</p>
                    <p>ghal, Kobe and Yokohama</p>
                    <p>PRI</p>
                    <p>8,100 lot. 814 Bingia, 46 Bern, Rod Begle Hose &amp; Co., Aissandris, Agents
                        ous Babarday, November so be followed by BA SETI fork and her UA as be
                        bented us einaive of Railway fare through to and from Cairo. Partieslars on
                        application. -11-004</p>
                    <p>or Dinent, Aden, ah, Da-doares, its Marte, Tame La Banion and Maurice Hethay,
                        Oelembe, Fremantle, Adelaide, Mel- beros, Bydney and Nemes...</p>
                    <p>Gaire Agency</p>
                    <p>Wednesday 14. Thursday 1 Dec Monday Not. hopheard's Hetal.J</p>
                    <p>Melbourne X</p>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO.'s LINE.</p>
                    <p>Bleetris des</p>
                    <p>Base &amp; Pors-Said formigasly tur London or Liverpoos direes</p>
                    <p>BALOON (A) FARE $12.</p>
                    <p>8.8 AMARAPOORA 6600 Tone will leave PORT-BAID abons Nov. MARTABAN 780</p>
                    <p>#Kanooo</p>
                    <p>B060</p>
                    <p>97 for Liverpool.</p>
                    <p>9 for Liverpool,</p>
                    <p>25 for Liverpool.</p>
                    <p>Due in Leadun or Liverpool 18 days thereafter 6., Port de THOS. SOOK &amp;
                        SON. Kara L., 6. J. GRAGE &amp; B... Asdr</p>
                    <p>A WORMS</p>
                    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p>(ROYPT), LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE-LUDGATE CIRCUS-LONDON, CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE-CAIRO, near
                        SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL Alexandria, Port-Said, Ismailia, Suez, Luxor, Assouan,
                        Halfa &amp; Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>TOURIST AND GENERAL PASSENGER AGENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>Baggage and Forwarding Agents. NILE STEAMER SERVICES.</p>
                    <p>TOURIST SERVICE. The large and spendidly sp. pointed S.S. Rameses, will leave
                        Cairo on Tuesday, November 29th, for Luxor, Assouan and Phile. Other
                        sailings Dec. 6, 13, eto..</p>
                    <p>EXPRESS SERVICE-Steamers will leave Cairo</p>
                    <p>Rivière</p>
                    <p>PRINCE LINE.</p>
                    <p>7,100</p>
                    <p>Tons, 8,000 WELSH PRINUS.. BLAUK PRINCE 2,000 SPANISH PRINUS (idg 7,000
                        NORMAN PRINCE 4,000 GEORGIAN PRINC</p>
                    <p>APRICAN PRINCE TUDOR PRINCE SWEDISH PRINCS (big- CHINESE PRINGS - ITALIAN
                        PRINCE MERCHANT PRINUR BOLDIER PRINCR</p>
                    <p>4000 SAILOR PRINCE</p>
                    <p>400 RUNBLAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>MAXICAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>A HIGHLAND PRINCE</p>
                    <p>BICELIAN PRINCE-</p>
                    <p>BRITISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>GRBUIAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>URBOLE PRINU</p>
                    <p>SYRIAN PRINUR - INDIAN PRINUR TUBUAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>8700 NEAPOLITAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>KI MOURISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>AT KARTERN PRINUS 8,060 CASIN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Koto ORANGE PRINCE</p>
                    <p>17M BUTTISH PRINCS 1,879 LOURAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Tona 8,000APORAN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>1,000 BAXON PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Tons</p>
                    <p>7,000 BURMESE PRINOR (bg)-</p>
                    <p>4710 180JAS PRINCE</p>
                    <p>4000 CROWN PRINCE</p>
                    <p>AMO SOYPTIAN PRINUS 400 SPARTAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>8,000 DMPERIAL PRINCE</p>
                    <p>A70 PERSIAS PRINOR KIM CASTELGIAN PRINO 3,060 AREATIO PRINCE 3,000 KAFFIR
                        PRINUR 57 CYPRIAN PRINCE BOTAL PRINUS</p>
                    <p>Good Accommodation for Passengers.</p>
                    <p>Liverpeal-New York</p>
                    <p>Liverpool-Beaton,</p>
                    <p>19,95 sons. UMBRIA 8,197 tops BAXON... 14,390 o 13,960 STRURIA... 8,119
                        13,564.</p>
                    <p>AUZANIA 7,598</p>
                    <p>18 Embarking passengers at the Riverside Railway</p>
                    <p>Ivana... 14,088 SYLVANIA.. 8,598</p>
                    <p>on Tuesdays and Saturdays.</p>
                    <p>Deession, Prince's songs, Lavertongh mos rom gypt inned by</p>
                    <p>the Agente suuANAUMI&amp;US, Alexandria; NICULAB KIRSIS, Ustro, B. BROADBENT,
                        Pore-Baldy</p>
                    <p>ELLERMAN LINES, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>CITY LINE.</p>
                    <p>MALTA, LONDON, COLOMBO &amp; CALCUTTA</p>
                    <p>CITY &amp; HALL LINES.</p>
                    <p>Joure ESIC TO MARSEILLES, LIVERPOOL, BOMBAY &amp; KARACHT.</p>
                    <p>The undermentionat First Class Ponger will be dispatched trom Port d'on or
                        shoot the following dates her Malta &amp; Landen 8.8, CITY OF BEANS Nov. 3
                        Liverpeel Celembe &amp; Caleutte S.S. CITY Catcurta Nov. Bombay &amp;
                        Kareahl Oro Loco Nov. 20 Nov, 20 Baker Fass-Fers Paid to Malle A Man Lendin
                        or UORY BROTHERS &amp; On, Ltd., Agents for the City Line, Port sald; W.
                        STAFLEDON &amp; Box, Agense for For further parents wel the Hall Line, Port
                        Said or to TROS COOR &amp; NOR (gypt, Ltd. Oxire,</p>
                    <p>36788-38-3-908</p>
                    <p>Navigation Generale Italienne.</p>
                    <p>Societes Reunies Florie-Rubattino. Services Postaux. Departs de Novembre. Les
                        Jendis 8, 10, 17 et 24 à 8h. p.m. direct pour Messine, Naples, Livourne et
                        Gines.</p>
                    <p>Lee' Mardis 1 es 15 à 8h. p.m. direes pour Brindisi, Bari, Anedae et
                        Venise</p>
                    <p>Le Meroredi &amp; 10 h s.m. pour les escales de la Syrie es Larusque,</p>
                    <p>Le Land 14 à 4h. p.m. poqr Port-aid, Suse et Massawah.</p>
                    <p>Lee Landi 7 et March 24h. p.m. pour Port Bald.</p>
                    <p>BANK OF ATHENS, Limited.. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co..</p>
                    <p>Ephial 20,000,000 (Tally sad p</p>
                    <p>achter and Liverpool and ghy them werp a lot lessra and Syrian Coast. The
                        dates are approximate and Town PAL PERSIAN FRINUS due from Antwerp &amp;
                        Middlesbro Nov.13 GRECIAN PRINCE de frem</p>
                    <p>Railings ry 10 days from</p>
                    <p>KAFFIN PRENUR</p>
                    <p>ROWN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>OCEAN PRINUS</p>
                    <p>Londo Fame &amp; Trieste Answerp</p>
                    <p>HABIATIC PRINOS</p>
                    <p>1 INDSN PRINUR SCOTTISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Manchester</p>
                    <p>Lendon Manchester Antwerp &amp; Tendon De</p>
                    <p>BOREWARD SHILINGK-The R8. alle Prince is weling her sad will be loved by the
                        &amp;&amp; Crown Pr For terms of freight or passage apply to O. J. Grace
                        &amp; Co., Alexandria, Agents. 31-12 904</p>
                    <p>THE PAPAYANNI LINE. (The Ellerman Lines, Ltd.)</p>
                    <p>Pank</p>
                    <p>ltakall banking bobate</p>
                    <p>ights N&amp; per</p>
                    <p>Despatch weakly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Malls
                        from ALEXANDRIA to CYPRUS and the STRIAN ODART and vice-varm For particolare
                        of freight, passage, st, apply to the Agent SD. A, MINUTTO 1099-9-9-906</p>
                    <p>SUDAN GOVERNMENT RAILWAYS. CAIRO-KHARTOUM SUMMER MAIL SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Watraday and Sunday</p>
                    <p>Dining set Dining sad Bleep</p>
                    <p>AR</p>
                    <p>part Catro</p>
                    <p>as also on train from Catro te Lamer on Mondaye psd from Jame to Onlyondage
                        Wall alivered Exart, Bunday and Wednesday evening and Ostre, Thursday and
                        Friday morning.</p>
                    <p>Pregnant Bailings from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL, also Begalar Services from
                        LIVERPOOL ALEXANDRIA and to ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT. BLACK SEA, and other
                        Mediterranean Ports and To Moderate Fares for single and return tickets
                        Excellent Passenger Accommodation. Stewardess carried. Liberal table and by
                        the 88. PARDINIA The CITY OF RUNDER, cow loading will leave for Liverpool in
                        a few days and will be followed SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY,
                        LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>INLAND TOWN ORRAT BRITAIN</p>
                    <p>CARGO when by special agreement only. Through Freight quoted for the UNITED
                        STATES and For passage or freight apply to the Agents, BARKER &amp; Co.,
                        Alexandria.. 9081-81-10-908</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT Says White Nile Tour Trip de Khartoum andar er plans may
                        be KHARTOUM AIRO OFFICE SHARIA KASB- ween sind gee ook at all list Agen of
                        goods undertaken so all pieces on SEBUTAL STRAM for private This and sa
                        Nther whhin navigation fai ENGINEERING DE TMENT Shipyard for construction of
                        rowheel, mar ai SOLE AGENTS FOR Dadbridge Of Engines from machinery,
                        buildings, brigacion Beat On, Lil</p>
                    <p>every Monday, and Friday during the season. First The Ellerman Lines Limited.
                        INTERNATIONAL SLEEPING AND RESTAURANT CARS COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>(Including Westcott &amp; Laurance Line.)</p>
                    <p>14</p>
                    <p>departure November 4, 19 days on the Nile for £22. SPECIAL COMMED BAKWAY AND
                        STEAMER BIKE TOURS AT GREATLY REDUCED FARER Hegular mailings from Liverpool
                        Glasgow Antwerp and London to Alisandra Frequent mailings from Alex Deer
                        BI-WERELY SERVICE TO HALFA ERARTOUM, BUDAN. W andzia to Liverpool and
                        London. Throngh freight rates to toland towns to Great Artain slao o the USA
                        SPECIAL STRAMESH AND DAHABRAHS FOR PRIVATE PARTIES S.S. Bolderss from Lendon
                        &amp; Mala Ellerman is due on or about Nov. 23 One Regular Service of
                        Freight Steamers between CAIRO and HALFA. Liverpo Bwana &amp; Malta- Westco
                        Antwerp &amp; London Cook's Interpreters in miform are present at the
                        principal Hailway Basions and Ianding plans in pssengers holding their kete.
                        10-18.004</p>
                    <p>Tours to Palestine, Byvin, and Demes. Best Canis egiptunk Lowest chan</p>
                    <p>Ellerman Westool</p>
                    <p>Flavian</p>
                    <p>Ararat Alisan</p>
                    <p>" R</p>
                    <p>Belgravian Grester</p>
                    <p>Liverpool &amp; Malte London</p>
                    <p>For para</p>
                    <p>M. TAMVACO, A</p>
                    <p>The 8 Athian, now on the bert for Liverpool, will be despatched to that pers
                        Ages</p>
                    <p>sandy</p>
                    <p>Vesil further wote the Tren Monday, Wednesday, and ap Supplement- Slots</p>
                    <p>ping and Barnt Care will re re e</p>
                    <p>4) Thebes all information ma be obed at Company's</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n1/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ric01" colSpan="2">
                    <head>Royal Insurance Coy</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>
                    <p>Largest Fire Office in the World.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782);</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">31-3-906</measure> FRED. OTT &amp; CO., Sub-Agents,
                        Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ahh01">
                    <head>"AL HAYAT" Helouan</head>
                    <p>First Class Health Resort</p>
                    <p>Unrivalled Position on the Mokattam Hills</p>
                    <p>96 metres above the level of the Nile, surrounded by desert.</p>
                    <p>All rooms full south with sheltered verandahs</p>
                    <p>Public Sitting Rooms in separate Pavilions communicating by glass
                        corridors.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light–Steam-Heating–Lift.</p>
                    <p>Bathing, Air and Diet Cures. Resident Medical Director. All kinds of sports.
                        Own stables. Omnibus meets all Trains.</p>
                    <p>Ilustrated Prospectus sent free on appplication</p>
                </div>
                <!-- drossos -->
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-spc01">
                    <head>SPIRO CONDOLÉON.</head>
                    <p>SMYRNA TURKEY-CARPETS.</p>
                    <p>Made entirely of wool and vegetable colours</p>
                    <p>THE BEST CARPETS IN THE WORLD.</p>
                    <p>SPIRO BUILDINGS, Sharia Kasr-el-Nile, Cairo</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">29501-7-1-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mav01">
                    <head>MAGASINS VICTORIA.</head>
                    <p>ECCLESTONE AND KEILL ENGLISH DRAPERY.</p>
                    <p>Opposite Austrian Consulate, near the Zizinia Theatre. Catalogue on
                        application.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE</head>
                    <p>Mr. W. Ernest Walton has arrived in Egypt and is now residing at Hotel du
                        Nil, Cairo. All retailers of postcards should without fail see the
                        collection which he has now at his disposal for the Egyptian market. This
                        collection is unique in the world. No time nor expense. has been prepared in
                        the production of these postcards, which are veritable reproductions of
                        aquarelles.</p>
                </div>
                <!-- notice -->
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                    <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                    <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">7-8-90</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-wlb01">
                    <head>Wrexham Lager Beer</head>
                    <p>Ask for</p>
                    <p>Brewed at Wrexham England</p>
                    <p>Wrexham Lager Beer Co. Pilsener</p>
                    <p>Registered Label</p>
                    <p>And if not supplied apply to</p>
                    <p>John B. Caffari</p>
                    <p>Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">27-10-0.</measure></p>
                </div>
                <!-- adr -->
                <!-- dunlop -->
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma03">
                    <p>Embossing Press for Stamping Own Paper with Address Crest &amp; c.</p>
                    <p>Engraving Office</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Cairo Bulac Road</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-wam01">
                    <p>Our Winter Season's Stocks</p>
                    <p>COMPRISING AN Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver &amp; Plated
                        Articles</p>
                    <p>CUTLERY, LEATHER &amp; ATHLETIC GOODS &amp; GAMES.</p>
                    <p>TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS.</p>
                    <p>CHOICE HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS.</p>
                    <p>VINTAGE WINES</p>
                    <p>PROVISIONS, CONFECTIONERY AND TABLE DELICACIES,</p>
                    <p>Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly moderate prices.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Supply Stores, (Branch Walker &amp; Co., Cairo)</p>
                    <p>WALKER &amp; MEIMARACHI, Limited.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cmh01">
                    <head>MENA HOUSE HOTEL</head>
                    <p>IS NOW OPEN.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24846—30-4-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <!-- grand continental -->
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-eeh01">
                    <head>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL, PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>First Class Hotel. Modern in all respects.</p>
                    <p>Fire-proof, Drained to the Sea, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French
                        Billiards, Fresh and Salt Water Baths.</p>
                    <p>The Coolest Summer Residence in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Special terms to Cairo Residents and their families desirous of enjoying the
                        cool air and sea bathing during the summer months.</p>
                    <p>Dragomans in Hotel Uniform Meet all Trains and Steamers.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">22941-23-8-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>John Haig's Glen Leven</head>
                    <p>Old Scotch Whisky.</p>
                    <p>BOLE PROPRIETORS</p>
                    <p>JOHN HAIG &amp; Co, Limited, MARKINCH, SCOTLAND.</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED PRIOR TO 1680. R. CORBO &amp; G. PARIENTE, Caire.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-twh02">
                    <head>The Tosh Whisky</head>
                    <p>Established 1726.</p>
                    <p>Mackintosh &amp; C. Inverness.</p>
                    <p>Agent: Ernest Thoron, Cairo &amp; Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>General Depot John Ross &amp; Co. Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Retailers. E. J. Fleurent, Square Halim Pacha, Cairo.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">126625-30-4-907</measure></p>
                </div>
                <!-- where to winter -->
                <!-- photographie reiser -->
                <cb n="4"/>
                <!-- sphinx -->
                <!-- weather -->
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</p>
                    <p>SUBBORT</p>
                    <p>Cairo, d</p>
                    <p>Intinelor of Mes</p>
                    <p>(including delivery</p>
                    <p>P.2. 116 e</p>
                    <p>PT. 90 the three months. Te</p>
                    <p>in the Portal Union F.T. 978 (83.10</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.-P.Z. 4par Hos. 1 sbarge E.T. 30. Births, Mazinges, de De</p>
                    <p>sonal line P.T. 10. Notions</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>Ens. Contraits anter</p>
                    <p>ding adver</p>
                    <p>a 10th of any month.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS Jos in advanos. P. O. Orders and Cheques to
                        be made payable to the Editor and Manage, Sowad Boulling, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>onde Offfese: 88, New Bed-stro; B.C.</p>
                    <p>"GYPTIAN GARETTE IN PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY TER COMDGN
                        PAPER KILLS MATTED CALES OF2202 E, CARRON STREAT, AC.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="birthDeathMarriage">
                    <p>BIRTH. SCOTT-At Kar-e-Nil; on the 19th inst, the wife of Mr. J. H. Scor, of a
                        son.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="imprint">
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>An English Daily Hewisper,</p>
                    <p>tablished in 1880</p>
                    <p>Hiror &amp; Manngar: B. Bra</p>
                    <p>Prios One Plastra Tarise.</p>
                    <p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 21, 1904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TANZIM DEPARTMENT AND CAIRO. </head>
                    <p>In our last issue we mentioned that the inhabitants of Helouan, weary of the
                        absolute contempt with which the Tanzim. Department treated their just
                        complaints, had determined to appeal directly to Lord Cromer. But it is not.
                        Helouan alone which suffers from the neglect and indifference of the Tanzim
                        Depart- ment. Cairo has also grounds for complaint, and it must be admitted
                        that the maintenance of the streets of the Capital is not carried out with
                        such a regard for the convenience of the public as it would be only
                        reasonable to expect. No one, who knows anything at all of the conditions of
                        life in the city and of the always increasing flood of traffic that poury
                        through its streets all day long, will deny that on the whole this work is
                        well done, for though it might, we should imagine, be easily expedited when
                        'tis done, 'tis well done, but there is a want of tact in the choice of time
                        and place for the labours of the department in charge that is not merely
                        annoying to the average man in the street, but a very serious impediment to
                        the business of the town. At the present moment Clot Bey-street has been
                        pulled up from one end to the other and all traffic throughout it is
                        completely stopped. In fact this has been the case for more than a month
                        past, with the single qualification that the Tramway Company has continued
                        to use its lines through the street. Those lines carry an immense aniount of
                        traffic, seeing that they form part of the 'direct tramway routes to
                        Abbassieh, Rod-el-Farag, and Shoubris, and form the connecting link between
                        the milway station and the Mousky, Nasrieb, and, in short, all parts of the
                        town. Fortunately for the ordinary carriage traffic the closing of this
                        street is not a great inconvenience inas -much as the alternative route by
                        the Bab el Hadeed street adds but little to the distance to be covered. With
                        the tramways, however, the case is different, for the whole of the traffic
                        that usually goes through Clot Bey has now to make a long detour passing by
                        the Post Office, Continental Hotel, and so on up the Boalse road and thence
                        along the new road to the railway station. The consequence of this is that
                        all day long a double stream of traimoars is passing right through the heart
                        of the town and crosses. the heavy carriage traffic that is always in motion
                        to and from the Sharia Kamel and the south and west parts of the town.
                        Happily both the Boalse road and the approaches to it from the east are wide
                        enough to easily meet the strain thus put upon them, or rather they would be
                        so if it had not been that just at this particular moment one half of the
                        Boulse road has been torn up and is being remacadamised in the leisurely
                        manner to which we are acoust omed. Why this work, which most certainly was
                        not pressingly needed, should have been undertaken exactly at the time that
                        the open- ing of the season brings a rush of traffic to this spot, and that
                        that rush is already spore or less seriously incommoded by the abnormal tram
                        way traffic, is a question that it would pale any sane man to answer, unless
                        the answer be that the authorities are quite indifferent to the convenience
                        of the public or are, for some rea son or other, incapable of judging its
                        needs It is really therefore to be hoped that some steps will be taken to
                        place some one in charge of the organisation and working of the depart ment
                        responsible who is competent to carry it on without exhibiting the utter
                        indifference to! the convenience of the public that is shown at present</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round. ELEOBRIG LIGHT.-LIFT.-ODERATE CHARGER</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WAR.<lb/>RUSSIAN BOMBARDMENT.<lb/>JAPANESE REPULSE<lb/>GREAT
                            BATTLE IMMINENT</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>MUxD, November 19.</dateline>
                            <p>A stiff artillery fire was opened on the Russian right at daylight,
                                and lasted for several hours. The fire continued at intervals during
                                the day. The Russians are expecting a general attack. All ranges
                                have been carefully marked, and whichever any attacks is likely to
                                suffer severely.. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Mexpax, November 19</dateline>
                            <p> The Hussians expect a general attack. (H.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, November 20.</dateline>
                            <p>The Russian artillery on the Sha Ho have ompelled the Japanese to
                                fell back. (Hans).</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Toxo, November 20.</dateline>
                            <p> Friday's report from Marshal Oyama, detail- ing the various
                                skirmishes and stating that the Russian bombardment of the Japanese
                                positions was resultless, seems to indicate the imminence of another
                                great battle, though, apparently, neither side has yet made any
                                decisive move- ment. The Russian feints were evidently intended to
                                draw the Japanese (Reiter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, November 20.</dateline>
                            <p>The attack on Putiloff, mentioned on 18th inst., was made in order to
                                ascertain the strength of the Russian position. The Japanese got
                                within 30 yards of the trenches, but were finally repulsed leaving
                                100 dead. (Beuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE UNITED STATES.<lb/>THE PRESIDENT'S MESSAGE.<lb/>PEACE
                            CONFERENCE,<lb/>NAVAL AMBITION.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>WASHINGTON, November 19.</dateline>
                            <p>It is understood that Mr. Roosevelt's message will say nothing
                                regarding tariff reform, but the party leaders are carefully
                                considering a revision which will be proposed next year. Nearly all
                                the European powers have indicat ed their acceptance in principle of
                                Mr. Hay's invitation for a Peace Conference, leaving the details for
                                future negotiations</p>
                            <p>The United States Naval Estimates for 1905 amount to 114,5000,000
                                dollars, which is an increase of 17,000,000. (Reuter)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>NEW YORK, November 19.</dateline>
                            <p>Mr. Morton, Secretary for the Navy, speaking here, declared that Mr.
                                Roosevelt aimed at having the best and strongest Navy in the
                                (Reuter)</p>
                            <p>world.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ANGLO-RUSSIAN CONVENTION. NEGOTIATIONS PROGRESSING.</head>
                        <dateline>Losos, November 19.</dateline>
                        <p>The Anglo-Russian negotiations for the Con vention are progressing.
                            Russia desires to exclude anything which would imply that the Russians
                            are necessarily to blame. (Router)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JAPANESE LOAN.</head>
                        <dateline>Loxton November 19.</dateline>
                        <p>The total subscriptions for the Japanese - loan here amount to
                            £80,533,800 (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RIO JANEIRO TROUBLES</head>
                        <dateline>Rio JANEIRO, November 19.</dateline>
                        <p>Colonel Sadre, the instigator of the troubles, has given himself up to
                            the authorities. (H.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STRIKE DISTURBANCES AT HAVRE</head>
                        <dateline>HAVAR, November 20</dateline>
                        <p>Disturbances have taken place as a result of the strike of port
                            labourers</p>
                        <p>(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nila Steamer,</p>
                    <p>&amp; HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF 00008 BETWEEN ALEANORIA &amp; CAIRO Three Ballinge
                        e-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agente at Alesandria</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO., L</p>
                    <p>81.10.200</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n2/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PORT ARTHUR.<lb/>ATTACK RECOMMENCED.<lb/>MAGAZINE
                            EXPLODED.<lb/>JAPANESE SUCCESS</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, November 19,</dateline>
                            <p>General Stoessel telegraphs that all the assaults up to the 15th
                                inst. have been repulsed. (Havas)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>St. Petra, November 20</dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese recommenced the attack on Port Arthur on Thursday. They
                                destroyed the powder magazine</p>
                            <p>(Hayas.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Toxto, November 20</dateline>
                            <p>It is reported that the Japanese, after success fal mining, have
                                occupied the counterscarp of the Sang su-shan fort</p>
                            <p>(Reuters)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Toxin, November 20 </dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese Headquarters at Port Arthur report that a shell from a
                                naval gun exploded a magazine near the Arsenal yesterday. The
                                operations against all forts are proceeding as Previously arranged.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.<lb/>GOING TO VLADIVOSTOK.</head>
                        <dateline>Mukdes, November 19. </dateline>
                        <p>The Russian authorities consider that the Baltic Fleet, will sot be
                            handicapped by the capture of Port Arthur. Even should the fortress hold
                            out the fleet will, in any case, proceed to Vladivostok, as small hopes
                            are entertained of the effectiveness of the Port Artur fleet.
                            (Heuter)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BRITISH YACHT </head>
                        <p>Catarina left Alexandria this morning.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A POST AND TELEGRAPH OFFICE </head>
                        <p>was opened at Geteins on the 3rd November.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CLOT BET STREET, </head>
                        <p>Cairo, is now entirely blocked for the laying down of asphalt.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>QUARANTINE</head>
                        <p> restrictions against arrivals in Egyptian ports from Salaya have been
                            sup pressed</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AN INCENDIARY.</head>
                        <p>The servant of Teufik Bey Abd el-Kader, who is accused of setting his
                            aster's house on fire, at Shoubra, and there by causing loss and damage
                            equivalent to has been arfested.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA OPERA SEASON. </head>
                        <p>The Italian opers company for the operatic season at the Zizinis Theatre.
                            and Khedivial Opera House arrived at Alexauria trim Italy yesterday by
                            the Fiorg Kubatto steamier. The first perform ance will take place at
                            the Zazinis on Monday ext</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FIRES-</head>
                        <p>A fire broke out at 1 o'clock yester day morning at an Armenian
                            tabantonist's in Cd Bourse street. The Alexandria Fire Bri de promptly
                            extinguished the conflagra tion. The damage is estimated at 20. The
                            dontents of the shop were insured lor 12,000 fs. Another fire broke out
                            last night in a house at Kate Ashri, but was soon put out also.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUEZ CANAL </head>
                        <p>On the 17th inst, 15 vessels pad thigh the Suei Canal. Of these, s were
                            British, French, 1 Austrian, 1 Spanish, Turkish, FEgyptian, 1 German,
                            and I Danish: The transit and passenger dues -for the day anted to
                            409,683.30 frs. The total transit and passenger des collected from the
                            1st to that date on 209 vessels amounted to 01.04 f</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive left Cairo this morning for Mastash, where he is, spending the
                        day.. det by HE the Governor of Alexandria Hthe Khedive gave audience at
                        Abdeen Palin on Starday morning to Herr von Bal, Sir Willisen Willocks, the
                        Archbishop of Most Sinai, and the new Cadi Sheikh Abd Ryan Yoda, and in the
                        afternoon to Abd Hamid Abaza Effendi and Sheikh Bakri Abur and his son</p>
                    <p>On Saturday afternoon the Barl of Cromer printed to His Highness the mearbers
                        of the Railway Commission</p>
                    <p>On Sunday afternoon His Highness gave sidience to HE Imail Sabri Fashs and
                        Sir Wie Gestin, K.C.M.G.-</p>
                    <p>A on Buday HRH Prince George Duke of Brunswick-Launeberg and the Bal at
                        Cromer visited tim Khedive at Abdeen Palace. At 3.30 pm. His Highness
                        returned the visit, paling upon H.R.H. Prince George at Shepherd Hotel.</p>
                    <p>The Khere has bestowed the following ranks on the ulermentioned officials
                        Moutamala Malmond Choukry Bay, Chiet Clerk to the Khedivial Deligstion at
                        Constan tinople</p>
                    <p>Bunich Aly Ponad Effendi, attaché to the same delegation.</p>
                    <p>Gamal Nagin Effendi, second clerk to the same.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SABA-NAHAS WEDDING<lb/>A SPLENDID CEREMONY.<lb/>FULL DETAILS</head>
                    <p>The marriage of Miss Mary Saba, the daughter of the popalar
                        Postmaster-General of Egypt, to F. Nahas Bey, the great Syrian notable, wais
                        celebrated on Saturday evening with all the splendour and hospitality
                        befitting sach an auspicions social event in the history of Alexandria. The
                        ceremony has been looked forward to for many weeks past by the inha bitants
                        of Egypt's commercial capital, for the popularity of our worthy Postmaster
                        General is widespread, and the magnificence of the fete was Tally in
                        accordance with the high official rank of the family, whose hospitality on
                        this occasion will long be remembered. The invita tions had been sent out
                        for 9.30 p.m. and shortly after that hour the immediate neigh bourhood of
                        that part of Ramleh, where is the palatial residence of Saba Pasha, was
                        alive with a ceaseless procession of carriages bringing the wedding guests.
                        A large number of those invited came also from Alexandria, and cant less
                        tramloads of invités were despatched at intervals of a few minutes from the
                        city ter minus of the line to Halt 1, which is con- veniently situated in
                        proximity to the scene of the festivities.</p>
                    <p>THE ENTRY</p>
                    <p>The road leading to the residence of the Pasha was gorgeously illuminated and
                        bedeck ed with prettily arranged lamps, which gave a fairy-like aspect to
                        the impressive surround- ings. Before the portal giving access to the
                        mansion a great tent had been erected, draped with tastefully-arranged
                        curtains, where at cloak-room had been installed. The immediate approach to
                        the house is by a staircase of marble steps, leading to an entrance hall,
                        through which the guests passed to the great balcony, where a scene of
                        enchanting loveliness met their astonished gaze.</p>
                    <p>THE PAVILION.</p>
                    <p>From the balcony to the extreme end of the garden there stretched one huge
                        pavilion, completely composed of Arabie curtains The superficies, covered
                        was very extensive and the flooring consisted of fanumerable Oriental rugs.
                        This vast expanse was relieved by beautiful floral decorations, and
                        numberless tables and chairs had been set out for the convenience of the
                        guests. Throughout the end of this pavilion the supper buffets were spread,
                        and these were concealed by a gigantic curtain until after the wedding
                        ceremony had been gone through.</p>
                    <p>THE BRIDAL PROCESSION.</p>
                    <p>At 10 o'clock the guests had nearly all arrived and the scene, was animated.
                        in the extreme. The uniforms of the officers of the Army of Occupation and
                        of the naval officers: of the Greek Squadron, the exquisite dresses of the
                        ladies, and the general diversity of the gathering, contributed to make the
                        spectacle most brilliant and entrancing. The most in- teretting moment of
                        the evening was when the bridal procession issued from the house and
                        advanced slowly along the spacious balcony, while Professor D'Ambra's string
                        band struck up the entrancing strains of the Wedding March from Lohengrin.
                        This impressive cor tage was headed by gorgeously caparisoned Ravasses, who
                        were followed by a. group of the high pontiffs of the Syrian Greek Catholic
                        Melchite rite.</p>
                    <p>The magnificent vestments and elaborately decorated robes of these
                        ecclesiastics presented an admirable coup d'ail. Immediately behind the
                        Vicar-General, the archimandrites, and the priests, the bride followed,
                        leaning on the art of her father. She looked charming and her dress elicited
                        general admiration. Her long train was borne by a lovely little child,
                        garbed in blue.</p>
                    <p>The bridegroom followed, leaning on Ma dame Saba Pasha's arm. That lady's
                        dress was a creation in ivoire chiffon with appliques. A bevy of
                        bridesmaids, exquisitely dressed, follow- ed, led by Mr. Saba and Miss
                        Tagher, dark beauty in a pale blue dress. The cortège advanced down the
                        steps, while the guests silently and respectfully fell back to make way for
                        them. As the bridal procession came to wards the spot where the sacred
                        ceremony was to take place, a startling and beautiful effect was produced by
                        the sudden illumination of numberless electric lamps, which were
                        arranged</p>
                    <p>iis festoons.</p>
                    <p>THE MARRIAGE RITE </p>
                    <p>The actual ceremony was performed in Rocordance with the quaint and solemn
                        rites of the Syrian Greek Catholic Melchite Churche The rubric of this
                        ritual has been handed down from the Bysantine epoch, and the curique chants
                        and elaborate ceremonial are survivals from the earliest era of the Eastern
                        Church. In the absence of the Patriarch of the Syrian Greek Catholic
                        Melchite Church, His Holiness Kyrillos Goha, who is at present at Rome, the
                        marriage ceremony was conducted by the Right Reverend Kyrillos Risk: Vicar
                        General of the Patriarchate</p>
                    <p>THE SUPPER</p>
                    <p>After the ceremony the bride and, brides grooms and Saba Pasha and his wife
                        received the heartiest congratulations of all present. Ices and sweets were
                        then handed round. The bonbons were lavishly distributed among the guests,
                        elaborately arranged in Japanese tine paper tied with pink silk Javours At
                        11 o'clock the supper buffets were thrown open and an exquisite repast was
                        partaken of by all present</p>
                    <p>THE GUESTS. </p>
                    <p>Two thousand invitations had been issued for the marriage; and the throng of
                        welding got was very grist, bet owing to the enormous available space there
                        was no erish. <cb n="3"/> The Khedive was represented by Youssef Pasha Dia,
                        1st Aide-de-Camp to his Highness. Among those present were Prince Omar Pasha
                        Toussoms, Brig. General Bullock, C. B., and his staff, Mahmoud Pasha Sidky,
                        Governor of Alexandria (who had returned from Cairo that evening spesially
                        in order to be presept), M. Belinfante Ustberg, Diplomatic Agent and Consul
                        General for Sweden and Norway, M. Girard, French Consul, and Mme Girard,
                        Baron von Humboldt-Dachroeden, German Consal, Chevalier Pascarius,
                        Austro-Hungarian Consul, Hassan Pasha Mohsen, Liegt. Col. McCracken, Major
                        and Mrs. Gamble, Captain and Mrs Bingley, Captain and Mrs. Pinch, and the
                        officers of the 2nd Battalion Royal Berkshire Regiment, a number of officers
                        from the Hellenie Squadron, Dr. Raffer, Director-General of the Quarantine
                        Board, and, Mrs. Ruffer, Michalla Pasha, Sub-Director General of the Customs
                        Administration, and Mrs. Michalla, Mr. Am broise Ralli, Vice President of
                        the Alexandria Municipality, Mr. Chataway, Administrator of fie Alexandria
                        Municipality, and Mrs. Cha- taway, Mr. Debbane; Consul General for Brazil,
                        Miralai Hopkinson Bey, Commandant of the Alexandria City Police, and the
                        Hon. Mrs. Hopkinson, Zananiri Bey, Secretary-General of the Quarantine
                        Board, and Mrs. Zananiri, Peake Bey, Deputy Postmaster-General, and Mrs.
                        Peake, Dr. Szarvazy, Austro-Hungarisa Vice-Consul, Mr. Jas. Hewat, American
                        Consular Agent, Mr. Borchgrevink, Procureur-General, Mr.Sootidis, Hellenic
                        Consal-General, Hafez Bey Mohamed, Sub Governor of Alexandria, Dr. and Mrs.
                        Morrison, Dr. Gottschlich, Beneducci Bey, Secretary to the Gouvernorst, and
                        Mrs. Beneducci, Mr. and Mrs. G. B. and Miss Alderson, Mohamed Bey Said,
                        Chief of the Native Parquet, M. Reiny, Belgian Consul, Councillors of the
                        Alexandria Municipality, Jadges of the Mixed and Native Tribunals, and a
                        representative gathering of the crème de la crème of the English, Greek,
                        Jewish, German- and French colonies, besides all the leading representatives
                        of Syrian, Coptic, and native society in Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Gould, H.B.M.'s Consul General at Alexandria, was unable to be present
                        owing to a cold.</p>
                    <p>FLORAL TRIBUTES</p>
                    <p>One of the most remarkable features of this splendid ceremony was the
                        profusion and taste of the floral tributes Throughout the salons of the
                        mansion, all round the walls, festoons of exquisite garlands and wreaths of
                        flower were displayed. The effect was most enchanting. Mr. G. B. Alderson
                        let off fireworks about 10 p.m. in his garden in honour of the mar
                        riage.</p>
                    <p>The presents were both costly and numerous and included a vast quantity of
                        jewellery and gems.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR W. WILLCOCKS EXPEDITION. </head>
                    <p>As Sir William Willcocks has received per- mission from the Turkish
                        Government to exa- mine into the ancient irrigation system on the Tigris and
                        Euphrates, he is leaving to morrow for Bombay en route for Basra and Bagdad,
                        where he hopes to make a preliminary examina tion of the ground this
                        winter.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE COLD STORAGE CO.<lb/>PROGRESS AND PROSPECTS.</head>
                    <p>The reserve shares of the Nile Cold Storage Company have had a most
                        successful issue. They were, in fact, largely over applied for. The object
                        of this issue was in order to comply with the desires of the principal
                        share- holders-who are the largest consumers of perishable goods in this
                        country.</p>
                    <p>The capitalists requested that the company's operations should be extended,
                        and that it should deal in all perishable provisions, and not in meat alone.
                        The company therefore made the above mentioned issue in order to extend its
                        sphere of operations to meet the wishes of these gentlemen.</p>
                    <p>The Board of the Nile Cold Storage Com- pany has also decided to erect a cold
                        store at Alexandria on a much larger scale than the one already approaching
                        completion at Port Said. This Alexandria cold store will be suffi ciently
                        extensive to store all the provisions that the company will import and yet
                        will still have a large space which can be let out to merchants, hotel
                        proprietors, eto.</p>
                    <p>The cold store at Cairo will be completed this week, and already the first of
                        a weekly series of shipments of game, poultry, fish, butter, eggs, ete, is
                        en route and will arrive before the end of this month.</p>
                    <p>The capital of the company is only £50,000, so that the return on this small
                        capital should be large, especially in view of the fact that the largest
                        consumers are interested as share holders. 7</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAILWAY COMMISSION </head>
                    <p>The Railway Commission left Cairo this morning to examine the line between
                        Zagazig and Dessouk. The members will afterwarder go to Tantah, whence they
                        cothe on to Alexandria, arriving here at 6.20 p.m.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item" feature="theatre">
                    <head>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE </head>
                    <p>Last night, Hamlet, the French composer Thomas's most substantial production,
                        and Mignon, his most genial, were given at the Alhambra and Abbas Helmy
                        Theatre, respect ively. The perfomance of the latter was frantically
                        applauded. The representation was from every point of view excellent. Signs.
                        Monti Baldini fully justified the celebrity which she has acquired on the
                        European stage. It would be dithenit indeed to find a more graceful and
                        perfect Mignon. The prima donna was well seccoded by the tenor Tomiani; who
                        made. his debut last night and met with con alegable access. The other
                        artisten wore all good in their respective roles, while the or chestra
                        worked wonders</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREEK FLEET'S VISIT.</head>
                    <p>FAREWELL RECEPTION</p>
                    <p>The members of the Hellenic Club organised on Saturday afternoon a farewell
                        reception to Commodore Coundouriotis and staff and the officers of the Greek
                        Fleet at 5 o'clock. They were received by the president, Mr. M. Sina dino,
                        surrounded by the other members of the club. A great many members of the
                        Greek community were present, including Mr. and Mrs. E. Benachi, Mr. and
                        Mrs. M. Salvago, Mr. and Mrs. Alex. Benachi, Mr. and Mrs. Delta Mr. and Mrs.
                        N. Sinadino, Dr. and Mrs. Valas- sopoulo: Dancing took place to the strains
                        of the band of the Greek Philharmonic Society and of the flagship Psara.</p>
                    <p>The proceedings opened by Mr. M. Sinadino proposing the health of the Greek
                        Fleet, which was received with the greatest enthusiasm: In his speech, Mr.
                        Sinadino, on behalf of the meinbers of the club and the Greek community
                        generally, wished the officers and men God- speed on the continuation of
                        their cruise. He asked Commodore Coundouriotis to convey to H. M. the King
                        of the Hellenes the thanks of the community for having sent the fleet to
                        these waters, and expressed the hope, shared by one and all, that this
                        pleasant visit would be the forerunner of others equally pleasant.</p>
                    <p>Commodore Coundouristis then thanked Mr. Sinadino and the entire community
                        for the very cordial reception which had been extended to the Fleet during
                        its stay here. He said he would have the greatest pleasure in conveying the
                        wish of the community to his Majesty that a return visit might be paid. He
                        only hoped that next time they came they would be stronger in numbers.</p>
                    <p>Other speakers followed, including M. Gen- nadis, Diplomatie Agent and
                        Consul-General, who also thanked Mr. Sinadino,and the bers of the club for
                        the manner in which they had entertained the Fleet, and wished the
                        Commodore, his officers, and men "bon voyage. The greatest animation
                        prevailed up to a late hour, dancing being engaged in up to 11 p.m.</p>
                    <p>DINNER PARTY.</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Em. Benachi subsequently gave a dinner party at their residence
                        in the Greek quarter to the departing Commodore and officers. Amongst the
                        guests were Mr. Gerandis, Hellenie Diplomatie. Agent, Mr. N. Seotidis,
                        Consul General, and the leading members of the Hellenic community, viz., Mr.
                        and Mrs. M. Sinadino, Mr. and Mrs. M. Sal- vago, Mr. and Mrs. 8. Delta, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Alex. Benachi, and Mr. G. Zervudachi. After dinner a reception
                        followed at which nearly, all of Hellenic society was present. Dancing
                        continued until the early bours of the morning. </p>
                    <p>MASS ON BOARD.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday morning, Mass was celebrated on board the Spetzai, at which about a
                        hundred civilians assisted. These were afterwards enter tained by Capt.
                        Caloyanni and his officers-</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURE OF FLEET</p>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon, the harbour of Alex- andria, on the occasion of the
                        departure of the fleet, was the scene of unwonted movement and animation.
                        Early in the afternoon large numbers of people collected on the quay and
                        sailed out in small boats to witness from near the departure of the ships. A
                        small steamer be longing to Mr. Minotto was also kindly lent to carry the
                        members of the committee of re- ception, besides a quantity of other people
                        and the band of the Philharmonic society. At about 3.30 p.m. the Hydra
                        weighed anchor and commenced to steam slowly out of the harbour. Her
                        departure was greeted with loud and prolonged cheers, the band of the
                        Philharmonie playing the Greek Anthem, as well as the band of the warship.
                        As the Hydra steamed towards the entrance of the harbour, she was followed
                        by Mr. Minotto's steamer and in- numerable small sailing boats, crammed with
                        enthusiastic and excited crowds, who greeted the departure of the vessel
                        with continued and repeated cheers. On the steam launch we remarked, besides
                        the Diplomatic repre sentative of Greece, M. Gennadis, and the
                        Consul-General, M. Scotidis, all the leading members of the Greek colony
                        here, M. E Benschi, M. M. Sinadino, M. &amp; Salvago, M. G. Zervudachi, M.
                        J. Cartalis,and many others, most also with their wives and children. The
                        enthusiasm and excitement manifested on the launch were great. Mr. Minotto
                        himself climb ed on to one of the masts and saluted from thence the
                        departing ship. When the Hydra reiched the entrance of the harbour, the
                        accompanying steamer and boats returned, and in like manner escorted the
                        warship Spetsi out of the harbour. The flagship Psara was the last to leave,
                        amidst an uproar of cheers, shouting, waying of hats, and, the playing of
                        music.</p>
                    <p>The beautiful weather added to thebright hess and animation of the scene, and
                        it being a Sunday afternoon, large numbers of the working classes also had
                        collected to witness the departure. It may be remarked that the Greek
                        colony, as on all preceding occa afons, also manifested on this final one
                        that patriotism and enthusiasm regarding their fleet which cannot but
                        impress the observer, and prove to him the close and powerful ties which
                        exist between the mother country, Greece pro- per, and the rich and powerful
                        Greek colony in Bgypt.</p>
                    <p>It may be remarked that throughout the whole stay of the fleet here, there
                        has not been cited a single example of disorderly or bad confuet among the
                        Greek sailors when in the town, a fact which reflects the highest credit on
                        the discipline and good conduct both of the officers and men.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday evening, at the Greek Club here most of the leading members of the
                        Greek colony met and discussed the means of raising the sum which is to be
                        contributed towards the fleet.</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAL AT FORT SAID </p>
                    <p>Port Said, Monday-The Greek Squadron has arrived. The ships were welcomed by
                        enthusiastic crowds on launches and on the breakwater</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET<lb/>DATE OF ARRIVAL</head>
                    <p>The ships of the Baltic Fleet.are expected to arrive at Port Said on
                        Wednesday next,</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL BERKS</head>
                    <p>Two companies of the 2nd Battalion Boyal Berkshire Regiment, left to-day for
                        Abonkir, where they will camp out for a week's training</p>
                    <p>The three companies of the regiment which are going to Cairo, will leave on
                        December 2, by the troop train which will have brought the 20th Hussars to
                        Alexandris for embarkation. The approximate strength of the three com-
                        panies is 330 men. They will be quartered at Abbassieh</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL AGRICULTURAL SOCIETY</head>
                    <p>With regard to the agreement to be come to between the Government and the K.
                        A. S., we understand that its terms are now drawn up and will shortly be
                        submitted to a meeting of the society.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The Canard SS. Cypria sailed yesterday for Liverpool with full cargo of
                        4,605, bales cotton, 846 tons cotton seed, etc.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>FREEMASONRY AT TANTAH.</head>
                    <p>A very interesting ceremony took place on Saturday evening at Tantah, namely,
                        the consegration of a new Masonic lodge under the English Constitution. This
                        lodge is passed the Delta No. 3060 W. Bro: Langley, of the DG. L of Egypt
                        and the Sadan, assisted by W, Bros Clifton, Delanoy, Lambton, Ablitt and
                        Bent, most worthily carried out this in- teresting ceremony. The brethren
                        from the Alexandria lodges turned up in strong force to assist in giving
                        this, the youngest, lodge in Egypt under the English Constitution a hearty
                        start.</p>
                    <p>After the ceremony a banquet was held in the Pelta Railway Institute, kindly
                        lent for the occasion.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>MIXED TRIBUNAL</head>
                    <p>The technical commission for the revision of the Codes as applied to the
                        Mixed Tribunals, and reforms in the working of certain branches of these
                        tribunals, has begun its sittings at the Mixed Tribunals, under the
                        presidency of Boutros Pasha Ghali, Minister for Foreign Affairs.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUARANTINE</head>
                    <p>Quarantine is imposed in Egyptian ports on ships having left Aden since the
                        13th inst.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item" feature="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS</head>
                    <p>ARRIVALS</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot Tebe de la Cie Florio Rubattino arrivé hier de Gènes avait à
                        bord:</p>
                    <p>Le marquis Salvago Raggi, E Isnardi, Pacho, M. et A. Miani, D. d'Anton,
                        Quartars, Bondi, cap. Schneider, Wernon et son fils, Sheppard, Parkes et
                        Lang, Ryan, Birdwood, M. et Mme B. Zecheri, Uggetti, Mile Bminente,
                        Anderson, Esvalls, Casossi, Morters, A. Viola, Zoughton, Dikran et sa mère,
                        A. Mouti, Mathilde Naus et Co, Ugo Lombando et saurs, lat. Bamard, E Figari
                        et son fils, A. Bensilum, Lasi et tam, Anna Unter, Torella e fam. Figari,
                        Palla viging, av. A. Morters, et 30, pasagers de 3me classe..</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot Bofors, arrivé hier de Venise avait à bord:</p>
                    <p>M. et Mile N. Syrigo, M. et Mnie C Pardo, baron &amp; de Merope et fam, Me
                        Manusardi, A. Liuni, Pannal, Comp. Gianol, Emma Co lonna, baron A. de
                        Menasce, Mme Acavalos, De Hanghy et sa dame, K-Figari, Vogel, Marta
                        Lindemann, Mme Sinmoth, Herr Woolf, Amelia Kommel, Me Rossi et sa fam.,
                        Silvio Fabbris, Colucci et a dame, Cie Dame Viennes, Thorn et tam, C. Monni
                        et sa dame, Silvio Ramazzotti, G. Zuccani et 80 passagers de 3ma classe Le
                        paquebot Habsburg du Lloyd Autrichien arrivé ce matin de Trieste avait à
                        bordi M. Gelse, Mme Schriffes, Me Rundt, Brioni, Mine Constantinidis, is
                        fille et Nice ladi, Sehway et 1 comp, de Montag, Orninger, Tamarky, Dragits,
                        Caravopoulos, Havodynsky, Klenier, Mateer, Me Rapps et swear, Fischer,
                        Agilla et 1 bébé, Mme Baila, 2 comp, et 1 bébé, Cap Gelletich, Spitzer,
                        Fowler, Mine Steinbach, Mme Stein, Paravicini, Hehake, Molteul, Dr. Faller,
                        Mme Hanson, Gessler, dom. et 1 bébé, Pantaleo, Ehrlich, Mme Heller,
                        Squarding, Muller, Thomoe, et sa fille, M. Homer, &amp; Heiber, Stieglitz et
                        2 enfants, A.La Denners, Mie Kingham, 2 enfants et dom, A. Miller, Dr F.
                        Hagel Bey, M. et Mme Kyan, Carlo Waiter, M. et Mme Weekes, M. et Mme Revel,
                        Mme Cattaui bey et sa fille, M. Cattaul Bay, Prince Ibrahim Hilmi et 8 de
                        fam, Mine Wegermann et 2 de fam, M. on Mme A Cattani, Kaufmann, Dr Wengler,
                        M. Weil, Schmidt, Vogel, M. et Mme Pittack, Mayer. bebé et gouv., Liepmann,
                        sa dame et 3 enfants Johnson Pacha, Spreafico et à de fam es 46 passagers de
                        3me classe</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURES</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot Semiramis, du Lloyd Autri chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait à
                        bord: MM. Rud. Patienhofer, Mma Goldalees Aram d'Ambro, Gewinner, B.
                        Springer, Wiese, C. Moer, Blas, Frita Pam, Milos Kaisler, Paal His, Marco
                        Mattatia et 22 passagers de 3me classe.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advert">
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA 8. PER BAY, WINE INCLUDED</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="notesHelouan">
                    <head>NOTES FROM HELOUAN</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Grand Hotel, Helaa A lange number of di having arrived there
                            lately.</p>
                        <p>Col. She</p>
                        <p>Amongst the guests staying at this hotel we notice Lady Bisset and
                            daughte W. Bisset, RE KC.SI, th Calthorpe, MH.N.P.Shaw Mrs. Birley Mr.
                            S. G, Fildes Alexandre Tilche M H</p>
                        <p>W. Niemeksa Mr. and Mr. Taming and Mrs Spearman, Max Hart Bey, Capt Mrs.
                            Leetham, Mrs. and the Misses Golloc Mr. A. B. Middleton, Mr and Mr Herr
                            Schwer Mr. S. Manuel Halifax and MP. Suares</p>
                        <p>Sydne</p>
                        <p>Rev. R. H. Longley arrived a few days? at the Grand Hotel, Helouan, and
                            ha over the chaplaincy of Helouan for the coming winter. The first
                            Anglican Church service held there yesterday,</p>
                        <p>The golf professional has arrived at Halguan and is in attendance at the
                            golf links of the Grand Hotel, which are now in splendid con- dition</p>
                        <p>For golfers we recommend the combined. return first-class railway
                            tickets, including lunch at the Grand Hotel, at PT. 20 ch. They are now
                            also to be had at the offices of the Anglo-American Nile Steamer and
                            Hotel Company. They give free access to the golfe links and golf house
                            of the Grand Hotel</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="section" feature="letters">
                    <p>LETTER TO THE EDITOR</p>
                    <p>We do not hold ou</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NILE BOILER EXPLOSION.</head>
                        <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZNITE </p>
                        <p>Dear Six-Having read in your esteemed journal a few days ago of a boiler
                            explosion, which occurred on a steamer lying nose Kate el-Nil Bridge,
                            Cairo, which resulted in the loss: of several lives; I would like
                            through the mediam of this paper to enquire why the boilers and engines
                            of river steamers are not put under compulsory inspection by the Pablio
                            Works Department, seeing that boilers and engines on land are under
                            compulsory super vision of the Department.</p>
                        <p>To the man in the street this appears a most absurd arrangement as it
                            stands at prest To say nothing of the very apparent ty for official
                            inspection of boilers and engines of river craft, it is a well known
                            fade to engineers engaged in repairing such steamers, that there are a
                            considerable number of steamers (if snol they can be called) working on
                            the Nile, that are, with respect to their boilers, a greater menage to
                            those who are employed on them and to any craft, that come near them,
                            than any floating mine yet designed. The writer knows the existence of
                            small craft on the Nile which are equipped with boilers the age of which
                            must be sought for in the long-forgotten past. Surely our Government in
                            Brypt can put their foot firmly, down now and demand the compulsory
                            inspection of these craft by competent and responsible officials.</p>
                        <p>According to statements appearing in the local papers since the disaster,
                            she boiler which exploded recently had been subjected to an overhaul a
                            short time before, but this does not do away with the necessity for
                            inspection. F think I may say that the owners of river steamers
                            themselves should be the first to wel come official inspection, and
                            morally speaking so they should do both for their own intereste and the
                            interests of those employed on them and who travel on them.</p>
                        <p>I sincerely hope this incident will be the mes of drawing public
                            attention and the attention of the Government to the immediate necessity
                            of placing river steamers under com pulsory inspection.</p>
                        <p>Yours truly,</p>
                        <dateline>Cairo, November 20</dateline>
                        <byline>Bons TER</byline>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. F. DAVIDSON Ophthalmic Optician,</p>
                    <p>of 140, Great Portland Breet, London, 9 eacher of Sight Testing and author of
                        "Sight Testing for the Medical Practitioner,Befraction Work," te.. May be
                        consulted for</p>
                    <p>SPECTACLES</p>
                    <p>at the HOTEL ABBATE for a</p>
                    <p>Short Time Only. Mr. DAVIDSON is the inventor of many of the latest
                        appliances for dealing with Defective Vision</p>
                    <p>And cordially invites all medical men to op them and to teak their practical
                        utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 19.30 and 2 to 6.</p>
                    <p>Mr DAVIDSON'S latest invention patented) is a new SUN GLASS, which bsolutely
                        prevents any of the Bl effects of Sun Glare.,</p>
                    <p>04019 8-4-1</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advert">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>Bulkalay, Ramlah</p>
                    <p>Newly</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DERNIERE HSURE</head>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                    <p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL. qui en feront la demande pourront accom</p>
                    <p>The widows of the late Khedive Ismail arriv. ed at Cairo yesterday morning
                        from Constanti nople.</p>
                    <p>The correspondent of the Times at Rome writing on the 9th inst., pays the
                        following</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER, 21, 1904</p>
                    <p>pagner le Mabmal. Les pèlerins qui suivront e tapis sacré se trouveront dans
                        les meilleures conditions de confort, d'écono- mie et de sécurité
                        désirables.</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui voudront accompa gner le Mabmal et profiter de ces avants-
                        ges devront en faire is demande à leur 4ouvernorat ou mon lirich an mois
                        su</p>
                    <p>21 novembre</p>
                    <p>Trieste et Brindisi; 61 h, vapaute. Habsburg, esp. Klaneberger, son: $42, an
                        Lloyd Antishies. Newle: 16j 1,2 ap. ang. Heldswell, cap Willes, ton. 1609,
                        &amp; Barber &amp; Son. Manchester es Malte4j. 1/3vap sog Grecian Prince,
                        cap Claridge, tom. 1405, &amp; Grace &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>moins avant le départ, c'est-à dire avant le STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>tribute to Sir Bennell Rodd: "Very great regret is felt in all quarters here
                        at the depart 31 décembre prochain et effectuer un dépôt ure of Sir Rennell
                        Rodd, the new Minister at te L.E. 25 en première classe, 22 en deu-
                        Stockholm, who leaves Rome to-morrow. Dur xième classe, 18 en troisième
                        classe. Ce ing his three years' service as Secretary of the arif est convenu
                        poar i chamead seale- Embassy, he has gained, not only the respectment. La
                        location de tout chameau supplé bat also the affection of all who have come
                        in mentaire sera comptée en plus à raison de contact with him; and this has
                        been partien L.E.13 1/2 en première classe. Ea troisième, larly the case
                        with the Italian official world, deas pèlerina s'arrangent pour voyager who
                        have always had for him a very high and vee un seul chameau, ils psieront
                        chacun 12 L.E. Si ces sommes n'ont pas été inté- alement dépensées pour le
                        compte da pèlerin, le surplus lui sera remboursé après soa retour.</p>
                    <p>marked esteem.</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. Hashim, chef de bureau of the Public Security Department at the
                        Alexandria Gou vernorat, has been promoted to the post of chef de bureau at
                        the Ministry of Interior.</p>
                    <p>QUESTIONS MUNICIPALES</p>
                    <p>Cloring Friese, to-day at 1 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Debenture</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>COPER DE LA DEPECHS DE L'ALEXANDRIA GENERAL PRODUCE</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL COTTON A880CIATION.</p>
                    <p>(Coare pentiquée se jour à la Bourse Khódiviale 108.15's m.)</p>
                    <p>-5 15 21.83 Livesison Novembre</p>
                    <p>$ 15 2/89</p>
                    <p>$15 25/32</p>
                    <p>Marché quist</p>
                    <p>Janvier Marn</p>
                    <p>Krivage d'oier et la ce jour, à Minet-el-Bassal .85,786</p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khédiviale 19h.45 p.m.)</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>BANKS Imperial Ovomen Beak... Nations! Bank of Egypt... New Insas 28
                        15:16</p>
                    <p>$ 15 1/3</p>
                    <p>$15 21/33</p>
                    <p>Marché quiet</p>
                    <p>24 5/16 Fos. 488 L.E. 1 ex Fos. 295</p>
                    <p>Fem. 1000</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui suivent le Mahmal LE. 56 et effectuent les dépôts ci-dessus
                        sont dis- pensées des autres formalités, excepté pour-518 sant du passeport
                        qui est toujours de igueur.</p>
                    <p>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demi).</p>
                    <p>Le marché des valeurs se maintient ferme et en hausse.</p>
                    <p>A</p>
                    <p>Il manquait à notre Municipalité, pour être complète, un corps de police
                        spécial Cette lacune, à peine signalée, vient d'être comblée. Déjà la
                        Délégation et le Gouver- norat se sont occupés da nombre et du salaire de ce
                        noavesa personnel. Il ne reste plus qu'à soumettre la proposition à la La
                        Banque Nationale atteint en clôture Commission Municipale. Quelles vont être
                        les attributions de cette police indépen- 24 5/16, la Wardan 7 7/8, la
                        Brasserie des dante, de cet Etat dans l'Etat, nous avons Pyramides 182, les
                        Markets 27, les Eaux en soin de le demander. Si nos informa d'Alexandrie 16
                        15/16, les Eaux du Caire tions sont exsictes, ce corps est destiné à 1090,
                        les Privilégiés Tramways 146 1/2 prêter main forte sax percepteurs munici-et
                        les Dividendes 385. psax, en ce qui concerne en particulier Is Saxe du 20/0.
                        Cet impôt que le contribu- able sisé paie sans difficulté, le pauvre est
                        obligé quelquefois de le refuser. C'est à quoi va servir la nouvelle police.
                        Les dé</p>
                    <p>bria de meubles de es malheureux seront vendus séance tenante et toutes les
                        mesures de rigueur qui sont permises par la loi, impitoyablement
                        appliquées.</p>
                    <p>Après avoir décroché de nouveau le prix de 40, la Salt &amp; Sods est
                        retombée in elóture à 39/6.</p>
                    <p>La Bébéra fléchit légèrement à 56, les Press Libres à 28 1/2,
                        l'Anglo-American</p>
                    <p>Nile à 5 1/4, et la Delta Light à 15 5/16.</p>
                    <p>Comme à ce trait on reconnait bien Anglo-Egyptian Spinning &amp; Weaving
                        Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>l'esprit qui anime notre Municipalité! Bi</p>
                    <p>cette conduite odieuse pouvais augmenter</p>
                    <p>de façon notable les recettes de la ville,</p>
                    <p>passe encore. Mais cette armée de pereep-</p>
                    <p>'ASSEMBLEE GENERALE ORDINAIRE.</p>
                    <p>th. 8916 F. 108 #1716.</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Grece...</p>
                    <p>Banque Industrielle Crédit Foncier Egyption Lottery Bonda</p>
                    <p>Sis 19 82 Livaison Novembre Janvier Mors</p>
                    <p>21 novembre:</p>
                    <p>EXTERIEUR</p>
                    <p>Déplebee parienes de 19 novembre 1904 PRODUITS GYPTIONS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOG Coton: Bial da Marahi-Satan Disponibis: Berde: iame sure Pature
                        déoscabre :8 9/84 (4/94 de baie) LIVERPOOK</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton-Sano changement Frus-Peu d'affaires</p>
                    <p>Grainas de coton-Mane cours Frees-Calme</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Fermes</p>
                    <p>Graine de colon From-Harebé nal</p>
                    <p>COTON.AMERICAIN LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Fates janvige-févrise: 5.21 (1 point de bias)</p>
                    <p>msi-jain: 5 31 (1 point de baisso Disponible: 5.82 († points de paises)</p>
                    <p>NEW YORK</p>
                    <p>Middling Upland: 1301 mm 001 Fame Jeur-$45,6 poias de baisse)</p>
                    <p>Marché de Minet-el-Bassal</p>
                    <p>21 novembre 1904-(11h.56 a.m.) Cotons: Cloare da marché da 19 novembre: Moins
                        d'affaires</p>
                    <p>BRUKERS</p>
                    <p>Fair. Fally Fair, Good Fair, Fully Good Pai- et Good: Très calme</p>
                    <p>ZAUTH-RAPPTE E FATOUM</p>
                    <p>Fair et Fully Fair: Bien. Good Pair, Fally Good Pair of Good: Très calme</p>
                    <p>Sme quali 6,Ire qualité, Extra: Calme JANNOVION</p>
                    <p>me quali, Ire qualité, Extra: Calme</p>
                    <p>Bu da marebé de ce jour, cot: Moins de demande prix faible..</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages d'hier et de ce jour se chiffren par mamare 69,149 coatre mème
                        jour l'année précé- dente canters 78,088.</p>
                    <p>LONDON STOCK EXCHANGE</p>
                    <p>8 13 Government</p>
                    <p>ABARST</p>
                    <p>EXCHANGE QUOTATION</p>
                    <p>London abeque</p>
                    <p>Bin-back paper Shogun papee</p>
                    <p>Paris obeque</p>
                    <p>8m. bank 8- hoge Switzerland Germany</p>
                    <p>Imlian cheque pape</p>
                    <p>Vienne &amp; Priva Joarantinople obeque..</p>
                    <p>479</p>
                    <p>SHARE LIST</p>
                    <p>ISSUED BY THE "ASSOCIATION DES COURTIE VALNUSS D'AGETANDRIN".</p>
                    <p>Lai: 11-</p>
                    <p>agypian Del Bul. exo... 51,4</p>
                    <p>#11-</p>
                    <p>Agris. Bank</p>
                    <p>LAND, &amp;c. Agris-Industrielle Beypt Fond</p>
                    <p>420 900</p>
                    <p>4-834</p>
                    <p>Behera Company... Egyptian Deln Land Co.</p>
                    <p>7.78</p>
                    <p>Wardan Briate Ocy.</p>
                    <p>61/4</p>
                    <p>Mai: 990 &amp; pointe la asissa Arrivages du jour: bile 43030 Contre m4ms in
                        Pen - 16 Pointer: balles 525,00 contre balles 335,000</p>
                    <p>Coons Oricines</p>
                    <p>83.11</p>
                    <p>Closure d'aujourd'hui</p>
                    <p>1a. 45 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Agria. Bank of Beyps</p>
                    <p>Land &amp; Morgage..</p>
                    <p>Nat Back Bype</p>
                    <p>21 5/8</p>
                    <p>80 1.</p>
                    <p>498 1/3</p>
                    <p>56</p>
                    <p>Pes. 238</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>151</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>New Daira Banish Fond. COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL Alex. Bonded Storse Pref.
                        Anglo-Egypt.Spinning Co. Boures Kaldivials pref. Cairo Sewage Trans- [port
                        Ord. Cr. Brewery, Alex., Fond. do 8%. Deba. do Cairo Fond.</p>
                    <p>129</p>
                    <p>Baalen sailway</p>
                    <p>frainwaye d'Alexandrie Fos. 45 1/2</p>
                    <p>147</p>
                    <p>41</p>
                    <p>div. 885</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>Alersadria Water</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>61 185 600 72</p>
                    <p>Prices on Tuesday, November 15, 1904, Console a/e...</p>
                    <p>Lais 15 15/16</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>dex da chire</p>
                    <p>Fe-: 1085-</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Dala sanish</p>
                    <p>Lot 31 58</p>
                    <p>Console Cash...</p>
                    <p>88 19 93 14</p>
                    <p>G</p>
                    <p>-113 -Sp</p>
                    <p>décem</p>
                    <p>LK. 55-8/4</p>
                    <p>514</p>
                    <p>dourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>Let 23 1/3</p>
                    <p>Egyptian 4% Uaifel 105-</p>
                    <p>&lt;-13</p>
                    <p>Byptian Markets.</p>
                    <p>871</p>
                    <p>4 114 Seats....</p>
                    <p>Sh. 7/9 Sh. 17</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton Mills</p>
                    <p>Angio Egyptina Spinning</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>Domain -104-</p>
                    <p>105-</p>
                    <p>do Markete</p>
                    <p>dière d'Alexandre Priv. Fos.: 33</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>Di</p>
                    <p>do Salt and Boda Fond</p>
                    <p>Prof. D -99 48</p>
                    <p>100-13</p>
                    <p>Ciments d'Egypte</p>
                    <p>da Uaire</p>
                    <p>Priv.</p>
                    <p>www www</p>
                    <p>34 Ias ribed</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>Div.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Syndicate... B.</p>
                    <p>4% Dairs 1980. xD 100</p>
                    <p>101</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>9 7/16 82</p>
                    <p>Kafr-el-Zayst Coston Coy. 109 New Bgyptian Company... Nangovich Hotels</p>
                    <p>Tarlosh 4% Uni-d</p>
                    <p>85 914</p>
                    <p>98.1</p>
                    <p>Sat &amp; doda</p>
                    <p>Granos de coton.-Pea de demande</p>
                    <p>Anerine God. 4.99 19</p>
                    <p>100 It</p>
                    <p>Promage</p>
                    <p>Disponible</p>
                    <p>Ticket</p>
                    <p>French 8% Banter...</p>
                    <p>87-</p>
                    <p>Presses Libe</p>
                    <p>Bouidé des Hailerice at</p>
                    <p>Mit-A-Baisse 10/40</p>
                    <p>Bian</p>
                    <p>German 3% 1898-</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>Oong. Uréfis Foncier</p>
                    <p>[Savon.</p>
                    <p>Haute-Brypto-Bisse 10,40</p>
                    <p>Bign</p>
                    <p>Greek 5% 1881</p>
                    <p>46 12</p>
                    <p>47-1</p>
                    <p>2612 18 13</p>
                    <p>Ind. de Karmons Presenge at Dépôte 102 Prosse Labres...</p>
                    <p> 5%</p>
                    <p>Fes. 94-</p>
                    <p>Blés-Petite demande</p>
                    <p>Italian 5% 188</p>
                    <p>118 84</p>
                    <p>104:1</p>
                    <p>Lum Paros et talon</p>
                    <p>125-</p>
                    <p>Qualité Satdi: Cond. Sahs P.T. 118 &amp; 180</p>
                    <p>Besan 4% Oon, 1889</p>
                    <p>93 114</p>
                    <p>438</p>
                    <p>109</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS.</p>
                    <p>Bihira Fives-Néant</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>n</p>
                    <p>116 139</p>
                    <p>Japan 5%</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>fja</p>
                    <p>#8-114</p>
                    <p>16 16 16 For..1090</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amer. Nile &amp;c. Co. Khedivial Mail S.S. ho. [Co. Fonds. 14/6 Alex.
                        Water Company Cairo Fonds. Tanish " "Fonds. BAILWAYS &amp; TRAMWAYS</p>
                    <p>Baldi-Bien</p>
                    <p>United States 4% 1945 x D 18: Daira Shaish</p>
                    <p>Saqas In laasrielle</p>
                    <p>184-</p>
                    <p>Jasa di socato</p>
                    <p>LS. 14 Fos.247</p>
                    <p>244</p>
                    <p>814</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amaha Nole</p>
                    <p>La 55-16</p>
                    <p>198</p>
                    <p>183-</p>
                    <p>of dam</p>
                    <p>For 181 3/4</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>National Bank.</p>
                    <p>112</p>
                    <p>Jeferred Dela</p>
                    <p>Let 17 14</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>Now...</p>
                    <p>718</p>
                    <p>938</p>
                    <p>650</p>
                    <p>88/4</p>
                    <p>Agricultural Banks</p>
                    <p>8% Bonds 73 pd 103</p>
                    <p>P.- #15 5/16</p>
                    <p>Basse Egypt, Fonds..... Delta Light..</p>
                    <p>195</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>COTON</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>do do Def.......</p>
                    <p>17 88</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>Cond. Baba P.T. 70 &amp; 78</p>
                    <p>Delta Leads 5-paid...</p>
                    <p>Cairo-Helona...</p>
                    <p>07</p>
                    <p>Exportation du mois d'octobre 1904.</p>
                    <p>Deferre...</p>
                    <p>Fayoum: disponible: Rin</p>
                    <p>Qualité Baldi: Cond. Baba P.T. 97 &amp; 92 Lentilles-Stationnaires</p>
                    <p>Disponible: Bien</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saba P.T. 82 &amp; 95</p>
                    <p>Orges: Bant ohangement</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. 50 &amp; 54 Mate: Mome allure Disponible: Bian</p>
                    <p>Delta Preference</p>
                    <p>Deferred......</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>Preferred..... 9718</p>
                    <p>104</p>
                    <p>igypting Joston Mille Lat</p>
                    <p>Banque Nat de Grice az.o... 482</p>
                    <p>Nangorina Hol</p>
                    <p>Dele Land</p>
                    <p>teurs civile, flu quée d'une armée de poi</p>
                    <p>Fayoum... Keach-Assocan.</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>480</p>
                    <p>do Foods 985</p>
                    <p>Messieurs les actionnaires sont convoqués. siers, occasionners des frais plus
                        considé-en Assemblée Générale Ordinaire le Lundi.98 814 rables que le
                        produit des taxes même. N 12 Décembre prochain à 5 h. de relevée. 148 1/3
                        Alexandria Trans... serait-il pas plus économique en me ne dans les locaux
                        de la National Bank of temps que plas humanitaire, sinon d'exo-Egypt à
                        Alexandrie. nérer de la taxe ces malheureux payant un faible loyer, du moins
                        de laisser les choars en l'état où elles sont ?</p>
                    <p>Nous connaissons trop malheureusement les tendances de nos conseillers pour
                        douter un moment qu'ils ne snetionnent Is me- sure proposé par la
                        Délégation. Ils ont tonjours déployé beaucoup de cèl pour la perception des
                        impôs et s'ils avaient montré la même rigu ur dans l'adminis- tration des
                        dépenses, ils ne mériteraient que des éloges.</p>
                    <p>ORDRE DU JOUR:</p>
                    <p>Rapport du onseil d'Administration, Approbation des comptes,</p>
                    <p>Election des censeurs.</p>
                    <p>Les porteurs d'actions devront, pour prendre part à l'assemblée, déposer
                        leurs actions 3 jours au moins avant la réunion dans une des Banques
                        ci-après désignées au Caire ou à Alexandrie.</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Egypt, Crédit Lyon nais, Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ld., Banque
                        Impétale Ottomane, Bank of Egypt Ld, on an Siège de la Compagnie à
                        Liverpool, 17, Sweeting Street.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 21 Novembre 1904 Le Président,</p>
                    <p>Nous aurons done une police municipale C'est une affaire entendae et qui sera
                        décidée à l'unanimité comme l'a été l'exelu- sion de la presse des séances,
                        comme va l'être bientôt le renvoi de la question des maisons ouvrières aux
                        calendes grecques. Au moins nous sera-t-il permis de suggérer A notre
                        Municipalité une oeupation plas utile pour cette police que la poursuite de
                        malheureux, nous voulons dire la mise en The Khedivial Mail Steamship
                        vigueur d'un système de poids et meenree</p>
                    <p>24931-8-1</p>
                    <p>ELWIN PALMER.</p>
                    <p>poinçonnés, fabriqués par l'Etat et délivrés and Graving Dock Company,
                        Limited.</p>
                    <p>aux marchands contre le prix de facture, Ce serait rendre aux pauvres un peu
                        de NOTICE IS HEREBY GIVEN that the cette justio qui leur est cons'amment re-
                        fusée que d'obliger ainsi los détaillants à Seventh Ordinary General Meeting
                        of the lede livrer le poids exact. Les bacals, les above Company, will be
                        held at Winchester marchands de légumes et de poissons, les House, Old Broad
                        Street, London, E C., boulang ra, las boashses, eta on, en eff, on Monday,
                        28th day of November, 1904, des poids inférieurs de 15 20 0/0 su paid at
                        noon; to receive and pass the Directors' 16gal. Ainsi le pauvre n'est pas
                        seulement Report and Accounts, to elect Directors vistime de la négligence
                        des autorités on ad Auditors, and to transact the ordinary ee qui regarde le
                        servies des quartiers, business of the Company.. l'embelissement et
                        l'assainissement, il est ensors volé sur la qualité et la quantité de s
                        nourriture et cela par la coupable in- carie de la Municipalité.</p>
                    <p>La elese aiség mit et peut faire res-</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, the 21st November, 1904. 24,935-1</p>
                    <p>peeter ses droits, andis que le pauvre reste MOUVEMENT MARITIME</p>
                    <p>Impaisant; et la Municipalité, sa ieu de lui venir en side dans ce qu ses
                        reven li estions peuvent avoir de légitime, s'on- cupe uniquement de le
                        pres-arer pour en obtenir jusqu'à la dernière piastre.</p>
                    <p>Le pelerinage de 1905 Le ministère de l'Intérieur vient de pablier la
                        circulaire relative su pèlerinage</p>
                    <p>de 1905.</p>
                    <p>En voidjan court sparça</p>
                    <p>DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p>ARRIVERS</p>
                    <p>19 novembre</p>
                    <p>Anvers it Malte; 4j..vsp ang Osa Prines, cap. Kirkwood, ton 1,074. &amp;
                        Grace &amp; Co. Smyrne et Pirie: #j, vap. hall. Byzantion, cap Mas romatio,
                        ton. 400, &amp; Kuchayas. 20 novembre</p>
                    <p>Alexandreite: vap. ang. Mariont, op. Silvestri, son 880, à la Kh4divial Mail.
                        Constantinople es girde: 40 h., vap ang. Prines Abbas, cap, Anderlich, tom.
                        861, à la Khedivial Mail.</p>
                    <p>Hambourg et Malte: 4) 11), vap all. Thissos, esp. Starke, ton. 1,80 &amp;
                        Bross.</p>
                    <p>Tries 73 84. vap ang. Crown Prince, a Thomas,</p>
                    <p>ton 16:16, &amp; Grace &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Les prix suivants ont été pratiquée ce jour</p>
                    <p>85/8 Bamleh Railway... Furnished by Baid &amp; Barnard 10, S. Marka
                        Vaildings, Alexandria, a haris Kural-Nil Damanhour... iro, who underks the
                        esle and purchase of oke and darsa, on the lossl Boarse ant also of he
                        London Brook Exchange.</p>
                    <p>BOURSE KREDIVIALS</p>
                    <p>Remarques sur le marché da disponible et Contrasts. Samedi, le 19 novembre
                        1904. Coton: ion a été bonne et elle été favorisée par le fait Disponible-La
                        demands de la part de l'exporta que maig 4 los afforis des détenteurs elle
                        n'a pas complètement anivi la hausse des contrats.</p>
                    <p>Les qualités laissent à désirer et ceste circonstance sendrait à donner
                        maison à ceux qui disent que la deolte a pent-être plus souffert qu'on ne le
                        préten- dis. Mentionnons aussi l'opinion qui eommence à révaloir que
                        l'Alexandria General Produce Associs- tion se trouvera probablemens dans la
                        nécessité de rédaire quelque pen en précédente e-timation</p>
                    <p>Kar-Zaysi... Tromb......</p>
                    <p>Coton G.M.B.</p>
                    <p>(BASER RETPTH) Province Bébér De P.T. 290 Provines Garbish</p>
                    <p>De P.P. 815</p>
                    <p>820-625-</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 165-270-</p>
                    <p>(HAUTH-ROYPTS)</p>
                    <p>De P.T. 872 1/3 &amp; 375</p>
                    <p>Dairs Sugar</p>
                    <p>Sals &amp; Sode</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Market...</p>
                    <p>34</p>
                    <p>Ingleterre</p>
                    <p>33/8</p>
                    <p>France</p>
                    <p>9,18</p>
                    <p>Russie</p>
                    <p>atricha</p>
                    <p>Italie</p>
                    <p>Allemagne</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES A MINER-EL-BASS&amp;L.</p>
                    <p>Espagne</p>
                    <p>Balles 4</p>
                    <p>Balles 74</p>
                    <p>Suède</p>
                    <p>Turquie, Grèce et Boumanie</p>
                    <p>Pesant cantars 564,65.60</p>
                    <p>N.B.-Dans les expéditions pour l'An orre aout comprises balles 4,97 à dest
                        tion des Etats-Unis.</p>
                    <p>Sile Valley</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>par Cantar</p>
                    <p>800-</p>
                    <p>835</p>
                    <p>du mois de novembe 903</p>
                    <p>Suisse</p>
                    <p>Da</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Graines de outon</p>
                    <p>Faver</p>
                    <p>(MOYENNE-GYPTA)</p>
                    <p>Belgique</p>
                    <p>1, b.</p>
                    <p>8827</p>
                    <p>ardeba 8.276</p>
                    <p>Province Fayoum</p>
                    <p>Hollande</p>
                    <p>4-12</p>
                    <p>25,810</p>
                    <p>Fayoum Baai-Sogef...</p>
                    <p>Indea</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>6707</p>
                    <p>25.310</p>
                    <p>674</p>
                    <p>24,973</p>
                    <p>Japon</p>
                    <p>8525</p>
                    <p>26,389</p>
                    <p>6-17</p>
                    <p>26,168</p>
                    <p>7.</p>
                    <p>871</p>
                    <p>19343</p>
                    <p>523</p>
                    <p>SECTION DES GRAINES ET CEREALES PRIE FRANOO-STATION: DISPONESAR Graines de
                        colon AAA P.T. 68- Pause Saili Haute-Bgypte Fayoumi</p>
                    <p>24,'91</p>
                    <p>7,40</p>
                    <p>164</p>
                    <p>TIONWT</p>
                    <p>10,</p>
                    <p>8,094</p>
                    <p>&amp;P.T.</p>
                    <p>11.</p>
                    <p>1085</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>56 1/3</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>5,738</p>
                    <p>21791</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>35.71</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>14.</p>
                    <p>8139</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>499</p>
                    <p>99</p>
                    <p>8,165</p>
                    <p>24156</p>
                    <p>1,353</p>
                    <p>8583</p>
                    <p>93 355</p>
                    <p>65</p>
                    <p>7023</p>
                    <p>3123</p>
                    <p>657</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>541</p>
                    <p>2670</p>
                    <p>91</p>
                    <p>90,</p>
                    <p>8.-11</p>
                    <p>28.177</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>31.</p>
                    <p>7.659</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>Association."</p>
                    <p>16,707</p>
                    <p>571</p>
                    <p>CHEMINS DE FAR 8/B 698</p>
                    <p>13,</p>
                    <p>.6 103</p>
                    <p>37,91</p>
                    <p>717</p>
                    <p>1535.</p>
                    <p>24,</p>
                    <p>1,816</p>
                    <p>2,384</p>
                    <p>941</p>
                    <p>Ominee de coton. Show 97718 Be Saldi.**** Béhárs... Fives Saldi</p>
                    <p>4:47</p>
                    <p>16,620</p>
                    <p>11283</p>
                    <p>30</p>
                    <p>26,</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>14,795</p>
                    <p>467</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>829 461 12</p>
                    <p>6,325</p>
                    <p>35,414</p>
                    <p>1/32</p>
                    <p>230</p>
                    <p>80-7</p>
                    <p>881</p>
                    <p>7,574</p>
                    <p>8.411</p>
                    <p>5,891</p>
                    <p>78</p>
                    <p>289</p>
                    <p>9-71</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES</p>
                    <p>des dimanche 10 et lundi 21 novembre 1904- Documente de "Alexandria General
                        Prodne</p>
                    <p>Les embargaments sont bons et l'on crois que Cotons wax de décembre aussi ne
                        seront pas inférieure à ceux de l'année dernière.</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages ne s'améliorent pas, co qui, d'aprie quelques-uns, pourrait
                        bien atre attribué an Bas dnes sit bien être de l'Ag ieulture qui loi
                        permet</p>
                    <p>d soutenir la marchandise. Franeo-gare.-Sans affaires pour les raisons déjà
                        expliquées.</p>
                    <p>Bibers...</p>
                    <p>Orge...... Malt....** Lentillee</p>
                    <p>Tol des arrivages depuis le 1er septe bre 1904 Jasqu'à ce jour Canaire
                        9,101,011. Contre même jour en 1908</p>
                    <p>......</p>
                    <p>Contrats.-Récolte seinelle. Les haussiers ont continné dominer et pour un
                        moment les cours Of ont épousede janga'à al. 18 14 pour le mars. Anjourd'hui
                        nous elörene &amp; tal 18 7/8 ce qui fait que la réaction an foud n'a pas
                        été importante Tont fais il y a un désir marqué de réaliser, es qui prodoit
                        de l'incertit de dans l'allare du marché. La troisième filière de novembre a
                        atteint cantire 65 000 minis elle a été antée par ni groupe de pienlstears
                        ont-iders eo qui a eu pour unigne eff-s d'inspirer pour un moment un pea
                        plas do courage atix haneriers.</p>
                    <p>Le cottes Américaines is flasheent ui pen grand nombre de faseurs, leur
                        importanos ayant l'apparar ce d'ane.eonfirmation des estimations lancées en
                        dernier lieu os donoant is risolte Améri eine somme devant atteindre les
                        18,000,000 balles Nouvelle résolta. La nouvelle delte ne donnent presque pas
                        lieu à des affaires et is ea et absoln. ment desblia d'après l'oest da
                        marché pour la récole sourelle</p>
                    <p>Dans le austinée Prix plus hango marslaris 15 81/82&amp;1 plas bas pour murs
                        16 15 818/</p>
                    <p>Grain de eatin</p>
                    <p>Disponibles disponible a's off et rien d'inté reemant et toutes les
                        ductussions sont restdes confl nées intre PT. 69 at P.T. 58, aveo PT. 68
                        10-0 somme dernier cours. Les ex sortations sont mold et als évite at marché
                        de l'empressement de la part du commerce. Frano gare-Nalité somplète
                        Contrats-Béla semella-Affaires insigni.</p>
                    <p>Venise et Brindisi 67 h. vapital. Boafor, pants et fastsations is importance.
                        La marond Milasso, ten 1518, &amp; la Cia Florio Rabauino. Gleet Mes ios 8
                        h, vsp. ital. Tbe, cap., Mancini, on 19:8, &amp; Is Cis Plorio
                        Rabkinino.</p>
                    <p>Le passport est de rigueur et ne pint être délivré que sur production: 1' d'a
                        billet d'aller et retour délivré par le Khe divial Mail, 9° d'an certificat
                        constatan que ie pàterin a les moyens pécanisirea de faire le voyage 8 d'an
                        réépissé de dépúerine et Jaffa: 40 h. vap ang Bravo, &amp; Mes de P:B. 186.
                        L palerias étrangers son soumis aux mms conditions.</p>
                    <p>La madirish ou le gouvernorat degr tenir un registre de tous le passeporte
                        qu'elle délivre. et noter avee soin le nou des pålerine qui sont de retons.
                        Moyanna les conditions el-dessus toutes les personnes</p>
                    <p>Laren, to 694, &amp; Minotto</p>
                    <p>04 Naple:5j, vp ital. Moreo Minghatti, sp. Deo, ton. 1816, &amp; la Cis Flo
                        lo Rabst</p>
                    <p>Ost Blade: 1) 13, vap ve Tes,</p>
                    <p>Eame isti, ton. 1424, &amp; la Cle</p>
                    <p>chypre et Port-Haid 19 b, voy ang. Bar,</p>
                    <p>Chiasmaro, son. 1894, &amp; Minotto</p>
                    <p>p</p>
                    <p>et pusat soutes paste du pon de ven-leare Dans le mannée, plas aos pour
                        fem</p>
                    <p>P.7 61 10/40 18,40 pe bar your février-mes</p>
                    <p>61 8,40%-/-</p>
                    <p>Pro-Baldi:</p>
                    <p>BARQUNS AT ONEMINS DO FR 8/B 9555 Show 43994</p>
                    <p>199</p>
                    <p>www www</p>
                    <p>428</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>747</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>Gesines de coton Bia Saldi... vee Shidi. Báhára.</p>
                    <p>Bébérs</p>
                    <p>Onge Mate ... Lentilles... etons-Toesl des arrivages deptis le 1er engtou-
                        hes 1008 jusqu'à ce jour Cantare 2 101 011</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS, (1,88 a.m.) Cours de la Bourse de Minet-el-Baral Oelen
                        F.G.F.Br.</p>
                    <p>sb 1:7, ardebe 7-0098</p>
                    <p>N.8 Cette liste est relevée de registre de PAlex ndri General Pdece
                        Association"; mons aplions ada qa on passe la o aparera eo ar arrivages du
                        sos de nove eb é de deste ann'e</p>
                    <p>Alexandria General Produce Associat</p>
                    <p>No. 177.</p>
                    <p>SECTION COTONNIERE</p>
                    <p>Les différences de pris pour livraison Contrats de Coton, "de novembre" 1904,
                        on</p>
                    <p>inées comme suit:</p>
                    <p>BROWN.</p>
                    <p>ter</p>
                    <p>Sintre Fair et Fully Fair. Fully Fair et Good Pair Good Fair et Faily God
                        Fair, 72 E Fally Good Fair et Good... HAUTE-EGYPTE ET FLYOUM antre Fully
                        Fair et Good Fair</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>...P.T.</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>www.</p>
                    <p>Good Fair et Fully Good Fair Fally Good fair et Good Alexandrie, le 31
                        octobre 1904. Pour le comé, Le Président,</p>
                    <p>C. DE ISOHUDI</p>
                    <p>ADMINISTRATION</p>
                    <p>DES DOMAINE DE L'ETAT</p>
                    <p>Enchères de jeudi 17 novembre 1904, à 11h a.m.</p>
                    <p>A8SOCIATION DES COURTIERS EN MARCHANDISE (Service Special)</p>
                    <p>DEPROBE D'OUVERTUR</p>
                    <p>A.adrinin</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, 10b. &amp; m</p>
                    <p>Pasare: Janviar Povciae: 8.21</p>
                    <p>Paesi Mai-Jain 1-</p>
                    <p>Seconde Diplohe, 10h. 5</p>
                    <p>Pature: Janvier-fiveiae: 5.91</p>
                    <p>Fature: mai jain: 8.87</p>
                    <p>Boarea Ebédiviale, 21 novembre 190</p>
                    <p>Aosson D'ALEXANDRIN</p>
                    <p>Low 161, Dsqér, 18 Beshaishe, 41 134,</p>
                    <p>Bailes Cantre</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>984</p>
                    <p>947</p>
                    <p>Prix 18 11/18 15 8/4</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>283</p>
                    <p>18 34</p>
                    <p>156, Rowiach, 40</p>
                    <p>gat</p>
                    <p>15 3/8</p>
                    <p>151, 189, Mieir</p>
                    <p>810</p>
                    <p>15 8/4</p>
                    <p>23</p>
                    <p>145</p>
                    <p>18 5/8</p>
                    <p>161, Sasha, 44.</p>
                    <p>968</p>
                    <p>18 18/16</p>
                    <p>168, Doquées, 25</p>
                    <p>168</p>
                    <p>18,7 16</p>
                    <p>168, Sant</p>
                    <p>88</p>
                    <p>919</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.B. 5 14 3/8: Novembre... Janvier...... Yo Mare Mai</p>
                    <p>166,</p>
                    <p>44</p>
                    <p>985</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>16:95/81</p>
                    <p>187,</p>
                    <p>69</p>
                    <p>409</p>
                    <p>15.5/16</p>
                    <p>www18 11/18</p>
                    <p>181.</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>15-></p>
                    <p>18 27/32</p>
                    <p>169,</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>208</p>
                    <p>16 9/16</p>
                    <p>16 1/32</p>
                    <p>170,</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>Praise de solem Nov. Die Jan.... vrier More... Avril...</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>18, 1/4</p>
                    <p>178,</p>
                    <p>...P.T. 89 90/40 a</p>
                    <p>170</p>
                    <p>18 7/8</p>
                    <p>180,</p>
                    <p>Nov, Die-Jan.... Févrige Mars</p>
                    <p>62 8:40 P.T. 78- 78-</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>993</p>
                    <p>17 11/18</p>
                    <p>174,</p>
                    <p>89</p>
                    <p>959</p>
                    <p>18-</p>
                    <p>&amp;90/40 175, 10/40 177.</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>17 8/8.</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>Novembre...</p>
                    <p>Javier</p>
                    <p>Cotons : Nouvelle récole. Calme.</p>
                    <p>Les los ontéé sons adjagia à l'Anglo-Egyptia Bank Cay Lal.</p>
                    <p>1800 Mai</p>
                    <p>N.B-Aliens de l'eoshare il ones proofdé à l</p>
                    <p>Pvrier Avril...</p>
                    <p>Poves Soldi</p>
                    <p>-Les 13 premiers sont de qualid add, 8 d'abbaas, 8 de nabari, les derniere de
                        joanovich.</p>
                    <p>Bicole stalls. Ora onvers &amp; tal, 18 97/89 pone Disponible.-Point
                        d'arrivages, poins d'affaires et te mare pour tomber &amp; al. 16 1/18 apur
                        Bominang J. 18 8/4 &amp; 96/89. La tenne set fuble et il y a peuvente dee
                        denx lots' da smo sivant d'affaires, en grande partie des ré-lisations.</p>
                    <p>Feno-gars Bien.</p>
                    <p>Contra-Bdeofte acinelle. La one est le máme pour los contrass es la cote
                        afflande, on bases on on wt parement nominale.</p>
                    <p>de den Bose annalle. In eines ouvert &amp; P.E. 61 pour le février-mart
                        Pro-Betdi Bolte natualle dans</p>
                    <p>Ior ios Us no de dak, baller 28 are 188 P.T. 181 &amp; Abdel Maghid</p>
                    <p>Bose let Usine de tot, ballee 11- 88 F.T. 140 &amp; Abiel Moghi</p>
                    <p>8 1/3</p>
                    <p>17 16</p>
                    <p>DERNIERE HSURE</p>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.B. 5 14 3/8: Novembre... Janvier...... Yo Mare Mai</p>
                    <p>166,</p>
                    <p>44</p>
                    <p>985</p>
                    <p>15 1/2</p>
                    <p>16:95/81</p>
                    <p>187,</p>
                    <p>69</p>
                    <p>409</p>
                    <p>15.5/16</p>
                    <p>www18 11/18</p>
                    <p>181.</p>
                    <p>18.</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>15-></p>
                    <p>18 27/32</p>
                    <p>169,</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>208</p>
                    <p>16 9/16</p>
                    <p>16 1/32</p>
                    <p>170,</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>Praise de solem Nov. Die Jan.... vrier More... Avril...</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>18, 1/4</p>
                    <p>178,</p>
                    <p>...P.T. 89 90/40 a</p>
                    <p>170</p>
                    <p>18 7/8</p>
                    <p>180,</p>
                    <p>Nov, Die-Jan.... Févrige Mars</p>
                    <p>62 8:40 P.T. 78- 78-</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>84</p>
                    <p>993</p>
                    <p>17 11/18</p>
                    <p>174,</p>
                    <p>89</p>
                    <p>959</p>
                    <p>18-</p>
                    <p>&amp;90/40 175, 10/40 177.</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>17 8/8.</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>Novembre...</p>
                    <p>Javier</p>
                    <p>Cotons : Nouvelle récole. Calme.</p>
                    <p>Les los ontéé sons adjagia à l'Anglo-Egyptia Bank Cay Lal.</p>
                    <p>1800 Mai</p>
                    <p>N.B-Aliens de l'eoshare il ones proofdé à l</p>
                    <p>Pvrier Avril...</p>
                    <p>Poves Soldi</p>
                    <p>-Les 13 premiers sont de qualid add, 8 d'abbaas, 8 de nabari, les derniere de
                        joanovich.</p>
                    <p>Bicole stalls. Ora onvers &amp; tal, 18 97/89 pone Disponible.-Point
                        d'arrivages, poins d'affaires et te mare pour tomber &amp; al. 16 1/18 apur
                        Bominang J. 18 8/4 &amp; 96/89. La tenne set fuble et il y a peuvente dee
                        denx lots' da smo sivant d'affaires, en grande partie des ré-lisations.</p>
                    <p>Feno-gars Bien.</p>
                    <p>Contra-Bdeofte acinelle. La one est le máme pour los contrass es la cote
                        afflande, on bases on on wt parement nominale.</p>
                    <p>de den Bose annalle. In eines ouvert &amp; P.E. 61 pour le février-mart
                        Pro-Betdi Bolte natualle dans</p>
                    <p>Ior ios Us no de dak, baller 28 are 188 P.T. 181 &amp; Abdel Maghid</p>
                    <p>Bose let Usine de tot, ballee 11- 88 F.T. 140 &amp; Abiel Moghi</p>
                    <p>8 1/3</p>
                    <p>17 16</p>
                    <p>DERNIERE HSURE</p>
                    <p>(Cire de la Bouree Khédiviale 1h. pm) ore de l'Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchan Taton P. P.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre N.R. $ 14 11/8 a</p>
                    <p>18 18/31</p>
                    <p>18910</p>
                    <p>15 25 31</p>
                    <p>P.P. 69 18/4)</p>
                    <p>83 8 40</p>
                    <p>82 8/40</p>
                    <p>Nov De INver-1</p>
                    <p>#7 10/40</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">

                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Egyptian mining activity -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZUBAIR PASHA.<lb/>HIS AUTOBIOGRAPHY.</head>
                    <p>(Concluded.)</p>
                    <p>It is in the Darfur campaign that Zubair's career gets mixed up with those
                        events that have led to the interest of England in the Sudan, While Zubair
                        was conquering Darfur, the Governor of Khartoum, Ismail Pasha Ayyoub, was
                        sent to Darfur by the Khedive to Assist in the conquest; probably, as some
                        of Gordon's biographers assert, to prevent Zubair being too independent. The
                        latter asserts that be had achieved his work when Ismail proffer ed his
                        assistance; that nevertheless he wel- comed the Khedive's emissary'st
                        Fasher, the capital of Darfur, and discharged a hundred guns in his honour;
                        that he handed over the government of the conquered countries to Ismail
                        Ayyoub, proceeding himself with a picked force to deal with the relics of
                        the defeated armies. With these be easily esme to terms, but a dispute broke
                        out on his return to Fasher between himself and Ismail Ayyoub with respect
                        to a propo sition that the son of the late Sultan of Darfur should be made
                        governor of the province, subject to the Khedive, and to pay £100,000
                        annually, a proposal favoured by Zubair. but rejected by Imail Ayyoub.
                        Zubair, was, however, entrusted with the command of an expedition to quell a
                        rebellion got up by a gon of the deceased Sultan; and in this, his last
                        expedition, he advanced as far sa Wadai, whence, however, he was summarily
                        recalled. He then asked leave to return to Cairo to interview the Khedive,
                        and received in reply an invitation to do so, sccompanied with the title
                        Pasha. He brought as sent to his master 1000 Sudanese soldiers, completely
                        armed, 100 Arab horses, 8 tons of ivory of the finest quality, four lions,
                        four panthers, and twelve parrots." But in spite of his munificence he was
                        not allowed to return to the Sudan, and the defence of his kingdom passed to
                        his son Suleiman, whom Gordon some years after caught and abot.</p>
                    <p>Portions of this narrative certainly bear some resemblance to the adventures
                        of Sindbad the Sailor; yet in the main it corresponds well with the records
                        of Junker and Nachtigal, while it contains many details unknown to them.
                        Throughout Zabair appears as what Wingate (1) describes him, a born leader
                        of men. The reputation which he enjoyed in the Sadan, and which nine years
                        after he had been exiled, from it would have sufficed, in Gordon's
                        well-grounded opinion, to keep the Sudanese from joining the Mahdi, was
                        based on his marvellous success in war, but also, it would seem, on the
                        strict justice of his rule, of which he bossts, though he admits that his
                        punishments were occasionally severe, including hanging with the head
                        downwards. The references to him in Gordon's later Journal do not contradict
                        Zubair's description of himself in these respects.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand, the autobiography affords little justification for the
                        hysterical passage cited above from Birkbeck Hill, the impression produced
                        by which on the British public probably cost the gallant officer his life.
                        Zubair's omission of all mention of the slave trade in his account of his
                        life is doubtless intentional, and his connection with it is too well
                        attested for us to attach moch importance to the omission. But the phrase
                        "riminal of boundless wickedness" is as unanit able as the terin "scoundrel"
                        for a man in the position of Zubair, pursuing a form of traffic which his
                        own religion tolerated, and which, Gordon admits, had been discovered in
                        Europe to be illicit only one generation before From Becker's "Ismailia" it
                        appears that it was difficult to do business in the. Sudan without being a
                        slave trader; and if Zubair con tributed to the desolation of the Sadan,
                        some credit should, on the other hand, be given him for having in places
                        arrested the process by the introduction of strong government. Nor dan we
                        treat his conduct in fomenting a rebellion which might lead to the
                        restoration of his sovereign rights as very heinous. Having conquered some
                        provinces by his own arm, he had then pre sented them to the Khedive, who,
                        rewarded kimh for the gift by interning him in Cairo. Some sympathy is
                        surely due to his son, "the City" in his attempt to say for his family sonde
                        relics out of his father kingdom.</p>
                    <p>Had Zubair been permitted to return to the Sudan in 1876 or 1894, the history
                        of that vart region would have been different, and much bloodsbed would have
                        been spared at least for a time. The course of events has provided it with a
                        permanent soures of good govern ment, which Zabair could not have given it
                        His autobiography, however, gives by the ground for Gordon's anxiety for his
                        service i 1884, just as Gordon's earlier Letters explai the prejudice by
                        which he was deprived of them. (The Monthly Review) "Made in the
                        Bgyption</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT EXPLORATION FUND.<lb/>APPEAL FOR SUPPORT.</head>
                    <p>The eighteenth ordinary general meeting of the Egypt Exploration Fund was
                        held in the rooms of the Royal Society, Burlington House, it on the 11th
                        inst, when the president, Sir John Evans, took the chair.</p>
                    <p>After some formal business the Treasurer read his report, expressing regret
                        that it was the most unfavourable he had had to deal with. In regard to the
                        Exploration Fund the total expenditure was £3,084, whereas the receipts C
                        were £1,806. As to the archaeological survey £558 was spent sa against £422
                        received; th while on the Greco-Roman branch £1,325 was spent and £931
                        received. There was, there fr fore, a serious deficit. In the case of the
                        fund y proper this arose from the necessity of sending out two expeditions
                        and from the falling off of th receipts from America. The second expedition
                        fo was necessary because the right of priority to excavate outside the
                        temple of Queen Hatshepu A would have otherwise had to be abandoned,- and
                        then they would not through Dr. Naville have found the remains of a temple
                        built prior to that of Queen Hatshepu. The diminution of </p>
                    <p>RECEIPTS FROM AMERICA </p>
                    <p>was serious, and was due to the fact that fe the Americans were now
                        undertaking inde- pendent excavations. As to the Greco-Roman branch it had
                        been intended to send out an 0 expedition every other year, but the success
                        of the discoveries at Behness put many other searchers in the field and an
                        annual expedition became necessary. Last year Dr. Grenfell and Dr. Hunt,
                        among most important papyri, un- earthed the new Logia, and the epitome of
                        Livy, and next year's work, for which enough money was available, would, it
                        was hoped, w produce something of equal importance. It was pointed out that
                        the ordinary subscription of s guines, after payment of the expenses of the
                        P publications and the, office dues, only left t about three shillings for
                        the purposes of excavation, and an urgent appeal was therefore M made to all
                        subscribers to double their sub- scription at least for the current year, or
                        to make a substantial donation, else the small capital of the fund would
                        have to be drawn on. The accounts were adopted without discussion.</p>
                    <p>PRESIDENTIAL ADDRESS.</p>
                    <p>Sir John Evans then delivered his address. After referring to the losses of
                        the society through the deaths of Dr. Stuart Murray, Mr. Edward Gilbertson,
                        the Bishop of Carlisle, Mr. G. F. Watts, R.A., the Rev. Dr. George Salmon,
                        and Sir William T. Charley, K.C., he appealed argently for funds and then
                        summarised the work done in the past season. Professor Flinders Petrie had
                        excavated on the site of Herakleopolis, now Ehnass, sixty miles south of
                        Cairo, and the principal object of interest found was a golden statuette of
                        a local divinity, Hershefi, bearing on its base a dedication by a King of
                        the XXIVth Dynasty, of whom no other relics are known, and a magnificent
                        triad in red granite representing Rameses 11, between the gods Hershefi and
                        Ptah, 11ft. high and 8ft. broad. At Thebes, close to the temple of Queen
                        Hatabepu, Dr. Naville and Mr. Hall had found the mortuary chapel of a King
                        of the XIth Dynasty, who reigned about 2500 s.c. Part IV. of the Oxyrhynchus
                        Papyri had been published, end with it a small volume of the Logia of Jesus.
                        Some of the minor papyri were of much interest.</p>
                    <p>LIGHT ON OLD CUSTOMS. </p>
                    <p>There was, for instance, a document recording the emancipation of a slave,
                        entering into all the minute particulars of a passport of the middle of the
                        last century. In a deed by which two brothers joined in the manumission of
                        the third part of a slave who as regards the other two parts had already
                        been made free, one brother Achilleus is described of middle height, fair,
                        having a long face and ascaron the middle of his forehead; while the female
                        slave, who to become entirely free Apollonous, aged about twenty six, of
                        middle height, fair-has a long face and a sear on the right foot. Her third
                        part seems to have been worth three handred drachm of silver, say, £10. Some
                        other</p>
                    <p>REMARKABLE DOCUMENTS </p>
                    <p>were bonds of apprenticeship. One witnessed that a boy named Thorus is
                        apprenticed for five years to learn the art of weaving from Heraclas, who
                        for the first year and seven months is to pay the boy no wages, bat find t
                        him in food and a stipulated quantity of clothes. After the term mentioned
                        the boy is to receive a gradually increasing amount of d wages and more
                        expensive clothes. Twenty holidays in each year are to be allowed on account
                        of festivals, but there is no mention in of "week ends.". The date of this
                        bond is A.D. in 183. Even more remarkable is the bond of of apprenticeship
                        of a slave for two years to the "semiograph, to be taught to read and write
                        shorthand of "the signa that your you <cb n="3"/> Dionysios knows, "the
                        teacher receiving in all the premiums of a hundred and twenty drachme This
                        is dated about A.D. 100.Someprivate letters are interesting, and an
                        invitation of a decurion to his party on the sixth day before the Kalends,
                        at eight o'clock has a distinctly modern flavour.</p>
                    <p>MODERN AND ANCIENT EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer, in his report on Egypt for1903, had alluded to their
                        publications, which, he said, showed that many of the abuses which until
                        lately existed in Egypt almost in their original form were of very ancient
                        date.. "For instance, plentiful allusions, are made to the system of
                        tax-farming, which it is well known prevailed in Egypt, as elsewhere, from
                        time immemorial, and which appears everywhere to have given rise to abuses
                        very similar in chs- racter." Lord Cromer then pointed out that with the
                        recent fishery reforms almost the last restige of this iniquitous and
                        oppressive sys tem would disappear. He noted with some in- terest that in
                        the days of Domitian the system -though without doubt equally oppressive to
                        the taxpayers-soned hardly to have been so lucrative to the tax-farmers as
                        in those of Abbas II. These have been of recent years making an annual
                        profit of over £30,000, whereas from the</p>
                    <p>OXYRHYNCHUS PAPYRI</p>
                    <p>it appears that on certain taxes being put up to auction those who had
                        previously held the concession not only refused to bid bat seemed likely to
                        abscond, "as they had incur red sufficient. loss already." In the case of
                        slavery, which is still not altogether unknown on the upper waters of the
                        Blue Nile, Lord Cromer compared a recent purchase of a lad of fifteen for
                        £12 with that of a woman, aged thirty-five, for £7 2s. 6d, and inquired
                        whether a slave really cost more on the Abyssinian frontier in 1903 than was
                        paid in Egypt in the year 86. In conclusion, the chairman referred to the
                        irrigation works in Egypt, and hoped that all possible precautions would be
                        taken! for the preservation of monuments within the ares of the extended
                        reservoir should the Assouan dam be heightened.</p>
                    <p>PLANS FOR THE FUTURE.</p>
                    <p>Subsequently Professor Flinders Petrie and Dr. Bernard Grenfell gave brief
                        accounts of their work and plans for the coming year. Pro- fessor Petrie
                        intends to completely examine Sinai, if permission can be obtained, and Dr.
                        Grenfell will resume the search for papyri at Oxyrhynchus</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>OCTOBER'S CHILLS.</head>
                    <p>BRING MANY ILLS: THE CURE IS DR. WILLIAMS' PINK PILIS</p>
                    <p>WOULD you be warm! Look to your blood supply. Chills, Rheumatism, and
                        Sciatica, come from poor or bad blood. Dr. Williams' Pink Pills for Pale
                        People prevent as well as cure. them: for these pills make new blood.</p>
                    <p>Mr. William Wright, a stonemason, 24 Morano-street, Firhill-road, Glasgow,
                        said: "I contracted a chill, sed a pain started in iny left ankle, and
                        jumped to my hip. I was obliged to. give up work, and take to my bed. In
                        spite of good nursing, two doo tors, poulticing, fomentation and medicine, I
                        felt as had after eight, weeks as when I was first laid up. Such was my Mr.
                        William Wright, a Stonemason, was cured of agony that I scar Sciatica, by
                        Dr. Williams cely slept. "I read in the Pink Pille newspapers of a miner who
                        had been cured of Beute Sciatics, or Rheumatism in the leg, by Dr. Williams'
                        Pink Pills for Pale People A box was therefore got for me. Before I had got
                        through it my spirits were better, and the pain was leaving my hip and lng.
                        After a second box, the Sciatica was entirely cured. The pills gave me rich
                        Nood, for, chancing to cut my finger, the blood that came from it was rich
                        and red, whereas when I was ill my blood was poor and thin. The pills gave
                        me a good colour, They sent me back to work in three weeks" Mrs. Wright
                        added:-" Till my husband had Dr. Williams' Pink Pills he could not bear his
                        left leg to be touched, even lightly. I noticed an improvement from the day
                        he started taking them. I, too, have found them a sure cure for the blinding
                        headaches, from which I often suffered.</p>
                    <p>In Chill October, we need new blood, not only to stave off Rheumatism and
                        Sciation, but also to cure the many diseases resulting from poor blood, Dr.
                        Williams' Pink Pills for Pale People (genuine pills bear the full seven-word
                        title) cure Paralysis, Locomotor Ataxy, Kidney Disease, Scrofula, Rickets,
                        Consumption, Anemis, Loss of Appetite, Palpitations, Neuralgia, Ladies'
                        Weaknesses, and Hysteria. These pills are not a purgativo. They are sold at
                        all medicine shops, and by Dr. Williams' Medicine Co, at 2. 9. ar per box,
                        or six boxes for 13s. 9d.</p>
                    <p>Sold in Reypt at all chemists at P.T, 13 per box or P.T. 70 per 6 boxes. Can
                        be bought at d the general depot: Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel of du Nd St,
                        (1st floor), and Alexandria, Roa Stamboul, No 8.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL</p>
                    <p>of Largeet 1et else and most comfortable ma Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the s
                        Central position. Under English management 01-11-00</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <!-- Libby's Luncheon -->
                <div type="item" feature="comingEvents">
                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events.</head>
                    <p>November</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA:</p>
                    <p>Mon. 91 Abbas Helmy Theatre. If Trovators,</p>
                    <p>Alhambra Thesis. Gioconda 8.15 pm. </p>
                    <p>Plase des Consale. Masoorini's Mons garis. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Thers. 14 Abbas Helmy Thestre Aida, in sid of c International Employés
                        Society.9p.m. </p>
                    <p>Fri. 25</p>
                    <p>Alderson's Garden. Vanety Maser mens. 4 p.m.:</p>
                    <p>December.</p>
                    <p>Sat 8</p>
                    <p>Abbat Hotel. A. L. M. &amp; D. 8 Consert 9pm.</p>
                    <p>November.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Mon. 31 Meeting of Raghab Lodge No. 61, at</p>
                    <p>Wed/28</p>
                    <p>Set 26</p>
                    <p>Masonic Hall, Boulae-road. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Opera House. M. Silvain. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>Thesare des Nouveautée. Variety Enter minment. 9.80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Troosdero. Variety Entertainment. 9.80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Masonic Hall. Idris Lodge No. 48 9pm. Meeting f Ragheb Mark Lodge No. 510 at
                        Masonic Hall, Boulse-road. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Ban. 37 Zoological Gardens. Performsines by Band of B. A. Infantry in
                        afternoon,</p>
                    <p>December.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 9</p>
                    <p>Sat. 10</p>
                    <p>Wed. 21</p>
                    <p>Fri 26</p>
                    <p>Mens House. Gymkhans.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Horticultural Society's Show. K 8.0. grounds. First Winter
                        Races.</p>
                    <p>K. 8.0. grounds Firet Winter Bacos. Sud day. 9p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>IMPORTANT NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>AGENCY WANTED.</p>
                    <p>The Sole Agency in England and her colonies required by a syndicate having
                        its head office in London, for RKALLY FIRST CLASS EGYP. TIAN CIGARETTE.Only
                        a really ex- cellent tobacco with fine delicte aro- ma and made with the
                        best paper pro- curable wil be entertained. Address, sending samples and
                        naming weight and price per ten thousand (carriage and duty forward), ASHLEY
                        BROWN, 132, Charing Cross Road, London, W.C. If reference desired, apply,
                        The Imperial Ottoman Bank, Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Emisssion de 5,000 actions DE LA</p>
                    <p>34037-1</p>
                    <p>Brasserie des Pyramides</p>
                    <p>(EX CROWN BREWERY OF CAIRO)</p>
                    <p>"SoCITS ANONYMN"</p>
                    <p>Constituée par acte passé devant le notaire Betors &amp; Bruzelles, le 24
                        Mare 1889. publié Moniteur Belge le 12 Avril 1889, oud. No 1863. Conforto
                        dment &amp; l'article 6 des Saints of enivant décision du Conseil
                        d'Administration du #8 Octobre 1904, la Braserie das Pyrsmides émes 5,000
                        Ae- tions de Capital portant le Capital de la Bonité de 1.500 000 franes
                        &amp; 2.000.000.</p>
                    <p>L'émissio est faite an prix de 108 franev l'action. Les Ae-ionnaires ont un
                        droit de préférence à rai- son d'une setion pour &amp; notions de Capital on
                        10 de vidende qu'ile pos ident</p>
                    <p>Les soions non souserites par les Actionnaires, sont attribuése anz
                        souseripteurs en proportion de leze souseriptions.</p>
                    <p>Pour l'ex-reios de droit de préférenson, les sotionnaires auront à fournir un
                        Certifiest de dépl de leare titres dane uns Banque d'Egypte on do
                        Brazelles.</p>
                    <p>Lee Hongoristare auront à verser 35 france par setion à la soneripsion, 30
                        franes à la répartition es le solde soit 88 franes, à la remise du
                        sitre.</p>
                    <p>Les veramente devront se faire à la Bangos Impériale Ottomane, an Egypte out
                        an Bidge, Bonial &amp; Brozelles 106, Bus Boyale of los borderenx de
                        seription sont déposés.</p>
                    <p>In soneription out ouverte la Vendredi 28 novem bre conrent et des le
                        lendemain Samedi &amp; midi. La Président du Conseil d'Administration
                        94980-99 J.G. CHAKOUR</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>The P. &amp; 0.8. N. Company's</p>
                    <p>in Yeah</p>
                    <p>"VBOTIS," 6,000 tone, will leave Aleredris Friday, the 9th and 80th of
                        December fee SILLAS, taking Flest loin Pogies sly, af</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>SALE BY AUCTION.</p>
                    <p>MESSRS. CONGDON &amp; CO. have been instructed to sell by Public Auction the
                        property and affects of the officers 20th Hussars. The sale will take place
                        in the Mese-room, Cavalry Barracks, Abbassieh, on Friday and Saturday, Nov.
                        98th and 26th, commencing at 9.30 on each morning. The property will be on
                        view on Tues day, Wednesday, and Thursday afternoons up to 6 p...
                        94982.5-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>GREAT SALE</p>
                    <p>OF</p>
                    <p>Winter Novelties</p>
                    <p>COMMENCES NOVEMBER 12</p>
                    <p>AT.</p>
                    <p>Walker&amp;Meimarachi.</p>
                    <p>PASCHAL BRANCH.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>LATEST</p>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PARIS CREATIONS</p>
                    <p>94870-14-11</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="prepaidAdvertisements">
                    <p>CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>(Prepaid.)</p>
                    <p>Under jada following</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>Inverted of</p>
                    <p>pes, P.T. 5, thres, P.T. 10. P.T. # throw</p>
                    <p>P.T.O</p>
                    <p>DVERTISING AGESTA-The beel pabe Ing fe in Ontre belong to Violal</p>
                    <p>Chalet Parela Dark</p>
                    <p>Special too fat parmasout allant Moderate Prompt despai</p>
                    <p>dvert</p>
                    <p>LEXANDRIA LENDING LIBRARY.-Ove 3,000 volimas Apply for catalogas so Bortan
                        &amp; Co., Bae Charif Paaba 94909-6-8</p>
                    <p>FURNISHED FLAT TO LET, &amp; rooms: ball-</p>
                    <p>reom, et, for about 12 months. Plassa y kitated near Ramlah Station,
                        Alexandria Apply by letter, "A. B.," 40"Magonia Victoria."</p>
                    <p>24907-8-6</p>
                    <p>JEUNE, DEMOISELLE antrichien, he</p>
                    <p>bien l'Allemand e l'Italie, demande inativaurice on dame de compagnie.
                        Excellent certificate of références or place d'adresse: Mme Torio, No. 1,
                        ras Chérif Poobs, Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>94939-8-9</p>
                    <p>188 MINA SHEPPARD will actinne her</p>
                    <p>ember 1. A Camp is to be inaugurated or the Pyramids, where patients and
                        osbere may be socommodated. 24904-8-1</p>
                    <p>TO LET-Fine Ville, furnished or unfarnished with garden and tables, enated on
                        the Ghairwh Promenade, Cairo, being the Ebedivial portis Omb, and next to
                        the second the garden</p>
                    <p>the Palace Hotel. Apply</p>
                    <p>Ville 94889-19-0</p>
                    <p>PHE UNION CLUB, Alexandria, invites appl</p>
                    <p>ervanta Chef, Hind Walter, Barm To be addressed to Berot</p>
                    <p>Union Cin, Alesandria</p>
                    <p>WANTED byrgs fres</p>
                    <p>Onstems</p>
                    <p>and</p>
                    <p>Apply</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>NEW SEASON'S</p>
                    <p>GOODS</p>
                    <p>ARRIVING</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Calro &amp; Alexandria</p>
                    <!-- incomplete -->
                </div>




            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-21/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <!-- page 6 contents -->
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>Pour GENES, par le batean italien Adria parti le A novembre:</p>
                    <p>Behmid &amp; Co., 848 bailes coton</p>
                    <p>G. Franger &amp; Co.. 806</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Bensoni &amp; Co., 250</p>
                    <p>J. Plante Co, 692</p>
                    <p>Carver Beck &amp; Coy. Ltd, 80</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 128</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann, 881</p>
                    <p>Mobr &amp; Fender, 288</p>
                    <p>2,882 balles coton</p>
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER, 21, 1904</p>
                    <p>Lyzarnot, November 19, 13 80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sales of the day</p>
                    <p>6,000</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>400</p>
                    <p>Aimerion (new erop) Maize Spot per</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>Americns fatures (Dee-Jan)</p>
                    <p>5.22</p>
                    <p>(April-May)</p>
                    <p>5.29</p>
                    <p>Ameriona Middling...</p>
                    <p>6.89</p>
                    <p>Egyptian fally good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>8 32/64</p>
                    <p>(Dec.)</p>
                    <p>8 9/64</p>
                    <p>(Jan.)</p>
                    <p>84.64</p>
                    <p>(March) 7 68/6</p>
                    <p>nominal</p>
                    <p>good fair (browa) do "good</p>
                    <p>nominal</p>
                    <p>fully good-fir</p>
                    <p>8 12/16 8 10 16</p>
                    <p>Four FIREE et ODESSA, par le batean ere Egyptian Brown fair per lb. d. Ep.
                        Nicoles II, parti le 5 novembre :. Divers, 150 ce riz, 249 so is destes, 88
                        colis divers G. Pranger &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>1,322 ballow soton</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 260</p>
                    <p>S</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderi,</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>Behmid &amp; Co..</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>280..</p>
                    <p>G. Riecken,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines à Co.,</p>
                    <p>50</p>
                    <p>E Mallison &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>2,129 belles coton</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Besas now (per 480 lbs) to 25/8 1</p>
                    <p>Cotton Werkly total sales...</p>
                    <p>On speculation</p>
                    <p>For export</p>
                    <p>Total Import</p>
                    <p>Forwarded to consumers...</p>
                    <p>For BYBIA. by the S.S. Minich; sailed on the 5th November:</p>
                    <p>Varions, 184 bags Baden besos, 108 bags rics, 28 bags coffee, 87 bags beans,
                        14 begs lentila: 6 asses cigarettes, 18 ampsy maks, 10 packages sombae, 14
                        packages vegetables, 1,991 poeksgus aundries</p>
                    <p>For HULL, by the S.S. Tycho, miled on the 6th November:</p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Actual export</p>
                    <p>Block.</p>
                    <p>East India aflost</p>
                    <p>American sfloat...</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton On speculation</p>
                    <p>8. Tswil,</p>
                    <p>Bebrend &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank,</p>
                    <p>N. E. Tamvado,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>ORENSTEIN &amp; KOPPEL, Limited. STEINEMANN MABARDI &amp; C</p>
                    <p>Capital 10,000,000 Frs.</p>
                    <p>PURVEYORS TO H.H. THE KHEDIVE:</p>
                    <p>PORTABLE AND, PERMANENT RAILWAYS PASSENGER AND GOODS CARS</p>
                    <p>Tipping and Platform Waggons</p>
                    <p>FOR ALL PURPOSES. R</p>
                    <p>LOCOMOTIVES FROM 10-400 H.P.</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Engineering Stores. MERCHANTS CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY Bole
                        Agents for Egypt, Asia Minor and Byria for</p>
                    <p>IMPORTES ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Mos, Olayton &amp; Shuttleworth, Lincoln Portable &amp; fred Engines &amp;
                        Bollers</p>
                    <p>mille Threaking Strawbruising &amp; Outting Machines.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Galloways Ltd. Manchester. The Ungest Boller Works in the World. Walter
                        A. Wood, Mowing &amp; Bearing Hoshine Co. Roosick Falls N. T. (America)
                        Piguet &amp; Co., Lyons. French Steam Engines.</p>
                    <p>Bespers, Moore, Harvesters &amp; Babes</p>
                    <p>Aveling &amp; Porter Lim., Rochester. Steam Rollers and Stoom Ploughs. Les
                        Tanneries Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Falling. (CATRO: 24 Kar
                        el Nil Strees. B. Hindley, Barton, Dorset, Vertical Engines and Boilers,
                        specially designed for opposite the Bank of Egypt driving Ketrie Dynasce
                        &amp; Centrifugal Pumpa, sto, F.O B. 690 Telephone No. 39 Hillstret Hugueot
                        Park Bicions LEXANDRIA: 29 Cher f Pasha Damont. Paris: Centrifugal pumps.
                        Street, Telephone No 661</p>
                    <p>bales 50,000 Large Stocks of Rails, Trucks, and Locomotives always kept in
                        Alexandris. E. &amp; E. Turner Ltd. powish Flow Hills.</p>
                    <p>500</p>
                    <p>2,000</p>
                    <p>100,000 SIEMENS &amp; HALSKE, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>194,000</p>
                    <p>7,000</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING OFFICES: CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>450,000 Slectric Light Installations.-Transmission of Power-lestie Railways
                        and Tramways-</p>
                    <p>4,000</p>
                    <p>Telegraphic &amp; Telephonic Apparatas. DYNAMOS-MOTORS.</p>
                    <p>CAIBO: 94, Karr-al-Nil Blast, opposite Bank of Brypt, P.OB. 690 Telephone No.
                        189. ALEXANDRIA: 39, Chérif Pasha Street. Telephone No. 661. 81-19-004</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>870,000</p>
                    <p>75</p>
                    <p>Weekly sales</p>
                    <p>2,600</p>
                    <p>Buick</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>90,000</p>
                    <p>Forwarded to co-</p>
                    <p>somers...</p>
                    <p>18,000</p>
                    <p>Actual Export...</p>
                    <p>1,800</p>
                    <p>Import</p>
                    <p>91.000</p>
                    <p>NEW-YORK, November 19.</p>
                    <p>Spot Cotton...</p>
                    <p>-10</p>
                    <p>904 tons cotton seed</p>
                    <p>Amerionn Fasares (December)</p>
                    <p>956</p>
                    <p>1,550</p>
                    <p>(January)</p>
                    <p>9.65</p>
                    <p>676</p>
                    <p>1,027</p>
                    <p>(April)... (May)</p>
                    <p>9.82</p>
                    <p>9.90</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers</p>
                    <p>668</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 8,8</p>
                    <p>Como day's receipts at all U.-S. Parts</p>
                    <p>49,000</p>
                    <p>Kafr Zayat Cotton Coy. Led, 1,800 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>G. Brach &amp; Co., 871 begs gam</p>
                    <p>Aly Moh. Balsh, 150 bags onions</p>
                    <p>H. Bindernagal, 60 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>Pour TREBIZONDE, par le batean dujoman Alez- andros, parti le 8 novembre:</p>
                    <p>Divers, 1,8:6 now rix, 165 saos benné, 80 anos fèves da Boudan, 379 enis:
                        danses, 109 barile alcool, 6x barie vides, 28 colis zerabile, 38 solis
                        poeax, 18 colis divers</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</p>
                    <p>BOURS da 19 novembre 1904 COURS DES VALEURS A TERMS, CLOTURE</p>
                    <p>PARIS</p>
                    <p>Bense Française 8%...</p>
                    <p>Actions de Boss...</p>
                    <p>Lots Taros.</p>
                    <p>Ture Unifié,</p>
                    <p>Dete Egyptienne Unde......ex</p>
                    <p>Dairs denied.</p>
                    <p>Crédit Foncier Egyptien...</p>
                    <p>Extérieur espagnol...</p>
                    <p>Obligations Beaque Nar, de Grios..</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Athènes, nouvelles souons Mesropotiain</p>
                    <p>Basse consolidé...</p>
                    <p>Bosnowice</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Change ar Londres...</p>
                    <p>Bases 2o.&amp; disponible</p>
                    <p>Boers No. 8 livrable les 4 de</p>
                    <p>...balee LIVERPOOL, November 19. American fatures (December January)... 5.92
                        Egyptian fally good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>8-19/64</p>
                    <p>EM (Dec.) 8 6/64 (Jan.) 81.04 (March) 7 59 64</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 19,</p>
                    <p>Private discount (3 month balls) Bar Bilver (per on d.)</p>
                    <p>Jonsole (December) Bio Tinto... Band Mines Egyptian Unifled..</p>
                    <p>Bailway Domain</p>
                    <p>Ottoman Defence... Turkish Unified...</p>
                    <p>Ian Bente 4...</p>
                    <p>Onoman Bank shares</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Egypt...</p>
                    <p>4566- Monopole Gree</p>
                    <p>Dairs Banish</p>
                    <p>98 60</p>
                    <p>New Dairs..</p>
                    <p>138</p>
                    <p>Bente Ureoque 4$</p>
                    <p>88 16</p>
                    <p>107</p>
                    <p>Charterede of d. Africa...</p>
                    <p>Agrionitaral Bank...</p>
                    <p>101 15 Nile Valley Gold Mine</p>
                    <p>714</p>
                    <p>-8%</p>
                    <p>26 14/16</p>
                    <p>88 1,4</p>
                    <p>62 12</p>
                    <p>11 1/4</p>
                    <p>104 7/8</p>
                    <p>99 8/4</p>
                    <p>104 -1/9</p>
                    <p>108 '1/3</p>
                    <p>88 88</p>
                    <p>ww</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>94</p>
                    <p>104-</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>100 1/3 91.5/8</p>
                    <p>...87</p>
                    <p>2 1/16</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>DOW 1 8/4</p>
                    <p>Delta Light Railway (Boarer shares) 16 to 15 1/8</p>
                    <p>89 80gypa. dos seed to Hall (Nov.) 5 13/18 steady Jerman Best g (ovembe)
                        18/10</p>
                    <p>£100,000 were wishdrawn from the Bank to-day for Egypt</p>
                    <p>25 14 1/2 bots Turos</p>
                    <p>Jrédia Lyonnais...</p>
                    <p>Ostonian Bank...</p>
                    <p>Chegnes dis London</p>
                    <p>Sagar Whise No. 8: (November).</p>
                    <p>Crédit Foncier Egyption</p>
                    <p>... 88 1/4</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Consolidés anglais......</p>
                    <p>Hecomptes-Parie 8, Londres 8, Berlin 6.</p>
                    <p>OKATWOOD'S A MILAN AFE stock</p>
                    <p>LINITD</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Mesars. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin.</p>
                    <p>Pized and Portable Beim and OIL gl Gers</p>
                    <p>Faten Tibbon-making Thrashing Machines,</p>
                    <p>Mesars. Platt Brothers &amp; Co., Limited, Oldham.</p>
                    <p>Cettos Glaning Maklary</p>
                    <p>Messrs. John Fowler &amp; Co., Limited, Leeds. Broom Ploughing Machinery and
                        Bnadrier,</p>
                    <p>The Central Cyolone Co., Limited, London. Grinding and Palverling
                        Machinery,</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Charles Cammell &amp; Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p>Messrs.</p>
                    <p>Stest Halis, springs, ballers, As</p>
                    <p>Patent and hit Dos</p>
                    <p>Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                    <p>at and Manual Fire Engin</p>
                    <p>Messrs. F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld., Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Unmal Brand Belting ote, she</p>
                    <p>Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p>The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                    <p>Bikes Vortex Turbines,</p>
                    <p>Meears. Greenwood &amp; Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>The (Laval) Fatest Stories, Meetrial Dynamo &amp; Motors.</p>
                    <p>MoCormick's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                    <p>Planet Junior Agricultural Implementa</p>
                    <p>Hores Hoss, Beed Drills, sta, ete. OLIYER PLOUGHS.</p>
                    <p>Agent in Cairo: M. A. FATTUCCI</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>38-8-905</p>
                    <p>Agents or OXBARB</p>
                    <p>.</p>
                    <p>TARIF D'EXPORTATION</p>
                    <p>Pour le mele de Novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 19.</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>128-</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>1147-</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>294-</p>
                    <p>...35.14 1/2</p>
                    <p>Obefales..... Tourteenx Grainos de soson... Olgnons</p>
                    <p>Bhg. 1/1 194 18</p>
                    <p>6,6</p>
                    <p>DESIGNATION</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>40-3/8</p>
                    <p>724-</p>
                    <p>138-</p>
                    <p>Ofriales.....</p>
                    <p>Tourionax...</p>
                    <p>Oignons.</p>
                    <p>Pets de</p>
                    <p>mote</p>
                    <p>Pytx di</p>
                    <p>Nomine!</p>
                    <p>LONDAN8</p>
                    <p>Outon</p>
                    <p>Canlar</p>
                    <p>2:610</p>
                    <p>Shgs. 1/1 1/2 &amp; 18 6/8</p>
                    <p>Octon</p>
                    <p>435</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Athènes (nouvelle usanos)....</p>
                    <p>PRIMES DES CONTRATS.</p>
                    <p>Liv. Mars P.T. 18 80/40 à 15-</p>
                    <p>inse de scton. Fr.... 180/40 1 85/4</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton...</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIRECTS Graines de eosan.... Oriales....</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL Engs. 11/ 1,8</p>
                    <p>"SIMPLE FACULTE</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>"STELLAGE</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Liv. Mars P.T. 27 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 aminos de soton, Fr.-M. 8 90/40 8 80
                        40</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>Bhge. 9,6-10/ 1/9-</p>
                    <p>CEREAL MARKET..</p>
                    <p>Con</p>
                    <p>BOG HL FABAD MARKET.</p>
                    <p>NATIONAL BANK'S BROOWAR</p>
                    <p>INSTRADAY'S PRI</p>
                    <p>Coton... Céréales... 100 Tourleans... Graines de coton...... Oignons.....</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Wheat, Taga Midd</p>
                    <p>Ard..P.T. 136 to P.T. 197</p>
                    <p>128</p>
                    <p>182</p>
                    <p>"DOUBLE"</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>150</p>
                    <p>Beans, Tug</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>98 G</p>
                    <p>Lov. Mare F.Z. 9 18/40 &amp; 10</p>
                    <p>CONTINENT (NANTES.DUNENBQUE) Graines de cot. (Dankergus) Fr. 10-1 (Nantes)...
                        19 1/2</p>
                    <p>95</p>
                    <p>(old</p>
                    <p>106</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Oignons</p>
                    <p>Lane Tugar...</p>
                    <p>91</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>Barley, Tagad</p>
                    <p>Zaws...</p>
                    <p>Dues Shemal</p>
                    <p>Helba</p>
                    <p>Hummor..</p>
                    <p>MARSEILLE</p>
                    <p>68 EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO, LTD Graines de soon...</p>
                    <p>DESTINATIONS DIVERSES Genes, Marseille... Fr. - Coton 1 Odes, Triose, Venise,
                        9.50 8.80 90.0&amp;99.80</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>(Between the hours of 10 am and 6 pm, Ontre time</p>
                    <p>Dunkerque Anvers Hambo</p>
                    <p>New York. Bombay Alexandri la 18 novembre 100s..</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>78</p>
                    <p>93</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>216</p>
                    <p>VERAGE TIME supled in tranmission Bevotion telegram from Byland te Almendra
                        Salurley, 19th November 1984</p>
                    <p>Le Havre</p>
                    <p>Baronione***#</p>
                    <p>Lale Crashed Kho</p>
                    <p>darl........</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS</p>
                    <p>Grashed Ta</p>
                    <p>ORRALS IN BOAT AT BARES.</p>
                    <p>What</p>
                    <p>Ard. 4030</p>
                    <p>FROM</p>
                    <p>85 0</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>1000</p>
                    <p>Dars banal..</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>960</p>
                    <p>206</p>
                    <p>Beans.</p>
                    <p>Lentils...</p>
                    <p>Farley</p>
                    <p>RANDED IN AT</p>
                    <p>Ris on paille</p>
                    <p>brus</p>
                    <p>(Parch</p>
                    <p>1.80</p>
                    <p>par 100 kilog.</p>
                    <p>poids.</p>
                    <p>andeb</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>21188-24-11-904</p>
                    <p>YOUNGS,</p>
                    <p>RYLAND STREET WORKS, BIRMINGHAM, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>LIFTING &amp; HOISTING APPLIANCES</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>HYDRAULIC TOOLS.</p>
                    <p>SCREW AND</p>
                    <p>HYDRAULIC RAIL-BENDERS.</p>
                    <p>Write for</p>
                    <p>Catalogue No. 73.</p>
                    <p>23694-4-4</p>
                    <p>Davey Paxman &amp; Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>COLCHESTER, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>Makers of high class steam engines and boilers for Brish, Colonial and
                        Foreign Governments, Celebrated for ECONOMY and DURABILITY.</p>
                    <p>PHILADELPHIA</p>
                    <p>SWEDEN</p>
                    <p>DENMARK</p>
                    <p>GERMANT eto., eto.. Awarded only Gold Medal, ever given by the Royal So. of
                        Arts and Gold Medals at the following Exhi sitions</p>
                    <p>LONDON VIRRA-1878 PARIS</p>
                    <p>PAXHAR FA</p>
                    <p>Teab Day Bace Bomam.</p>
                    <p>VERTICAS LARGASHION &amp; Cess BUSAN BOILERS,</p>
                    <p>DAVEY PAXMAN &amp; Oo.'s Trip-Geared Engine gives off a full horse- power for
                        one hour at 1 lbs. of fuel. At the great trial of Com found, Portable and
                        Single Cylinder Steam Engines by the Royal Agricultural Society at Newcastle
                        open to the whole world, Davey Paxman &amp; Co. took the only prises
                        offered, establishing a record which has not yet been equalled.</p>
                    <p>AGENTS IN EGYPT</p>
                    <p>Messrs. HASSABO BEY MAHOMED &amp; Co. ALEXANDRIA. Who have a big stock of
                        casinos and bollers always on view. 1st Khedive's treat. (Telephone
                        998.)</p>
                    <p>DINNEFORD'S</p>
                    <p>The Universal Remedy for Acidity of the Stomach, Headache, Heartburn,
                        Indigestion, Sour Brectations Bill</p>
                    <p>DINNEFORDS</p>
                    <p>Avotions</p>
                    <p>The Physician's Cure for Goot, Rheumatic dout and. Gravel..</p>
                    <p>Safest and most Gentle Medielne fot Infants, Children, Delicate Females, ad
                        the</p>
                    <p>Makness of Pregnancy</p>
                    <p>MAGNESIA MAGNESIA</p>
                    <p>99-11-904</p>
                    <p>Credit Lyonnals SHRAGER BROTHERS</p>
                    <p>Société Anonyme.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, CALCUTTA, ALEXANDRIA. SINGAPORE AND. OOLOMBO (UTION).</p>
                    <p>OURANY PRIOM FRA YON PAR ON WA Japital 350.000.000 de France Merchants in
                        Jute and Jute Fabries</p>
                    <p>Far Ton</p>
                    <p>Shgs</p>
                    <p>Cardi Newport Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Best quality Best quality</p>
                    <p>Bethal</p>
                    <p>24/ 23 6 18</p>
                    <p>24 6 24 186</p>
                    <p>Coupon</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>186</p>
                    <p>Davison</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>West Hartley Main</p>
                    <p>Joolak</p>
                    <p>Morry's</p>
                    <p>Bairds</p>
                    <p>Dunlops</p>
                    <p>Best Hamiltos B</p>
                    <p>L</p>
                    <p>Yorkshire Lavorpool</p>
                    <p>Michiedend</p>
                    <p>Best Lasashire</p>
                    <p>Bad quality</p>
                    <p>Besond Lancashire Anchor</p>
                    <p>Orown</p>
                    <p>Star</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN MINING</p>
                    <p>NAMN OF COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>Central Egypt Exploration.....</p>
                    <p>Wayptian Mines Explor. Bynd...****** Eyptian Badan Minerals......</p>
                    <p>Kayptian and Hodan Mining Bynd.</p>
                    <p>Osbait (dan Mining Hynd.</p>
                    <p>Hile Development Synd</p>
                    <p>Nile Goldfalds (10 paid)</p>
                    <p>Nile</p>
                    <p>Valley Block</p>
                    <p>Valley</p>
                    <p>North Mile Valay</p>
                    <p>MARKET</p>
                    <p>All shares are 21 Making up Prices. Latest Prices</p>
                    <p>Shares Issued.</p>
                    <p>and fully paid</p>
                    <p>sisted.</p>
                    <p>exceps where</p>
                    <p>144 www TVE</p>
                    <p>312</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>114</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>144</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>oposing Byndaf</p>
                    <p>here)</p>
                    <p>United Afrin</p>
                    <p>Budan Exploration (10</p>
                    <p>414 www</p>
                    <p>November 8-</p>
                    <p>November 11.</p>
                    <p>11,9 1/8</p>
                    <p>PILULES</p>
                    <p>BUDORTRA</p>
                    <p>DEHAUT</p>
                    <p>DE PARIS</p>
                    <p>a'hésitent pas-4 se parger, quand elles en ont besoin. Elles ne craignent at
                        le dégodt at la fatigue, parce que, &amp; l'opposé des autres purgatifs,
                        celui-ci n'epère bien que lorsqu'il est pris avec de bons alimenta et des
                        fortifiantes, telles que vin, café, the Chacus choisit, pour se purgar
                        Pheure et le repas qui lai conviennent ecenpations.La Patigue Ce in
                        purgation étant annulée par Pertel de la bonne alimentation,</p>
                    <p>as se décide aisément &amp; recom encer gatant de fois que</p>
                    <p>cala est nécessaire</p>
                    <p>L'EGYPTIAN GAZETTE est en vente</p>
                    <p>dans les rast du Caire tous les soirs, à</p>
                    <p>7h. 80, excepté les dimanches et jours</p>
                    <p>Heide. Ta journal at aussi vente our Patent Fuel Swansea Graigola 21/6 carse
                        du Caire, d'Al</p>
                    <p>de Dame , de Haft-Royal et de Baparie</p>
                    <p>Allontie Poundry Onbe 38 Cole</p>
                    <p>de Testal</p>
                    <p>ENTIREMENT VERSES</p>
                    <p>AGENCES D'EGYFTE</p>
                    <p>(@enny Bags).</p>
                    <p>Free all Pills</p>
                    <p>OOTTON PACKS.</p>
                    <p>(own and he </p>
                    <p>(11 by 11)</p>
                    <p>186 ALEXANDRIE-LE OAIBS-PORT-SAID</p>
                    <p>Avances sur Marchandises, Consignation.</p>
                    <p>(11 by 10)</p>
                    <p>by 10) (11 by 10</p>
                    <p># by 101</p>
                    <p>ONION POCKETS</p>
                    <p>OBEDIT LYONNAIS tale des avances (sewn and hewed) sur marenandices, telles
                        que t</p>
                    <p>COTONE, GRAINES DE COTON, CEREALES, SUCRES, ete.</p>
                    <p>Il reçoit également des marchandise</p>
                    <p>soit en dépos libre, avee droite de maner</p>
                    <p>104 on (40 by (by 10)</p>
                    <p>GRAIN BACKS</p>
                    <p>www and humal)</p>
                    <p>SUGAR BAGE</p>
                    <p>asgs, soit en consignation, pour la vente at (4 by by 38/ Barple on a
                        l'oran</p>
                    <p>41</p>
                    <p>97</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>11.</p>
                    <p>8-10-004</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
