<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!--Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-09-09">October 18, 2023<!-- October 18, 2023 --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 1904-11-22 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-22">Tuesday, November 22,
                        1904<!-- November 22, 1904 --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/mode/1up">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p> COMPANY LIMITED-</p>
                    <p> his Company's spent of harine felegraph cables is mot direct and quickest
                        means of communication from pt to Eampe, North and South America, East,
                        South West Africa, India, Autralia, New Zealand, Chins Japan. mision,
                        telegrams should be marked</p>
                    <p> were quick</p>
                    <p> Eastern</p>
                    <p> latest average time to London, see daily balletto paper</p>
                    <p> TATIONS IN EGTIT: Almadria, Cairo, Boes, Pa 6k, Port-Said, Sukin. Head
                        Office, London.</p>
                    <p> EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p> THE</p>
                    <p> The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p> No. 7,052)</p>
                    <p> ALEXANOBIA, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904.</p>
                    <p> [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</p>
                    <p> COMFANY, LIMITED</p>
                    <p> detze</p>
                    <p> de albis tigraphiques sous-marins eyes de commattication le ple ples faple
                        pour Europe, Amérique Ford et de Sud arentale, méridicale et cidentale, In
                        Ind Chine Te Japon Pour aerer une vent porter-Fiest Voir le temps yen de
                        Lendres STATIONS</p>
                    <p> eninsular &amp; Oriental S. N. Company. British India S. N. Company,
                        Limited. Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Coy.</p>
                    <p> The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said. on or about the</p>
                    <p> wing dates:</p>
                    <p> MALACCA</p>
                    <p> "SUMATRA</p>
                    <p> Malta and London.</p>
                    <p> Marshes, Plymouth and Lenden. Marseilles, Plymouth and London. Malts and
                        Lenden.</p>
                    <p> 4,046 Tons</p>
                    <p> Sorember 1</p>
                    <p> for</p>
                    <p> Malta and London.</p>
                    <p> 4,807</p>
                    <p> "OURANA"</p>
                    <p> 6,610</p>
                    <p> "EGYPT</p>
                    <p> 7912</p>
                    <p> 5 December</p>
                    <p> MANILA.</p>
                    <p> 4210</p>
                    <p> 11</p>
                    <p> "BARDINIA"</p>
                    <p> 8574</p>
                    <p> MACEDONIA"</p>
                    <p> 10,819</p>
                    <p> "MARMORA</p>
                    <p> 10,819</p>
                    <p> 1,006</p>
                    <p> 4074</p>
                    <p> 9713</p>
                    <p> "PERA"</p>
                    <p> SUNDA</p>
                    <p> PURINA"</p>
                    <p> The BRINDISI</p>
                    <p> Malta and London.</p>
                    <p> Marseilles, Plymonth and London.</p>
                    <p> Marselle, Plymouth and Lendon. Marvelles and Tendon</p>
                    <p> Malta and London Marettios, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p> Port-Baid to London via Brindisi</p>
                    <p> MAIL AND PASSENGER STEAM SHIPS. SAILINGS FROM SUBZ London and Calcutta
                        Line.</p>
                    <p> Chief-Office: Sharia Boulac,</p>
                    <p> Grand Continental Hotel Buildings Brack Uger, Uppte dary Hotel, Chies
                        Regular weekly, Tourist Steamer Departures between CATRO and AssoUAN by the
                        following steamers 1904-</p>
                    <p> Cailing at Aser, Cosowo and Manas Outward, and Max (GOs and PLYMOUTH
                        optional) Homeward Forteghly Service in connection with the Co's Indian Mail
                        Line and monthly with the East African Mail Line between Apar, Mom and ZAPAL
                        OUTWARD: 8.8. Muttra November 26- HOMEWARD: B:B. Mombasa...... Nov. 23
                        MAYFLOWER PUBFTAN</p>
                    <p> Queensland Line of Steamers between London and Brisbane. MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p> Ciling at Cotos, BATAVIA, GODTOWN, TORTIL, Bewas, and BOCKHAMPTON 8.8.
                        "ITIA," will mil from Saws on or about the 14th December. cried. los rucu,
                        Panlabs, and</p>
                    <p> BEMARKS and Carge backed through Gulf, Afrios, Bar</p>
                    <p> money, sa below, inefode</p>
                    <p> hoard for payment</p>
                    <p> or leave PORT-BAID ar arrival of Ladian Mail. Combined steamer ander in
                        which there ng car fars from PORT-BAID to LONDON vis BRINDISI or via
                        MARSEILLES 42911.</p>
                    <p> To the Best</p>
                    <p> The Mall Seasors leave BURZ for ADEN and BOMBAY every Wednesday, and for
                        AUSTRALIA ELINA every aberse Wednesday. &amp;mmer isave for CALCUTTA,
                        fightly, and another for 2. Pagers bark as PORT-SAID.</p>
                    <p> For all further information apply so Me. Thos. Coost &amp; Bor (gp)
                        Lad....</p>
                    <p> Grones Borta, Baqi</p>
                    <p> Messrs. HABULDAN &amp; Co....</p>
                    <p> Company's Agents,</p>
                    <p> CATBO</p>
                    <p> PORT-BAID ALEXANDRIA. /</p>
                    <p> F. G. DAVIDSON, Superlatendent P. &amp; O. B. N. Company in Myps BURZ</p>
                    <p> 81-19-00</p>
                    <p> ient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers.</p>
                    <p> UTWARDS to AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p> B.M.B. Orotava will leave Bo about Groya</p>
                    <p> Deo. Dee.</p>
                    <p> 16</p>
                    <p> TOMEWARDS NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY B.M...
                        Ortona will leave Pors-bald about... Dee. 5</p>
                    <p> Orizaba</p>
                    <p> 19</p>
                    <p> Homeward meets are sometimes before their advertised dates. engers landed
                        and embarked at Ismailia, Quarantine Regulations permitting, free of all
                        expense.</p>
                    <p> From Port</p>
                    <p> Agents in LONDON, Managing Agents in INDIA, Agecie PORT BAID, AREA PORT BAID
                        Thon Ucek</p>
                    <p> For further partie</p>
                    <p> comfort for</p>
                    <p> MONEY FROM SURE AND IMA</p>
                    <p> Twe Thirde of at Ch</p>
                    <p> CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p> Docember 9th VICTORIA xord PURITAN 80th MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p> 1905.</p>
                    <p> Weekly SECOND CATARACT SERVICE by the First Class Tourist Steamer INDIANA
                        AGENTS FOR PRINCIPAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANIE Through Bookings to Khartoum
                        and Gondebors RAILWAY TICKETS TO ALL PARTS OF EGYPT. FREIGHT SERVICE by tam
                        barges between ALEXANDRA and CAIRO SAVOY HOTEL Elephantine Island, Assuas,
                        Company's Property. LAW UNION &amp; CROWN INSURANCE COMPANY OF LONDON,
                        ENGLAND. Funds in Hand-</p>
                    <p> Established 1825.)</p>
                    <p> 25,500,000 Annual Income-4800,000.</p>
                    <p> LOANS.</p>
                    <p> Applications for Loans on eligible Agricultural or City Property are invited
                        and may be addressed to Mr. W. E. KINGSFORD, Karla Cherifele, Sharia
                        Kaar-e-Nil. Caire, ers FIRE INSURANCE.</p>
                    <p> ply to G. BEYTS &amp; Co., Aga, Bues, 31-19-904 Messrs. ED. SUAMES &amp;
                        Co., Alexandria.</p>
                    <p> ANCHOR LINE, Limited.</p>
                    <p> (HENDERSON BROTHERS), LONDON, LIVERPOOL, AND GLASGOW. First class passenger
                        steamers, Booking Passengers and Cargo through to Ports in INDIA, EUROPE
                        &amp; AMERICA Bailings Fortnightly from Bues. 8.8. Bohemia</p>
                    <p> For LONDON</p>
                    <p> Dec. 10 For CALCUTTA 8.8. Ayria...... December 7 Nov. 24 For BOMBAY 8.8.
                        Circaria... November 26</p>
                    <p> The Company's Agents in &amp;gypt for Fire Insurance are Mesere. GUSTAV
                        BRACH &amp; Co. Alexandria.</p>
                    <p> 24/24-30-4-004</p>
                    <p> NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.</p>
                    <p> Fortnightly Bervice from ALEXANDRIA (Passengers and Freight). Contounding
                        our be 10 of Naver To NAPLES and MARSEILLAS, walk the Twinsrew-baloon
                        Sahleswig (7,100 tone)</p>
                    <p> For MARSEILLES 8.8. Manlia &amp;LIVERPOOL Gaiden Pars from Port-Haid, to
                        bisitar 69 Marvelis, Liverpool (all see route) #16 London (all so route)
                        413, Lendoning ALEXANDRIA every alternate Wedessday at 3pm.: 16 a 80 Nov.,
                        is Deo, Ia di 36 Marsalles 416140 Pangurs anbarking at malis 41 mors, Sacs
                        43 mere, le 20 redmotion allered of the Army of Occupation and Government
                        employs Throngh tickets led to New-York (vil Glagow). Farm on application
                        Agente in Cairo, Mats THOMAB 000K &amp; BON, Pors-Beid, Mrs CORY BROTHERS
                        &amp; Co., La.. For further particulars of Freight or Pinge apply to G.
                        BEYTS &amp; Co., Sues.</p>
                    <p> The following steamers are intended to leave FORT BAID:</p>
                    <p> 81-13-904 HOMEWARD: for Bremen or Hamburg NAPLIN, GENOA, (GERALTAR),
                        SOUTHAMPTON, ARTVARP</p>
                    <p> Novom</p>
                    <p> Pa. Ras, Leveres BARBERUA</p>
                    <p> PRAUSSEN</p>
                    <p> to Marasilies..</p>
                    <p> Port-Baid to Naples....... 1 Class, 411 and Class, 4 1 Brd Class, 4410</p>
                    <p> 16</p>
                    <p> 10</p>
                    <p> 10-</p>
                    <p> "</p>
                    <p> 18</p>
                    <p> 10</p>
                    <p> 10-</p>
                    <p> MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p> ZETEN OLDENBURG PRINUMS ALIUS 1001 SCHARNHORST</p>
                    <p> 81-18-904</p>
                    <p> 8 16-</p>
                    <p> OUTWARD: for Chian and Japan V SURS, ADRY, COLOMBO, PERANG, SINGAPORE</p>
                    <p> 16 Nev,</p>
                    <p> ONEISENAU SEMEN</p>
                    <p> Dec</p>
                    <p> to Plymouths or Tübary. earn sickes no longer issued, bus pengers paying the
                        fall, fare in one direction are allowed an mens of one-third of their fare
                        back if the resorn voyage be made wishin four months of arrival, or ssement
                        of 20$ if remara voyage be made wishin six months of arrival. to, Cairo
                        1-THOMAS COOK &amp; Bow. Alexandra B. J. Moss &amp; Co.-For all information
                        apply to m. STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Port-Said and Port-Tewik Sues).
                        81-18-904</p>
                    <p> IBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p> SPROLAL REDUCED RATES DURING THE SUMMER SEASON.</p>
                    <p> FARDS to GOLOMBO. TUTICORIN, etc., and BANGOON</p>
                    <p> se. Yerkakere 6 tons will have Bues abou. November 25.</p>
                    <p> 3.8 Warwickshire, tons, will leave dues about Decumber 7,</p>
                    <p> BWARDS MakskiLLE LOADOR.</p>
                    <p> tp. Worcestershire, 60 tons will leave Port-Said about Novemi'or 29,
                        Shrupere, Titus will leave Port-aid about Desember 3</p>
                    <p> 68 from turcald to Marsellies 12.0.0 London 417., mo0 48,10.0, Rangoon,
                        487.10.0, Fissed with Befrigerators, loota io Light, Blootrie fans and all
                        recent improvements. xperienced Stewardesses and earsons carried, Agents in
                        Cairo: Meers, THO COOK &amp; SON. parstoniais apply W. STAFLEDON &amp; SONS,
                        Port-Said &amp; Port-Tewalk (anes). 81-19-904</p>
                    <p> HEDIVIAL MAIL LINE.</p>
                    <p> FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p> Gronen-Turkey Liss,</p>
                    <p> we sioscore love Alesandria every Wednesday 6p.. for PIRMOS (Athens); SMYRNA
                        Facts, and London.</p>
                    <p> Established 1886. Capital 41,000,000. Beserve Fund 4835,000. THE IMPERIAL
                        FIRE OFFICE united with THE ALLIANCE ASSURANCE Co.,LD. -1, Old Broad Barees,
                        LONDON-Hablished 180-Tom Finde exooed 10,000,000. Policies insted as SUEZ by
                        G. BEYTS &amp; Co., Agent.</p>
                    <p> 81-13-904</p>
                    <p> 27nd inst</p>
                    <p> Deutsche Levante-Linie.</p>
                    <p> Mail and Passenger Bamatupe. Begular shree-weekly bervice from HAMBURG, VIA
                        ANTWERP &amp; MALTA, 10 ALEXANDRIA and vice versa, adriang goods from all
                        the principal GasMAN BAILWAY STATIONS on direes Bill of Lading to ALEXANDMA
                        and all the propel port of Bers, BYRIAN Coser, 6, at the avotumble shrough
                        me of the Davrick VARENAN (se). EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p> SEYDLITS BOON BAYKEN ZIETEN</p>
                    <p> FRIEDRICH D. GR. BREMEN</p>
                    <p> Go-Tone</p>
                    <p> 10014</p>
                    <p> For Australia</p>
                    <p> FOR FURTAR PARTICULAR area 20 2D MOBSTS OF NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD Catie,
                        Alesandria, Port Se OTTO STERZING, AGENT Caire, Ora SQUAR C. M. SCHOELLES,
                        AGENT ALEEANDRIA, Ultr THOR COOK &amp; BO (UL ANG BARURRAD CARO in
                        ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p> Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation.</p>
                    <p> Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste-Venice Line,</p>
                    <p> 8.8. Siegfried, now on the berth loading will mail for Rotterdam and Hamburg
                        on the B.B. Thasos now in port will sail for Bayront on the 38rd inst.
                        Lesbos from Antwerp will mil for beyrons on the 20rd inst. Weekly Express
                        Maal Bervice. Somers Jane Alesandria every For write and parous apply to
                        ADOLPHESTRUSS, &amp;exandra, Agent,- 18-9-905 Brinda, arving Tonday morning
                        in me for express to Paris, Lond Trieste We day noon connecting with Vienna
                        apres (T-Ode exprospe Imaly and Germany. No... 13 p.m. Cleopatra Ongt. A.
                        Ivaltiob. Semiramis</p>
                    <p> EGYPTIAN NITRATE AND PHOSPHATE SYNDICATE.</p>
                    <p> WORKS AT KEFT, MAALA AND SABIEH. OFFICES AT LUXOR. Egyptian Nitrates and
                        Ground Phosphates sold separately and mixed accord- ing to the requirements
                        of the individual crops. 24833-81-10-905</p>
                    <p> MEN, and CONSTANTINOPM, in commoosion with the Orient Magus Wain-de-luze for
                        Belgrade Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Company, Ld.</p>
                    <p> Palestine-Syria Line.</p>
                    <p> cars leave Alexandria every p., and Fort Bald every Banday at 6p.m., fos
                        ATTA, MEMBISA, conmusing in sense weeks to LARNACA and LIMASSOL (Cype), Red
                        Sea Liser</p>
                    <p> and ZAMBO, and sepsioning in alsamase weeks to NUAKIM, MANOWAR, HORIDAE
                        DEN,</p>
                    <p> Desk abaire provided for the use of</p>
                    <p> exellent celelse and male wine free.</p>
                    <p> grans may be seen and housed at the Company's Agnoles as Alexandria, Cairo,
                        Pors Thos. Oool a son of obes Tourtes Agency,</p>
                    <p> 81-18-906</p>
                    <p> he Moss S.S. Company, Limited.</p>
                    <p> LVPORAUTA. ET MA</p>
                    <p> 6,700</p>
                    <p> freighs to Leona</p>
                    <p> 2.M. &amp; HARD</p>
                    <p> Mingle,</p>
                    <p> abous Baturday, November 26,</p>
                    <p> T.M. 8.</p>
                    <p> Sur, og</p>
                    <p> RONS &amp; CR, Alexandra, Ago followed by SETI</p>
                    <p> www, new-surt and other .. towns on be abond</p>
                    <p> inclnaive of Ballway fare through to and from Ostro. Partienlags on
                        application.</p>
                    <p> HENDERSON &amp; CO.'s LINE.</p>
                    <p> Sri Bass Port-aid tornsgasty for London or Liverpool dress</p>
                    <p> Pe Lighs</p>
                    <p> SALOON (4) FARK AIR.</p>
                    <p> 8. AMARAFOORA 6600 Tone will leave PORT-SAID about Nov. 7600 #MARTABAN
                        BANGOON. 6000</p>
                    <p> (lators Improvements,</p>
                    <p> 97 for Liverpool.</p>
                    <p> Des.</p>
                    <p> 9 for Laverpool,</p>
                    <p> 36 for Liverpool. Due in Leados or Liverpool 13 days thereafter. AN WORMS
                        &amp; G., Ford TMOS. GOOK &amp; SOM. Bayat) Ld.. Otros 6. J. GRAGE &amp;
                        Ga.. Asandrin</p>
                    <p> 81-19-004</p>
                    <p> Thos. Cook &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p> (EOTP), LAMIN</p>
                    <p> HEAD OFFICE-LUDGATE CIRCUS-LONDON. CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE-CAIRO, near
                        SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL Alexandria, Port-Said, Ismailia, Suez, Luxor, Assouan,
                        Halfa &amp; Khartoum.</p>
                    <p> TOURIST AND GENERAL PASSENGER AGENTS. BANKERS. Baggage and Forwarding
                        Agents. NILE STEAMER SERVICES. TOURIST SERVICE. The large and spendidly ap-
                        inted 8.8. Rajeses, will leave Cairo on Tuesday, vember 29th, for Luxor,
                        Assouan and Philse. Other lings Dec. 6, 13, etc.</p>
                    <p> EXPRESS SERVICE-Steamers will leave Cairo ery Monday and Friday during the
                        season. First</p>
                    <p> (Moolete des Entrepote d'Ales arie) BONDED WAREHOUSES</p>
                    <p> IN ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, FORT SAID, and SUEZ. Special Departments for cleaning
                        and forwarding and for a logge and parcel Express Bervies Goede delimored
                        against ask for sound of shippers. 91191-1-4-00</p>
                    <p> Telephone Company of Egypt, Limited.</p>
                    <p> 19</p>
                    <p> Nov. 264 pm. Habiburg Marsinobeh. Dee. 8 Uleopatra
                        Alexandria-Patras-tirindisi-Trieste Line.. Sector Iesves Alasaadna on or
                        abona rd November, 7th and slat Desaber.</p>
                    <p> Far East Line.</p>
                    <p> (D from Bos). To Aden, Bombay, Colombo, Pana abama, Kobe about Deo. &amp;.
                        To Aden and Bombay too To Adon, Colombo, Madma, Hangoon and Onesti ahone
                        November 90. East African Line.</p>
                    <p> To Adi, Momba, Zambar, Boiro, Delagon Bay, Dusion about Deenhor 4.
                        Syrian-Caramania Line</p>
                    <p> می.</p>
                    <p> Steamer leave Alexandria on or about November 14 and 98, Desember 19 and
                        26.</p>
                    <p> Syrian-Cyprus-Caramanian Line.</p>
                    <p> Beamer 1.aver Alexandria on or about Novaber 31, Desember &amp; and 19.</p>
                    <p> For</p>
                    <p> Lo Leon Hass: Oniro Agent Special</p>
                    <p> CACRO-ALBRANDRIA TREEFRONT-Baten so follows-P.T.&amp; for each 8 minutes, or
                        traction of 3 minutos P.T. 10 for over 8 up to sinuses communion PYRO
                        CAL-Urons: Catre, Central Office, Opers and New Bar Helcoat, Central Offes,
                        Maison Parvis: Alexandria of the Army of Mark's Hathings, Bayan Bar</p>
                    <p> Homieh, Central Oflox dan afsne Udine</p>
                    <p> tion and that Action Government o</p>
                    <p> HOTEL BRISTOL, CAIRO. GUARDIAN ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED,</p>
                    <p> Fail 8.nth, Electric Light, opposite Eebekich Gardens, Large Verandahs,
                        Moderate Charges, CHAB. BAUEK Proprietor. This Hotel is beansifully fitted
                        up and is in the most central part of Cairo. The terms for pension are at
                        the rate of ten shillings a day. Special terms for officers of the Army of
                        Occupation.</p>
                    <p> 34,883-81-10 905</p>
                    <p> OF LONDON. Established 1821.</p>
                    <p> CAPITAL PAID UP AND INVESTED ONE MILLION STERLING Annual Income</p>
                    <p> NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA. Total Funds</p>
                    <p> Pris elem Hotel, hosted in Rosetts Avenus, the font quarter in the Town. Two
                        minutes freds Railway Station Connistes and the Opers Hossat. Biserie Lighs
                        Throughout Ferfees Banitary Arrangements Magnificent Ball, Re ption,
                        Reading, and Muale Rooms and Bmoking Room</p>
                    <p> FINE TERRAGE IN TEN ATANTE-OPLENDID GARDUM. 88746-38-3-808</p>
                    <p> OMNIBUS MEST ALL TRAINS AND STRAMERS HENRI CHAMOULLRAU, PROPRESTOR</p>
                    <p> 6895,000 65,200,000:</p>
                    <p> Agents for Egypt and the Sudan- HEWAT &amp; Co., Alexandria. sun Insurance
                        LONDON.-Founded 1710.-Total sum insured in 1908 4487,000,000. Agents: LON
                        HELLER, Corn, and BEHREND &amp; Co., Alexandria</p>
                    <p> Ofoe,</p>
                    <p> 16.1-908</p>
                    <p> PORT SAID. SAVOY HOTEL. The Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe Insurance
                        Co.</p>
                    <p> NEW FIRST-CLASS HOTEL, OVERLOOKING THE HARBOUR &amp; OPPOSITE CUSTOM HOURS
                        Open all the year round. Well-appointed Bar. MODERATE OHARGR8.-8PBOIAL TREMS
                        FOR RESIDENTS</p>
                    <p> National Bank of Egypt.</p>
                    <p> CAPITAL L 2,500,000 RESERVE (environ): L 700,000. Gouverneur: Sia ELWIN,
                        PALMER, KOB, KCM.O. Sage Social au Caire, Succursale à Almondria. Agnes à
                        Mansourah, Khartoum, Tantah, Fayoum, Zagarig, Ariont, Suakim et Londres (45,
                        King William Street) LA NATIONAL BANK OF EGYPT reçois des dépôts à sermen
                        fixes, fait den avande et onvre des comptes courants our res, valeurs et
                        marchandises Elle s'occupe de l'aebat et de la vente d'effets sur l'aranger,
                        de l'escompte, ainsi que de temes opérations de Banque 81-18-904</p>
                    <p> CAPITAL: 410,000,000.</p>
                    <p> LIVERPOOL. FIRE AND LIFE. Total Claims paid exceed...</p>
                    <p> 840,000,000 Agents: LEON HELLER, Cairo, &amp; PEEL &amp; Co.. Alexandria,
                        NORTHERN FIRE AND LIFE ASSURANCE Coy.</p>
                    <p> The undersigned agents are authorised to ferme policies on behalf of the
                        above Company at moderate rot IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK, Alexandria,
                        Orro-TERZING, Catro, GRORO, MEINDOKE, S 8113904</p>
                    <p> 1072</p>
                    <p> 811908</p>
                    <p> LONDON ASSURANCE CORPORATION. Established 1720. A: BANK OF EGYPT, Limited
                        ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE. INCORPORATED A. D.. 1790 Chief Omee: ROYAL
                        EXORANGE, LONDON, E.0. FUNDS IN HAND EXORED **** 4,800,000 CLAIMS PAID
                        $40,000,000 FIRE MARINE ALEXANDRIAM. J. B. CAFFARI Mr. J. B. CAFFARI Beas.
                        Mr. GO. MINBOKE</p>
                    <p> BANK. ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</p>
                    <p> IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK. HRAD OPPIOR IN CONSTANTINOPLE. ONI AGO LONDON &amp;
                        PARIS. EBANCHES IN ALL THE PRINCIPAL TOWNS IN TURKEY. Agencies in Egypt:
                        ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, &amp; PORT SAID. Securities Wouvent past and fored
                        periods Parohsen and sale of lars of credi</p>
                    <p> Advance and Sharm phops and</p>
                    <p> the world</p>
                    <p> parture November 4, 19 days on the Nile for £22. Egyptian Delta Light
                        Railways Co., Limited.</p>
                    <p> SPECIAL COMBINED-RAR WAY AND STEAMER LE TOURS AT GREATLY REDUCED FARES
                        WEEKLY SERVICE TO RALFA, ERARTOUM, &amp; BUDAM. SPECIAL STEAMERS AND
                        DARABEAHH FOR PRIVATE PARTIE rular Service of Freight Steamers between CAIRO
                        and HALFA. Bastions and Landing in</p>
                    <p> o's Interpreters in sniforms are present at the to sexies pagers holding
                        their sake</p>
                    <p> Tere to Palestine, Syria, and Doors, Best Only equipment Lewest changes.</p>
                    <p> Connections made with the most important trains of the Egyptian, State
                        Railway in the Provinces of Behers, Gharbieh, Dakahlich, Charkish, and
                        Galionbich Through service for gode between all stations of the Company and
                        over 100 pr stations of Kuption Government Radway in Upper and Lower Egypt.
                        Goods may through-booked from or to any station on the Oairo-Halsuan
                        Hallway. The Company 70 stations opened for publis Telegraph Bervice in
                        conjunction with all the Government Telegraph Department. For time tables,
                        torn and re 10-10000 to the affles as Cairo, Alesandria, Damanhour, Tantah
                        of Bagnalg. $1416-01-194</p>
                    <p> CAMBO</p>
                    <p> INSURANCE. Assurance Coy.</p>
                    <p> LIFE The Edinburgh 2ffa MARINE Union Insurans Fidality National Guara Bias
                        accepted at</p>
                    <p> Agents for Bgypt:</p>
                    <p> 19789-10-10-905</p>
                    <p> ety of Canton (Limited.) Suretyship Assco. (Limited.) Olatma liberally and
                        promptly settled. HEWAT &amp; Co., Alexandria.</p>
                    <p> CAIRO SEWAGE TRANSPORT CY., LD.</p>
                    <p> Chief Octos: Sharia Beau, CAIRO. Near the National Bank of 1</p>
                    <p> ENGRAIS NATURELS COMPLETS Engrals Chimiques Organiquse.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"  
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n1/mode/1up">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904</p>
                    <p>Royal Insurance Coy. IND, COOPE &amp;</p>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>
                    <p>LARGEST FIBE OFFIOR IN THE WORLD.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; Co., Agnis, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; Co., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LD.</p>
                    <p>$1-3.905</p>
                    <p>THE BRITISH</p>
                    <p>AERATED &amp; MINERAL</p>
                    <p>WATER</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTORY.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISH D 1782.J HASELDEN &amp; Co., Agents, Alexandria. FEED. OTT &amp;
                        Co., B &amp;guste, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>N. SPATHIS</p>
                    <p>CAIRO Esboklek</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Rue Avereff,</p>
                    <p>Soda Water, Lemonade, Ginger Ale, Ginger Beer, Tonio Water Pomegranade,
                        Orangende, Pineapple, Champagne Oider, etc., etc. Water guaranteed by
                        CARLAND'S FR (PAT'S ST). Inventor of WHISKY &amp; BODA and BRANDY &amp;
                        SODA, bottled ready for use.</p>
                    <p>J. CALVET&amp;Co....</p>
                    <p>LOUIS BONDERS</p>
                    <p>AUGUST ENGEL MACKIS&amp;Co.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGAST IN BUTT AND SOUDAN FOR</p>
                    <p>DUNVILLE &amp; Cor. TAD....</p>
                    <p>Ww LANAHAN &amp; SON</p>
                    <p>THE COOK &amp; BERNHEIMER do.</p>
                    <p>STONE &amp; BON</p>
                    <p>FREUND BALLOB &amp; Co...</p>
                    <p>PIERRE BINSET</p>
                    <p>TERRABONA TEA COMPANY, La.</p>
                    <p>BORDEAUX Wines &amp; Cognacs Beawa Champagnes. WIRSBADEN Rhine and Moselle
                        Wines.: Grassow Lagavalin, White Horse Cullar, &amp; other Whiskies.</p>
                    <p>BELPART</p>
                    <p>Old Irish Whiskies.</p>
                    <p>Bangabels XXXX Whiskey</p>
                    <p>New Yoax</p>
                    <p>01 Valley Wai key and Gold Lion Cookills, Lopes Guinases Stout &amp; Bass
                        Pale Al TORISO Vermouth. OHITS Tras.</p>
                    <p>Vermouth &amp; Aperitivas.</p>
                    <p>Depos for Prinde Metternich's "Biohardaqu-ile," the beat mineral table water
                        in the world. Great assortment of Wines, Spirits, Liqueurs, of the finest
                        Brands, etc.</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>IN</p>
                    <p>18-1-906</p>
                    <p>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK, MARSH, SON &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>LIMITED:</p>
                    <p>LONDON, PARIS, ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, MALTA, GIBRALTAR, TANTAH, AND PORT
                        SAID.</p>
                    <p>Subscribed Capital 1.200,000 Paid up</p>
                    <p>Reserve Fund</p>
                    <p>&amp;</p>
                    <p>400,000 350,000</p>
                    <p>Limited.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS &amp; EXPORTERS</p>
                    <p>ELECTRICAL ACCESSORIES AND FITTINGS.</p>
                    <p>The Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Limited, 15, Gerrard St., Soho,</p>
                    <p>undertakes every description of banking busines</p>
                    <p>on the most favourable conditios.:</p>
                    <p>Current accounts opened with commercial ha ises</p>
                    <p>London, W.</p>
                    <p>and private individuals in conformity with th-ND AT BIRMINGHAM &amp;
                        MANOHESTER</p>
                    <p>castom of Banker</p>
                    <p>Fixed deposits for one year certain received at à per cent per annum.
                        Depo-its at interest for shorter periods are also received at mates to be
                        agreed upon. Letters of Credis for the use of travellers are isted payable
                        in al parte of the World. Approved hills discounted.</p>
                    <p>Bille, documentary invoices, eto, collected. Deaf and singapoio transfers
                        inued pay- able all over the World.</p>
                    <p>Foreign exchange bought and sold. Advsners made upon approved securities and
                        upon cotton, cotton-seed, sugar and other mer abandies.</p>
                    <p>The parchaee and sale of stocks and shares on the London Stock Exchange and
                        on the loesl and Continental Bourses, undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Customers osa deposit their valuables, bonds, , for le enstody in the Bank's
                        fire-proof strong-rooms, and the Bank will attend to the collecuen of the
                        coupons and drawn bonds deposited as they fall due</p>
                    <p>Mercentile credits issued.</p>
                    <p>Annaides, pensions, dividends, eto, collected. All farther particulars and
                        information can be oblained on application.</p>
                    <p>The officers and olerke, of the Bank are pledged to secrecy as to the tran-
                        sactions of customers.</p>
                    <p>Brus</p>
                    <p>DAILY WEATHER REPORT:</p>
                    <p>OPENRTATIONS. BY SURVEY DEPARTMENT</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Max, Temp, is the charte</p>
                    <p>Unsteady in Fury rough 20 deg</p>
                    <p>REMARKS</p>
                    <p>About noon yesterday the wind commmed to freshes from Hight mibday shower,
                        the wasther becoming rather, ol and ally, giving vary appesrose of an
                        Approaching ators, Throughout the night the wasther was very at The wipd how
                        from WW timer in g with viol-mes just so fret gale. There was very rough us,
                        with front heavy showers of fain, the register being 600 The beetle fall
                        lightly.</p>
                    <p>In Cair veterday morning the most unpleasant experienced for two pears &amp;
                        torty sold wind, accompanied</p>
                    <p>Sy is of ontd rain, swept over the city..between</p>
                    <p>19, when the clots began to break, and by one</p>
                    <p>OTHER STATIONS</p>
                    <p>For the 4 hour dinem. Toturday,</p>
                    <p>Wedy Halfs</p>
                    <p>FORNER RATIONA</p>
                    <p>AR</p>
                    <p>Onlin Might</p>
                    <p>PRAINS OF TER MOON</p>
                    <p>THE BUN</p>
                    <p>Sole Agents</p>
                    <p>FOR EGYPT AND THE SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>L. REIS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Roe Cherif Pachs,</p>
                    <p>Oppoet'e Mesure. Thomas Cook &amp; Son, ALEXANDRIA..</p>
                    <p>s8761-15-114-904</p>
                    <p>VISITORS AND RESIDENTS</p>
                    <p>KINDLY NOTE THAT</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX,</p>
                    <p>THE CAIRO WEEKLY NEWSPAPER,</p>
                    <p>Is Under Entirely New Management</p>
                    <p>AND WILL BE PUBLISHED AS USUAL</p>
                    <p>During the Season 1904/5.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTION</p>
                    <p>For the Season P.T. 20</p>
                    <p>PAYABLE IN ADVANCE</p>
                    <p>All Communications and Subscriptions to be addressed to the EDrron, Mr. P. P.
                        GRAVES.</p>
                    <p>And for Advertising Space apply to Mr. W. E. WALTON.</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX O fices,</p>
                    <p>Hotel du Nil, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>94808 10</p>
                    <p>PHOTOGRAPHIE REISER</p>
                    <p>(RRIS-&amp; BIND) SPECIALITY:</p>
                    <p>Childrens Photos. High Class Portraits.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA1 OLD Bows Bran OrPosers OPFOWAN BANK.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>MUMBERING</p>
                    <p>MACHINES</p>
                    <p>AND.</p>
                    <p>DATING STAMPS</p>
                    <p>J MARGOSCHES</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>RU AL</p>
                    <p>STATIONERY ENGRAVING</p>
                    <p>PRINTING</p>
                    <p>ROAD</p>
                    <p>OFFICE</p>
                    <p>BREWERS,</p>
                    <p>Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>BURTON-ON-TRENT AND ROMFORD.</p>
                    <p>PALE ALE &amp; DOUBLE STOUT,</p>
                    <p>23047</p>
                    <p>SPECIALLY BREWED FOR EXPORT.</p>
                    <p>Agents:</p>
                    <p>MESSRS. JOHN ROSS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO:</p>
                    <p>THEODORE VAFIADIS &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF</p>
                    <p>HIGH CLASS</p>
                    <p>Bombay, Caloutta,</p>
                    <p>30-5:00</p>
                    <p>18117</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. CAFFARI'S ECONOMICAL STORES</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>REMOVED TO</p>
                    <p>Rue de l'Eglise Debbane</p>
                    <p>No. 8.</p>
                    <p>Boulevard de Ramleh No. 6.</p>
                    <p>16-11-904</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Cigarette Co.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURE HIGH-CLASS CIGARETTES ONLY. Latest Award: Grand Prix St. Louis
                        1904.</p>
                    <p>"AL HAYAT." HELOUAN.</p>
                    <p>FIRST CLASS HEALTH RESORT. Unrivalled position on the Mokattam Hille 96
                        metres above the Nile surrounded by desert. Every modern appliances.
                        Resident Medical Director. Illustrated Prospectus sent free on
                        application.</p>
                    <p>94803 80-11-904</p>
                    <p>HOTEL DU NIL, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>IS NOW OPEN</p>
                    <p>247:0-81 3.905</p>
                    <p>H. D. RAWLINGS, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>BODA WATER, LEMONADE, &amp; GINGER ALE. As SUPPLIED TO KING AND BOYAS
                        FANBY.</p>
                    <p>Agent:</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. CAFFARI.</p>
                    <p>The George Nungovich Hotels.</p>
                    <p>Grand Hotel, Heleuan.-Finest and most luxurious Hotel near Cairo. Patunised
                        by Royalty. Moderate charges. Special terms for resident Hotel des
                        Bains-Most comfortable hotel, opposite the Baths. Pension from P.T. 4.
                        Attached to the above hotels and specially roved for their clients are the
                        Golf Links (18 holes) with English Professional. Own Golf House in the
                        desert. Sulphur Bath Establishment-Sulphur water stronger than any in
                        Europe. Eight European Masseurs and ose Every modern sprovement.</p>
                    <p>THE WORLD'S MEDICINE.</p>
                    <p>BEECHAM'S PILLS</p>
                    <p>Care all Billous and Nervous Disorders, Sick Headache, Constipation, Impaired
                        Digestion, Wind and Pains in Stomach, Disordered Liver and Female Allments.
                        They act like Magie on the Vital Organs, Regulating the Secretions,
                        restoring the long-lost Complexion, bringing back the keen edge of Appetite,
                        and arousing with the Rosebud of Health the whole physical energy of the
                        human frame..</p>
                    <p>BEECHAM'S PILLS are the most popular English family Medicine, and are
                        composed entirely of Medicinal Herbs. They cleanse the stomach, and bowels,
                        purify the blood, invigorate the nervous system, and give tone and energy to
                        the Muscles. BEECHAM'S PILLS have the largest sale of any Medicine in the
                        World.</p>
                    <p>Sold at all Drug Stores In Egypt, is boxes, 4 plastres and 6 plastres.</p>
                    <p>MELLIN'S</p>
                    <p>4-31-405</p>
                    <p>For Infants FOOD</p>
                    <p>and Invalids.</p>
                    <p>Prepared as directed is rich in those sub- stances which nourish and sustain
                        children and sick persons.</p>
                    <p>Always uniform, easily prepared, speedily digested and absorbed.</p>
                    <p>MELLIN'S FOOD WORKS, PECKHAM, S.E.</p>
                    <p>Representative in Egypt, Max Fischer, Cairo and-Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>CIGARES</p>
                    <p>CHAMPAGNE</p>
                    <p>de la HAVANE GEORGE GOULET.</p>
                    <p>de provenance directe</p>
                    <p>et de toutes les meilleures marques</p>
                    <p>Nicolas G. Sabbag</p>
                    <p>IMPORTATEUR GENERAL OUREMSEUR DE 3. A. LE KHEDIVE de less les grasie Clube
                        Hotele Rypla Rue de in Gare du Caire9 ALEXANDRIE Adres Taligraphions: Babbag
                        Alexandrie Telephone No. MS</p>
                    <p>94808-86-904</p>
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. P. Grow</p>
                    <p>Gesells at Calro</p>
                    <p>the Correspondent of the for him should be addressed</p>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>MOLE AGENTS IN EGYPT AND SOUDAN, M. ELEFTERION &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>Halise Armenienne, Rue Averoff. CAIRO,</p>
                    <p>Avenue Boulso, Immeuble Hali.</p>
                    <p>Mensaèle In Alexandria: NICOLAS G SABBAG.</p>
                    <p>CIGARETTES.</p>
                    <p>Factory, Cairo (Egypt)</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES:</p>
                    <p>Hangoon,</p>
                    <p>72 Marchant Street</p>
                    <p>Square</p>
                    <p>19 Basinghall Street, E.O 16-4-906</p>
                    <p>Agents in all the principal Ofties in the World.</p>
                    <p>LE SOLEIL DU FOYER</p>
                    <p>c'est l'éclat des yeux de vos enfants.. Quand ceux-ci pâlissent, une nuée de
                        chagrins obscurcit cette douce lumière. Mais si vous donnez à votre petit
                        malade de</p>
                    <p>L'ÉMULSION SCOTT</p>
                    <p>le chagrin s'envole et la santé revient à votre enfant. Comme l'Emulsion
                        Scott prévient la maladie, rend les enfants forts et conserve à leurs yeux
                        tout leur éclat, ne soyez jamais sans</p>
                    <p>L'ÉMULSION SCOTT,</p>
                    <p>elle vous épargnera, ainsi qu'à vos enfants, des jours et des nuits de
                        souffrances et de désespoir. Veillez bien à ce que le flacon soit enveloppé
                        d'un papier, couleur saumon, portant la marque de fabrique ci-contre.. Si
                        c'est bien L'EMULSION SCOTT</p>
                    <p>Marque de Fabrique. que vous vous procurez, vous tenez votre guérison. En
                        vente chez tous les pharmaciens et droguistes.</p>
                    <p>Thorough efficiency</p>
                    <p>Is proved by the enormous sale of</p>
                    <p>CALVERT'S</p>
                    <p>CARBOLIC</p>
                    <p>Tooth Powder</p>
                    <p>Being antiseptic, its regular use keeps the teeth healthy as well as clean,
                        and also gives them the requisite polish without injuring the enamel. It is
                        at the same time most pleasant to use</p>
                    <p>Calvert's Prickly-heat Soap</p>
                    <p>is very serviceable in bot climates as a preventive of prickly-heat and other
                        irritation of the skin. It is pleasantly perfumed and contains a Crystal
                        Carbolic</p>
                    <p>P. C. CALVERT &amp; Co., Manchester, ENGLAND</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS-Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of gypt (inalading delivery
                        in Alex- andria or posinge to rabeeriber's address) PT 281 por anum, P.T.
                        116 for six month. P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries In the
                        Postal Union F.. 973 (48.168.) per</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.-F.T. 4 per Hos. Minimum abarge P.T. 90. Births, Marriages, or
                        Des the not exceeding three lines, PT, 90, every ad sional Hine P.T. 10.
                        Notices in new columns P.T. 30. per line. Contraete entered into for anding
                        advertiseme</p>
                    <p>weakness in the step they had taken. The Russian Government first accedes to
                        a most important political step and then at the last moment withdraws ite
                        sanction. But instead of putting an absolute veto on the conference it
                        allows the representatives of the Zemstvos to meet in private. The
                        consequences were obvious Radical resolutions are adopted, a Constitution is
                        demanded, together with liberty of conscience, liberty of the Press, liberty
                        of speech, and liberty of education, besides an elective legislative
                        assembly. This private conference was only held on Saturday, but by Monday
                        the facts are known to the world and the ball has been set rolling which,
                        under the leadership of a Slavonic Mirabeau or Lafs- yette, may lead to the
                        ruin of militant auto- eracy throughout the Russian Empire:</p>
                    <p>At the same time, serious observers of the conditions of modern Russis, even
                        among those who sympathise with the aspirations of the Russian people for a
                        form of government which will give some legitimate scope for their ener
                        gies, entertain grave doubts as to the capacity of the Russians for
                        self-government. The mem- bers of the bureaucracy, indeed, base their claim
                        to govern Russia, when they condescend to argue the matter at all; on the
                        ground that acceptance of office the new Minister of the In- no other
                        government is possible. Soon after his</p>
                    <p>terior made a mendorable declaration." Abroad," said Prince Sviatopolk
                        Mirski, "people speak of a new Constitution for Russia: such a thing is,
                        impossible under present conditions.". It is not only abroad that people
                        speak of a new Constitu tion; it is in Russia itself that the demand is
                        being did not stop short at a repetition of the common made. But Prince
                        Sviatopolk-Mirski's declaration official formula. "But," he continued,
                        "there is such a thing as local self-government, as is exemplified in the
                        Zemstvos. I believe," he added, "in Zematvos." That is a declaration of
                        immense importance coming from such a quarter how important is demonstrated,
                        with singular appositeness in an article on "Self-government in Russia" in
                        the new number of the Empirs Review. For reasons which may readily be sur
                        mised, the writer of the article desires to pre- serve his anonymity; but
                        internal evidence renders almost superfluous the editorial as surance that
                        the writer is entitled to be listened to with respect when he seeks to
                        supplement Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's state- mont by giving a sketch of the
                        Zemstvo institution in Russia. The evidence which THEOFPTIAN GASETTE IS
                        PRINTED ON PAPER is adduced of the existence of the seeds of a
                        representative system of government throughout the greater part of
                        European</p>
                    <p>N.B-9ribecriptions commence trees the 1e or 10th of any month SUBSCRIPTIONS
                        and ADVERTISEMENTS at dne la advices P. O. Orders and Thayer t be made
                        payable to the Editor and Manager Bowland Snelling, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>London Offene 1-88, New Broad-triot, B.O.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THR</p>
                    <p>LONDON FAPER MILLS O., LIMITED/BAL OPzon Russia is derived mainly from
                        official sources</p>
                    <p>CANNON STREET, RG</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian</p>
                    <p>But it may be said with some confidence that it will be for the most part
                        new, to Western Europe. The existence of the Zemstvo system was, of course,
                        a matter of common know-</p>
                    <p>Gazette edge; what is now is the extent to which it</p>
                    <p>An English Daily Bewper, etablished in 1880 or &amp; Manager: B. Braastre.
                        Price One Ptaatre Tarit.</p>
                    <p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904.</p>
                    <p>REFORM IN RUSSIA.</p>
                    <p>appears to have taken root in Russian provin cial life, the success which has
                        on the whole attended it, and the possibilities which it presents of
                        preparing the people for the difficult. task of self-government. The Zemstvo
                        instita tion is a tiny plant, but if it be wisely tended it may yet grow
                        into a noble tree. Unfortunately Prince Sviatopolk-Mirski's belief in the
                        Zemst vos is not a common article of bureaucratic</p>
                    <p>A very interesting telegram from St. Peters-faith, and there have been
                        indications that, if burg this morning announces that the Russian some of
                        the bureaucrats of St. Petersburg Government actually gave permission for a
                        could have their way' even this struggling public conference to be held at
                        St. Peters experiment in local self government would be barg, composed of
                        representativos of "Zems crashed beneath the heel of autocracy. But tvos"
                        throughout the country. At the last the fact that the delegates of the
                        Zemstvos moment, however, the courage of the autocracy Saturday last is an
                        historical event of the were allowed, even to confer in private on failed,
                        and the sanction for a public con utmost significance, and we may live to
                        reckon ference was withdrawn, though the delegates November 19, 1904, as one
                        of the cardinal were allowed to meet in privata A more dates in the history
                        of the human race. portentous step. in the history of the poli tical
                        emancipation of the human race has not occurred since the summoning of the
                        States General. The analogy can be pressed</p>
                    <p>further. The weakness of the Government GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</p>
                    <p>is, quite on a par with the foolish pre- cedents set by the Ministers of
                        Louis XVI, who alternatively showed their distrust and</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>86. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED. $1000-16.7.008</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS.</p>
                    <p>A NEW RUSSIA!</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>WAR.</p>
                    <p>JAPS BLOWN UP.</p>
                    <p>ALL QUIET IN. MANCHURIA..</p>
                    <p>DAWN OF NEW ERA.</p>
                    <p>CONSTITUTION DEMANDED.</p>
                    <p>ST. PETERSBURG, November 21. As a result of Prince Mirskis appointment the
                        Government gave permission for a public ST. PETERSBURG, November 21. from
                        the Zemstvos throughout the country, but conference to be held here of
                        representatives General Kuropatkin reports that, during at the last moment
                        deslined to sanction the the night of the 16th inst., four volunteers with
                        same, though allowing the delegates to meet pyroxyline bombs blew up a
                        Chinese building privately. The Government forbade the news on the Russian
                        left, which was occupied by 25 papers to mention the matter. The delegates
                        Japanese. The latter were all killed or wounded, met last Saturday
                        privately, and adopted and were buried in the debris. With this radical
                        resolutions demanding a constitution, exception, all is quiet in Manchuria.
                        (Reuter.) an elective legislative assembly, together with liberty of
                        conscience, press, speech, and educa (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PORT ARTHUR.</p>
                    <p>ERHLUNG-SHAN FORT.</p>
                    <p>tion.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904.</p>
                    <p>THE KHEDIVE</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is still on his estates at Mon- tazah.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been graciously pleased to bestow the following ranks on the
                        under mentioned officials:</p>
                    <p>Sanich Nicolas Sawaya Bey, ex-postmaster of Tantah.</p>
                    <p>Salissah Salib Nakhla Effendi, ex-chief accountant of the province of
                        Sharkieh, and Iskandar Khalil Effendi, ex-station-master at Suez</p>
                    <p>THE GREEK FLEET.</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAL AT PORT-SAID. have been made to welcome and entertain the Port Said,
                        Sunday. Great preparations where it is due to arrive to-morrow morning Greek
                        Squadron during its visit to Port Said, from Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>members being Messrs. Coroni, Roidis, Smyr A reception committee has been
                        formed, the niadis, Pneumaticos, and Kantaris.</p>
                    <p>According to the programme drawn up at Rabea: Maximos Youssef Effendi,
                        ex-chief present, on Monday evening Commodore Coun- accountant of the
                        province of Gharbieh. douriotis, his staff, and principal officer will be
                        officer (4th class) of the Imperial Order of the His Highness has conferred
                        the rank of entertained at dinner by Mr. Coroni. de bureau at the Alexandria
                        Post Office, and attended by the officers and men Medjidick on M. Giuseppe
                        di Giorgio, ex-chef celebrated at the Greek Church, which will be On Tuesday
                        morning a "Te Deum" will be the rank of Chevalier (5th class) on M.
                        Gio-banquet will be given to the Commodore and vanni.Cortessi, ex chet de
                        bureau at the Alex officers at the Continental Hotel in the evening, A grand
                        andria Post Office. eovers being laid for 100.</p>
                    <p>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS. The Council of Ministers, under the pre- sidency of H.
                        H. the Khediver will meet on Saturday afternoon at Abdeen Palace, to discuss
                        the provisions of next year's Budget. The modifications in the ranks of the
                        engineers in</p>
                    <p>The fleet may possibly leave on Wednesday or at the latest on Thursday. There
                        is a report the departure of the Greek Squadron, that the Russian Fleet will
                        not arrive till after</p>
                    <p>THE BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</p>
                    <p>Prince Humain Path</p>
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL PASSAGE. for Chino yosterday af</p>
                    <p>LIKELIHOOD OF ATTACK IN LOCAL</p>
                    <p>WATERS</p>
                    <p>We regret to of the Maldives locomotor ataxy</p>
                    <p>to this affiction. The readers are aw, father-in-law; Rabe lady of Suer last
                        year,</p>
                    <p>dan Bay,</p>
                    <p>Principe Camille Baapoli and Conte de la</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Sunday-It is now understood that the Baltic Fleet will reach Port
                        Said on Wednesday next at dawn. The Fleet, which is under the command of
                        Vice Admiral Volker Penne have left Naples on a trip to Egypt sahm, will
                        number 20 vessels, comprising 2 of the Volunteer Fleet, and 4 German
                        colliers Controller-General of the Port battleships, 2 cruisers, 7
                        destroyers, 5 steamers Bose Admiral Sir Matie supply of coal, water, and
                        provisions, suficient yesterday from Cairo. to carry them to the next port
                        of call. Arrangements have been made for a prompt Administration, and
                        Lady</p>
                    <p>KONG</p>
                    <p>During their stay at Port Said a police patrol will be drawn round the
                        vessels, defining Rembold, son of Sir Horace Rambold The St. James's Gazette
                        states the limit beyond which all unauthorised persons the composer of the
                        entr'acte music for will not be allowed. The Flute of Paa". week's
                        production in London of Milk Craigie's</p>
                    <p>The Canal authorities are quite confident that they can pass the fleet
                        through to Suer merchant traffic. Fleet without great hindrance to the
                        ordinary It is very necessary to emphatically deny</p>
                    <p>Port-Said, Monday. arrived at Port-Said about 10 o'clock this -The Greek</p>
                    <p>ghter Heary</p>
                    <p>The marriage of Mile Bea Ammy of M. and Mme Emin Anny Bey, to Guarino will
                        take place at the Church of the</p>
                    <p>the Ministry of Public Works will also be orning and saluted the port, the
                        salute being the ridiculous reports which have been Nativity, Bacos, on
                        Saturday next</p>
                    <p>LOCAL AND GENERAL. considered.</p>
                    <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the Ramleh and Moharrem Bey districts, on
                        the COUNTERSCARP OCCUPIED. 23rd inst. will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    <p>inst.</p>
                    <p>THE RUSSIAN SORTIE.</p>
                    <p>Arthur on the 19th inst.</p>
                    <p>A. L. M. &amp; D. S.-The next practice of the choral union of the A.L.M.
                        &amp; D.S. will take place at Kudolph's Asile on Friday at 6.30 p.m. BRITISH
                        RECREATION CLUB, CAIRO.-Parents who have not already done so are kindly
                        asked to send in names and ages of their children.</p>
                    <p>THE PILGRIMAGE-Dr. Hayes, of the Qua- rantine Service, has arrived at
                        Alexandria from Suez on important duty connected with the forthcoming
                        pilgrimage.</p>
                    <p>stalls in the. Zazinis Theatre for the coming OPERA SEASON.-The drawing for
                        boxes and operatic season will take place at the Khe- divial Bourse st 6.15
                        p.m. to-day.</p>
                    <p>HEDJAZ RAILWAY. Marshal Kiazim Pasha, director of the works of the Hedjar
                        Railway, has telegraphically communicated to the High Commission for that
                        line a summary of the contents of the chief engineer's report on the work
                        done during this report, the work is making good progress the past month,
                        beyond Maan. According to both as regards the earthworks and the build- ing
                        of bridges and tunnels. The boring of tunnels Nos. 1 and 5 is very shortly
                        to be taken in hand. Tunnel No. 2 has been bored, No. 3 has been commenced,
                        No. 4 is practically finished, and No. 6 is completely finished.</p>
                    <p>returned by the battery.</p>
                    <p>As soon as the vessels were signalled the Greek colony made holiday, and
                        assembled in thousands on the breakwater and along the Quai François Joseph,
                        to welcome their com patriots. Several crowded launches, on the largest of
                        which (the Ibis) was the reception committee and a band playing national
                        airs, went out to meet the ships and accompanied usual official calls were
                        paid. them to their moorings Shortly after, the</p>
                    <p>Greek flags and decorations are in evidence</p>
                    <p>circulated by mischiet-makers from time to time, respecting a probable attack
                        upon the Russian Fleet in Egyptian waters by the Japanese or their
                        emissaries, such having not the slightest foundation in fact.</p>
                    <p>official sources fixed the arrival of the fleet for Port Said, Monday. On
                        Sunday, last even the following Monday. A space on the Asiatic side of the
                        canal was cleared of all shipping, so that the nerves of the fleet might not
                        be un- everywhere, Port-Said possessing a large or other formidable craft.
                        Special pilots duly strained by the presence of felucas, barges, Greek
                        community. were also warned for duty. It is now reported that the Russian
                        Consal has advised the Canal Company officials that the fleet will not
                        arrive until Saturday next. It has struck more than one, that it is a good
                        deal safer for this fleet, composed as it is of old ships (barring the dan
                        troyers) to await the arrival in the Indian Ocean of the main fleet before
                        venturing past Aden alone.</p>
                    <p>GREEK FLEET LOTTERY.</p>
                    <p>The Hellenie Minister of Finance has sent 50,000 tickets to Egypt for the
                        Greek Fleet Lottery. It is believed that more than 100,000 tickets will be
                        taken in Egypt</p>
                    <p>TORIO, November 21., The Japanese mined and occupied the counterscarp of
                        Erhlung-shan Fort on the 19th (Heuter.) SHEIKH BARGHUT. TOKIO, November 21..
                        The Japanese have mined and occupied, the THE SANGANEB REEF. counterscarp of
                        Erblung-shan Fort at Port ward of Sheikh Barghut harbour, and it is The
                        Sanganeb reef. lies about 13 miles east- MOTORS FOR EGYPT. (Havas.)
                        essential that a lighthouse should be erected Prince Djemil Toussoun has
                        ordered a LONDON, November 21.. on this reef, if Sheikh Barghut is to be the
                        double phaston body, to be sent to Egypt for The Daily Telegraph understands
                        from chiet harbour on the Egyptian side of the Red his Panhard "chassis,"
                        from Botiaux, of be Shanghai that a steamer from Chi-tu reports andra last
                        night and inspected the Bab-elton have decided, therefore, to erect a light-
                        THE RAILWAY COMMISSION arrived at Alex Sea. The Ports and Lagushouses
                        Administra-vallois. the news that four Russian destroyers, incluuhedid
                        station this morning. It is expected house on the southern portion of the
                        reef. It eight, horse power three-cylinder Panhard Comte Michel de Zogheb
                        has purchased an ing the Rastorpny, carrying identical des patches, left
                        Port Arthur at the same time, the quays will be visited this afternoon. is
                        to be an open iron-work tower and the height sutomobile, with landaulet body
                        by Labour The Japanese stopped two. The fate of the of the focal time above
                        high water will be 165 dette. feet. The light is to be of the first order,
                        showing third is unknown. Their orders were to deliver all round. The type
                        of lamp is to be petroleum the despatches at Chi-fu at any cost. (Reuter)
                        barung. Quarters for four hightkeepers are to JAPS SEIZE GERMAN STEAMER.
                        Tokio, November 21. The Japanese have seized and taken to marez returued
                        from Cairo yesterday. A Mal- SUPREME CONSULAR COURT-Judge de Saus- CATTLE
                        EXPORTS, TO EGYPT. Sasebo the German steamer Batelan, whichse maintenance
                        case was heard before him Our Constantinople Correspondent states was waking
                        for Port Arthur with a cargo of this morning in the Supreme Consular
                        Court..that the reason why the Ottoman Government water clothing, blankets,
                        medicines, and has decided to temporarily prohibit the export corned beef.
                        The captain declared that the Jael was bound for Nighwang (Heuter. THE
                        BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>OUTRAGES AT CANEA.</p>
                    <p>OFFICERS AND MEN RUN AMOK</p>
                    <p>The ASILE RUDOLPH gratefully acknowledges with thanks the receipt of a
                        quantity of bread and sandwiches for the use of the poor from Messrs. Walker
                        and Meimarachi, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>be constructed.</p>
                    <p>PUBLIC WORKS</p>
                    <p>the Suez Canal, the London Morning Pt Referring to the passage of the ships
                        through</p>
                    <p>says</p>
                    <p>Lady Low has arrived at the Grand Con tinental Hotel, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Marquis Salvago-Raggi amived at Cairo on Sunday from Italy.</p>
                    <p>yesterday. Dr. Leigh Canney left Cairo for Assousn</p>
                    <p>Chitty Bey, Director-General of Customs on business connected with his
                        Administration, left Alexandria yesterday afternoon for Cairo,</p>
                    <p>Drs. Ward R. F. Campbell and Takvorian Arshag have been authorised to
                        exercise their profession in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will short- ly take place, between Misa
                        Bother Kamer and Mr. Henry Margosches, of Cairo</p>
                    <p>Mr. Carl Otto Montan, Judge at the Mixed transferred in the same capacity to
                        the Alex Tribunal of 1st Instance, Mansourah, has been andria Mixed Tribunal
                        of 1st Instance.</p>
                    <p>OMDEH MURDERED Tahta, November 20. The omdeh of El-Agbanneh, a wealthy</p>
                    <p>Russian Baltic Fleet, of which there are now a Egyptian authorities to permit
                        vessels of the In regard to the reported resolution of the number off Crete
                        or approaching the Levant, to take provisions and coal at Port Said suffi-
                        cient to "enable them to reach the next port," man, held in high esteem in
                        Tahta district, it is to be remarked that this is wholly at while on his way
                        home on the evening of the variance with the Suez Canal regulations. The
                        first 18th inst, accompanied by another omdel The adjudication of 1st
                        instant-relative to the annual works of repairing, etc., to be three clauses
                        of those regulations relate to the and the sarraf of El-Aghannah, was
                        sudden- carried out in the canals and drains of the passage of men of war in
                        what may be termed y accosted by three armed men. They Behera province has
                        been approved in favour the question of such warships' stay in the Cand
                        Tema, where he had been attending ordinary circumstances. The next three
                        bear on met him nearly half way between his village of the following
                        contractors :- Markaz. an assembly, presided over by the police nal. But the
                        seventh clause expressly provides Abou-Hommos, Mohamed El-Mahallawi 2,930
                        shall embark "warlike stores, supplies, or equip rushed towards the omdeh
                        and stabbed him in that no vessel belonging to a belligerent Power officer.
                        One of the three armed men, STABBING AFFRAY-in the course of a brawl of
                        cattle to Egypt owing to the enormous Kafr El-Dawar Mohamed El-Maballawi
                        2,150 ment" in the Suez Canal or "any of its ports the face. His: two
                        companions were threatened known afterwards to be Bakit Hassein, between
                        four natives in a coffee shop in Mo-rise in the price of seat consequent on
                        these harrem Bey yesterday, two were seriously exports, especially in the
                        vilayet of Aidin. stabbed. They were conveyed to hospital, and the two
                        others arrested.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</p>
                    <p>GAMBLING HELL RAID. The Alexandria The Khedive has been most graciously</p>
                    <p>Rosetta... Assad Hanna...</p>
                    <p>Damanhour... Attia El Sayed Chibrakhit... Attia El Sayed... Hoche Issa...
                        Saied Khalil.. Teh El Baroud Aly Ghonem... Kom Hamada Aly Ghonem.....</p>
                    <p>LE</p>
                    <p>3,090 of access," meaning Port Said or Suez, and</p>
                    <p>2,260</p>
                    <p>3,922 perhaps Ismailia. Obviously the Suez Canal with the same fate should
                        they utter any ery 4,440 authorities will infringe their own regulations or
                        give help. One of the two companions knew in adopting the course towards the
                        Baltic the first assailant by name and, being unarmed, 3,200 Fleet which
                        they are reported to have in con- the last. The first blow he received clean
                        alieed both took to their heels. The victim resisted to ... 3,280
                        templation. As for Egyptian ports other than off his nose, the second out
                        away four fingers,</p>
                    <p>police, with the aid of the Hellenje Consulate,pleased to approve of the
                        following promotions, Khatatbah... Mustapha Azmi...... 1,003 those of access
                        to the Saez Canal, they are the last broke his skull. The post-mortem</p>
                    <p>made a raid on a gambung-bell in Nubar Pasha-street on Sunday night and
                        arrested the owner, the cards and money being seized.</p>
                    <p>HOSPITAL SUPPLIES The adjudication for</p>
                    <p>the supply of provisions to the Kasr el-Aini Hospital, the infectious
                        diseases hospital, and the lunatic asylum, not having given satis factory
                        results, it will be renewed on the 10th</p>
                    <p>FIVE PERSONS MURDERED. December next.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>The Daily Expres learns from Cabes that</p>
                    <p>tron dates stated:-</p>
                    <p>Local Kaimakam St. C. M. G. MacEwen Bey, Sudan Civil Administration, to be
                        Kaimakam, 2-7-04</p>
                    <p>Officer for Supplies, Sudan South, to be Kai El Bimbashi H. G. A. Garsia,
                        D.S.O., Staff</p>
                    <p>makam, 1-10-4.</p>
                    <p>to be Local Kaimakam, 1-11-04. El Bimbashi S. L. Cummins, Medical Corps,</p>
                    <p>THEFTS AT LUXOR</p>
                    <p>covered by another regulation which prohibits SILVAIN IN CAIRO any
                        belligerent resorting to any such Egyptian ten serious blows before he was
                        slain. examination shows that the victim received Papa Lebonnard is not a
                        great drama, but port or roadstead for the purpose of obtaining it was
                        admirably performed on Saturday night, any facilities for warlike
                        equipment." If The ghaffir belonging to the victim's owa house gave the
                        veteran actor, M. Silvain, a it will be impracticable for the Baltic Fleet
                        to but he had slackened pace and could not keep at the Khedivial Opera
                        House, Cairo, when the Egypt chooses to enforce her own regulations village
                        was in Tama together with the omdeh very warm welcome. Comparisons are
                        always coal in her waters, and it is above all to be up with his master.
                        When he did reach the odious, especially when two such different borne in
                        mind that the intention of the law is spot where the victim lay, he found
                        him dead schools of acting as those represented by Mnot in any case that
                        coal should be supplied and saw Bakit Hassanein erasing the canal Coquelin
                        Ainé and M. Silvain are discussed, wherewith to continue the voyage Eastward
                        in with two other men unknown to him.</p>
                    <p>but the difference in the style of the two men hostile expedition against a
                        Power friendly News of the occurrence reached here, and is very remarkable.
                        M. Silvain is a master of to Egypt, but to enable the vessels to reach Hilmy
                        Bey Issa, the Substitut du Parquet, EGYPTIAN STATE RAILWAYS-The Board of In
                        the course of his recent lecture at the declamation, his utterance of verse
                        always ore the nearest Russian port. The expedition is together with the
                        medical inspector, proceeded Administration informs us that, from Thursday,
                        Egyptian Institute on the discoveries at Karritundo, and his interpretation
                        of the title role bound away from, not towards, its own coun- to the spot.
                        They were joined by the Ing- daily to No. 5 train leaving Shellal for Luxor
                        petrated at Luxor. The inspector of the Aati seems to us to exaggerate a
                        little the human Russia among the Powers which may have the An inquiry was
                        opened, and Bakit Hassanein, 1st proximo, a dining car will be attached nak,
                        M. G. Legrain dealt with the theft per- is thoroughly human, but in Louis he
                        try's shores. Egypt appears to be classed by pector for the Interior and the
                        Bab Moudir. at 9.10 am, and to No. 6 train leaving quities Service informed
                        his hearers that; weakness of the king threatened by the dagger will but
                        have not the strength to refuse aid, the suspected perpetrator of the crime,
                        has nxor for Sheilal at 10 am. thanks to the mossures taken, the two fine of
                        Nemours. It is possible to argue that in though it should constitute a
                        breach of been arrested. statues had been recovered. The thieves were this
                        moment the king is only a frightened ani- neutrality. But there is a Power
                        that stands run to earth and punished. All had been pre mal, but it is
                        equally permissible to contend behind Egypt, and that Power has given proof
                        district as a most brutal character. He has The man arrested is known
                        throughout the MENAGERIR-The stay of Masserini's Mena: meditated in this
                        theft, and it was within their that even in such a moment of terror and dis
                        of its resolve that neutrality shall be observed; been brought several times
                        before the Courts (Reuter)gerie at Alexandria is, drawing to a close. No
                        knowledge who had paid the thieves £10 to carry may certain relics of the
                        kingly dignity would therefore the Japanese will take leave to doubt for
                        crime. one should miss seeing the serpentine dance, it out. The speaker
                        hoped that the Antiquities still enable Louis to present a more royal front
                        if the intention with which the Suez Canal executed by Mme Masserini in the
                        midst of Service would receive a certain amount of to his foe. a group of
                        lions. In other respects, also, the support from the native judges in the
                        adequate Company is credited will be carried out. show is well worth a
                        visit. punishuient of antiquity thieves.</p>
                    <p>some of the officers and men of the Baltic Fleet have roamed the streets of
                        the town in a state of wild.intoxication, insulting and assaulting the
                        inhabitants. During the drunken brawls, they murdered at least five persons.
                        Forty Russians have-deserted.</p>
                    <p>OUTRAGE ON HUNGARIAN PREMIER, ASSAILED WITH SNOWBALLS.</p>
                    <p>November 21.</p>
                    <p>ALBAMBRA THEATRE- The Castellano Ita- Count Tian, the Hungarias Premier,
                        whilst lian opars company commenced its return visit leaving a meeting at
                        which he had justified the on Saturday with Manon Lescaut, which was policy
                        of the Government, was received by a fully produced, as also were Hamlet ou
                        noisy crowd with cries of "Resign." He was Sunday and Gioconda laat night.
                        This evening ated with snowballs. The police dispersed Un Ballo in Maschera
                        will be given. the crowd with blank cartridges, and arrested forty
                        persons.</p>
                    <p>(Heuter)</p>
                    <p>DEVASTATING BORF. 30,000 PEOPLE HOMELESS</p>
                    <p>BATAVIA, November 21.</p>
                    <p>DELTA LIGHT BAILWAY. The committee of the London Stock Exchange has ordered
                        the following security to be quoted in the official List Egyptian Delta
                        Light Railways Com pang, further issue of £107,000 4. percent Debentures of
                        £100 each, Non, 3531 to 4,600</p>
                    <p>COTTON KING SOLD UP</p>
                    <p>It is not precisely that Japan apprehends danger from the continuance of the
                        voyage of The office furniture of Mr. Sully, the great the Baltic Squadrons,
                        or their possible reunion KORDOFAN TRADING COMPANY, LTD. York last week in
                        connection with his bank but because it would form &amp; bad precedent
                        cotton speculator, was sold by auction at Newsone Armada somewhere south of
                        the equator, This company has been registered with a ruptcy. It realised
                        only £1,580, although it were the Suez Canal to be made the scene of a
                        capital of £8,100 in 6,000 shares of £1 each must have cost twice as much.
                        and 2,000 shares of Is each, to carry on in the United Kingdom and in Egypt,
                        Kordofan, and the neighbouring provinces, or in any part of Africa, the
                        business of general mer chants, traders in, and purchasers of ivory, ostrich
                        feathers, rubber and other products, import and export merchants, etc. The
                        office of the company is at 46, Leadenhall street, London, C.E.</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE-The No-</p>
                    <p>GHEZIREH PALACE</p>
                    <p>ALDERSON'S GARDEN, BULKELEY.</p>
                    <p>GRAND VARMETY ENTERTAN Be Tis ROYAL TOOKEY FAMILY. CHEVALIER J. ODRESS Magle
                        Concluding with the Coach "THE BRIGANDS"</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable least attention. It would be nearer
                        the mark, Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the perhaps, if the vivid imagination
                        of Russian Central position. Under English management. spectacle of vast
                        fleets of Chinese junks men of war's men should prepare them for the
                        81-11.004</p>
                    <p>gross infringement of the obligations imposed on neutrals is impossible to
                        say what inter- national difficulties might not arise were the door to be
                        opened to systematic infraction of Shepheard's Hotel have decided, owing to
                        the observance of neutrality; &amp; Power like Egypt The inanagement of
                        Ghesireh Palace and the privileges which, in virtue of a strict large number
                        of applications for zooms, to enjoys. The idea of an organised attack by
                        re-open the Ghezireh Palace on December 13 Japanese desperadoes, if such
                        individuals are made at Ghezireh. The west balcony has been ships during
                        their passage through the famous We hear that many improvements have been to
                        be found in this heinisphere, on the Russian enlarged, and nothing has been
                        spared to make gyptian waterway is too absurd to merit the the park worthy
                        of its world-wide reputation. ATTEMPTED MURDER A Greek (local subject) A new
                        Trigane orchestra of, 12 performers, A bore has devastated the Taloet
                        archipelago fired at and seriously wounded a compatriot in vember issue of
                        the monthly Bulletin of the one of the best which Budapest possesses, has
                        Thirty thousand people are homeless. (H.) the Mir Ganeh quarter of
                        Alexandria. The British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt is, as been engaged by
                        the general management or would be murderer, on being arrested, stated
                        usual, full of interesting information. The both hotels for the season. that
                        he had fired in self-defence as his victim contenta include extracts from a
                        paper on PARTNER WANTED well-edited had attempted to kill him. No hope is
                        enter moisture in cotton and cotton yarn, re narrow Eastern channels-the
                        Straits of Sunda and with business ability, to establish tained of the
                        latter's recovery. cently read before the New England Cotton or the Formosa
                        Channel as. examples with The 8. 8. Bolders, of the Westcott and Japanese
                        torpedo craft dashing, forth from - semi-professional and wholesale business
                        Maiifacturers Association, summaries of the Laurance Line, left Malta
                        yesterday and is behind the shelter this afforded and sinking in Alexandris
                        and absquently in Cairo: VERDE THEATRE, CAIRO. The alterations consular
                        reports ised by H.M.'s representa due here on Friday with general cargo,
                        from their foes right and left. branch of London House, tapital required.
                        The Russians could £1,500, of which advertiser, who is the made in the Verdi
                        Theatre were completed tives at Alexandria, Port Said, and Sues and many
                        London. principal of a large and well-known London resterday, and the house
                        should now be perseful remarks and feofa in regard to exports, Japanese the
                        original idea as derived from the only thank themselves for having given the
                        BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER Firm, Will contribute share. Business will
                        feetly, secure against all danger of fire. The cotton, cotton seed, beans,
                        freights, company phantoms of the North Se be thoroughly taught. English
                        language Italian opera company now performing at the meetings, Egyptian
                        imports, traffic on the Mah necely. Write for appointment to Abbas Helmy
                        Theatre will go up to Cairo mondieh Canal, contracts, counie of exchange Mr.
                        F. Davidson, Hotel Abbate. shortly and give a series of performances there
                        stocks and shares, coal imports, dividends and 24920-24-2 till the end of
                        February reports, conversion tables, etc.</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman 8.8. Ararat sailed from Malta on Monday, and is due here with
                        passengers mails, and general cargo on Friday morning. The Khedivial Mail 8.
                        8. Prince Abbas will leave Alexandria on Wednesday, for Pir Smyrna,
                        Mitylene, and Constantinople..</p>
                    <p>Mocking the passage of the squadrons through EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round, ELECTRIC LIGHTLIFT.-BODERATE CHARGIN</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CRUISER AT SUEZ Sues Thesday-The British cruiser Fhe PL has arrived
                        here from Trinhomall</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n3/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>NOTES FROM HELOUAN.</p>
                    <p>Helouan, Monday-The dust of the long summer months has been effectively laid
                        to-day by a sharp shower of 10 minutes, when 2 mil limetres of rain fall.
                        The atmosphere has also been cleared of dust, and the desert air is now as
                        crisp and bracing as one could wish for. A company of Royal Engineers are
                        encamped behind the Tewfik Palace Hotel for the annual field exercises.</p>
                    <p>La fin d'un conflit</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER, 22, 1904</p>
                    <p>Le Cadi vient de reconnaitre à l'Admi- nistration des Wakfs le droit exclusif
                        de</p>
                    <p>SALE BY AUCTION.</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS.</p>
                    <p>492 1p3</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amer. Nile &amp;c. Co.. Shodivial Mail 3.8. do. (Co. Foods. 14/6</p>
                    <p>5 3,8</p>
                    <p>Alex. Water Chiro</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Jompany Ponds Fonds.</p>
                    <p>683</p>
                    <p>BAILWAYS &amp; TEAMWAYS Basse Byple, Fonds.. Delas Light do</p>
                    <p>Del</p>
                    <p>Chiro-Helonan....</p>
                    <p>103 1788 97</p>
                    <p>Fayound...</p>
                    <p>MESSRS. CONGDON &amp; CO. have been contrôler la gestion des directeurs des
                        Wakf instructed to sell by Public Auction the de bienfairane, outrôle que le
                        Mehkémel: property and effects of the officers 20th For 11:30 Charich
                        prétendait se réserver. Pour tran-Hussars. The sale will take place in the
                        cher ce différend entre les deux grandes Mess-room, Cavalry Barracks,
                        Abbassieh,on administrations indigènes, le Cadi s'es: Friday and Saturday,
                        Nov. 25th and 26th. basé sur le chapitre VII du règlemen commencing at 9.30
                        on each morning. promulgué en juillet 1895. The property will be on view on
                        Tues- day, Wednesday, and Thursday afternoons up to 6 p.m. 24932.5-30
                        3:4</p>
                    <p>Les ministres, réunis dimanche sous la The hotels and pensions are all open
                        now, présidence du Khédive, ont approuvé la looking bright and clean, ready
                        for the season olution donnée à l'incident soulevé à visitors. George
                        Nungovich Bey is to be con-propos des comptes des nazirs. C'est ainsi
                        gratulated on the new hall he has added to que le conflit entre les deux
                        grandes admi nistrations se trouve enfin splani.</p>
                    <p>the Grand Hotel.</p>
                    <p>The garden of the Tewfik Palace Hotel in looking beautifully green just now.
                        Amongst the already numerous guesta staying at this well-known hotel I
                        notice Baron and Baroness de Gordon-Coldwells, Miss O'Calloghan, Miss H.
                        Gordon, Rev. Patrick Buckley, Mr. A. S. Wylie, Dr. Beddoe, Capt. Bigge, R.E,
                        Lieut. Clogstoun, and Lieut. James.</p>
                    <p>Amongst those expected shortly are, General and Mrs. Fred Lance, Miss Smail,
                        Mrs. H. W Finch, Mr. and Mrs. E. Bullock Workman, Mr. and Mrs. Wood, Mr. H.
                        Lory, etc. Lond are the praises of the, cooking this season at the Tewfik
                        Palace Hotel, I believe the services of the chef and kitchen staff of one of
                        the best sanatoria in Switzerland have been secured by the management.</p>
                    <p>LES PROTETS EN EGYPTE</p>
                    <p>Conference Silvain</p>
                    <p>NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>$15 3/16 1913</p>
                    <p>Vol 147 1/3</p>
                    <p>Lent Bea-Mame allure</p>
                    <p>Cand Saba P.T. 80 85 Cond Saba P.T. 80 &amp; 55 Dsponible: Bian</p>
                    <p>Oras: Pas de variations</p>
                    <p>Cond, Saba F.T. 70 &amp; 78</p>
                    <p>Les priz suivants ont été pratiqués es jour Caton</p>
                    <p>G.M.B.</p>
                    <p>(BASS HOTPTS)</p>
                    <p>Province Bébém</p>
                    <p>480</p>
                    <p>...De P.T. 290-</p>
                    <p>803</p>
                    <p>Fonds</p>
                    <p>883</p>
                    <p>Pravings Garbish</p>
                    <p>Kal-Zayat</p>
                    <p>Da P.T. 80</p>
                    <p>820-</p>
                    <p>825 895</p>
                    <p>&amp; 810</p>
                    <p>Kayeb-AssocaS. Alexandria Te... do do £8 7/16 Balsh Railway Furnished by Beid
                        &amp; Barnard 10, 8 Buldings, Aleraadris, and Sharia Kar-e-Nil cok and
                        Sharee, on the local Boarse sad also of Jairo, who undertake the sale and
                        purchase of Menonf..</p>
                    <p>London Book Exchange.</p>
                    <p>Fayoum</p>
                    <p>Province Menonieb</p>
                    <p>Da P.P. 8:35-</p>
                    <p>(NOTHING-NGYPTH)</p>
                    <p>Province Fayou</p>
                    <p>...De P.T. 263-967 1/8 (HAUTH-NOYPT</p>
                    <p>Mr. W. Ernest Walton has arrived in Egypt and is now residing at Hotel du
                        Nil, Cairo. All retailers of post cards should without fail see the
                        collection which be M. Silvain, l'éminent sociétaire de l he now at his
                        disposal for the Egyptian comédie française, professeur au Conser market.
                        This collection is unique in the Vatoire de Paris, a bien voulu donner un
                        world. No time nor expense has been onférence sur l'Art de dire, sous le
                        patro-pared in the production of these post nagé et à la demande du Comité
                        de l'Uni-cards, which are veritable reproductions of Jours de l'Association
                        des Coursiers sa Marchand.) Graines de eston &amp; P.T. 69 1/4 P.T. eraité
                        populaire.</p>
                    <p>Cette conférence aura lieu vendredi pro-</p>
                    <p>aquarelles.</p>
                    <p>Cloture de la Bourse Khediviale CONTRATS</p>
                    <p>chain 25 Novembre à 5h précises p. MOUVEMENT MARITIME Novembre. ane la grande
                        salle du New-Khedivial Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Les billets d'entrée sont en vente à l'U- niversité populaire, aux librairies
                        L. Schu- ler et Nacamuli et au magasin de cartes gostales Kardiache, raé
                        Chérif pachs.</p>
                    <p>Le produit de cette conférence est con- sseré entièrement aux frais des cours
                        de Université populaire.</p>
                    <p>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demi)</p>
                    <p>A un moment donné la question des protéts a captivé l'attention de la presse
                        égyptienne, des juristes et des chambres de commerce. Lears avis étaient
                        par- sagés, mais un point. sur lequel tous étaient d'accord, c'était celui
                        de réduire le coût du protés, qui; comme on le sait, s'élève à 58 r.T. sans
                        compter les frais Le marché est légèrement oppressé. Le mou- de déplacement
                        de l'huissier. En effet, Ivement s'est concentré sur les Cotton Mills qui
                        protêt, pour être logique, devrait être atteignent 8/3 acheteurs et la Salt
                        &amp; Soda qui fléchit à 39/3. établi proportionnellement en montant d
                        l'effet et non sur une base unique de 68 P.T., que la traite soit d'ailleurs
                        d'une ou de cent livres égyptiennes.</p>
                    <p>Mais si le prix du protés est excessif pour les effets de moindre valear,
                        nous ne eroyons pas qu'il en soit ainsi pour les autres et voici
                        pourquoi:</p>
                    <p>sensible, la Banque Nationale à 24 1/8, l'Agri- La plupart des valeurs
                        accusent une baisse cole à 10 1516, la Béhéra à 35 1/2, la Delta Land à 3
                        11/16, la Nungovich à 9 1/16, la Delta Light à 15 3/16, et la Ramleh Railway
                        87/16.</p>
                    <p>PASSENGER LISTS.</p>
                    <p>ARRIVALS</p>
                    <p>DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p>ARRIVENS</p>
                    <p>21 novembre</p>
                    <p>Janvier</p>
                    <p>Mai...</p>
                    <p>GRAINES DE COTON</p>
                    <p>Bani-Sonef...</p>
                    <p>...De P.T. 170-975</p>
                    <p>SHOTION DES GRAINES ET ORBRALES PRIX FRANCO-STATION: DISPONIBLE</p>
                    <p>58-8,4</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES</p>
                    <p>COTON F.G.F.BR. Novembre..</p>
                    <p>Sh. p.3. N.BS 14 7/16 -15/33 15 19/32-58</p>
                    <p>Haute-Egipte From Baldi Payou</p>
                    <p>15 1/3</p>
                    <p>17/89</p>
                    <p>15 2/83 m.</p>
                    <p>11/18</p>
                    <p>15 27 83-7,8</p>
                    <p>61-</p>
                    <p>-5/40</p>
                    <p>63 10/40. P.T. 76 10/40&amp;-90/40 78 10,40-20/40 BEMARQUES nominale.
                        Coros-Nouvelle récolte L'après-midi: cote</p>
                    <p>do mardi 23 novembre 1904 Doerente. de "Alexiadna General Prodos Asociation."
                        GENMINS UN Fus Ootdan 8/S 5668 Graines Je 3000 Sacs 14714 Blés Sai 60
                        178</p>
                    <p>BARQUES 265</p>
                    <p>2495</p>
                    <p>Bb6</p>
                    <p>Orge...</p>
                    <p>Odesia e Port-Said: 20 h.. ap. str. Helios, cap. Nov.-Déc. Jan. Signorelli,
                        ten: 1198 au Lloyd Autrichien.</p>
                    <p>22 novembre</p>
                    <p>Smyrns; 3 j. 1/2, vap. hell. Athènes, esp. Catra- matos, ton. 899, &amp;
                        Kechayas, Marseille: 4 j. 1/3, vap. franç. Sénégal, e. Vinoanti. ton. 2985,
                        aux Mosseries Maritimes. Trieste as Patres; 3j, 84, vap. satr. Maria Teress,
                        cap. Marinovich, son. 1914, sin Lloyd Autrichien.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTE</p>
                    <p>19 novembre Malts et Manchester; vap. ang. Sailor Prince, cap. Jones.</p>
                    <p>Barcelone et Marseille; vap. ital, Nins, osp. Vioari. Marseille vag, inl.
                        Alba M., cap. Teodorico. Alexandrette vap. ots. Garcia, cap. Bosteriai,
                        anz</p>
                    <p>last.</p>
                    <p>20 novembre</p>
                    <p>Forner-Mars. Avril</p>
                    <p>Faves SAIDE Nov.-Dée.-Jan. Février-Mare.</p>
                    <p>P.T. 59 15/40-90/40</p>
                    <p>Bécolte actuelle: L'après-midi, après Fouverture, ilya sa mailleare tenue à
                        la suite de quelque demande surgie inopinément, et la clôture a ea lieu en
                        reprise.</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>Cotons-Tosal den arrivages depuis le 1er septe bre 1904 jusqu'à ce jour
                        Chasse 2.145,747. Contre même jour en 1908 v</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Dane la matinée prix plus haat pour ses talatis 15 27.89 -/-; plus bas pour
                        mare 15 9,16 à -- Dans l'après-midi prix plus haut pour Graines de obten
                        mars 15 21,89 à 11/16; plus bas pour mars 15 17/83</p>
                    <p>117</p>
                    <p>N-B-Les autres livraisons avec reports irréguliers. Au moment de la closure
                        les nouvelles daient les égyptien n'est pas cosé, sauf le Good Fair qui
                        suivantes : 86/16. Futurs dée. : 8 1/64 Liverpool coton égyptien disponible:
                        Le dispo Liverpool: coton achéricain: Fature Janvier février: 6.31. Favors
                        masi-jain: 6.37</p>
                    <p>Liverpool; rap. ang. Oypris, esp. Bailone. Syrie; vap. ang. Minish, op.
                        Damir. Port-Said; nav, de guerre gree Fesra, osp. Ghinis.nible Port-said;
                        nav. de guerre grve Sperzis, osp. actoris. Port-Saidyn. de guerre gres
                        Hytra, cap. Damisnos.</p>
                    <p>31 novembre</p>
                    <p>Braila; vsp. bell. Princesse Sods, esp. Callimsais, sar lest.</p>
                    <p>Pour destination inconte; yacht ang. Catarina, cap.</p>
                    <p>Caws.</p>
                    <p>CANAL DE SUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Par contre il y a hausse de l'Anglo Ame- rican Nile à 5 3/8, des Eaux
                        d'Alexandrie à 17, Le nombre de traites annuellement pro-des Eaux du Caire à
                        1100 et des Privilégiées testées au tribunal d'Alexandrie est de Tramways à
                        147 1/2. 2,500 à 8,000, sans compter les effets pro- testés aux divers
                        consulats de la ville et au tribunal indigène. Sur ce chiffre, deux cents
                        traites seulement ont des suites en justice et le nombre de poursuites en
                        décla ration de faillite est bien plus faible encore 14 novembre Indreasmha;
                        vap. ang. de New-York p. Manills Pourquoi dons cette habitude de 1.isser Le
                        paquebot Sénégal de la Cie Messageries Fri: vap. norv. de New-York p. Java
                        protester des billets qu'on a l'intention de Maritimes arrivé hier de
                        Marseille avait à bord: Britannia; vep. ang. de Sydney p. Londres payer
                        ensuite? Le motif en est bien simpl Mme Campana et fils, M. Hancel, Mme et
                        rnia; vag. ang. de Bombay p. Marseille Yes kinoor; vep. ang de Kuarachee p.
                        P. 8. po. at les commerçants qui sont à court d'ar- Mlle Linant de
                        Bellefonds, Mme Reboul, Mlan Cumming; vap. ang. de Chittagong p. Londres
                        gest le comprendront tout de suite. Les R. G. André, M. Raybaud, Mile
                        Mariatte, M.Zold; vap. ott. de Constantinople p. Djeddah formalités du
                        protét. sont fort longues; sor Gison, Mlle Rougier, M. Backer, M. P. Vlasto,
                        Camaran; yap.ott. de Constantinople p. Camovan enregistrement, son retrait
                        par la Banqu M. Pergentin, Lieut. Col. Campbell, Mlle Maud Nabis; vap, ang,
                        de Caloauts p Londres chargée de l'encaissement, son envos aux Smith, Mile
                        Kingsford, Mile Hansard, M. Meltokefala; vap. all. de Karmobee p. Hambourg
                        fabricants d'Europe, son renvoi par eni à d'Astagne, Mile M. N. Hainworth,
                        M. Boulinier, Beckenham; vap ang. de Calmans pene Botterdam leurs
                        représentante ou à leurs avocats en Mile Poster, Mme Sivade et fillette, Mme
                        Knight Bachelor; vap, aug. de Calcutta p. Hall Egypte, le temps que ceux-ci
                        metient paret fillette, M. Azzi, Mlle Brantis, M. de Debourg, Mme Pillafort,
                        Mme J. de Zogheb Fes. 4,405,088.04. fois à encaisser, tout cela prend
                        souvent la Boaglise, M: et Mme Brissac, M. de Historia; vap. ang. de
                        Calentia pour Londres jusqu'à six mois. On comprendía que pou Peretti, Mme
                        Fleurent, M. et Mme Pangalo, City of Asbens; vap. ang. de Liverpool p.
                        Calcutta un négociant ayant besoin de disponibiMme Atkinson, Capt. D. G.
                        Poole, M. Tousoby lusvep. all. de Breuen pour Yokohams lités le moyen le
                        plus économique d'essaint Caneri, Mme Mathieu, M. J. Aghion, M. Kaighs
                        Erant; vag ang de Calents pone Hall Clan Fraser; vap ang. de Maire pour
                        Londres avoir à sa di-position est de laisser pro- Sacazan, M. et Mme J.
                        Aghion, fillette et gou- Ehrenfels; vap. all. de Calenta pur Hambourg tester
                        ses traites: Moyennant 58-P.T. dvernante, M. Pados bey, Hon. Reginald Walsh,
                        Assas: vap. sag de Karesches pour Bickoshesd protat et quelques menus frais,
                        il opère M., Mme et Miles Jackse, M. et Mme Chakour City of Visnns; vap.
                        ang. Liverpool pour Bombay pendant des mois sur des sommes de 10 bey et
                        enfants, Mme B. Gandur, M. A.Tawil, M. Berwick Castle; vap. ang. de Calenta
                        p Hambourg 200 livres qui, s'il eft du les emprunter, G. Gauthier, Mme H.
                        Ebrard, M. et Mme Jullien, Aspern: vapaase. d'Aden pone Pola lai eussent
                        euáté un intérês bien supésars Hinmanuel, Gertrude, Marie, Henriette, Kank;
                        vap, norv. d'Emden pour Kianteshao rieur... M. J. W. Hogg, M. et Mme Ancelin
                        et enfant, Umberto I; vap, ital. de Gènes pour Ma swal doambawa: vap. hoil
                        d'Amsterdam pode Batavis Voilà pourquoi des négociants égyptiene M. et Mme
                        J. Keill, Mile C. Fourlany, Mile R. Bergedorf; vap. allem d'Adelaide pour
                        Ma-seille continueront à laisser protester leurs trai-A. Work, Mile M. E.
                        Moore, M. Osmond, M. Nordbora vap dancia de Glass pou Kurmohes tes et qu'il
                        n'y a pas lieu, pur les fortes et Mme Borghetti, M. Lahlo, M. Binshiman, Fr.
                        4,817,900.60. sommes du moins, de réduire le prix du M. Senli, M. Tabat, M.
                        Davet, M. Marulli, M. protét. Pavaron, Mme Trompette, M. P. Gonot, M. E
                        Abel, M. G. Hiertz, M. et Mme Avon, Père</p>
                    <p>15 novembre</p>
                    <p>Nourrit, M. Jacob, M. Beller, et 35 passagers STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>de 3me et 4me classe,</p>
                    <p>Municipalité d'Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>dea. teresis des Fortifiestions par 1 ts de 400 &amp; Is Porte Roseste, d'ans
                        quantité de pierres extraites 10rma Les sahateirs devront payer le drois
                        d'en chère de 1 0/0 et époser le 10 0/0 de is valene de marchandise aché an
                        moment de la vente et mer le paiement intégral &amp; là Caises Mani aipale,
                        le lendemain. da jur de l'adja lination.</p>
                    <p>Shares 418 518 24 1/8 For. 483</p>
                    <p>New-York: coton simér.: Fatars jan: :, manque, mai:</p>
                    <p>GRADIES DE COTON. Récolte nouelle: On n'a pro-qne rien fait dane toate
                        l'après midi, mais la dose est restée forme par suite du tanque de
                        vendeurs.</p>
                    <p>5,40:</p>
                    <p>Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour for-mare P.T. 61-/--/ pins bas pour
                        fv.-mare P.T. 60 85/40&amp;-- Dans l'après-midi, prix plus hant pour février
                        murs P.T. 81 -/- plae bas pour février-ses P.T. 61-1--1- N.B.-Les autres
                        livraisons syee reports irréguliers. FaVES-SAIDL Récolte actuelle: Marché
                        nal. Alexandrie, le 31 novembre 1904.</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>COPTE DE LA DEPECHE</p>
                    <p>OR L'ALEXANDRIA GENERAL PRODUCA</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION ABA</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL COTTON ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>(Joare clôture d'hier soie à 6h. p.m. alobé Association des Courtiers en
                        Marchandises, Soarse Khédivials.)</p>
                    <p>$ 15 19/32 Livraison Novembe 15 12 Janvier Mare</p>
                    <p>15 91/31</p>
                    <p>Marché steady</p>
                    <p>(Oonre pratiquée ce jour à la Boarve Khidiviale à 9h.45 s.m.)</p>
                    <p>5.15 11/16 Livraison Novembre $ 15 19,89 $ 15 8/4</p>
                    <p>Marché ferme</p>
                    <p>Janvier Marf</p>
                    <p>Arrivages de en jour, à Minet-al-Bassal, an. 84,816</p>
                    <p>(Ooare poignée de jour à la Bouree Khédiviale 1b.45 p.)</p>
                    <p>$18 11/16 Livsion Novembre</p>
                    <p>$ 16 31/83</p>
                    <p>Blée Saidi.</p>
                    <p>Béhér..</p>
                    <p>Bibirs Five-Saidi Orge... Vale... Lentilles</p>
                    <p>BARQUES IT CHEMINS DE 7 8B 4916 Sa 90354</p>
                    <p>EXTERIEUR</p>
                    <p>Déplobes is de 31 novembre 1964 PRODUITS BOYPTIENS</p>
                    <p>Colonial</p>
                    <p>Calme</p>
                    <p>Disponible Beanie: Non cotés, maf le Good Fair qui est à 86/16.</p>
                    <p>Puture décembre: 8-1/86(8/64 de baissel</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Graine de eston-Bointeausa Foren-Calins, même cours-</p>
                    <p>sin pea de demobile, change nook</p>
                    <p>Press-Sacin aires, quoique prix sontes</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Graines de colen. Faris, affaisse modis Fros-Marobé nal</p>
                    <p>OOTON AMHBIOADS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Fasco joavier-Sener: 5.38 ( point de bainse) mi-jzia 681 (an on prix)
                        Disponible: 5.82 (4 poiare de osive)</p>
                    <p>WWW-YORK</p>
                    <p>Middling Upland:, 1003 a obsagensat Furry Jade: 970 5 pointe de benise) Mai
                        59.94.4 points de hyzma</p>
                    <p>Arrivage du jour: baile- 62,000 Quatre mime jour l'année écoulée; balle
                        60,000</p>
                    <p>SHARE LIST</p>
                    <p>ISSUED BY THE "ASSOCIATION DES COURTIER VALEURS D'ALEXANDRI".</p>
                    <p>Couns OFFICIELS</p>
                    <p>Closure wajidhai a 13. 45. p.m. Agrio. Bank of Egypt Lat. 10 713-15/16 Nat
                        Beak of Egypt</p>
                    <p>-87/16 - 1/9/</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Del Bail. exc. 15 8/16-1/4</p>
                    <p>Tramways d'Alersadrie.Fos. 47</p>
                    <p>div. 885</p>
                    <p>Let 17</p>
                    <p>Fe. 1.03</p>
                    <p>Let 31 5,9</p>
                    <p>Bamlet Hailway</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Water</p>
                    <p>Boax da Caire Daima sanish Béofen</p>
                    <p>Boarse Sh&amp;diviale</p>
                    <p>Egyptina Mackow</p>
                    <p>L.B. 55 1/3</p>
                    <p>Les. 23 1/4</p>
                    <p>7/</p>
                    <p>Angio Egyptisa Spinning. Bière d'Alexiadne Pav. Fox 31</p>
                    <p>177</p>
                    <p>Div. 180</p>
                    <p>wda Caire</p>
                    <p>Priv. 133 Div.</p>
                    <p>73-</p>
                    <p>83</p>
                    <p>Detene. Towl des arrivages depuis le 1er septen bra 1908 jusqu'à ce jour
                        Cantare 3 567 658</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS, (11h:66 s.m.)</p>
                    <p>Conte de is Boarse de Miget-al-Barsal Coton F.G.F.Br. Novembre ...N.B.
                        5.14.34 Novembre</p>
                    <p>Janvier......</p>
                    <p>Mars... Mu</p>
                    <p>Graince de solen Nov.-Dée. Jan. Févrior-Mor</p>
                    <p>From Baidi</p>
                    <p>Nov.-Dia-Jan.... Février-Mare...</p>
                    <p>15 43,31</p>
                    <p>15 11/16</p>
                    <p>15 97/19</p>
                    <p>16 1/32</p>
                    <p>1,9 61 1/4</p>
                    <p>...PT 75.1/3 79 14</p>
                    <p>11111</p>
                    <p>BENARQUES Catone: Nouvelle récolte. La nouvelle récole, on pent le dire,
                        reste en dehors da marché, oar ce n'est que de temps à autre qu'on s'en
                        coeupe.</p>
                    <p>Bécole actuelle. On a ouvert à tal 15 11 16 poar le mars pour monter à tal.
                        15 34. On tiche de soutenir, msis en vain, les personnes sur la sedne
                        n'inepirans que peu de enfiance. Contre toute attonte, la haame a continué
                        plus tard jusqu'à tal. 15 7/8.</p>
                    <p>Grainse de ceton Récole.actualle: On a débuté APT 61 8/40 pour le
                        février-mars. Frees-Salds: Bécolte actuelle: Mam ondre</p>
                    <p>CEREAL MARKET.</p>
                    <p>BOG EL PARAD MARKET. NATIONAL BANK'S, SHOOMAN.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton Mills Lat</p>
                    <p>Pressage.</p>
                    <p>Salt &amp; Soda</p>
                    <p>Obig dit 'anciee</p>
                    <p>Predes, Libres</p>
                    <p>Byphas.</p>
                    <p>m. 78 84</p>
                    <p>For 91-</p>
                    <p>126-</p>
                    <p>Lo Tares ex alon Banque Nat de Grdoa ez.a., 483</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Asian</p>
                    <p>147 1/3</p>
                    <p>888</p>
                    <p>438</p>
                    <p>deaque In lastrielle LE 516 esa di sogato</p>
                    <p>Fon.249</p>
                    <p>346</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amena Nile</p>
                    <p>L. 588</p>
                    <p>7/16</p>
                    <p>Foo. 1st 1/4</p>
                    <p>181</p>
                    <p>Deferred Deite Naagorjon Bonel Delay Land Fue Nile Land</p>
                    <p>La 17 19</p>
                    <p>8,4</p>
                    <p>1/16</p>
                    <p>36</p>
                    <p>8 11/16 Lat. 8.1,3 10</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; RIMLEH RAILWAY C. REOETTES</p>
                    <p>da Dimanche 18 Nov. au Samedi 19 Nov. 1904 Carmele Billete Abonnements et
                        Divers</p>
                    <p>20</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>P.P. 8,989 8,339 1,45 1,041 2,814 7,818</p>
                    <p>Année exurante 57,367 dernière 50,921 Augmentation 6,846 Toraux-Année
                        coursate 89,475; année dernière 53,490; Agestion 16,985.</p>
                    <p>du 1er octobre 1904 sa amedi 19. nov. 1904 Carnett Billete Abonnements et
                        Divers P.P. P.T.</p>
                    <p>Année courante 463,995 70,982 89,870 dernière 4.7,477</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Angmentation</p>
                    <p>Divination</p>
                    <p>98,794</p>
                    <p>48,318</p>
                    <p>8,044 66,824.</p>
                    <p>E</p>
                    <p>$7,813 TOTAUE Année courante 608,947; année dernière 518,817: Angmentation
                        85,530.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA TRAMWAY CO</p>
                    <p>BEOETTES</p>
                    <p>du Dimanche 18 Nov. 1904 au Samedi 19 Nov. 1904 Caroeta Billets et Divers</p>
                    <p>da ler Janvier 1904 sa stali 19 Nov. 1904 Carnete</p>
                    <p>Billet ét Divers</p>
                    <p>P.R...</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>Tomax AR</p>
                    <p>YNSTURDAY'S PRIORS</p>
                    <p>Wheat, Tugael Ard. Pt. 1:8 to PT. 198</p>
                    <p>Middling...</p>
                    <p>198</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>Tomax</p>
                    <p>Mawan...</p>
                    <p>145</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>P.P.</p>
                    <p>Beanie, Tagart</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Zaworl...</p>
                    <p>98</p>
                    <p>94 Année courante dernière</p>
                    <p>99,50 9 8.910. 79,929 7 4511</p>
                    <p>P.T. 101,580,9 84,440.7</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Debentare</p>
                    <p>$18 13/8 Marché steady</p>
                    <p>Janvier Mare</p>
                    <p>(old erop) Lentile Tagari...</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>90</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>Anguention</p>
                    <p>19.0919 4,509</p>
                    <p>17,0909</p>
                    <p>Zawali red</p>
                    <p>22 novembre.</p>
                    <p>Anow.....</p>
                    <p>105</p>
                    <p>108</p>
                    <p>Barley, Tags</p>
                    <p>70</p>
                    <p>" 72</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>D</p>
                    <p>Shami Bal</p>
                    <p>76</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>92</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>135</p>
                    <p>Egmon</p>
                    <p>915</p>
                    <p>Gentile Crushed Kho-</p>
                    <p>Augmentation</p>
                    <p>Crushed Tu garl.</p>
                    <p>900</p>
                    <p>CHRBALS DE BOAT AT SAWs.</p>
                    <p>144</p>
                    <p>99</p>
                    <p>HAURRES</p>
                    <p>Whont</p>
                    <p>Ard. 4030</p>
                    <p>6 1/4</p>
                    <p>Fair. Fully Fair, Good air, Fally Good Pair o Jood? En baisse de 1/8 &amp;
                        1/4</p>
                    <p>Beans</p>
                    <p>45.0</p>
                    <p>Len</p>
                    <p>1000</p>
                    <p>Harley</p>
                    <p>1800</p>
                    <p>139</p>
                    <p>Dars Sher</p>
                    <p>203</p>
                    <p>Fasure: Mai-Jain :-</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>Helbe</p>
                    <p>900</p>
                    <p>Patare: janvier-vrier: 6.83</p>
                    <p>Olesing Priest, lo-day at 1 pm. BANKS Imperial Ottoman Bank... National Bank
                        of Egypt... New Lane 38 518. National Bank of Grees Bangse Industrielle
                        Ordis Foncier Baytion [Lottery Bonds LAND, A Agris-Industrielle Beypt 690-
                        Fond. Behers Company. Hyptian Delta Land Co. Wardan Be Day... Land &amp;
                        Morgage. New Daira Banish Fond.</p>
                    <p>10 1516 Agrio. Bank Por. 1000 L.B. 66 13 &amp; 8 11 14 #778 45ps 21 6/8</p>
                    <p>La Conference Judiciaire B'il faut en aroire un de nos confrères, dans les
                        deux réunions qui ont eu lieu la semaine passée à Alexandrie, la sous-
                        Commission judiciaire s'est occupés de Is question de la suppression du
                        tribunal mixte de Manedarah. Tout en laissant-le Le Jeudi 24 Novembre conant
                        &amp; partir de 8 h... 1d en gouvernement libre d'obéir à d'autres con- m.,
                        la Man/cipalité prooiders &amp; la vente ans on- Few. 298 sidérations
                        d'ordre politique ou adminis-chores publiques pris des einfetières Européens
                        sis tratif,elle sémis, au point de vue judicisire, un avis favorable à
                        l'opportunité de la suppression de se tribunal. En ce qui concerne le
                        renouvellem nt 'des pouvoirs de la Réforme pendant un an, tout er laissant
                        aux agents diplomaciques le soin de se prononcer en dernier ressort, elle
                        eroit bon de proposer is prorogation des pouvoirs pendant un an aña de
                        permettre aux membres de la Commission d'étudier à fond les modifigations à
                        elle soumises par 24044-8-1 la gouvernement et de les adopter, s'il y a
                        lieu,pour le proch sin renouvellement quin- quennal des pouvoirs de is
                        Bétorms. L Commission s'est mise également d'accord sur la projes
                        d'expropriation pour esse d'utilité pobliqus et un rapporteur à 616 chargé
                        de coordonner les articles du projet aves les modifications apportés.</p>
                    <p>profis de la Valle et devront enlever les pierres ashe Ils auront &amp;
                        supporter les droise de oarrière an. és dans un délai de dix jours, some
                        peine de folle enchère, pour compte de l'adjafiosaire. Alexandrie, le 21
                        Novembre 1904. L'Administrateur, W. P. ONATAWAY.</p>
                    <p>(Niged)</p>
                    <p>ADMINISTRATION DES CHEMINS DE FER Telegraphes et du Port d'Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>Es de qui con erne, toutefois, la sup Les Consell &amp;&amp; Iministra inns
                        l'honneur d'infor pression da tribunal, de Mansourah, nous mer to pbis, qu's
                        ps tie de Jeuti ler Diembre apprinoos de soares autorisée que la quin, il
                        sera, é journallahin we tion n'a pas encore été abordée.. restarat sa train
                        N parant de Challal por Ls proshsins réunion de la Commission or 10 m. da
                        mass ainel qu'en train N° 6 parisul da Louse you Chsilal &amp; 10 h. de</p>
                    <p>technique sara lieu au Oaire le lundi qui mesis. suivre les fios du
                        Bafram.</p>
                    <p>Le Caire, le 18 Novembre 1904.</p>
                    <p>480 498 1/9</p>
                    <p>Fo. 389, 135</p>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL Alex. Bonded Storm Prof Anglo- Bgypt Spinning Co.
                        Bearse Khédivials... praf, Cairo Sewage Trabe [port Ord 81 Or. Brewery,
                        Alex., Fond. 185 do do 8 Debe. 800 do Osire Fond. Bgyptian Cotton
                        Mille...</p>
                    <p>Marché de Minet-el-Bassal</p>
                    <p>93 novembre 1904.- (11h.58 a.m.)</p>
                    <p>Cotons: Cloture da murahé da 31 novembre:1 La marahás altaré lourd et en
                        baisse Plas d'on détenteurs est en train de s'alléger.</p>
                    <p>-HAUTH HOTPER ET FATOUR.</p>
                    <p>Fair et Pally Fair: Rien. Good Fair, Fully Good Fair et Good: En baisse de
                        1/8 &amp; 1/4</p>
                    <p>ABARBE</p>
                    <p>me quali 6, tre gralité. Exses: En baisse de 1/8&amp; 1/4.</p>
                    <p>JANNOVION</p>
                    <p>Ime qualité, Ire qualis, Exins: Ba baiere .de 1/84 1/4</p>
                    <p>Est de marché de ce jour, eos: Marché sontenu mais affaires modérées.</p>
                    <p>Le arrivages de ce jour se chiffrent par an, 44788 ontre mame jour l'année
                        présidanten 88538 Grains de solon-Ex demande</p>
                    <p>Mit-And-Hausse 10/40</p>
                    <p>rale</p>
                    <p>Année courante 4,853,842.5 818,149 3 5,474708 is decnière 4,007,238.8
                        518,75%.5 4,321,047.8 815,033 7 108,859.8 949.448.8</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATION DEB COURTIERS EN MAROHANDISES (Service Special) DAFRONE
                        D'OUVERTURN Lrvanroos, 10h. 8.30</p>
                    <p>Aadrionin t</p>
                    <p>Pasare: Janvier Février: 5.91</p>
                    <p>Seconde Diplobe, 10h. &amp; a.m.</p>
                    <p>Fators: mai jain: 3.99</p>
                    <p>Bourse Khidiviale, 28 novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>DERNIERE HOURS (Closure de Bouree Kalivale lb. p.) Cours de l'Association des
                        Courtiere en Marabandines Oeten FPBr</p>
                    <p>Novembre Novembre</p>
                    <p>EXCHANGE QUOTATIONS</p>
                    <p>Bas bank paper Ban house paper,</p>
                    <p>Banks'</p>
                    <p>Banka'</p>
                    <p>baying</p>
                    <p>bolting</p>
                    <p>ratee</p>
                    <p>97 1/8</p>
                    <p>78</p>
                    <p>do Marksin</p>
                    <p>01</p>
                    <p>London choque...</p>
                    <p>97 8/8</p>
                    <p>b. 89,8</p>
                    <p>F: 108</p>
                    <p>do Salt and Bods Food C&amp;Reye..</p>
                    <p>96 88</p>
                    <p>03 9/10</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>Disponible</p>
                    <p>Tekes</p>
                    <p>914</p>
                    <p>Janvier</p>
                    <p>Hayptian Syndicate... B.</p>
                    <p>Paris obajte...</p>
                    <p>846 1/1</p>
                    <p>MA</p>
                    <p>Kard-Hayes Coton Ooy. 109</p>
                    <p>1/18</p>
                    <p>New Rypsian Company.. Nangorich Hotels</p>
                    <p>Haste Raypse 10, 40 B-Rien sigasler</p>
                    <p>Quality Satdi 1. Cond</p>
                    <p>Bond des Halleries of</p>
                    <p>P.T. 118 &amp; 180 #114-198</p>
                    <p>8. bank paper... In house p Switserland Bo paper. 881 1/4- Germany sheque,
                        478 14</p>
                    <p>Mai... Graince</p>
                    <p>&amp; noter</p>
                    <p>Ind. de Kanan</p>
                    <p>Bot-Bien</p>
                    <p>Dight</p>
                    <p>B. osak paper... 471 1/3 Thalian sheque paper 888- Vienna &amp; Trieste
                        chaque 405</p>
                    <p>Avril.</p>
                    <p>How Die</p>
                    <p>Pr</p>
                    <p>Old Baldi Onde 2.3. 14&amp;</p>
                    <p>castantinople sheqe</p>
                    <p>N.R. 5 14 19 32</p>
                    <p>18 11/18</p>
                    <p>23 88</p>
                    <p>16 17:01</p>
                    <p>181</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>30/40</p>
                    <p>10/40</p>
                    <p>83 14/43 PT 74 80 40 T7</p>
                    <p>TS 10/40</p>
                    <p>2040</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n4/mode/1up">
             <div type="item">
                    <p>011 92</p>
                    <p>Coughs Bronchitis Lung Troubles</p>
                    <p>Angier's Emplsion has a wonderfully soothing and healing effect upon throat,
                        Inngs and air passages. The relief which it affords from cough, bronchial
                        distress and difficult expectoration-is almost immediate, while the rapidity
                        with which it cuts short the attacks is a surprise to all who have tried it.
                        Angier's Emulsion is both a healing lang remedy and a powerful tonic that
                        benefits the entire system; it is pleasant to take, promotes appetite, aids
                        digestion and builds up strength.</p>
                    <p>Angier's Emulsion</p>
                    <p>(PETROLEUM WITH HYPOPHOrsal.</p>
                    <p>In three sizes; of Chemins and Bazaars Avoid imitations-all of which are made
                        with ordinary petroleum. Be sure to get Anglers ANGIER CHEMICAL COLD.22 SHOW
                        HILL, LONDON,ENG</p>
                    <p>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN COTTON.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH FINANCIAL OPINION.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1904</p>
                    <p>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR. The Standard Life Assurance Company. DAVIES</p>
                    <p>not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions</p>
                    <p>by our correspondente, bas we wish, in a spiris of fair play to all, to
                        permit within certain secary Hmite-free discussion</p>
                    <p>COST OF LIVING IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>The Financial News remarks: The present conditions of the Egyptian market and
                        the relative values of Egyptian and American cotton are attracting
                        considerable To THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE attention. In some
                        respects these conditions Sir, I was greatly interested in reading the are
                        quite abnormal. At the beginning of the list of comparative prices published
                        in the season crop expectations ran as high as Gazette to-day, and I quite
                        sympathise with 7,000,000 cantars. Inasmuch as last season's the employés of
                        the Ministry of Finance in erop of 6,508,947 cantars, plus a carry-over of
                        their attempt to get the Minister to bring up 69,000 cantars, left a stock
                        in Alexandria on their salaries so as to be proportionate to the August 31
                        last of 409,000 cantars, despite enormous,increase in the cost of living
                        which profitable trade in Egyptian yarns, lower prices seemed inevitable.
                        The trade acted accordingly, of the Ministry of Finance, had no need to</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED 1825.</p>
                    <p>Head Office:-3, George Street, Edinburgh.</p>
                    <p>ACCUMULATED FUNDS ANNUAL REVENUE CLAIMS PAID...</p>
                    <p>$11,000,000 81,390,000 £22,775,000</p>
                    <p>LOCAL BOARD FOR EGYPT. cooks0, E, Manager, Anglo-gyptian Bank Limited,
                        Cal-HARRY CROOKSHANK PAUEA, Dairs, nih. Head Office for Egypt: sharia
                        Kar-el-Nil, Ontro. B. NATHAN &amp; Co., A. V. THOMSON,</p>
                    <p>23:01-14-11-306</p>
                    <p>Secretary for Egypt</p>
                    <p>Chief Agents for Alexandria. WASTE ENAMELLED UTENSILS</p>
                    <p>has taken place only recently. But the employés of one of the most important
                        Austrian manufactories, 100 waggons</p>
                    <p>CANON DAVIS MEMORIAL</p>
                    <p>24942-1</p>
                    <p>GREAT SALE</p>
                    <p>BRYAN</p>
                    <p>&amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>and contracted ahead for cotton very sparingly compare the present year with
                        1885. They to sell, at once or partly, but not less than 5,000 kos. at a
                        time. Very CONTINENTAL HOTEL BUILDING indeed. As the season developed crop
                        conditions might have only gone back five years. But it cheap prices.
                        deteriorated, and have continued to do so, until is quite easy even to show
                        that since last year quite well-informed houses no longer look for a the
                        cost of living has greatly increased in Moss, Vienna I, Seilerstatte 2.
                        Offers under W. U. 6890 to the advertising agency, Budolf larger crop than
                        6,250,000 cantars, and some Alexandria. For example, I pay now even
                        6,000,000 cantars. The holders and P.C. 6 per oke of sugar; last year I only
                        paid controllers of stocks in Egypt, from the natives P.C. 3) per oke.
                        Ordinary coffee last year was to the large financial institutions, have been
                        P.C. 11 per oke, I have now to pay P.C. 14. unwilling sellers, with the
                        result that Egyp Last year I used to pay P.C. 2 for seven eggs. tian cotton
                        has advanced both absolutely and cannot get eggs to-day for less than P.C. 2
                        publish the account, herewith, from which Sir, I will feel obliged if you
                        will in comparison with American. The advance is for four. Last year
                        petroleum was P.C. 11s it will be seen that there is a deficit of larger in
                        the interior than in Alexandria, whilst safieh, but this year I have paid as
                        much as P.T. 1,028. 6. Vouchers and other details that market, in turn, is
                        well above the parity P.C. 22. Milk has not fluctuated in price and may be
                        seen at my office.. of the Liverpool market. It is obvious, therefore, I pay
                        P.C. 4 and 5 for an oke, as I have done that this market has stood, and
                        presently ever since I have been here, which is five stands, at a
                        disadvantage, for attracting stocks. years. Bread has also not
                        increased,</p>
                    <p>I</p>
                    <p>I am, etc.,</p>
                    <p>JAS. HEWAT.</p>
                    <p>RECEIPTS.</p>
                    <p>EXPENDITURE</p>
                    <p>Cost of memorial portrait- medallion, inscription, case Freight and landing
                        charges. and packing £109... Quay and paving duty, por</p>
                    <p>P.T. 10,627. 3 268 2</p>
                    <p>REPORT FOR THE YEAR The report of the Directors of the Anglo- Egyptian Bank
                        will be presented at the Now the spinning conditions in. England as but the
                        cost of meat hiss greatly increased, and eighteenth ordinary general meeting
                        of the regards Egyptian cotton are the exact contrary as to house rent it
                        has gone up everywhere. I Subscriptions (per details company which will be
                        held at the Bank, 27, to those which obtained last season, Paving find that
                        with the utmost economy and herewith) £107 6s. 11d.... P.T. 10,466. 2
                        Clement's Lane, London, this afternoon. The become so very unsatisfactory
                        that spindles going to the bazaar myself the cost Deficit... 1,028. 6 report
                        shows that for the year, ended the 31st are being turned from Egyptian on to
                        Ameri- of living. for food also since last year August last, the gross
                        profits,after making provi-can cotton, and mills newly built for the pro-
                        has increased by otie frane for every six P.T. 11,494. 8 sion for all bad
                        debts and contingencies, amount duction of Egyptian yarn are similarly chang
                        francs spent last year. If the same pro- ed to £146,329 14s. 11d; and
                        deducting ing their intention in favour of American, more portion is to go
                        on with each year, life will the expenses, amounting to £46,898 189. Id.,
                        particularly in view of the brilliant prospects be intolerable for English
                        married people there remains a balance of £99,430.16s. 10d., now enjoyed by
                        spinners of that growth of with small incomes. We were unfortunately net
                        profit for the year. To this amount must be cotton. The immediate prospects,
                        therefore, induced to leave England between five and added £17,000, the
                        balance carried forward on the are for a consumption of Egyptian cotton six
                        years ago because my husband was offered 21st August, 1903, making £116,430
                        168 iod, considerably less than that of last season. situation here of £300
                        a year, while in which the Directors propose should be dealt with In due
                        time, doubtless, the law of supply England we had £180 a year, but we were
                        far in the following manner-Contribution to staff and demand will assert
                        itself, and pro- better off at home on £180 than we are here provident fund,
                        £1,430 16s. 10d., interim bably when Egypt endeavours to réalise on £300 and
                        we enjoyed life far more at home. A dividend at 10 per cent. per annum, paid
                        1st a considerable recession from present prices person who leaves England
                        for Egypt, and who June, £20,000, dividend at 15 per cent. per will ensue.
                        Meantime, the Liverpool market is married, commits a most unwise step if his
                        annum, to be paid on 1st December, £30,000, is interested in the fact that
                        the high prices of income is not trebled as an inducement. The transfer to
                        reserve fund, £50,000, balance Egyptian cotton have provoked a considerable
                        cost of living is increasing every day, while the carried forward, £15,000,
                        making a total of line of "straddles"-by sale of Egyptian and salaries do
                        not keep pace with it, and I should purchase of American cotton-an operation
                        strongly dissuade any friends of mine, contem- which so far has proved
                        unprofitable by the plating settling in Egypt, unless their income
                        continuous widening of Egyptian from American was to be considerably more
                        than doubled. cotton. As concerns "neat" cotton, this 1 am, etc., disparity
                        is more pronounced on the one side by the decline in American on the
                        favourable crop promise and rapid accumulation of stock here, and on the
                        other by the extreme scarcity of tenderable Egyptian cotton in the market.
                        In view of the speculative sentiment pervad ing Egypt just now it is
                        doubtful if the dis ... £1,500,000 o oparity has yet reached its extremity,
                        although</p>
                    <p>£116,430, 16s. 10d.</p>
                    <p>In accordance with the articles of association, Mr. Alan Richardson retires
                        from -the Board, and being eligible will offer himself for re- election.
                        Messrs. Cooper Brothers and Co. will offer themselves for re-election as
                        auditors. The balance sheet (31st August) is as follows: To Capital-</p>
                    <p>Authorised 100,000 shares of £15 each</p>
                    <p>Increased 27th May, 1904,</p>
                    <p>from 80,000 by the crea</p>
                    <p>tion of 20,000 additional shares.</p>
                    <p>Issued.</p>
                    <p>J80,000 shares £5 per</p>
                    <p>share paid up</p>
                    <p>To reserve fund</p>
                    <p>212</p>
                    <p>Amouns received on ao- count of additional sharer issued</p>
                    <p>NOTE Singe 31st August,</p>
                    <p>1904, the balance</p>
                    <p>of the 20,000 addi-</p>
                    <p>tional shares has</p>
                    <p>been issued, and</p>
                    <p>the paid up Capital</p>
                    <p>and the Reserve</p>
                    <p>Fund now amount</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>to £500,000 each. Bills Payable.... Deposit, Current, and other Accounts...
                        Liabilities on Bills Nego ciated... Balance of Profit and Loss</p>
                    <p>By Cash in London and at Branches.......</p>
                    <p>Sundry Investmenta Advances and other Ae- counts</p>
                    <p>Bills Receivable Freehold Premises in Egypt</p>
                    <p>Liability to the Bank for. Bills Negocisted, se per- contra</p>
                    <p>£</p>
                    <p>8.. d.</p>
                    <p>.400,000 0 0 400,000 0 0</p>
                    <p>it is hoped that for the sake of the Egyptian section of the spinning trade,
                        now comparat ively unfavourably situated, the Egyptian markets may soon be
                        restored to normal and non-speculative conditions.</p>
                    <p>SUAKIN NOTES.</p>
                    <p>Suakin, October 27.- The Sudan Government 8.8. Mukhbir arrived 92,579 00
                        yesterday evening from Suez and brought with her several steel barges for
                        the Sudan Rail- way, besides a large quantity ofother material for the
                        railway.</p>
                    <p>I</p>
                    <p>AN ENGLISH HOUSEWIFE.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, November 18.</p>
                    <p>JAPAN'S FIGHT FOR FREEDOM.</p>
                    <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</p>
                    <p>terage dues, cartage, load- ing and custom house Cost of fixing tablet in St.
                        labourage. Difference of exchange on Mark's Church... Carriage hires,
                        postages, and</p>
                    <p>remittance cost of tablet...</p>
                    <p>petties.</p>
                    <p>75</p>
                    <p>400</p>
                    <p>24. 1</p>
                    <p>100</p>
                    <p>P.T. 11,494. 8</p>
                    <p>Calendar of Coming Events.</p>
                    <p>November.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA:</p>
                    <p>Alhambra Theatre. Un Ballo in Maschera. 0.15 p..</p>
                    <p>feel, had Japs allowed Russia to grip Man- Re my remark, "Japa fighting for
                        existence," Tass. 22 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Mignon, 9 churis and Port Arthur,
                        they would have been powerless to keep her out of Korea, then Japan itself
                        would have been at her mercy-as Finland. Tableauz</p>
                    <p>GEO. B. ALDERSON.</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, November 18.</p>
                    <p>KASR-EL-NIL BRIDGE.</p>
                    <p>Place dee Consale. Masserini's Mone gerie. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 74 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Aida, in aid of International Employée
                        Society.9p.m. Fri. 25 Alderson's Garden. Vactory Anserm mont. 4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>OF</p>
                    <p>Winter Novelties</p>
                    <p>COMMENCES NOVEMBER 12</p>
                    <p>Walker&amp;Meimarachi.</p>
                    <p>PASCHAL BRANCH.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>LATEST</p>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PARIS CREATIONS</p>
                    <p>94870-14-19</p>
                    <p>CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>(Prepaid.)</p>
                    <p>Under this heading advertismente are Inserted at the following rates 18 words
                        and, P.T., the PT. 1 dix-tipon, P.T. 28-80 words non, P.T. # three almo P.T.
                        10 lx time, P.T. M. For every 10 words or under beyond. 00 words: mos, P.T.;
                        three times, P.T. 4 times, P.T.C</p>
                    <p>walk The aim is t</p>
                    <p>Lotters in reply to and will be</p>
                    <p>this role</p>
                    <p>statige are sent by the oder fo</p>
                    <p>GARD'S INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES</p>
                    <p>THE ENGLISH DIRECTORY)</p>
                    <p>December. Sat. 8</p>
                    <p>Abbai Hotel. A. L. M. &amp; D. 8 Concert. p.m.</p>
                    <p>list of the Mann</p>
                    <p>and</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>November.</p>
                    <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. Sir, Whilst desiring to endorse the
                        tribute The Port steam tug Hawke (Captain Taglis paid by "Unicorn" to the
                        designer of the Tues. 23 ferro, late of the Khedivial Mail Line) leaves
                        bridge, it occurs to me that had he been a to-day for Suez and will, on
                        arrival there, go little more expert in clairvoyance and heraldry into dry
                        dock for painting and general repairs. he would have symbolised British
                        supremacy Another big shower of rain came down upon the Nile by the Lion
                        Rampant ! yesterday but has done no damage worth I am, etc., Laos
                        KING-AT-ARMS</p>
                    <p>2,315,264 10 10 noting, except to the new railway line, which is slightly
                        damaged.</p>
                    <p>2,777,209 &amp; 4 The Suskin International Club, which was opened some time
                        ago, is doing well, and its 922,149 19 7 members have greatly increased. Its
                        supporters Are the leading merchants of Suskin, and they 46,430 16 10
                        thoroughly enjoy the club during the dull winter evenings. Some sports and
                        boating £6,953,624 12 7 races are being got up. A swimming bath is attached
                        to the club.</p>
                    <p>d.</p>
                    <p>419,420 2 9 320,186 9</p>
                    <p>Graham's Point in very lively now. It has become quite a little colony with
                        the cottages for workmen built by the Railways. A coffee shop and canteen
                        have sprung up, and, in 4,092,350 12-5 less than a year a desert has been
                        trasformed into a busy European colony. The Arab workmen also enjoy the
                        bright English cottages, 25,000 00 which they have never seen before.</p>
                    <p>1,192,517 8:2</p>
                    <p>922,149 19 7 £6,953,624 12 7</p>
                    <p>VISITORS' LIST. CARLTON HOTEL, BULKELEY. Major and Mrs. Feetham, Mrs. Burges,
                        Mr. N. Montrau, Miss Scott, Mr. E. La Edgar, Mr Jos Montrat, Mme Dr.
                        Modinos, Mme Vve A. Aghion, Mr. and Mrs. Mosseri, Mane Bog dah, Miss Vinette
                        Bogdadli, Comtesse de Pignol, Mr. and Mrs. J. O Argil, Mr. Gerald Hill, Mr.
                        and Mrs. D. Rofé and Master Rofé, Mr. Ch. Anhoury, Mian M. Anhoury, Mr. J.
                        Steinbach, Capt. and Mrs. Crawley, Mr. A. Rofé, Miss V. Hofé, Miss Daisy
                        Rofé, Miss MePherson.</p>
                    <p>SPORT AND PLAY.</p>
                    <p>K. 8. C. SKYE MEETING. Owing to the illness of our Cairo Corres pondent, the
                        names of the winners in the first two races in Friday's meeting were wrongly
                        given. They should be as follows</p>
                    <p>POLO SCURRY-Mr. Hemp's Grand Slam. 1, Mr. Dudgeon's Bulbul 2, Mr. Little's
                        Black Sand a</p>
                    <p>HACK STAKES-Mr. Schreiber's Rainbow 1, Mr. Little's Thunderbolt 2, Capt.
                        Byrne's Mahmoud 3.</p>
                    <p>A. C. C.</p>
                    <p>The construction of some squash. racket courts at the Alexandria Cricket
                        Club's grounds will be taken in hand within the next few weeks.</p>
                    <p>Before the end of the year the club expect to lay down a third asphalt tennis
                        court in place of the existing sand court.</p>
                    <p>POOTBALL.</p>
                    <p>THE HANDICAP OF MARRIAGE. At Plainfield, Connecticut, Lucille Leclaire,
                        seventeen years old, lately gave birth to triplets. She is the daughter of
                        Levi Brisson, seventy one years old, who is the father of There was a
                        football match at Victoria forty three children by three wives. His children
                        College laat Saturday between "The Masters include three sets of triplets
                        and one of and Hoys" and a second XL of "A" Company quadruplets by his first
                        wife, as well as five of the Royal Berkshire Regiment. The game pairs of
                        twins by his second wife. ended in a win for the College by 9 goals to 1</p>
                    <p>Cairo, November 19.</p>
                    <p>GREEK SQUADRON'S DEPARTURE</p>
                    <p>mood portar</p>
                    <p>sad in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Frien of</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Opera House. M. Silvain. half page 9pm. Thestre das Nouronnée.
                        Variety Enter inment. 9.80 p.m. Troedero Variety Entertainment</p>
                    <p>9.80pm.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 38 Masonia Hall. Idris Lodge No. 43 9p.m. Meeting of Bagheb Mark Lodge
                        No. 510 si Masonic Hall, Bonlao-road. 9 p.. Zoological Gardens. Performance
                        by Band of E. A. Inbhnery in afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Bab 16</p>
                    <p>Sun. 27</p>
                    <p>December.</p>
                    <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. Dear Sir, I have just read with some
                        sur. Fri. 9 prise that I climbed on to the mast of the Sat 10 small steamer
                        which followed the Greek squa- Wed, 21 dron yesterday afternoon out of
                        Alexandria harbour.</p>
                    <p>I thank you for this compliment, which, were it exact, would speak highly of
                        my agility, and I cannot help regretting that such was not the case.</p>
                    <p>I would, I confess it, be quite incapable of performing such a feat. I
                        remain, dear Sir, Yours faithfully, Alexandria, November 21.-</p>
                    <p>EDWARD MINOTTo.</p>
                    <p>YOST</p>
                    <p>THE TYPEWRITER FOR BEAUTIFUL WORK.</p>
                    <p>NO BIBBON</p>
                    <p>NO COMPLICATIONS.</p>
                    <p>NO SHIPTRY.</p>
                    <p>85 CHARACTER.</p>
                    <p>LIGHT TOUCH QUIET &amp; CONVENIENT</p>
                    <p>BUYING AGENTS WANTED.</p>
                    <p>APPLY TO</p>
                    <p>THE YOST TYPEwames Co., La.,</p>
                    <p>60, Hesser VIDEO, London, 1.0.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 96</p>
                    <p>Mons, Honie. Gymkhana.</p>
                    <p>lines 41;</p>
                    <p>(including in the Alexandr Jame's, Cairo, for</p>
                    <p>Gate</p>
                    <p>F</p>
                    <p>A copy Grat to men Boil Firm</p>
                    <p>simens of</p>
                    <p>by breach</p>
                    <p>DVERTISING AGENTS-The best gablle advart</p>
                    <p>ning often to Outro belong to Violal &amp; On, Advert ing Agents Chalet
                        Parvia Darb-el-M Spectal rates for permanent cliente Moderate bors Prompt
                        deapaliok 90.100</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Hortional Society's Show BLICE TYPEWRITERS. No. &amp; 49, No.
                        7411:</p>
                    <p>K 8.0. grounds. First Winter Bas 3. p.m.</p>
                    <p>X. 8. C. grounds First Winter Races. Sad day. 3 p.m.</p>
                    <p>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</p>
                    <p>SALE OF HORSES.</p>
                    <p>W.T. Emmens, 99 Rue Attarice, Alexandria: Address, Post Office Box 85.
                        81-13-906A</p>
                    <p>BILLIARD TABLES-French and English.</p>
                    <p>D Becond Hand For Sale. Apply A. &amp; G. Mon- ferrato, Alexandria,
                        24785-804-15</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH PROFESSOR, well in English abjects, iranted in Cairo, for two to
                        three hours daily any part of day will it Apply, stating qualißentions and
                        terms, to "M. " Cairo.</p>
                    <p>94041-9-1</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Mieli &amp; Della Torre, Austion-J BUNE DEMOISELLE satriehienne,
                        mebant eers, have been INSTRUCTED to SELL incitrice on dame de compagnie
                        Excellent bien l'Allemand es l'Ilion, demande plase by PUBLIO AUCTION, about
                        certifloste et référence sur place d'adresser: Me Iorio, No. 1, rue Chérif
                        Pache, Alexandrie 94999-8-8</p>
                    <p>60 HORSES,</p>
                    <p>MINA PHEPPARD will continue her</p>
                    <p>the property of the Army of Occupation. The Fale will be held at Sharis
                        Babish neere tratament for ladies afer De el-Khalk, near the Egyptian
                        Gouvernorat,</p>
                    <p>at 9 am. on. Tuesday, the 29th November 14 Camp is to be inaugurated at the
                        Fyramids, where patients and others may be ber, 1904. accommodated.
                        24004-20</p>
                    <p>By Order.</p>
                    <p>Head Quarters, ARTHUR COLVILLE,</p>
                    <p>Colonel,</p>
                    <p>LET-Fine Villa, furnished or unfurnished, wish den and the Ghealreh the
                        Ebedivial Sporting</p>
                    <p>Cairo, 19th Nov., 1904. Chief Staff Officer. Chob, and next to the recondle
                        of the arden of 24939-84-1 the False Hotel. Apply at "The Villa
                        "ges-19-10</p>
                    <p>THE UNION CLUB, Alexandria, invites app sions for the following pots (e
                        servantes Chal Red Water Barman, all 2018-0-6</p>
                    <p>THE CROWN PRESERVED COAL CO. porter Applesions to be addressed to lary</p>
                    <p>Works and shipping-Poptat</p>
                    <p>Union Cin, Aldria</p>
                    <p>CARDIFF</p>
                    <p>Port Talbot.</p>
                    <p>WANTED bygdin (Frisie)</p>
                    <p>"CROWN FURL</p>
                    <p>Cest</p>
                    <p>ST. DAVID'S BUILDINGS ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>35-37, Noble St, Londen,</p>
                    <p>NEW SEASON'S</p>
                    <p>GOODS ARRIVING</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co,</p>
                    <p>Catro &amp; Alexandria</p>
                </div>   
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n5/mode/1up">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL, by the 8.8. Meeris, miled</p>
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS LIVERPOOL, November 21, 1.0 gm</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER, 22, 1904</p>
                    <p>A. &amp; J. MAIN &amp; Co., Ld., Glasgow.</p>
                    <p>CLYDESDALE IRONWORKS.</p>
                    <p>Structural Engineers.</p>
                    <p>Manfacturers of, ima and steel framed buildings, Agri- cultural sholding,
                        granarien Bungalows, etc. Iron fencing and mailing.</p>
                    <p>HELOUAN RAILWAY.</p>
                    <p>HORAIRE DES TRAINS A PARTIR DU 3 NOVEMBER. 1904 DEPARTS DE BAB-EL-LOUK</p>
                    <p>BOER</p>
                    <p>55</p>
                    <p>SIMPSON STRICKLAND &amp; Co., Dip... 6.50 8.05 9.10 110 12.10 1.15 2.10 3:10
                        4.10 5.15 6.15 7.15 8.30 10.10 12 39 7.45 9-10-11-12.55 1.50 3. 355 4 5.55
                        455 750 9.30 11. 1.20</p>
                    <p>LIMITED. DARTMOUTH. ENGINEERS, STEAM TACHT &amp; LAUNCH BUILDERS. SUITABLE
                        FOR THE NILE AND CANALS POR INFORMATION APPLY TO</p>
                    <p>Arr</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; XOLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Messrs. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin.</p>
                    <p>red and Port and OIL gr</p>
                    <p>Paten Tibbes-making 2</p>
                    <p>king Booktans</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Platt Brothers &amp; Co., Limited, Oldka. Messrs. John Fowler &amp;
                        Co., Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>the 6th November:</p>
                    <p>alm of the day</p>
                    <p>bales 8,000</p>
                    <p>-Peal &amp; Co..</p>
                    <p>974 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>400</p>
                    <p>Birds &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>850</p>
                    <p>Spot</p>
                    <p>Toriel es file,</p>
                    <p>107</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>8. Tawil,</p>
                    <p>407</p>
                    <p>American fatares</p>
                    <p>5.19</p>
                    <p>Bold &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>145</p>
                    <p>5.26</p>
                    <p>7.C.Baines&amp;Co.,.</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>6.28</p>
                    <p>B. &amp;0. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>Egyptian fally</p>
                    <p>X. Constantinidin,</p>
                    <p>(Nov.) (Dea.)</p>
                    <p>8 19/64 81/04</p>
                    <p>39613</p>
                    <p>Ms. W. E. KINGSFORD, SHARIA KASR-EL-NIL, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Barelli &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>Papopandalides fr</p>
                    <p>(Jan) 7 60,64 (March) 7 58/64</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 1,266</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Brown fair per lb.</p>
                    <p>G. Becken,</p>
                    <p>good f</p>
                    <p>(brown notinal 6/16</p>
                    <p>7. Andres,</p>
                    <p>good</p>
                    <p>J. Plante &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>fully good fair</p>
                    <p>G. Frange &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Beans new (per 480 lbs.) to 25/3</p>
                    <p>A. Arbib e figli,</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>H. bindernagel,</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>insole (December)</p>
                    <p>W. Gony &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>111</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Unified...</p>
                    <p>88 7/8 105-1/4</p>
                    <p>B. J. Conry &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>79</p>
                    <p>Privats Discount m bill</p>
                    <p>.8%</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd, 112</p>
                    <p>New-Yoax, November 21.</p>
                    <p>Carrer Beos.&amp; Coy. Lad, 1,459</p>
                    <p>Spot Coston...</p>
                    <p>10-</p>
                    <p>Bank of Egypt Lad,</p>
                    <p>74</p>
                    <p>Amerionn Futures</p>
                    <p>-9.59</p>
                    <p>Imp. Out. Bank,</p>
                    <p>169</p>
                    <p>9.70</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fender,</p>
                    <p>249</p>
                    <p>9.87</p>
                    <p>Moura Bros,</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>9.94</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 1/3</p>
                    <p>6,748 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>3,016 ardebs beans</p>
                    <p>1.000</p>
                    <p>260</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>162</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy, Lid,</p>
                    <p>Tedros Ghirghis &amp; Co., Anglo-Egyptian Bank Lod.</p>
                    <p>8. Taw,</p>
                    <p>B. Minoto, 1,628 ardebs beans, 908 boxes Private dissous (mansh bille)</p>
                    <p>oranges</p>
                    <p>Batterworth &amp; Balley, 317 bales ragas</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Lad, 48 bales wool</p>
                    <p>B: Beown &amp; Co., 10 packages mixed-manila roper</p>
                    <p>Fiz &amp; David, 176 angos ogge</p>
                    <p>B. Attal, 66 mese egge</p>
                    <p>G. M. Adei, 94 cases eggs</p>
                    <p>Bar Bilver (per os d.)</p>
                    <p>Jossan dayle reeipts Ports</p>
                    <p>69,000</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, November 21.</p>
                    <p>American fasares (December Jantiary)....</p>
                    <p>6.91</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 21.</p>
                    <p>8%</p>
                    <p>27 1/16.</p>
                    <p>Jonsole (December)</p>
                    <p>88 8.8</p>
                    <p>Bio Tinto...</p>
                    <p>09-88</p>
                    <p>11 1/4</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Unified..</p>
                    <p>105 1/8</p>
                    <p>Bailway</p>
                    <p>Th. Cook &amp; Son, 1 live horse</p>
                    <p>Domain</p>
                    <p>Walker &amp; Meimarsobi, 209 empty osaks</p>
                    <p>Varions, 80 packages snadries</p>
                    <p>100-</p>
                    <p>104 1/9</p>
                    <p>108 1/9.</p>
                    <p>86 8/4</p>
                    <p>OBATWOOD'S MILREN'S SAFE in stock</p>
                    <p>J. B. Caffari, 275 ecopty onaks</p>
                    <p>Goran Defence...</p>
                    <p>Pour BARCELONE MARSEILLE, par le batean Dairs Banish freng. Foria, par le 8
                        novembre:</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann,</p>
                    <p>Tarkish United...</p>
                    <p>Daliani Beose 4 ...</p>
                    <p>104-</p>
                    <p>Onoman Bank Shares</p>
                    <p>18 8/4</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Egypt..</p>
                    <p>38 7/8</p>
                    <p>100 1/3</p>
                    <p>New Daira..</p>
                    <p>21 5/8</p>
                    <p>POUR BARCELONE</p>
                    <p>Monopole Gree</p>
                    <p>48-</p>
                    <p>Bents Greoque 45</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>-87-</p>
                    <p>125 balles soton</p>
                    <p>hartereds of 8. Afrios</p>
                    <p>3 8/16</p>
                    <p>3. Plants &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>85</p>
                    <p>Agricultural Bank...</p>
                    <p>10 7/8</p>
                    <p>F. O. Baines &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>76</p>
                    <p>Nile Valley Gold Mine</p>
                    <p>DOW</p>
                    <p>1 8/4</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Lad,</p>
                    <p>484"</p>
                    <p>Mobe &amp; Fenderl,</p>
                    <p>Mours Bros,</p>
                    <p>16</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>82</p>
                    <p>W. Gotty &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>B. Barki,</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Beschi &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Delte Light Bailway (Bearse shares) 15 to 15 1/3-1 Haypt. cot seed to Hall
                        (Nov.) 5 13/16 sellers Jerman Best dagse (November) 18/10 8/4 PARIS,
                        November 21. 199 1147- 593- 95.15- 89 7/8 ...794- Banque d'Athènes (nouvelle
                        dene) 197 1/3</p>
                    <p>Lote Tauros</p>
                    <p>Crédit Lyonnsis...</p>
                    <p>Owoman Bank.....</p>
                    <p>978 bailes cosom</p>
                    <p>Cheques on London</p>
                    <p>Sagar White No. 8 (November).</p>
                    <p>Griva fr., 67 fardes gomme</p>
                    <p>B. Nathan &amp; Co., 7 fardee gomme</p>
                    <p>POUR SKILLE</p>
                    <p>L. Heller, 107 barile mélasss</p>
                    <p>B. Conry &amp; Co., 148,500 kilos fever</p>
                    <p>&amp; Antonello, 6 mais. cigar sises</p>
                    <p>N. Diab, halos mos vides</p>
                    <p>Oamming &amp; Calleja, 100 ballots sacs vides]</p>
                    <p>86 Entrop, BOU os engrais</p>
                    <p>Four CONSTANTINOPLE, par le batean oftoman Bloni, parti e 8 novembre:</p>
                    <p>Divers, 800 so ris, 80 mos beons, 900 oair. pétrole, 20 arile vides, 188
                        colis peats, 50 olis</p>
                    <p>divere</p>
                    <p>Oridis Foncier Egyptien</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</p>
                    <p>BOURSE da 21 novembre 1904 COURS DES VALEURS A TEAMS, CLOTURE PARIS</p>
                    <p>Astions de Saes... Rente Française 3...</p>
                    <p>Loss Tares</p>
                    <p>Fare Uaillé..</p>
                    <p>Dette Egyptienne Unidée...... Daira Sanish</p>
                    <p>For LONDON, by the 8.8. North Flint, called on Jeddit Foncier Egyption</p>
                    <p>Fr.</p>
                    <p>98 55 4677- 199-</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>88 87 105 70 101 15 724-</p>
                    <p>Brienr espagnol</p>
                    <p>90 72</p>
                    <p>Obligations Basque Nat. de Grise</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Athènes, nogvelles so</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>Behrend &amp; Co,</p>
                    <p>3,169 bage oil ke</p>
                    <p>Méopolisin</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Kafr Zayas Cotton Co.,</p>
                    <p>1,200</p>
                    <p>Basss sonsolidé.</p>
                    <p>Balt &amp; Boda Ooy.</p>
                    <p>Haileries et Sav</p>
                    <p>7,849 8,687</p>
                    <p>doanowice...</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>Change anz Londres...</p>
                    <p>nore No. 8 disponible...</p>
                    <p>the 5sh November 1</p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co., 474 tons cotton seed</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Ltd.. 546 too solion ased</p>
                    <p>G. Brach &amp; Co., 50 legs gam</p>
                    <p>L. Hell, 660 bars molasses</p>
                    <p>H. Dunsterviio, 4 barrels brandy</p>
                    <p>A. Arbibs Bgli, 19 packages Ivory</p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co., 608 quarters midi beane Various, 17 gangos sundries</p>
                    <p>Pone MARSEILLE, par le batean frang, Douro, parti is 8 nove</p>
                    <p>B.B. Tavo, 611,30 kilos gr. de coton 0.0 Perdicachi, 10 fard. de 5 ages</p>
                    <p>Ag. Prinsigel, Balls et shevsaz</p>
                    <p>For PIMUS and CONSTANTINOPLE, by the 8.8 Prince Abbas sailed on the 9th
                        November: Varions,,118gs dos, 197 bags henna, 601 ones dates, 46 package
                        skins, 16 pasageri</p>
                    <p>For BX, by the 8.8. Mariout, eiled on the 9th November</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Snore No. 8 livrable les 4 de mars...</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>Consolidés anglais</p>
                    <p>Bream Fleighing Hashisory and Bestches</p>
                    <p>The Central Oyolone Co., Limited, London. Mears. Charles Gammell &amp; Co.,
                        Ld.,, of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p>Messrs.</p>
                    <p>Patent and hot les</p>
                    <p>Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                    <p>Bboom and Mannal Fire Engla</p>
                    <p>Mesars. F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld., Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Gomal Brad Motting,</p>
                    <p>Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p>The Engelberg Rice Huller.</p>
                    <p>Giken Vortex Turbine,</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Greenwood &amp; Batley Limited, Leeds, The (Laval) Fatent Blites,</p>
                    <p>MoOormiok's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                    <p>Planet Junior Agricultural Implements.</p>
                    <p>OLIYER PLOUGHS.</p>
                    <p>Agent in Cairo: M. A. FATTUCCI,</p>
                    <p>30-4-905</p>
                    <p>11-1-006</p>
                    <p>Agents for GREEN'S Boonomisers.</p>
                    <p>THOS. COOK &amp; SON (Egypt) Limited.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERS, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>MECHANICAL AND ELECTRICAL ENGINEERS, ALSO SHIPBUILDERS, &amp;c., de. All
                        classes of engineering work and supply of stores undertaken. Pontoon Dosk
                        for raising vessels of the largest sine. BOULAC ENGINE WORKS.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS DE HELOUAN.</p>
                    <p>Đẹp 7. - 750 3.90 9.15 1015 12 10 170 215510 415 nlữ 8.40 2.05 &amp; 5 10 15
                        11 15 Ar 7.50 -8.20 9.05 9.55 11.05 11.55 2.55 3.55 5.-6-7-7.559.25 11.06 12
                        05</p>
                    <p>N.B. Ne soronk</p>
                    <p>porware da</p>
                    <p>billete de Ire 68 2s olas seulement et les abounds à our deaz 'arriers pas le
                        Dimanches au garage Costiks.- La sin N° 23, ' In Dunnebos &amp; Merah on
                        lien di train N° 18, N.B.- Toak le media et les joodis de chaque semaine,
                        pendant la saisin shiatrale à l'Opér Khédivial le der traia partins de
                        Babel-Look &amp; 19 h. 45 sa Sea de 19 à 30</p>
                    <p>19964-81-1105</p>
                    <p>Milner's Safes</p>
                    <p>SOLE ASTS FOR BOTPT</p>
                    <p>G. Marcus &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Large Stook Kept in</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA-</p>
                    <p>Res Casetantinople Maloos A.N. Abet</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>Hant leon Ree Move TANTA</p>
                    <p>Sheria El Alall.</p>
                    <p>Davey Paxman &amp; Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>COLCHESTER, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>Makers of high alsas steam engines and hollers for British, Colonial and
                        Foreign Governments, Celebrated for ECONOMY and DURABILITY.</p>
                    <p>PHILADELPHIA</p>
                    <p>Swaba</p>
                    <p>DEEWARE GERMANY etc., etc.</p>
                    <p>Awarded only Gold Medal, ever given by the Royal Bo. of Arts</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES AT SHARIA BAB-EL-HADEED (CAIRO), ALEXANDRIA &amp; KHARTOUM and Gold
                        Medals at</p>
                    <p>BOLE AGENTS Richard Garrett &amp; Sons, Ltd. Portable and semi-portable stain
                        angines, Road rollers, threshing and straw-shopping machines.</p>
                    <p>Shand, Mason &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Patent Steam and Manual Fire Engines.</p>
                    <p>Nobel's Explosives Co., Ltd. delignite nad high explostren "Sporting Ballite"
                        and "Empire" Cartridges,</p>
                    <p>IN EGYPT FOR</p>
                    <p>Tangyes, Ltd. Sole Vendors.)</p>
                    <p>Steam, oll, petrol and alcohol engines and gas prodnar plant</p>
                    <p>Pampe and machinery of all descriptions.</p>
                    <p>Crompton &amp; Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>the following Exhi- bitions</p>
                    <p>LONDON VINA 1873</p>
                    <p>PARIO</p>
                    <p>PARMAN PLOW &amp; Tee DRY BAG Benass</p>
                    <p>LANGANO &amp; Cerise</p>
                    <p>DAVEY PAXMAN &amp; Co.'s Trip-Geared Engine given off a fall horse- Dynamon,
                        Motort and Mectric Machtpary of a power for one hour at 1 lbs. of fuel. At
                        the great trial of Com</p>
                    <p>deseriptions.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Chubb &amp; Son's</p>
                    <p>Lock &amp; Safe Company Limited Makere to the Bank of Hagland Chubb's soal
                        tes of all elses on hand. Building of Strong Booms undertaken.</p>
                    <p>Gee: Angus &amp; Co., Ltd. Machino balting of every descripilon anther,
                        rabber, hair, cotton and Balato Specialities 1-TANGYES OIL ENGINES, supplied
                        to the Government Administrations, and suitable for driving, pumping,
                        electrical installations, four mills, workshops, etc.</p>
                    <p>98 10 Tangyes' Marine Type Petrol Launch Engine which has won four first
                        prises open to the whole world-1903. Tangyes' Alcohol Engines up to 37
                        BHP.</p>
                    <p>28 15</p>
                    <p>13781</p>
                    <p>488 5/16</p>
                    <p>Escomptes-Parie 8, Londree 8, Berlin 5.</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>ORARY PRIOR PER TOR FARE ON WARDS</p>
                    <p>Best quality</p>
                    <p>Bethal</p>
                    <p>Cowryon</p>
                    <p>Dorlion</p>
                    <p>Tangyes' Suction Producer Plants for Driving Gas Engines. Telegraphie Addres:
                        GEER, OAINGINER, ALEXANDRIA." Works Office in town, Sharia Bab-El-Hadeed
                        (Calro),. Alexandria Ofee and Stores. Aba Dirdar S. No. 19</p>
                    <p>NOUVEAU REMEDE PURGATIF IDEAL</p>
                    <p>Conte: Constipation, Congestion, Hemorrhoides, Migraine, Obenite, . Conserve
                        le teins frais es la mille valse; d'ane effimisé abeolae agit ans douleurs.
                        Il out sonseillé par toutes les sommitée mées. Le pergatit le plus
                        dennemique.</p>
                    <p>PURGEN</p>
                    <p>Defodral so e UELBERG, barmion, Alexandria</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>Bhg. 1/1 19&amp;18 이 6,0</p>
                    <p>66</p>
                    <p>Cardig Howport</p>
                    <p>Per Ton Best quality</p>
                    <p>Shgs. Shgs. 24/24 6 23 6 24 18 186 18,3 18,6 18</p>
                    <p>18 6</p>
                    <p>Varions, 18 hoge 00, 48 packagee henna, 1,817 package wandries</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>Okefalos</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Woat Hor</p>
                    <p>Toartea...</p>
                    <p>Gesinae de acous</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL, by the 8.8. Roumelia, miled on</p>
                    <p>Beotak</p>
                    <p>18 3</p>
                    <p>Oignone</p>
                    <p>the 9th November 1</p>
                    <p>Bairde</p>
                    <p>A. Arbibi figli,</p>
                    <p>171</p>
                    <p>N. G. Casali,</p>
                    <p>Moursi Beos.</p>
                    <p>118</p>
                    <p>G. Rincken,</p>
                    <p>Yorkshire torpool</p>
                    <p>Doslogs Beat Hamilton B Michigbord</p>
                    <p>183 18 3</p>
                    <p>Nominal</p>
                    <p>LONDARE</p>
                    <p>Best Lasiathing</p>
                    <p>3. Bishes &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>fnd quality</p>
                    <p>Ofefales.. Tourmax Gaines Olgnens</p>
                    <p>1/1, 1/2 &amp; 18</p>
                    <p>8/6</p>
                    <p>Borond Lancashiri</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIE</p>
                    <p>Ascher</p>
                    <p>Orows</p>
                    <p>Stor</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Ltd, 909</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>-F. C. Baines &amp; Co</p>
                    <p>960</p>
                    <p>3,778 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>I Heller, 1000 barrels molasses</p>
                    <p>Eg. Balt&amp;soda Coy., 8,140 bage oil cak</p>
                    <p>L Onofrio, 861 bage bones</p>
                    <p>Hedjie &amp; Co., 607 bags bones</p>
                    <p>Conegliano &amp; Viranse, 88-bage horns</p>
                    <p>W. Gosty &amp; Co, 141 bags dry blood</p>
                    <p>L. Onofrio, 61 bandles dator, 131 hose date</p>
                    <p>A. Panzieri, 1,049 boxes dates</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail,-6,904 boxes</p>
                    <p>Hadjas &amp; Co.; 14 bags Horne</p>
                    <p>0. M. Adie, 60 s</p>
                    <p>Carver Bris &amp; Coy. Lad, 9 balee wist</p>
                    <p>Patent Fuel Swassen Graigola 21</p>
                    <p>Atlantle</p>
                    <p>Foundry Oche 38 Ca Oshe</p>
                    <p>PRIMES DES CONTRATS.</p>
                    <p>Abd el Aly Bosiman, 18 pakage andles</p>
                    <p>On</p>
                    <p>Levi Nahmias &amp; Co., 8 cases offe</p>
                    <p>MPEN WADULTE Lv Mare V.: 18 30/40 &amp; 18 9inas de deton. Fie..M...</p>
                    <p>85/40</p>
                    <p>Four FORT SAID LA BYRIN, per le hatoon</p>
                    <p>frang, Niger, parila 9 novembre 1</p>
                    <p>P. Bless, 10ls, champagne</p>
                    <p>Ag Prionigel, 9.008 hons, 100 barile elment</p>
                    <p>Aghies, 10 a lie légumes</p>
                    <p>A. I Orasso. 18 balles tiers.</p>
                    <p>Divers, colis di</p>
                    <p>E CONSTANTINOPLE,</p>
                    <p>Fouilise Olga, peni</p>
                    <p>Divas, 188</p>
                    <p>AG</p>
                    <p>Liv. Mare P.E. 91 80/40</p>
                    <p>10/00</p>
                    <p>10/40</p>
                    <p>Olgon</p>
                    <p>LIVERPO</p>
                    <p>CONTINENT</p>
                    <p>dound, Portable and Single Cylinder Steam Engines by the Royal Agricultural
                        Boalety at Newcastle open to the whole world, Davey Paxman &amp; Co. took
                        the only prises offered, establishing a record which has not yet be
                        equalled.</p>
                    <p>AGENTS IN EGYPT</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. HASSABO BEY MAHOMED &amp; Co. Who have a big stock of engines and
                        boilers always on view. as Khedive's Street. (Telephone 995.)</p>
                    <p>CLEAN WALLS AND</p>
                    <p>23-11-904</p>
                    <p>WHITE CEILINGS</p>
                    <p>ARE ALWAYS POSSIBLE AT A MINIMUM COST, PROVIDED YOU USE</p>
                    <p>FRESKEL</p>
                    <p>(REGD.)</p>
                    <p>Credit Lyonnais THE GREAT SANITARY WATER PAINT.</p>
                    <p>Société Anomyise</p>
                    <p>Capital 960.000.000 de Francs</p>
                    <p>ANTIEREMENT VERSES</p>
                    <p>AGENCES DEGYPTE ALEXANDRIN-LE CAIRPORT-SAID</p>
                    <p>90-10/ L OBRNIT LYONNATS Sale toutes opérations de banque, telles que :</p>
                    <p>(NANTES DUNKERQ Graines de eos. (Dankoges) Pr. (Na)...</p>
                    <p>MARSEILLE</p>
                    <p>DESTINATIONS. DIVERERS Opters Odeon, Talents, Van</p>
                    <p>1.80</p>
                    <p>100 hilag</p>
                    <p>5.80</p>
                    <p>Avances sur titren;</p>
                    <p>Ouverture de comptes squrante comie dépin de valeu</p>
                    <p>Kmimon de</p>
                    <p>de lettre de Oddit</p>
                    <p>brion ant par télégraphe</p>
                    <p>sur les principales villes de</p>
                    <p>ranger</p>
                    <p>Garde de titres :</p>
                    <p>ECONOMICAL</p>
                    <p>W</p>
                    <p>EFFECTIVE.</p>
                    <p>Composed of strictly first class non-poisonous materials, Thoroughly
                        incorporated and finely ground.</p>
                    <p>SHADE CARDS &amp; CIRCULAR GIVING FULL PARTICULARS ON APPLICATION TO THE
                        MANUFACTURERS</p>
                    <p>THOS. HINSHELWOOD &amp; CO.,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Freno de EASTERN TELEGRAPH GOY. LTD.</p>
                    <p>Becouvrement d'effets sur l'Egypte et Pétranger.</p>
                    <p>Le Crédit Lyonnais reçoit des fonds oe en compie de dépos et délivre des
                        bonsa ohdance Axe aux baax suivante 9% sax bons de 1 an ei au-del</p>
                    <p>8119904</p>
                    <p>LEGYPTIAN GAZETTE le</p>
                    <p>du Onire</p>
                    <p>AFARAGE TIM in tren Byyption tolgrams from gland to Alandrie on Monday, at
                        Noebinder, 2004</p>
                    <p>DR. LE CLERC'S Pills for the Liver &amp; Kidneys</p>
                    <p>of these important organa gout rheumatiam, gravel are an unfading sed
                        reliable remedy for disag palna in the back and kindred allments (oquired or
                        constizasonal), Bok prinsipal Chainate not In loses quantities, but only te
                        bess price L bearing the British Government Stamp with th (Between the houre
                        of 10 am and 6pm, Ostre thire to pretect the pable from frand words "Eugene
                        Le Clore" bapros</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS</p>
                    <p>Dr. 8 OLBRO'S SOAP. Motion antiseptle used and recommended by aminant
                        dermatologie in the rant of e</p>
                    <p>prop</p>
                    <p>of contracting IM</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <!-- if necessary            
            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n6/mode/1up">
                
            </div>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-YYYY-MM-DD/page/n7/mode/1up">
                
            </div>
            --> 
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>