<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary"><!-- Ryan Schefstad--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-10-30">October 30, 2023<!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/<!-- enter issue date 1904-11-23 -->/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-23">Wednesday, November 23,
                        1904<!-- 1904-11-23 --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p1.jpg">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- Peninsular & Oriental S. N. Company. British India S. N. Company, Limited. Anglo-American Nile Steamer & Hotel Coy.
The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the following dates:-
Marseille, Plymouth and Lenden. Marseilles, Plymouth and London Malta sud London Malta and London.
Marseilles, Plymouth and London.
MALACCA" "HUMATRA
6,046 Tone
November
Malta and Landon Maits and Landco.
CRANA
4410
7,913
MANILA
December
4.210
SARDINIA"
574
MACEDONIA"
10,811
MARMORA
10,809
PERA
9,712
SUNDA
CHINA
 -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- 1,000 ROYAL PRINCE
Good Accommodation for Passengers.
Navigation Generale Italienne. Societes Rousies Flerie-Rabatties Services Postaux. Departs de Decembre
Les Jendis 1, 8, 16, 99 99 8h. p. direct pour Messine, Naples, Liveure et Génes.
Les Jendis 1 es 13 à 8h. p.m. direes poor Brindisi, Bari, Aneboe et Veniso
Le Mercredi 18 & 10 ham. pour les vales de la Syrie es Larnaque
Le Lundi 19 & 4 b. p.m. pone Port-Sald, Snes et Masen wah.
Le Mercredi 7 et Jeudi à 8h. p.m. pour Fort Said.
BANK OF ATHENS, Limited. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.
Failings hegy 10 days from Haste sal gel and beinghtly Awad Less to Aldra and Byrias Coast. The dates are apprinteri & Teeth Fasha ARIATIC PRING due trois Lende
Nov
INDEAN FRIZUR
Manhbester
Du
SCO TISH PAINOR
TROJAN PRINUR
Anwery & London Manchester
 -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p2.jpg"
                ><!-- Royal Insurance Coy
FIRE AND LIFE. LARGEST FIRE OFFICE IN THE WORLD. HAJELDEN & Co., Agents, Alexandria.
B. VITERBO & Jo., Agents, Cairo.
THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.
Our Winter Season's Stocks
COMPRISING AN
Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver & Plated Articles, CUTLERY, LEATHER & ATHLETIC GOODS & GAMES..
TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS. CHOICE HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS. VINTAGE WINES.
PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LD PROVISIONS, CONFECTION RY AND TABLE DELICACIES,
$1-8-906
ESTABLтеHED 17821
HASELDEN & Co., Agmis, Alexandria, FRED. OTT & Co., Sub Agents, Calro
GWYNNES, LIMITED.
(J. & H. GWYNNE, LTD., & GWYNNE & Co., UNITED.)
GWYNNE, LONDON
Onde
ABO, and th Baltions, Al. MORNING & MEALS.
Trade Mark- "INVINCIBLE."
MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT
Telephones
544 BANK.
Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly moderate prices.
The Egyptian Supply Stores, (BRANCH WALKER & CO., CAIRO). WALKER & MEI MARACHI, Limited.
MENA HOUSE HOTEL.
IS NOW OPEN.
Centrifugal Pumping Machinery CAIRO SAVOY
in the world, suitable for all purposes, including
RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE, IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING & FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, & ALL MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.
These Pumps can be driven by Bears, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other power, for Lifts of from 1. in 5008., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a Minnie Makers of the Mex Pamps. Results Guaranteed. Over 50 Years' Practical Experienos.
All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet Egyptian requirements.
London Omees
81, Cannon Street, London, E.O.
Works Hammersmith, London,
38369-11-13-904
BOEHME & ANDERER
NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB,
24848-80-4-905
HOTEL.
Will Open November 26.
31-8-905
EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL
PORT SAID. First Class Hotel. Modern in all respects. Fire-proof, Drained to the Ses, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French Billiards, Fresh and Salt Water Baths..
The Coolest Summer Besilence in Bgypt Special terms to Cairo Besidente and their families desirous of enjoying the cool air and ses bathing during the summe months. DRAGOMANS IN HOTEL, UNIFORM MENT ALL TRAINS AND STRAMERS,
23041-38-8-818
JOHN MOIR & SON,
LIMITED.
LONDON, ABERDEEN, AND SEVILLE. PURVEYORS TO THE KING.
MANUFACTURERS OF
THE SEVILLE ORANGE MARMALADE, WHOLE FRUIT JAMS, PURE PICKLES,&c.
Head Office: 9 & 10, GREAT TOWER ST., LONDON. Agents: D. A. VAFIADIS & CO., P.O. BOX 540, CAIRO,
DAILY WEATHER REPORT.
OBSERVATIONS BY SUBTY DEPARTMENT.
ALEXANDRIA
8.8.W. Eight
shade
130 1.0.004
REMABER
As noon yesterday the wind blew, strong from the NW. There was a rough a Howry, dark, travelling clouds pre- wind falling light. At midnight it became almost calm, with
allied and it was showery at times in the afternoon, the heavy continuous rim and qually weather from the 8.8.W.. the ses becoming smoother arometer rising slowly.
 --></div>
        <div type="item">
                <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                <p>An English Daily Newspaper, Betabilahed in 188 disce &amp; Manager: B. Bas. Petoe
                    One Plastre Tarttt.</p>
                <p>rainty over Samos. It is thought that France and Russia would not be favourable
                    to union in the near future; the relations between-Italy and Greece are not
                    particularly good, the Italians and the Greeks are rivals in Epirus, and the
                    compulsory recall of the Italian Minister from Athens last spring did not
                    improve the feelings of the two races: Great Britain has no special interest, in
                    hindering, or in hastening, the union, except that, when once the Greeks have
                    Crete, they will demand-Cyprus, which is always regarded by them as an Hellenic
                    island. The most formidable argument in favour of the unión is that no one
                    desires a fresh disturbance in Crete this winter, which would certainly A dead
                    calm appears to prevail for the time call for the intervention of the 'Powers
                    being in Manchuria, and a telegram from Few will be so singuine as to pretend
                    Mukden to-day states that owing to the strength that the Cretans will find
                    amalgama of the respective positions, neither army ap- tion with the Greek
                    Kingdom a complete</p>
                <p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER, 23, 1904.</p>
                <p>THE CAMPAIGN..</p>
                <p>Victoria pars inclined to attack, unless possessing such succeys, nor will the
                    Athenian politicians have</p>
                <p>Magasins Victoria</p>
                <p>WOOLESTONE AND EBILL.</p>
                <p>a preponderance in numbers that they are able an easy task in governing the
                    warlike popul to make a flanking movement. It will be useful tion of the island.
                    Besides, certain Balkan during the present lull in the campaign to study States
                    will almost certainly put forward claims the climatic conditions which must
                    exercise a for compensation, as Greece herself did when ENGLISH DRAPERY. In
                    Manchuria the climate oscillates between two garia in 1883. Meanwhile, wa cannot
                    shut our. very large influence upon the course of the war. Hastern Roumelia was
                    united to North Bul extremes. In winter the cold experienced is eyes to the fact
                    that the Cretan question like a burning copper diso, and the thermo- time when
                    Europa bae many preoccupations very severe, while in summer the sun shines has
                    been once more reopened, and that at meter rises to dearly one hundred degrees
                    elsewhere.</p>
                <p>Opposite Austrian Consulate, near the Batala Theatre. Onilogues on
                    application.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p3.jpg"> 
                
           <div type="item">
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. F. DAVIDSON, Ophthalmic Optician, 140, Great Portland Street, London,
                        Teacher of Sight Testing and author of "Sight Testing for the Medical
                        Practitioner," "Refraction Work," eto. May be conanlted for</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">SPECTACLES At the HOTEL ABBATE for a Short Time Only.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">Mr. DAVIDSON in the inventor of many of the latent
                            appliances for dealing with and cordially invites all medical men to
                            Defective Vision see them and to test their</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>practical utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 12.30 and 9 to 6. Mr DAVIDSON'S Intel Invention (patented) is a
                        new SUN OLA88, which absolutely prevents any of the ill effects of Sun
                        Glare,</p>
                    <p>TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS. LOCAL AND GENERAL</p>
                    <p>THE</p>
                    <p>WAR.</p>
                    <p>A STALEMATE.</p>
                    <p>MUKDEN, November 22. Owing to the strength of the respective positions,
                        neither army appears inclined to attack unless possessing such a
                        preponderance in numbers that they are able to make a flank ing movement.
                        The Japanese probably have the most available troops. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>THE GREEK Aseize COURT at Alexandria will begin its sittings on the 13th
                        December</p>
                    <p>THE BRINDISI MAIL will be distributed at the GPO, Alexandria, to-morrow
                        morning st 8 o'clock.</p>
                    <p>MARIOUT RAILWAY.-The Dairs Khasss has bought a large quantity of old material
                        from the Railway Administration for use on the Mariout line.</p>
                    <p>ter reunions of this society will commence on REUNION DES FAMILLES. The
                        series of win- Saturday, 17th December, with a ball and Xmas Tree.
                        Subsequent balls will be given on January 21, February 25, and April 1
                        respect ively, the last closing the season.</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1004</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY. THE EVENING EXPRESS. In response to petition presented by
                        the inhabitants of Ram leh to the State Railway Administration, the latter
                        have arranged to stop the evening ex- press train from Cairo at Sidi Gaber,
                        com-</p>
                    <p>RESPONSIBLE OFFICER ARRIVES.encing from the 19th inst.</p>
                    <p>THE FRERES CASE-The appeal of M. Yayon against the judgment of the French
                        Consular ST. PETERSBURG, November 22. Tribunal at Cairo, which condemned him
                        to a It is stated that, at the request of Great month's imprisonment for
                        defaming the Con- Britain and Russia, the Emperor of Austria gregation of
                        the Frères, will be heard by the Aix will nominate the fifth member of the
                        Com-Court of Appeal on January 26: mission of Inquiry. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 22. It is stated here that, at the request, of Great Britain,
                        the Russian officer, of the transport Kamchatka, who first gave the order to
                        open fire on the trawlers, has been landed at Dakar. He will appear before
                        the Commis sion of Inquiry.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>GENERAL NEWS.</p>
                    <p>A RUSSIAN RUSE. DESTROYER BOUGHT IN ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22.</p>
                    <p>BLIND SCHOOLS-A "bazaar in aid of the blind schools at Alexandria and Tantah
                        will be held at the residence of Mrs. Coventry (which has been kindly lent
                        for the purpose), Mansourah, on Friday next, at 2 p.m. The sale is under the
                        patronage of Mrs. B. Dale.</p>
                    <p>THE BALTIC FLEET.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS FOR PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>CANEA, November 22. A division of the Baltic Fleet has left for Port Said. It
                        consists of two battleships, three cruisers, six destroyers, and nine
                        transports. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>As we go to press, we learn that the Baltic morrow morning. Squadron is
                        expected to arrive at Port Said to</p>
                    <p>Russian Squadron is composed :- The following are the vessels of which
                        the</p>
                    <p>Battleships: Sissoi Veliki and Navarin Cruisers: Almas and Seietlana.
                        Besuprechy, Buistry, Byjedoci, Braci, Bodri, Torpedo boat destroyers:
                        Blestyaschtchy, and Buini</p>
                    <p>Volunteer Fleet steamers: Voronej, Tamboe, Vladimir, Kief, and Jarosla
                        Transports: Gortchakof, Juppiter, Kitai,</p>
                    <p>and Meteor</p>
                    <p>JAPS AND THE RED SEA. A nautical correspondent writes: in the Red Sea on the
                        look-out for the Russian If the Japanese are lurking about somewhere fleet,
                        the most likely spot for them to be lying Daedalus lighthouse, to the
                        north-east of in waiting is in the neighbourhood of the Berenice. The reefs
                        run out there in every direction and yet one cannot touch bottom in 300
                        fathoms with deep sea lead. The Japanese could place two torpedo-boats
                        there, one on the east and one on the west of the channel, and they could
                        knock the Russians into a cocked hat at this point.</p>
                    <p>THE HOUSING PROBLEM.</p>
                    <p>MR. ALDERSON'S SCHEME</p>
                    <p>The following is the text of a proposal which is to be placed before the
                        Alexandria Muni- cipal Commission by Mr. G.-B. Alderson on question in the
                        city: Wednesday next, in regard to the housing</p>
                    <p>"In answer to the locataires plea re more accommodation for artisans and
                        employés, I beg to submit the following suggestions:</p>
                    <p>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK</p>
                    <p>YESTERDAY'S MESTING.</p>
                    <p>the twelve months' working.</p>
                    <p>ARMY AND NAVY. (FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT</p>
                    <p>London, Novem</p>
                    <p>15</p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENT.) Major R. G. Tallet D.S.O., ho tion joins
                        the 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade in London, November 22. Egypt, has worn the
                        "green jacket for Egyptian Bank (Limited) was held this after well as the
                        medal with five clasps in Bulle The annual general meeting of the Anglo-
                        sixteen years and earned his decoration and the dividend of 15% declared
                        which, includ- Talbot, who is a member of the ancient military noon. The
                        report and balance sheet were passed, fighting for the relief of Ladywith.
                        Mo ing the dividend of 10% for the first six and naval family of which the
                        Bal of Shrews- On the table you will find complete plans, months, made a
                        dividend of 13 per cent on bury is the head, at the with all details, for a
                        block of 110, to cost, Colenso, Vaal Kats, Montecristo, say, under L.E.
                        20,000. The Chairman, in the course of his speech, Hill, Langs Nek, etc.,
                        etc.. "Also plan of the city, showing the lands at gave some details as to
                        the issue of the 20,000 present not used and belonging to the Govern-new
                        shares. The shareholders took up the quota Major G. C. L. Stockwell, D.3.0.,
                        Highland ment and the city. to which they were entitled to the extent of
                        Light Infantry, has been appointed second-in- "Will the Municipality request
                        the Govern-Stock Exchange at £12 each nett to the bank, moyed from Egypt to
                        Bengal, 18,000; the remaining 2,000 were sold on the command of the 1st
                        Battalion, which lately ment to cede plot marked A, or rather, say, or £2
                        premium on the issue price, giving the 30,000 sq. m., on the following
                        conditions: "1. This block to be built according to plans deducted £1,000,
                        the cost of issue (mostly the province of Bahrel Ghaal, who commands bank a
                        profit of £4,000. From this must be Major W. A. Boninois, RA, Governor of
                        presented, possibly in about a year. 2. Apartments to be let at rents not to
                        £3,000. This £3,000 is to be devoted to paying of cannibalistic propensities
                        known as Government stamps), leaving a nett profit of the expedition
                        destined to punish those gentary exceed 10% on actual cost to workmen ap the
                        staff a bonus of 10 per cent. on their "Nism Niams" in the Upper Nile
                        regions, is a proved, and who will be selected or balloted salaries for the
                        past year. This decision met very smart offer who has won a fine reputa with
                        the hearty approval of those presant. tion during his six years' connection
                        with the the capital of the bank was one million and in the Nile Expedition
                        of 1899, including the The Chairman then went on to state that Khedive's
                        Army. He served with distinction half, of which half a million is paid up.
                        The final rout of the Khalifa's forces (mentioned in reserve fund is also
                        half a million, equal to the despatches) and would have chastised the of the
                        Board in dealing with the profit. The cient forces at his disposal. paid-up
                        capital. He then sketched the policy Niam-Niams early this year had he had
                        suffi first charge on the profit will be £62,500,, or 12 per cent. dividend
                        on the capital of to staff provident fund £1,500; the third Sir C. J. Graves
                        Sawla, Bart, M.V.0.) took half a million; the second charge, subscription
                        that the first-class cruiser Aboukir (Captain charge, the very large amount
                        of £30,000 to first place in the recent long-range firing, par establish a
                        pension fund for the benefit of the ticulars of which were given some time
                        ago in staff. This is undoubtedly a very large sum, these notes. The
                        battleship Montagu (Captain equal, as it is, to 6 per cent, on the capital
                        of T. B. 8. Adair) was a good second. Indeed, alf the bank. The £30,000 will
                        become the property the cruisers and battleships shot well. of the staff,
                        and the scheme for its appropria For a considerable time shorter
                        commisions</p>
                    <p>for, of all nationalities.</p>
                    <p>"3. Capital to bear 6% interest, and no more, balance for a sinking fund,
                        repairs, and</p>
                    <p>administration.</p>
                    <p>"4. These houses to be free of all taxes such as water, light, and 2%
                        tenant's tax.</p>
                    <p>15. Water to be supplied by Municipality free. dividend of 3% on the capital.
                        "6. Municipality to guarantee a minimum the necessary capital, build, and
                        when finished "On these terms I will undertake to obtain hand over to the
                        Municipal Council to admi- nistrats</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>News from the Mediterranean Fleet states</p>
                    <p>The Suez correspondent of the Daily Er for the first block, till finished and
                        handed over tion to individuals will be carefully drawn up abroad have been
                        strongly urged on in these</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN POSTAL ADMINISTRATION-It has been announced by some of our
                        contemporaries that Douglas Morice Bey has been appointed director of the
                        Port Said Post Office in succes-press wires to that paper on the 15th inst.
                        as sion to Mr. Mancantelli: The appointment has follows: not yet been filled
                        up, but it is vacant, as Mr. Mancantelli has been transferred to Alexandria.
                        vessels have arrived here with the intention of It is reported that
                        disguised Japanese war blowing up that portion of the Baltic fleet which
                        will go through the canal. The Russian admiral has cabled to the consulate
                        here to arrange about supplies. Four steamers of the Volunteer fleet which
                        are said to be flying the commercial flag are expected hourly at Port Said.
                        Their names are unknown.</p>
                    <p>INSURANCE. The "Fidelitas" Assurance Company of Brussels has authorised
                        Messrs. Alf. G. Buhagiar &amp; Co., of Alexandria, to repre- sent it
                        throughout Egypt. This company is one The Standard says that Messrs. Yarrow
                        of the leading assurance companies in Belgium, reported to the Admiralty
                        last September that and insures against maritime, fluvial, and fire a
                        destroyer had been bought from them by a risks. gentleman in Paris, who
                        wished to have it altered for yachting purposes. The Admiralty DAIRA SANISH
                        BONDS- The Committee of communicated with the Foreign Office, who the London
                        Sotek Exchange has allowed the made inquiries in Paris. Their suspicions
                        being following security to be quoted in the official aroused, they sent
                        Messrs. Yarrow instructions list: Egyptian Government, £1,264,820 Dairs to
                        retain the boat. It was, however, too late to Sanieh Bonds, 1890 "stamped
                        for exchange," It eventually reached Libeu, and joined the Baltic Fleet</p>
                    <p>do this, as the destroyer had left the Thames in lien of the same amount of
                        bonds unstamped</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>MACEDORIA EFFECT OF REFORM SCHEME</p>
                    <p>VIENNA, November 22. According to an official statement issued here, the
                        Austro-Russian reform scheme has greatly improved the general condition of
                        Macedonia. The population itself desires pence. (Router)</p>
                    <p>CRETE. CERTAINTY OF DISORDERS.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22, Cin a memorandum by Prince George, handed to the Powers,
                        he emphasizes the certainty of disorders in Crete, if the people's
                        aspirations for the union to Greece are again, rejected.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>GREAT GALE IN NORTH SEA PORTUGUESE ROYALTIES SNOWED UP.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 22.</p>
                    <p>A great gale is raging in the North Sea There are several wrecks with loss of
                        life Blinding snowstorms are taking place in the North and Midlands of
                        England. The tele graphs are broken, and the trains delayed. The King and
                        Queen of Portugal were mowed mp at Chatsworth, where they are the guests of
                        the Duke of Devonshire.</p>
                    <p>FRENCH CHAMBER</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 22. The Chamber of Deputies has rejected the suppression of
                        secret funds. M. Combes had put the question of con</p>
                    <p>fidence</p>
                    <p>STRIKE AT LORIENT.</p>
                    <p>(Havas.)</p>
                    <p>LORIENT, November 29. The workmen at the powder factories have declared a
                        general strike, and the workmen at Brest areal are joining with them
                        (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>'AU DE ROUGE.'</p>
                    <p>now quoted.</p>
                    <p>THE AMERICAN ANNUAL NATIONAL THANKS- GIVING will be observed to-morrow
                        (Thursday). In recognition of this anniversary, &amp; service will be held
                        at 11 o'clock to-morrow in the American Mission Church, Cairo, near Shep-
                        heard's Hotel: Residents and visitors are cordially invited to participate
                        in this service.</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>SURZ CANAL-On the 19th and 20th inst. 33 vessels passed through the Suez
                        Canal. Of these, 24 were British, 2 French, 4 German, Dutch, 1 Austrian, and
                        I Portuguese. The transit and passenger dues for the two days amounted to
                        884,032.02 fra. The total transit and passenger dues collected from the 1st
                        to that date on 298 vessels amounted to 6,612,139.09 frs.</p>
                    <p>THE KHEDIVE.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is spending to day at Mariout, where he is inspecting his
                        estates. His Highness will return to Montazah in the evening.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN STATE DOMAIN.</p>
                    <p>Masar, M. M. Rothschild and fortune that Egyptian State Domain Mortgage bonds
                        to the amount of £20,220 nominal capital have been drawn for payment at par
                        on December 1. The drawing consists of all bonds (not pre- viously cancelled
                        by the operation of the sinking fand) comprised in the series of numbers
                        advert ised.</p>
                    <p>ELEMENTARY EDUCATION.</p>
                    <p>About a thousand children of the employés of the Egyptian Railway
                        Administration are without any means of obtaining any education whatsoever.
                        The Board has now decided in principle to pay a few fikis, who will begin
                        the work of instructing the progeny of platelayers</p>
                    <p>and others.</p>
                    <p>YACHTING</p>
                    <p>The British turbine yacht Emerald sailed from Alexandria harbour yesterday,
                        bound North The steam yacht Catarina is now at Port Said, and leaves for
                        Suez in a day or two</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner Moeris arrived at Liverpool 11 on Monday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>General Drapery Establishment. (Central Tramway station), CAIRO. P.
                        PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail 8.8. Dakaklich will leave Alexandria on Saturday and Port
                        Said on Sunday for Beyrout, Tripoli, Mersin, Alexandretta, Larnaca,
                        Limassol, Caiffs, and Jaffa.</p>
                    <p>BRITISH CRUISER AT SUEZ Suez, Tuesday-As wired to-day, H.M.'s second-class
                        cruiser. For arrived at Suez this morning from the East Indies.</p>
                    <p>She will change her crew with that brought</p>
                    <p>"I have visited the various quarters of the city and the artizans' dwellings,
                        and find it is a real want to avoid disease and discontent. "P.S. The
                        expenses of finding the capital to Council, will be my affair. "Shares will
                        be disposed of, say, £1 to £25 to hold to industrious artizans and £500 the
                        limit one</p>
                    <p>sure investment for the artizans.- "It is fay desire to create a profitable
                        and GEO. B. ALDERSON." IRRIGATION DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <p>The chairman then dealt with the general</p>
                    <p>affairs.</p>
                    <p>NUNGOVICH HOTELS CO.</p>
                    <p>outlines of the pension fund. The meeting notes, both in the interests of the
                        health of the ended without any incident, the shareholders officers and men
                        and the efficiency of our present expressing their general satisfaction
                        squadrons. The Admiralty has just announced with the prosperous position of
                        the bank's that in the future his Majesty's ships will be commissioned for
                        periods of two years instead of three. This will be a great boon to all
                        ranks, Another important point is that re- In regard. to the various rumours
                        as to the pairs will not be allowed to accumulate, Nungovich Hotels Co., we
                        understand that as we often the case under the three-years Mr. K. George
                        Veitch Murray is appointed Nungovich Bay has not resigned, but that rule.
                        The first ship to be commissioned under surveyor of contracts of the 3rd
                        class and is Sir Elwin Palmer, Sir John Rogers and Mr. the new conditions is
                        the first-class craiser attached to the service of the Assiout Barrage.
                        Cattaoui have sent in their resignations, as mouth on the 19th inst. for
                        service on the Mr. G. Parker is appointed surveyor of Sutlej, which will be
                        commissioned at Porte- to the 2nd Circle, and Mr. F.B. Jacomb to the
                        contracts to the 3rd Circle, Mr. L. R. Wallace 4th Circle.</p>
                    <p>The salaries of each of these officials will amount to L.E. 240 per annum.
                        The Govern- should it seem fit, to the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>matter will be amicably settled. members of the Board of that Company. It is,
                        however, fully expected that the</p>
                    <p>China station.</p>
                    <p>out by the Hermione, and then return to her ment reserves the right of
                        transferring them, PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.oldiers; it is much to be feared that
                        the ne</p>
                    <p>station. It it probable that the Four will remain at Suez with the Hermione
                        pending the arrival of the Baltic Squadron.</p>
                    <p>PUNITIVE EXPEDITION IN SUDAN. The War Office issued the following state- ment
                        to the Press yesterday:</p>
                    <p>On the 10th ult. a patrol left El Obeid for Rahad, under the command of
                        Miralai O'Con- sell Bey, to proceed against Abou Zeida of Kitra, who had
                        expelled the Mek appointed by the Moudir of Kordofan last April and usurped
                        his authority.</p>
                    <p>P. W. D. CONTRACTS.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has given out the contracts for the winter
                        cleansing works in</p>
                    <p>the canals as follows:-</p>
                    <p>Assiout-Mr. Sturgess Galioabieh.-1 and II. groups, Khalil Chahin. Chaker; 3.
                        Moh. Ali Wanis. Dakahlieh.-Group 1., Messrs. Bellini; 2. S.</p>
                    <p>Baldi; 3. Luca Lanitiche; 4. D. Cangos; 5. Charkieh.-1. Nasu Ghoraieb; 2. Mr.
                        F W. Cossena; 6. C. Cangos; 7. Youssef Gho- raieb; 8. Ibr. Khalil Chahim; 9.
                        Khalil Khoury.</p>
                    <p>Markas Abnoub-C. Passaris.</p>
                    <p>Assiout and Manfalout-Kamel Roufail. Minieh (West of the Nile).-MM. Th. Yanni
                        and B. Hanna; Minich (East of the Nile), J. Chasseand; Samalout, W.
                        Papadopoulo; Beni Mazar, W. Taylor; Fashn, D. A. Andenis. Beni Sonef-Beba,
                        MM. Liotto and Wour lich; Beni Souef and Wasta, Mr. E. Bramall. Fayoum, Moh.
                        Afifi.</p>
                    <p>While I am in hearty sympathy with the. appeal of the National Association
                        for the employment of Reservists and time-expired sponse will prove
                        disappointing. With all Colonel Younghusband, of Lhasss fame, labour are
                        compelled, by commercial stagna the good will in the world, most employers
                        of and his wife were passengers by the P. &amp; 0. tion, to reduce rather
                        than increase the 'nam- They disembarked at Suez early on Monday that they
                        are less able than when business is SS. Mongolia, homeward bound from
                        Bombay-ber of people in their service, with the result morning. brisk to
                        comply with such appeals But it is Lady Low also landed at Sues from the
                        Empire's gallant defenders, whether sailors an utterly vicious system which
                        makes the</p>
                    <p>same steamer.</p>
                    <p>or soldiers, dependent on such chances of subsistence after they retire.
                        Yesterday I Ronald Lechmere are among the passengers Time-Expired Tommy,"
                        illustrating from Sir Edmund and Lady Lechmere and Mr. came across a
                        striking letter from a by the P. and O. steamer Persia, which is due his own
                        experiences the ingratitude of the at Port Said on Tuesday next, Sir Edunnd
                        is State to his class. Of blameless character, The force arrived at Gebel
                        Daier on October 12, when Abou Zeida was ordered to come in proceeding to
                        East Africa on another big game and in possession of two war medals with six
                        by the 13th. He refused, and on the 14th the shooting expedition. clasps, he
                        served for a little over thirteen axpedition advanced, capturing the village
                        and years before passing back into civil life. With. some hills. Meantime,
                        the Meks of Feria and in Egypt in a few days' time by the steam to count on
                        receiving one of the many thou- An interesting party of tourists are
                        arriving such an excellent record, he had every right Kemla joined Abou
                        Zeids and desultory firing continued till the 18th, when the Camel Corps
                        yache Vectis, belonging to the P. and O. Steam-sands of berths which are in
                        the gift of the ship Company She has on board many well- State and artillery
                        captured the two villages. In the known passengers, including Sir William J.
                        both at the Army Clothing Stores and the But although he registered his name
                        afternoon of the same day, the Meks of Farla Dupree,, mayor of Portsmouth;
                        Mr. John Royal Laboratory nearly three years ago, he and Kimla came in and
                        received the "Amam." After the last skirmish Abou Zeida, with a Gordon, M.
                        P. for Elgin; Mr. B. Dosse, is apparently as far as ever from attaining his
                        few followers, took to the hills, but on October formerly courier to the
                        late Queen Victoria; desire. We are aware, of course, that something The
                        second performance of Thomas's Mignon, Mr. J. Lockwood Kipling, father of
                        the wall has been done during recent years, especially 21 he surrendered and
                        received the "Amam." No further trouble is expected in this part last
                        evening, proved again a very great success, known author, and also an author
                        himself, by the Post Office. But if recruiting for the of the country. The
                        following was the composi-signa. Baldini and Signor Tomisani being having
                        written a charming book on animals, Army is to be extended to classes which
                        now tion of the expeditionary force - frantically applauded throughout the
                        evening. Sir James Pelle, K.C.S.I.; Mr. H. W. Uloth, refuse to enlist, as
                        Mr. Arnold-Forster hopes, Artillery officers, 34 N.C.O.'s and men, Signa.
                        Baldini's interpretation of the title role director of the Peninsular and
                        Oriental Com the well-conducted soldier must be secured Was one deserving of
                        the highest commends pany, accompanied by his wife; Mr. Tristram reasonably
                        comfortable maintenance after he 3 guns. Camel Corps-6 officers, 200
                        N.C.O.'s and tion, and the many present who were moved Ellis, Mr. C. Martin,
                        Sir Acquin Martin, Mr. even to tears by her pathetic impersonation of G. J.
                        Ingram, with his daughter; Mr. R. E. 12th Sudanese-7 officers, 126 N.C.O.'s
                        and Mignon, is proof of the excellence of this very Craig, Jr., Mr. and Mrs.
                        Fletcher, and Mr. B. accomplished lady's performance. As Gugliel W. Knox,
                        with his wife and daughter mo, Signor Tomisani, who possesses a voice of</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                    <p>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE</p>
                    <p>good timbre and delightful freshness, was A marriage has been arranged, and
                        will take SOLAR MOTORS FOR EGYPT. eminently successful, and his delicate
                        handling place at the end of December, between Adrian, Egypt is shortly to
                        have what are called of the several charming romances falling only son of
                        the late Sir Adrian Dingli, G.C.M.G., "solar motors." The heat of the sun,
                        so long to his lot, brought him enthusiastic applause. C.B., Chief Justice
                        of Malta, and Lady Dingli, neglected as a practical factor in producing
                        Indeed, it is difficult to understand why this of 3, Strada Forui, Valetta,
                        and grandson of power as applied to industries, is being taken theatre is
                        not crowded to overflowing every William Henry Charlton, of Hesleyside,
                        North up seriously, and another generation (or our evening, when two such
                        artistes as those above umberland, and Geraldine, youngest daughter own)
                        will see the land dotted over with devices mentioned are included in the
                        caste of the late H.F. Curwen, of Workington Hall, of one kind or another
                        for gathering and con- This evening, Rossini's opera Il Barbiere-di
                        Cumberland, and Mrs. Curwen, of The Island, centrating the heat and power,
                        arriving at the Siviglia will be given, with the tenor Tomisani Windermere,
                        and 14, Manson place, Queen's earth from the sun, and heretofore absolutely
                        in the caste. To-morrow evening, a benefit Gate. wasted, so far as human
                        utility is concerned. performance of the ever popular deda will be One
                        development of the practical use of solar given for a very deserving object,
                        vis, the heat is the solar motor. This is so designed international Employés
                        Society of Alexandria. to automatically face the sun at all times of The
                        performance is placed under the patronage the day, and by the use of a steam
                        boiler in its of M. Pierre Girard, French Consul, and the focus, produces
                        steam at a high pressure, and two celebrated prime donne, Signe. Popovici
                        and Fabbri, will take part. in great quantity, for any use</p>
                    <p>One of these devious is to day in actual practical use in Arizona, at
                        Willoox, and is pumping all the water needed for irrigating very large farm
                        in that arid,country.</p>
                    <p>a</p>
                    <p>Others, according to a correspondent of the New York Herald (Paris), are
                        being sent to Egypt and South Africa</p>
                    <p>ALHAMBRA THEATRE</p>
                    <p>Un Ballo in Maschera was successfully given yesterday evening. Tonight,
                        Rigoletto, will be given, with the tenor Apostolou.</p>
                    <p>To-morrow Cavalleria Rusticana and I Pa gliacci will be staged, and on Friday
                        Verdi's</p>
                    <p>The native Press announces the death of Mohamed Bay lakander, son of Soliman
                        Pasha El Franssoni (Colonel Seves), late Minister of War. The deceased was
                        60 years of age.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Gottheil, professor at Columbia Univer sity, has left the Carlton Hotel,
                        Balkaley, and is now staying at Shepheard's</p>
                    <p>R. M. S. 8. Ophir for New Zealand on the Mrs. A. G. Harris left by the
                        Orient-Pacific</p>
                    <p>17th inst</p>
                    <p>The great economic problem solved by the Simon Bocanegra will be produced for
                        the CARLTON HOTEL, utilisation of the sun's heat is, of course, the first
                        time in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer, pretical production of power to any degres</p>
                    <p>&amp;HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH RIVER-TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN
                        ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>Three Sailinge a Week. Agents at Alepandria ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO.,
                        LB. 18-11-900 $3.10.004</p>
                    <p>JUST ARRIVED LATEST DESIGNS IN LADIES 31916</p>
                    <p>BASES 0000S</p>
                    <p>without cost of fuel.</p>
                    <p>That this will be developed more and more GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</p>
                    <p>as the years go by, producing power where fual</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>ie absent or its price prohibitive, seems now an Be. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED..
                        unquestionable fact. 0800-16.7.000</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh Nowly</p>
                    <p>retires; and that would be effected to a verg large degree by giving our
                        fighting men, whether in the Navy or the Army, a preferen tial claim to
                        employment in the lower non- combatant grades of the Civil Service, the
                        Admiralty, and the War Office</p>
                    <p>of</p>
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. F. DAVIDSON, Ophthalmic Optician, 140, Great Portland Street, London,
                        Teacher of Sight Testing and author of "Sight Testing for the Medical
                        Practitioner," "Refraction Work," eto. May be conanlted for</p>
                    <p>SPECTACLES At the HOTEL ABBATE for a Short Time Only.</p>
                    <p>Mr. DAVIDSON in the inventor of many of the latent appliances for dealing
                        with and cordially invites all medical men to Defective Vision see them and
                        to test their</p>
                    <p>practical utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 12.30 and 9 to 6. Mr DAVIDSON'S Intel Invention (patented) is a
                        new SUN OLA88, which absolutely prevents any of the ill effects of Sun
                        Glare,</p>
                </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>(FROM OUR FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENT.) Major R. G. Tallet D.S.O., ho tion joins the
                    2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade in London, November 22. Egypt, has worn the "green
                    jacket for Egyptian Bank (Limited) was held this after well as the medal with
                    five clasps in Bulle The annual general meeting of the Anglo- sixteen years and
                    earned his decoration and the dividend of 15% declared which, includ- Talbot,
                    who is a member of the ancient military noon. The report and balance sheet were
                    passed, fighting for the relief of Ladywith. Mo ing the dividend of 10% for the
                    first six and naval family of which the Bal of Shrews- On the table you will
                    find complete plans, months, made a dividend of 13 per cent on bury is the head,
                    at the with all details, for a block of 110, to cost, Colenso, Vaal Kats,
                    Montecristo, say, under L.E. 20,000. The Chairman, in the course of his speech,
                    Hill, Langs Nek, etc., etc.. "Also plan of the city, showing the lands at gave
                    some details as to the issue of the 20,000 present not used and belonging to the
                    Govern-new shares. The shareholders took up the quota Major G. C. L. Stockwell,
                    D.3.0., Highland ment and the city. to which they were entitled to the extent of
                    Light Infantry, has been appointed second-in- "Will the Municipality request the
                    Govern-Stock Exchange at £12 each nett to the bank, moyed from Egypt to Bengal,
                    18,000; the remaining 2,000 were sold on the command of the 1st Battalion, which
                    lately ment to cede plot marked A, or rather, say, or £2 premium on the issue
                    price, giving the 30,000 sq. m., on the following conditions: "1. This block to
                    be built according to plans deducted £1,000, the cost of issue (mostly the
                    province of Bahrel Ghaal, who commands bank a profit of £4,000. From this must
                    be Major W. A. Boninois, RA, Governor of presented, possibly in about a year. 2.
                    Apartments to be let at rents not to £3,000. This £3,000 is to be devoted to
                    paying of cannibalistic propensities known as Government stamps), leaving a nett
                    profit of the expedition destined to punish those gentary exceed 10% on actual
                    cost to workmen ap the staff a bonus of 10 per cent. on their "Nism Niams" in
                    the Upper Nile regions, is a proved, and who will be selected or balloted
                    salaries for the past year. This decision met very smart offer who has won a
                    fine reputa with the hearty approval of those presant. tion during his six
                    years' connection with the the capital of the bank was one million and in the
                    Nile Expedition of 1899, including the The Chairman then went on to state that
                    Khedive's Army. He served with distinction half, of which half a million is paid
                    up. The final rout of the Khalifa's forces (mentioned in reserve fund is also
                    half a million, equal to the despatches) and would have chastised the of the
                    Board in dealing with the profit. The cient forces at his disposal. paid-up
                    capital. He then sketched the policy Niam-Niams early this year had he had suffi
                    first charge on the profit will be £62,500,, or 12 per cent. dividend on the
                    capital of to staff provident fund £1,500; the third Sir C. J. Graves Sawla,
                    Bart, M.V.0.) took half a million; the second charge, subscription that the
                    first-class cruiser Aboukir (Captain charge, the very large amount of £30,000 to
                    first place in the recent long-range firing, par establish a pension fund for
                    the benefit of the ticulars of which were given some time ago in staff. This is
                    undoubtedly a very large sum, these notes. The battleship Montagu (Captain
                    equal, as it is, to 6 per cent, on the capital of T. B. 8. Adair) was a good
                    second. Indeed, alf the bank. The £30,000 will become the property the cruisers
                    and battleships shot well. of the staff, and the scheme for its appropria For a
                    considerable time shorter commisions</p>
                <p>for, of all nationalities.</p>
            </div></div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p4.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>Pone MARSEILLE, par le batean français Congo, parti le LF novembre: VHA FOUR
                    MADRILLE</p>
                <p>$4966-11 Bolio, 24 colie vieux enivre 844 dolls vient lailon 517 pains sind
                    Buerories, 20 store Candiegión, 19 are willes Divers, 40 olive Behrend, 600 de
                    vi FC Baines &amp; Co, G. Franger &amp; Co.,</p>
                <p>NEW YORK COTTON MARKET. Telegram received to-day from New York by Moms Andres,
                    Chawarby &amp; Co., of Alexandria. the large somhsen oefers to sell, to the
                    weaknes The fall is due to the disappointed hopes of Bulle, of southern sharks,
                    to a good deal of operation</p>
                <p>Après Jure restés longtemps stationnaieston having seen thrown upon the market
                    and rés à 7 environ, les Cotton Mills viennent de monter subitement à 9/9
                    acheteurs. O a4changé ce matin 6 à 7,000 titres.</p>
                <p>En husse également la Ward an à 8 1/8 acheteurs, les Markets à 27/3 acheteurs,
                    les Esux d'Alexandrie à 17 1/8 et les Esax du Caire à 1125 achetears.</p>
                <p>Par contre on fléchit légèrement sur 1s Crown Brewery do 232 à 230, sot l'Anglo
                    Ameriein Nile de 5-3/8 5 5/16 acheteurs et sur les Privilégiées Tramwaya
                    d'Alexan- dris de 147 1/2 146 1/2 acheteurs. Lea Dividendes sont demandées à
                    386.</p>
                <p>ADMINISTRATION DES POSTES.</p>
                <p>AVIS</p>
                <p>L'Administration dos Poster met en sjufestion entreprise des transporte potent
                    dans la ville de Fort Baid,ans conditions stipndes dans le eshier des aharges
                    doped as de ostle Direction Gindrals (Parra da Sedarist) &amp; la Direction
                    Leals dea Postes de Port-id.</p>
                <p>pressed for sale, and in consequenes of large selling ont of parohsses for want
                    of margins.</p>
                <p>The heavy rossipts depress the market, The semens shows 9 more cotton giand shan
                    same time last year.</p>
                <p>vis. 1 sottod gianed up to the" 14th Nove aber, 1938. Bales 7,070,deo More 69%
                    4,171,000 Total ginned up to the 14th. November, 1934 Balos 11,741,000</p>
                <p>GUNNY BAG MARKET SCHRAGER BRO CALCUTTA MARKET REPORT FOR WEEK ENDING 10th Novexa,
                    1904.</p>
                <p>Monday and Tuesday were closed days and the Gunny market opened yesterday very'
                    strong, the firmness being due to the rather excited state of the loose Jate
                    market, both here and upcountry, and higher prices havo- been paid by Home
                    buyers and spinners for</p>
                <p>Jute</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p5.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>"I can recommend Perusa for dys- pepsia and stomach trouble. I have been using
                    your medicine for a short period and I feel very much relleved. It is Indeed a
                    wonderful medicine be sides a good tonic."--M. C. Butler.</p>
                <p>gained nothing by saying it-indeed, be would microbe of cancer, or a secondary
                    microbe; whe only have played straight into the hands of ther it will be
                    susceptible of inoculation, and enemies of the Church, who would have quoted
                    whether the animals inoculated will develop in his protest as unmistakable
                    evidence of Papal fections which can be treated for cure. All this hostility to
                    the Republic. They will do that will occupy months. as it is of course. But they
                    will not be able tot over the plain declaration of his Holi news that the
                    profession of Christianity can be in complete accord with a Republican form of
                    government. It can, no doubt; but, as French Christianity is learning, to its
                    cost, the anti- Christian influences which dominate the policy SAINT ANDREW'S
                    FOOTBALL CLUB. of France at the present time have no desire to This fixture was
                    brought off on the parade work in harmony with the Church. On the ground at
                    Mustapha Pasha on Saturday after contrary, it is their deliberate intention to
                    suppress Christianity, if they can. They will noon in lovely weather and before
                    a good turn- out of spectators. The Signallers started the made manifest without
                    grievous spiritual suffer early in the vicinity of Curtis &amp; Co.. Keill fail,
                    of course; but their failure will not be game with the wind at their backs and
                    were There are certainly two opinions as to the and clearing the Saints began to
                    gain ground. ing and spiritual loss. was soon in evidence, and through his
                    tackling expediency of the Channel tunnel, but 1 Neither team for a time could
                    claim any great imagine that if Paris were polled on the sub-advantage, the play
                    being pretty much of the ject of the Champs Elysées "tube" it would
                    give-and-take order. The Saints' forwards were return an emphatic "yes." It is
                    the latest pro- not displaying any brilliancy in their move- jeet to build
                    subterranean passages at the ments, and in this department certainly the The
                    ratification of the Anglo-French Agree-most important points beneath the
                    principal homesters were the superior lot. Cowie was ment having been voted in
                    the Chamber byennes of this great thoroughfare. For long their front-rank
                    warrior, and he, supported by 443 to 105, we may now take it that the the
                    pedestrian public have taken their lives in good half-back play, steadied the
                    attack.. The Sugate will follow suit, and that final success their hands in
                    attempting to "negotiate the Signallers defence, however, was not found will
                    crown the work upon which M. Delcassé formidable stream of traffic that sweeps
                    by at wanting, both New and Harper offering active sad Lord Lansdowne are to be
                    heartily con- certain hours of the day, almost without inter-opposition. The
                    first point of the game fell to gratulated. Nevertheless, it is to be regretted
                    lude, from the Place de la Concorde to the the Saints, and came from the foot of
                    Hutch- that, while the Agreement is accepted as a Arc de Triomphe. ings. That
                    player, taking up the ball close in Prance and England are happily very good and
                    lifting it over the heads of all, placed it whole, a resolution should have been
                    proposed and carried which affirmed that the Chamber friends, but as joint
                    administrators of the New just out of Quarterman's reach. The Signal- counts on
                    M. Delcassé to open negotiations Hebrides they can hardly be described as lers
                    tried hard to square before the interval with the British Government, as soon as
                    a success. One of the French papers in the and certainly their play deserved to
                    meet with possible, with a view to improving the New neighbouring island of New
                    Caledonia, re some success. Their efforts, however, were foundland Convention.
                    That Convention will, ferring to a recent massacre in the New Hebri- unavailing,
                    and the interval arrived with of course, when ratified by the Senate, be des,
                    describes the condition of this group as the score: Saint Andrew's 1, Signallers
                    0. binding upon the two Governments; bat M. "flagrant anarchy," and says neither
                    life The restart gave promise of a very fast Delossé is charged with the task of
                    getting it or property is safe there. Furthermore, moiety. The Signallers were
                    evidently bent altered to meet the requirements, real or both France and England
                    "incur a serious on penetrating the visitors' defence, but Keill aginary, of the
                    French fishing industry. I responsibility" in encouraging settlers to and
                    Fitzgerald were playing a sterling game, and am sorry that the Chamber has laid
                    that duty emigrate there under the present governing were well supported by the
                    halves. Curtis, too, up the Foreign Minister; I hoped that the arrangements.
                    French rights and interests in seemed to be in his element. Still the home-
                    troublesome question of the "French Shore" the New Hebrides are described as
                    "incon-sters persevered and reward at last attend would be settled once and for
                    ever; and the testably predominant," and the suggested solu-ed their efforts,
                    Saxton patting a beauty which fact that it will not be finally settled by the
                    tion of existing evils is the voluntary retire Curtis in clearing over-ran. This
                    gave the other present Convention constitutes a distinct draw-ment of England
                    from the scene and the part-forwards an opening which they were not slow back to
                    complete satisfaction. However, there nership. That remedy, however, would be
                    far to take advantage of, and the score stood one is no reason to fear that
                    England and France from popular either in England or in Australia all. From the
                    kick off play was pretty much That peculiarly Parisian institution, the confined
                    to midfield. The remaining twenty "revue," is more or less a standing dish in
                    the minutes was very finely contested, but no other music halls, but as the year
                    begins to wane, it scoring took place. The whistle sounded with It is a funny
                    country, this country of hair partakes more and more of the character of the
                    score. Signallers 1, Saint Andrew's 1 splitting and of duelling. Why M. Syveton
                    the English pantomime in its allusion to recent The following were the teams
                    smacked General André in the face has been and current events. The Alliance,
                    unfortun- Signallers: Quarterman, New, Harper, Hand- a mystery to everybody, but
                    a greater ately, forbids, but one can imagine the fun ley, Dovey, Austin,
                    Saxton, Limmer, Glee, one is why, as one of his officers has chosen that
                    sprightly French artists of the "Café Herbert, and Woodley. to make the insuit
                    offered to the Minister of concert would extract from the ludicrous Saint
                    Andrew's Curtis, Fitzgerald, Keill, War a personal matter, as Captain de Gail,
                    or story of the Russians in the North Sea. An- Bright, Clark, Nixon, Sweet,
                    Jones, Cowie, the 1leme. Cuirassiers, has done, he should other incident most
                    certainly to be seized upon Hutchings, and Halley. not be allowed to fight M.
                    Syveton and be is the escape and subsequent arrest of M done with it. After all,
                    he merely acted as Syveton. The escapade has little that is noble all, by 58
                    feet moulded breadth, and 36.6 feet deep to the tonnage deck, with a gross
                    tonnage an officer standing up for the Army, and is in it, but the "revue" lets
                    who will be moralist, not that what we are constantly inciting it simply amuses.
                    One has need of an extensive The Anchor Line have added to their fleet of 9,400
                    tons, and when fully loaded her dis ofhears to do! De Gail is an aristocrat
                    knowledge of "argot" and of all the ramifica- the steel twin-screw passenger
                    steamer Cale placement will be not less than 16,000 tons. The first-class
                    accommodation is situated by birth, and has always marked himself out tions of
                    French politics to thoroughly appre- donia, which was launched at Meadowsile,
                    amidships, with staterooms for 300 passengers as begg more of a thinker than
                    most of ciate the niceties of a Paris ""revue" where Parties, on theind Deprem
                    da, beristen on the main and bridge decks. The second- those of his class in the
                    Army. What he has parody is piled on parody, and paradox upon ing ceremony being
                    performed by her Grace class accommodation is also fitted amidships to done
                    in-challenging Syveton may be a rash paradox, often with a talent and a
                    brilliance the Duchess of Montrose, and the vessel will be wards the after end
                    of the vessel; with staterooms all ready and fully equipped in every particu-
                    for 400 passengers. The third class galley and a foolhanty act, but one cannot
                    help that are bewilderingly clever. The quality of lar to take her place in the
                    regular service of contains a most complete steam cooking plant. feeling glad
                    that some French officer should the jokes may be strained, but they generally
                    the company in good time for the spring and do such a thing after Friday's most
                    disgraceful drop in the right place.</p>
                <p>will quarrel over the matter, and we must be content with that we have got.
                    Perfection is not of this world.</p>
                <p>incident.</p>
                <p>Americans. have known how to turn the As to André, he is, it appears, very ill,
                    for theatres of London into a gold mine, and they M. Byveton's blow was a
                    thundering one; but are about to Americanise the theatres of Paris. I think it
                    is pure "méchanceté" that makes According to statements made in the local the
                    journalists talk about his "ratelier" having press, a powerful syndicate has
                    been formed, been deranged. They merely want to throw and it is proposed to
                    found as many as ten new ridicule upon him, and of that there is plenty theatres
                    in the French capital. Playwrights to throw, "Dieu le sait!" Meanwhile, he is
                    quake at the thought. At present they have a unmbtedly ill, and as far as it is
                    at present society strong enough to prevent managers known, both M. Syveton and
                    M. de Gait are from crushing them under the weight of com- under arrest. M.
                    Syveton was arrested just as petition. But in presence of a trust which can the
                    duel was about to take place, and there control ten theatres, a bitter struggle
                    against the was a rumour later to the effect that General power of capital is
                    feared. André had had his generous-defender "mis aux In Paris, at least, the
                    pawnshop has quaint, ariéts." Politics, and political manoeuvres, are
                    half-pathetic humours which it would probably always "tout puissant" in this
                    country, and be difficult to match in England. This is the in all probability
                    the general public will not time of year for renewals, and the expiry of the
                    know more of this affair until it is all over. date makes it possible to take an
                    inventory of En attendant, persons who are really indigold pledges remaining or
                    gone. This year a nant that the French Army should have small object pledged for
                    12s. 8d. in 1869 has contained spies, and others who have some been withdrawn,
                    after 36 annual renewals, in other reason, private or otherwise, for volving £1
                    138.-4d. Among the other "relics" showing up the methods General André still
                    remaining is a mantel ornament pledged for has employed in the carrying out of
                    58. 22 years ago, and regularly renewed. But what he doubtless considered his
                    duty, are the champion "relie" of the place is an ivory- busily exposing the
                    recent manoeuvres of the headed cane, on which the owner has paid 74d. Masonic
                    Lodges in the Army, and the Gaulois a year since 1859. and other papers are full
                    of revelations on the subject. This is, doubtless, quite right, and I because
                    the constant ringing of the bells and on only, imagine that good should come out
                    the call and protests of subscribers told so of the whole thing. That it will
                    bring about a severely on her nervous system that she was fresh Dreyfus
                    disturbance I can hardly believe compelled to leave her position, which she I
                    believed last year that such a thing as a had filled for nine years. revival of
                    that famous affair was not only An interview has taken place between the
                    possible, but even imminent. It is only fair Japanese Minister and M. Delossé
                    with that one should be allowed to change one's reference to "certain matters
                    relative to the opinions when one has a reason for so doing, observance of
                    neutrality," and the Tempe says and I now believe quite the contrary. I believe
                    that explanations are proceeding in an amicable that such a thing would be
                    considered by most way and there is very reason to hope for a infoential
                    Republicans as danger to the satisfactory result. In the present awkward
                    Republic, so great has been the prejudice position of France in the affixirs of
                    the nations, However, we shall in the utmost delicacy and tactfulness is
                    rendered Another series of duels has shaken Paris to necessary, and the country
                    has reason to feel its depths. In two pistols were used, and the grateful that
                    in M. Delcased it has a Minister seconds having apparently exercised the cus who
                    may be depended on to exercise the fomary care in loading them harmlessly
                    necessary quality of discretion. The progress there was, of course, no result.
                    One of the en of the Baltic Fleet is attended with the utmost counters was, that
                    postponed from Thursday danger to the Powers, and not until it has between M.
                    Syveton and Captain de Gait. The reached a destination, whether in the waters of
                    affair with swords was a thore serious matter, warfare or elsewhere, will they
                    be able to General Andre's son being distinctly pricked in breathe freely.</p>
                <p>A Paris telephone girl has committed suicide</p>
                <p>the wrist. The victim afterwards rode agay The Pasteur Institate of Paris is now
                    just on his bicycle, with much less inconvenience entering upon, the experiments
                    which it has than if he had taken part in a football match. undertaken for the
                    purpose of testing exhaus The language of the Papal allocation on the tively the
                    so-called-cancer serum of Dr., Doyen. ecclesiastical situation in France is
                    informeel by The experiments are under the care of Dr. &amp; spirit of dignity
                    and moderation. On this Metchinkoff, and have just reached the primary ocession
                    Plus X would seem to have derived stage of having ready two large
                    bladders-filled bie inspiration from the consummate states with Doyen cultures,
                    with which to propagate,</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" 
                facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/YYYY-page-images-N/YYYY-MM-DD-p6.jpg"> 
                
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>are an unfailing and reliable remedy for die of the important organe gout,
                    rheumatism, gravel pains in the bank and kindred silmante (nquired or
                    constitutional), Sold by prinetpal Chemite, not to loom quantities, but only in
                    boxes, price L bearing the British Government Bamp with th wonde Eugene Le.
                    Clero pred thereen</p>
                <p>The Biter of the Bgyption Gonette wil be pleased to resolve come nications
                    dealing with malies of local, interest, for yabletion. Notes of to covering in
                    (Between the hours of 10 am and 6pm. Outro time to protect the pable from frid
                    the Provinces are especially welcome. hould be sent to T by and Addres, not
                    nece</p>
                <p>Le Jeudi 24 Novembre conant pactis de 8h. pm., Man/elpalité groolders &amp; la
                    vente atten ahires jobliques pris de ontières Heropéens is &amp; is Porte
                    Rosene, d'ane quantité de pierres extraites der ersion des Forossions par de 400
                    1 100m Les betere devront par le droit d'an shore da 1020 époser le 10 000 de la
                    valore de la marebandise sehetés ant moment de la vante of soon Fon-M... 80/40.
                    Liv. Mare FT. 97 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 offener le paiement insigral &amp; Onlee
                    Mani. All come eipale, le leglessin da jour de l'etindiastion. Ile auront
                    sapporter le droise de carrière an prods de la Ville et devront enlever les
                    pierres ache tée dans un délai de dix jours, sone geins anah Are, pour compte de
                    l'adjudicataire. Alexandrie, le 21 Novembre 1904.</p>
                <p>"DOUBLE</p>
                <p>dv. Mare FT. 880/40 &amp; 10 .-M.</p>
                <p>10/40 1.18/40</p>
                <p>94044-8-9</p>
                <p>folle</p>
                <p>Writer's good faith The B</p>
                <p>1/Adminiralour W. P. CHATAWAY.</p>
                <p>THUM</p>
                <p>1:18</p>
                <p>Dr. LE CLERO'S SOAP. Molloal antiseptia used and recommended by ambent
                    dermatologists in the treatment of eos lepra, psoriaals, alourations, alta
                    eruptions: thehing and treating the bumours baby rashes ode, ale prophyte
                    against the risk of contmoting des and Infotions disordare generally. I healing
                    propension greatly minimise the bon ventence of shaving to use of phapes pote
                    ten La Tablete price / old by Cairo and Ale</p>
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p> Mors.</p>
                    <p> Bumi Halla, prigi, for as Patent mad at Dis</p>
                    <p>Sons, London.</p>
                    <p> Stoom and Maanal Fire Engin</p>
                    <p> F. Reddaway Co. Ld, Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p> The Oarel Brands Baiting at, she</p>
                    <p> Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p> The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                    <p> Rik Vortes Turbines,</p>
                    <p> Mosers. Greenwood Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p> Ths (a) Palent Bomb Batsriaal Dynamo Motors</p>
                    <p> McCormick's Reapers Mowers.</p>
                    <p> Planet Junior Agricultural Implements.</p>
                    <p> Borne Joan, Bood Dri, ate, st OLITER PLOUGES.</p>
                    <p> Agent in Cairo: MA. FATTUOOI.</p>
                    <p> 38-8-805</p>
                    <p> Agents for amEENE Economisers.</p>
                    <p> STEINEMANN MABARDI Co.</p>
                    <p> MERCHANTS,</p>
                    <p> The Egyptian Engineering Stores. CONTRACTORS MACHINERY</p>
                    <p> Bole Agenta for Egypt, Asia Minor and Syria for</p>
                    <p> IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p> Mears. Clayton Shuttleworth, Lincoln. Portable Exed Engines Boffers, Cos</p>
                    <p> milla, Thrashing Strawbruising Cutting Machines </p>
                    <p> \Piguet o., Lyons. French Steam Bagisan</p>
                    <p> Aveling Porter Lim., Rochester. Ste Bollers and Steam Ploughs Les Tanneries
                        Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Belting E.. Hindley, Burton,
                        Dorset, Vertical Engines and Bollars, specially designed for driving estrie
                        Dynamos Owntrifugal Pumps, sto, eta Hillafret Hagueot, Paria
                        Mectricians.</p>
                    <p> L. Dumont. Paris. Centrifugal pumps.</p></div>
                
               
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mesars. Platt Brothers, Limited, Oldham. Messrs. John Fowler &amp; Co.,
                            Limited, Leeds.</p>
                        <p> Steam Panghing Machinery and Bandries,</p>
                        <p> The Central Crolone Co., Limited, London. Grinding and Pulering
                            Machinery.</p>
                        <p> Mers Charles Cammell Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                        <p> Mors.</p>
                        <p> Bumi Halla, prigi, for as Patent mad at Dis</p>
                        <p> Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                        <p> Stoom and Maanal Fire Engin</p>
                        <p> F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld, Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                        <p> The Oarel Brands Baiting at, she</p>
                        <p> Ratner's Safes.</p>
                        <p> The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                        <p> Rik Vortes Turbines,</p>
                        <p> Mosers. Greenwood Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                        <p> Ths (a) Palent Bomb Batsriaal Dynamo &amp; Motors</p>
                        <p> McCormick's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                        <p> Planet Junior Agricultural Implements.</p>
                        <p> Borne Joan, Bood Dri, ate, st OLITER PLOUGES.</p>
                        <p> Agent in Cairo: MA. FATTUOOI.</p>
                        <p> 38-8-805</p>
                        <p> Agents for amEENE Economisers.</p>
                        <p> STEINEMANN MABARDI &amp; Co.</p>
                        <p> MERCHANTS,</p>
                        <p> The Egyptian Engineering Stores. CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY</p>
                        <p> Bole Agenta for Egypt, Asia Minor and Syria for</p>
                        <p> IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                        <p> Mears. Clayton &amp; Shuttleworth, Lincoln. Portable &amp; Exed Engines
                            &amp; Boffers, Cos</p>
                        <p> milla, Thrashing Strawbruising &amp; Cutting Machines</p>
                        <p> Mrs. Galloways Ltd. Manchester. The Largest Boller Works in the World
                            Walter A. Wood, Mowing &amp; Beaping Machian Co. Boorish Falla N. F.
                            (Acarion) Beapers; Mowers, Harvesters &amp; Bakes</p>
                        <p> Piguet &amp; Co., Lyons. French Steam Bagisan</p>
                        <p> Aveling &amp; Porter Lim., Rochester. Ste Bollers and Steam Ploughs Les
                            Tanneries Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Belting E.. Hindley,
                            Burton, Dorset, Vertical Engines and Bollars, specially designed for
                            driving estrie Dynamos &amp; Owntrifugal Pumps, sto, eta Hillafret
                            Hagueot, Paria Mectricians.</p>
                        <p> L. Dumont. Paris. Centrifugal pumps.</p>
                        <p> 8. E. &amp; E. Turner Ltd. Ipswich. Flour Mille</p>
                        <p> 31188-94-11-904</p>
                        <p> Winter Novelties Credit Lyonnais SHRADER BROTHERS.</p>
                    </div>
                   
               </body> </text>
</TEI>