<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Ryan Schefstad</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2023-10-20">October 20, 2023</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1904-11-23/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1904-11-23">Wednesday, November 23, 1904</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE</head>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, CITED</p>
                    <p>This Company's: f</p>
                    <p>the stirect and quickes</p>
                    <p>Purp Zompe, North and</p>
                    <p>wipe telegraph calles is munication fres</p>
                    <p>Americs, East, Sout</p>
                    <p>and West Africa, India, Australia New Zealand, Chines</p>
                    <p>To</p>
                    <p>e quick transmission, telegrams should be marke</p>
                    <p>Vis Eastern</p>
                    <p>For et average fire to Lolo, see daily balletta, STATINS IN EGYPT Alex,
                        Cairo, Bags, P Tew Pors-Said, Saskin fead Office, Londen,</p>
                    <p>THE EASTERN TELEGRAPH</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette,</p>
                    <p>No. 7,053]</p>
                    <p>ALEXAN BIA. WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>[SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</p>
                    <p>COMPANY, LINITED</p>
                    <p>La rées de cibles graphiques sous-marins de cetis compagnie enkelte le moyen
                        de communication le ple direct et le plus rapide d'Egypte pour Earepe
                        Amérique de Nord et do Sad, FAfriqa onentale, meridionale e Decidentale, Im
                        India TAstrabe à Nouvelle-Zélande, Chine et le Japon</p>
                    <p>Four serer one transmon rapide l elégra delrent porter Tindication VIA
                        Eastern Voir le tempe moyen de tranen le Londres a ballet journalier geblie
                        STATIONS EN EGYPTE Port-Tewik, Port- Senki Bare</p>
                    <p>Peninsular &amp; Oriental S. N. Company. British India S. N. Company,
                        Limited. Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Coy.</p>
                    <p>The following steamers are intended to leave Port Said on or about the
                        following dates:-</p>
                    <p>Marseille, Plymouth and Lenden. Marseilles, Plymouth and London Malta sud
                        London Malta and London.</p>
                    <p>Marseilles, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>MALACCA" "HUMATRA</p>
                    <p>6,046 Tone</p>
                    <p>November</p>
                    <p>Malta and Landon Maits and Landco.</p>
                    <p>CRANA</p>
                    <p>4410</p>
                    <p>7,913</p>
                    <p>MANILA</p>
                    <p>December</p>
                    <p>4.210</p>
                    <p>SARDINIA"</p>
                    <p>574</p>
                    <p>MACEDONIA"</p>
                    <p>10,811</p>
                    <p>MARMORA</p>
                    <p>10,809</p>
                    <p>PERA</p>
                    <p>9,712</p>
                    <p>SUNDA</p>
                    <p>CHINA</p>
                    <p>Marselle, Plymouth soul Leidon. Waris and Lendon</p>
                    <p>Malta and Lendon, - Marsellies, Plymouth and London.</p>
                    <p>Port-Baid to London via Brindisi. The BRINDISI steamer leaves PORT-BAID sher
                        arrival of Indian Mail. Combined steamer and giging me fare from PORT-SAID
                        to LONDON via BRINDISI or via MARSEILLES 25:9.11.</p>
                    <p>To the East</p>
                    <p>The Mall Bosses leave BUEZ for ADEN and BOMBAY every Wednesday, and for
                        AUSTRALIA and CHINA every alternate Wednesday. A same leavec for CALCUTTA,-
                        fortnightly, and another for JAPAN. Pagers en etabari PORT-SAID.</p>
                    <p>For all further information apply to the Company's Agents, Mors. Twoe. Coon
                        &amp; Bow (ayy) Lad.... Gueses BoTLE,</p>
                    <p>Moners. HARULDAN &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>MAIL AND PASSENGER STEAM SHIPS. SAILINGS FROM SUEZ London and Calcutta
                        Line.</p>
                    <p>Chiet-Office: Sharia Boulae, Grand Continental Hotel Buildings Br Ufice,
                        Upponte Savey Hotel, Caire Regular weekly Tourist Steamer Departures between
                        Carno and Assocax by the following</p>
                    <p>steamers --</p>
                    <p>Queensland Line of Steamers between London and Brisbane. MAYFLOWER</p>
                    <p>1904.</p>
                    <p>December 9th VICTORIA 38ed PURITAN 80th MAYFLOWER.</p>
                    <p>1905.</p>
                    <p>Calling at Apes, Cososo and Mansas Outward, and MasILE (GENOA and Purour
                        dpsional) Homeward Fortly rice in connection with the Ce's Indian Mail Line
                        and monthly with the East African Mail Lane between Aass, Mo sod EATERAL
                        OUTWARD S.S. Mutira. November 26 HOMEWARD: S.S. Mombassa Nov. 38 MAYFLOWER
                        FURITAN Weekly SECOND CATARACT SERVICE by the First Class Tourist Steamer
                        INDIANA AGENTS FOR PRINCIPAL STEAM NAVIGATION COMPANIES Through Bookings to
                        Khartoum and Gondokare. RAILWAY TICKETS TO ALL PARTS OF EGYPT. FREIGHT
                        SERVICE by steam barges between ALEXANDRIA and CAIRO SAVOY HOTEL Elephantine
                        Island, Accap, Company's Property.</p>
                    <p>Calling at Cusco, BATAVIA, Coorowy, Towa, Bows, and RockArrow S.S. "ITIA,"
                        will mail from Boes on or about the 14th December. REMARKS Surgeons and
                        Stewardes carried. Ice rooms, Funkata, and every comfort for stropical
                        climate. Passengers and Cargo booked shrough to Continental and American
                        Forte and to Gulf, East Africa, Burmah, Straits Settlements Eastern Archipel
                        important Porte on Cons of India, Persian may, so below, metode ble for Fint
                        acid Becond Cisas Pgly, bet not winds of spirit, which may be Jars and
                        Quomeland Perte. Bates of Pangs on beard for payment. Pengers are allowed to
                        break the reog my intermediate Parts probed by following FIRST GLASS BATH OF
                        PASSAGE MONEY FROM BURS AND IRMAT</p>
                    <p>Karmacha Bothbay Brshire</p>
                    <p>From Port Said # Agents in LONDON, Murs</p>
                    <p>Fonging Agent INDIA</p>
                    <p>CAIBO.</p>
                    <p>PORT-SAID. ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>81-19-90</p>
                    <p>F. G. DAVIDSON, Soprintendens P. &amp; O. B. N. Company in Egypt. BUEZ.</p>
                    <p>Orient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDE to AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p>B.M.B. Orotava. will leave Bass abous, Oroya</p>
                    <p>Orizaba</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Agence at PORT SAID,</p>
                    <p>Agmin M PORT SAID, Men Tho</p>
                    <p>For furth</p>
                    <p>Onlomb</p>
                    <p>Ola, Twe Thirds of 1st Cine T</p>
                    <p>and Karocbon</p>
                    <p>Company, GALNO &amp; ALARKANDRIA</p>
                    <p>G. BEXTS &amp; Co., Agents, Bues. 81-15-804</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE, Limited.</p>
                    <p>(HENDERSON BROTHERS), LONDON, LIVERPOOL, AND GLASGOW. First class passenger
                        steamers, Booking Passengers and. Cargo through to Ports in INDIA, EUROPE
                        &amp; AMERICA</p>
                    <p>Sailings Fortnightly from Buss.</p>
                    <p>Dec. 10 For CALOUTTA S.S. Ayria...... Nov. 24 For BOMBAY 8.8.
                        Circassia...</p>
                    <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.</p>
                    <p>Fortnightly Service from ALEXANDRIA (Passengers and Freight). Commonning on
                        the 16 of Novetube.</p>
                    <p>To NAPLES and MARSEILLES, with the Twinsrow-baloon mer Schleswig (100)
                        leaving ALEXANDRIA Ovary aboca Wedomday at 2 pm.: 16 &amp; 80 Nov., 14 Des.,
                        11 Jan 6 Jan, 3 Fab The following steamers are intended to leave PORT SAID:
                        HORNWARD: for Bremen or Hamburg v NAPLE, GOA (ISBALTAR), SOUTHAMPTON, P.
                        Bas. LavyOL 300 2008 BARSABUSSA PRAUSSEN</p>
                    <p>ZIETEN OLDENBURG</p>
                    <p>84 Ton PRINCES ALICE 10911 SCHARNBORST</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD: for Chine and Japan sum, ADES, UOLOMBO, PARANG, SINGAPORS, December
                        7 SKYDLITZ BOUN November 28 BAYERN ZIXTAN</p>
                    <p>Dee.</p>
                    <p>2</p>
                    <p>For LONDON</p>
                    <p>Lee.</p>
                    <p>16</p>
                    <p>For MARSEILLES ALIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>8.8. Bohemia S.S. Marilia</p>
                    <p>Dee</p>
                    <p>6</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>Baloon Farms: from Port-Baid, to Gibraltar 40; Marseille : Leverpool (alla
                        route) 818 London (all sea rente) 41311 vs Marvellion $16.16.0 Pangs
                        embarking at Ismailis &amp; more, 65 mars 10 00 reduction allows of the Army
                        of Occupation and Government employs. Through Hoke wed to New-York (v G).
                        Fares o Agentia in Oairo, Mons THOMAS,000K &amp; SON, Part-Bal, Mrs. CORY
                        BROTHERS &amp; OT For further particulars of Freight or Page apply to G.
                        BEYTS &amp; Co., Sues.</p>
                    <p>81-13-306</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY B.M.
                        Ortona will leave Port-bald about... NB-Homewarders are sometimes before
                        their advertised dates. Passengers landed and embarked at Ismailia,
                        Quarantine Regulations permitting, free of an expense 1 Class, 411 And
                        Clasi, &amp; 1 Brd Class, 44 81-</p>
                    <p>VARES</p>
                    <p>Pors-Hald to Nagles......</p>
                    <p>to Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>to Ginealta.....</p>
                    <p>18 18</p>
                    <p>10 10</p>
                    <p>10 MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED. Betablished 1888. Capital £1,000,000,
                        Bearve Fund 4035,000.</p>
                    <p>10-</p>
                    <p>8 16-</p>
                    <p>81-13-906</p>
                    <p>8000</p>
                    <p>-14 Nov De</p>
                    <p>GNEISENAU RHIN FRIEDRICH BREMEN</p>
                    <p>Zor Anetralla</p>
                    <p>FOR FURTHER PARTICULARS ARPAY TO TER ARNTS OF FER NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD at
                        Cairo, Alemandria, Port Said and Suen OTTO STERZING, A Cairo, Orena
                        BQUARE</p>
                    <p>C. H. SCHOELLER, AGA ALEXANDRIA, Oleopatra Lans</p>
                    <p>DALBO and AMBEANURIA</p>
                    <p>Hevur tickets so long tested, as per paying the full he in one duression are
                        allowed no Ola Broad Beroes, LONDON.-Hemblished 1908. Avial Funds exceed
                        $10,000,000, Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation.</p>
                    <p>to Plymouth or Tilbury. abstemens of one-third of their fars back if the rear
                        voyage be made within four monste of arrival, or An abotecons of so if
                        resten voyage be made within six months of armval. Ages, Cairo-THOMAS COOK
                        &amp; BOR. Alexandina B. J. Moss &amp; Co.- For all information apply to Wm.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Port-Said and Port-Tewik Sues), 81-18-904</p>
                    <p>BIBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>SPROIAL REDUURD RATES DURING THE SUMMER SHAUN</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS to 0OLOMBO: TUTICORIN, etc., and BANGOON</p>
                    <p>5. Yorkalere, 136 tons will have us abou. November 28,</p>
                    <p>8 Warwickshire, 19 tons, will leave bus; about December 7.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD MARSEILLE and LONDON,</p>
                    <p>Sa Worcestershire, 60 tons will leave Port-Said about November 29,
                        Shrupehors, 720 tons will leave Port-aid abous Desemoir</p>
                    <p>FARBS from Fortid to Marseilles 12.0.0, London 417.0.0 moo 632.100, Rangoon,
                        437.19.0. Fitted with Refrigerators, Bleonic Lights Electric fane and all
                        recent improvemente, Experienced Stewardesses and burgsons carried, Agents
                        in Cairo: Memes, THOS, GooR &amp; BON. Yor all particulars apply to W.
                        STAPLEDON &amp; SONS, Port-Said Port-Tewak (Sues).</p>
                    <p>81-18-904</p>
                    <p>1, Street,</p>
                    <p>81-19-904</p>
                    <p>2nd inst</p>
                    <p>Policies invoed at BUEZ by G. BEYTS &amp; Co., Agents.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste-Venice Line. Express Mail Hervice. Beam leave
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Deutsche Levante-Linie, in Today morning for agent to Paris, London</p>
                    <p>Weekly</p>
                    <p>Tneste We</p>
                    <p>Nov. 19</p>
                    <p>19</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>Mail and Passenger Beamships. Regular three-weekly serve from expresse
                        HAMBURG, VIA ANTWERP &amp; MALTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice vers, admitang
                        goods from all the prinelyal GERMAN BAILWAY STATIONS on diroos, Bill of
                        Lading to ASRXANDRIA and all the principal port of Bers, SYRIAN CHART,, as
                        she favourable through mana, of the Day Va (tm).</p>
                    <p>EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>8.8. Siegfried, now on the berth loading will sail for Rotterdam and Hamburg
                        on se S.S. Thasos now in port will sail for Beyrout on the 28rd inst Lesbos
                        from Answerp will mail for Beyrons on the 23rd inst.</p>
                    <p>For tariffs and parstenars apply to ADOLPHE STEOB8, Alexandria, Agent,
                        18-9-905</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE. Messageries Maritimes.</p>
                    <p>FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Green-Turkey Liss,</p>
                    <p>Express momers vs Alexandria every Wednesday 6pm. for FIRMUS (Athens), SMTRNA
                        MITYLENE, and CONSTANTINOPLE. in sospesos wish the Ons greasin-de-lass for
                        belgrade, Vienna, Paris, and London.</p>
                    <p>Palestine-Syita</p>
                    <p>Fasters gre Alexandria very day gim., and For Bald every Bunday atp., for
                        JAVVA (for Jessie), CALFFA (for Bar), BYHOUT. (for Demeras), TRIPOLI, ALEX-
                        ANDRETTA, MENINA, sensing in wks so LANNACA and LIMANNOL (Cyprus).</p>
                    <p>Red Sea Line.</p>
                    <p>mer leave Sues every Thursday sp. for JMDDAR, alling as required at TOR (for
                        Mouns Stasy and XAMBO,, and sonatsing in abseness wo UAKIN, MANNOWAR,
                        HODEIDAR And ADEN.</p>
                    <p>H.B. Desk chairs provided for the mes of passengers, excellent enivine and
                        table wine free.. ms plant may be seen and poenget booked st the Company's
                        Against Alexandria, Cairo, Fors Bad, and Uses of a Thos. Cook a son or oshee
                        Touries Agacey,</p>
                    <p>31-18-904</p>
                    <p>The Moss S.S. Company, Limited.</p>
                    <p>For GAVERFOUL ng MALTA, JANE MUU, LA, MARGIN</p>
                    <p>Baillage from alexandria in November, 1904,</p>
                    <p>Rate of passage Including bis wine</p>
                    <p>nd Ola</p>
                    <p>From Aidonsdria! For Marseilles direct Friday Nov. noon</p>
                    <p>Cap. Vincenti</p>
                    <p>Galent</p>
                    <p>Prem Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Wednesday</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>For Part Said Jaffa and Bayrants 1 Nov. Portugal Conge For Port Said and
                        Beyrouth Wednesday Nov. at p... Senegal Trongh tickets for Paris (vi
                        Marellin</p>
                    <p>Camagit Riquier Owp Galett</p>
                    <p>To Naple</p>
                    <p>To Marsiline</p>
                    <p>Raquier</p>
                    <p>Galet</p>
                    <p>Capt. Camagit Fascents</p>
                    <p>To Pers Bald To Jaffo</p>
                    <p>L161</p>
                    <p>-47.10</p>
                    <p>To Bayreut</p>
                    <p>Through tickets for London (vis Maresiae) (Unials Donyres)
                        Ceningns-Polkestone) marchangable return deal with the Antrian Lloyd Oy
                        (available Marlitosen and on redom by Austrian Lloyd) er Tre) Sallings from
                        Port Said In November 1904 Probably on Thursday 10 Nov, Bolaria Okpt. Négre
                        Gregort</p>
                    <p>For Mareation Directi</p>
                    <p>For A, Chicho, Bingapore, Balgo, Hong-Kong, Shandy Robe and Yokohams For
                        Dibena Colombo, Singapore, Belgin, Yekobams</p>
                    <p>Caledonien</p>
                    <p>Sallings from Seen In November, 1904</p>
                    <p>Saturday Wednesday 18</p>
                    <p>19 Nov. Ernet- Tombin Melbourne</p>
                    <p>marile, Adelaide, Mal-Monday</p>
                    <p>1 Den 38 Nov.</p>
                    <p>X</p>
                    <p>For Dbons Bannibar, Mutamado, Mayotte, Magune</p>
                    <p>For Dribeos, Aden, Mabe, Dag</p>
                    <p>T.M.</p>
                    <p>8,000</p>
                    <p>TADOS</p>
                    <p>Send</p>
                    <p>modation only, ani aiya</p>
                    <p>apply</p>
                    <p>ES. NITOURIN</p>
                    <p>birth, will an</p>
                    <p>freight</p>
                    <p>Lancashire inland i</p>
                    <p>FAR TO LAverpool, la, la Bingia, Ben, Ind. Bingle, BOSS &amp; C, Alexandria,
                        Agents fallowed by B SETI other UJA. town on be obtained en Railway are
                        through to and from Ontro, Partieniars on application,</p>
                    <p>Bunton and Mearice</p>
                    <p>For A</p>
                    <p>30-11-004</p>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO.'s LINE.</p>
                    <p>Somers or Bass Port-basd rialgaly tos London or Liverpoos dire Mastrie Light
                        SALOON (A) FARE AIR. (later improvement S.S. AMARAFOORA, 6600 Tone will
                        leave PORT-SAID about Nov. 97 for Liverpool. MARTABAN BANGOON 8000</p>
                    <p>750</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>A WORMS &amp; G., Part</p>
                    <p>for Laverpool 26 for Liverpool.. Dus in Leadon or Liverpool 18 days
                        thereafter. TMOS. GOOK A BON. EU La., 6. J. GRAGE &amp;. drie</p>
                    <p>Dee. "</p>
                    <p>31-18-40</p>
                    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p>(ROYPT), LIMIT.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFICE LUDGATE CIRCUS-LONDON,</p>
                    <p>CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE CAIRO, SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Port-Said, Iamallia, Suez, Luxor, Assouan,</p>
                    <p>Halfa &amp; Khartoum,</p>
                    <p>TOURIST AND GENERAL PASSENGER AGENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>bey, Gelembe, bearse, Bydiy and Neumen.</p>
                    <p>Gaira Agency Shepheard's Metal.)</p>
                    <p>returning from China</p>
                    <p>Anatralla</p>
                    <p>day noon conusong with Vienne pres (T-Ovende Imly and Germany. 4pm. Cleopatra
                        Capt. A. Ivallich. Nov. 284 p.m. Habsburg C Semiramis Marsinolich. Deo. 8
                        Ulkopatra Alexandria-Patras-Brindisi-Trieste Line. Beamer leaves Alexandra
                        on or about 3rd November, Tah and 21st December. Far East Line. (Departure
                        from Sun). To Aden, Bombay, Colombo, Fapang,</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Colombo, Madras, Hangoon and Calea abous November 90. East African
                        Line.</p>
                    <p>To Aden, Mombasa, Zanzibar, Beirs, Delagon Bay, Durban about December 4.
                        Syrian-Caramania Line</p>
                    <p>Steamer leaves Alexandria on or abous November 14 and 98, December 13 and
                        96.</p>
                    <p>Syrian Cyprus-Caramanian Line.</p>
                    <p>Beamer Laves Alexandria on or about November 23, December 5 and 10.</p>
                    <p>For all information apply to the Company's Age. And, Fort Bald and Soo, Te
                        &amp; Bon, L., Leon Hasan, Oniro Agent, 4 Sharia Maghaky (Telephone 198),
                        Cle Tapason, Heloman. Special passage rates granted to Egyptian Government
                        oficials, of the Army of Occupation and their families.</p>
                    <p>CUNARD LINE.</p>
                    <p>Trieste-New York. Liverpaal-New York BLAVONIA... Sept. 80, LecaMZA... 12,962
                        sons. UMBRIA PANTONIA Oct 14 CAMPANIA... 12,950 15,564</p>
                    <p>SLAVONIA... PANNONIA</p>
                    <p>Liverpool-</p>
                    <p>8,197 tone. Baxo</p>
                    <p>ErSURIA 8,119</p>
                    <p>AURANIA 7,526</p>
                    <p>16</p>
                    <p>18 Embarking passengers at the Riverside Railway Dec. 2 haion, Prince's age,
                        Liverpool, on Tuesdays and</p>
                    <p>the Agents UDUGANAUHI &amp; UB, Alandria; NICOLAS KIRSIS, Ore, B. BROADER</p>
                    <p>ELLERMAN LINES, LIMITED</p>
                    <p>CITY &amp; HALL LINES.</p>
                    <p>WARSHILLSS, LIVERPOOL, BOMBAY &amp; EARACHL</p>
                    <p>CITY LINE.</p>
                    <p>MALTA, LONDON, COLOMBO &amp; CALCUTTA</p>
                    <p>The undermentional First-Use Penger Steamere will be dispatched from Port bud
                        on or about the following Malta &amp; Landes S.S. Cry OF BEARS Nov. 30
                        Liverpeet. Colombe &amp; Caloutte &amp; Cor Caters No. Bombay &amp;
                        Kareahl-</p>
                    <p>for</p>
                    <p>&amp; Pros</p>
                    <p>Nov, 1</p>
                    <p>Cery on Lecko BALOO FassPort Had to Malta, 441 Mar 200 London or Liverpool,
                        41164 Calho, Cal Bombay or Karachi, 100. peal rate for more bot carrying
                        Doctor or Steward For further person GORY BROTHERS &amp; Uo., Ltd., agents
                        for the City Line, Port Said; W. STAPLEDON &amp; SON, Agent for the Hall
                        Link Port Baldy or to Tros. Cook &amp; Bon (gypt, Ltd. Ostro</p>
                    <p>L</p>
                    <p>Nov. 30</p>
                    <p>apply to</p>
                    <p>Tone</p>
                    <p>PRINCE LINE.</p>
                    <p>AFRICAN PRINC TUDOR PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Tons 5,000 WALAH PRINUBE 7100 BLACK PRINCE</p>
                    <p>CHINESE PRINCS (bd).</p>
                    <p>SWEDISH PRINCE (bida)-</p>
                    <p>ITALIAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>MERORANT FRINGE.</p>
                    <p>BOLDIRK PRINCE</p>
                    <p>MEXICAN PRINUR SICILIAN PRINC BRITISH PRINCE. GRECIAN PRINCE ORBOLE PRINUR
                        SYRIAN PRINGR.. INDIAN PRINC TUBGAN PRINU</p>
                    <p>2000 SPANISH PRINCE (Olde NORMAN PRINCES GROBOTAN FRINGE</p>
                    <p>16 BAVIAR PRINCR RUSSIAN PRINC 4,490 HIGHLAND PRINUS 8,780 NRAPOLITAN PRINO
                        IM MOORISH PRINCE 307S BAUTERN PRINCE 8060 CARES PRINCE COBANOS PRINUS..
                        SCOTTISH PRINCE</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>TOURAN PRINOR</p>
                    <p>Tona 1,000 | AFGHAN PRINC 2000 BURMESE PRINUS (dg). 7,000 BAXON PRINUR 4,000
                        CROWN PRINCR</p>
                    <p>4780 TROJAN PRINUS 463 BOYPTIAN PRINUS 4800 SPARTAN PRINCR 800 IMPERIAL
                        PRINCE 8,780 PERSIAN PRINUR 8.IM 33 CASTILLIAN PRINCE 800 AREATIO PRINUR
                        8,00 KAFFIB PRINCE..</p>
                    <p>3878 UTPRIAN PRINOR--</p>
                    <p>10 BOMAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>1,000 ROYAL PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Good Accommodation for Passengers.</p>
                    <p>Navigation Generale Italienne. Societes Rousies Flerie-Rabatties Services
                        Postaux. Departs de Decembre</p>
                    <p>Les Jendis 1, 8, 16, 99 99 8h. p. direct pour Messine, Naples, Liveure et
                        Génes.</p>
                    <p>Les Jendis 1 es 13 à 8h. p.m. direes poor Brindisi, Bari, Aneboe et
                        Veniso</p>
                    <p>Le Mercredi 18 &amp; 10 ham. pour les vales de la Syrie es Larnaque</p>
                    <p>Le Lundi 19 &amp; 4 b. p.m. pone Port-Sald, Snes et Masen wah.</p>
                    <p>Le Mercredi 7 et Jeudi à 8h. p.m. pour Fort Said.</p>
                    <p>BANK OF ATHENS, Limited. Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</p>
                    <p>Failings hegy 10 days from Haste sal gel and beinghtly Awad Less to Aldra and
                        Byrias Coast. The dates are apprinteri &amp; Teeth Fasha ARIATIC PRING due
                        trois Lende</p>
                    <p>Nov</p>
                    <p>INDEAN FRIZUR</p>
                    <p>Manhbester</p>
                    <p>Du</p>
                    <p>SCO TISH PAINOR</p>
                    <p>TROJAN PRINUR</p>
                    <p>Anwery &amp; London Manchester</p>
                    <p>CANTILLIAN PRINCE dee from Antwerp &amp; London Dee ROYAL PRINCS ARIB PRINOR
                        101RROLE PRINCE</p>
                    <p>Manchaster Antwerp &amp; London Manchester</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD SAILINGR-The &amp;&amp; Crown Prince is welding este sad will be
                        loved by the &amp; Asiátie Prinon For terms of freight or passage apply to
                        O. J. Grace &amp; Co., Alexandria, Agents. 31-12 904</p>
                    <p>THE PAPAYANNI LINE. (The Ellerman Lines, Ltd.)</p>
                    <p>Fregnant Sailingo from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL, aleo Begular Services from
                        LIVERPOOL ALEXANDRIA and to ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT. BLACK SHA, and other
                        Mediterranean Ports Excellent Passenger Accommodation. Stewardess carried.
                        Liberal table and</p>
                    <p>ap-Moderate Fares for single and return tickets by the 88. BARDINIA</p>
                    <p>Baggage and Forwarding Agents. NILE STEAMER SERVICES, TOURIST SERVICE. The
                        large and spendidly pointed P.S. Rameses, will leave Cairo on Tuesday,
                        November 29th, for Luxor, Assouan, and Phils. Other sailings every Tuesday
                        during the Season.</p>
                    <p>EXPRESS SERVICE-Steamers leave Oairó every</p>
                    <p>The BK CITY OF Dexos, cow loading will leave for Liverpool in a few days and
                        will be followed CARGO aken by spasial agreement only. Through Freight
                        quoted for the UNITED STATES and INLAND TOWNS in GREAT BRITAIN. For passings
                        or freight apply to the Agents, BARKER &amp; Co., Alexandria 8081
                        81-10-908</p>
                    <p>Monday and Friday during the season for Luxor, The Ellerman Lines.
                        Limited</p>
                    <p>ssouan, and Philae. 20 days on the Nile for £22. SPECIAL COMBINED BARWAY AND
                        STEAMER BE TOURS AT GREATLY REDUCED FARES. $1-WEEKLY SERVICE TO BALFA,
                        KHARTOUM, &amp; BUDAR. SPECIAL STEAMERS AND DAHABBAHN FOR PRIVATE PARTIES
                        Regular Service of Freight Steamers between GAIRO and HALFA. Cook's
                        Intergradere in miforts are prevent at the principal Bailway Batons and
                        Landing places in Boot Camp equipes. Lowest changes. 10-18-906</p>
                    <p>To to Palons,</p>
                    <p>(Including Westcott &amp; Laurance Line.)</p>
                    <p>Capital 28,000,000 (Fally paid a BANERS London, ha reet Within-Ales hent Gree
                        The Bank apdartakes all banking businem in gypt, Gre 6. Interests on caah
                        deposit</p>
                    <p>à per from Po P.P. 10,00</p>
                    <p>Despatch weakly a steamer with socommodation carrying Malls to Ceraus and the
                        SYRIAN OBART C For particulars of treight pa the Agent RDA, MINUTTO</p>
                    <p>SUDAN GOVERNMENT RAILWAYS. CAIRO-KHARTOUM SUMMER MAIL SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Dime</p>
                    <p>Dining and opting</p>
                    <p>Bunday and Wat</p>
                    <p>Lazee on Mondays, and from and Cairo, Tharaday and Friday more</p>
                    <p>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED. TRANSPORT DEPARTM et
                        goods anderskan to all coxon Whe ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT SOLE AGENDE FOR Digs
                        C Engine; from 1 Heat Co., Ltd, eto,</p>
                    <p>KHARTOUMAIRO OFFIC, SHARIA KASB--N NT day White Nile Tours Tripp Khartoum
                        Thotays Samar plasmay be Niles within navigation Shipyard he construin of
                        merwheel mit erection of all dies of machinery, bushings argon p B..Pplied
                        to Sudan Governan</p>
                    <p>Sheet</p>
                    <p>INTERNATIONAL SLEEPING AND RESTAURANT CARS COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>Depart</p>
                    <p>16.40</p>
                    <p>Alavambis</p>
                    <p>Regular sailings from Liverpool, Glasgow Antwerp and London to Alaxandris
                        Proquant sailings from Ales edria, to Liverpool sad des Throngh freight
                        rares to Inland towns in Great Aritate ale to the USA Work S.S. Bolderaa
                        from London &amp; Mali is due on or about Nov. 98 Che Ararat Liverpool
                        Hwaneos &amp; Malta Antwerp &amp; Londos Liverpool &amp; "Malts London</p>
                    <p>Ellerman Westcott Ellerman. Wenteos</p>
                    <p>Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Flavian</p>
                    <p>Delgravian Crestes</p>
                    <p>The B. Athenian, now the berth for Liverpool, will be despatel</p>
                    <p>For parsiquiars apply. E. TAMVACO,</p>
                    <p>every</p>
                    <p>Cal ser notice the Trais de ese componed anusitely Soping and Tarsat Care
                        will Cole res Monday, Weinlay, and Baluniag Thursday, and day from LaWMAN
                        Supplemant for leaping On PT. 18 (1) Tubes and all information can be
                        obtained at Company's</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/page/n1/mode/1up">

                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ric01">
                    <head>Royal Insurance Coy</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>
                    <p>Largest Fire Office in the World.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782);</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">31-3-905</measure> FRED. OTT &amp; CO., Sub-Agents,
                        Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-gwy01">
                    <head>GWYNNES, Limited.</head>
                    <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                    <p>Telegrams--GWYNNE, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Telephone--544 BANK</p>
                    <p>Codes-- ABC, 4th and 5th Editions, A1.</p>
                    <p>MORNING &amp; NEAL'S.</p>
                    <p>Trade Mark — "INVINCIBLE."</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
                        In the world, suitable fcr all purposes, including RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE,
                        IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL
                        MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                    <p>These Pumps can be driven by Steam, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other
                        power, for Lifts of from 1 ft. to 500ft., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a
                        Minute. Makers of the Mex Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Results Guaranteed.</p>
                    <p>Over 50 Years' Practical Experience.</p>
                    <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet
                        Egyptian requirements.</p>
                    <p>London Offices— 81, Cannon Street, London, E.C.</p>
                    <p>The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd: Rue de la Gare du Caire,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Works- Hammersmith, London, W</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">23362-11-12-904</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dcl01">
                    <head>D C L Scotch Whisky</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt &amp; Sudan</p>
                    <p>G. G Drossos &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Late Prazzica &amp; Drossos.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria. Cairo. Port-Said and Khartoum.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">1080 31-5-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-spc01">
                    <head>SPIRO CONDOLÉON.</head>
                    <p>SMYRNA TURKEY-CARPETS.</p>
                    <p>Made entirely of wool and vegetable colours</p>
                    <p>THE BEST CARPETS IN THE WORLD.</p>
                    <p>SPIRO BUILDINGS, Sharia Kasr-el-Nile, Cairo</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">29501-7-1-905</measure></p>
                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma01">
                    <p>Note Paper with Stamped (Raised) Address, &amp; c.</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Brass Plate Engraver<lb/> General Sign Writer<lb/> and Letter
                        Manufacturer</p>
                    <p>Bulac Road Cairo</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Printers Stationers Bookbinders.</p>
                    <p>Dealers in Fancy Goods.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">7-8-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>ASK FOR</p>
                    <p>BREWED AT WREXHAM, ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>WREXHAM LAGER BEER Co.</p>
                    <p>EXPORT</p>
                    <p>PILSENER</p>
                    <p>REGISTERED LABEL</p>
                    <p>AND IS NOT SUPPLIED</p>
                    <p>APPLY TO</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. CAFFARI</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO</p>
                </div>
                <!-- Humber -->
                <!-- Margosches -->
                <!-- Eden Palace -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-wam02">
                    <head>Walker &amp; Meimarachi, Limited.</head>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN SUPPLY STORES.</p>
                    <p>Portmanteaux.</p>
                    <p>Portmantenux.</p>
                    <p>Travelling Bags.</p>
                    <p>Travelling Bags.</p>
                    <p>Gladstone Bags.</p>
                    <p>Kit Bags.</p>
                    <p>Kit Bags.</p>
                    <p>Ladies' Fitted Bags.</p>
                    <p>Ladies' Fitted Bags.</p>
                    <p>Gents' Fitted Bags.</p>
                    <p>Gents' Fitted Bags.</p>
                    <p>Dress Suit Cases.</p>
                    <p>Uniform Cases.</p>
                    <p>Uniform Cases.</p>
                    <p>Soiled Linen Bags.</p>
                    <p>Soiled Linen Bags.</p>
                    <p>Holdalls.</p>
                    <p>Holdalls.</p>
                    <p>Bonnet Boxes.</p>
                    <p>Deck Wicker Chairs.</p>
                    <p>Deck Wicker Chairs.</p>
                    <p>A magnificent selection of solid leather goods and traveller's requisites by
                        the best English manufacturers.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO and Old Bourse Buildings, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">80—4-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cmh01">
                    <head>MENA HOUSE HOTEL</head>
                    <p>IS NOW OPEN.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24846—30-4-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>CAIRO-SAVOY HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Will Open November 26</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">31-3-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-eeh01">
                    <head>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL, PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>First Class Hotel. Modern in all respects.</p>
                    <p>Fire-proof, Drained to the Sea, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French
                        Billiards, Fresh and Salt Water Baths.</p>
                    <p>The Coolest Summer Residence in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Special terms to Cairo Residents and their families desirous of enjoying the
                        cool air and sea bathing during the summer months.</p>
                    <p>Dragomans in Hotel Uniform Meet all Trains and Steamers.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">22941-23-8-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>John Haig's Glen Leven</head>
                    <p>Old Scotch Whisky.</p>
                    <p>BOLE PROPRIETORS</p>
                    <p>JOHN HAIG &amp; Co, Limited, MARKINCH, SCOTLAND.</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED PRIOR TO 1680. R. CORBO &amp; G. PARIENTE, Caire.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>"AL HAYAT" Helouan</head>
                    <p>First Class Health Resort</p>
                    <p>Unrivalled Position on the Mokattam Hills</p>
                    <p>96 metres above the level of the Nile, surrounded by desert.</p>
                    <p>All rooms full south with sheltered verandahs</p>
                    <p>Public Sitting Rooms in separate Pavilions communicating by glass
                        corridors.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light–Steam-Heating–Lift.</p>
                    <p>Bathing, Air and Diet Cures. Resident Medical Director. All kinds of sports.
                        Own stables. Omnibus meets all Trains.</p>
                    <p>Ilustrated Prospectus sent free on appplication</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-abp01">
                    <head>THE ARTESIAN BORING AND PROSPECTING COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>(SOCIÉTÉ ANONYME)</p>
                    <p>CAIRO, 28, SHARIA-EL-MANAKH,<lb/> (OPPOSITE IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK).</p>
                    <p>I. —Installation of complete Water supplies for drinking, agricultural,
                        and<lb/> industrial purposes by means of artesian wells.</p>
                    <p>II. - Deep borings for prospecting purposes in all conditions of soil by
                        means of the<lb/> "Express Boring System."</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24,437-12-1-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-tph02">
                    <head>WHERE TO WINTER IN EGYPT.<lb/>The Tewfik Palace Hotel.</head>
                    <p>Telephone No. 5 Helouan.</p>
                    <p>Tel. Address "Tewfik, Helouan."</p>
                    <p>If you seek Health, Rest, and Recreation, Do not Fail to Visit Helouan.</p>
                    <p>"The Tewfik is Helouan and Helouan is the Tewfik."</p>
                    <p>The Tewfik-Helouan,"should be known to all who purpose to visit Egypt. – <hi
                            rend="italic">Glasgow Herald</hi>.</p>
                    <p>The Tewfik-Helouan,"is surrounded by pure dessert air under the best possible
                        conditions." – <hi rend="italic">Lancet</hi>.</p>
                    <p>The Tewfik-Helouan,"enjoys an exceptional position." <hi rend="italic"
                            >Egyptian Gazette</hi>.</p>
                    <p>The Tewfik-Helouan,"views from the windows absolutely charming – <hi
                            rend="italic">Egyptian Gazette</hi>.</p>
                    <p>Tel Address: </p>
                    <p>"Tewfik, Helouan." </p>
                    <p>Office in Cairo – Stephenson &amp; Co.,(English Chermists), Opera Square,
                        Telephone 82.</p>
                    <p>General Manager – C.Aquilina,</p>
                    <p>(late of Thos. Cook &amp; Son).</p>
                    <p>Pension from 10/3 per day.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24863-15-3-905-4</measure></p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>ALDERSON'S GARDEN, BULKELEY.</head>
                    <p>Friday, November 25, at 4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>GRAND VARIETY ENTERTAINMENT by the</p>
                    <p>ROYAL TOOKEY FAMILY. Chevalier J. Odress. Magician. Concluding with the Comic
                        Sketch "THE BRIGANDS." </p>
                    <p>GOD SAVE THE KING.</p>
                    <p>British Garrison with their families and officers of mercantile marine in
                        harbour and holders of permits are invited.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mav01">
                    <head>MAGASINS VICTORIA.</head>
                    <p>ECCLESTONE AND KEILL ENGLISH DRAPERY.</p>
                    <p>Opposite Austrian Consulate, near the Zizinia Theatre. Catalogue on
                        application.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>JOHN MOIR &amp; SON, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>LONDON, ABERDEEN, AND SVILLE.</p>
                    <p>PURVEYORS TO THE KING.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF</p>
                    <p>THE SEVILLE ORANGE MARMALADE,</p>
                    <p>WHOLE FRUIT JAMS, PURE PICKLES, &amp;C.</p>
                    <p>Head Office: 9 &amp; 10, GREAT TOWER ST., LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Agents: D.A. VAFIADIS &amp; CO., P.O. BOX 540, CAIRO.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="weather" status="unverified">
                    <head>DAILY WEATHER REPORT</head>
                    <p>OBSERVATIONS BY THE SURVEY DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <table rend="frame" xml:id="deg-ta-dawr01">
                            <head>ALEXANDRIA<lb/>Kom-el-Nadoura Observatory.</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">Direction of wind</cell>
                                <cell>S.S.W.</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">Force</cell>
                                <cell>Light</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">State of Sea</cell>
                                <cell>Slight</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell rows="4">During 24 hours ending 8 a.m.</cell>
                                <cell>Max. Temp in the shade</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">24.5</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Min. Temp in the shade</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">13</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Humidity of the air</cell>
                                <cell><measure type="percentage">70</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Rainfall</cell>
                                <cell><measure>0</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                        <p>REMARKS.</p>
                        <p>As noon yesterday the wind blew, strong from the NW. There was a rough a
                            Howry, dark, travelling clouds pre- wind falling light. At midnight it
                            became almost calm, with</p>
                        <p>allied and it was showery at times in the afternoon, the heavy continuous
                            rim and qually weather from the 8.8.W.. the ses becoming smoother
                            arometer rising slowly.</p>
                        <table cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-dawr02">
                            <head>OTHER STATIONS.</head>
                            <head type="sub">For the 24 hours ending 8 a.m. Yesterday</head>
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell>Stations.</cell>
                                <cell>Max. temp. in the shade.</cell>
                                <cell>Min temp. in the shade.</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Port Said</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">24</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">14</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Suez</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">21</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">12</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cairo Halouan</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">22</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">12</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cairo Ghizeh</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">16</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">12</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Beni Suef</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">-</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">-</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Assiout</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">24</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">9</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Assouan</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">27</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">10</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Wady Halfa</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">25</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">12</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Berber</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">35</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">17</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Suakin</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">32</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">23</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Khartoum</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">34</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">16</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Wad Medani</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">35</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">17</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Duam</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">36</measure></cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="dC">17</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:id="deg-el-egsa03">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</head>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS.– Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including
                        delivery in Alexandria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231½ per
                        annum, P.T. 116 for six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries
                        in the Postal Union P.T. 273 (£2.16s.) per annum.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.– P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages,
                        or Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20, every additional line P.T.
                        10. Notices in news columns P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for
                        standing advertisements.</p>
                    <p>N.B.– Subscriptions commence from the 1st or 16th of any month.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS are due in advance. P.O. Orders and Cheques
                        to be made payable to the Editor and Manager, Rowland Snelling,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>London Offices: 86, New Broad-street, E.C.</p>
                    <p>THE "EGYPTIAN GAZETTE” IS PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE
                        LONDON PAPER MILLS Co., LIMITED (SALES OFFICE: 27, CANNON STREET, E.C.)
                            <measure type="indexNo">25-6-90</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="imprint" xml:id="deg-el-egpi01">
                    <head>The Egyptian Gazette</head>
                    <p>An English Daily Newspaper, Established in 1880.</p>
                    <p>Editor &amp; Manager: R. Snelling.</p>
                    <p>Price: One Piastre Tariff.</p>
                    <p><date when="1904-11-23">WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904</date>.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAMPAIGN..</head>
                    <p>A dead calm appears to prevail for the time being in Manchuria, and a
                        telegram from Mukden to-day states that owing to the strength of the
                        respective positions, neither army ap pears inclined to attack, unless
                        possessing such a preponderance in numbers that they are able to make a
                        flanking movement. It will be useful during the present lull in the campaign
                        to study the climatic conditions which must exercise a very large influence
                        upon the course of the war. In Manchuria the climate oscillates between two
                        extremes. In winter the cold experienced is very severe, while in summer the
                        sun shines like a burning copper dise, and the thermometer rises to dearly
                        one hundred degrees</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Sunlight Soap</head>
                    <p>Absolutely Pure Genuine. The Great English Laundry Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fahrenheit in the shade. On the other hand, forty-nine below sero, or
                        eighty-one degrees of frost, is the lowest aqtually recorded in Man- churia.
                        Generally, speaking, in the south the average winter minimum is not much
                        below zero Fahrenheit. But what the armies have chiefly to fear is the north
                        wind, which is the terror of Manchi When it blows no cover ing of furs is
                        sufficient to keep out the piercing cold, and life in the open will be
                        almost un- bearable, especially, for men doomed to outpost and sentry work
                        at night. Fortunately, this awful wind rarely lasts three days; and in its
                        absence the winter sun shines 80 brightly that the dry cold is not felt.
                        When once the country becomes ice-bound and the rivers and streams are
                        frozen over, the tactics and even the strategy of the opposing armies will
                        be greatly affected. The side adopting the defensive will find that the
                        rivers have completely disappeared as a calculable factor, and can no longer
                        be reckoned upon as useful tactical obstacles to the passage of an
                        assailant. The lies, therefore, of the Tai-tae, the Sha bo, and the Hun will
                        shortly disappear from the nomenclature of the campaign as the special
                        localities of great struggles. It is a complete transformation of the
                        conditions of warfare, which will bestow a unique interest upon this
                        campaign, already so fruitful in sur prises. Another thing we may look for
                        is a great increase in mobility. As soon as the country roads and tracks
                        have been worn down they acquire the smoothness almost of an asphalt roadway
                        in Alexandria. With the new possibility of moving in all directions without
                        let or hindrance, the scope of the cavalry arm will be greatly enlarged.
                        Accordingly, until April and May next we may be on the lookout for many new
                        features in the winter struggle strugglo between the rival armies.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CRETE AND GREECE.</head>
                    <p>A telegram from London this morning an nounces that Prince George has made
                        another attempt to force the hands of the Powers in regard to Crete. No one
                        acquainted with. Cretan politics can doubt that the union to Greece is bound
                        to come sooner or later; but the moment of its consummation must depend on
                        the goodwill of the four Powers. Turkey would hardly do more than formally
                        protest, for she has practically lost all hold over the island, which has no
                        Turkish garrison, such as the soldiers who represent the Ottoman Suze rainty
                        over Samos. It is thought that France and Russia would not be favourable to
                        union in the near future; the relations between-Italy and Greece are not
                        particularly good, the: Italians and the Greeks are rivals in Epirus, and
                        the compulsory recall of the Italian Minister from Athens last spring did
                        not improve the feelings of the two races: Great Britain has no special
                        interest, in hindering, or in hastening, the union, except that, when once
                        the Greeks have Crete, they will demand-Cyprus, which is always regarded by
                        them as an Hellenic island. The most formidable argument in favour of the
                        union is that no one desires a fresh disturbance in Crete this winter, which
                        would certainly call for the intervention of the Powers Few will be so
                        singuine as to pretend that the Cretans will find amalgama tion with the
                        Greek Kingdom a complete success, nor will the Athenian politicians have an
                        easy task in governing the warlike popula tion of the island. Besides,
                        certain Balkan States will almost certainly pat forward claiek for
                        compensation, as Greece herself did when Hastern Roumelia was united to
                        North Bul garia in 1883. Meanwhile, we cannot shut our, eyes to the fact
                        that the Cretan question has been once more reopened, and that at a time
                        when Europe has many preoccupations elsewhere.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/page/n2/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>TO-DAY'S TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WAR.<lb/>A STALEMATE.</head>
                        <dateline>Mexes, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>Owing to the strength of the respective positions, neither army appears
                            inelined to attack unless possessing such a preponderance in numbers
                            that they are able to make a flanking movement. The Japanese probably
                            have the most available troops (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY.<lb/>RESPONSIBLE OFFICER ARRIVES.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETSSBURG, November 22.</dateline>
                            <p>stated that, at the request of Great Britain and Rassis, the Emperor
                                of Austris will nominate the fifth member of the Com mission of
                                Inquiry.</p>
                            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>PARIS, November 22. </dateline>
                            <p>It is stated here that, at the request, of Great Britain, the Russian
                                officer, of the transport Kamchatka, who first gave the order to
                                open fire on the trawlers, has been landed! at Dakar. He will appear
                                before the Commis sion of Inquiry. (Reuter)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GENERAL NEWS.<lb/>A RUSSIAN RUSE. DESTROYER BOUGHT IN ENGLAND.</head>
                        <dateline>LowDos, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>The Standard says that Messrs. Yarrow reported to the Admiralty last
                            September that a destroyer had been bought from them by a gentlems in
                            Paris, who wished to have it altered for yachting purposes. The
                            Admiralty communicated with the Foreign Office, who made inquiries in
                            Paris. Their suspicions being aroused, they sent Messrs. Yarrow
                            instructions to retain the boat. It was, however, too late to do this,
                            as the destroyer had left the Thames. It eventually reached Libnu, and
                            joined the Baltic Fleet. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MACEDORIA.<lb/>EFFECT OF REFORM SCHEME</head>
                        <dateline>VIENNA, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>According to an official statement issued here, the Austro-Russian reform
                            scheme has greatly improved the general condition of Macedonia. The
                            population itself desires ponce.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRETE.<lb/>CERTAINTY OF DISORDERS.</head>
                        <dateline>Lowpos, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>Cin a memorandum by Prince George, handed to the Powers, he emphasizes
                            the certainty of disceders in Crete, if the people's spirations for the
                            union to Greece are again rejected.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GREAT GALE IN NORTH SEA PORTUGUESE ROYALTIES SNOWED UP.</head>
                        <dateline>LONDON, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>A great gale is raging in the North Sea There are several wrecks with
                            loss of life Blinding snowstorms are taking place in the North and
                            Midlands of England. The tele graphs are broken, and the trains delayed.
                            The King and Queen of Portugal were snowed up at Chatsworth, where they
                            are the guests of the Duke of Devonshire. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRENCH CHAMBER</head>
                        <dateline>PARIS, November 22.</dateline>
                        <p>The Chanrber of Deputies has rejected the ppression of secret funds</p>
                        <p>M. Combes had put the question of con fidence (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STRIKE AT LORIENT</head>
                        <dateline>LORIEST, November 29.</dateline>
                        <p>The workmen at the powder factories have declared a general strike, and
                            the workmen at Bret areal are joining with them (Hans)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>"AU DE ROUGE." General Drapery Establishment.</p>
                    <p>(Central Tramway station), CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>P.PLUNKETT</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH</p>
                    <p>TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>JUST ARRIVED LATEST DEMONS IN LADIES'</p>
                    <p>18-11-000</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GREEK ASIZE COURT </head>
                        <p>at Alexandria will begin its sittings on the 13th December</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BRINDISI MAIL </head>
                        <p>will be distributed at the G.P.O, Alexandria, to-morrow morning at 8
                            o'clock.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MARIOUT RAILWAY-</head>
                        <p>The Dairs Khasss has bought a large quantity of old material from the
                            Railway Administration for use on the Mariout line.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>REUNION DES FAMILLES.</head>
                        <p>The series of win- ter reunions of this society will commence on
                            Saturday, 17th December, with a ball and Xmas Tree. Subsequent balls
                            will be given on January 21, February 25, and April 1 respect ively, the
                            last closing the season.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EVENING EXPRESS. </head>
                        <p>In response to a petition presented by the inhabitants of Ram- leh to the
                            State Railway Administration, the latter have arranged to stop the
                            evening ex- press train from Cairo at Sidi Gaber, com- mencing from the
                            19th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE FRERES CASE-</head>
                        <p>The appeal of M.Yayon against the judgment of the French Consular
                            Tribunal at Cairo, which condemned him to a month's imprisonment for
                            defaming the Con gregation of the Frères, will be heard by the Aix Court
                            of Appeal on January 26:</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BLIND SCHOOLS-</head>
                        <p>A 'bazaar in aid of the blind schools at Alexandria and Tantah will be
                            held at the residence of Mrs. Coventry (which has been kindly lent for
                            the purpose), Mansoursh, on Friday next, at 2 p.m. The sale is under the
                            patronage of Mrs. B. Dale.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN POSTAL ADMINISTRATION-</head>
                        <p>It has been announced by some of our contemporaries that Douglas Morice
                            Bey has been appointed] director of the Port Said Post Office in succes-
                            sion to Mr. Mancantelli: The appointment has not yet been filled up, but
                            it is vacant, as Mr. Mancantelli has been transferred to Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INSURANCE. -</head>
                        <p>The "Fidelitas" Assurance Company of Brussels has authorised Messrs. Alf.
                            G. Buhagiar &amp; Co, of Alexandria, to repre sent it throughout Egypt.
                            This company is one of the leading assurance companies in Belgium, and
                            insures against maritime, fluvial; and fire risks.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DAIRA SANIEH BONDS. </head>
                        <p>The Committee of the London Sotek Exchange has allowed the following
                            security to be quoted in the official list: Egyptian Government,
                            £1,264,820 Daira Sanieh Bonds, 1890 "stämped for exchange," in lien of
                            the same amount of bonds unstamped now quoted.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE AMERICAN ANNUAL NATIONAL THANKS GIVING </head>
                        <p>will be observed to-morrow (Thursday). In recognition of this
                            anniversary, a service will be held at 11 o'clock to-morrow in the
                            American Mission Church, Cairo, near Shep- heard's Hotel Residents and
                            visitors are cordially invited to participate in this service.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUEZ CANAL-</head>
                        <p>On the 19th and 20th inst. 33 vessels passed through the Suez Canal. Of
                            these, 24 were British, 2 French, 4 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Austrian, and 1
                            Portuguese. The transit and passenger dues for the two days amounted to
                            884,032.02 fra. The total transit and passenger dues collected from the
                            1st to that date on 298 vessels amounted to 6,612,139.09 frs.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive is spending to-day at Mariout, where he is inspecting his
                        estates. His Highness will return to Montazah in the evening.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN STATE DOMAIN. </head>
                    <p>Messrs, N. M. Rothschild and Sons announce that Egyptian State Domain
                        Mortgage bonds to the amount of £20,220 nominal capital have been drawn for
                        payment at par on December 1. The drawing consists of all bonds (not pre-
                        viously cancelled by the operation of the sinking fund) comprised in the
                        series of numbers advertised</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ELEMENTARY EDUCATION. </head>
                    <p>About a thousand children of the employée of the Egyptian Railway
                        Administration are without any means of obtaining any education whatsoever.
                        The Board has now decided in principle to pay a few fikis, who will begin
                        the work of instructing the progeny of platelayers and others.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>YACHTING</head>
                    <p>The British turbine yacht Emerald sailed from Alexandria harbour yesterday,
                        bound North The ateam yacht Catarina is now at Port Said, and leaves for
                        Suez in a day or two</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Mose liner Marie arrived at Liverpool- on Monday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail 8.8. Dabablish will leave Alexandria on Saturday and Port
                        Said on Sunday for Beyrout, Tripoli, Mersins, Alexandretta, Larsen,
                        Limassol, Caiffa, and Jalla.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer,</p>
                    <p>&amp;HOTEL COMPANY. RIVER-TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO
                        Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agente al Alegendris</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA BOLD WAREHOUSE CO., L</p>
                    <p>$1.10.004</p>
                    <p>LO</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.<lb/>DEPARTS FOR PORT SAID.</head>
                    <dateline>CANEA, November 22.</dateline>
                    <p>A division of the Baltic Fleet has left for Port Said. It consists of two
                        battleships, three ernisers, six destroyers, and nine transports</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>As we go to press, we learn that the Baltic Squadron is expected to arrive at
                        Port Said to morrow morning.</p>
                    <p>The following are the vessels of which the Russian Squadron is composed:</p>
                    <p>Battleships: Sissi Veliki and Navaria Cruisers: Almaz and Seietlana.</p>
                    <p>Torpedo bost destroyers: Blestyachtchy, Bezprechwy, Buistry, Byedoci, Bravi,
                        Bodri, and Buini</p>
                    <p>Volunteer Fleet steamers: Voronej, Tamboe, Vladimir, Kief, and Jaroslan</p>
                    <p>Transports Gortchake, Jappiter, Kitai and Meteor</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JAPS AND THE RED SEA.. </head>
                    <p>A nautical correspondent writes</p>
                    <p>If the Japanese are lurking about somewhere in the Red Ses on the look-out
                        for the Russian fleet, the most likely spot for them to be lying in waiting
                        is in the neighbourhood of the Daedalus lighthouse, to the north-east of
                        Berenice. The reefs run out there in every direction and yet one cannot
                        touch bottom in 300 fathome with deep ses lead. The Japanese could place two
                        torpedo-bosts there, one on the east and one on the west of the channel, and
                        they could knock the Russians into a cocked hat at this point.</p>
                    <p>The Sues correspondent of the Daily Er přess wires to that paper on the 15th
                        inst. as follows:</p>
                    <p>It is reported that disguised Japanese war vessels have arrived here with the
                        intention of blowing up that portion of the Baltic Boet which will go
                        through the canal. The Russian admiral has cabled to the consulate here to
                        arrange about supplies. Four steamers of the Volunteer fleet which are said
                        to be flying the commercial flag are expected hourly at Port Said. Their
                        names are unknown."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH CRUISER AT SUEZ</head>
                    <dateline>Suez, Tuesday-</dateline>
                    <p>As wired to-day, H.M.'s second-class cruiser. For arrived at Suez this
                        morning from the East Indies.</p>
                    <p>She will change her crew with that brought out by the Hermione, and then
                        return to her station.</p>
                    <p>It it probable that the Fe will remain at Suer with the Hermione pending the
                        arrival of the Baltic Squadron.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PUNITIVE EXPEDITION IN SUDAN. </head>
                    <p>The War Office issued the following state- ment to the Press yesterday:</p>
                    <p>On the 10th ult. a patrol left El Obeid for Rahad, under the command of
                        Miralai O'Con- nell Bey, to proceed against Abou Zeids of Kitrs, who had
                        expelled the Mek appointed by the Moudir of Kordofan last April and asurped
                        his authority.</p>
                    <p>The force arrived at Gebel Daier on October 12, when Abou Zeida was ordered
                        to come in by the 13th. He refused, and on the 14th the axpedition advanced,
                        capturing the village and some hills. Meantime, the Meks of Feria and Kemla
                        joined Abou Zeids and desultory firing continued till the 18th, when the
                        Camel Corps and artillery captured the two villages. In the afternoon of the
                        same day, the Meks of Parla and Kimla came in and received the "Amam." After
                        the last skirmish Abou Zeida, with few followers, took to the hills, but on
                        October 21 he surrendered and received the "Amam." No further trouble is
                        expected in this part of the country. The following was the composi tion of
                        the expeditionary force-</p>
                    <p>Artillery</p>
                    <p>officers, 34 N.C.O.'s and men,</p>
                    <p>3 guns. Camel Corps-6 officers, 200 N.C.O.'s and</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                    <p>12th Sudanese-7 officers, 126 N.C.O.'s and</p>
                    <p>men.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOLAR MOTORS FOR EGYPT. </head>
                    <p>Egypt is shortly to have what are called "solar motors." The heat of the sun,
                        so long neglected as a practical factor in producing power as applied to
                        industries, is being taken up seriously, and another generation (or our own)
                        will see the land dotted over with devices of one kind or another for
                        gathering and con centrating the heat and power, arriving at the earth from
                        the sun, and heretofore absolutely waited, so far as human utility is
                        concerned. One development of the practical use of solar heat is the solar
                        motor. This is so designed na to automatically face the sun at all times of
                        the day, and by the use of a steam boiler in ita focus, produces steam at a
                        high pressure, and in great quantity, for any use</p>
                    <p>One of these devices is to-day in actual practical use in Arisons, at
                        Willcox, and is pumping all the water needed for irrigating a very large
                        farm in that arid,country. Others, sopording to a correspondent of the New
                        York Herald (Paris), are being sent to Egypt and South Africa</p>
                    <p>The greal economic problem solved by the utilisation of the sun's heat is, of
                        course, the practical production of power to say degree without cost of
                        fuel</p>
                    <p>That this will be developed more and more As the years go by, producing power
                        where fual is absent or its price prohibitive, seems now an unquestionable
                        fact,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HOUSING PROBLEM.<lb/>MR. ALDERSON'S SCHEME</head>
                    <p>The following is the text of a proposal which is to be placed before the
                        Alexandria Municipal Commission by Mr. G. B. Alderson on Wednesday next, in
                        regard to the housing question in the city:</p>
                    <p>"In answer to the locataires plea re more accommodation for artisans and
                        employés, I beg to submit the following suggestions:</p>
                    <p>"On the table you will find complete plans, with all details, for a block of
                        110, to cost, say, under L.E. 20,000.</p>
                    <p>"Also plan of the city, showing the lands at present not used and belonging
                        to the Govern ment and the city.</p>
                    <p>"Will the Municipality request the Govern ment to cede plot marked A., or
                        rather, say, 30,000 sq. m., on the following conditions: </p>
                    <p>"1. This block to be built according to plans presented, possibly in about a
                        year.</p>
                    <p>"2. Apartments to be let at rents not to exceed 10% on actual cost to workmen
                        ap proved, and who will be selected or balloted for, of all
                        nationalities</p>
                    <p>"3. Capital to bear 6% interest, and no more, balance for a sinking fund,
                        repairs, and administration.</p>
                    <p>"These houses to be free of all taxes such as water, light, and 2% tenant's
                        tax.</p>
                    <p>free</p>
                    <p>15. Water to be supplied by Municipality</p>
                    <p>"8. Municipality to guarantee a minimum dividend of 3% on the capital.</p>
                    <p>"On these terms I will undertake to obtain the necessary capital, build, and
                        when finished hand over to the Municipal Council to admi nistrata</p>
                    <p>"I have visited the various quarters of the city and the artizans' dwellings,
                        and find it is a real vant to avoid disease and discontent. "P.S. The
                        expenses of finding the capital for the first block, till finished and
                        handed over to Council, will be my affair.</p>
                    <p>"Shares will be disposed of, say, £1 to £28 to industrious artizans and £500
                        the limit one to hold</p>
                    <p>"It is my desire to create a profitable and sure investment for the
                        artizans</p>
                    <byline>GEO. B. ALDERSON."</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IRRIGATION DEPARTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Mr. K. George Veitch Murray is appointed surveyor of contracts of the 3rd
                        class and is attached to the service of the Assiout Barrage Mr. G. Parker is
                        appointed surveyor of contracts to the 3rd Circle, Mr. L. R. Wallace to the
                        2nd Circle, and Mr. F.B. Jacomb to the 4th Circle.</p>
                    <p>The salaries of each of these officials will amount to L.E. 240 per annum.
                        The Govern ment reserves the right of transferring them, should it seem fit,
                        to the Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>P. W. D. CONTRACTS</head>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has given out the contracts for the winter
                        cleansing works in the canals as follows:-</p>
                    <p>Assiout-Mr. Sturgess</p>
                    <p>Galioabieh.-1 and II. groups, Khalil Chahin. Dakahlieh-Group 1., Messrs.
                        Bellini; 2. 8. Chaker; 3. Moh. Ali Wanis.</p>
                    <p>Charkieh.-1. Nasu Ghoraieb; 2. Mr. F Baldi; 3. Les Linitiche; 4. D. Cangos;
                        5. W. Cossena; 6. C. Cangos; 7. Youssef Gho mieb; 8. Ibr. Khalil Chahim; 9.
                        Khalil Khoury.</p>
                    <p>Markas Abnoub-C. Passaris.</p>
                    <p>Assiout and Manfalout-Kamel Roufail.</p>
                    <p>Minieh (West of the Nile)-MM. Th. Yanni and B. Hanna; Minich (East of the
                        Nile), J. Chasseand; Samalout, W. Papadopoulo; Beni Maar, W. Taylor; Fashn,
                        D. A. Andenis. Beni Sooef-Beba, MM. Liotto and Wour lich; Beni Souef and
                        Wasta, Mr. E. Bramall. Fayoum, Moh. Aff.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="theatre">
                    <head>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE </head>
                    <p>The second performance of Thomas's Mignon last evening, proved again a very
                        great saccess, Signa, Baldini and Signor Tomisani being frantically
                        applanded throughout the evening. Signa. Baldini a interpretation of the
                        title role was one deserving of the highest commends tion, and the many
                        present. who were moved even to tears by her pathetic impersonation of
                        Mignon, is proof of the excellence of this very accomplished lady's
                        performance. As Gugliel mo, Signor Tomisani, who possesses a voion of good
                        timbre and delightful freshness, was eminently successful, and his delicate
                        handling of the several charming romances falling to his lot, brought him
                        enthusiastic applause Indeed, it is difficult to understand why this theatre
                        is not crowded to overflowing every evening, when two such artistes as those
                        above mentioned are included in the caste</p>
                    <p>This evening, Rossini's opera Il Barbiere-di Siviglia will be given, with the
                        tenor Tomisani in the caste. To-morrow evening, a benefit performance of the
                        ever popular Ada will be given for a very deserving object, vis, the
                        International Employés Society of Alexandria The performance is placed under
                        the patronage of M. Pierre Girard, French Consul, and the two celebrated
                        prime donne, Signe. Popovici and Fabbri, will take part</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALHAMBRA THEATRE </head>
                    <p>Un Ballo in Maschera was succesfully given yesterday evening. Tonight,
                        Rigoletto, will be given, with the tenor Apostolon.</p>
                    <p>Tomorrow Cavalleria Rusticana and I Paplincci will be staged, and on Friday
                        Verdi's Simon Boccanegra will be produced for the first time in Egypt</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Be. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED,</p>
                    <p>16.7.00</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.<lb/>YESTERDAY'S MEETING.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENT.) </byline>
                    <dateline>London, November 22,</dateline>
                    <p>The annual general meeting of the Anglo- Egyptian Bank (Limited) was held
                        this after noon. The report and balance sheet were passed, and the dividend
                        of 15% declared which, includ ing the dividend of 10% for the first six
                        months, made a dividend of 13 per cent on the twelve months' working.</p>
                    <p>The Chairman, in the course of his speech, gave some details as to the issue
                        of the 20,000 new shares. The shareholders took up the quota to which they
                        were entitled to the extent of 18,000; the remaining 2,000 were sold on the
                        Stock Exchange at £12 each nett to the bank, or £2 premium on the issue
                        price, giving the bank a profit of £4,000. From this must be deducted
                        £1,000, the cost of issue (mostly Government stamps), leaving a nett profit
                        of £3,000. This £3,000 is to be devoted to paying the staff a bonus of 10
                        per cent. on their salaries for the past year. This decision met with the
                        hearty approval of those presant</p>
                    <p>The Chairman then went on to state that the capital of the bank was one
                        million and a-half, of which half a million is paid up. The reserve fund is
                        also half a million, equal to the paid-up capital. He then sketched the
                        policy of the Board in dealing with the profit. The first charge on the
                        profit will be £62,500,, or 12 per cent. dividend on-the capital of half a
                        million; the second charge, subscription to staff provident fund £1,500; the
                        third charge, the very large amount of £30,000 to establish a pension fund
                        for the benefit of the staff. This is undoubtedly a very large, sum, equal,
                        as it is, to 6 per cent, on the capital of the bank. The £30,000 will become
                        the property of the staff, and the scheme for its appropria- tion to
                        individuals will be carefully drawn up. The chairman then dealt with the
                        general outlines of the pension fund. The meeting ended without any
                        incident, the shareholders prosent expressing their general satisfaction
                        with the prosperous position of the bank's</p>
                    <p>affairs.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NUNGOVICH HOTELS CO.</head>
                    <p>In regard. to the various rumours as to the Nungovich Hotels Co., we
                        understand, that Nungovich Bey has not resigned, but that Sir Elwin Palmer,
                        Sir John Rogers and Mr. Cattaoui have sent in their resignations, as members
                        of the Board of that Company.</p>
                    <p>It is, however, fully expected that the matter will be amicably settled.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Colonel Younghusband, of Lhams fame, and his wife were passengers by the P.
                        &amp; 0. 8. Mongolia, homeward bound from Bombay They disembarked at Suez
                        early on Monday morning</p>
                    <p>Lady Low also landed at Soes from the same steamer:</p>
                    <p>Sir Edmund and Lady Lechmere and Mr. Ronald Lechmere are among the passengers
                        by the P. and O. steamer Persia, which is due at Port Said on Tuesday next,
                        Sir Edmund is proceeding to East Africa on another big game shooting
                        expedition.</p>
                    <p>An interesting party of tourists are arriving in Egypt in a few days' time by
                        the steam ach Vectis, belonging to the P. and O. Steam- ship Company She has
                        on board many well- known passengers, including Sir William J. Dupree, mayor
                        of Portsmouth; Mr. John Gordon, M. P. for Elgin; Mr. B. Dosse, formerly
                        courier to the late Queen Victoria; Mr. J. Lockwood Kipling, father of the
                        well- known author, and also an author himself, having written a charming
                        book on animals; Sir James Pelle, K.C.S.L.; Mr. H. W. Uloth director of the
                        Peninsalar and Oriental Com pany, accompanied by his wife; Mr. Tristram
                        Blis, Mr. C. Martin, Sir Acquin Martin, Mr. G. J. Ingram, with his daughter;
                        Mr. R. E. Craig, Jr, Mr. and Mrs., Flotober, and Mr. B. W. Knox, with his
                        wife and daughter</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will take place at the end of December,
                        between Adrian, only son of the late Sir Adrian Dingli, G.C.M.G, C.B., Chief
                        Justice of Malta, and Lady Dingli, of 3, Strada Forui, Valetta, and grandson
                        of William Henry Charlton, of Hesleyside, North amberland, and Geraldine,
                        youngest daughter of the late H.F. Curwen, of Workington Hall, Cumberland,
                        and Mrs. Carwen, of The Island, Windermere, and 14, Manson plac, Queen's
                        Gate</p>
                    <p>The native Press announces the death of Mohamed Bey lakander, son of Soliman
                        Pagha El Franssoni (Colonel Seven), late Minister of War. The deceased was
                        60 years of age. Dr. Gottheil, profesor at Columbia Univer sity, has left
                        the Carlton Hotel, Balkaley, and is now staying at Shepheard's</p>
                    <p>Mrs. A. G. Harris left by the Orient-Pacific R. M. S. 8. Ophir for New
                        Zealand on the 17th inst</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramlah</p>
                    <p>Heal Nowly</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item" feature="army">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAVY.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM Or Own COMOVENT</byline>
                    <dateline>London, November 15</dateline>
                    <p>Major R. G. Taibet D.SO., ho ar promo- tion joins the 2nd Battalion Rifle
                        Brigade in Egypt, hair worn the "green jacket for party- sixteen years and,
                        earned his decoration as well as the medal with five clasps in Buller's
                        fighting for the relief of Ladywith or Talbot, who is a member of the
                        ancient military and naval family of which the Bal of Shrews- bary is the
                        head, was present at the actions ou Colenso, Vaal Kats, Montecristo,
                        Pieter's Hill, Langs Nek, etc., etc..</p>
                    <p>VARR</p>
                    <p>Major G. C. L. Stockwell, D.3.0, Highland Light Infantry, has been appointed
                        second-in- command of the 1st Battalion, which lately moyed from Egypt to
                        Bengal,</p>
                    <p>Major W. A. Boninois, RA, Governor of the province of Bahr el Ghatal, who
                        commands the expedition destined to pazish the entry of cannibalistic
                        propensities known s "Niam-Niama" in the Upper Nile regions, in a very smart
                        officer who has won a fine reputa tion during his six years' connection with
                        the Khedive's Army. He served with distinction in the Nile Expedition of
                        1899, including the final rout of the Khalifa's forces (mentioned in
                        dopatobe and would have chastised the Niam-Nias early this year had he had
                        suffi cient forces at his disposal.</p>
                    <p>News from the Mediterranean Fleet states that the first-clas cruiser Aboukir
                        (Captain Sir C. J. Graves Bala Bart, M.V.0) took first place in the recent
                        long-range firing, par ticulars of which were given some time ago in these
                        notes. The battleship Montagu (Captain T. B. 8. Adair) was a good second,
                        Indeed, all the cruisers and battleships shot well.</p>
                    <p>For a considerable time shorter commissions abroad have been strongly urged
                        on in these notes, both in the interests of the health of the officers and
                        men and the efficiency of our squadrons. The Admiralty has just announced
                        that in the future his Majesty's ships will be commissioned for periods of
                        two years instead of three. This will be a great boon to all ranks, Another
                        important point in that re- pairs will not be allowed to accumulate, As we
                        often the case under the three years rule. The first ship to be commissioned
                        under the new conditions is the first-class cruiser Sutlej, which will be
                        commisioned at Ports mouth on the 19th inst. for service on the China
                        station.</p>
                    <p>While I am in hearty sympathy with the. appeal of the National Association
                        for the employment of Reserviste and time-expired soldiers; it is much to be
                        feared that the re sponse will prove disappointing. With all the good will
                        in the world, most employers of labour are compelled, by commercial stagna
                        tion, to reduce rather than increase the hum- ber of people in their
                        service, with the result that they are less able than when business is brisk
                        to comply with such appeals But it is an utterly vicious system which makes
                        the Empire's gallant defenders, whether sailors or soldiers dependent on
                        such chances of subsistence after they retire. Yesterday I came across a
                        striking letter from a Time Expired Tommy," illustrating from his own
                        experiences the ingratitude of the State to his class. Of blameless
                        character, and in possession of two war medals with six clasps, be served
                        for a little over thirteen years before passing back into civil life. With.
                        sach an excellent record, he had every right to count on receiving one of
                        the many thou- sands of berths which are in the gift of the State But
                        although he registered his nama both at the Ariy Clothing Stores and the
                        Royal Laboratory nearly three years ago, be is apparently as far as ever
                        from attaining his desire. We are aware, of course, that something has been
                        dose during recent years, especially by the Post Office But if recruiting
                        for the Army is to be extended to classes which now refuse to enlist, as Mr.
                        Arnold-Forster hopes the well-conducted soldier must be secured a reasonably
                        comfortable maintenance after he retires; and that would be effected to a
                        very large degree by giving out fighting men, whether in the Navy or the
                        Army, a preferen tial claim to employment in the lower non- combatant grades
                        of the Civil Service, the Admiralty, and the War Office</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Defective Sight.</p>
                    <p>MR. F. DAVIDSON,</p>
                    <p>Ophthalmic Optician, of 140, Great Portland Street, London, Teacher of Sight
                        Testing and author of "Bight Testing for the Medical Practitioner,"
                        "Refraction Work," eto. May be consulted for</p>
                    <p>SPECTACLES</p>
                    <p>at the HOTEL ABBATH for a</p>
                    <p>Short Time Only.</p>
                    <p>Mr. DAVIDSON in the inventor of many</p>
                    <p>of the latest appliances for dealing with Defective Vision</p>
                    <p>and cordially invites all medical men to eee them and to test their</p>
                    <p>practical utility.</p>
                    <p>Hours: 10 to 19.30 and 9 to 6.</p>
                    <p>Me DAVIDSON'S latest invention (patented in a new SUN GLASS, which absolutely
                        prevents any of the ill effete of Sun Glare,,</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/page/n3/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN MINING ACTIVITY.</head>
                    <p>the dething setivity in Bgyptian Mining the Director at the thadon and Paris.
                        Exchange have reteled services of a competent Mining Engineer, whose reports
                        on the present on of Se variens proportie la of the utmost importance. This
                        Information is at Correspodents contraplating investment in Egyptian Mining
                        nag with the Exchange before doing s Sciered by the purchase of worthless
                        searities</p>
                    <p>The Landon &amp; Parie</p>
                    <p>Drafts feas</p>
                    <p>dertake the purchase or onte 2 all classes of the Landon Stock Exchange and
                        Continental Bourses. KIELEN ANSTRIDAN, ANTWERP, NEW YORK &amp; MONTREAL</p>
                    <p>LONDON &amp; PARIS EXCHANGE.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL BANKERS</p>
                    <p>BALDON BOULL, MIL, LONDON GLID</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="municipality">
                    <head>Délégation Municipale</head>
                    <p>(Communication officielle)</p>
                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s'est réanie le 22 novembre 1904 9 h. p.m. soms la
                        présidence de M. Amb. A. Balli."</p>
                    <p>Priete: MM. E. Benschi, P. Fenderl, Mohamed Bey Said, Mansyur Bey Youssef, E.
                        Bros, Soliman Bey Abani, membres; W. P. Chatsway, administrateur; I. Sedky,
                        secrétaire.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation désigne dans son sein un sous-comité spécial pour étudier,
                        d'accord avec les services, une règlementation pour. les tramways de la
                        Ville d'Alexandrie, en s'inspirant du règlement édicté par le Gouvernement
                        pour les tramwaye de 1s Ville da Caire.</p>
                    <p>Un satre sous-comité est chargé d'exa miner les propositions faites par les
                        serviors techniques et sanitaires en vae d'une règlementation sur les
                        constructioni et de lui faire rapport à ce sujet.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation émt en ce qui la concern) et sous certaines conditions, an avis
                        favo rable à une demande tendant à l'établisse- ment d'an bain de mer à
                        Chatby, son acceptation étant subordonnée aux auto- ristions néosessires à
                        délivrer par to. Gouvernorat</p>
                    <p>Une proposition de M. Kempner ten- dant à établir un service de transport pa
                        sotomobiles, est renvoyée à l'ersmen da comité da Contentieux.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide de vélocigraphier et de distribuer aux membres une nou
                        velle lettre de la Commission de défens der foestaires s'nsi qu'ane note de
                        M. Alderson précissos es proposition pour la construction de maisons à bon
                        marché. L'administration est chargée de pré enter ane notesar cette
                        question.</p>
                    <p>Communication est donnée d'ane lettre da Ministère désignant M. Williams,
                        ins- peatear da 8me Cercle d'Irrigation, comm deuxiè ne délégué du
                        Gouvernement auprè de la Commission chargée de déciler quels sont les
                        travaux que l'entreprise Almazi sats à exécuter pead ant la période d'en
                        tretien des qusis.</p>
                    <p>Le Délégation prend note d'ane lettre minatérielle donnant la comp wition de
                        ls Commision chargée des rectisations à faire à le délimitation de la
                        ville</p>
                    <p>Elle serite l'ordre du jour de la pro- chaide séance de la Commission Maniei.
                        pale qui a réunira mercredi 30 novembre à 9 h. du soir</p>
                    <p>La séance est levée à minuit et demie.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="bulletinBourse">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demi 1</p>
                    <p>Le marché est trèr ferme et en reprise. La Banque Nationale remonte à 24
                        3/16, Is Béhára à 55 8/4; l'Agricola est deman- dée à 10 15/16, 1s Delts
                        Light à 15 3/16, et la Salt &amp; Sids à 80/8..</p>
                    <p>Après dure restés longtemps stationnai- rée à 7 environ, les Cotton Mills
                        viennent de monter subitement à 9/9 acheteurs. O aéchangé ce matin 6 à 7,000
                        titres.</p>
                    <p>En hvasse également Is Ward un à 8 1/8 acheteurs, les Markets à 27/3
                        acheteurs, les Esux d'Alexandrie à 17 1/8 et les Esax du Caire à 1125
                        achetears.</p>
                    <p>Par contre on déchit légèrement sur l Crown Brewery do 232 à 230, soe l'Anglo
                        Ameriein Nile de 5-3/8 &amp; 5 5/16 acheteurs of sur les Privilégiées
                        Tramwaya d'Alexan- drin de 147 1/2 146 1/2 acheteurs. Les Dividendes sont
                        demandées à 386.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>ADMINISTRATION DES POSTES.</head>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>1.Administration dos Foster met-en sjudiestion l'entreprise des transporte
                        poslans dans la ville de Pork Baida conditions stipndes dans le eshier des
                        aberges doped ans de cetle Direction Générals (Parra da Seoidarist) &amp; la
                        Direction Isla des Postos de Port-Held.</p>
                    <p>Ers demandes devrons Atre adressies à BE. le Direton 040l des P &amp;
                        Alexiedrie papier tim 4 de PT. es sons double envelope sex wid se porisot is
                        ration "Offre poor trans gens dans la ville de Port-Haid' alles jorgs' &amp;
                        (ing Diabre prossis 610, dernier déla Adololation ie s'engage peak seepter
                        l'offre la plus bel &amp; donner anise &amp;Tedjudication. 1 Reed 1904
                        14948-1</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item" feature="comingEvents">
                    <head>Calendar of Loming Events</head>
                    <p>November.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA:</p>
                    <p>Wid. 28 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Il Barbiere di Biviglia. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>Albambre Theairs, Rigoletto. 9.15 p.m. Place des Console Mini's Me gerin.
                        9p.m</p>
                    <p>Thars. 24 Abbas Helmy Theatre. Aida, in aid of International Employés
                        Society.@p.m. Alderson's Garden. Variety Enerman ment. 4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 25</p>
                    <p>Zizinia Theatre. M. Silvain in Iphigénie. 9pm.</p>
                    <p>Mon. 28 Zizinis Theatre. Debat of Italian opera company in Tristan of Isault.
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>December.</p>
                    <p>Bat</p>
                    <p>Abbat Hotel. A. L. M. &amp; D. B. Concert.</p>
                    <p>8</p>
                    <p>p.m.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>November.</p>
                    <p>Wed, 28 Masonis Hall. Idris Lodge No. 48</p>
                    <p>Bat. 26</p>
                    <p>9p.m.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Opera House. M. Silvain.</p>
                    <p>9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Theatre des Nouveautés. Variety Enter ainment. 9.80 pin.</p>
                    <p>Trocadero, Variety Entertainment. 9.80 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Meeting of Ragheb Mark Lodge No. 510, at Masonic Hall, Bonlae-road. 9
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Bun. 27 Zoological Gardess. Performance by Band of E. A. Infantry in
                        afternoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>VISITORS AND RESIDENTS</p>
                    <p>KINDLY NOTE THAT</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX,</p>
                    <p>THE CAIRO WEEKLY NEWSPAPER,</p>
                    <p>Is Under Entirely New Management</p>
                    <p>AND WILL BE PUBLISHED AS USUAL</p>
                    <p>During the Season 1904/5.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTION</p>
                    <p>For the Season P.T. 20</p>
                    <p>PAYABLE IN ADVANCE.</p>
                    <p>All Communications and Subscriptions to be addressed to the Korros, Mr. P. P.
                        GRAVES.</p>
                    <p>And for Advertising Space apply to Mr. W. E. WALTON,</p>
                    <p>THE SPHINX Offices,</p>
                    <p>Hotel du Nil, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>SIMEST</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>NEW YORK COTTON MARKET. Telegram received to-day from New York by Moss
                        Andrea, Chamarby &amp; Co., of Alexandria. The fall is due to the
                        disappointed hopes of Balle, to the large southern orders to sell, to the
                        weakness of southern arkose, to a good deal of speenfation cotton having ona
                        shrown upon the market and pressed for sale, and in consequenes of Targe
                        selling ont of parohsses for want of margins. The heavy receipts depress the
                        market. The semens shows 9 more cotton giand than same time last year.</p>
                    <p>vis. 1 sotto gianed up to the"</p>
                    <p>14th Nove aber, 1938..... Bales 7,070,deo-</p>
                    <p>More 69%</p>
                    <p>Total ginned up to the 14th.</p>
                    <p>November, 1934</p>
                    <p>4,171,000</p>
                    <p>Bales 11,741,000</p>
                    <p>E</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>GUNNY BAG MARKET</p>
                    <p>SCHRAGER Bao CALCUTTA MARKET REPORT FOR WEEK ENDING 10th Novexa, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Monday and Tuesday were closed days and the Gunny market opened yesterday
                        very" strong, the firmness being due to the rather excited state of the
                        loose Jate market, both here and upcountry, and higher prices have- been
                        paid by Home buyers and spinners for</p>
                    <p>Jute</p>
                    <p>A good amount of inter bassar business was- put through in Gunnies amongst
                        dealers during The holidays, and with some shippers covering up their
                        requirements prices have further hard and the tendency is still upesifis
                        Almost all consuming centres have been putting in enquiries, such as were
                        for prompt shipment being met as far as possible from second hand holdings,
                        while for forward 'de liveries, mills are quoting very cautiously, and
                        speenlative bolders in some instances bave <cb n="3"/> been unloading on
                        terms most advantageous to themselves. 291</p>
                    <p>For local requirements fair quantities of E bags have been taken for
                        Jan./April, and with the Crops that will have to be handled, there should be
                        a big consumption of both E bags and 2 lb B Twills for Bombay and the up
                        antry markets Heavy C bags were also largely taken at Rs. 25-8, both by
                        speculators and Burmah skippers, right on to Jute next year, and with the
                        Straits and Far East operating later the tendency is to a higher level of
                        prices</p>
                    <p>8</p>
                    <p>HESSIANS are firmer and do not look like giving way in value. Rs, 12-4 is the
                        nominal quotation for wheat bags, with no sellers, while Rs. 10 has been
                        paid for 40 10 on eloth for Jan./June, and Rs. 7-14 for 40 8 oz. Jan./March
                        and Re: 7-12 April-June. These are the last rates at which business has been
                        done, and mills are reluctant to go on. This and next month's goods are at a
                        premium, more especially nine-porter cloth, and nothing can P be had now at
                        Rs. 8 for Nov./Dec. Eleven-E porter cloth is more easily obtainable in
                        moderate quantities at Rs. 10-4 and Rs. 10 respectively.</p>
                    <p>Closing quotations are as follows:</p>
                    <p>GLf. Spes</p>
                    <p>216 Freight</p>
                    <p>ALL Part Bald</p>
                    <p>Nov. Dec. Jatt Jane Nov./Dec. Janu</p>
                    <p>C</p>
                    <p>Grain Backs 50 by 30 Th.</p>
                    <p>abys</p>
                    <p>-70/5 70'5</p>
                    <p>40/10</p>
                    <p>17/Sciros-17/9 scarce</p>
                    <p>Bugar Bags 68 by 387 by 93468545</p>
                    <p>by sabys</p>
                    <p>Onion Pockets 40 bp 2) 15 on</p>
                    <p>8. Twills 66 by 3 3 lbs.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS</head>
                    <p>For MALTA and MANJEESTER, by the 8.8. Spartan Prinos, sailed on the 10th
                        November: </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 1,348 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>J. Planis &amp; Co., 365</p>
                    <p>G. Riecken, 565</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 437</p>
                    <p>H. Bindecangel, 1,428</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co., 2,977</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Lad, 1,705</p>
                    <p>Firch &amp; Co, 100</p>
                    <p>Schmid &amp; Co., 125</p>
                    <p>F. Andres, 100</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fender, 100</p>
                    <p>W. Getty &amp; Co.,75</p>
                    <p>9.320 balee cotton</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 50 asses oranges</p>
                    <p>Chalom Attal, 75 ms eggs</p>
                    <p>L. Heller, 200 bertold molasses</p>
                    <p>Various, 5 packages stodries</p>
                    <p>Pour MESSINE of GENES, par le batean italien Singapore, parti le 10
                        novembrer</p>
                    <p>POUR DESTINATIONS DIVERSES</p>
                    <p>H. Fisari, 18 aos fèves et petits pois (Tripoli) </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 50 balles coton (Naples) </p>
                    <p>8. Albertini, 82 cilindres vides (Livourne) </p>
                    <p>Divers, 94 colls divers</p>
                    <p>POUR GENES</p>
                    <p>Krah &amp; Naggiar, 5 sans gomme </p>
                    <p>Padova Rolio, 25 colis vieux cuivre</p>
                    <p>Jook &amp; Bon, 7 colis trophées</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderi, 140 balles coton</p>
                    <p>B&amp;O. Lindemann, 24</p>
                    <p>P. O. Bain &amp; Co,146</p>
                    <p>J. Plant &amp; Co.484</p>
                    <p>G. Petracahi,64</p>
                    <p>W. Trapp &amp; Co,94</p>
                    <p>Carrer Beds &amp; Coy. Ltd, 241</p>
                    <p>Schmid &amp; Co.,155</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co.,30</p>
                    <p>1,544 balles coton</p>
                    <p>Pone LE PIREE ODESSA, par le batean rasse Reine Olga parti le 11 novembre</p>
                    <p>Divers, 800 mes ris, 56 sacs henné, 15 snes faves, 18 sace lentilles, 30 mos
                        noix de coco, 11 colis dive</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fender,106 balles coton</p>
                    <p>F: 0. Baines &amp; Co.,80 "</p>
                    <p>9. Franger &amp; Co.,330</p>
                    <p>B. Mallison &amp; Co.,215</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Lindemann, 300</p>
                    <p>Sohmid &amp; Co.36</p>
                    <p>Carvae Brow &amp; Ooy. Ltd, 86</p>
                    <p>1,071 balles coton</p>
                    <p>Pear MARSEILLE, par le bainen français Congo, parti le LF novembre:</p>
                    <p>FOUR MADRILLE</p>
                    <p>Bolio, 24 eolie vieux enivre</p>
                    <p>", 344 colis vieux laiton</p>
                    <p>", 517 pains zinc</p>
                    <p>Buorories, 26 sucre</p>
                    <p>Candinglón, 19 huilles</p>
                    <p>Behrend, 600 sacs riz</p>
                    <p>Divers, 40 colis divate</p>
                    <p>F.C Baines &amp; Co 64 balles coton</p>
                    <p>G. Franger &amp; Co., 201</p>
                    <p>Mhr &amp; Fenderl, 81</p>
                    <p>d. Parselh 64</p>
                    <p>B.&amp;O. Ededemann, 220</p>
                    <p>Sebmid &amp; Oo 186</p>
                    <p>W. Gelly &amp; O 60</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co.. 10</p>
                    <p>Mallison &amp; Co...62</p>
                    <p>Choreini Benschi &amp; Co.,60</p>
                    <p>927 balles coton</p>
                    <p>POUR DESTINATIONS DIVE</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co., 41 billen sofon (Dunkerque)</p>
                    <p>K Nargisr, 5 henné</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros &amp; Co 180 balles coton </p>
                    <p>Choremi Benachi &amp; Co., 25</p>
                    <p>175 balles soton</p>
                    <p>B. Trabelei, 12 ballee onir (Sfax)</p>
                    <p>Boris, 160 balles hendes (Algory</p>
                    <p>Barki, 80 ballos heard t</p>
                    <p>Four ALGER et HAMBOURO, par le babies allemand Gunther, part 1 novembre </p>
                    <p>Divers, 1,420, sen ris, 88 os. g, 66 cais. dattes, 199 harila vieux for, 211
                        colie gomme, 28 eolis palmes, 80 enlis divers</p>
                    <p>G. Franger &amp; 06., 108 balles colon</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros &amp; Co, 100</p>
                    <p>P. Andre, 180.</p>
                    <p>Mallison &amp; Op, 90</p>
                    <p>FG. Baise &amp; Co 192</p>
                    <p>J. Planta &amp; Co 200</p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fandori 122 </p>
                    <p>R&amp;O. Lindemann, 330</p>
                    <p>Cho nui banh. C. 416</p>
                    <p>A. Has 117</p>
                    <p>Perl &amp; O 100</p>
                    <p>Behold &amp; 195</p>
                    <p>0. Bike, 318</p>
                    <p>6.444 balles</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item" feature="shippingMovements">
                    <head>MOUVEMENT MARITIME DU PORT D'ADRIANDRI</head>
                    <p>ARRIVHUS</p>
                    <p>22 novembre</p>
                    <p>Byrie et Port-Said: 1j. ap. gree Yorghios, Vashiaki, too. 755, &amp;
                        Maonis.</p>
                    <p>23 novembre</p>
                    <p>Geavora; 5 j. Bps, vap. wate. Anas Gaich, capimine Tomich, ton. 1446, &amp;
                        Giuraevich.</p>
                    <p>Salonique et Pitle; j 12, vap hall. Vavilions Og cap manos, tom. 919,
                        Nanopould. Alexandreis: 33, 86, vip. ang. Milo, of Barnett, son: 689,&amp;
                        Micoo..</p>
                    <p>Smyme;j. 12, vap. kell. Costas, cap. Boutis, ton: 851, &amp; Maquis.</p>
                    <p>Odessa et Cavak; 4 j.. 84, v. russe Paal Spoliaziaky, cap. Seemano, sou.
                        1858, &amp; Msonis.</p>
                    <p>Mersine of Port-Sald; 16 h, vap ang. Dakabliah, osp. Findlay, ton. 644, &amp;
                        la Khedivial Mail.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS</p>
                    <p>93 novembre</p>
                    <p>Por t-Eaid; vap. ital. Bosforo, cap. Milazzo. Purs Said of Chypre; vap. ang.
                        Bene, &amp; MacMahon. Candia; vap holl. Byzantion, dag. Mavromatie. Maite et
                        Hambourg; v. all. Siegfried, cap. Möller.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>STOCKS AND SHARES</p>
                    <p>Closing Priem, to-day at 1pm.</p>
                    <p>$18 5,8</p>
                    <p>24 8/18</p>
                    <p>488</p>
                    <p>BANKS</p>
                    <p>Debenture</p>
                    <p>Imy ban Bank... National Bank of Hyp</p>
                    <p>"New Inns 25 11116</p>
                    <p>National Bank of Greee...</p>
                    <p>Bade</p>
                    <p>Jersey Boy</p>
                    <p>LAND.</p>
                    <p>10 1516 Agris. Bank</p>
                    <p>Fos. 1000 Agris. Industrielle Egypt 530</p>
                    <p>4811,16 Brian Del Land Co..</p>
                    <p>Fonds 900.</p>
                    <p>L.B. 55 34</p>
                    <p>Bebars Company-</p>
                    <p>99</p>
                    <p>8 18</p>
                    <p>61/4</p>
                    <p>468</p>
                    <p>199</p>
                    <p>91 5/8</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>1/2</p>
                    <p>For. 280</p>
                    <p>138</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Sh. 99</p>
                    <p>sh. #7,8</p>
                    <p>Sh. 89,8 Fed. 108</p>
                    <p>41716 6814</p>
                    <p>9 1/16</p>
                    <p>32</p>
                    <p>Wardan te Coy.</p>
                    <p>Ladd &amp; Mongage</p>
                    <p>New Dairs Bad Fond.</p>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL Alex. Bonded Stores Pref Anglo-Egypt Spinning Co.
                        Bourse Khédiviale... gral. Chiro Bewage Trans-</p>
                    <p>Or. Brewery, Alex., Fond.</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>do 6%. Debe. do Chiro Food</p>
                    <p>46</p>
                    <p>Tort Ord.</p>
                    <p>61</p>
                    <p>178</p>
                    <p>500</p>
                    <p>TE</p>
                    <p>07</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Cotton Mith</p>
                    <p>do Markete</p>
                    <p>do Salt and Boda Fond Clients &amp;gry.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Syadiente... B. Kafe-el-Zayat Cotton Coy. 102 New Bgyptian
                        Company... Nangovich Hotels</p>
                    <p>Bode Baileries ot</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Ind. de Karmons</p>
                    <p>96 19</p>
                    <p>11.</p>
                    <p>98 1</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>Presange et Dépôt Presses Libree</p>
                    <p>10</p>
                    <p>10%</p>
                    <p>5516</p>
                    <p>17 118</p>
                    <p>NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS,</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Amer.. Nile de Co.</p>
                    <p>Khedival Mail 8.3. e. 1 [Oo. Fonds.</p>
                    <p>Alex. Water Company</p>
                    <p>F. 1145 499 1</p>
                    <p>Chiro</p>
                    <p>4/6</p>
                    <p>Fonds.</p>
                    <p>650</p>
                    <p>17</p>
                    <p>Fonds.</p>
                    <p>BAILWAYS &amp; TRAMWAYS</p>
                    <p>Bases Bgypte, Fonds..</p>
                    <p>15 8/16</p>
                    <p>Dale Dig</p>
                    <p>193 108</p>
                    <p>99 19</p>
                    <p>do do i Def....</p>
                    <p>Oniro-Helonan...</p>
                    <p>1789 97</p>
                    <p>Payoun</p>
                    <p>20 84 F. 148 1/3</p>
                    <p>Keneb-Assonan.</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>480</p>
                    <p>do</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Tramas..</p>
                    <p>do Foods 285</p>
                    <p>88 7/16 Ramlah Bailway...</p>
                    <p>Parnished by B&amp;Backed 10, St. Marke Bail hags Averia Shalal-Ni Cairo, who
                        address the sale and parobste Joke and Shares, ad the lossl Board and Web of
                        the London doek sabange.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Cloture de la Bourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS</p>
                    <p>Cours de l'Association des Courtiers en Marohani.</p>
                    <p>Novembre.</p>
                    <p>Javier</p>
                    <p>HE ? કે</p>
                    <p>COTON F.G.F.B.</p>
                    <p>N.B.5 14 1/9</p>
                    <p>e</p>
                    <p>17/8</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>15 17/82 18 11/18</p>
                    <p>9/16</p>
                    <p>93/82</p>
                    <p>129</p>
                    <p>15 78</p>
                    <p>wr</p>
                    <p>P.T. 89 8/40</p>
                    <p>61 8/40</p>
                    <p>10/40</p>
                    <p>"</p>
                    <p>69 18/40</p>
                    <p>30/40</p>
                    <p>Mai.</p>
                    <p>GRADES DE COTON</p>
                    <p>Dée. Jan.</p>
                    <p>Février Marn</p>
                    <p>Ayril</p>
                    <p>Pavas SA</p>
                    <p>De-Jan.... Février-Mare.</p>
                    <p>344</p>
                    <p>www</p>
                    <p>P.T. 76 90/40 &amp; 77-</p>
                    <p>78 20,40. 80/40</p>
                    <p>REMARQUES</p>
                    <p>Ooros-Nouvelle récolte Rien de changé dans</p>
                    <p>Is aisastion et la cote est zhodifiée sur la barb to</p>
                    <p>récolte sotmelle.</p>
                    <p>Bicole melle: L'après-midi</p>
                    <p>46 pea sotive,</p>
                    <p>faible et en baisse, l'Amérique &amp;ant pea encoure important</p>
                    <p>geante di Taitente a'une Blière pour dechain ayant provoqes des offres qai
                        quoique Wyant de dire</p>
                    <p>loms offer &amp; 1/4'de</p>
                    <p>ri sa- sos da dived</p>
                    <p>Dand instinde prta pa bi potte</p>
                    <p>- Dane l'après midi pris plus at pour are 15 35,89-plus bas pour mare 18
                        31/83 11/10. NB-Lee tree livraisons avee reports irrigations Au moment de la
                        dire-les nodvelles</p>
                    <p>Every soon gyption disponible: Begeis Mome prix. Patare diet 780/84 Vi
                        Liverpoolt, eolen adelosin: Future Janvier vier 5.90. Fears naljain 1
                        6.98</p>
                    <p>New York: coton wande, Pature Jah.: 9.64 mat 988</p>
                    <p>GRADES DE COTO Récolte soelle, L'aprie di à des sons à fhit nalle, mais
                        là-sanque d'offres third phet klient for core</p>
                    <p>Dane la msinde prix pha hátt pour v.-mare PT. 8 10,40: phies pour v / Dans
                        Pagriemi, Neder-mes P.T. 61 8/40 pour ferier-mare PT. 01-8/40 &amp; entres
                        livraisons are reports irrigaliers</p>
                    <p>Demadri</p>
                    <p>10,40</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <!-- cotons -->
                <!-- mmeb -->
                <!-- cultures cotonieres -->
                <!-- exterieur -->
                <!-- share list -->
                <!-- arrivages -->
                <!-- derniere heure -->
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/page/n4/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904.</p>
                    <p>Our Paris Letter. might certainly have said; but he would have whether the
                        microbe will prove to be the spécifie</p>
                    <p>manship of his illustrions predecessor. More be the Doyen microbe. The points
                        to be tried are</p>
                    <p>FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT) PARIS, November 7. We have taken so kindly to
                        English ways that, for two days this week, we were enjoying Landin
                        particular-almost. The fog was not quite of the yellowish hue that prevails
                        by the banks of the Thames, but it had sufficient sistency-and a sufficient
                        blackness to cause general fighting up at noon. I have just meta French
                        friend, who said, "I have come from London. Do you know-it is astonish ing
                        there was no fog there. The first I saw was at Havre, where the boat had to
                        remain half an hour outside the harbour because of it. The cold and the rain
                        and the fog are the usual heralds of the winter, in Paris. If wish for
                        another sign you have it in the you disconsolate crowd that besieges the
                        doors of the municipal, refuges. It says something for British prosperity
                        that of the fifteen hundred of all nationalities applying for relief last
                        month, only one spoke with the tongue of the Englishman.</p>
                    <p>SPORT AND PLAY.</p>
                    <p>FOOTBALL</p>
                    <p>ROYAL BERK'S SIGNALLERS F.C.</p>
                    <p>A UNITED STATES SENATOR</p>
                    <p>Used Pe-ru-na For Dyspepsia with Great Benefit</p>
                    <p>HON. M. C. BUTLER, Ex-United States Senator From South Carolina</p>
                    <p>AX-U. S. Senator M. C. Butler from that state for two terms. In a recent
                        letter from Washington, D. C.; he says:</p>
                    <p>E South Carolina, was Senator from</p>
                    <p>"I can recommend Perusa for dys- pepsia and stomach trouble. I have been
                        using your medicine for a short period and I feel very much relleved. It is
                        Indeed a wonderful medicine be sides a good tonic."--M. C. Butler.</p>
                    <p>gained nothing by saying it-indeed, be would microbe of cancer, or a
                        secondary microbe; whe only have played straight into the hands of ther it
                        will be susceptible of inoculation, and enemies of the Church, who would
                        have quoted whether the animals inoculated will develop in his protest as
                        unmistakable evidence of Papal fections which can be treated for cure. All
                        this hostility to the Republic. They will do that will occupy months. as it
                        is of course. But they will not be able tot over the plain declaration of
                        his Holi news that the profession of Christianity can be in complete accord
                        with a Republican form of government. It can, no doubt; but, as French
                        Christianity is learning, to its cost, the anti- Christian influences which
                        dominate the policy SAINT ANDREW'S FOOTBALL CLUB. of France at the present
                        time have no desire to This fixture was brought off on the parade work in
                        harmony with the Church. On the ground at Mustapha Pasha on Saturday after
                        contrary, it is their deliberate intention to suppress Christianity, if they
                        can. They will noon in lovely weather and before a good turn- out of
                        spectators. The Signallers started the made manifest without grievous
                        spiritual suffer early in the vicinity of Curtis &amp; Co.. Keill fail, of
                        course; but their failure will not be game with the wind at their backs and
                        were There are certainly two opinions as to the and clearing the Saints
                        began to gain ground. ing and spiritual loss. was soon in evidence, and
                        through his tackling expediency of the Channel tunnel, but 1 Neither team
                        for a time could claim any great imagine that if Paris were polled on the
                        sub-advantage, the play being pretty much of the ject of the Champs Elysées
                        "tube" it would give-and-take order. The Saints' forwards were return an
                        emphatic "yes." It is the latest pro- not displaying any brilliancy in their
                        move- jeet to build subterranean passages at the ments, and in this
                        department certainly the The ratification of the Anglo-French Agree-most
                        important points beneath the principal homesters were the superior lot.
                        Cowie was ment having been voted in the Chamber byennes of this great
                        thoroughfare. For long their front-rank warrior, and he, supported by 443 to
                        105, we may now take it that the the pedestrian public have taken their
                        lives in good half-back play, steadied the attack.. The Sugate will follow
                        suit, and that final success their hands in attempting to "negotiate the
                        Signallers defence, however, was not found will crown the work upon which M.
                        Delcassé formidable stream of traffic that sweeps by at wanting, both New
                        and Harper offering active sad Lord Lansdowne are to be heartily con-
                        certain hours of the day, almost without inter-opposition. The first point
                        of the game fell to gratulated. Nevertheless, it is to be regretted lude,
                        from the Place de la Concorde to the the Saints, and came from the foot of
                        Hutch- that, while the Agreement is accepted as a Arc de Triomphe. ings.
                        That player, taking up the ball close in Prance and England are happily very
                        good and lifting it over the heads of all, placed it whole, a resolution
                        should have been proposed and carried which affirmed that the Chamber
                        friends, but as joint administrators of the New just out of Quarterman's
                        reach. The Signal- counts on M. Delcassé to open negotiations Hebrides they
                        can hardly be described as lers tried hard to square before the interval
                        with the British Government, as soon as a success. One of the French papers
                        in the and certainly their play deserved to meet with possible, with a view
                        to improving the New neighbouring island of New Caledonia, re some success.
                        Their efforts, however, were foundland Convention. That Convention will,
                        ferring to a recent massacre in the New Hebri- unavailing, and the interval
                        arrived with of course, when ratified by the Senate, be des, describes the
                        condition of this group as the score: Saint Andrew's 1, Signallers 0.
                        binding upon the two Governments; bat M. "flagrant anarchy," and says
                        neither life The restart gave promise of a very fast Delossé is charged with
                        the task of getting it or property is safe there. Furthermore, moiety. The
                        Signallers were evidently bent altered to meet the requirements, real or
                        both France and England "incur a serious on penetrating the visitors'
                        defence, but Keill aginary, of the French fishing industry. I
                        responsibility" in encouraging settlers to and Fitzgerald were playing a
                        sterling game, and am sorry that the Chamber has laid that duty emigrate
                        there under the present governing were well supported by the halves. Curtis,
                        too, up the Foreign Minister; I hoped that the arrangements. French rights
                        and interests in seemed to be in his element. Still the home- troublesome
                        question of the "French Shore" the New Hebrides are described as
                        "incon-sters persevered and reward at last attend would be settled once and
                        for ever; and the testably predominant," and the suggested solu-ed their
                        efforts, Saxton patting a beauty which fact that it will not be finally
                        settled by the tion of existing evils is the voluntary retire Curtis in
                        clearing over-ran. This gave the other present Convention constitutes a
                        distinct draw-ment of England from the scene and the part-forwards an
                        opening which they were not slow back to complete satisfaction. However,
                        there nership. That remedy, however, would be far to take advantage of, and
                        the score stood one is no reason to fear that England and France from
                        popular either in England or in Australia all. From the kick off play was
                        pretty much That peculiarly Parisian institution, the confined to midfield.
                        The remaining twenty "revue," is more or less a standing dish in the minutes
                        was very finely contested, but no other music halls, but as the year begins
                        to wane, it scoring took place. The whistle sounded with It is a funny
                        country, this country of hair partakes more and more of the character of the
                        score. Signallers 1, Saint Andrew's 1 splitting and of duelling. Why M.
                        Syveton the English pantomime in its allusion to recent The following were
                        the teams smacked General André in the face has been and current events. The
                        Alliance, unfortun- Signallers: Quarterman, New, Harper, Hand- a mystery to
                        everybody, but a greater ately, forbids, but one can imagine the fun ley,
                        Dovey, Austin, Saxton, Limmer, Glee, one is why, as one of his officers has
                        chosen that sprightly French artists of the "Café Herbert, and Woodley. to
                        make the insuit offered to the Minister of concert would extract from the
                        ludicrous Saint Andrew's Curtis, Fitzgerald, Keill, War a personal matter,
                        as Captain de Gail, or story of the Russians in the North Sea. An- Bright,
                        Clark, Nixon, Sweet, Jones, Cowie, the 1leme. Cuirassiers, has done, he
                        should other incident most certainly to be seized upon Hutchings, and
                        Halley. not be allowed to fight M. Syveton and be is the escape and
                        subsequent arrest of M done with it. After all, he merely acted as Syveton.
                        The escapade has little that is noble all, by 58 feet moulded breadth, and
                        36.6 feet deep to the tonnage deck, with a gross tonnage an officer standing
                        up for the Army, and is in it, but the "revue" lets who will be moralist,
                        not that what we are constantly inciting it simply amuses. One has need of
                        an extensive The Anchor Line have added to their fleet of 9,400 tons, and
                        when fully loaded her dis ofhears to do! De Gail is an aristocrat knowledge
                        of "argot" and of all the ramifica- the steel twin-screw passenger steamer
                        Cale placement will be not less than 16,000 tons. The first-class
                        accommodation is situated by birth, and has always marked himself out tions
                        of French politics to thoroughly appre- donia, which was launched at
                        Meadowsile, amidships, with staterooms for 300 passengers as begg more of a
                        thinker than most of ciate the niceties of a Paris ""revue" where Parties,
                        on theind Deprem da, beristen on the main and bridge decks. The second-
                        those of his class in the Army. What he has parody is piled on parody, and
                        paradox upon ing ceremony being performed by her Grace class accommodation
                        is also fitted amidships to done in-challenging Syveton may be a rash
                        paradox, often with a talent and a brilliance the Duchess of Montrose, and
                        the vessel will be wards the after end of the vessel; with staterooms all
                        ready and fully equipped in every particu- for 400 passengers. The third
                        class galley and a foolhanty act, but one cannot help that are bewilderingly
                        clever. The quality of lar to take her place in the regular service of
                        contains a most complete steam cooking plant. feeling glad that some French
                        officer should the jokes may be strained, but they generally the company in
                        good time for the spring and do such a thing after Friday's most disgraceful
                        drop in the right place.</p>
                    <p>will quarrel over the matter, and we must be content with that we have got.
                        Perfection is not of this world.</p>
                    <p>incident.</p>
                    <p>Americans. have known how to turn the As to André, he is, it appears, very
                        ill, for theatres of London into a gold mine, and they M. Byveton's blow was
                        a thundering one; but are about to Americanise the theatres of Paris. I
                        think it is pure "méchanceté" that makes According to statements made in the
                        local the journalists talk about his "ratelier" having press, a powerful
                        syndicate has been formed, been deranged. They merely want to throw and it
                        is proposed to found as many as ten new ridicule upon him, and of that there
                        is plenty theatres in the French capital. Playwrights to throw, "Dieu le
                        sait!" Meanwhile, he is quake at the thought. At present they have a
                        unmbtedly ill, and as far as it is at present society strong enough to
                        prevent managers known, both M. Syveton and M. de Gait are from crushing
                        them under the weight of com- under arrest. M. Syveton was arrested just as
                        petition. But in presence of a trust which can the duel was about to take
                        place, and there control ten theatres, a bitter struggle against the was a
                        rumour later to the effect that General power of capital is feared. André
                        had had his generous-defender "mis aux In Paris, at least, the pawnshop has
                        quaint, ariéts." Politics, and political manoeuvres, are half-pathetic
                        humours which it would probably always "tout puissant" in this country, and
                        be difficult to match in England. This is the in all probability the general
                        public will not time of year for renewals, and the expiry of the know more
                        of this affair until it is all over. date makes it possible to take an
                        inventory of En attendant, persons who are really indigold pledges remaining
                        or gone. This year a nant that the French Army should have small object
                        pledged for 12s. 8d. in 1869 has contained spies, and others who have some
                        been withdrawn, after 36 annual renewals, in other reason, private or
                        otherwise, for volving £1 138.-4d. Among the other "relics" showing up the
                        methods General André still remaining is a mantel ornament pledged for has
                        employed in the carrying out of 58. 22 years ago, and regularly renewed. But
                        what he doubtless considered his duty, are the champion "relie" of the place
                        is an ivory- busily exposing the recent manoeuvres of the headed cane, on
                        which the owner has paid 74d. Masonic Lodges in the Army, and the Gaulois a
                        year since 1859. and other papers are full of revelations on the subject.
                        This is, doubtless, quite right, and I because the constant ringing of the
                        bells and on only, imagine that good should come out the call and protests
                        of subscribers told so of the whole thing. That it will bring about a
                        severely on her nervous system that she was fresh Dreyfus disturbance I can
                        hardly believe compelled to leave her position, which she I believed last
                        year that such a thing as a had filled for nine years. revival of that
                        famous affair was not only An interview has taken place between the
                        possible, but even imminent. It is only fair Japanese Minister and M.
                        Delossé with that one should be allowed to change one's reference to
                        "certain matters relative to the opinions when one has a reason for so
                        doing, observance of neutrality," and the Tempe says and I now believe quite
                        the contrary. I believe that explanations are proceeding in an amicable that
                        such a thing would be considered by most way and there is very reason to
                        hope for a infoential Republicans as danger to the satisfactory result. In
                        the present awkward Republic, so great has been the prejudice position of
                        France in the affixirs of the nations, However, we shall in the utmost
                        delicacy and tactfulness is rendered Another series of duels has shaken
                        Paris to necessary, and the country has reason to feel its depths. In two
                        pistols were used, and the grateful that in M. Delcased it has a Minister
                        seconds having apparently exercised the cus who may be depended on to
                        exercise the fomary care in loading them harmlessly necessary quality of
                        discretion. The progress there was, of course, no result. One of the en of
                        the Baltic Fleet is attended with the utmost counters was, that postponed
                        from Thursday danger to the Powers, and not until it has between M. Syveton
                        and Captain de Gait. The reached a destination, whether in the waters of
                        affair with swords was a thore serious matter, warfare or elsewhere, will
                        they be able to General Andre's son being distinctly pricked in breathe
                        freely.</p>
                    <p>A Paris telephone girl has committed suicide</p>
                    <p>the wrist. The victim afterwards rode agay The Pasteur Institate of Paris is
                        now just on his bicycle, with much less inconvenience entering upon, the
                        experiments which it has than if he had taken part in a football match.
                        undertaken for the purpose of testing exhaus The language of the Papal
                        allocation on the tively the so-called-cancer serum of Dr., Doyen.
                        ecclesiastical situation in France is informeel by The experiments are under
                        the care of Dr. &amp; spirit of dignity and moderation. On this Metchinkoff,
                        and have just reached the primary ocession Plus X would seem to have derived
                        stage of having ready two large bladders-filled bie inspiration from the
                        consummate states with Doyen cultures, with which to propagate,</p>
                    <p>ANCHOR LINE</p>
                    <p>summer season of 1905.</p>
                    <p>The new steamer is 515 feet in length over</p>
                    <p>Peruns is not simply a remedy for dyspepals. Peruns is a catarrh remedy.
                        Peruns cures dyspepsia because it is generally dependent upon catarth of
                        the</p>
                    <p>stomach.</p>
                    <p>If you do not derive prompt and satie factory results from the use of Peruns,
                        write at once to Dr. Hartman, giving t full statement of your case and he
                        will be pleased to give you his valuable ad- vice gratis.</p>
                    <p>Address Dr. Hartman. President of The fortman Sanitarium, Columbus, O</p>
                    <p>For special directions everyone should read "The Ills of Life," a copy of
                        which surrounds each bottle. Peru- na is for sale by all chemists and
                        druggists at five shillings per botles or six bottles for twenty-five
                        shillingt</p>
                    <p>Those wishing direct correspond ence with, Dr. Hartman and can wait the
                        necessary delay in receiving a reply should address Dr. S. B. Hart man,
                        Columbus, Ohio, U.S.A.</p>
                    <p>The following wholesale druggist will supply, the retail drug trade in
                        Alexandria, Egypt</p>
                    <p>MAX FISCHER, Alexandria, Egypt.</p>
                    <p>The Caledonia is propelled by two sets of latest type. powerful triple
                        expansion marine engines of the</p>
                    <p>EST. 1847.</p>
                    <p>Allcock's</p>
                    <p>PLASTERS</p>
                    <p>Are a universal remedy for Pains in the back (so frequent in the case of
                        women). They give instantaneous relief. Wherever there is a pain apply a
                        Plaster. DIRECTIONS FOR USE.</p>
                    <p>For pains in the Kidneys,</p>
                    <p>We Back, the plaster should applied</p>
                    <p>Where there</p>
                    <p>in pain apply Alle's Plaster</p>
                    <p>Rheudration Paine in For Sore Throat, Cough, Shoulders, tib Bronchitis, for
                        Weak Lungs and fox-painful and sensitive parts of the-abdomen, apply as
                        indicated</p>
                    <p>Sutteess</p>
                    <p>Peet cor</p>
                    <p>Aching Shape equired and apply to part affected as dues above</p>
                    <p>Rheumatism, Colds, Coughs,</p>
                    <p>Weak Chest, Weak Back,</p>
                    <p>Lumbago, Sciatica, &amp;c., &amp;c.,</p>
                    <p>REMEN BERAllcock's Plasters are the original and genuine porous plaster and
                        have never been equalled as pain-curers. Furthermore, they are absolutely
                        safe as they do not contain belladonna, opium or any polson whatever,</p>
                    <p>firmaren Hospital Balhat</p>
                    <p>CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>(Prepaid))</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH PROFESSOR, well</p>
                    <p>How 2.2.</p>
                    <p>in English</p>
                    <p>subjecte, wanted in Cairo, for two to three hours daily; any part of day will
                        b Apply, stating qualifications and terms, to "M. E., Cairo.</p>
                    <p>DAVIES</p>
                    <p>BRYAN</p>
                    <p>&amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>94941-9-3 CONTINENTAL HOTEL BUILDI</p>
                    <p>TO LET-Fine Villa, furnished or unfurnishe with garden and sesoles, seated on
                        the Gheared Promenade, Caird; thing the Khedivial porting Cinb, and next to
                        the reccod gase of the gurdsn of the Palace Hotal. Apply at "The Villa.
                        "94889-1x-11</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>THE UNION CLUB, Alexandria, invite appli ST. DAVID'S BUILDINGS</p>
                    <p>tions for the following posts (for Europ servants): Chef, Head Water, Barman,
                        Hall- porter. Applications to be addressed to Becretary, Union Cimb,
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>91918-6-6</p>
                    <p>WANTED by a large firm (British) at Alexandria,</p>
                    <p>competent clark with thorough knowledge of Customs clearing formalises and
                        band ing of bags and merabandise; knowledge of English and Amb
                        indispensable; ommanding salary 415- pe month. Applications, which will be
                        treated as confidential, must slate previous experisoos Apply, P. O. Box No.
                        185, Alexandria. 91988-8-8</p>
                    <p>ESSONS-TURKISH, FRENCH Langu Seisnoes (experimental method of ching). Tanali
                        Bey, opposite Poss-offes, Abbessiah, Cairo. 24980-6-1</p>
                    <p>MISS MINA SHEPPARD will continue her</p>
                    <p>Swedish nerve treatment for ladies after De cember 1. A Camp is to be
                        inaugurated ear the Pyramids, where patients and others may be accommodated.
                        24984-8-8</p>
                    <p>W clerk, preferably having knowledge Type ANTED, for Khartoum, competent
                        English writing and Sboriband. Balary LE 16 per month. Apply, sting age,
                        experience, etc., No. 94949 alo Egyptian Gazette offoes. 94949-3-1</p>
                    <p>Sanitas</p>
                    <p>Unequalled Parifying Agent Indispensable In Hot Countries.</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>Sanitas" Disinfecting Flaid</p>
                    <p>general or personal use is thoreogbly vetive It completely disinfects the
                        house in which it is used, and administered internally prevents Cholers,
                        Typhoid Fever, Dysentery, etc.</p>
                    <p>"Sanitas "Disinfecting Powder</p>
                    <p>is the best air purifier known, and a stronger antiseptic and deodorant than
                        carbolic acid, besides being pleasant and refreshing "Sanitas" Eucalyptus
                        Soap</p>
                    <p>is specially recommended by the medical faculty for use in hot climates,
                        because of its Ene disinfecting qualities and its fragrance</p>
                    <p>Kingzott's Fumigating Candles apply the safest and most convenient mesh of
                        sulphur fumigation. For the disinfection of infected places beating,
                        clothing, etc. they are both dicacious and economical Destroy all
                        injects</p>
                    <p>THE "BANITAS" OG LTA BETHNAL GREEN, LONDON, E</p>
                    <p>CALLARD</p>
                    <p>&amp;</p>
                    <p>BOWSER'S</p>
                    <p>BUTTERSCOTCH</p>
                    <p>(The Celebrated Sweet for Children). Really wholesome Confectionern</p>
                    <p>his popular English Sofment can be obtained at r</p>
                    <p>Mr. CARONIS, ANGLO-AMERICAN EYOREs, Port-Bal DEMETRIADER,</p>
                    <p>Moss TANCRED BONNICI &amp; O</p>
                    <p>The PATISSERIE DE LA BOURSE, Rua Charif Paba, Alexandria,</p>
                    <p>Manufactory: London, England.</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management.</p>
                    <p>81-11-904</p>
                    <p>PATENT.</p>
                    <p>FOR FLAT ROOFS OF PERMANENT BUILDINGS.</p>
                    <p>VULCANITE ROOFING</p>
                    <p>Adopted by nearly all leading Arell Private</p>
                    <p>gets e Pabile</p>
                    <p>Hotels Schools</p>
                    <p>of Industrial</p>
                    <p>Repairs</p>
                    <p>Being</p>
                    <p>Root ware may be set as garden, any other pay</p>
                    <p>ention Committee</p>
                    <p>ASA IMPORTANT C</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>35-37, Noble St., London,</p>
                    <p>NEW</p>
                    <p>GOODS</p>
                    <p>SEASON'S</p>
                    <p>ARRIVING</p>
                    <p>Wills for fell partijalar tastes, detail shatakan, amples. Ps. to</p>
                    <p>VULCANITE, LTD., I CANNON STREET,</p>
                    <p>LONDON, EC, ENGLAND</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Cairo &amp; Alexandria</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1904-11-23/page/n5/mode/1up"
                status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>REUTER'S TELEGRAMS</p>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, November 22, 12.66 pm</p>
                    <p>Baise of the day</p>
                    <p>of which Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Amerion (new stop) Maise Bgot per</p>
                    <p>American fatares (Des-Jan.)</p>
                    <p>(April-May)</p>
                    <p>American Middling...</p>
                    <p>bales 7,000</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>4/9</p>
                    <p>6.19</p>
                    <p>5.26</p>
                    <p>5.28</p>
                    <p>8 12/64</p>
                    <p>(Dec.)</p>
                    <p>7 59154</p>
                    <p>(Jan.)</p>
                    <p>7-88.64</p>
                    <p>Reyptian fully good fair, delivery (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Brown fair per lb, d.</p>
                    <p>(March) 7.47164</p>
                    <p>good fair (browajnominal 8 6/16 good</p>
                    <p>fully good fair...</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Saidi Besas new (per 490 lbe) to 25,8</p>
                    <p>Arrivals from Egypt S.S. Moeris, 8,746 bales of</p>
                    <p>60sion</p>
                    <p>Spot Cotton...</p>
                    <p>American Futures (December)</p>
                    <p>Cable transfers Cotton day's receipts at all U.S. Porte</p>
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1904</p>
                    <p>BANKING FIRM "EL NASSIB," ORENSTEIN &amp; KOPPEL Limited</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Tewfik Pacha-Street, No. 12.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL AGENT OF THE ROYAL HUNGARIAN LOTTERY.</p>
                    <p>Telegraphic Address: EL NASSIB. - Telephone No. 1280.</p>
                    <p>We have succeeded, contrary to the general rule, in receiving from Budapest
                        by 1st Class of the 15th ROYAL HUNGARIAN LOTTERY. of which the drawing is
                        definitely fixed for the</p>
                    <p>the last mail a limited number of tickets for the</p>
                    <p>24th and 25th of this month.</p>
                    <p>Now it will be possible for us to satisfy the demands for tickets which we
                        have been obliged to refuse for several days.</p>
                    <p>For this reason we beg all those whose requests had to be refused kindly to
                        renew them and they shall be certain to receive the tickets by return of
                        post. Payments may be made in the following manner :-</p>
                    <p>1st from class to class as indicated in the Official Prospectus.</p>
                    <p>New York, November 22,</p>
                    <p>9.90</p>
                    <p>981</p>
                    <p>(January)</p>
                    <p>9.41</p>
                    <p>(April)...</p>
                    <p>(May)...</p>
                    <p>-- 9.60 9.66</p>
                    <p>dol. 4.87 5/8 bales 109,000 LIVERPOOL, November 22</p>
                    <p>Amerion fatores (December Janasry).... Egypsin fully good fair, delivery
                        (Nov.)</p>
                    <p>6.17</p>
                    <p>8 15/84)</p>
                    <p>(Dea.)</p>
                    <p>7 81/64</p>
                    <p>A WHOLE TICKET</p>
                    <p>A HALF TIOKST</p>
                    <p>(Jan.) 7 66 64</p>
                    <p>March) 7 49 64</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>A QUAQTER TIONET P.T.</p>
                    <p>AN EIGHTH TICKET P.T.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 29.-</p>
                    <p>Private dissonas (8 month bills)</p>
                    <p>Bar Bulver (per os d)...</p>
                    <p>27 4/16</p>
                    <p>1st CLASS.</p>
                    <p>50.5</p>
                    <p>25.5</p>
                    <p>13.-</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>Console (December)</p>
                    <p>89 3,8</p>
                    <p>2nd</p>
                    <p>84-</p>
                    <p>42-</p>
                    <p>21.</p>
                    <p>10.5</p>
                    <p>Bio-Tinto...</p>
                    <p>61 84</p>
                    <p>3rd</p>
                    <p>134.5</p>
                    <p>67.5</p>
                    <p>33.5</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>Band Mines</p>
                    <p>11 1/8</p>
                    <p>Egyptian United..</p>
                    <p>106 88</p>
                    <p>4th</p>
                    <p>168.</p>
                    <p>84.-</p>
                    <p>42,-</p>
                    <p>21.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Bailway</p>
                    <p>100-</p>
                    <p>5th</p>
                    <p>134-</p>
                    <p>67-</p>
                    <p>33.5</p>
                    <p>16.5</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>Domain</p>
                    <p>104 1/2</p>
                    <p>6th</p>
                    <p>101.-</p>
                    <p>50.-</p>
                    <p>25.-</p>
                    <p>13.</p>
                    <p>Ottoman Defence...</p>
                    <p>108 1/2</p>
                    <p>Turkish Unibed.</p>
                    <p>88 58</p>
                    <p>Italian Bente 6s...</p>
                    <p>104-</p>
                    <p>Onoman Bank Shares</p>
                    <p>18 5,8</p>
                    <p>Nasional Bank of</p>
                    <p>Dairs Banish</p>
                    <p>101</p>
                    <p>New Dairs</p>
                    <p>91 5/8</p>
                    <p>Manopole Gree...</p>
                    <p>87-</p>
                    <p>Charterede of 8. Afri</p>
                    <p>95/16</p>
                    <p>Agricultural Bank...</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>Nile Valley Gold Mins</p>
                    <p>new 18/4</p>
                    <p>Beats Greoque 4*</p>
                    <p>P.T.</p>
                    <p>672-</p>
                    <p>336.-</p>
                    <p>168.-</p>
                    <p>84.-</p>
                    <p>Delis Light Railway (Bearer share) 15 to 15 1/3 Egypt. dos seed to Hall
                        (Nov.) 5 19/16 nominel</p>
                    <p>German Best Bagar (November)</p>
                    <p>2nd. For all the 6 classes by one payment in advance: ie., for a whole ticket
                        672, for</p>
                    <p>a half 336, for a quarter 168, for a eighth 84 P.T.</p>
                    <p>3rd. In two equal payments of P.T. 336 for a whole ticket, P.T. 168 for a
                        half, P.T. 84 for a quarter, and P.T. 42 for an eighth. The first is payable
                        (with the order and the 2nd before the drawing of the 5th class.</p>
                    <p>4th. In 6 equal payments in advance of</p>
                    <p>Lote Taros</p>
                    <p>Crédit Lyonnais...</p>
                    <p>Om</p>
                    <p>Bank...</p>
                    <p>Cheques on London</p>
                    <p>18/11 1/3</p>
                    <p>PARIS, November 23.</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>1149</p>
                    <p>598</p>
                    <p>35.16</p>
                    <p>40</p>
                    <p>722</p>
                    <p>Bar White No. 8 (November).</p>
                    <p>Crédis Foncier Egyptien</p>
                    <p>Beaque d'Athènes (nouvele nesnee). 128 1,1.</p>
                    <p>BOURSE. da 39 novembre 1904-</p>
                    <p>COURS DES VALEURS A TERMS, CLOTURE</p>
                    <p>Bense Française 3......</p>
                    <p>PARIS-</p>
                    <p>Actions de Snez</p>
                    <p>Los Tares.</p>
                    <p>Ture Unifié.</p>
                    <p>Deite EgyptienneUnifiés...</p>
                    <p>Daira Banish</p>
                    <p>98 40 4505 180-</p>
                    <p>Céréales.....</p>
                    <p>Touring</p>
                    <p>88 14</p>
                    <p>Graines de ecton...</p>
                    <p>105 40</p>
                    <p>Olgons</p>
                    <p>101 16</p>
                    <p>P.T. 112 per whole ticket.</p>
                    <p>56</p>
                    <p>22</p>
                    <p>28</p>
                    <p>14</p>
                    <p>25</p>
                    <p>half "quarter eighth</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>29</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>BANKING FIRM "EL NASSIB."</p>
                    <p>R. KRONFELD.</p>
                    <p>COALS.</p>
                    <p>OUBARET FatoRS PER TON VREE</p>
                    <p>236 18'</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, Tewfik Street 12.</p>
                    <p>24</p>
                    <p>SALE BY AUCTION.</p>
                    <p>WASOS MESSRS. CONGDON &amp; CO. have been Shgs instructed to sell by Public
                        Auction the @ 246 property and effects of the officers, 20th Hussars. The
                        sale will take place in the 186 Mess-room, Cavalry Barracks, Abbassieh,on
                        186 Friday and Saturday, Nov. 25th and 26th, commencing at 9.30 on each
                        morning. The property will be on view on Tues day, Wednesday, and Thursday
                        afternoons 18 3 up to 6 p.m. 24982.5-4</p>
                    <p>186 -</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</p>
                    <p>24943</p>
                    <p>NOLIS</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p>1/1 8/</p>
                    <p>18 66</p>
                    <p>Per Tom</p>
                    <p>Nominal</p>
                    <p>Cardi Newport Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Best quality Best quality</p>
                    <p>Shgs. 24</p>
                    <p>Bothal</p>
                    <p>Ordis Fonciar Egyptiens...</p>
                    <p>712-</p>
                    <p>Compou</p>
                    <p>Extérigne espagnol...</p>
                    <p>90 50</p>
                    <p>LONDAR8</p>
                    <p>Davison</p>
                    <p>183 18</p>
                    <p>29</p>
                    <p>Obligations Banque Nas, de Grice</p>
                    <p>Céréales.....</p>
                    <p>Banque d'Ashines, nouvelles actions</p>
                    <p>Touriesas</p>
                    <p>139</p>
                    <p>Métropolisain...</p>
                    <p>Grainse de sosed... Olgnone</p>
                    <p>Bhgo, 1/1 1/3 &amp; 18 7/0</p>
                    <p>Hastings</p>
                    <p>-1</p>
                    <p>West Hartley Main-</p>
                    <p>Boolek</p>
                    <p>Merry's</p>
                    <p>179</p>
                    <p>Basse sonsolidé...</p>
                    <p>Bairds</p>
                    <p>17,9</p>
                    <p>Bosnowine...</p>
                    <p>Change ear Londres...</p>
                    <p>26 10</p>
                    <p>Dunlops</p>
                    <p>17,9</p>
                    <p>18 3</p>
                    <p>Beat Hamilton B</p>
                    <p>Boere No. 8 disponible</p>
                    <p>Graines de soton...</p>
                    <p>Buers No. 8 livrable</p>
                    <p>Forkshire Liverpool</p>
                    <p>Miebleford</p>
                    <p>Best Lancashire -</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p>and quality</p>
                    <p>Consolidés anglale****</p>
                    <p>288 5/16</p>
                    <p>Besond Lancashire</p>
                    <p>Becomptes-Parie 8, Londres 8, Berlin</p>
                    <p>Coton</p>
                    <p>Anchor</p>
                    <p>Crown</p>
                    <p>GERBAL MARKET.</p>
                    <p>Tourtesas... Graines de coton... Olgnens...</p>
                    <p>Star</p>
                    <p>Arrow</p>
                    <p>Patent Fuel Newcastle</p>
                    <p>Swansea Graigola 22/6</p>
                    <p>Atlantic- Foundry Cobe Cake</p>
                    <p>38 34</p>
                    <p>39</p>
                    <p>PORTS DIRECTS Hhgo. 90-10/ 1/9-</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL ...Hogs. 11/ 1,8</p>
                    <p>CONTINENT (NANTES.DUNKERQUE)</p>
                    <p>BOG BL FARAD. (NATIONAL BAR' BHOOMAN) Grainse is ook (Dunkerque) Fr.</p>
                    <p>Olgnene...</p>
                    <p>Wheat, Tagarl Arl. P.T. 199 to P.T. 196</p>
                    <p>Middling Mawani...</p>
                    <p>188</p>
                    <p>MARGRILLE</p>
                    <p>146</p>
                    <p>Beans, Tugri</p>
                    <p>Gminer de soton...</p>
                    <p>-7.80</p>
                    <p>95</p>
                    <p>(old erop)</p>
                    <p>110</p>
                    <p>88</p>
                    <p>DESTINATIONS DEVERE</p>
                    <p>Lanule Tagad</p>
                    <p>Zaws</p>
                    <p>Amiawi..</p>
                    <p>Barley, Togari</p>
                    <p>#</p>
                    <p>Zawad</p>
                    <p>Dam Bhacal</p>
                    <p>Helbe</p>
                    <p>Bala</p>
                    <p>Lentils Orished Rho-</p>
                    <p>Orushe l</p>
                    <p>ORMAS IN BOAT AT BANNE</p>
                    <p>Ard. 8000</p>
                    <p>1400</p>
                    <p>1600</p>
                    <p>607</p>
                    <p>800</p>
                    <p>140</p>
                    <p>Coton : Odes, Trierts, Venies,</p>
                    <p>106 Gas, Marvellie... Pr. S</p>
                    <p>78 Barone</p>
                    <p>88 Le Havre</p>
                    <p>76</p>
                    <p>Dankerge</p>
                    <p>3.60 8.00</p>
                    <p>par 100 kille</p>
                    <p>Hambourg</p>
                    <p>186 P</p>
                    <p>210 New-Yo</p>
                    <p>Bombay</p>
                    <p>90.0 99.60</p>
                    <p>die, le 16 novembre 1904</p>
                    <p>PRIMES DES CONTRATS.</p>
                    <p>"SIMPLE VACULT</p>
                    <p>Ostos Tdy: Mare P. 18 80/40 &amp; 18: Gainer is set. 76. M... 1-a 38/40</p>
                    <p>LEGYPTIAN GAZETTE en vente dane les rues du Caire tous les soirs, à F 7h. 80,
                        cepté le dimanches et jours Hride. Le journal out at on wit aus Iris, de
                        Tantak</p>
                    <p>mire de jer, P.T</p>
                    <p>Pyle du</p>
                    <p>meg</p>
                    <p>"TELLAGE</p>
                    <p>183</p>
                    <p>GREAT SALE</p>
                    <p>OF</p>
                    <p>Capital 10,000,000 Frs.</p>
                    <p>PURVEYORS TO HH. THE KHEDIVE. PORTABLE AND PERMANENT RAILWAYS PASSENGER AND
                        GOODS CARS</p>
                    <p>Tipping and Platform Waggons</p>
                    <p>FOR ALL PURPOSES. LOCOMOTIVES FROM 10-400 HP.</p>
                    <p>(CATO: 24 Kaar el Nil Street opposite the Bask of Egypt</p>
                    <p>OFFICES OB. 690, Telephone No.39</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 29 Cher f Pasha Street. Telephone No. 661</p>
                    <p>Large Stocks of Rails, Tracks, and Locomotives always kept in Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>SIEMENS &amp; HALSKE, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING OFFICES: CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA Electric Light Installations.
                        Transision of Power Electric Railways and Tramways- Telegraphic &amp;
                        Telephonic Apparatze DYNAMOS MOTORS.</p>
                    <p>OFFICES</p>
                    <p>OHATWOOD'S and ILMER'S SAFES 2 steek</p>
                    <p>CAIBO: 34, Karl- Blest, opposite Bank of Bgypt, P.0.B. 600. Triophone No.
                        189. ALEXANDRIA: 29, Chéri Pasha Street. Telephone No. 867. 81-33-904</p>
                    <p>Allen, Alderson &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>LIMITED</p>
                    <p>SOLE &amp; EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR Leers. Ruston, Proctor &amp; Co., Limited,
                        Lincoin. Palon T-mobing Kaisaking Hoshinas</p>
                    <p>Fixed and Fortable Bom and OIL Bags Oers</p>
                    <p>Mesars. Platt Brothers&amp;Co., Limited, Oldham. Messrs. John Fowler &amp;
                        Co., Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>Steam Panghing Machinery and Bandries,</p>
                    <p>The Central Crolone Co., Limited, London. Grinding and Pulering
                        Machinery.</p>
                    <p>Mers Charles Cammell &amp; Co., Ld., of Sheffield.</p>
                    <p>Mors.</p>
                    <p>Bumi Halla, prigi, for as Patent mad at Dis</p>
                    <p>Merryweather &amp; Sons, London.</p>
                    <p>Stoom and Maanal Fire Engin</p>
                    <p>F. Reddaway &amp; Co. Ld, Pendleton, Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Oarel Brands Baiting at, she</p>
                    <p>Ratner's Safes.</p>
                    <p>The Engelberg Rice Haller,</p>
                    <p>Rik Vortes Turbines,</p>
                    <p>Mosers. Greenwood Batley Limited, Leeds.</p>
                    <p>Ths (a) Palent Bomb Batsriaal Dynamo &amp; Motors</p>
                    <p>McCormick's Reapers &amp; Mowers.</p>
                    <p>Planet Junior Agricultural Implements.</p>
                    <p>Borne Joan, Bood Dri, ate, st OLITER PLOUGES.</p>
                    <p>Agent in Cairo: MA. FATTUOOI.</p>
                    <p>38-8-805</p>
                    <p>Agents for amEENE Economisers.</p>
                    <p>STEINEMANN MABARDI &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>MERCHANTS,</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Engineering Stores. CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY</p>
                    <p>Bole Agenta for Egypt, Asia Minor and Syria for</p>
                    <p>IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Mears. Clayton &amp; Shuttleworth, Lincoln. Portable &amp; Exed Engines &amp;
                        Boffers, Cos</p>
                    <p>milla, Thrashing Strawbruising &amp; Cutting Machines</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Galloways Ltd. Manchester. The Largest Boller Works in the World Walter
                        A. Wood, Mowing &amp; Beaping Machian Co. Boorish Falla N. F. (Acarion)
                        Beapers; Mowers, Harvesters &amp; Bakes</p>
                    <p>Piguet &amp; Co., Lyons. French Steam Bagisan</p>
                    <p>Aveling &amp; Porter Lim., Rochester. Ste Bollers and Steam Ploughs Les
                        Tanneries Lyonnaises, Oullins (Rhône) Best Leather Belting E.. Hindley,
                        Burton, Dorset, Vertical Engines and Bollars, specially designed for driving
                        estrie Dynamos &amp; Owntrifugal Pumps, sto, eta Hillafret Hagueot, Paria
                        Mectricians.</p>
                    <p>L. Dumont. Paris. Centrifugal pumps.</p>
                    <p>8. E. &amp; E. Turner Ltd. Ipswich. Flour Mille</p>
                    <p>31188-94-11-904</p>
                    <p>Winter Novelties Credit Lyonnais SHRADER BROTHERS.</p>
                    <p>COMMENCES</p>
                    <p>Société Anonym</p>
                    <p>22/9 NOVEMBER 12. Capital 250.000.000 de Franos</p>
                    <p>EXCHANGE QUOTATIONS</p>
                    <p>London cheque... 8m. bank paper Bai hege paper...</p>
                    <p>Parie cheque Cine</p>
                    <p>8m. bank paper...</p>
                    <p>Sm. hoe paper.</p>
                    <p>Banks Banks baying selling</p>
                    <p>rated 97 1/8 97 96</p>
                    <p>886 1/4 887 888 14 888</p>
                    <p>Bwitserland &amp; bank paper.. 881 1/4-</p>
                    <p>Germany chage......</p>
                    <p>Ben, bank-pape</p>
                    <p>mies</p>
                    <p>475 14</p>
                    <p>471 1/8</p>
                    <p>Italian sheque paper</p>
                    <p>888-</p>
                    <p>abaque</p>
                    <p>405. 1/3</p>
                    <p>888 1/4 406</p>
                    <p>88 1/8</p>
                    <p>88 8/8</p>
                    <p>Vienna &amp; Trie</p>
                    <p>Constantinopla cheque...</p>
                    <p>Municipalité d'Alexandrie</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>AT</p>
                    <p>Walker &amp; Meimarachi.</p>
                    <p>PASCHAL BRANCH.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>LATEST</p>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>PARIS</p>
                    <p>ENTLERUMENT VERSES</p>
                    <p>AGENCES DEGYPTE ALEXANDRI LE CAIRE PORT SAID</p>
                    <p>Avamoos sur Marchandises, Consignation.</p>
                    <p>LE CREDIT LYONNAIS fait des avances Fur marshandises, telles que :,</p>
                    <p>COTONS</p>
                    <p>GRAINES DE COTON, ORREALES SUORES, te</p>
                    <p>Il reçoit également des marchandisee soit en dépôt libre, avee droite de
                        magaal Rayole ou a l'airanger.</p>
                    <p>CREATIONS age, solé en consignation, pour la vente en</p>
                    <p>NOTICE</p>
                    <p>94870-14-18</p>
                    <p>8170004</p>
                    <p>LONDON CALCUTTA, ALEXANDRIA. SINGAPORE AND COLOMBO (Union). Merchants in Jute
                        and Jute Fabrios (Gunny Baga).</p>
                    <p>COTTON PACKS</p>
                    <p>and based)</p>
                    <p>(00 by 48′′) (11 by 11)</p>
                    <p>(11.by 10)</p>
                    <p>(11 by 10)</p>
                    <p>(by 10)</p>
                    <p>ONION POCKETS (own and homel</p>
                    <p>19) on (40 by 2 by 10)</p>
                    <p>(Swa</p>
                    <p>GRAIN BACKS (rown and hommel)</p>
                    <p>SUGAR BAGE</p>
                    <p>80</p>
                    <p>DR. LE CLERC'S</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>8.701.04</p>
                    <p>EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO, LTD. Pills for the Liver &amp; Kidneys</p>
                    <p>VERAGE SIM m By from good to Aldria Ted Nebr</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS</p>
                    <p>are an unfailing and reliable remedy for die of the important organe gout,
                        rheumatism, gravel pains in the bank and kindred silmante (nquired or
                        constitutional), Sold by prinetpal Chemite, not to loom quantities, but only
                        in boxes, price L bearing the British Government Bamp with th wonde Eugene
                        Le. Clero pred thereen</p>
                    <p>The Biter of the Bgyption Gonette wil be pleased to resolve come nications
                        dealing with malies of local, interest, for yabletion. Notes of to covering
                        in (Between the hours of 10 am and 6pm. Outro time to protect the pable from
                        frid the Provinces are especially welcome. hould be sent to T by and Addres,
                        not nece</p>
                    <p>Le Jeudi 24 Novembre conant pactis de 8h. pm., Man/elpalité groolders &amp;
                        la vente atten ahires jobliques pris de ontières Heropéens is &amp; is Porte
                        Rosene, d'ane quantité de pierres extraites der ersion des Forossions par de
                        400 1 100m Les betere devront par le droit d'an shore da 1020 époser le 10
                        000 de la valore de la marebandise sehetés ant moment de la vante of soon
                        Fon-M... 80/40. Liv. Mare FT. 97 90/40 &amp; 98 80/40 offener le paiement
                        insigral &amp; Onlee Mani. All come eipale, le leglessin da jour de
                        l'etindiastion. Ile auront sapporter le droise de carrière an prods de la
                        Ville et devront enlever les pierres ache tée dans un délai de dix jours,
                        sone geins anah Are, pour compte de l'adjudicataire. Alexandrie, le 21
                        Novembre 1904.</p>
                    <p>"DOUBLE</p>
                    <p>dv. Mare FT. 880/40 &amp; 10 .-M.</p>
                    <p>10/40 1.18/40</p>
                    <p>94044-8-9</p>
                    <p>folle</p>
                    <p>Writer's good faith The B</p>
                    <p>1/Adminiralour W. P. CHATAWAY.</p>
                    <p>THUM</p>
                    <p>1:18</p>
                    <p>Dr. LE CLERO'S SOAP. Molloal antiseptia used and recommended by ambent
                        dermatologists in the treatment of eos lepra, psoriaals, alourations, alta
                        eruptions: thehing and treating the bumours baby rashes ode, ale prophyte
                        against the risk of contmoting des and Infotions disordare generally. I
                        healing propension greatly minimise the bon ventence of shaving to use of
                        phapes pote ten La Tablete price / old by Cairo and Ale</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
