<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-28">January 28, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7109 ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JANUARY 25, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AUTOCRACY TRIUMPHS. DEPORTATIONS TO SIBERIA. STRIKE MOVEMENT LIKELY TO "FLICKER” OUT</head>
                    <dateline>London, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>The “Daily Chronicle learns from St. Petersburg that 5,000 persons were
                        arrested last Wednesday evening, including one hundred lawyers, who are now
                        on their way to Siberia. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Thirty strikers were killed or wounded during an encounter with the troops at
                        Riga. Tire sub-chief of the police and two soldiers were killed.</p>
                    <p>-Minor disorders have occurred in other large</p>
                    <p>towns.</p>
                    <p>The Councils of the Civil Engineering, Polytechnic, and Aiming institutes
                        here have sent to the Ministers to whom they are subordinate resolutions
                        denouncing the butchery on the 22nd inst., and refusing to continue their
                        courses.</p>
                    <p>The University Senate has suspended the re-opening of the University until
                        the 22nd prox. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Warsaw, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>The strike has begun. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Although the strike is spreading slightly in different towns, the impression
                        is growing here that the worst is over, and that the movement will gradually
                        flicker out.</p>
                    <p>The newspapers are reappearing but they are forbidden by the censor to
                        mention the strike. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Riga, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>The hospitals here notify having received 31 killed and 45 wounded.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHINA’S NEUTRALITY.</head>
                    <dateline>Washington, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Mr. Hay has suggested to Russia that the questions regarding the violation of
                        Chinese neutrality should be submitted to a Conference of the Power's.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH CHAMBER.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies has approved by 410 votes against 107 the
                        declarations of M. Rouvier, promising the accomplishment of reforms with the
                        support of all sincere Republicans. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Chamber of Deputies.—M. Rouvier announced his adherence to M. Combes’
                        anticlérical programme, and to the Russian alliance. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HUNGARIAN GENERAL ELECTION.</head>
                    <p>Budapest, January 27. At the general election, the Opposition unexpectedly
                        gained a number of seats. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTH DORSET ELECTION.</head>
                    <dateline>London, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Mr. Wills, Liberal, 4,239 votes, Sir Randolf Baker, Conservative, 3,330.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WORLD’S LARGEST DIAMOND.</head>
                    <p>Johannesburg, January 27. The largest diamond in the world, weighing 2,032
                        carats, has been found in the Premier Mine. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOSTILITIES RESUMED. KUROPATKIN TAKES OFFENSIVE. JAPANESE DRIVEN AT POINT OF BAYONET</head>
                    <dateline>London, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>Reuter’s correspondent with Kuroki, cabling on the 26th inst., states that
                        heavy continuous artillery tire to the west was heard all day. Apparently an
                        important engagement was proceeding. It was stated that a Russian force had
                        crossed the Hun-Ho on the Japanese left. The Japanese were then attacking
                        the Russians. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>London, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>The “Daily Telegraph” understands from St. Petersburg that Kuropatkin has
                        telegraphed to the Tsar to the effect that his power to take the offensive
                        has been seriously hampered by the reluctance of the European regiments to
                        advance against the enemy. They argue that now Port Arthur has fallen there
                        is no object in continuing the war. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>General Kuropatkin has taken the offensive. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 27.</dateline>
                    <p>General Kuropatkin wires that on the 26th inst. he assumed the offensive
                        against the Japanese left, and occupied a position from which the Japanese
                        were driven at the point of the bayonet. He was repulsed when making an
                        attack on the Japanese right. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>For the Unemployed</head>
                        <p>The collections at all the military services of the Church of England in
                            Cairo to-morrow will be given to the Lord Mayor of Loudon’s Fund for the
                            Unemployed.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>At Mena House</head>
                        <p>The 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers will be encamped at Alena
                            House from to-day up to the loth February. The next small dance at Mena
                            will be on February 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Automobilism in Egypt</head>
                        <p>should receive a great impetus by the foundation of the new Motor Club.
                            A general meeting was held at Shepheard's Hotel on Thursday evening,
                            when the club came into existence.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Royal Visit</head>
                        <p>A set of very successful photographs of the arrival of H.R.H. the Duke
                            of Connaught at Alexandria have been taken by Messrs. Reiser and Binder,
                            the well-known photographers, and are now exhibited in their
                            windows.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Italian Consulates</head>
                        <p>Our Constantinople Correspondent says that the Italian Government has
                            demanded of the Sublime Porte, through its embassy there, the exequatur
                            for the newly-appointed Consuls at Cario, Alexandria, and Port Said.
                            This has now been duly delivered.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“In Memoriam.”</head>
                        <p>A brief service to the memory of the late General Gordon will be held in
                            the church-room of the Sailors’ and Soldiers’ Institute to-morrow at 10
                            a.m. by the Rev. W. Dickins, Acting Wesleyan Chaplain. The Wesleyan men
                            of H.M.S. "Essex” are expected to be present. Others are cordially
                            invited.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Hedjaz Railway</head>
                        <p>The Turkish papers announce that the works on the Damascus-Meeca Railway
                            beyond Catrana are now to be taken in hand, and are to be actively
                            pushed on. The plans of the viaducts in this new-section are under
                            consideration.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sporting Cairo</head>
                        <p>“In Cario and the vicinity are to be found facilities for indulging in
                            practically every form of sport dear to the average Englishman,” writes
                            Mr. Horace Wyndham in the penultimate number of the “Field.” There is no
                            need for us to reproduce the article, as the ground it covers is known
                            to most of our readers, but we recommend it to tourists.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Amateur Theatricals</head>
                        <p>The date of the performance in Cairo of “The Pirates of Penzance” is
                            fixed for the 14th or 15th of February. It will take place in the Opera
                            House and it is hoped that H.R.H. the Duke of Connaught will be able to
                            be present. The rehearsals promise well and reflect great credit upon
                            Major Delavoye, the stage manager. All the company works with spirit,
                            and both principals and chorus have put in some excellent drill during
                            the last three weeks. The ladies’ gavotte in the 1st act is a very
                            graceful measure and ought to prove one of the successes of the piece.
                            The policemen, with Captain Tucker, R.E., at their head, provide the
                            comic element, and their ‘business’ is very good fun. The box-office
                            will shortly be opened ; the booking is likely to be full, all the
                            baignoires for the first night being already bespoken. The performance
                            will be repeated at intervals during the season.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURE FOR UPRIVER.</p>
                    <p>The Duke of Connaught and Lord Cromer visited the Princes of the Khedivial
                        family</p>
                    <p>The Duchess of Connaught, accompanied by the Princesses, proceeded to Koubbeh
                        Palace yesterday morning at ten o'clock to return the Khedivah's visit of
                        the previous day.</p>
                    <p>Alter attending the races the Duke and Duchess of Connaught, accompanied by
                        the Princesses, left Cairo at 6.45 p.m. on their way</p>
                    <p>Our Keneh Correspondent, telegraphing this morning, states that the Royal
                        party passed through Keneh station, en route for Luxor, at 9:50 a.m. two
                        hours behind time. The Duke arrived on the station platform and conversed
                        for some little time with the Sub-moudir. There was a large crowd of
                        spectators at the station to greet their Royal Highnesses.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PROGRAMME FOR KHARTOUM.</head>
                    <p>The Royal party are due to arrive at Khartoum at 2 a.m. on February 2. The
                        following is the programme of their stay ;</p>
                    <p>Feb. 2 and 3. Mornings free for inspection of Rifle brigade. Afternoon,
                        garden party at the Palace and opening of Agricultural Show,
                        respectively.</p>
                    <p>Feb. 4. Morning. Review of all the troops. Afternoon. Visit to Omdurman.
                        Evening.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Torchlight Tattoo.</head>
                    <p>Feb. 5. After morning service at Church. Visit to Gordon College and Drive
                        round Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>If the Duke stays another day he will arrange a picnic up the White Nile.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                    <p>The Khedive yesterday was amongst the visitors to the Ghezireh race course,
                        together with the Duke and Duchess of Connaught. At 6:30 p m the Khedive
                        accompanied them to the train which is to take the Royal visitors to
                        Khartoum. His Highness afterwards returned to Kouhbeh.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive came this morning to Abdeen Palace to preside over the Council of
                        Ministers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EMPRESS EUGENIE</head>
                    <p>The Empress Eugene had luncheon in the Savoy Restaurant yesterday, her guests
                        including Princes' Bonaparte dc la Moskawa Mile B. De Bassatro, Comte
                        Primoli, Comte Clary and Franceschini Pietn.</p>
                    <p>During the morning the Empress received visiting Prince Gustavus Adolphus of
                        Sweden and Norway. the Duchess of Connaught, accompanied by the Princesses
                        and the Countess of Comer, and the Duke of Connaught, in company with the
                        Earl of Cromer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KAISERS BIRTHDAY.</head>
                    <p>The anniversary of the Kaiser's birthday was celebrated with the usual
                        loyalty by the German xxxxx at Cairo and Alexandria. Yesterday at 10 a.m.
                        there was a service in the Lutheran Church at Cairo. followed by a largely
                        attended reception, held by Dr. Rucker-Jenson at the German Agency. Tbe Duke
                        of Connaught and Prince Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden visited Dr. Jenisch.
                        Another reception was held by Mr. Gumprecht at the Consulate, and in the
                        evening there was a banquet at the Grand Continental Hotel and a tete at the
                        Cercle Artistique.</p>
                    <p>At Alexandria the day began with a mass at the Kaiser Wilhelm's Home. There
                        was a service at the Lutheran Church and baron von Humboldt Dachroeden held
                        a reception. The Krieger Verein had a loyal gathering of members and the day
                        ended with a Kommers</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="councilMinisters"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
                    <p>The Khedevial decrees published today after the Council of Ministers Abdeen
                        Palace refer merely to appointmentus which we have already published, and to
                        certain expropriations of land for public utility.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL ROBBERY.</head>
                    <p>The statement which appears to-day in a Cairo morning newspaper, to the
                        effect that the 8,000 pounds, which had disappeared, have been found again,
                        and that the soldiers, who had been arrested ou suspicion of having stolen
                        the money, have been released, is totally erroneous and has no foundation in
                        fact.</p>
                    <p>It seems that in the specie van the cases containing the money were arranged
                        in three rows, each case having its own number and the amount of the money
                        contained therein marked on it. The cases nearest the sliding</p>
                    <p>door of the van contained sums of about £3,000 in Maria Theresa dollars. The
                        stolen box was in the middle of the second row and the thief, after lifting
                        out the box from among the others, arranged them so as to fill up the gap in
                        their line</p>
                    <p>From this it would seem more probable than ever that the thief or thieves had
                        sometime allowed them lor effecting their nefarious enterprise. It is not
                        considered likely that the thief was a European, but it a Moslem he was
                        evidently one of those to whom the Arab proverb Yiferagu mal en Nebi" is
                        applicable</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT'S TRADE IN 1904.</head>
                    <p>ENORMOUS DEVELOPMENT.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Customs returns for December are always of exceptional
                        importance inasmuch as they furnish us with the statistics not only for that
                        mouth, but for the whole year, and enable us to anticipate, in so far as
                        regards the larger totals, the annual report of the Customs Administration,
                        which will not appear tor some mouths.</p>
                    <p>The imports for December have maintained the upward tendency which has been
                        incidence throughout the year, being LE. 638,959 in excess over those for
                        the same month in 1903, and bringing the total imports to the record figure
                        of LE 20,559,588. This is an enormous increase, for we considered the
                        imports for 1903 to be extraordinary, when they showed a total of L.E.
                        16,753,190. That was a record, being nearly two millions 13%, over that of
                        1902, and 1 1/2 millions, or 10% over the total for 1901, the highest
                        touched previously to 1903. Rut 1904, with its increase of nearly four
                        millions, L.E. 3,806,398, over the previous years, is the best on record and
                        is a proof of</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT'S AMAZING PROSPERITY.</head>
                    <p>Our share in Egypt's import trade for the last few years is as follows :</p>
                    <p>Groat Britain : 1901 ; LE 5,699,201. 1909 ; LE 5,559,559. 1903 ; L.E.
                        5,919,404. 1904 ; LE 6,990,689.</p>
                    <p>These figures show that our share of Egypt's total trade in 1901 was 37.4, in
                        1909 37.5, in 1903 36.9, and last year 99.8.</p>
                    <p>A full analysis and comparison of our trade with Egypt as compared with that
                        of other countries is impossible without the fuller details that will be
                        supplied by the forthcoming annual returns, so we shall reserve until their
                        appearance an exhaustive review of the year's trade, it does not need,
                        however, more than a glance to discover under wbat heads the imports have
                        chiefly increased. The following figures represent the total increase in
                        Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Animals and alimentary products of animals 374,110.</p>
                    <p>Cereals, vegetables, flour, etc. 307.666. Sugar, spices, coffee 210,015.</p>
                    <p>Wood and coal 370,033.</p>
                    <p>Textiles 1,319,175.</p>
                    <p>Iron, ironwork, copper, brass, etc. 694,051. Parcel-post 138,559.</p>
                    <p>EXPORTS.</p>
                    <p>The exports during the past twelve months amounted to L.E. 20,811,040, an
                        increase of LE. 1,271,516 on 1903. The total value of the cotton exported
                        was LE 16,702,730, an increase of L.E. 1,025,916. Bean exports rose from
                        L.E. 196,515 to LE. 953,914, onions from LE. 191,158 to LE. 965,974, and
                        cigarettes from L E. 493,339 to L.E. 494,964. The biggest falling off in
                        exports was in sugar cane, which decreased by L.E 93,933.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Prince Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden and Norway attended the reception held by
                        the German Diplomatic Agent and Consol General yesterday on the occasion of
                        he anniversary of the Kaiser's birthday.</p>
                    <p>In Lady Cromer’s brother, the now Undersecretary for India, Mr.Brodrick will
                        find a colleague who is both able and amiable, and possibly, if occasion
                        serves, a successor to Lord Curzon. The fifth Marquess of Bath has had some
                        valuable official experience as private secretary to the late Earl of
                        Iddlesleigh—himself Indian Secretary—and as assistant secretary to Lord
                        Goschen when he was at the Treasury.</p>
                    <p>As Viscount Weymouth he spent six years in the House of Commons as member for
                        the Frome division, and revealed himself as a fluent and ready speaker with
                        a comprehensive grasp of the subjects under debate, and he has been proving
                        himself an exceedingly capable chairman of the Royal Commission on Idiots
                        and Inebriates, he is Lord Lieutenant of Somerset, in which office he
                        succeeded the late Earl of Cork, and be is the owner of some sixty thousand
                        acres, of which the eight-and-twenty thousand which comprise his Wiltshire
                        and Somersetshire properties represent a rent-roll of something like eighty
                        thousand a year.</p>
                    <p>General de Negrier intends to make a long stay in Egypt and will also make a
                        trip to the Sudan. One of his reasons for visiting Egypt, says a French
                        newspaper, is, “outre autres projets, d'étudier l'organisation des contrées
                        musulmanes qui envoient des missions nombreuses au Maroc, uti elles ont
                        acquis une très grande influence."</p>
                    <p>The Savoy Restaurant presented an animated appearance yesterday evening on
                        the occasion of the concert organised by the “Comité des Fêtes. Both the new
                        enlarged restaurant and a second private dining room, which had to be opened
                        for the occasion, were quite full. Among the diners we noticed Mr. Speyer,
                        with a party of 12. Sir W. Garstin was entertained by the Duke and Duchess
                        of Devonshire. Mrs. Simon had a party of 6. The Master of Elibank's party
                        included Sir Thomas Lipton, Mr. Armstrong, Mr. Hobhouse, M.P., the Hon.
                        O'Brian, Mr. and Mrs. H Pasha Owing to the death of Nungovich Bey's
                        daughter, the small dance announced was put off.</p>
                    <p>We much regret to announce the death ol Sacha Nungovich, the infant daughter
                        of Nungovich Bey, who succumbed to pneumonia on Thursday evening. The
                        funeral took place yesterday afternoon. We offer our sincere condolences to
                        the parents in their bereavement</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO SECOND WINTER MEETING</head>
                        <p>Second Day's Racing.</p>
                        <p>Yesterday's races were a great success. The presence of H.H. the Khedive
                            and H.R.H. the Duke and Duchess of Connaught, the improvement in the
                            weather, and the excellent sport provided by the K.S.C. on Wednesday,
                            all helped to attract a very large attendance, and no previous meeting,
                            in the Cairo season of 1904-5, could have rivalled it in the numbers of
                            residents and visitors present. H. R. H. Prince Gustavus Adolphus, H. H.
                            Prince Mohamed Aly Pasha the Earl and Countess of Cromer, the Duke and
                            Duchess of Devonshire, Sir William Gafatin, the Hon. F. O. Lindley and
                            the Hon. Mrs. Lindley, Mr. A. L Webb C.M.G., Mr. P. Machell, Mr. H.
                            Carter Wilson, Major-General Slade, C.B., and Mrs. Slade. Sir Edward and
                            Lady Zobrab, Sir John and Lady Rogers, Mr. and Mrs. Sharman, Sir Elwin
                            Palmer, Mr. H. Rumbold, Mr. Higgins, Mr. and Mrs. Brunyate, Mme. Adolphe
                            Cattaui, Mr. and Mrs. Alban, Mr. and Mrs. Scott-Dalgleish, Dr. Keatinge
                            and Mrs. Keatinge, Dr. and Mrs. Nolan, Major and Mrs. Delavoye, Mr. and
                            Mrs. Hogg, Mr. and Mrs. Parvis, Milhem Bey Shakour and Miss Shakour, Mr.
                            and Mrs. Wylde were there and many others—in fact, almost all the
                            best-known members of Cairo society, and the grand-stand and enclosure
                            presented a most brilliant spectacle.</p>
                        <p>The racing, it less sensational than on Wednesday, presented many points
                            of interest, but it was the greatest of pities that there were such
                            small fields in the second and fourth races. The race of the day was the
                            Paddock Handicap, which resulted in a well-earned victory for Ishak Boy
                            Hussein's Farhan II., which also came home second in the Galloway
                            Handicap. Khalil Pasha Kayat, though be could not repeat Wednesday’s
                            success, did well, and Mr. Lockett had the satisfaction of riding two
                            winners.</p>
                        <p>The starts were managed with the minimum of delay. Shortly after the
                            arrival of the Khedive, escorted by a detachment of his Body Guard and
                            greeted by the strains of the Khédivial Anthem, came the first race. The
                            Duke and Duchess of Connaught arrived after the second race, accompanied
                            by the Princesses, and followed by their escort. They were received with
                            the National Anthem.</p>
                        <p>TURF CLUB HANDICAP—Value L.E. 40, 2nd horse to receive LE 3, if four or
                            more start, and 3rd horse LE 2, if six more start, out of the stakes.
                            For Arabs and C.B’s Distance 1 1/2 miles.</p>
                        <p>Captain Gillson’s c.h.c.b. Brennus, 11.0. M. Reid. 1</p>
                        <p>Moharrem Pasha’s g.b.g. Mizzaud, S.S. Kon-kides. 2</p>
                        <p>Omar Boy Sultan and Bakry Bey's g.a.h. Rachid, 9.7. Stillwell.</p>
                        <p>Omar Bey Sultan and Bakri Bey's be.c.m.</p>
                        <p>Florence, 13.0. Ali Farag. 0</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat’s g.a.h. Banaback, 10.12.</p>
                        <p>Mr. Lockett. 0</p>
                        <p>Messrs. Rees and Barker's b.c.b.m. Jewel of Asia, 12.7. Mr. G. H. Barker.
                            0</p>
                        <p>Jewel of Asia led but was passed at the end of the first half-mile by
                            Brennus, who led up to the corner pressed by Banaback. At the corner
                            Jewel of Asia was out of it and Banaback had nothing left for a spurt
                            and was passed by Rachid, while Mizzaud, making a good effort, worried
                            Brennus all the way up the straight, but was beaten by about 3/4 of a
                            length. A poor third.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 128 on winner and 38, 27. and 22 for places.</p>

                        <p>THE INTERNATIONAL HANDICAP. Value L.E. 100, presented by the Egyptian
                            Government For classes 1, 2 and 3, and Country B’s Distance about 1 1/2
                            miles.</p>
                        <p>Hassan Pasha Mohsen's b.e.h. Merry Rustic, 11.3. Mr. Reid. 1</p>
                        <p>Omar Bey Sultan and Bakri Bey’s b.e.h. Bonus, 8.11. Bonser. 2</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat’s ch.e.m. Ravensden, 9.7. 0 Omar Bey Sultan and Bakri
                            Bey's b.a.c.m.</p>
                        <p>Florence, 9.0. 0</p>
                        <p>Omar Bey Sultan and Bakri Boy's ch.e.b.</p>
                        <p>Flying Gipsy, 10.3. 0</p>
                        <p>Ibrahim Boy Cherif's ch.e.h. Oberon, 8.13. Eliseo. 0</p>

                        <p>Bonus led at the start, Oberon being a long way behind and never making
                            up. Merry Rustic caught Bonus after 1/2 a mile and the horses ran
                            together till the corner, when Hassan Pasha Mohsen's horse went ahead
                            and won without being really pressed. Oberon was a deplorable third.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 37 on winner and P.T. 21 and 26 for places. THE
                            PADDOCK HANDICAP. Value LE 300. 2nd horse to receive LE 50, and 3rd
                            horse LE30, out of the stakes. For Arab ponies Distance about 1 mile, 1
                            furlong.</p>

                        <p>Ishak Bey Hussein's ch.ah. Farhan II., 11.2.</p>
                        <p>Stillwell. 1</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's g.ah. Latiff, 9.13. White-side 2</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's g.ah. Sadik, 10.9. Jenkins. 3</p>
                        <p>Captain Gillson's flg.a.h. Sirur, 8.9. Shaker. 0 Saleh Bey Yaghen’s
                            b.a.h. Abou Arkoub, 9.19.</p>
                        <p>Hassan. 0</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's ch.ah. Klondyke,- 9.12.</p>
                        <p>McCall. 0</p>
                        <p>Ishak Bey Hussein’s g.ah. Saber, 10.12. H. Sulitnan. 0</p>
                        <p>Ibrahim Bey Cherif's g.a.h. Royalist, 10.12.</p>
                        <p>Elias. 0</p>
                        <p>Ibrahim Bey Cherif's ch.ah. Fantasia, 10.11.</p>
                        <p>Elise 0</p>
                        <p>Moharrem Pasha's g.a.h. Agib, 10.5. Mr. A. J.</p>
                        <p>Michaelides. 0</p>
                        <p>Messrs. Rees and Barker's g.ah. Vandal, 10.6.</p>
                        <p>Mr. G. H. Barker. 0</p>
                        <p>Messrs. Rees and Barker's g.ah. India, 9.7.</p>
                        <p>Abdullah. 0</p>
                        <p>Mr. Tueni's Kah. Viking, 8.6. Matthews, 0 Mr. R Sursock and Mr. Tueni's
                            b.a.h. Amory, 9.7, Batty,</p>

                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's stable were favorites,</p>
                        <p>Farhan II., Agib, and India being well backed for places. Farhan II. went
                            off splendidly at the start, and after being temporarily passed by Agib,
                            went ahead again ; and Latiff</p>
                        <p>then came up from the crowd and passed Agib, who was done at the corner.
                            Klondyke and Saber both challenged but were shaken off, though Sadik and
                            Latiff never got very near Farhan II., who got in by 2 lengths. Latiff
                            was half a length ahead of Sadik.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 128 on winner and P.T. 88,27, and 22 for
                            places.</p>

                        <p>THE PYRAMID STEEPLECHASE Value LE 40, 2nd horse to receive LE 10, if four
                            or more start, and 3rd horse LE 5, if six or more start, out of the
                            stakes. For all horses that have never won a race of LE 40. Catch
                            weights over 11 st. 7lba Distance 2 miles. Ibrahim Bey Cherif and E. Bey
                            Sursock's g.a.b. Arabi, Mr. Reid. 1</p>
                        <p>Mr. E Karam’s g.a.h. Soutfi, Mr. Lockett. 0 The rewere only two horses in
                            for this race, which excited little or no interest and was fairly easily
                            won by Soutfi.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 27 on winner.</p>

                        <p>THE UNITED SERVICE HANDICAP SCURRY, of LE 30, 2nd horse to receive LE 7,
                            and 3rd LE 3, if 6 or more start, out of the stakes, for Arabs. The
                            property of Officers of the Army of Occupation, British Officers
                            attached to the Egyptian Army, British Civilians the Egyptian Government
                            and British Members of the K.S.C. Distance 1/2 mile.</p>
                        <p>Mr. Lockett’s ch.a.h. Fits, 12.7. Owner. 1 Captain G. Gillson's g.a.h.
                            The Clown, 10.10.</p>
                        <p>Mr. Reid. 2</p>
                        <p>Mr. C. W. Hemp's b.a.h. Grand Slam, 11.0.</p>
                        <p>Owner. 8</p>
                        <p>Mr. A. Schreiber's g.a.h. Shewiman, 12.0.</p>
                        <p>Owner. 0</p>
                        <p>Captain G. B. Byrne’s g.a.h.. Samhane, 11.4 Starkey. 0</p>
                        <p>Captain G. B. Byrne’s g.a.h. Emilias, 9.12.</p>
                        <p>Mathews. 0</p>
                        <p>Mr. Lockett's g.a.h. Game Chicken, 10.0. 0</p>
                        <p>Mr. J. W. Simonds' b.a.h. The Bard, 10.7 Whiteside. 0</p>

                        <p>Fitz led from the start, and though challenged by Clown at the corner,
                            was never in difficulties and won well After passing Shewiman, Grand
                            Slam came up well at the finish and was half-a-length behind behind
                            Clown. Won by a length and a half.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 54 on winner and P.T. 21,49, and 49 for places.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>THE GALLOWAY HANDICAP. Value LE 40, 2nd horse to receive L.E.3, if four
                            or more start, and 3rd horse L.E.2, if six or more start, out of the
                            stakes. For Arabe. Distance round the course.</p>
                        <p>Ibraim Bey Cherif's b.a.h. St-Frusquin, 9.12.</p>
                        <p>Clements. 1</p>
                        <p>Ishak Bey Hussein's ch.ah. Farhan II., 11.2.</p>
                        <p>Stillwell. 2</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat’s g.a.h.. Latiff, 10.12.</p>
                        <p>McCall 3</p>
                        <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat’s g.a.h.. Sadik, 11.2. Jenkins. 0</p>
                        <p>Moharrem Pasha's g.b.g. Mizzaud, 11.0. Mr. A.</p>
                        <p>J. Michaelides 0</p>
                        <p>Mr. Tueni's g.a.h.. Petrone, 9.0. Matthews 0 Ibraim Bey Cherif and Elie
                            Bey Sursock’s b.a.c.</p>
                        <p>Mikado 9.3. Elias. 0</p>
                        <p>Mr. E Karam's ch.ah. Eclipse, 10.5. Michaelises 0</p>
                        <p>Ishak Bey Hussein’s b.a.h. Shahrour, 10.8. H. Suleiman. 0</p>
                        <p>Messrs Branch and Mason’s b.a.h. Starboard Light, 10.12. Kamel Effendi.
                            0</p>
                        <p>Messrs. Rees and Barker's g.a.h. 10.6. 0</p>
                        <p>Kamel Eff. Maher's g.a.h.. Social Life, 9.7. Abdallah. 0</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sadik and Latiff got well away at the start, Mikado, who had some
                            support, beginning badly. Mizzaud came up, followed by Farhan II., and
                            St. Frusquin then challenged and led at the corner, Farhan II., Sadik,
                            and Latiff close behind. Sadik could not stay and St. Frusquin,going
                            very strongly down the straight, won by a length, Farhan being nearly
                            the same distance ahead of Latiff.</p>
                        <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 224 on winner and P.T. 56, 37, and 38 for
                            places.</p>
                        <p>On the conclusion of the race the Royal visitors and their suite, who had
                            to leave at 6.45 for the Sudan, drove off escorted by cavalry, the band
                            playing the National Anthem. The Khedive followed, the Khédivial Anthem
                            being played as he drove away, and a most successful day’s racing came
                            to an end.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOOTBALL</head>
                        <p>In consequence of the Military Tournament taking place at Cairo on
                            February 15, the Boulac Railway Institute have decided to play their 5
                            a-side football competition on February 16.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS.</head>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo yesterday by the P.S. "Tewfik" Nile
                        trip—Mr. and Mrs. Max Polter, Baron and Baroness Podesta, Mr. and Mrs. J. N.
                        Palmer, Mr. and Mrs. Geo. F. Volkmann, Mrs. A. Le C. Adams, Mr. and Mrs. E
                        Isakiewicz, Mr. and Mrs. J. D. Taylor, Mrs. Arrigo Fraus, Miss Elizabeth
                        Marcbet, Mrs. Thornton, Mrs. G. V. Benson, Dr. Ludwig and Mrs. Korn, Mr.
                        Felix Field, Sir Edmund Verney, Mr. H. C. W. Verney, Miss Volkmaun, Mr. Pier
                        Francisco Casaretto, Mr. and Mrs. John W. Stewart, Mrs. and Miss Wezermann,
                        Dr. Hugo and Mrs. Hinze, Mr. and Mra Heinrich Biagosch, Miss Sophie
                        Biagosch, Miss Bailey, Mr. J. B. Barker, Mr. Harry Gamble, Mr. John Henry
                        Robinson, Mr, R. Boyle, Mrs. Priester, Mr. Knopf.</p>
                    <p>The following left Kasr-el-Nil yesterday by the S.S. "Victoria” of the
                        Anglo-American Line M. Munier, M. Pureur, Mr. and Mrs. Heidelbach, Mrs. D.
                        C. Blair. Mr. and Mrs. Franklin Sidway, Mr. Ralph H. Sidway. Mr. Hugh
                        Cayley, Mrs. C. B. Paul, Mrs. H. T. Heald, Miss Leila Kerby, Miss Gwendolen
                        Kerby, Miss Lucie Hartrath, Baroness Gray, Hon. Mrs. H. Campbell, Miss Thorn
                        Gray, Mr. and Mrs. Edward L Osgood, Master and the Misses Osgood, Miss Clara
                        Davidson, Rev. E.J. and Mrs. Hardy, Mrs. Elliott and Miss Catherine Russell,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Janos Donnelly, Herr and Fran Lenz, Miss S. P. and Miss T. H.
                        Graham, Jushsrat Felix and Frau Kaufmann, mme. Wolff, Mme. Rosenthal, Herr
                        and Fran Wechaler.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
