<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Courtney Coyle</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">September 19, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-03-29">March 29, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7160] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, MARCH 29, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE WAR</head>
                    <p>ANOTHER JAPANESE ADVANCE</p>
                    <p>LINDEVITCH TO PURSUE FABIAN TACTICS</p>
                    <p>Gutzuling, March 28</p>
                    <p>General Lindevitch is taking measures to cope with the Japanese turning
                        movement.(Havas)</p>
                    <p>Gutzuling,March 28</p>
                    <p>The Japanese are again advancing. They caused the Russian reargaurd to
                        retreat 13 miles to xxx, which is 40 miles to the south of
                        Gutzuling.(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, March 28.</p>
                    <p>It is uderstood that the intention to mobilize on a large scale has been
                        abndoned for the present. Only drafts of sufficient strength to stiffen
                        Linievitch's army will be sent. Te General will pursue Fabian tactics.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE JAPANESE LOAN</head>
                    <p>SCENES IN LONDON</p>
                    <p>New York, MArch 28</p>
                    <p>The bankers state they are receiving many French subscriptions for the
                        American version of the Japanese loan.(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>London,March 28</p>
                    <p>The exterior of the bamks which are issuing the Japanese loan resembles
                        Boxing Day at the theatres. Special police are preserving order. There are
                        long queues of persons outside the banks, the largest being around the Hong
                        Kong and Shanghai office. It is certain that the loan will be heavily
                        oversubscribed.(R)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANGLO-JAPANESE ALLIANCE</head>
                    <p>London, March 28</p>
                    <p>The "Daily Telegraph", in taking up the idea of strengthening the alliance
                        between Britain and Japan, says that the suggetion is receiving general
                        approbation in the City. This will especially be the case if the idea enjoys
                        the moral support of America.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FINLAND</head>
                    <p>SYSTEMATIC CONSTITUTIONAL AGITITATION</p>
                    <p>Helsingfors, March 28.</p>
                    <p>A systematic constitutional agitation has begun in Finland and is spreading
                        considerably. A demonstration at Abo was attended by 20,000 persons. Crowds
                        are parading the streets waving revolutionary flags; bands are playing
                        national airs.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RISING IN CRETE</head>
                    <p>Suda,March 28</p>
                    <p>H.M. cruiser "Lancaster" has arrived here.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHURCH AND STATE IN FRANCE</head>
                    <p>Paris, March 28</p>
                    <p>Five Cardinals have sent M.Loubet a protest in favor of the
                        Concordat.(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW ITALIAN CABINET</head>
                    <p>Rome, March 28</p>
                    <p>The Cabinet has been formed with Signor xxxx as President and Signor Tittoni
                        as minister for Foreign Affairs.(Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RACING</head>
                    <p>LINCOLNSHIRE HANDICAP</p>
                    <p>London, March 28</p>
                    <p>1.Sansovino; 2.Catty Crag; 3.Ranger II. 18 ran. Won by a head,neck dividing
                        second and third. Starting Price Betting: 100 to 9 against Sansovino, 11 to
                        2 against Catty Cray, and 25 to 2 against Ranger II. (R)</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TROUBLES OF RUSSIA</head>
                    <p>THE CRIMEAN DISTURBANCES</p>
                    <p>VIOLEN OUTBREAKS IN CAUCASUS</p>
                    <p>Yalta(Crimea),March 28</p>
                    <p>The disturbances begn here on Sunday evening when the town was ignited in
                        five places. The crowd obstructed the work of extinguishing the themes. All
                        the police stations were wrecked and the prisoners liberated the attempt to
                        sack the municipal treasury wa frustrated. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St Petersburg, March 28</p>
                    <p>Violent outbreaks are occuring in many parts of the Caucasus both in the town
                        and country. The peasants declare that they can only obtain concessions by
                        force, and they are, therefore, attacking the municipal buildings and the
                        country seats of the nobles. The Government is sending troops into the
                        district. There is a marked recrudescence of unrest throughout Russia,
                        apparently in pursuance of a "mot d'ordre." (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Yalta, MArch 28</p>
                    <p>Warships and military reinforcements have arrived here. Order has been
                        restored(R)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the GPO, Alexandria, at 6:30 pm
                        today. The French Ball at Cairo on the 24th ulto. has yielded from 38,000 to
                        40,000 francs. An Assault at Ams will e given in hte Sulle d'Escrime in the
                        Esbekich Gardens on Saturday next. Ministry of Justice- The report of the
                        Judicial Adviser will be presented t the Council of Ministries before the
                        end of the month. The Reunion Des Families Society are giving their last
                        ball of the winter season on Saturday next, April 1. Masks and costumes will
                        be worn. PWD-Mr. AH Perry, Director-General of towns and Buildings, has
                        completed his annual report, which is to be submitted shortly to Sir Wm.
                        Garstin. Aldersons Garden.- On and from Saturday, 8th April, the variety
                        entertainment in Aldersons Garden Theatre will take place every SAturday at
                        5pm instead of Fridays. A Ball will be given in Saturday net at the "Club
                        des Princes", Cairo, under the patronage of Miss Gennadis, on behalf of the
                        Greek language propoganda in Thace. Viennese Choral Society.- The members of
                        this society gave a concert at Abdeen Paalace on Monday evening. Yesterday
                        they made an excursion to Sakkara and are gving a concert in Shepheard's
                        Hotel garden this evening. Egyptian Investment- The London Stock Exchange
                        Committee has ordered the undermentioned security to be quoted in the
                        Offiial List:- Egyptian Investment and Agency, 200,000 shares of 1 each, 5s,
                        paid, Nos.1 to 200,000. Suez Canal.- On the 25th and 26th inst. 34 vessels
                        passed through the Canal, the receipts for the two days being frs.
                        815,022,84. 15 of the ships were British, 2 Italian, 9 Russian, 3 Greek, 5
                        German. The total receipts from the 1st inst. amounted to frs. 9,087,41299.
                        ALM&amp;DS- At the Sailors and Soldiers' Institute last night, a lecture was
                        given under the auspices of the above society b the Rev. Reginald Rynd, BA,
                        on the "The Natural Use of the Voice". A ggrsat deal of valuable information
                        was conveyed by the lecturer as to the proper mode of developing the vocal
                        organs, and his description of the various reasonant organs of the human
                        frame- in themselves very lucidly described-was rendered still more plain by
                        a large diagram of the head and throat, The importance of the proper
                        management of the resonant organs, nd the way in whic to best avoid the
                        hindrances to good singing, presented by the tongue, throatiness, etc., were
                        fully set forth, and at the close of the lecture the appreciation of the
                        audiece as plainly expressed. A vote of thanks to the reverend lectuer was
                        proposed by Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, KCMG, who presided, and was
                        heartily accorded. We hope that Mr.Rynd wll favor he society with many more
                        of these interesting contributons to the proper understanding of music,
                        nothwithstanding the discouragingly small number of members who turned up
                        last night.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TERRIBLE ACCIDENT</head>
                    <p>THREE MEN BURIED ALIVE</p>
                    <p>A terrible accident occurred at Alexandria yesterday afternoon about 5
                        o'clock, by which three men lost their lives. In Stamboul street, just
                        behind Groppi's establishment, building operations are proceeding, and at
                        the time mentioned the foundations of the house being built gave way,
                        burying three native masons in the debris. Towards evening, the dead bodies
                        of two of the men were recovered, while the other remained buried under a
                        mass of earth and stone. From investigations which we have made, it appears
                        that at a depth of four metres these men were engaged in building up the
                        earth i nthe form of an arch. Th carelessness of native workmen is
                        notorious. It seems that in forming the arch they had taken away some earth
                        on the side of the escarpment. This weakened the layer of earth on top and
                        caused the landslip. Under the circumstances the blame for the unfortunate
                        accident must fall on the victims themselves, as no one but they can tell
                        the stability of their position. Had they been simple workmen, the
                        responsibility would lie with the employers, who should have capable
                        overseers.</p>
                    <p>AL AZHAR UNIVERSITY</p>
                    <p>The third uhma of the Al Ahzar University, Sheikh Ahmed el Hanbali, has
                        resigned his seat in the council of directors of the University. Two sheikhs
                        only remain, Sheikh Hassanein El Boulaki and Sheikh Hassanein El Edoui. We
                        hear on good authority that candidates for cadi hip will near future, after
                        passing an examination at Al Azhar at an early period of their studies
                        there, go through a special course of training which will be entirely
                        independent of the ancient university</p>
                    <p>UPPER EGYPT HOTELS COMPANY</p>
                    <p>Referring to the announcement which appeared in our columns yesterday, we are
                        informed that the Savoy Hotel, Assouan, will not now be included in the
                        above company, as stated, owing to the fact that the necessary arrangements
                        have not been concluded with the Anglo-American Company. The capital of the
                        new company is 220,000, in shares of 4 each, snd 100,000 in 5% first
                        mortgage debentures. The directors will be Mr. AE Harrison, general manager
                        of Messrs. Thos. Cook &amp; Son, (Egypt), Ltd, George Nungovich Bey, Mr.
                        Charles Baehler, and Mr. Pagnon.</p>
                    <p>STATE OPERA</p>
                    <p>We hear that a petition is circulating among the abonnes of the Khedival
                        Opera House (and obtaining numerous signatures), copies of which will be
                        addressed to the Minister of Public Works and to Lord Cromer, Mr Vincent
                        Corbett and Sir William Gastin. The petitiondeals with the decision of the
                        Socitete Artistique to bring an Italian company over in the season
                        1905-1906, in spite of the decision taken some time ago, and aproved by the
                        Government, to bring French companies over in alternate years. The
                        signatories of the petition complain of this breach of the regulations
                        pointing out that the arrangement previously made enabled good new operas
                        (which by the concession must be produced to the number of four a year) to
                        be brought before the Cairo public. They disclaim all nationalist bias and
                        assert that the plea of the societe Artistique, viz, that a good French
                        company cannot be procured, is utterly untenable. They therefore beg the
                        Minister of Public Works to intervene on behalf of the Government and the
                        public. In our opinion the best way out of the difficulty would be to revoke
                        the concession as soon as possible, and hand over the entire business to a
                        good impressario.. The proverb "Too many cooks" is alarmingly true in Egypt. </p>
                    <p>CAIRO ZOOLOGICAL GARDENS</p>
                    <p>Many additions have been made to the menagerie in these gsrdens during the
                        last two months, and one of the prettiest sights now to be seen near Cairo
                        is that of the young gazelles and ibex, of which more than a dozen have
                        recently been born at Ghizeh, playing and frisking about with their mothers
                        in the large paddock which occupies the site of the ruins of the old palace.
                        The births thi spring also include an Arui wild sheep and two Hedjaz sheep,
                        and among the birds, besides numerosu doves of various kinds, two
                        buff-backed egrets have been hatched and reared. Seventeen animals have been
                        presented: an Egyptian weasel by Mrs. Colville, a hawk-eagle by Mr. H.
                        Raczinski of Alexandria, a Nilotic waran-lizard from Luxor by Prof. Dr. G.
                        Schweinfurth, a ring-necked parakeet by Mrs.Bazil, three slender lorises by
                        Mr. J.A. Tarrell, a jungle cat by Mr.AE Branch, seven trumpeter bullfinches
                        and a spotted cuckoo by Mr. GH Malcolm, an a greyheaded love-bird by Mr. S.
                        Hanauer. The purchases during the same period include a yellow baboon, avery
                        larg bonnet-monkey, a white nosed red monkey, some lemurs, two species of
                        wild cat, a Loder's gazelle from the Fayoum, a mouse deer from India,
                        several pretty species of birds not previously represented in the
                        collection, as the lavender finch of Tropical Africa and the Pein
                        nightingale, also two Mina birds, and finally an Algerian tortoise. </p>
                    <p>By the kind permission of the Inspector General of Prisons, the band of the
                        Ghieh Boys' School will play on Friday afternoons in the gardens throughout
                        this year.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SIRDAR AT SUAKIN</head>
                    <p>RECEPTOON BY INHABITANTS</p>
                    <p>(from our Correspondent)</p>
                    <p>Suakin, March 16</p>
                    <p>During his recent visit to Suakin, the Sirdar distributed several robes and
                        other valuable gifts, such as medal dresses, watches, revolvers, knives, and
                        shaving articles, to a large number of sheikhs of tribes, clergy, and
                        faithful guides and attenants for their loyal services these few years to
                        the Government. After this ceremony was over he delivered an eloquent
                        address in English which lasted 45 minutes, and which was then interpreted
                        into Arabic by his Arabic secretar, Shaheen Bey, and afterwards again
                        interpreted into Hadendow by the Commandant of Police, Mohamed Bey
                        Ahmed.</p>
                    <p>In the evening his Excellency was entertained at dinner at the Moudirieh.
                        Afterwards a reception was held, when Saghcolaghassi Aly Effendy
                        Ahmed,Deputy-Inspector of Suakin Moudirieh, addressed his excellency the
                        Sirdar in English as follows: "Your Excellency,-I have been chosen by the
                        Egyptian officers, officials and employes of the Government of Suakin to
                        stand respectfully before your Excellency and to express their happiness on
                        your visit to this province and town. All the people of whatever station,
                        the richest and the poorest, the highest and the lowest, have taken this
                        oppurtunity to welcome you by their shouts and respond to the consideration
                        and goodwill you have ever shown to all. All whom you find around you are
                        anxious to assure you of their warm feelings and pleasure. The whole Sudan
                        recognises and is grateful for the wise and good administration of the
                        coutnry. The whole Sudan recognises and is ggrateful for the manner in which
                        the happiness and well-being of all classes are considered. Not only the
                        whole Sudan, but the whole world recognises the spledid way in which the
                        country has thriven during the years which you have been Sirdar and Governor
                        General of the Sudan, and wonders at the magnificent manner in which the
                        resources of the coutnry are being developed. It is true that during this
                        period all departments of the GOvernment have accomplished much, but in this
                        province we watch perhaps more keenly than others, the miles of railway
                        which are joining the Nile and Red Sea, and the plans for the development of
                        the ports of the Sudan. We know that all that has been the result of your
                        master spirit and encouragement. I am not able to express all that is on my
                        mind, but specially we would thank your Excellency for the honor of your
                        visit to us this evening, and in this way showing that you have a warm heart
                        and kind feelings for all those serving the Government of this country. I
                        ask all who are present to drink the health of his Excellency the Sirdar of
                        the Egyptian Army and the Governor-General of the Sudan, El Ferik Sir
                        Francis Reginald Wingate Pasha." The following congratulatory order was
                        published after the Sirdar's departure:-El Miralai Howard Bey, Mr. Kerr, and
                        the military officers and officials of the Egyptian Army and Sudan
                        Government for their admirable arrangements for his recetion, and for their
                        good and hard work to which the very marked improvement in the condition and
                        progress of the town and province since his last inspection in 1901 is due.
                        "He was much struck with the smartness and turn out of the guard of honor
                        furnished by the 3rd Battalion, and the excelence of the organisation and
                        the careful arrangements made for the treatment of the sick in the military
                        and civil hospitals. The interest taken in education as evinced by the
                        satisfactory state of the school and scholars, was most marked. He also
                        wishes you to convey to El Miralai Macauley Bey his great appreciation of
                        the hard and valuable work done by him and his staff on the new Railway, of
                        which the substantial progress already made is the best testimony. In
                        conclusion he would like to express to you, your officers and officials, and
                        to all classes of people of Suakin, his cordial thanks for the loyal and
                        hearty reception on his arrival and hospitatlity extended to him during his
                        stay." (Signed): LO Stack, Kaimakam, Mil. and Private Secretary.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN ARMY</p>
                    <p>The following officers have been promoted to the rank of Miralai:- Kaimakams
                        H Matchett Bey, L. Stanton Bey, R Griffith Bay, W Persse Bey, C Blunt Bey,
                        R. Griffith Bey, G. Maucalay Bey, and L Satck Bey. Miralai GP Hunter Bey,
                        DSO., has been appointed Principal Medical Officer of the Egyptian Army.</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Tabor" arrived at Liverpool yesterday morning. The SS
                        "Grecian Prince", from Manchester, left Malta on Monday and is due here on
                        Friday next, with passengers and general cargo. The SS Crypian Prince, from
                        Antwerp, left London on Monday last, with passengers and general cargo for
                        Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                    <cb n="5"/>
                    <p>CANON DAVIS MEMORIAL</p>
                    <p>DEDICATION SERVICE</p>
                    <p>The short service held by the Bishop in Jerusalem and the East at 4:45pm on
                        Monday in St. Mark's Church was quite private. It had not been possible to
                        fix the exact hour until the day before, too late t announce it in the
                        "Gazette". The Bishop, who was attended by his acting chaplain, the Rev.
                        Canon Ward, inserted the following special prayers in a shortened form of
                        evening service. "In the faith of Jesus Christ we dedicate this memorial
                        stone, now handed over to the charge of the chaplain and the trustees of St.
                        Marks Church, to the peretual memory of the Csnon Edwin John Davis, MA i
                        nthe church in which he s long ministered. May those who worship here, and
                        face his effigy as they go out from this House of God into the world, hear
                        in memory the example of one of whose loving and charitable labours for the
                        good of Christ's poor, should stimulate the spirit of charity in others; and
                        whose watchful care of the interests of this foundation of St. Mark's has
                        left to his successors great possibilities for happy influence in the
                        chaplaincy which he served for so long a time. "Assist us mercifully, O
                        Lord, in these our supplications and prayers, and in this our act of thy
                        servants towards the attainment of everlasting salvation, that among all the
                        changes and chances of this mortal life we may ever be defended by Thy most
                        gracious and ready help; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen"</p>
                    <p>PROVINCIAL CHURCH SERVICES</p>
                    <p>TANTAH</p>
                    <p>MANSOURAH</p>
                    <p>At Mansourah the services will be as follows:- April 2, evensong, 6pm; April
                        9, Litany and HC, 11 am; April 16, evensong, 6pm. Note- Collections on the
                        last Sunday at both chuches (1st after Easter) will be devoted to the SPG.
                        All other offertories and collectioms go to the Delta Itinerating Chaplaincy
                        Fund. J. David C. Firminger, SPG Chaplain </p>
                    <p>LA DELEGATION MUNICIPALE</p>
                    <p>La Delegation Municipale s'est reunie le 28 mars 1905 a 4h. pm sous la
                        presidence de M. Amb. A. Ralli. La Delegation arrete parmi le programme des
                        routes a faire cette annee. Les devis at cahier des charges devront etre
                        presentes au fur et a mesure au College pour la mise en adjucation. Elle
                        adjuge a M. Degiarde la furniture de 60 bancs et 40 chaises pour le jardin
                        Nousha; la route de Ramleh, a M Erriques; enfin la fourniture de balais et
                        couffins, a MM Abdel Rahim Hekel et a M Stamatepoulo. Les offres presentes
                        pour la demolition d'une maison, rue Sinadino, n'ayant pas para
                        satisfaisantes, la Delegation decide de refaire une nouvelle adjucation pour
                        ce travail. La Delegation renvoie au sujet de la construction de la conduite
                        de raccordement pour le deversement des eaux de lavage des nouveaux filtres.
                        Elle proposera a la Commission l'overture d'un credit supplementaire de LE
                        600 pour le jardin Nouzhe. La seance est le ee a 8h. pm.</p>
                    <p>CHRONIQUE THEATRALE</p>
                    <p>THEATRE ZIZINIA</p>
                    <p>NOTRE JEUNESSE</p>
                    <p>Avec la representation de Notre Jeunesse, la compagnie Coquelin Cadet a pu
                        enregistrar une de see crations, et M. Jean Coquelin s'y est autant
                        distingue dans le role de Lucien Briant qu'avanthier dans celui du marquis
                        de La Seigliere Quant a Mme Moreno, elle a su rendre a la perfection deux ou
                        trois soenes pathetiques qui lui ont valune ovation. Nous devons encore une
                        mention particuliere a Mme Bouchetal et a l'heureuse interprete du role de
                        Luoienne Briant qui ont ete toutes deux justement remarquees. M. Coquelin
                        Cadet a termine la representation par trois monologues qu'il a debite d'uue
                        facon exquise. Ce soir Lee Romanesques, comedie en trois actes de M. Edmond
                        Rostand, et L'Ete de la Sanit Martin, comedie en un acte de MM. Meilhac et
                        Halevy. </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Major General Sir Ronald Lane and Lieutenant General Sir Thomas Kelly Kenny,
                        who have respectively held the positions of Military Secretary and Adjucant
                        General to the British Army, are leaving Egypt on Monday next by the Bibby
                        SS Staffordshire from Port Said Sir Ronald Line is staying with Mr. Gould
                        until tomorrow when he returns for a few days to Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday Sir Ronald paid a visit to Victoria College in company with Mr.
                        Gould and was very much pleased with this institution.</p>
                    <p>The "Journal du Cairo" remarks:- On donne comme probable la nomination de M.
                        Sheldon Amos, juge au Tribunal indigene de re instance du Caire, comme
                        conseiller a la Cour d'appel indigene en remplacement de M. Coghlan.</p>
                    <p>The Italian man of war "Liguria" is expected to arrive at Alexandria shortly
                        with the Duke of the Abruzzi, who is on his way home after a voyage round
                        the world.</p>
                    <p>It is not generally known that the credit for the suggestion of England's
                        purchase of the "St. James Gazette", whose 75th birthday is to be celebrated
                        by a banquet in London. When an oppurtunity offered of buying the Suez Canal
                        shares which now form so important a national asset, it was Mr. Greenwood
                        who suggested the purchase to Disareli. Disareli jumped at it, and the thing
                        was done. The statesman got the kudos, but to the journalist belongs the
                        credit.</p>
                    <p>Egypt has been from the beginning the background for a career of much
                        distinction in the case of Captain Colin Keppel, who has been recently
                        appointed to succeed Sir A Milne in command of His Majesty's yachts. During
                        the attempt to relieve General Gordon, in the subsequent rescue of Sir C.
                        Wilson under Lord Charles Beresford, on the Nile in 1898, when he commanded
                        the flotilla, and at the CB, Captain Keppel won unqualified praise for his
                        ability and courage. As a midshipman be participated in the bombbardment of
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Mr JIR Dempster, whose sudden death we annonced yesterday, was chief engineer
                        of the New Egyptian Compsnys Nile reclamation works.</p>
                    <p>Mr.ALP Weigall has been appointed inspector to the Antiques Service at an
                        annual salary of LE 400.</p>
                    <p>The Rev. Alf. A. Cooper, MA, of the British and Foreign Bible Society, is
                        expected back in Alexandria on the 1st prox. Mr. Cooper travels by way of
                        Berlin, Vienna, and Constantinople. </p>
                    <p>The following officers have been granted leave of absence on private
                        affairs:- Capt. S.J.Somerville and 2nd Lieut.CEG Varnon, 2nd Royal
                        Inniskiling Fusiliers; Liet Col. Berks. Regt., Capt.GB Byrne and 2nd Lieut
                        RSW Walpole, 2nd Rifle Brigade; Liet. TC Cunningham, AOD. Major EJ Lawson,
                        AVD.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
