<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-11">December 11, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-08">September 8, 2016</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7288] ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 8, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, SEPTERMBER 8. 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIA AND JAPAN. LAST DEFEAT OF RUSSIANS. SERIOUS RIOTS IN TOKIO. CHRISTIAN CHURCHES DESTROYED.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The Japanese defeated the Russians in a series of sharp engagements in
                        North-Eastern Korea on the 1st instant The remnant of the Russians in
                        Saghalien were crushed at Naibnti on the west coast of the island on the
                        30th August. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Tokio, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The resentment in Japan regarding the treaty is unquestionably very strong.
                        Certain newspapers and a party of politicians are condemning the humiliation
                        and the inade-quacy of the safeguards for future peace, but the strong
                        conservative element urges the folly of continuing the war for the sake of
                        money, when the chief objects have been obtained.</p>
                    <p>The mob burned and destroyed 10 Christian churches and one mission house and
                        school during the night of the 6th inst.</p>
                    <p>The rioting here continued throughout Tuesday. The mob attacked and burned
                        the Home Minister’s residence, despite the stre-nuous resistance of the
                        police. They destroyed large and 15 small police stations. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Tokio, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The rioting ceased at midnight on Tuesday, it is estimated that 2 persons
                        have been killed and 500 wounded. Some police stations have been destroyed
                        daring the night. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>St. Petehsburg, September 7.</p>
                    <p>It is authoritatively stated that no secret arrangement whatever exists with
                        Japan. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAUCASUS RIOTS. HEAVY CASUALTIES. PRECAUTIONS FOR PROTECTION OF BRITISH.</head>
                    <p>Baku, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The condition of this district is frightful. 1,000 milltowers, besides a
                        whole quarter of the own, are on fire. Fierce fighting continues, he troops
                        yesterday employed artillery in order to quell the attack on the Governor’s
                        headquarters. The naphtha famine is mining any trades.</p>
                    <p>The situation in the Caucasus is continually becoming more alarming. Hundreds
                        of shots ave been fired by the infantry and artillery. At Balakhany 1,000
                        persons were killed and wounded daring a desperate attack on the military
                        camp and provision depots. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 7. </p>
                    <p>The Hon. C. Hardinge, British Ambassador here, has sent an urgent note to
                        Count Hasmsdorf, and has also telegraphed to the viceroy of the Caucasus,
                        requesting protection for British lives and property. (Reuter}</p>
                    <p>Baku, September 7.</p>
                    <p>All the naphtha works have been set fire to. thousand people have been killed
                        or wound-ed in a fight with the troops. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN IMPERIAL UKASE. NEBOGATOFF DEGRADED.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 7. </p>
                    <p>An Ukase dismisses and degrades Admiral nebogatoff. The Captains of the
                        battleships emperor Nicholas I., Admiral Apraxin, and Admiral Seniavin, who
                        are liable to the penal and other officers, including those of the will be
                        tried on their return to Russia. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOROCCO APOLOGISES. ACCEDES TO ALL DEMANDS.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 7.</p>
                    <p>Morocco has acceded to all the French demands, and publicly apologised.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Tangier, September 7. </p>
                    <p>France has obtained complete satisfaction after the arrest of the Algerian
                        chief, Boum-in and full apologies. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROSEN ARRIVES IN PARI8.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 7.</p>
                    <p>M. Rosen, German Minister at Tangier, has arrived. He will confer with M.
                        Rouvier. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EAST AFRICAN RISING. MASASI AND MIKINDANI RAIDED.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The rebels in German East Africa have decided and destroyed Masasi and
                        Mikindani. The British missionaries escaped. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SHAH’S DEPARTURE.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 7.</p>
                    <p>The Shah has left. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL,</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Anniversary</head>
                        <p>To day is the four hundred and fortieth anniversary of the repulse of the
                            last great assault on Malta made by the Turks.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and OWNERLESS Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Esbekieh district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at
                            dawn of the 10th inst. will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Smuggler Arrested</head>
                        <p>A greek subject named Yanni Vassilia was arrested today while trying to
                            pass through the Customs gates with seven torbas of hashish in his
                            possession.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Affray</head>
                        <p>A native coffee house keeper of the Karmous quarter yesterday kick-ed a
                            Berberin lad named Hanafi Ibrahim in the abdomen causing his death. The
                            police have since arrested the culprit who has confessed bis guilt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Recent Suicide</head>
                        <p>The unfortunate girl whose suicide we announced yesterday proves to have
                            been a maid servant employed by European family named Gorgia living in
                            Gordon Pasha street. The girl had only arrived from Cairo a month
                            ago.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Railway Accident</head>
                        <p>The death of a European is reported from Defra. It appears that the
                            deceased, who is believed to be an Italian, attempted to jump on to a
                            moving train and fell under the wheels. His body was literally cut to
                            pieces. The remains have been taken to Tantah.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Watch Stolen</head>
                        <p>This morning a native named Shaban Shahuta stoie a gold watch from the
                            cabin of E. Johnson, the carpenter of the British S.S. Yorkmoor and
                            escaped with his booty. Orders have been given to the secret police to
                            make every effort to discover the thief’s whereabouts.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fayoum Light Railways</head>
                        <p>The receipts of of the Fayoum Lights Railways Co. for the last ten days
                            of August amount to L.E. 656.999 against L.E. 596.539 during the
                            corresponding period last year. For the whole month the total receipts
                            are L.E. 1,945.144, showing an increase of L.E. 180.329 over the
                            receipts of August, 1904.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Notable Robbed</head>
                        <p>Hassan Bey ol Harmil a notable of Mahelet Marhoum, Tanta Mariksz, woke up
                            yesterday morning in the Montazeh Hotel, Alexandria to find that his
                            purse containing £35 had disappeared. He promptly informed the Menshieh
                            caracol, and on an inquiry being made it proved that one of the hotel
                            servants had disappeared at the same time as the money. A telegram has
                            been sent to Cairo by the caracol giving his description and asking the
                            authorities to search for him.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Esbekieh Theatre</head>
                        <p>The Gardet comedy and operetta troupe gave their first per-formance at
                            the theatre of the Esbekieh gardens last night. The principal pieoe
                            staged was Le Surtis, an exceedingly humorous vaudeville, and presented,
                            we believe, for the first time in Cairo. A fairly large audience
                            assisted, and the play met with much langhter and applause. The short
                            operetta, La Rose de St. Flour, was also given and was very well
                            received. Mlle Smyiane Val immediately established herself as a
                            favorite, and M. Millet and M. Laurent Roland greatly delighted the
                            audience with their singing and acting alike.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of
                            the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with
                            the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services
                            of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring
                            information on trade matters generally, including the question of
                            appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is
                            obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become
                            members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription
                            is merely the nominal one of £l. The latter payment also includes a copy
                            of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain
                            further particulars from our London office, 36, New Broad-street, which
                            acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>H.H. Prince Mohamed All is expected to to return to Cairo in the near
                        future.</p>
                    <p>H.H.- Princess Hussein Kamel and suite have arrived from Constantinople.</p>
                    <p>The Sirdar and Sir R. von. Slatin Pasha are expected to retorn to Cairo
                        towards the end of the month.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that Count A. de Zogheb, diplomatic agent and consul general
                        for Danmark in Egypt has completely recovered from the slight injuries which
                        he sustained in his recent motor accident.</p>
                    <p>Maltre Carton de Wiart is expected to retorn to Egypt towards the end of next
                        week.</p>
                    <p>The Sultan bas conferred the title of Sakieh on Saleh Bey Selim, the wakil of
                        the Sherif of Mecca at Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <head>A NEW MANSION</head>
                    <p>"Al-Ahram" states that H.H. The Khedive has bought and furnished a large and
                        beautiful house at Divonne, and will use the new residence as a palace
                        daring bis yearly visits to his favorite summer resort. The house, which
                        commands a wide view of the town and the surrounding country, is to be
                        enlarged and made in every way a fitting residence for the ruler of
                        Egypt</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SULTAN OF MOROCCO.</head>
                    <p>Early this week the latest Egyptian mission to the Sultan of Morocco left
                        Egypt for Gibraltar and Fez. The personnel of this mission has been
                        carefully selected by Moha-med el Helon, the Sultan's agent in Egypt, and
                        oonsists of two celebrated dancing girls named Badia and Zeinab, with two
                        less distinguished but accomplished under-studies and three native
                        musicians. The dancing girls are engaged for four months at L.E. 80 per
                        month, with all their travelling expenses paid. Such is the first use made
                        by his Sherifian Majesty of the loan so obligingly provided by the thrifty
                        Teuton at the ridiculously low rate of one per cent.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO HOTELS.</head>
                    <p>The large and handsome row of new shops and offices that the management of
                        Shep-heard’s Hotel have had erected in the place of the old ones in Sharia
                        Kamel are now completed, and are certainly a great ornament to that part of
                        the street. The facade of the new premises has been brought three metres
                        forward on the broad pavement in front of that part of the hotel. The roofs
                        of the new row have been so built that they will serve as balconies or
                        promenades to the occupants of the rooms above them. The work was only began
                        on the 1st July, and has thus been finished in an incredibly short time for
                        this country.</p>
                    <p>At the Continental many improvements and additions have been carried out
                        daring the past three months, the most important being the erection of a
                        Largo electric lift which will accommodate eight or ten persons, and the
                        enlargement of the hall next to the bar and billiard room, where the evening
                        concerts, so much appreciated daring the winter, take place. Mr. Klingler,
                        the manager, will return from Europe in the first week of next month, when
                        Mr. Braun will take a short holiday previous to taking up the management of
                        the Hotel d’Angleterre in November.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COMING SEASON.</head>
                    <p>Judging from present appearances the com-ing winter season promisee to be
                        quite as brilliant, if not more so, than its predecessor, which was a record
                        one. Already applications for rooms are being received by each mail and both
                        Mena House and the Hotel d’An-gleterre will re-open in November. In Cairo
                        two new hotels, the National and the Khedivial, are also opening their doors
                        for the first time, so that there will not be the same crash this winter, as
                        was experienced the last, when numbers of tourists were kept up the Nile for
                        weeks for want of accommodation. From New York the news comes to the
                        Anglo-American Nile Steamer Co., that it is expected that the number of
                        American visitors to Egypt next winter will be greater than that of any
                        previous season. Even at this early date thousands of tourists from all
                        parts of the United States have made arrangements for the journey. Clark’s
                        famous cruises, inaugurated four or five years ago, have already been
                        organised for the coming winter and most of the berths have already been
                        booked for the first trip of the well-known ocean leviathan Arabic, one of
                        the steamers chartered for the annual cruises to the Mediterranean and Egypt
                        The river steamer Viotoria, of the Anglo-American line, has already been
                        engaged to run between Cairo, Luxor, and Assouan in connection with the
                        above cruises. The above should prove good news to the hotel proprietors and
                        many others in the capital who profit so largely from the ever-increasing
                        tourist traffic from Europe and America.</p>
                    <p>A local contemporary has, however, been drawing upon bis imagination, in
                        stating, two or three days back that in consequences of the unusually heavy
                        demand upon the passenger accommodation of the P. &amp; O. and
                        Orient-Pacific liners daring the winter months caused, by bookings for Egypt
                        and India in connection with the forthcoming royal visit to the latter
                        country, both these companies were going to doable their sailings from next
                        month. Neither the P. &amp; O. agents nor Messrs. Thos. Cook &amp; Son have
                        received advice of any such intention.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The following is the menu to be given on the occasion of the night fete
                        to-morrow.</p>
                    <p>Consomme de volallle glace Dorer de. roche e urdolse Quartler d'aloy au a la
                        Strabourgeolse Pilaff de. callles de chase Glace Hatavais Fruits..
                        Desserts.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Khedivial express mail steamship Ismailia will leave Alexandria at 4 p.m.
                        on Wednesday next for Pirens, Smyrna, Mitylens and Constantinople.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES SITUATION. APPLICATION TO MIXED COURTS.</head>
                    <p>The Hon. A. J. Davey, who is acting at present as general manager of the
                        Societe des Snoreries et de la Raffinerie d’Egypte, and is being granted
                        special powers by the meeting of the board of administration held at Paris
                        on the 30th ult. has handed to the commercial registrar of the Cairo Mixed
                        Court of First Instance a declaration of the suspension of payments. The
                        Commercial Chamber of the Coart will meet on Saturday, the 19th inst, under
                        the presidency of Judge Tuck and will have to decide whether the company
                        will be entitled or not to the benefit of the "concordat preventif"</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KASR EL ALY PROPERTY.</head>
                    <p>A correspondent writes:— The history of this property is an interesting and
                        forcible illustration of the almost phenomenal rise in the price of land for
                        building purposes that has been going on in the best parts of Cairo within
                        the past year or two. The Kasr el Aly property formerly belonged to the
                        mother of the Khedive Ismail and consists of 200,000 square metres of land,
                        having frontages on the river and the fine road leading to the Kasr-el-Aini
                        hospital and Old Cairo, and is situated in close proximity to
                        Kasr-el-Donbara, the most aristocratic quarter of the city. Some five years
                        ago a group of American financiers were in treaty, through the Bank of
                        Egypt, for the purchase of the estate at £85,000, but on hearing of it
                        Prince Ahmed Kamel got a relative to exercise his right of pre-emption, and
                        the Tribunals having found the claim valid, the property was bought by the
                        Prince at the above figure. Two years ago a Belgian syndicate made an offer
                        of £150,000, which was refused, the owner asking only £10,000 more, which
                        the syndicate declined to give. Now the property is in the market once more,
                        the enormous sum of £400,000, or £2 per square metre, being demanded. The
                        estate will no doubt gain by the erection of the new Nile bridges from Old
                        Cairo to Rodah Island and Ghizeh and, compared with the prices some lots are
                        fetching in the vicinity, even this sum does not seem exorbitant, for
                        suitable building sites in the favorite localities are becoming rarer every
                        day, in consequence of the extraordinary extension the metropolis is taking
                        in the westward direction.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BOULEVARD ABBAS.</head>
                    <p>The new boulevard that is to run the whole length from Kasr-el-Nil to Gamrah
                        Bridge, a distance of about three kilometres, will be one of the finest
                        drives in Cairo when completed, and will cost £25,000. The work, which was
                        begun in April has been finished as far as Pont Limoun station and the other
                        and more important part will be commenced in November, when several of the
                        clubs established on the right bank of the canal will be pulled down and
                        removed to the left bank, the British Recreation Club being the last to go.
                        From the new museum to the railway station, the boulevard will have a width
                        of no lees than 120 metres, and there will be on the left side separate
                        tracks for cyclists, carriages, and pedestrians, and a garden, whilst the
                        portion from Pont Limoun to Gamrah bridge will be narrower, so as to provide
                        room for the new electric railway that is to join the Abbasaieh Oasis with
                        the city, and which will termina'e at the Daira Khassa buildings in the
                        Avenue Bonlao.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ CANAL APPOINTMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Administration Beard of the Suez Canal Company met on the 1st inst. to
                        elect a vice-president and two directors, the former official to replace the
                        late M. Henri Boncard. M. Casimir Perier, formerly President of the French
                        Republic, was elected Vice President, the directorships going to
                        Vioe-Admiral Hu-mann and M. Stephane Derville.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A REPLY.</head>
                    <p>In enference to our correspondent C. A.’s letter, which we published in our
                        issue of the 6th inst, we are requested to state that the remarks therein
                        contained are incorrect, that C. A’s telegraphic application for a reserved
                        2nd class compartment on the 7-9 a.m. train only arrived five minutes before
                        the departure of the train in question, and that such applica-tions mast be
                        made at least an hoar before the train leaves. Secondly, that the statement
                        that the Alexandria station authorities wired back confirming the
                        reservation of a compartment is not correct, and thirdly, in answer to the
                        statement that no compartment was reserved for ladies on the 3.45 train on
                        the 6th inst., that a whole carriage was reserved for Sidi Gabor where an
                        empty ladies compartment might have been found by the author of the letter
                        with little difficulty, had he troubled to look about him or addressed
                        himself to the proper authorities at Sidi Gaber station.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OBITUARY.</head>
                    <p>CAPTAIN REES.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death of Captain E T. Rees, formerly in the
                        merchant service, and at the time of his death in charge of the Kom el
                        Nadoura signal station. The deceased, who had only been ill for three days
                        succumbed last night to an attack of heart disease at the Government
                        hospital. The funeral will take place this afternoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SULTANS’ ACCESSION. CELEBRATIONS AT BEYROUT.</head>
                    <p>An Egyptian eye-witness gives us the following interesting description of the
                        fetes held at Beyrout in honor of the anniversary of the Sultans’ accession
                        : - This morning Beyrout emerged in festive attire to celebrate the
                        anniversary of its Sovereign's accession to the throne. Everywhere in the
                        highways and even in the narrow bazaars of the old town you could see
                        childish, unpretentious attempts at decoration, in the form of primitive
                        triumphal arches, and festoons of flowers and verdure, palm and laurel
                        branches, and whole pine-trees stuck into the ground along the roads,
                        while,crowning all this, waved the Turkish flag with the Crescent and the
                        Star staring out of the background of blood-red. Apart from the
                        illuminations at night and the usual abundant flying of flags, there was no
                        offical display properly so-called, and it is perhaps this that brought out
                        into stronger relief the charming and simple spontaneity of the town’s
                        festive expression of joy. The gaiety of the populace is very shallow and
                        very easy to stir. I have seen this fete celebrated in Beyrout several
                        times, and what used to mar the beauty of it was the insolent arrogance of
                        the teeming crowds of the lower Moslem classes in the streets and the
                        squares. This year the feeling did not seem to me to exist, with the odious
                        obtrusiveness of former times. Is a sane spirit of brotherhood at last
                        developing between Christians and Moslems : If I am no visionary, and this
                        spirit does now exist even though in a germinal form, a great measure of
                        credit is, I think, due to the present Vali. On the whole he exercises an
                        influence for good. He shows the spirit of benevolence on his face, but he
                        has also shown it in his acts, by the way in which he has been stamping out
                        the spirit of fanatical intolerance and savagery of the mob. I will give an
                        instance. But lately two Christians were fighting with each other, when a
                        Moslem riding by recognized in one of the youths an old acquaintance of his,
                        and, prompted by friendly feelings, dismounted to part the hot-headed
                        fighters. But these were so obstinate that he had to use a little violence
                        to separate them, when the ungrateful youth, in whose interest the Moslem
                        had intervened, —at least this is the Moslem version-turned round and dealt
                        the latter a few fatal stabs. This immediately determined a demonstration on
                        the part of the Moslem rabble, who gathered in reckless bands bent on
                        vio-lence. The scene of the murder was the jewellers’ bazaar, and fearing,
                        as on former occasions, the failure of the force of the law, the jewellers
                        immediately closed their shops. But this fanatical outbreak was forthwith
                        quelled, thanks to the energetic and timely measures taken by the Vali. On
                        the succeeding nights clandestine attempts at vengeance were made by some
                        bad spirits, and one of the notables of the town, while driving with his
                        wife at night along the barracks thoroughfare was shot at several times, by
                        a man armed with a revolver but happily without effect From that oft-trodden
                        highway, the barrack road two steep, crooked, and dark lanes lead down to
                        the bazaar that bisects the old town from north to south, and these dark
                        lanes have always served as hiding places and safe retreats for nocturnal
                        miscreants, besides being very convenient short outs for the inhabitants of
                        the neighbourhood, which is exclusively Moslem. Well, the Vali with
                        admirable cour-age had both these issues of crime blocked up by walls of
                        masonry. One wall has since been palled down, bat the credit for the
                        initiation of such a fearless act on the part of the Vali remains, and if
                        measures prompted by an enlightened and equitable spirit are carried out,
                        but not maintained it is because this is unfortunately in the order of
                        things in Turkey. Was it not also due to the enlightened spirit and sincere
                        concern in the town’s welfare on the part of the Governor, that the
                        arrangement was finally made between the Municipality and the Beyrout Water
                        Company. The latter now undertakes the watering of the streets, and does the
                        work with English thoroughness and punctuality. The work is of course, still
                        susceptible of much improvement, but, as the director has remarked, unless
                        the municipality be prepared to pay for a high standard of efficient work,
                        matters will be maintained at the present mediocre state. As it is however,
                        the service done to sanitation is very great The people of Beyrout now
                        breathe air instead of air and dust, and as one remarked “the days of Just
                        are happily over for Beyrout."</p>
                    <p>This is a long digression, and I must now return to the fete. The Vali
                        received in the vast reception hall of the Seraglio between tad 10 am., all
                        the military, civil and ecclesiatical dignitaries, as well as the members of
                        the different consular corps, and the affability and easy grace with which
                        he per-formed the function was admirable. The Commandant of the barracks and
                        the Mushir of Damascus, who happened to be here on the day of the fete,
                        received in state, at the same time, at the reception hall of the barracks.
                        At the Seraglio, the military hand played martial airs and waltzes all the
                        while, adding a note of gaiety to the festive occasion. At about a Quarter
                        to ten in the morning the Vali re-paired to the barrack, to return the
                        congratulations of the Commandant and dignitaries, and by all the high the
                        spot where founded in com-memoration municipal hospital anniversary. The
                        memoration of the laying of foundation a very solemn one, and was attend-ed
                        by a very distinguished crowd, including the different consular corps. After
                        refreshments were served—and they were very welcome at that hour of the day,
                        rendered doubly hot by the glare of the burning sand that stretched
                        inimitably away on three sides—and the performance of the traditional
                        ceremony of the immolation of sheep and the distribution of their flesh to
                        the poor, followed by invocation for the preservation of the sacred person
                        of his august Majesty, the Vali stood up, and on the foundation stone gave
                        the three traditional hammer- beats, when a huge huzza from the crowd burst
                        out accompanied by the loud notes of the band.</p>
                    <p>At the barracks during the reception an aged officer entered, and, after a
                        humble salaam, tendered the Mushir Hakki Pasha an imposing looking document,
                        which the Mushir reverently kissed and touched his forehead therewith, in
                        token of extreme respect and gratitude, and then delivered it back to the
                        grey-bearded officer. The document apparently contained an announcement of
                        the Saltan’s pleasure in conferring further honors on a distinguished and
                        loyal servant of the throne, possibly by the promotion of his grade.</p>
                    <p>At the further end of the hall at the barracks stands a lifesized portrait of
                        the German Emperor in imperial costume and full insignia, said to have been
                        presented by his Majesty on the occasion of his last visit to Syria. At both
                        receptions one could not help noticing the marked attention and cordiality
                        with which the German Consul was received, and the fact is fall of political
                        significance. German influence is insinuating itself into the political life
                        of Turkey with systematic and studied assiduity. The German Consul converses
                        with the Mushir in Turkish with apparent ease and fluency, and this alone
                        flatters the Turk's amour-propre, and establishes a sort of fraternity
                        between him and the German, who in the meantime does not confine himself to
                        the domain of platonic sentiment, but exploits his generous host with
                        consummate skill and the fatal scientific thoroughness of the Teuton.</p>
                    <p>At night the Seraglio and other public buildings, including mosques and some
                        of the churches, were lit with gas and oil-light decorations while bumbler
                        illuminations on private buildings and the highways, also lent their share
                        to the general brightness. These, with a crowd of men, women, and children
                        in Arab gar, formed occasional glimpses of picturesque effect. What a superb
                        sight Beyront would present with her queenly position,—the classic
                        Mediterranean at her feet and the, stately Lebanon as a solemn imperial
                        guard around her—what a superb sight, I say, she would present beneath the
                        magic touch of the artist and decorator, lavishly patronised. Perhaps,
                        however, her narrow, tortuous, and filthy streets give her a peculiar exotic
                        charm, which appeals so strangely to the distant dreamer and artist who
                        would selishly denounces the intruduction of modern methods with all their
                        benefits and blessings into a classis land, because they jar on his dream of
                        the mystic path. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID,</head>
                    <head>THE CHATHAM FLOODED</head>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <p>Port Said, Thursday</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Clan Cumming which collided with the Chatham close to Raz-el-E h
                        arrived here this morning from the canal, and appears very slightly
                        damaged.</p>
                    <p>The latest news which I have been able to gather about the latter ship is
                        that the Canal company’s huge pumps have succeeded in completely flooding
                        the holds of the vessel thus rendering the enormous quantity of explosives
                        on board her quite harmless. The vessel is now practically awash, I
                        understand, at least round her forward decks, and she is to be secured with
                        heavy chains so that she may not slide into the navigable channel</p>
                    <p>There is a passage on one side of the ship which up to the present has been
                        utilised solely for daylight navigation. Ships peas the vessel either way,
                        it appears, tad have done so since yesterday evening. </p>
                    <p>The real cause of the accident is a matter of doubt, conflicting rumours are
                        heard everywhere and apparently it will not be discov-ered for some
                        time.</p>
                    <p>One cannot say too much about the way the matter has been taken in hand bv
                        the Canal company, the chiefs and men all working as they have done with a
                        complete disregard of danger, and it is undoubtedly owing to this real pluck
                        and bravery on all hands that the danger of a great disaster has been
                        averted. Had the vessel not been flooded it once there is no question but
                        that falling spars and timbers would have causes an explosion, which for the
                        seriousness of its results would have been unparalled, for the entire
                        commerce of the world through the Canal would have been interrupted for an
                        unknown length of time.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER SEASON COMMENCING.</head>
                    <p>The streets of Port Said are once more becoming thronged with passengers
                        bound eastward and for Egypt. By every mail numbers arrive, Who leave as
                        rapidly by the trains for Cairo and elsewhere.</p>
                    <p>The much improved service of trains which we now have; since the taking over
                        of the line by the government, in a measure does a certain amount of harm to
                        the local business, for whereas in the days of the steam tramway a couple of
                        years ago, passengers remained here frequently some time, they now depart
                        for other towns, possessing greater attractions, in as short a time as
                        possible.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
