<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Gwen Lofman</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-10-06">October 6, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Fruday, <date when="1905-10-06">October 6</date>, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, <date when="1905-10-06"><date when="1905-10-06">October 6</date> 1905</date></head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TUBERCULOSIS PROFESSOR BEHRING’S CLAIM.</head>
                    <head>DISCOVERY OF REMEDY.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>At the great tuberculosis conference Professor Behring, the discoverer of the diphtheria serum, announced that he has discovered the remedy for tuberculosis. It is neither a serum nor vaccine, and he cannot explain his methods until next August, but from to day sufferers may recover hope.</p>
                    <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    <dateline>Paris, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Professor Behring, who is taking part in the tuberculosis conference, has declared to the "Matin" that he has discovered the preventive and curative remedy for tuberculosis, and that he will reveal it in August next year. He will make a communication to that effect on Saturday.</p>
                    <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GRAVE SITUATION IN BERLIN.</head>
                    <head><unclear>IsoToou</unclear> MEN RENDERED IDLE.</head>
                    <dateline>Berlin, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>A grave situation is arising from the strike of all electrical workers, by which 50,000 men are rendered idle, including those indirectly effected. The metal manufacturers have now declared a lock out for the 4th inst. (sic) in sympathy with the electrical firms. The number of men idle will then bo 120,000, that is to say more than a twentieth of the population. The garrison has been reinforced.</p>
                    <byline>(R.)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN IMPERIAL RESCRIPT.</head>
                    <head>THE REFORMED NAVY SCHEME</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>A rescript of the Tsar orders the retirement of naval officers who are not able to satisfy the increased demands under the reformed navy scheme.</p>
                    <byline>(Renter)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RED SEA PIRACY.</head>
                    <head>PORTE GRANTS SATISFACTION.</head>
                    <dateline>Constantinople. <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The Porte has agreed to all the demands of Great Britain for satisfaction on account of piracy in the Red 8ea.</p>
                    <byline>(Renter)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HONORS FOR KINO EDWARD.</head>
                    <dateline>London, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The King has been gazetted Colonel in the Eighth Spanish Regiment.</p>
                    <byline>(Renter)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF A TURKISH CAMPAIGNER.</head>
                    <dateline>Constantinople, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Edhem Pasha is dead.</p>
                    <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RACING.</head>
                    <dateline>London, <date when="1905-10-05">October 5</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Jockey Club Stakes. l.St. Amant ; 2. Polymelus ; 3. Mondamin.</p>
                    <byline>(Renter)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTER TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not bold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by car correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all to permit — within certain necessary limits — free</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BOULOGNE TO ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <quotedLetter>
                        <opener>
                            <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                            <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>The following criticisms passed on the Boulogne-Alexandria route may interest your readers. The railway carriages from Boulogne to Paris are of the old conventional type. There are no corridor carriages. The second class carriages are provided with lavatories, but not the first! Of course there is no communication between such carriages. The European edition the “New York Herald” can be bought at the station in Marseilles at 11 p.m. on day of publication, but not the same edition of the "Daily Mail,” which cannot be had there till about 10 a.m. the following day. In the Messageries steamers, passengers have no opportunity of seeing a barometer, thermometer, or compass. These steamers have only one gangway (aft) for embarkation and disembarkation ; the result is utter confusion and noise on leaving and arriving. There ought to be two gangways, one forward and one aft, to relievo the congestion.<p>
                        <p>To an Englishman it seems strange that the P. and O. Company can run "through” trains from Calais to Marseilles, whilst the Messageries Company,—a French concern—cannot, or does not do so through its own country for its own steamers. There is another matter which is worthy of note, namely in regard to baggage. Would it not be possible to send the baggage of passengers for places beyond France under bond in sealed waggons (small size for conveyance on deck of Channel steamers) from say Charing Cross to Marseilles, and vice versa. If this were done it seems to me that there would be a great saving in time, trouble and expense, the last in the pay of Customs House officials. The searching of such baggage is after all a very perfunctory affair.<p>
                        <closer>
                            <salute>I am, Sir. etc, -</salute>
                            <dateline>Alexandria, October 4.</dateline>
                        </closer>
                    </quotedLetter>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ministry of Public Instruction</head>
                        <p>Our Cairo contemporaries state that no less than fifty professors engaged by Mr. Douglas Dunlop for the Ministry of Public Instruction are expected to arrive at Cairo on the 10th inst Surely their number is slightly exaggerated.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New School Opened</head>
                        <p>Our Minet el Kamh correspondent informs us that Messrs. Sourial have just opened a new school at Mit Bashar village in Sharkich mudirieh. The teaching staff of the school is. we are informed, highly efficient, and the support of the neighbourring population quite assured.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Pit Accident</head>
                        <p>A young native workmen, who was digging in a pit at Mex, was buried beneath a heavy mass of sand and earth. Tee man, besides being almost suffocated was seriously hurt and had to be taken to hospital, where, it is hoped, ho will recover with careful treatment, and so be able to resume work at no very distant date.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hedjaz Railway</head>
                        <p>News comes from Ma'an of the discovery of the ruins of an ancient city at about five hours journey from that town. Two large rock tombs, the gates of a fort and the remains of a temple are said to have been cleared by an excavating party. The ruins are, apparently, of Nabathaean origin and date from the first or second century of the Christian era.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Church Missionary Society</head>
                        <p>The Church Missionary Society have arranged a series of autumn meetings for the native youth of Cairo. A Dumber of addresses will he given both in English and Arabic, dealing with the moral life, and pointing out the pits and snares into which the young man is apt to fall, and the way of avoiding them. The next meeting will be held on the 8th inst., and the following ones on successive Sundays at Beit Arabi Pasha, Bab el Look.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Pro Calabria</head>
                        <p>This morning the committee of the "Reunion des Families” handed over to Baron Acton, Consul General of Italy, a sum of 1,000 franca, being the proceeds of the lottery drawn for last Saturday at Mex Casino, for the benefit of the Calabrian earthquake victims. A very successful entertainment was given at the Tour Eiffel the night before last with the same object. The music hall was crowded in spite of advanced prices, and the artistes made every effort to excel themselves in their varied roles. The three sisters d’Orsay were especially popular with their energetic dancing, and songs sang in trio in several languages. Mlle Tina Dumonte, an Italian artiste, was also loudly applauded as, indeed, were the majority of the large number of artistes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring information on trade matters generally, including the question of appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain farther particulars from our London office, 36, New Broad-stree, which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Horrible Murder Near Tahta</head>
                        <p>A man of Oneibis (near Tahta, Ghirgeh Mudireh) had a great affection for a young woman whom he made his wife. Shortly after their marriage, however, he paid his addresses to another, and having asked her if she would marry him, she only consented on the condition that he would send his first wife away. In order to get rid of his wife the miscreant butchered her, cut her body into pieces, and cast them into the Nile. After this barbarous act he informed the police authority that his wife was away, and he knew nothing of her whereabouts. At the same time, the omdeh of the village advised the markez of Tahta of the woman's fate, and the authorities in their cross-examination suspected the murderer in the person of the husband. The man is now in prison awaiting his trial, and the police have arrested other suspects.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Unrequited Love Results in Murder</head>
                         <p>After being betrothed for four years a young man of Rod-El-Farag (near Cairo) oonld not arrange to marry his fiance, and the girl’s mother requested him either to break off the engagement or to marry her daughter within a short time. Shortly afterwards another suitor for the girl's hand appeared and these two became engaged and were married. The thwarted lover was seized with jealousy and on Wednesday night, knowing that the young wife had gone to visit her parents, he broke into her old house, accompanied by two other men, with the intent to kill her whilst she was asleep, Taking with him a heavy stone he dropped it on the head of one whom he thought to be his quondam lover but who proved to be her brother. The weight of the stone and the force with which it was brought down crusheded in the head of the unfortunate man, who died in a very short time. The murderer and his two accomplices were discovered by the polioe and are now in prison.</p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>QUARANTINE STATIONS.</head>
                        <head type="sub">NEW BUILDING FOR TOR.</head>
                        <p>We are informed that the Ministry of Finance has, on the request of the Quarantine Board, made a further grant of £10,000 for extending the accommodation at Tor by the erection of new buildings. As a proof of the need for such an extension we may mention that whereas on the opening of the quarantine camp there, the number of pilgrims was some 18,000, it increased to nearly 40,000 last season. In this number is included only the pilgrims coming from the north, and not those from India and the Far East The latter undergo the prescribed period of quarantine at Camaran Island in the Red Sea, which is a Turkish quarantine station.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MR. DAVID LONGWORTH.</head>
                        <p>Mr. David G. Longworth, the former proprietor and editor of the "Sphinx," the weekly paper published in Cairo during the winter season, is leaving by the P. &amp; 0. steamer Persia for Aden, and thence proceeds to British East Africa with the view of starting at Nairobi, the capital of the Protectorate, a weekly periodical entitled the "Globe Trotter.” Mr. Longworth, daring the many years that he has resided in Cairo, contributed in a great measure in bringing to the notice of the American public, through the columns of his paper, the climatic and other advantages of our metropolis as a health resort, and succeded in a marked degree, as those who have noted the very large increase of American visitors to this country of recent years must admit</p>
                        <p>Mr. Longworth is of the same conviction as Mr. McMillan, that there is a great future in store for the comparatively new British colony to which he is now turning his attention and energies, and we wish him every success in the new venture upon which he has now embarked.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE NILE FLOOD.</head>
                        <p>We mentioned in our issue of the 9th ultimo that the condition of the Nile flood during August had distinctly, improved and though it could not be regarded as a high Nile, the readings of the various gauges at that time did not compare unfavorably with those of last year. We note, however, that a sadden and ominous fall which took place on the 27th September at Rosaries has since continued unininterruptedly and yesterday's gauge registered 8.47 comparing very unfavorably with that of last year’s at the same time, which was as high as 4.56. This portends a bad water supply for next year's summer crops. The fall we mention will not be apparent at Khartoum for quite another ten days or so, as its effect is felt there about three weeks after it occurs at Rosaires.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW BANK FOR EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>We are able to state that arrangements are now practically complete for the establishment of another bank to conduct business in this country. It will be called the Egyptian Bank of Commerce, and its capital will be something like half a million sterling, to which public subscriptions will be invited very shortly. The directorate, we believe, will prove to be an influential one, comprising names connected with leading banks in London.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE YEMEN REBELS.</head>
                        <p>A Beyrout contemporary remarks that the rumour that the Yemen rebels have reached a point very near the Hedjaz is absolutely without foundation. On the contrary our contemporary asserts that it learns from an authoritative source that the rebel army is at least 700 kilometres distant from the Hedjaz, and gives as its opinion that they will find it a by no means easy task to cross the rough and deserted stretch of country which leads to the Vilayet.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                        <p>The following is the menu of the dinner to be given to-morrow evening on the occasion of the small dance at the San Stefano Casino.</p>
                        <p>Consomme double glace Fillet de Bar Bonne femme</p>
                        <p>Mignon de bœuf REnaissance Pilaff aux cailles Petite pois à l'Anglaise Ponlarde rôite Salade de laitue Parfait au Moke Gàtean St. Germain</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The express Khedivial mail steamship Ismailia will leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on Wednesday next for Piræus, Smyrna, Mitylene, and Constantinople.</p>
                        <p>The S.S. Ocean Prince from Manchester and Tunis with passenger, and general cargo left Malta to-day, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KASSASSIN COLLISION.</head>
                        <head>ENGINE DRIVER RESPONSIBLE.</head>
                        <p>The enquiry opened by Abd-el-Hamid Bey Ridha, Chief of the Native Parquet at Zagazig, has proved that the entire responsibility for this accident rests on the driver of goods train No. 331. It appears that on nearing Kassassin he took no notice of the signals, which were against him, and ran through the station. The station master and the pointsman called and signalled vigorously but vainly to him, and between Kassassin and Nefishe the goods train collided with train No. S.S. with disastrous consqeuences. According to one of our Cairo contemporaries, the ambulance van arrived from Cairo too late at the scene of the disaster to be of any service to the twenty-two victims of this accident, who had already been sent to Ismailia. -</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRINCE BUELOW’S INTERVIEW.</head>
                        <byline>(From our London Correspondent).</byline>
                        <byline>(By Telegraph).</byline>
                        <dateline><date when="1906-10-05">Thursday.</date></dateline>
                        <p>A representative of the "Temps," Paris, has had an interview with Prince Von Buelow, who emphatically denies that Germany has any designs to get France to take part with her in any action against Britain. He could not but describe the prevalent idea that war against England was inevitable, as stupid in the extreme. Germany will not attempt any experiments. The Governments at London and Berlin have too much regard for their responsibilities to allow themselves to be influenced by violent articles in the Press, and international solidarity is too strong for any Power to flatter itself that it can play the part of a tertius gaudens in any quarrel. The prejudices between England and Germany will sooner or later disappear and France can play an important part in bringing the countries into greater harmony.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUMOURED GOLD DISCOVERY.</head>
                        <p>"Al Mokattam” states that the engineers of the Corporation of Western Egypt have have discovered traces of gold in the rooks in the Western Oases. Should the gold prove worth working measures will be taken to start workings.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>H.H. the Khedive attended prayers at the Terbaneh Mosque to-day and afterwards proceeded to Ras el Tin Palace.</p>
                        <p>The Countess of Cromer is leaving Marseilles On the 3rd proximo by the Bibby liner Worcestershire for Port Said.</p>
                        <p>The marriage arranged between Major Edward Sydney Herbert and Miss Gwendolen Gorst will take place on the 12th inst. at St. Margaret’s, Westminster.</p>
                        <p>Among the visitors now stopping at the Continental Hotel, Cairo, we notice Mr. and Mrs. Anhouri, Mr. B. Jaicombe, Mr. H. Greaves, Mr. H. Skill, Sir Rudolph von Slatin Pasha, Mr. H. Greis, Mr. F. Norman, Mr. and Mrs. A. McCullogh, Lieut. and Mrs. C. Ranee, Major and Mrs. Little, Mr. D. M. Macleod, Mrs. Sangster Miss Kennidy, Mr S. Levy, Mr. Rodcanachi, Mohamed Bey Taher, Mr. Duvork Van Hell, Mrs. G. W. Hensley, Col. Livingston, Major Lethbridge, Mr. Fred. Batty, Saleh N. Bey, Mr. Morgan, Mr. Patterson, Mr. W. C. James, Mrs. Buchanan, Miss Eccott, Mr. L. Twiss, Mr. J. E. Anderson, Mr. Witham, Mr. C. Shorrock, Mr. A. Müller, Mrs. Wright, Miss Kellie, Mr. H. O. Lane, Mr. M. Lakah, Mr. C. R. Rolo, Mr. Bansch, Mr. Saeger, Mr. A. Arditi, Mr. A. A. Barnes, Mr. and Mrs. A. Travis Walker, Comm. and Mme. Zeppa, Mr. A. Bonnet, Major and Mrs. Le Breton, and several members of the British Association.</p>
                        <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice Miss A. Spencer, Mr. Petrovich, Colonel T.R.P. Gordon, Mrs. Sardon, Mr. F. B. Tacomb, Mr P. Schulze Berge and family, Mr. Seton Karr, Mr. T. Hicks Paull, Mr. W. T. Wayle, Mr. W. R Field, the Hon and Lady Barrington, Major. Le Breton, Mrs. and Miss Le Breton, Mr. and Mrs. A. F. Bronn, Miss K. Mosley.</p>
                        <p>The following visitors are staying at the Beau-Rivage Hotel, Ramleh. Mr. and Mrs. C. Davacos H. E. Abbate Pasha, Mrs. M. Young, Mr. and Mrs. L. Thomas, Mr. and Mrs. Marins Berlioz, Dr. Kautsky Bey and family, Mr. W. Cohle, Mme Rhallic, Mr. and Mrs. F. Davey, Mr. G. Metral, Mr. W. Romances, Mr. and Master Delanoy, Mr. and Mrs. V. Cadoyan, Mr. and Mrs. W. Firth.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item"><!-- TODO replace with advertisement boilerplate-->
                        <head>BECK &amp; C0’8 PILSENER BEER</head>
                        <head>BREMEN.</head>
                        <p>Fears no honest competition for quality.</p>
                        <p>B—Inferior Breads now being offered to Man ager of certain good <unclear/>.</p>
                        <p>Beware of wily <unclear/> competition making <unclear/> of <unclear/></p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A HISTORY OF EGYPT.</head>
                        <head type="sub">XIXTH TO XXXTH DYNASTIES.</head>
                        <p>The Athenaeum gives the following interesting criticism of Professor Petrie's latest work : —</p>
                        <p>The concluding volume of Prof. Petrie's part of this history of Egypt is out at last, and certainly does not err on the side of verbosity. The complaint that has been brought against it by foreign critics, to the effect that it is not so much a history as a catalogue of monuments, is here more justified than ever, a period of more than a thousand years - neither the least eventful nor the worst documented in Egypts history-being jammed into a small volume of 400 pages. The delay in its appearance is, we are told in the text, almost entirely due to the groat quantity of monuments remaining to us from the reign of Rameses II., which apparently made it necessary for Prof. Petrie to go carefully through the list and to throw out such as he considered either appropriations of the works of earlier kings, or for some other reason unworthy of note. In this, as in some other matters, he apparently thinks that bis ipse dixit must be taken as settling the question.</p>
                        <p>The same feature is noticeable in his preface, where he tells us that</p>
                        <q>
                            <p>"as some persons still continue to quote Dr. Brcgsch's chronology, I ought, perhaps, to point out that it entirely rests on two certainly false assumptions, and [that] it is only rendered possible by freely making any number of arbitrary omissions. In short it is no system and has no reason” ;</p>
                            <p>while, after discussing the two assumptions in question, he concludes that “no one who uses it can be supposed to know of the facts of the history which are stated in this volume.” There have been nearly as many systems of chronology in Egyptian history as historians, and Brugsch's system" is, like all the others, in great measure a system of inferences from rather slender foundations. But Brugsch was a man of deep and wide learning, as well as an Egyptologist who had spent has life in the study of his subject; and as the founder of demotic studies he possessed a knowledge of the language of the monuments for greater than any of which Prof. Petrie can boast We think, therefore, that his theories should be treated with respect and that it will require something more than Prof. Petrie’s pronouncements ex cathedra to dispossess a system which still has much to reccommend it This apart, Prof. Petrie is, in other respects, unusually tolerant of the opinions of other in this volume, and it is good to find him actually referring with courtesy and even with approbation to the works of those whom he is pleased to consider his rivals. Thus he not only speaks with approval of certain work of Mr. H. R. Hall, but also says, with regard to the supposed route of the Exodus, that “the result of Naville's discussion of it is reasonable and generally accepted.” We think, however, that he might have devoted a little more space to Dr. Breasted's very clear and careful account of the battle of Kadesh.</p>
                            <p>From its extremely condensed form it is impossible to review the book in detail, bat it may be said that the evidence quoted is fairly up to date, although Prof. Petrie does not seem to have examined M. Legrain's discoveries at Karnak. Had he done so, we fancy he would have found it necessary to make a considerable change in his genealogy of the Sheshonkide kings. Yet, on the whole, he seems to have chosen the facts recorded with care, and we are glad to see that he will have nothing to do with Prof. Winkler’s Masri theory. He takes, perhaps, too professional a view of ethics when he tells us that Seti I.’s character was one of the best in history, because, apparently, he left monuments in honor of bis predecessors and usurped no monuments without recording the name of the king under whom they were originally inscribed. Later, he characteristically uses the reputation with which Seti is thus generously presented in favor of his own arguments, saying that “the general character of this king is so honorable in his works, that we are bound to credit his statements if we cannot show them to be wrong.” We do not think that Prof. Petrie’s identification of place and other names shows much acquaintance with the Semitic, or, for that matter, with the Aryan languages, and we have noticed some mistakes, such as “cieling” for ceiling, "Revillont” for Revillout and a Greek pi for an eta. His English is still slipshod The lists of the monuments of every king, with provenance and abiding place, that he gives, will be extremely useful to students ; and for the care and pains that he has bestowed on their compilation all Egyptologists should be grateful.</p>
                        </q>
                        <p>A History of Egypt from the XIXth to the XXXth Dynasties. By IF. M. Flinders Petrie. </p>
                        <byline>(Methuen).</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                        <p>Table d'Hete Luncheons &amp; Dinners</p>
                        <p>Served on the Terrace.</p>
                        <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ST. ANDREW'S CHURCH.</head>
                        <head>CAIRO</head>
                        <p>Services</p>
                        <p>Beginning Sunday, 8th October.</p>
                        <p>MW</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head>
                        <head type="sub">TO-MORROW’S AQUATIC SPORTS.</head>
                        <p>The third annual aquatic sports of the Alexandria Swimming Club will be held tomorrow in the New Graving Dock, Gabbarl, commencing at 8 p.m. An excellent programme of events has been arranged and should afford some exciting races ; the handicaps seem to have been most carefully and well and a glance at the list of competitors assures the spectators of several dots contests.</p>
                        <p>The first event, for which there are 19 competitors, will be the 60 yards club run in four heats, and the winner will secure H. E. Sir Reginald Wingate Pasha's Sirdar Medal”, presented as a perpetual trophy, upon which the winner's name of each year will be engraved; the club also offers three prizes for this event, the first of which is a miniature in silver in the Sirdar’s prize.</p>
                        <p>Event II. will be the 60 yards juniors' handicap, for which there are six entries and three prizes presented by the club, and then will come a 60 yards handicap for members of 35 years of age or more, for which then are nine entries and three prizes, and this will be followed by the final race for the "Sirdar Medal."</p>
                        <p>The junior’s diving championship comes next, in which we will see nine boys vying with each other in graceful dives from three, five, and eight feet Take note, youthful competition, that while the "swallow" is permitted, the “book” must be avoided on penalty of disqualification. For this event a silver cup has been presented by the Hon. Secretary and three club prizes will also bo given.</p>
                        <p>For the plunging championship, which whill  follow 17 members will compete for a cup and three prises, presented by the Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Co., Ltd., and there will then be a polo match between the Eastern Tele graph and the Alexandria Swimming Club; each member of the winning team will secure a prize, for which they will be indebted to the dub. This event will conclude the first part of the programme.</p>
                        <p>The second part of the programme will commence with a blindfold race for three prizes presented by the dub, and will be followed by an open diving competition; the rules of this competition are the same as for the junior competition, with the exception of the heights which will 3, 8, and 15 feet, and there are three prizes presented by the club.</p>
                        <p>Event X takes the form of an obstacle race for which there are 15 entries, and the for this race are presented by the staff of the Eastern Telegraph Co., Ltd. Than comes a military polo match, with a prise for each member of the winning team, and the junior members will then “walk the pole”, after whisk the seniors will follow their example; for each of these two races only one prise will be given.</p>
                        <p>A military tug of war and than a military team race follow, and each member of the winning teams will secure a prise, and the programme will then be concluded with a cock fight for which the dab ‘offer one prise.</p>
                        <p>It only remains to add that Lady has kindly consented to present the victorious competitors with their trophies of success. and that Mr. D. Dampergola's orchestra will play selections daring the afternoon. The sports promise to follow the general tendency of the year by eclipsing all previous aquatic and the attendance also promisee to break all records.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A POEM.</head>
                        <p>We reproduoe ( unedited ) the following poem sent us by a native reader :—</p>
                        <q>
                            <head>LIFE, A BAZAR.</head>
                            <p>The slothful laws of meager life,<lb/>
                            Are but marital fare.<lb/>
                            The universe that rolls about,<lb/>
                            Whose trend la ever change.<lb/>
                            Is but a public bazar free.<lb/>
                            When all is bought for sale.<lb/>
                            Man is the price that's freely paid To buy the lady sought,<lb/>
                            For woman an the; things for sale To him who highest pay.<lb/>
                            They're trained to this as they are born,<lb/>
                            For man is but their dice.<lb/>
                            Their fickle heart doth seek anew For change to others win.<lb/>
                             The one who flees their subtle snare,<lb/>
                            They ever seek to how.<lb/>
                            They always train themsleves to show For sale within the fare.</p>
                        </q>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PASSENGER LIST.</head>
                        <head>ARRIVALS.</head><!-- TODO Figure out how to best represent the data -->
                        <p>Le paquebot Nilo de la Cie Florio Rubattino arrive de Venire avait a bord :</p>
                        <p>MM. N. Jacovelli, Mme Maocari, M. et Mme Balestrieri, Jabes, Schinari et fam., Klatengue, G. Drosso, Vais, Reas et fam., Wamhe, Av. et Mme Cuzzer, Antranikian et fam., Uliedes et fam., Dr. Rossi, Alessandrini, Terni, P. Milk, Rodriguez, Hermann, D. Sebton, M. et Mme Pugnaletto, Vuta et fam., Warn, fam. Luochess et 100 autres passagers.</p>
                        <head>DEPARTURES.</head><!-- TODO Figure out how to best represent the data -->
                        <p>Le paquebot Eona de la Cie Florio Rubat tino parti hier pour Genes avait a bord.</p>
                        <p>MM. Chidiao. Terranova, Mlle Con Van Camp, A. Franck, M. et Mme Bahadurgi, Mme R. Fichelett, Duchesse d’Andria, P. Dablis, Ah. Zeki, Barotti, Hanna Bassombay, lieut. Eloseda, Cap. B. Dalle Piane, Mme Femallah et bebe, lieut comte Belisario, M. et Maw V. La Piassa et 2 fils, Lafsovish et fam, et 25 passagers de 3e classe.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
