<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kara Hofmeister</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-01">October 1, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-06">January 6, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, JANUARY 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head> THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, JANUARY6, 1905</head>
            <head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>
            <head>PORT ARTHUR.</head>
            <head>RUSSIAN EVACUATION.</head>
            <head>JAPS ENTER ON SUNDAY</head>
            <head>SUGGESTED COURT MARTIAL.</head>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 5.</p>
            <p>The Russians are evacuating Port Arthur.
            The Japanese will make their formal entry on
            the 8th inst.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p>
            <p>Port Arthur, January 5.</p>
            <p>The Russians will march out from the town
            to-morrow. The Japanese will make their
            formal entry on the 8th inst.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 5.</p>
            <p>General Nogi reports that the total number
            of the surrendered amounts to 48,000, of whom
            16,000 are sick and wounded. The transfer of
            the forts and batteries is completed.</p>
            <p>It is impossible to move the majority of the
            sick and wounded. The Japanese are hurrying
            food and medicine to Port Arthur.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 5.</p>
            <p>With reference to the statement that there
            will be an enquiry regarding the surrender of
            Port Arthur, the Novoye Vremya declares :—
            "Let us have a court-martial by all means, and
            then we shall discover why the fortress was
            not supplied with food and munitions and who
            are Russia's real enemies. Such enemies are
            infinitely more dangerous than the Japanese.''</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <div type="item"> <head>H.M.S. "ANDROMEDA.’’</head>
            <head>FRUITLESS ERRAND.</head>
            <p>Wei-Hai-wei, January 5.</p>
            <p>The "Andromeda” has returned. The Japa-
            nese would not allow her to disembark the
            stores or to approach the land on the ground
            of the presence of undiscovered mines. (R.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
            <head>FRANCE'S NEUTRALITY.</head>
            <p>Paris, January 5.</p>
            <p>France, replying to the representations made
            by Japan regarding the coaling and victualling
            of the Baltic Fleet in Madagascar, says that
            there is no danger of the non-observance of her
            neutrality, as the local authorities have receiv-
            ed strict instructions.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>JAPANESE CRUISERS.</head>
            <head>SEEN NEAR MANILA.</head>
            <p>Manila, January 5.</p>
            <p>Two Japanese cruisers have been signalled
            outside the port.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE “NIGRETIA” CONDEMNED.</head>
            <head>BY JAPANESE PRIZE COURT.</head>
            <p>Tokio, January 5.</p>
            <p>The British S.S. “ Nigretia” has been con-
            demned by the Prize Court.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>OUTSPOKEN RUSSIAN PAPERS.</head>
            <head>WARNED BY AUTHORITIES.</head>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 5.</p>
            <p>The old established newspaper Rus and the
            new liberal paper Nashidni have been warned
            and penalized owing to articles on the fall of
            Port Arthur. They declared that reforms are
            essential to Russia's rehabilitation. The
            Nashidni also strongly urged that peace should
            be made.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ADMIRATION FOR BELLIGERENTS.</head>
            <head>SPEECH BY LORD SELBORNE.</head>
            <p>London, January 5.</p>
            <p>Lord Selborne, speaking at Wolverhampton,
            said that we regard the Russians and Japanese
            with the greatest respect. It is comparatively
            esay to admire the Japanese as they are our
            allies, and we do admire them without restraint
            or reserve. It would, however, ill become us if
            we did not equally admire the Russians.</p>
            <p>(R.)</p></div>
           <div type="item"> <head>AMERICAN MERCHANT MARINE.</head>
            <head>NEW MAIL ROUTES SUBSIDISED.</head>
            <p>Washington, January 5.</p>
            <p>The report on the Merchant Marine Service
            submitted to Congress includes subsidies for
            new mail routes, and certain measures for
            stimulating the American carrying trade to
            South Africa and the East.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ILLNESS OF SIG. TITTONL</head>
            <head>SEIZED WITH CEREBRAL CONGESTION.</head>
            <p>Rome, January 5.</p>
            <p>Sig. Tittoni, Minister for Foreign Affairs, is
            ill with cerebral congestion.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p>
            <p>Rome, January 5.</p>
            <p>Signor Tittoui has been seized with cerebral
            congestion due to severe cold contracted while
            on a shooting excursion.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
           <div type="item"> <head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS.</head>
            <head>NEW CABINET FORMED.</head>
            <p>Bucharest, January 5.</p>
            <p>M. Stourdza has resigned, and M. Can-
            taccizene has formed the new Cabinet (H.)</p></div>
           <div type="item"> <head>THE TSAR.</head>
            <head>RETURN TO ST. PETERSBURG.</head>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 5.</p>
            <p>The Tsar has returned here.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
            <p>Orthodox Christmas Day falls to-morrow
            and all the banks will be closed.</p>
            <p>General Holiday.—The Ministries will be
            closed on Accession Day.</p>
            <p>Quarantine restrictions are now applied in
            Egyptian ports to arrivals from Iodia.</p>
            <p>Alhambra—A matinee performance will be
            given at this theatre to-morrow, on the occasion
            of the Orthodox Christmas Day.</p>
            <p>The Abousir Papyrus.—Prof.Diels,of Berlin,
            reports that a papyrus recently fund at Abousir
            near Cairo consists of what may really be
            described as part of a Greek encyclopedia,
            apparently condensed from a larger work.
            They contain lists of lawyers and artists, the
            seven wonders of the world, and the then
            known mountains, islands, and rivers.</p>
            <p>Royal Artillery Gun Practice. — 2nd
            Lieut. A. J. Gatt and 10 men of the Detach-
            ment, R.M.A., Citadel, Cairo, will be attached
            under tho orders of the O.C. RA. in Egypt, to
            either the 56th Bty., R.F.A., or 4th M.B.,
            R.G.A., during their gun practice, from the
            9th to 25th inst The remainder of the Detach-
            ment, R.M.A., at the Citadel, will be attached,
            for discipline, to the Detachment, 2nd Batta-
            lion Rifle Brigade, during the above period.</p>
            <p>British Chamber of Commerce.—We would
            call the attention of persons interested in
            Egyptian trade to the work of the British
            Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, whose office
            in Alexandria gives information as to stand-
            ings, trade, &amp;c., to its members, and whose
            monthly publication reviews our commerce-
            The annual subscription is £1 and all British
            traders should become members. Our London
            office, 36, New Broad-street E.C., acts as
            London agency to the Chamber.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
            <p>The Khedive is leaving Montazah for Cairo
            this evening.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ACCESSION DAY.</head>
            <p>On the occasion of the anniversary of the
            accession of the Khedive to the Throne, the
            Egyptian troops in Cairo will be formed up
            for review by his Highness on the Observatory
            parade-ground at 3 p.m. on Sunday.</p>
            <p>A salute of 21 guns will be fired from the
            Citadel and Polygon Barracks at 12 noon, and
            similar salutes will be fired by the Artillery at
            Alexandria and Port Said at the same hour.</p></div>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                    Sudan.</p>
                <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. </p>
                <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
                <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"> <head>Ramleh Electric Railway</head>
            <head>PUBLIC EXCITEMENT QUELLED.</head>
            <p>We are glad to be able to announce that the
            excitement which prevailed yesterday among
            the "abonnes" of the Alexandria and Ramlah
            Railway has in a great measure subsided, and
            the various sentiments, ranging from wild
            defiance to passive but indignant submission,
            have now given way to a conviction that we
            are within measurable distance of a peaceful
            settlement of the question. The public is
            awaiting with great interest the results of this
            afternoon's deliberations of the board of direc-
            tors of the company, which will meet at 4
            o'clock, when a decision will be arrived at in
            regard to the establishment of a definite tarif
            which will satisfy the legitimate demands of
            the public. Boghos Pasha Nubar, the chairman
            of the company, is now on his way from Cairo
            to attend this afternoon's meeting.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE POLICE AND THB PUBLIC</head>
            <p>Throughout yesterday morning a posse of
            the Alexandria City Police remained at the
            Alexandria terminus of the line and a large
            number of “proces verbaux” were drawn np
            against recalcitrant Ramlehites who insisted
            on travelling without paying their fares. A
            climax was reached shortly after noon, when a
            scene of considerable excitement ensued, as large
            numbers of the Ramlehites were flocking to
            the terminus in order to get home to their mid-
            day meal. Some of them showed signs of defiance
            and tried to pass through the gates without
            tickets in spite of the efforts of the police.
            They forced the police cordon and made for
            the cars with a rush. They succeeded in
            boarding the cars and triumphantly got off to
            Ramleh without having to submit to the
            exactions of the company.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE TENSION IS RELIEVED.</head>
            <p>At 2 p.m. the company, seeing that the
            presence of the police appeared to aggravate
            the exasperated feelings of the Ramlahites,
            asked the Commandant, Miralai Hopkinson
            Bey, to withdraw his men from the station.
            This was done and the wise step appeared to
            greatly relieve the feeling of extreme tension.
            Immediately afterwards the delegates of the
            Ramlehites distributed the following</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>IMPORTANT MANIFESTO.</head>
            <p>Ramlisti!</p>
            <p>Abbiamo l'onore d'informarvi che da questo
            momento la forza di polizia si e ritirata dalla
            stazione.</p>
            <p>Vi esortiamo dunque al buon ordine ed
            aspettare fino a nuovo avviso per darvi il ri-
            sultato delle trattative in corso.</p>
            <p>Sono pure pregati tutti quelli che gli viene
            richiesto d'indicare il loro nome, di non refiu-
            tarlo all'ispettore della Compagnia in funsione.</p>
            <p>Consigliamo la calms.</p>
            <p>Alessandria, 5 Gennaio 1905.</p>
            <p>I Delegati,</p>
            <p>Arbib, Stross E Zenie</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PEACE IN SIGHT.</head>
            <p>After the publication of this manifesto, it
            was felt that the most acute stage of the crisis
            had been passed, and the excitement that had
            hitherto prevailed began to gradually fizzle
            away, to be replaced by more calm feelings. We
            are happy to state that the attitude of both
            is becoming more and more conciliatory and
            the feeling appears to be gradually gaining
            ground that some modus vivendi will be ulti-
            mately discovered, for there is no doubt that
            the new tarif cannot be maintained. A
            a sign of the improvement in the outlook,
            we may mention that the company did
            not make any application for extra police
            this morning at the Alexandria terminus,
            which has resumed its wonted peaceful ap-
            pearance.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>A MASS MEETING</head>
            <p>of Ramlehites has been convened for to-morrow
            evening by the delegates. It will begin at 9 p.m.
            and will be held at the Bacos Theatre. The
            results of the deliberations of the board of di-
            rectors will be carefully and judicially taken
            into consideration, and in all probability a
            happily adjusted compromise will be arrived at.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PETITION TO THE AUTHORITIES.</head>
            <p>The Committee appointed for the defence
            of the interests of Ibrahimieh and Ramleh has
            addressed the following letter to the Minster
            of Public Works, a copy of which has been
            sent to Lord Cromer and H.E. the Governor of
            Alexandria, as president of the Municipal
            Commission:—</p>
            <p>Excellence,</p>
            <p>Nous avons l'honneur, au nom des habitants
            de l'Ibrahimieh et Ramleh d'appeler la bien veil-
            lante attention de V. E. sur la grave situation
            dans laquelle se trouve la population de ces
            deux localites par suite des agissements de
            l'Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Co. Ld.</p>
            <p>Le service de cette Compagnie est vital pour
            Ramleh et Imbrahimieh qui ont environ 20,000
            habitants et comprennent 3750 maisons
            payent L.E.7,881 d'impot par an.</p>
            <p>Le service de traction entre Alexandrie et
            Ramleh fut assume par l’A &amp; R.R. Co. Ld, en
            date du 28 Juin 1883 et ensuite un nouveau
            contrat fut paste entre le Ministere des Tre-
            vaux Publics et cette Compagnie le 17 Julliet
            1890 suivant copie ci-incluse.</p>
            <p>Quand la concession initiale fut accordee en
            1860, Ramleh etait presque on desert et il est
            concevable que l’on ne se soit pas preoccupe
            d'imposer a la Compagnie un Cahier des
            Charges.</p>
            <p>Aujourd'hui Ramleh a pris un developpe-
            ment considerable et il est de toute necessite
            que ce Cahier des Charges soit impose a une
            Compagnie faisant un service publiq de cette
            importance.</p>
            <p>Nous passons outre les inconvenients dont
            Ramleh et l’Ibrahimieh ont longuemeut souf-
            fert par suite de ce manque d’un Cahier des
            Charges et nous nous limitons a enumerer a
            V.E. les privileges exorbitants dont jouit la
            Compagnie.</p>
            <p>Elle peut a son gre :</p>
            <p>Elever ou abaisser les prix de transport,creer
            dos tarifs d'abonnement, les supprimer.</p>
            <p>Modifier les horaires; suspendre ou ajoumer
            les departs.</p>
            <p>Allonger ou diminuer la duree du trajet.</p>
            <p>Creer des gares ou des stations ou bon lui
            semble ; les changer de place, les supprimer.</p>
            <p>Fournir un materiel mal dispose et de qualite
            mediocre.</p>
            <p>Augmenter ou supprimer le nombre de voi-
            tures en service.</p>
            <p>Faire servir une voie ferree etablie pour des
            locomotives et de lourds wagons a des voitures
            legeres qui cahotent d'une facon permanente.</p>
            <p>La seule enumeration de ces privileges,
            ajoutes au droit de menopole, demontrers a
            V.E. qu'il est urgent, en presence des reclama-
            tions unanimes d’une population irritee, de
            prendre les mesures necessaires pour mettre un
            trein au principal souci des actionnaires qui
            est l'augmentatation des dividendes.</p>
            <p>Il resulte de ces privileges que la Compagnie
            peut d'un trait de plume faire hauseer ou
            baisser les prix des terrains et des maisons de
            Ramleh et de l'Ibrahimieh, qu'elle peut ruiner
            des quartiers populeux; quelle peut modifier
            a son gre le budget de depenses de toute une
            population, et o’est precisement ce qu'elle vient
            de faire a la date du 1er Janvier de cette
            annee.</p>
            <p>Elle a etabli que les abonnees de 1re Classe
            qui payaient P.T. 950 par an paieront a raison
            de 120 voyages par mois a Mill 15 environ
            P.T. 2200. Ceux de 3me Classe qui payaient
            P.T. 570 par an paieront P.T. 1100.</p>
            <p>Ce tarif est prohibitif pour la classe la plus
            nombreuse d’abonnes dont beaucoup devront
            renoncer a habiter Ramleh tout en y ayant des
            proprietes.</p>
            <p>Une simple oomparaison :</p>
            <p>Les abonnements des Chemins de Fer Egyp-
            tiens pour la ligne de Matarieh, qui est a tres
            pen de chose pres, de la meme longueur que
            celle de Ramleh, sont bien interieurs a ceux de
            l'A. &amp; R. R. Co. Ld.</p>
            <p>En effet l'abonnoment en premiere coute
            L.E. 8 et en seconde L.E. 6 par an.</p>
            <p>Dans ces conditions nous venons prier le
            Gouvernment, qui protege impartialement
            tous ses administers d'user des droits que lui
            confere la concession du 6 sout 1860 pour
            imposer a la Compagnie un Cahier des Charges
            analogue a celui des autres Compagnies de
            traction electrique, portant sur les points que
            nous vous avons signales et sur toutos les
            questious d'ordre public.</p>
            <p>Dans le cas ou la Compagnie s'y refuserait,
            l'article 6 de la concession initiale auquel nous
            nous referons et qui, pensons-nous, conserve
            toute sa force, donne le droit au Gouvernement
            “de retirer sa concession a toute epoque sauf a
            indemniser la Compagnie des travaux executes
            a dire d’experts."</p>
            <p>Nous espersons que V.E. voudra bien prendre
            a couer les interets d'une nombreuse fraction
            de la population d'Alexandrie et d'une plage
            salubre qui ne demands qu'a prendre un deve-
            loppement toujours plus grand.</p>
            <p>Nous vous prions d’agreer, Excellence, l'as-
            surance de notre plus profond respect.</p>
            <p>Le Comite de protection des interets de
            l'Imbrahimieh et Ramleh.</p>
            <p>Le President	(aigne) S. H. Carver
            V. President     	„	    A. Stross
            Secretaire	      „	    F. Frontali
            Tresorier	        „	    D. Rieti
               Membres:	      „	    V. Debono
                                    S. Garofalo
                                    D. Klat
                                    E. de Pitner
                                    A. Prazzica
                                    E. Tschopp
                                    S. Wellnoff</p></div>

            <div type="item"> <head>ZIZINIA THEATRE</head>
            <head>CABRERA.</head>
            <p>The fourth performance of Dupont's Cabrera
            last evening proved a great success. Siga.
            Pinto, it goes without saying, again distinguish-
            ed hereolf as Amalia, and was well seconded by
            Sig. Bravi, the tenor. The latter possesses a
            voice of very fine timbre and delightful fresh-
            ness, but rather light for an opera such as
            Cabrera. The performance of a portion of
            Don Pasquale met with a similar success.
            To-morrow, Siberia will be staged.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>VERDI THEATRE, CAIRO.</head>
            <head>LUCIA DI LAMMERMOOR.</head>
            <p>The Verdi Theatre company gave a most
            excellent performance of Lucia di Lammer-
            moor on Wednesday night. Signore Svicher
            thoroughly deserved the applause given her,
            especially for her song in Act II. Signori
            Pagani, Badini, and Baldelli all showed to
            great advantage. We were glad to note that
            the house was well filled and we hope that
            the fears of a Cairo correspondent will prove
            unjustified, though we cordially agree with his
            remarks and hope that Cairo in general will
            appreciate them and will give the Verdi Thea-
            tre the support it so well deserves.</p></div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p>
                <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                <p>Ten miniutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                    charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron
                    Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                <p>xxxxx-xx-x-905</p>
                <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EDEN PLACE HOTEL
            CAIRO</head>
            <p> Open all the year round.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BANKING DEVELOPMENTS
            IN EGYPT.</head>
            <p>The Comptoir National d'Escompte of Paris
            has definitely decided to found a branch in
            Egypt in a few months' time and will start
            operations at Alexandria. Mr. P. Llewellyn,
            formerly manager of the French Bank of Brazil
            at Rio de Janeiro, has been sent, here by the
            Comptoir National to make all the necessary
            preparations and will assume the management
            of the branch here.</p>
            <p>Mr. Llewellyn was at the Credit Lyonnais
            at Alexandria some years ago, where he was a
            "fonde de pouvoirs." A branch will probably
            be opened at Cairo next year.</p>
           <div type="item"> <head>LAND LAW REFORM.</head>
            <p>We learn on excellent authority that the
            Egyptian Government's scheme on the subject
            of the Bureaux de Publicity has been adopted
            by the Mixed Judicial Commission. The
            Agents and Consuls General belong, wil meet
            in a few days' time in order to give their sanc-
            tion to this important reform.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
            <p>Major-General Slade, C.B, G.O.C, inspected
            the 2nd Company R.R. at 9 a.m. to-day at
            Kasr-el-NiL On Monday next he will inspect
            the 71st Co. A.S.C. Inspections of tho A.O.C.,
            the detachment of the 2nd Rifle Brigade, the
            RA, and the 2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers
            follow on the 9th, 10th, 12th, 16th and 23rd
            inst, respectively.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
            <p>The total number of cases of plague in
            Egypt in 1904 was 843, out of which 501 proved
            fatal. 108 cases occurred at Alexandria and 92
            at Nag Hamadi.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SHEPHEARD’S HOTEL BALL</head>
            <p>Perfect arrangements and organisation
            were manifest at the ball given at Shepheard's
            Hotel on Wednesday night. There was
            no crowding, though a great proportion of
            the 800 invited appeared, the floor of the great
            dining-room was very good, and the supper
            arrangements and buffet were up to the standard
            set by all the other accessories. The decora-
            tions, toilettes, and uniforms made a very
            striking picture, and the dancing was as ani-
            mated as it could be, while the Bracale or-
            chestra played in period time. Of course, the
            cotillon was the event of the evening and was led
            by Mme. Adolphe Cettaui and M. Ferdinand
            de Martino, with all the grace and skill that
            the occasion—and it was a great occasion—
            demanded. After the conclusion of the
            “official programme” the dancers began again
            and it was nearly 4 a.m. before the fast went
            home.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
            <p>By kind permission of Lieut.-Colonel G. M.
            Mackenzie, commanding, and officers 2nd
            Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will
            play the following programme at Shepheard’s
            Hotel on Saturday afternoon from 4 to 6 o’olock:
            Japanese War March- Benzai- Fred. Haines.
            Overture—Ivan—Conterno.
            Song—Pansy Faces—W. H. Penn.
            Musical Comedy—Kitty Grey—Monckton.
            Valse—Pomone—Waldteufel.
            Mazurks Milltaire—Sabre au Clair—Missa.
            Selection—The Earl and the Girl—Caryll
            Polka—The Post Horn-Moore.
            Regimental March.
            Khedivial Anthem.
            God Save the King.
            R. Watson Ramsey, Bandmaster.</p></div>
           <div type="item">  <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
            <p>The renowned Italian musician Puccini,
            composer of La Boheme, La Tosca, and Manon,
            is expected to arrive in Egypt on the 15th inst.</p>
            <p>A marriage has been arranged between
            Captain the Hon. Cuthbert James, Egyptian
            Army, second son of Lord and Lady North-
            bourne, and Florence elder daughter of Mr.
            and lady Alice Packe.</p>
            <p>Sir Thomas Salt, who was formerly in the
            11th Hussars, is to be married in London to
            Miss Nora Wiggin on the 17th inst.</p>
            <p>Leave of absence, pending retirement, has
            been granted to Major EAF. Dawson, 2nd
            Battalion Rifle Brigade, from 23rd December.</p>
            <p>Leave of absence, on medical certificate,
            has been granted to Major H M. Finch,
            2nd Battalion Royal Berks. Regiment, from
            5th inst to February 2.</p>
            <p>Miss L. Jackman, A. N. S. R., has been
            granted leave of absence, on private affairs,
            from 15th inst to February 12.</p>
            <p>Mr. H. C. F. Archer, Inspector of Police,
            Cairo City, has been granted the local rank of
            Saghcolaghasi.</p>
            <p>The death occurred at Cairo yesterday of
            M. Zarzecki, civil engineer attached to the
            Tanzim Service. The deceased was specially
            charged with the supervision of the Rodah
            bridge works.</p>
            <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy
            Hotel, Port Said, we notice Major General
            Slade, C.B., Mr. P. E. Clunn, Mr. E W. Knox
            and party, Mr. and Mrs. Bentley, Mrs. General
            Collis, Capt and Mrs Parvis, Mrs Multiz
            and son, M. and Mme. Bastard.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET</head>
            <p>(From our Financil Correspondent)</p>
            <p>London, December 30.</p>
            <p>The Stock Markets are so closely associated
            with political matters that we most crave
            indulgence if from time to time we refer to
            the latter. Those who look ahead are not at
            all happy as to the outcome of the finan-
            cial position in Russia. Another loan for
            £25,000,000 is on the eve of being launched,
            report says on the 12th January-this time in
            Berlin—4 1/2 per cent. Bonds at 95. This will
            materially increase the weight of the prodi-
            gious "Baby'' now resting on "Dame Europe's”
            lap. France, and her neighbor are so heavily
            involved that they cannot afford to let the
            issue be anything but a so-called success. If
            it were not for this we do not suppose Russia
            would be able to obtain within 20 or 30 points
            of this price for the issue. The cost of the war
            to Russia has so far been estimated at 100
            millions, but we know from sad experience
            that these estimates are well below the mark,
            and that the real figure is generally nearly
            double. With the internal troubles increasing
            throughout the country, the Russian Govern-
            ment will be having its hands full at home as
            well as abroad. The peace negotiations are for
            the moment going slow—so that altogether
            one is not surprised if the old posesores in the
            financial world are inclined to shake their grey
            beads in an ominous fashion. The general
            tone of the market is wonderfully firm,
            exceptionally so far the end of the year.
            South Africans look like opening the New
            Year with higher prices. All the leading pro-
            perties good and hold their prices well
            although business is small at present. The
            Continent has been a persistent buyer of Gold-
            fields. The break in cotton which has
            resulted from over-production in America
            caused a sharp set-back in Egyptian
            Stocks yesterday, Bank shares especially drop-
            ping back nearly a point from Wednesday's
            closing prices, Agriculturals opening 9, and
            Nationals 22. There was some support at
            these prices and a consequent recovery of
            about 1/2 in both cases which is fully maintained.
            Delta Lands, in spite of the forthcoming
            increase of capital by £150,000, keep their
            price well at 2 1/2, and Dairy Sugar remain firm
            and are likely to go higher. There has been
            some demand for Nile Land and Agricultural
            Co.'s shares which stand at about 8, but there is
            little or no free market in them at present.
            Corporation of Western Egypt shares are being
            quoted at a premium, but sotive deal-
            ings cannot be looked for until the turn of the
            New Year. Egyptian Mines are a shade
            steadier, although Nile Valley shares are
            rather dull in tendency, doe to the fact that
            the jobbers did not consider the annual meet-
            ing as satisfactory as it might been.
            Americans are firm again. Consols are dis-
            tinctly good, and investment stocks are all
            firmer, the chief factor being cheap money.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>L'ABOLITION DES CAPITULATIONS.</head>
            <p>Dans sa lettre ouverte a MM. les membres
            de la commission de la reforme des Tribunaux
            Mixtes, publiee dans le No. 23 de son journal
            arabe El Mounnem, mon eminent confrere et
            ami, M. Loatfi bey Ayrout, a exprim4 un desir
            qui fermentait depuis longtemps dans le sein
            de la majorite desinteressee de la population de
            l'Egypte. On ne saurait trop insister sur le
            bien fonde de la theorie qu’il a soulevee.</p>
            <p> Il est interessant de remonter a ce propos a
            l'origine des Tribonaux de la reforme. Dans
            son projet de 1867, adresse aux puissances,
            Nubar Pacha demandait pour lee nouveaux
            Tribunaux le droit de connaitre de toutes les
            infractions commises par les Europeans, quelle
            que soit leur nature; il demandait, en principe,
            l’abrogation complete des capitulations.</p>
            <p>La commission qui sieges a Paris du 8
            Novembre au 3 Decembre 1867 reconnut, dans
            sa decision, la necessite d’obtenir en Egypte
            l'unitfe de legislation et de juridiction; elle
            approuva l’etabllisement des tribunaux mixtes,
            mais elle refuse une competence aussi etendue
            que celle proposee dans le rapport de Nubar.
            Neanmoins, celui-ci ne se decourages pas et en
            Nfianmoins, oelnl-ci ne se dfioouragea pas ettrn
            1869 obtint la reunion au Cairo d’une Commis-
            sion internationale chargee d'etudier le projet.</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAN.</head></div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
                <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                <p>x.10.904</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"> <head> TO WHOLESALE BUYERS STORE-KEEPRS AND OTHER TRADERS</head>
            <p> If you are not a reader of
            "African Commerce," the British Trade
            Medium for All Africa, send 7d. for a
            specimen copy to, The Publisher, "African
            Commerce," Tower Chambers, Moorgate
            Street, London, E.C. Annual subscription
            7/6 port free.</p></div></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
