<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kara Hofmeister</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-05">January 5, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JANUARY 5, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, JANUARY 5, 1905.</head>
            <div type="item">
            <head>RUSSIAN SURRENDER</head>
            <head>JAPANESE CONDITIONS</head>
            <head>25,000 PRISONERS.</head>
            <head>STOESSEL ASKS FORGIVENESS.</head>
            <p>Tokio, January 4.</p>
            <p>The terms of the surrender are contained in
            eleven articles. The garrison and officials are
            prisoners. All the forts and war materials are
            to be transferred to the Japanese. If the Rus-
            sians destroy anything, the negotiations are to
            be annulled, and Japan will then be free to take
            action. The Russians are to give plans of the
            fortifications and mines. Considering the
            gallant resistance made by the place, the Rus-
            sian officers are to be permitted to keep their
            swords and private property. On giving their
            parole, they will be allowed to return to
            Russia. The rank and file in uniform, with
            their portable property, are to assemble, under
            their respective officers, in a place indicated
            by the Japanese. The sanitary corps and the
            accountants are to be retained in order to
            assist in caring for the sick and wounded.</p>
            <p>Russian officers who have reached Chifu
            state that Stoessel's army was originally
            35,000 of whom 11,000 have been killed, and
            16,000 are sick or wounded. There were 8,000
            in the forts, 2,000 of whom were unable to
            fight. During the siege, 265% of the garrison
            were “hors do combat." This remarkable fact
            is due to the wounded having returned to
            the front</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Japanese have made 25,000 prisoners at
            Arthur.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 4.</p>
            <p>General Stoessel, in telegraphing to the
            Tsar his formal surrender, says:—“Great
            Sovereign, forgive us, we have done all that
            was humanly possible. Judge us, but be
            merciful.”</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Tsar has cabled to General Stoessel
            allowing the officers the option between giving
            their parole and imprisonment.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SIGNIFICANT MOVE BY TSAR.</head>
            <head>REVIEWS ABANDONED.</head>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Tsar has cancelled all reviews in the
            provinces. He returns to St Petersburg im-
            mediately.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>AN ERRAND OF MERCY.</head>
            <head>BRITISH RELIEF FOR THE WOUNDED.</head>
            <p>Wei-hai-wei, January 4.</p>
            <p>H.M. cruiser “Andromeda” has left here for
            Port Arthur. She carried 80 tons of medical
            supplies and other comforts for the sick and
            wounded, including 350 beds and 100,000 lbs.
            of provisions. The cargo was rushed on board
            during the night following the granting of
            permission for the errand of mercy.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE MUSCAT AFFAIR.</head>
            <head>APPOINTMENT OF ARBITRATOR.</head>
            <p>The Hague, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Dutch Government has appointed the
            Deputy M. Lohman as arbitrator in connection
            with the Anglo-French difference with reference
            to Muscat. The affair is to be settled by the
            Hague Tribunal.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>HUNGARIAN DIET.</head>
            <head>DISSOLVED BY THE EMPEROR.</head>
            <p>Budapest, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Emperor has dissolved the Diet. The
            ceremony passed undisturbed. The Opposition
            was absent.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Budapest, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Speech from the Throne closing the
            session states that the situation necessitates an
            appeal to the electors.</p>
            <p>(Havas)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>HELLENIC CHAMBER.</head>
            <head>DATE OF GENERAL ELECTION.</head>
            <p>Athens, January 4.</p>
            <p>The Chamber of Deputies has been dissolved.</p>
            <p>The general election will take place on
            March 5 next.</p>
            <p>(Havas)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
            <p>The Branch Office of Messrs. Thos. Cook
            A Son (Egypt), Ltd., opposite the Savoy
            Hotel, Cairo, is now open.</p>
            <p> Bubonic Plaque.—To-day's bulletin records
            a fresh case at Toukh, where a patient died in
            hospital and another was discharged as
            cured.</p>
            <p>Business Notice.—Mr. Edward Nathan has
            ceased to be a member of the firm of B. Nathan
            and Co., Alexandria. Mr. Victor F. Naggiar
            has also retired from the business.</p>
            <p>The End of a 'Bull'.—Our Zifta Correspon-
            dent writes under yesterday’s date announc-
            ing that a Greek had hanged himself in the
            Mit Ghamr district owing to his great cotton
            losses.</p>
            <p>The British Turbine Yacht “Emerald,''
            about whose movements during the passage
            through the Canal of the Baltic Fleet there
            was so much speculation, arrived at Alexandria
            yesterday from Port Said.</p>
            <p>Motor Transport Company. — We hear
            that a motor transport company has Just
            been founded in Cairo under the auspices
            of Rostovitz Bey, George Nungovich Bey,
            and Messrs. Lonkas and Lonkaitis.</p>
            <p>The Italian Consulate—The lease of the
            present habitation of the Italian Consulate at
            Cairo, in the Ismalia quarter, has been renew-
            ed, the scheme for removing the consulate to
            Kasr-el-Nil or Shoubra having been postponed
            for the time being.</p>
            <p>Verdi Theatre, Cairo.—Part of the Italian
            operatic company at the Verdi have resolved
            to stay on and try their fortune at the theatre.
            We congratulate them on their decision and
            hope that they will have no cause to repent.
            The Cairo public should do their best to help
            them.</p>
            <p>Siemens-Schuckert-Werke—The firm's ge-
            neral agency of Cairo, up to the present under
            the direction of Messrs. Orwnsein &amp; Koppel
            and Mr. Gustav Grob, has been handed over
            exclusively to the latter. Mr. Gustav Grobb,
            E.E., is now the sole representative of the
            house for Egypt and the Sudan.</p>
            <p>Fatal Collapse of a Roof. — At an early
            hour this morning the roof of an old and
            delapidated tenement in Sisters-street, Alex-
            andria, collapsed over a bedroom while the
            occupants, Mr. and Mrs. Baila, were still in
            bed. The former was awakened by a rumbling
            noise, and believing that robbers had entered
            the house, rushed out of the room. When he
            returned he found his wife had been buried
            in the ruins and asphyxiated. The police are
            engaged in removing the body from the debris.</p>
            <p>Children's Savings Bank.—On tho 16th
            inst, the Egyptian Post Office scheme for
            Childrens’ Savings Banks will come into force.
            For the present the area of its operations will
            be confined to Cairo, Alexandria, and Port-Said.
            Each child desiring to deposit will be furnished
            with a booklet. When five milliemes are
            collected a stamp will be bought and put in
            the booklet and when the sum of one shilling
            (10 stamps of P.T. 1/2) is attained, the amount
            will be deposited in the Post Office Savings
            bank</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
            <p>The Khedive has gone to Edfina from Mon-
            tazah.</p>
            <p>His Highness will attend Friday prayers to-
            morrow at Montazah mosque.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
            <p>(Aujourd'hui a midi et demie)</p>
            <p>Le marche des valeurs se maintient forme
            et a la hausse.</p>
            <p>A signaler en particulier la Salt and Soda
            qui, sur da forte orders d’achat, a attaint dans
            la matinee le prix do 41/9; le oours a flechi
            en cloture a 41 scheteurs, 4 a 5000 titres ont
            ete echanges entre 40 el 41/9.</p>
            <p>La Banque Nationale debute a 23 1/4 et
            atteint 23 1/2, prix auquel elle cloture. De
            nombreuses transactions ont eu lieu.</p>
            <p>Tres ferme egalement la Dairs a 21 5/8 et
            la Filature d’Alexandrie a 13/16 acheteurs.
            Cette derniere a meme atteint a un moment
            donne 27/32.</p>
            <p>Toutes les autres valeurs se maintiennent
            formes ou sont en hauase.</p>
            <p>La tendance generale est bonne et one fois
            les fetes passes on s'attend a un redoublement
            d'activie sur notre marchd.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten miniutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron
                        Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
            <div type="item"> <head>RAMLEH ELECTRIC RAILWAY</head>
            <head>THE PUBLIC AGITATION.</head>
            <p>The Theatre at Bacos station was filled
            yesterday evening by a crowd of about 200
            persons for the purpose of discussing the
            new tariff instituted by the board of directors
            of the Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Com-
            pany. The meeting began at about 8.30 p.m.,
            when the chairman, Mr. Benjamin Arbib,
            made a statement as to the attitude which
            the board of directois had taken up towards
            the committee of Ramlehites, who had en-
            deavoured to set their grievances before
            them. He said that all the inhabitants of
            Ramleh should demand the maintenance of
            the former season-tickct system. This was
            the one aud only programme which the com-
            mittee would ask the board to take into con-
            sideration, as although there were many
            questions pending between the population of
            Ramleh and the company, these did not ne-
            cessarily call for immediate settlement.</p>
            <p>Mr. Halil Zenia then spoke in Arabic and
            expressed himself as being in hearty agreement
            with the opinions of the chairman.</p>
            <p>Many other speakers followed and gavo vont
            to a number of various and conflicting sugges-
            tions for settling the question at issue.</p>
            <p>Chevalier Rouci, chairman of the Tenants'
            Defence Committee, then rose and, in an im-
            passioned oration in Italian, announced that
            the cause of Ramleh was also the cause of the
            committee over which he presided.</p>
            <p>Mr. Geo. B. Alderson shortly afterwards ar-
            rived on the scene and was greeted with
            acclamation. A scene of great enthusiasm
            followed, and afterwards Mr. Alderson’s scheme
            for settling the problem was given forth to the
            meeting in Italian by Mr. Quintavalle.</p>
            <p>The meeting broke up at 11 p.m. All the
            persons attending the meeting refused to pay
            their fares both on going and coming to the
            meeting. The employes of the Company did
            not make any fuss.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THIS MORNING'S DEVELOPMENTS.</head>
            <p>Great excitement prevailed on the line this
            morning. The meeting last night was the
            subject of universal discussion by the passen-
            gers. As a large number persisted in refusing
            to pay the fare the company was obliged to
            seek for the assistanoe of the Alexandria City
            Police. Fifteen policemen were placed at the
            service of the company in order to draw up
            “proces-verbaux" in cases of non-payment of
            fares. Some angry Ramlehites tried to rush
            through the cordon of police and a scene of
            considerable excitement ensued. But the
            majority of them accepted the situation with
            an air of peaceful resignation and agreed to
            pay tho fares. The police were stationed at
            the gate of the station and asked each passen-
            ger arriving from Ramleh for his or her ticket</p>
            <p>As we go to press we learn that matters are
            proceeding quietly and that no serious distur-
            bance has as yet taken place. We understand,
            however, that the agitators do not intend to
            let things resume their normal course unless
            the directors give way, and that other mani
            festations against the new system will take
            place shortly.</p>
            <p>The committee of Ramlehites will meet the
            directors to-day, in order to ascertain from
            them if they intend to bow to the wishes of the
            inhabitants. Another general public meeting of
            Ramlehites will be held on Saturday evening
            next at 9 o’clock at the Bacos Theatre.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>“G.B." AND THE SITUATION.</head>
            <p>Mr. Geo. B. Alderson writes:—The company
            have right on their side, to a certain extent.
            I have noticed how travellers look at the
            "oommissaires" and say “Abonne.” They may
            have been, as myself, an abonne for 40 years,
            but the commissaire may have been employed
            40 hours only and knows not the “Abonne"
            of 40 years. I have also noticed how tra-
            vellers take tickets to Ibrahimieh and go past
            it, and if asked, pay the difference. Control,
            under these conditions, is difficult for the
            company. Their right to annul season tickets
            without giving a “quid proquo” I dispute—and
            should wish to have it brought before tribunals
            to decide. But I suggest, to meet all parties
            amicably, that the company issue to all
            residents or householders who wish to be
            abonnes and have a right at old price ‘‘carnets’’
            special for 3, 6, 9, or 12 months, calculated
            at 4 journeys per day. Each "carnet" to be
            for 3, 6, 9, or 12 months, paid in advance
            and every ticket dated and personal, but
            each quarter the "carnet” to be returned to the
            company, and any tickets unusrd to be accept-
            ed back by the company at 50% on its value.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE HEDJAZ RAILWAY.</head>
            <p>Marshal Kiazim Pasha has sent the follow-
            ing report to the Grand Vizier:—The Maan-
            El-Hassa section has been completed, and the
            military engineers are now working on the
            embankment beyond Maan, the rails being
            laid as the line is built. The line has also
            been finished between kilometres 490 and 520.
            Important levelling work is now being done on
            the Haiffa section. Tunnel No. 1 is in course
            of construction, and No. 2 is making favor-
            able progress.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>GRAND HOTEL HELOUAN.</head>
            <p>The Bracale orchestra will play the follow-
            ing programme on the terrace of the hotel
            tomorrow from 3 to 5 p.m.</p>
            <p>Marche—Militar Revue-Czibulka
            Valse—Fruhlingsstimmen—Strauss.
            Serenade—....—Pierne.
            Valse des Amoureuz-Ragglianti
            Fontaisie—Carmen—Bizet
            Potpourri—Die Fledarmans —Strauss.
            Mazurka—Violettes Rosses-Eavan.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SUEZ CANAL DUES.</head>
            <head>REPORTED REDUCTION.</head>
            <head>(From our own Correspondent)</head>
            <p>Port-Said, Thursday.</p>
            <p>Although as yet not officially admitted, I
            have it on reliable authority that it has been
            decided in Paris to reduce the Canal dues from
            8 fes. 50 cms. per ton to 8 fes. Bridge deck
            dues will still be charged.</p>
            <p>The date on which the reduction will come
            into force is not yet known.</p>
            <p>On the 31st ulto. 13 vessels psssed through
            the Canal, viz., 7 British, 1 Austrian, 1 French,
            1 Norwegian, 1 German, 2 Dutch; the re-
            ceipts for the day being frs. 852,274.76.</p>
            <p>The returns for the year 1904 show that
            during the twelve months ended December 31,
            4,257 ships entered the Canal, the total amount
            received in dues being 114,875,154.68 frs,
            an increase of frs 12,292,113.41 over the
            preceding year. In 1903 the number of ships
            passing through the canal was 3,775. The year
            just closed, therefore, shows an increase in the
            total, as compared with 1903, of 482 vessels, a
            considerable advance on last year’s figures,
            which only showed an excess of 67 when com-
            pared with 1902. If we take the number of
            ships returned during the past six years as
            having used the Canal the great increase in
            number during 1904 beoomes still more marked,
            the respective totals being:-</p>
            <p>1899-	3,607	1902-3,708
            1900-	3,441	1903—3,775
            1901-	3,699	1904—4,257</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BIBBY LINE</head>
            <p>The steamer "Worcestershire" having proved
            herself such a complete success, and commend-
            ed herself to the many passengers by her on
            her maiden voyage, Messrs. Bibby Brothers
             Co., have placed with Messrs. Harland &amp;
            Wolff of Belfast, an order for a sister ship, to
            be called the "Herefordshire,” the construction
            of which is now being proceeded with. With the
            advent of this steamer, the “Lancashire" and
            “Yorkshire," which have in the past done such
            good service in the line, will drop out as soon
            as possible—indeed they will not again appear
            in the lists for the busy season, either outwards
            or homewards. The Bibby Line will therefore
            in future be composed entirely of twin screw
            steamers of the most up-to-date type. Outward
            passengers via Marseilles will be glad to know
            that it has been arranged that they can now
            leave London a day later, say on the Thursday
            morning, embarkation at Marseilles being fixed
            for noon on Friday. This extension of time
            will not alter the time at which the steamers
            will arrive in the East, which will be as here-
            tofore.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EXPEDITION VIA KHARTOUM.</head>
            <p>Mr. J. J. Harrison left London last week for
            Khartoum on his second expedition on the
            Congo. He intends to travel along the west
            side, bordering on the Nile and Ituri district
            He hopes to be able to secure an okapi in the
            forest region. Mr. Harrison has obtained leave
            in Brussels to bring home some pigmies.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SUDAN EXPLORATION CAPITAL</head>
            <p>An extraordinary general meeting of the
            Sudan Exploration, Limited, was held last
            week for the purpose of considering a resolu-
            tion for increasing the capital to £100,000,
            by the creation of 80,000 new shares of 10s.
            each, to rank for dividend and in all other
            respects pari passu with the existing shares
            of the company. Mr. Edgar Anderson, who
            presided, moved the resolution, and it was
            agreed to.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SLEEPING SICKNESS IN THE
            SUDAN.</head>
            <p>A short time ago we published an article by
            the director of the Gordon College Laboratories
            on Trypanosomiasis in the Sudan, which was
            reproduced from a London medical paper.</p>
            <p>We are requested to state that some portions
            of the artiole appear to have been inaccurately
            printed. We may point out that it has not
            been proved that trypanosomiasis in man, i.e.,
            tree sleeping sickness spread by Glossina
            palpalis, exists in the Sudan.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EXPORT OF GUM ARABIC.</head>
            <p>During the month of November last, 868,243
            kilos of gum arabic, valued at L.E. 19,412, were
            exported from Egypt. In the same month of
            1903 the exports were 730,738 kilos, of the
            value of L.E. 16,426, showing an increase this
            year 132,505 kilos, value L.E. 2,986.</p>
            <p>From the 1st January to 30th November
            1904, the exports show increases of 1,532,316
            kilos in weight and of L.E. 31,144 in amount
            as compared with 1903, the respective figures
            being as follows:- 1904, 9,370,440 killos, value
            L.E. 210,843; 1903, 7,838,124 kilos, value
            L.E. 179,699.</p>
            <p>Of the above, the export to England and
            her Mediterranean possessions was 1,737,422
            kilos, value L.E. 39,091; Germany, 1,559,925
            kilos, value L.E. 35,099; Austria-Hungary,
            664,921 kilos, value L.E. 14958; France and
            Algeria, 2,555,552 kilos, value L.E. 57,474;
            Italy, 260,548 kilos, value L.E. 5,849; Turkey,
            12,303 kilos, value L.E. 269; America, 1,380,571
            kilos, value L.E. 31,062., and to other countries
            1,200,198 kilos, value L.E 27,044.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
                    <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>x.10.904</p>
                </div>
            <div type="item"> <head> PILGRIMAGE REGULATIONS</head>
            <head>TEXT OF GOVERNMENT NOTE.</head>
            <p>The following is a translation of ths Note
            issued yesterday by the Egyptian Govern-
            ment:-</p>
            <p>The different measures taken by the Egyptian
            Government with regard to persons desiring to
            make the pilgrimage to the Holy Places have
            been prompted by two motives:</p>
            <p>1.	To insure tho greatest freedom and
            facilities to all who wish to fulfil this sacred
            duty, while guarding them from all useless
            expenditure and from the dangers of the
            journey, and giving them all the medical
            attention that their health during the pilgrim-
            age may necessitate.</p>
            <p>2.	To control the return of the pilgrims
            with a view to the avoidance of epidemics,
            which are always possible. In this connection
            the circular addressed to all moudirs and
            governors on November 16, 1904, deserves to
            be noted. This circular states that every
            Egyptian has the right to make the pilgrimage
            whenever his means allow of it, and that if he
            fears to travel alone the Government gives
            him the opportunity of accompanying the
            Mehtmal, being anxious to make the pilgrimage
            as easy as possible.</p>
            <p>Last year the same measures were taken and
            600 pilgrims asked to be allowed to accompany
            the Mahmal. This year 1,614 had inscribed
            their names on the list of those desirous to
            accompany the Mahmal before it was closed.</p>
            <p>Those who have already left for the Hedjaz
            admit that the oooditions imposed on the
            pilgrims who accompany the Mahmal are
            pecuniarily the most advantageous, not to
            mention the advantages of military protection
            and medical assistance.</p>
            <p>If the pilgrim travels alone he must make a
            deposit of P.T. 156 at the Moudirieh whence
            he draws his passport, of which P.T. 100
            represents the rations given him by the Go-
            vernment in the quarantine camp at Tor and
            P.T. 56 the quarantine expenses. If, as is
            usually the case, he travels 3rd class, he will
            have to pay some LE 5 for his return ticket
            on the Khedivial mail boat and once in the
            Hedjaz will have to find a camel. Even if one
            camel is taken by two pilgrims there is no
            chance of getting one for less than LE 18 or
            20 even for the journey from Jeddah to Mecca
            and Arafat and thence to Yambo. Taking this
            cause as a test the 3rd class pilgrim will have
            to pay:-
            Deposit... ......................   P.T.	156
            Return ticket. .................... „	500
            Minimum half share in one camel.	„	900
            P.T. 1,586
            without counting the alms and bakhshish
            which he will be obliged to pay.</p>
            <p>If, on the other hand, he travels with the
            Mahmal he will only have to pay.
            Deposit...................... P.T.	156
            Transport and return.......... „	300
            Half share in a camel......... „	675
            Unforeseen expenses...	...	...	„	69
            P.T. 1,200</p>
            <p>But in reality this is only a deposit, and if
            the camel hire does not reach the fixed price
            and there are no unforeseen expenses the sur-
            plus will be returned to him.</p>
            <p>So far from profiting the Government, these
            measures are decidedly costly owing to the
            necessary arrangements with the Khedivial
            Mail S. S. Co. by the guarantee of a mini-
            mum number of pilgrims in return for the
            reduction of fares.</p>
            <p>This year, moreover, the Government has
            not hesitated to bring the escort of the
            Mahmal up to 400 men, this increase of 280
            men involving an additional expenditure of
            LE 5,000. In spite of this the obligatory depos-
            its are not be increased.</p>
            <p>Only the deposits of the lowest class cover
            all the expenses. As for the others, if the
            price of a camel is the same as last year
            the Government will pay the difference itself
            to convince the pilgrims of its anxiety for
            their comfort and welfare.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>CAIRO ZOOLOGICAL GARDENS.</head>
            <p>On Sunday, 8th inst., in honor of the Khe-
            dive’s acceesion to the throne, the Egyptian
            Army Infrnatry Band, being required in Cairo,
            will not play at QGhizieh. The drums and fifes
            of the Ghizieh Boys’ Band will play in the
            Zoological Gardens from 3 to 5 p.m. on
            that day.</p>
            <p>Among the additions to the Zoological
            Gordons during December, 1904, were a grivet
            monkey, presented by Lieut. A. Sargent,
            Army Ordnance Department, a Soemmerring’s
            gazelle and a Hedjaz sheep born in the
            gardens, and the following animals pur
            chased :—two marmosets, one of the white
            and one of the black whiskered race, a
            greater mealy amazon-parrot, a Levaillant’s
            amazon-parrot, two white-shafted francolins
            from Massowah, several beautiful little wax-
            bills and weaver birds from Tropical Africa,
            and some flamingoes from Lake Menzalah.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
            <p>The Meseageries Maritimes SS. ‘Sydney"
            arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria yester-
            day at 9 a.m.</p>
            <p>The Ellerman SS. "Britannia" arrived to-
            day from Fiume.</p>
            <p>The Canard SS "Brescia" arrived at Liver-
            pool on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
            <p>The Khedivial Mail SS “El Kahira" will
            leave Alexandria on Sunday for Jaffa, Caiffa,
            Beyrout, Tripoli, Mersina, Alexandretta, Lar-
            naos, Limassol and Port Said.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
            <head>DEPARTURE INDEFINITELY
            POSTPONED.</head>
            <head>(From our own Correspondent.)</head>
            <p>Port Said, Thursday.</p>
            <p>The departure of the Russian fleet from
            Ceuta Bay has been indefinitely postponed.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>OUR ROYAL VISITORS</head>
            <p>On the conclusion of the Duke and Duchess
            of Connaught's stay in Cairo, they will proced
            by rail to Luxor and will then go on in the
            steamer “Isis” to Wady Halfa and will continue
            their voyage to Khartoum by rail. The arrange-
            ments for the Royal journey to the Sudan ere
            in the capable hands of Nungovich Bey.</p>
            <p>We understand that it is not the Crown
            Prince of Sweden and Norway, but his esdest
            son, H. R H. Prince Gustaf Adolf; who is
            coming to Egypt on a visit His Royal
            Highness is expected in Cairo on the 16th
            inst and will put up at Shepheard's Hotel.
            His Royal Highness is accompaniad by Baron
            de Ralamb, his aide-de-camp.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>CAIRO FETE COMMITTEE</head>
            <head>LAST NIGHTS BALL</head>
            <p>The ball given at Shepheard's last night was
            a huge success, and reflected the greatest credit-
            on the organising powers of the Cairo Fete Com-
            mittee. Nearly all the leading members of Cairo
            society were present, also a large number of
            visitors, and the scene in the ball-room was a
            most brilliant one, especially during the cotillon,
            which began on the stroke of midnight and
            was led by Mme Cottaui and Mr. De Martino.</p>
            <p>We believe that this is the first occasion on
            which all the principal hotels have combined
            in organising a fete on such a large scale, and
            the success of the experiment is of good augury
            for the future.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
            <p>H H. the Maharajah of Khapurtala and suite
            are expected in Cairo early in March. Large
            apartments have been reserved at the Ghe-
            rireh Palace for his Highness and suite.</p>
            <p>The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire and
            Mr. and Mrs. MacGuire are leaving Marseilles
            on the 20th inst, and are expeoted at the
            Savoy Hotel, Cairo, on the 25th.</p>
            <p>Sir Ernest Cassell, Lord and Lady Howes,
            the Hon. Mr. and Mrs. Colebrooks, with a
            party of friends, are leaving Marseilles on the
            27th inst and are expected at the Savoy on
            the 3rd February.</p>
            <p>Lord and Lady Cromer have postponed their
            journey up-river till the beginning of February.</p>
            <p>Mr. Vincent Corbett will leave for Khartoum
            to-morrow. He will be absent for three or four
            weeks.</p>
            <p>Count Teziersky and suite are expected
            back at the Bristol, Cairo, from their shooting
            expedition in the Zudan, at the mid of the
            month.</p>
            <p>Sir Colin Scott-Moncrieff, hit wife, and two
            daughters left England on Tuesday last
            for Egypt, where they will pass four months.
            Sir Colin has taken a dahabieh, and the late
            Under Secretary of State for Public Works is
            looking forward to re-visiting many scenes of
            his former labors.</p>
            <p>Lady Magheramorne, who is to marry Lord
            Cromer's nephew, Mr. Hugo Baring, has been
            a widow not quite two yean. She was the
            second of the five beautiful daughters of the
            eighth Earl of Shaftesbury, of whom the other
            four married the Earl of Mar and Kellie, Sir
            George Warrendcr, Mr. George Allsopp, end
            Mr. Levett. Lady Evelyn Ashley married the
            second Baron Magheramorne, Sir James Doa-
            glss McGarel-Hogg, in 1889, when she was
            twenty-four, and has one charming daughter
            who is now in her fifteenth year. Lady Maghe-
            ramorne, though well known and very popular
            in society, is still better known in county
            Antrim, for country life appeals very strongly
            to her.</p>
            <p>Mr. Hugo Baring is the youngest brother of
            Lord Revelstoke. He is twenty-eight, end was
            a lieutenant in the 4th Hussars. He served
            with some distinction in the Transvasl War,
            and still carries the scars of that campaign.</p>
            <p>The marriage of Miss Dorothy Wynn (sister
            of Lord Newborough) to Commander Cuthbert
            Chapman, is fixed for February 1 at the pictu-
            resque Chapel Royal, Savoy, where Lord and
            Lady Newborough themselves were married
            four years ago. After the wedding Commander
            Chapman and his bride will leave for Italy and
            Egypt.</p>
            <p>The rumour as to Saba Pasha’s retirement
            appears to have arisen in some mysterious
            way from Journalistic speculations as to
            Kaimakam Borton Bey's future post.</p>
            <p>The Sanitary Administration has authorised
            Mr. Augustus Newton to practice as a phar-
            macist in Egypt.</p></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
