<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Jacob Stefonek</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">"2016-10-11"</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-26">"1905-04-26"</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7183] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, APRIL 26, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY APRIL 26, 1306.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">

                    <head>Royal Insurance Coy</head>

                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>

                    <p>Largest Fire Office in the World.</p>

                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>

                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.</p>

                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>

                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782); </p>

                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria. </p>

                    <p>31-3-906 FRED. OTT &amp; CO., Sub-Agents, Cairo.</p>

                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">

                    <head>N. SPATHIS</head>

                    <p>THE BRITISH AERATED &amp; MINERAL WATER MANUFACTORY. </p>

                    <p>CAIRO Exbekieh ALEXANDRIA Rue Avernoff</p>

                    <p>Soda Water. Lemonade, Ginger Ale, Ginger Beer. Tonic Water </p>

                    <p>Pomegranade, Orangeaade, Pineapple, Champagne, Cider, etc., etc. </p>

                    <p> Water guaranteed by Chamberlain’s Filter (Pasteur’s System).</p>

                    <p>Inventor of WHISKY &amp; SODA and BRANDY &amp; SODA, bottled ready for
                        use.</p>

                    <p> Sole Agents in Egypt and Soudan for </p>

                    <p> J. Calvet &amp; Co. Bordeaux. Wine &amp; Cognacs.</p>

                    <p>Louis Roederer. Rheims. Champagnes.</p>

                    <p>August Engel. Wiesbaden. Rhine and Moselle Wines.</p>

                    <p>Mackie &amp; Co. Glasgow. Lagavulin, White Horse Cellar &amp; other
                        Whiskies.</p>

                    <p>Dunville &amp; Co, Ltd. Belfast. Old Irish Whiskies.</p>

                    <p>Wm. Lanahan &amp; Son. Baltimore. Monongshels XXXX Whiskey.</p>

                    <p>The Cook &amp; Bernheimer Co. New York. Old Valley Whiskey and Gold Lion
                        Cocktails.</p>

                    <p>Stone &amp; Son. London. Guinness' Stout &amp; Bass' Pale Ale.</p>

                    <p>Freund Ballor &amp; Co. Tornio. Vermouth.</p>

                    <p>Pierre Bisset. Cette. Vermouth &amp; Aperitives.</p>

                    <p>Terrabonatea Company, Ld. Teas.</p>

                    <p>Depot for Prince Metternich's "Richardsquelle," the best mineral table water
                        in the world.</p>

                    <p>Great assortment of Wines, Spirits, Liqueurs, of the finest Brands, etc</p>

                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</head>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS.—Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including
                        delivery in Alexandria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231 1/2 per
                        annum, P.T. 116 for six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries
                        in the Postal Union P.T. S73 (£2.16.) per annum. Six months P.T. 136 1/2
                        (£1.88.), three months P.T. 92 (£0.19s.) N.B.—Subscriptions commence from
                        the 1st or 16th of any month.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.—P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages,
                        or Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20. Every additional line P.T.
                        10. Notices in news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for
                        standing advertisements.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS are due in advance. P.O. - Orders and
                        Cheques to be made payable to the Editor and Manager, Rowland Snelling,
                        Alexandria. London Offices : 36, New Broad-street. R.C.</p>
                    <p>THE "EGYPTIAN GAZETTE" IS PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE
                        LONDON PAPER MILLS Co. LIMITED. (SALES OFFICE:27 CANNON STREET, E.C.)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian Gazette An English Daily Newspaper, Established in 1880
                        Editor and Manager : R. Snelling. Price 1 One Plastre Tariff.</head>
                    <p>WEDNESDAY APRIL 26, 1905.</p>
                    <p>STAGGING IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Recent events in connection with company promoting might lead the man in the
                        street to suppose that of the million pounds of cash recently paid into the
                        Anglo-Egyptian Bank in Alexandria and Cairo to cover the applications for
                        the ten million shares in the last flotation, there will shortly be some
                        £300,000 available for investment elsewhere. In our opinion this is absurd,
                        for it toast not be supposed that all this application money is money
                        awaiting investment. It is to a great extent money borrowed, money
                        temporarily withdrawn from other uses, or money scraped together somehow in
                        order to snatch the premium on every share allotted. The premium quoted in
                        the market on recent flotations for some days before the subscription list
                        was opened was in a great measure the secret of the enormous number of
                        applications. People thought they conld be immediately selling their
                        allotments, and would at once secure a handsome profit on the money
                        suooessfally deposited for a few days. Neither the question of the soundness
                        of the business nor the desirability of the investment ever enters the heads
                        of these stags. The rush was to a great extent one of premium-hunters and
                        not of investors, and we would suggest to those who may be arguing among
                        themselves that if more companies similar to those recently floated are
                        offered to the public they will meet with as good a welcome, is not by any
                        means a certainty.</p>
                    <p>The stag has always been a puzzle to issuing houses in every financial
                        centre, and no satisfactory means has as yet been discovered of eliminating
                        him. The issuing capitalists do not desire to eliminate the stags among
                        their friends, but they do desire to eliminate the stranger stag. For a time
                        it was customary in London to make allotments as freely as possible to small
                        applicants, and the stag, seeing this, split his big application into small
                        sums. Then the issuing house took to disregarding the small applicant
                        altogether, much to the disappointment of the stag, who abandoned his
                        trickery. Seeing that most of the last Japanese loan was issued once again
                        to small applicants, the stag at home must find some difficulty in knowing
                        how to effectively apply, while the issuing house is put to some trouble in
                        dodging him. There is, however, a new way, made in Germany. In connection
                        with the important new Imperial loan, an arrangement is made by which those
                        who do not desire to sell their allotments for six months pay 101 10 pet
                        cent, while those who desire to sell before that must pay 101 20 per oent
                        The arrangement not only givee the real investor an advantage over the mere
                        stag, but it also enables the issuing house to discriminate between the two
                        classes of applicants. Perhaps some day we shall adopt the system for
                        Egyptian flotations.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET, NIEBOGATOFF'S DIVISION. WHERE IS IT?</head>
                    <p>New York, April 25.</p>
                    <p>The correspondent of the “New York Sun” at Saigon has arrived from Kamaranh.
                        He reports passing at 10 o'clock on Sunday morning, 30 miles to the south of
                        Kamaranh, nine large vessels, unloading a battleship and cruiser. He
                        believes the vessels form Niebogatoff’s division.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>Kamaranh, April 25.</p>
                    <p>It is believed that twenty Japanese destroyers passed off the bay on Sunday.
                        (Havas.)</p>

                    <p>London, April 25.</p>
                    <p>Although the whereabouts of Niebogatoff are unknown, it is not believed that
                        he passed the Straits of Malacca unperceievd, even it he has crossed the
                        Ocean.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>Saigon, April 25.</p>
                    <p>The Baltic Fleet has captured two steamers from Saigon to Japan laden with
                        rice. (R.)</p>

                    <p>RODJESTVENSKY BETTER.</p>
                    <p>Saigon, April 25.</p>
                    <p>It is stated in Kamaranh that Rodjestvensky is now better. (Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>JAPANESE HOSPITAL-SHIP.</p>
                    <p>London, April 25.</p>
                    <p>The "Morning Post” learns from Shanghai that a Japanese hospital ship passed
                        the Raugtse estuary on Sunday afternoon. She was travelling southwards.</p>
                    <p>( Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>TRAIN SERVICE TO MUKDEN.</p>
                    <p>London, April 25.</p>
                    <p>Reuter’s correspondent with Oku reports that the first train has reached
                        Mukden, crossing the Hun-Ho on a temporary bridge. A regular service from
                        Dalny is being arranged.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>THIBET.</p>
                    <p>THE MURDER OF THE AMBAN.</p>
                    <p>London, April 25. </p>
                    <p>The Government has received from Peking confirmation of the murder of the
                        Amban and the whole of his escort. There are no particulars. (Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>SITUATION IN CRETE.</p>
                    <p>Rome, April 25.</p>
                    <p>M. Tittoni and the British, French, and Russian Ambassadors have conferred
                        together on the subject of the situation in Crete. (R.)</p>

                    <p>Malta, April 25.</p>
                    <p>H.M.S. "Leviathan," with Admiral Lambton on board, "Lancaster" and "Minerva”
                        have left for Crete.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>FRANCE AND MOROCCO. DETAILED DISCUSSION PROCEEDING. </p>
                    <p>Paris, April 25.</p>
                    <p>The "Temps” learns from Tangier that a detailed discussion on the French
                        proposals is proceeding at Fez. The attitude of the Moorish Government
                        appears to be quite satisfactory An agreement has been reached on several
                        essential points. (Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>BANKER'S HEAVY DEFALCATIONS. £300,000 LOST THROUGH SPECULATION.</p>
                    <p>Chicago, April 25.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Bigelow, President of the First National Bank at Milwaukee, has been
                        arrested for defalcations amounting tb £300,000 through speculations in
                        wheat. (Reater.)</p>

                    <p>UNVEILING OF GAMBETTA’S STATUE.</p>
                    <p>Bordeaux, April 25.</p>
                    <p>The unveiling of the statue to Gambetta was a solemn ceremony. (Havas.)</p>

                    <p>EPSOM RACES.</p>
                    <p>London, April 25.</p>
                    <p>Great Metropolitan Stakes. 1, Long Tom ; 2, Karakoul; 3, Caro City. Betting 8
                        to 1 against Dean Swift and 100 to 9 against Laveuse, Ob Pharisee and
                        Queen’s Holiday; 100 to 7 against Vril and Sansovino. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZZETTE, WEDNESDAY, APRIL 26, 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL, CRUISE. KING'S VISIT TO PARIS.</head>
                    <p>Marseilles, April 25.</p>
                    <p>King Edward lands here on the 29th inst. and reaches Paris in the evening. He
                        will have an interview with M. Loubet on Sunday or Monday.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G.P.O, Alexandria, at 6:30 p.m.
                        to-day.</p>

                    <p>The Pension Law. — The details of the new Pension Law are still under
                        discussion and nothing has yet been definitely settled.</p>

                    <p>Foot and Mouth Disease exists in Cairo and in the province of Ghizeh and
                        Dakahlieh Mention of this is made on bills of health delivered at all
                        Egyptian ports.</p>

                    <p>Postal Management.-Althoughour Cairo news budget was handed in at the G.P.O.,
                        Cairo, before 10 o'clock yesterday eveuing, owing to some mismanagement on
                        the part of the Postal Administration it bad not arrived as we went to press
                        at 2 p.m. to-day</p>
                    <p>A Native Thief went Monday afternoon to a jeweller's shop at Khan Khalil and
                        asked the proprietor, M. Carissiau, to show him some jewels. He made a
                        purchase and departed, but the jeweller found that articles to the value of
                        £250 had been stolen. The native has not been arrested.</p>

                    <p>The Bar of Messrs. Walker and Meiuaracht is springing rapidly into life, like
                        the Phoenic from its ashes. No expense is to be spared in making it, not
                        only the first bar in Alexandria, but the most magnificent bar in Africa.
                        The inauguration of the bar and of the store will take place simultaneously
                        next June.</p>

                    <p>The Cleopatra Cigarettes Company (of which Messrs. Nuungovich Bey and C.
                        Memarachi are the founders) have been appointed purveyors of their
                        well-known high class cigarettes to H.H. the Khedive. The Company is to be
                        congratulated on such signal honor being conferred on it so early in its
                        career.</p>

                    <p>A Desperate Suicide.—A few days ago a Greek, aged 25 years, threw himseld in
                        frot of a goods train near Salt el Muluk, Teh el-Baroud, but
                        the-engine-drive drew up in time. The Greek then rushed to the canal close
                        by and tried to throw himself in, but ne was prevented by a passerby. He
                        however, got free and finally succeeded in jumping into the canal, where he
                        perished.</p>

                    <p>Prince Colibri—The stay in Alexandria of this interesting man in miniature
                        has been prolonged for another 8 days, in cousequence of the general desire
                        of the public to be afforded further opportunities of seeing so remarkable a
                        sight. The little man will remain at his present quarters, adjoining the
                        Aihambra Theatre, and no one should miss paying him a visit.</p>

                    <p>Happiness in the Harem.—Discontented women, according to an American girl
                        quoted here, should at once join a harem. "I" can assure my American
                        sisters," she is reported to-say, "that they can dream of no greater bliss
                        than to enter a rich nd well-bred Eastern gentleman's harem." Sue has tried
                        the life herself, and is happy as the day is long since she became one of
                        the wives of a potentate, described as Nasruilah Khan, "In a harem," she
                        continues,"life glides softly, like a sweet, peaceful dream. Each wife has
                        her servants. Our slaves obey our least sign of command, and they can never
                        leave us. We can punish their least fault hy cutting off their heads, or, at
                        any rate, having them flogged." This sounds alluring, indeed. Finally, it
                        appears that bad temper, sceces, jealousies, bickerings, are unknown in a
                        harem, and the lord and master is unflaggingly attentive, and never
                        grumbles. The lady urges all American girls to find a harem instantly, and
                        apply for a berth therein, if they want to know perfect bliss, ("Daily
                        Telegraph's" Paris correspondent).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE OF ZAGAZIG.</head>
                    <p>A correspondent at Zagazig writes :—</p>
                    <p>The greater the attempt to push Zagazig ahead, the more it falls back, and
                        becomes remarkable for an increase of filth and darkness. The few petroleum
                        lamps we have remain unlit when the moon shines, although she may not rise
                        till 11 o'clock at night! This being the case, in Rue Tewfik, a street
                        nearly a mile long, there are frequent collisions in the darkuess between
                        foot passengers and carts, carriages, and donkeys coming from the interior,
                        in Rue Tewfik are two of the principal banks and two churches; many
                        well-to-do people reside in it, and yet it has been frequently pitch dark
                        there of late.</p>
                    <p>The dyke is nothing but a place of convenience for the occupants of the huts
                        and hovels of the quarter, and much indecency meets the eyes of the ladies
                        and young girls coming trom the Greek and French schools, who have to pass
                        nearly naked men on the road. And all this takes place under a regime in
                        which British influence is paramount!</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL. Op«n nil u»« ronud. all'll a uui.~ IIP!.-Ilium
                        DIMM</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE RAILWAY SERVICE SUMMERTIME TABLE.</head>
                    <p>The following changes in the time-table of the Government Railways come into
                        force on May 1:—</p>

                    <p>ALEXANDRIA LINE.</p>
                    <p>The train de luxe between Alexandria and Cairo and vice versa at noon has
                        been abolished.</p>
                    <p>The afternoon express will leave Cairo at 6.35 p.m. (instead of 4.45 p.m.)
                        and the corresponding train from Alexandria at 6 p.m. (instead of 4.25) and
                        a restaurant car will be attached to each.</p>
                    <p>The 4.15 p.m. train from Cairo and the 3.46 p.m. train from Alexandria will
                        be considered as express trains and will stop at a few stations (see time
                        table).</p>
                    <p>The 3.10 p.m. mixed train from Cairo and the 2.10 p.m. mixed train from
                        Alexandria will be proiouged, the first as far as Cairo and the other as far
                        as Alexandria, to pick up and set down express train passengers. The 10 a.m.
                        mixed train from Alexandria has been changed to 10.50 a.m. owing to the
                        suppression off the train de luxe.</p>

                    <p>BARRAGE LINE.</p>
                    <p>All the trains have been extended to Cairo, consequently the train which used
                        to leave the Barrage for Calioub at 7.22 has been altered so as to leave at
                        6.22 p.m., arriving in Cairo at 6.55 p.m., and the train which used to leave
                        Calioub at 8 p.m. for the Barrage has been altered so as to leave Cairo at
                        7.30 direct for the Barrage, and the train leaving the Barrage at 2.55 p.m.
                        will leave at 2.15 p.m.</p>

                    <p>TEH EL BAROUD LINK</p>
                    <p>So as to improve the service on this line, two new trains have been added,
                        one leaving Teh el Baroud at 6.15 a.m. and the other leaving Cairo at 6 p.m.
                        The present afternoon service has therefore been modified as follows. The
                        3.30, p.m. train from Cairo will hence forth leave at 1.45, p.m. and the
                        5.10 p.m. train from Teh el Baroud 5 minutes later.</p>

                    <p>CAIRO LUXOR LINE</p>
                    <p>A new fast service between Cairo and Minieh will be established.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will leave Cairo by special tram on Thursday, 4th May, for
                        Alexandria, arriving here at 11.30 a m. His Highness will be accompanied by
                        the Resident of the Council of Ministers, the Ministers, and the Financial
                        Adviser.He will proceed direct from the station to Ras el-Tin Palace,
                        accompanied by his mounted esoort, and after lauching at the Palace will go
                        to Montazah.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivah will arrive at Montazah on the same day. It is stated that the
                        Khedive will probably make a cruise in the Mediterranean this summer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD MILNER.</head>
                    <p>Lord Milner will be received in audience by the Khedive to-morrow. Lord
                        Milner is accompanied by Mr. Walrond, who was private secretary to the late
                        High Commissioner. Mr. Walrond was formerly under Lord Milner in Cairo,
                        having been on the Land Tax Adjustment Commission of the Finance Ministry
                        from 1894 to 1897. He is the son of the Rev. M. Walrond and was born in
                        1870. He was educated at Harrow and Balliol.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN GOVERNMENT.</head>
                    <p>Miralai J. J. Asser Bey, Financial Secretary, has been appointed Station
                        Commandant, Khartoum, and Miralai Phipps Bey, Station Commandant, Khartoum,
                        has been transferred to the service of the Sudan Government.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WARSHIPS IN.THE SUEZ CANAL.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Weir, in the House of Commons, having asked on what grounds the
                        facilities for coaling and revictualing afforded to the Russian fleet during
                        its recent passage through the Suez Canal were withheld from the Spanish
                        fleet under similar circumstances in 1898, Lord Percy stated that the
                        circumstances of the two cases were entirely different in the receut case of
                        the Russian squadron, cool was allowed because the vessels were entitled
                        under Rule 3 of the Canal regulations now in force to an amount sufficient
                        to take them to the nearest port where they could obtain the supplies
                        necessary for the coutinuation of their voyage, —and the amount which they
                        had on board was not sufficient. In 1898 Admiral Camara might have claimed
                        under the general principles of international law coal sufficient to enable
                        him to reach the nearest Spanish port or some nearer neutral destination,
                        but for the fact that the Spanish warships had already enough for that
                        purpose, and further supplies were, therefore, refused on that ground.</p>
                    <p>There is a vast discrepancy between the letter of the Judicial Adviser to the
                        "Times" on the same question, and the answer of the Under Secretary of State
                        for Foreign Affairs. Did the discussion in our columns on the matter
                        necessitate a legal change of front?</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS Guarantesd Distilled.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. MARK'S CHURCH. JUBILEE COMMEMORATION.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday, the commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the Consecration of
                        St. Mark’s Church commenced with a celebration of the holy communion at 8
                        a.m. At 11a.m. morning prayer was said by the assistant chaplains and an
                        address was given by the Rev. F. B. N. Norman Lee (S. C. F.). At 5 p.m. for
                        evensong the chapel was filled to overflowing. Among those present were
                        H.B.M.'s Consul General at Alexandria, Rear-Admiral Sir R. Masie Blomfield,
                        K.C.M.G., Lady Blomfieid, and Judge and Miss Batcheller.</p>
                    <p>At 5.30 p.m., before a representative company, the unveiling and dedication
                        of the handsome and beautifully executed memorial tablet commemuratiug the
                        jubilee took place. The ceremony began with the singing of the hymn for St.
                        Mark’s Day. The Consul Geueral, Mr. E.B. Gould, I.S.O., than unveiled the
                        tablet at the request of the officers of the church. The Chaplain afterwards
                        dedicated the tablet, and read some appropriate prayers specially compiled
                        for the occasion. A photograph was then taken of the compauy by a local firm
                        of photographers.</p>
                    <p>At 5.45 p.m. the rendering of Gaul’s sacred cantata, "The HolyCity," began.
                        The church was crowded and the chairs from the chapel were removed into the
                        church to give further sitting accommodation. At the end of the first part a
                        collection was made by four of the sidesmen of the Church and amounted to
                        P.T. 810. This sum will cover all expenses incurred by the purchase of
                        music, etc.</p>
                    <p>The Chaplain closed with the Benediction. Then ended the jubilee
                        commemoration, which will long be remembered by all who were present.</p>
                    <p>The dimensions of the brass tablet are 26:40 inches. The block of dark marble
                        in which it is mounted measures 35:50 inches. Immediately above this block
                        of marble, and resting upon it, is an arched piece of marble, affixed to
                        which is a brass bearing upon it the figure of the Winged Lion of St. Mark
                        with an opened book of the Gospel.</p>
                    <p>The inscription on the tablet, which was executed hy Joseph La Macchia, gives
                        the date of the foundation of the chaplaincy, the laying of the foundation
                        stone, and the consecration, besides a list of the Anglican bishops who have
                        been consecrated to the see, and the chaplains of St. Mark's sinoe its
                        foundation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN IMPROVEMENTS CORPORATION.</head>
                    <p>This company is being formed with a capital of £100,000, divided into 25,000
                        shares of £4 each, for the purpose of undertaking all property operations,
                        and especially the purchase and sale of lands situated in the cities and
                        suburbs, the improvement of land, building operations, the administration of
                        property, transactions, loans on mortgage, etc. Several important schemes
                        are being studied. Half the capital will be offered for public subscription
                        at par. There will be no Founders' or Deferred shares or Debentures. The net
                        profit, after deducting IQ % for the board, will be wholly available for
                        dividend. The first board consists ot Messrs. Alexandre Rustovitz Bey,
                        George Nungo ich Bey, George Royle, Charles J. Nicole, Maxime Charvaut,
                        Anthony S. Constantinidi, and Demetrius E. Casdagi. The managing director
                        will be M. Charles J. Nicole, of Messrs. Nicole and Naef, Geneva, of which
                        firm he is one of the heads, and which he has managed since its foundation
                        in 1881. Tho firm is one of the largest in that city and is engaged in
                        property operations.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DELTA LIGHT RAILWAYS LTD.</head>
                    <p>We beg to draw the attention of our readers to the important change in the
                        notice in today’s paper of the proposed issue of 19,308 further 5 1/2 %
                        Cumulative Preference shares of £10 each by the Egyptian Delta Light
                        Railways, Limited. Hitherto the notice has stated that deposits must be made
                        between the 15th and 26th inst. The time has now been extended three days
                        and owing to the Easter holidays the lists will be closed on the 29th
                        inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REMISIERS AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>The following note to Lord Cromer's article in his Report on "Gambling in
                        Futures," will arouse considerable local interest: —</p>
                    <p>M. Vercamer, the very able Belgian judge on the Mixed Court of Appeal, who
                        has studied this subject with special care, has drawn attention to the harm
                        which results from the employment of a number of “remisiers” or "half
                        commission men" by the brokers at Alexandria. This view is confirmed by many
                        other excellent authorities. This system affords an easy means to gain, for
                        a time, considerable incomes by half commission broking. At first
                        good-natured people pass business to the new comer, and he makes large
                        brokerages. Then come fewer orders, and he has to speculate to maintain his
                        income. The principal reason these "remisiers" flourish is the abnormally
                        high brokerage of 1/2 per cenk on the value of the transactions paid at
                        Alexandria, as against 1/4 per cenk, which is the customary rate at most
                        Exchanges. If the brokerage were limited to 1/4 per cent there would not be
                        a sufficient margin to permit of the brokers paying so highly for the
                        servioes of “remisiers."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BECK AND GO’STJLSENER BEER Obtfllaafct* fraan avary RttMtUklt Fir* lx
                        Gazbo, Auhajtdiua k m Bud**. OfJlimui mbI« u IJ.ntnEVT, F.lSSlff SelSAceet
                        OHO* u. tontrfM. IHMMn</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABOUKIR COMPANY, LIMITED. PERSONAL AND SOCIAL DIRECTORS' REPORT.</head>
                    <p>The following is the report of the directors of the above company, which is
                        to be submitted to the shareholders at the eighteenth ordinary meeting which
                        will be held at the company's offices, 134, Palmerston House,
                        Bishopsgate-street, London, RC., on Friday, 28th inst.—</p>
                    <p>The total sales of land, including those of previous years, are as follows
                        3,420 19/24 feddans sold for cash, £47,665.3.6; 14.476 5/24 feddans on
                        deferred payments, £446,310.19.2, Less discount on ditto
                        £5,617.18.7—440,693.0.7, making 17,897 feddans, at £488,358 4.1. During the
                        year ending 81st December, 1904, 2,723 feddans wore sold on deferred
                        payments for £123,882. Of this area his Highness the Khedive purchased a
                        further 510 feddans and he now owns a fine estate of 2,800 feddans of
                        Aboukir lands, as an adjunct to his favorite residential palace at Montazah.
                        Other sales were made to Europeans of 1,369 feddans, in hods of 300 to 500
                        feddans, for £57,900. About 900 feddans were also sold to natives, of which
                        800 realised about £60 per feddan, and the remainder about £45. These sales
                        included all the land let or fit to be let, but the company will receive a
                        proportion of the rents up to the dates the sales were made. The arrears of
                        instalments due by purchasers on the 31st December amounted to £17,140, of
                        which £4,675 has since been paid. After long negotiation the Government
                        consented to the construction of the new syphon and head sluice referred to
                        in the last report, and the work is now being proceeded with as rapidly as
                        possible. The value of the unsold land will be materially increased by the
                        large expenditure involved.</p>
                    <p>Mandara Division.— Pending completion of the syphon, no new land was taken in
                        hand for canalisation. About 4,000 feddans were in various stages of
                        reclamation, and, of this area 2,600 feddans were sold during the year. Two
                        staff houses, of which one was sold with the land, have been built with the
                        necessary offices, stables, and servants’ houses. The construction of staff
                        houses has greatly facilitated sales of land and the company has at
                        different times built ten, of which seven have been sold with the land. The
                        tramway through the centre of the division has been a great boon; without
                        it, the rapid development of the land would not have been possible.</p>
                    <p>Bahari Division.— Reclamation in this division has been retarded by the
                        uneven state of the land, which required a great amount of levelling, but
                        the position has now improved and more rapid progress will be made.</p>
                    <p>Wastani Division.—There are about 5,000 feddans in this division, and it is
                        expected that at least 1,000 feddans will be canalised this year. A new
                        staff house and some esbehs will be built, and the tramway will be extended
                        along the bank of the new canal for a distance of about two miles to the
                        Mahmoudieh Canal.</p>
                    <p>Cattle —In compensation for the cattle lost by the compvny in 1903, referred
                        to in the last report, the Government have ceded a long a narrow piece of
                        land containing abont 665 feddans along Aboukir Bay. In January there was
                        another outbreak of cattle plague and the company lost abont a dozen cattle;
                        later on malaria and foot and mouth disease caused sickness and some deaths,
                        but the plague has now almost disappeared from Egypt. The young stock has
                        done very well, and will more than compensate for losses by death and old
                        age.</p>
                    <p>Work and responsibility having greatly increased during the year, as
                        evidenced by the large sales of land and the heavy expenditure, Mr. Richmond
                        has been appointed sub-manager, a position well earned by his continued good
                        work and application for over six years with the company. Of the original
                        30,000 feddans possessed by the company, only about 12,000 now remain
                        unsold, and the directors have felt that it would be a pity not to utilise
                        the valuable experience acquired in land reclamation. They have, therefore,
                        in conjunction with two other Egyptian land companies, acquired a valuable
                        property in the province of Gharbteh of 1,677 feddans, with the intention of
                        extending reclamation to adjoining areas when opportunity presents itself.
                        From the accounts presented the profit and loss account shows a credit
                        balance of £23,048. 17s. lOd., which, added to £3,780. 17a, brought forward
                        from the preceding year, makes £25,829. 14. lOd. The arrears of dividend due
                        to the Ordinary shares to 31st December, 1903, amounting to £9,057. 14s.
                        2d., or 10a lOfd. per share, srero paid in January, 1905, and it is now
                        proposed to pay dividends for the post year of 7 per cent. on both the
                        Ordinary and Deferred shares which swill amount to £11,769. 2s, leaving
                        £6,002. 18s. 8d. to be carried forward.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IMPORTANT PROPERTY SALE.</head>
                    <p>The site and buildings known as the Palais ds l'Anoienne Boone at Alexandria
                        have been sold by the landlord, M. Laurens, to a native capitalist of Cairo
                        for £24,000 All the expenses and costs of the transfer are to be borne by
                        the purchaser. The block embraces a site of 1,882 square pics and includes
                        the "Le Khedive” cigarette manufactory, the stores and bar of Messrs. Walker
                        and Meimarachi; and the offices of the “Egyptian Gazette.” The reason for
                        the sale was that M. Laurens finds his present premises too small for the
                        cigarette business and he intends building a large cigarette factory in the
                        neighbourhood of Messrs. Degiardi Brothers' works.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TVPnT _Weissenstein Castle 3410 I I I\UL. ft Firat-olaas private hotel
                        near Windisoh-Matrei; Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                        mountaineering centre. Tennis. Pishing; beet June and September.
                        Prospectuses and Photographs, "Egyptian Gasette’’offir*</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Lady Cromer wishes it to be known that she will not be “at home” on Thursday
                        afternoon.</p>

                    <p>A very successful “At Home" was given by Dean and Mrs. Butcher at Church
                        House, Cairo, yesterday afternoon. Loyd and Lady Cromer, Lord Milner, the
                        Judicial Adviser and Mrs. Mcllwraith. Lady Rogers Mrs. and the Misses Coles,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Brunyate, and many other well-known members of the British
                        colony in Cairo were present The function proved a very successful and
                        enjoyable one.</p>

                    <p>The Princess Nihmet Hanem, Baron and Baroness d'Erlanger, Chewky Pasha,
                        Baroness von Knoop, Mahmoud Muktar Pasha. Baron von Wersebe, and many other
                        distinguished passengers are leaving Alexandria to-day for Europe by the
                        North German Lloyd “Schleswig.”</p>

                    <p>We are asked to remind our readers that Mrs. Chataway’s garden party, at
                        Nouzhe has been postponed from the 28th inst to May 5.</p>

                    <p>The state of health of Mme Beyerle, wife of the managing director of the
                        Credit Foncier Egyptien, is, we regret to say, causing considerable
                        anxiety.</p>

                    <p>Sheikh Ahmed el Yemegi, Grand Sheikh of the Mussulmans of Pretoria, is now
                        staying at Cairo.</p>

                    <p>Capt and Adjutant J. H. Davidson, D.S.O., 1st King’s Royal Rifle Corps, and
                        the Rev. E. J. Hardy, M. A., chaplain to the forces, have been granted leave
                        of absence.</p>

                    <p>QUINTANA-PRIOR.</p>
                    <p>The marriage of Mr. William H. Quintana, third son of Mr. J. Quintana, late
                        British Consul and Eastern Telegraph Superintendent at Chio, Turkey, to Miss
                        Mary Louisa Prior, only daughter of the late Commander R. T. Prior, took
                        place at St. Catherine's Cathedral, Alexandria, on Monday last at 2 p.m. The
                        bride, who was given away by her brother, wore a handsome gown of white
                        satin trimmed with mousseline de soie and real lice. Her court train was of
                        satin and mousseline de soie, and her wreath of orange blossoms was arranged
                        over her long embroidered tulle veil. The bridegroom was supported by Mr. F.
                        R. Acheson, as best man. The principal bridesmaid was Miss Mabel Lamb, who
                        looked very pretty in a beautiful robe of pale pink chiffon silk. She wore a
                        white chiffon hat trimmed with white ostrich plumes and ospreys and carried
                        a bouquet of pink and white roes. The two little bridesmaids who acted as
                        train-bearers were the Misses Lily and May Ablitt. They both looked very
                        sweet in white accordian-pleated silk frocks, and white picture hats of
                        chiffon. The bride’s mother looked charming in a mauve silk gown and mauve
                        hat to match, and carried a lovely bouquet of red and white roses.</p>
                    <p>After the ceremony at the church the guests were invited to a reception held
                        by Mrs. Prior at the New Khedivial Hotel. The newly-married couple left
                        shortly after 4 o’clock for the Beau-Rivage Hotel, Ramleh, where they are
                        staying until their departure for Liverpool to-day by the 8.8.
                        “Anatolia."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <head>Arrivals.</head>
                    <p>Per P. AND O.S.S. “Egypt,” from Bombay, arrived Monday:-</p>
                    <p>Mr. Herrmann Janss, Mr. Edwin Jauss.</p>
                    <p>Per P. AND O.S.S. “Britannia," from London to Marseilles, arrived yesterday:
                        —</p>
                    <p>London to Port Said:— Mr. L.R. Storm, Mrs. W. Darmer, Miss Darmer, Miss A.
                        Carroll, Mrs. G. M. Dawson, infant and child, Mr. J. Gooch.</p>
                    <p>Marseilles to Port Said:— Mr. S. Gladstone, Lieut E.R. Pratt, Mr. F.
                        Shelford, Mr. F. Gowenloch, Mrs. Macbride, Mr. R.M. Gladstone, Lieut. W. R.
                        Meredith.</p>

                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Per S.S. “Schleswig" left Alexandria for Marseilles to day:—</p>
                    <p>Mr. Arnold Bhorner, Mr. W. von Bentivegni, Miss Bennett, Mr. and Mrs. Walter
                        Berla, Mr. Rene Baexuer, Mr. E.C. Bowen, Mr. Friedrich Bolbuck, Miss Booth,
                        Mr. Wilhelm Birkmeyer, Mr. Bowden, Mrs. Colquhoun, Misses V. and H.
                        Colquhoun, Mrs. and Miss Cochrane, Chewky Pacha and Mme Chewky, Mohamed Aly
                        Chewky, Mr. Joseph Alfred Cohen, Misses Alice, Emmy, Beatrice, and Eleonore
                        Cohen, Mr. Grat Diepholz, Baron and Baronne d’Erger, Comm. Glician, Mr. and
                        Mme Guillemot, Mr. Hochstrosser, Dr. Hobson, Mrs. Johnston, Mrs. Johnston,
                        Baronnee von Knoop, Dr. and Mme von Kellner, Mr. A. Klamroth, Mrs. A.
                        Klamroth, Princess Nihmat, Mr. Dr. Lurtz. Dr. Leigh Canney, S.R Mahmoud
                        Mouktor Pacha, Mr. and Mrs. Miller, Mr. Bankdirector Mosevius, Mr. Alfred
                        Missland, Mr. Alfred Marx, Mr. and Mrs. Johann J. Nelson, Mr. and Mrs. P. G.
                        Psycha, Mr. Psycha jr., Mr. J. Z. Papazian, Miss Pettican, Mr. Oscar Ruesch,
                        Mr. and Mrs. A. Rocha, Mr. Max Reiger, Mrs. E. Stephens, Mr. F. G. Swan,
                        Miss Swan, Mr. Tunbridge, Mr. Rittmeister, Baron von Wersebe and Mme
                        Wantz-Balmer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Windsor Pharmacy Kaar-eLNII Square, CAIRO. BEIT CHEMICAL PROPHETS, ini
                        Foreign Pressriptwni carefully prepared by Osrtfreisa Cksaisfa ALWAYS ■ STMK
                        USN OHim— I if w*m mmmrmmmm * yggjurm</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.</head>
                    <head>FIRST SUMMER MEETING. List of Entries.</head>
                    <p>FIRST DAY!</p>
                    <p>Maiden Arab Race. — Capt. G. Gillison's The Clown; Gapt G. B. Byrne's
                        Mahmoud, Mr. E. Karam's Perth, Khalil Pasha Khayat's Klondyke; Messrs. W. B.
                        Rees and G. Barker’s Ion; Ibrahim Bey Cherif's Kendal, Omar Bey Sultan and
                        Ahmed Bey Bakry's Samham and El Ghemehi; Ishack Bey Hussein's Sir Visto;
                        Hamah Bey Sioufi's Sweetie; Prince Omar Pasha Toussaoun’s Marzouk; Saleh Bey
                        Yaghen's Wassal; Hassen Pasha Mohsen’s Gogo; Mr. Tueni’s Caprice; Messrs.
                        Nicolas Sousa and Kamel Eff. Maher's Social Life.</p>
                    <p>Pony Handicap.—Mr. and Karam's Eclipse; Khalil Pasha Khayat's Sadik and
                        Dougham; Messrs. W. B. Ree. and G. H. Barker's Vandal; Ibrahim Bey Cherif's
                        Royalist; Ishak Bey Yaghen’s Spectre and Mayesha; Hassan Pasha Mohsen's,
                        Taib.</p>
                    <p>Galloway Plats. — Messrs. Branch and Mason's Starboard Light; Khalil Pasha
                        Khayat’s Loulou; Messrs. W. B. Rees and G. H, Barker’s Vandal; Mr. A. J.
                        Sursock's Sans Pareil; Saleh Bey Yaghen's Spectre and Siham; Hassan Pasha
                        Mohsen’s Gogo; Baron J. E. de Menasoe's, Radium.</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley Plate.—Mr. P. W. Stout's Shewman; Mr. E. Karam's, Coeur de Lion;
                        Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Banaback; Ibrahim Bey Cherifs Gladisteur; Omar Bey
                        Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakry's Rachid; Bey Hussein’s Moofid; Saleh Bey
                        Yaghen’s Mashkour II and Wassal; Mr. Tueni's Caprice and Faineant.</p>

                    <p>SECOND DAY.</p>
                    <p>Arab Selling Race.-Capt. G. B. Byrne’s Chinaman; Mr. K Karam’s, Boheme; Mr.
                        J. Hoyami’s Tonnerre ; Khalil Pasha Khayat's Doughan; Ibrahim Bey Cherif s
                        Menelik and Lottery II; Ishack Bey Hussein and Hasaan Bey Kheir el Din's
                        Faik; Hassan Bey Kheir el Din's White Eye; Mr. A. J. Sursock's Ruy-Blas.</p>
                    <p>Pony Plate—Mr. E. Karam's Nimred Khalil Pasha Khayat's Louloa; Messrs. W. B.
                        Rees and G. Barker’s India and Firefly; Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s St. Frusquin
                        and Fantasia; Omar Bey Sultan and Bey Bakry’s Oyama; Saleh Bey Yaghen’s
                        Spectre and Siham; Hasaan Pasha Mohsen's Taib; Mr. Tuen’s Viking.</p>
                    <p>Lord of Rosna Stakes. — Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Bandusia; Prince Mohamad
                        Ibrahim’s Theodore and Tartine; Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakry’s Bonus;
                        Mr. Nasri E. Tagher’s Fra Antonio.</p>
                    <p>Ramleh ’Scurry. — Capt. Q. B. Byrne's Fitz; Mr. K. Karam’s Couer de Lion and
                        Tamerlan; Khalil Pasha Khayat's Banabeck and Klondyke; Omar Bey Sultan and
                        Bey Bakry’s Rachid; Ishack Bey Hussein's Moofid ; Hasaan Bey Sioufi's
                        Sweetie; Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun’s Marzouk; Bey Yagen's Wassal; Mr.
                        Tueni’s Ajax; Moharrem Pasha Chehin’s Mizzaud.</p>
                    <p>Pony Handicap.— Mr. E. Karam's Nimrod and Eclipse; Mr. E. Boustro’s Roland;
                        Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Suleik and Sadik; Messrs. W. B. Rees and G. H.
                        Barker's Suari and India; Ibrahim Bey Cherif's Fantazia and Royalist; lshack
                        Bey Hussein's Shahrour; Hasaan Bey Sioufi's Peacock; Prince Omar Pasha
                        Toussoun’s Hadban; Saleh Bey Yaghen’s Abu Roucoup and Spectre; Hassan Pasha
                        Mohsen’s Taib; Mr. Tueni’s Viking; Elie Bey Sarsock and Mr. Tueni's
                        Amory.</p>

                    <p>A.S.C. GOLF.</p>
                    <p>The Golf Steward wishes to remind members that the handicap score competition
                        is to be played off on Saturday next, at any hour convenient to members.
                        Soores, which must be certified by a member, must be marked on the special
                        cards which have been provided for the purpose and which can be obtained
                        from Vassili, price P.T. 15 each.</p>
                    <p>The second round of the driving competition will take place on Friday
                        afternoon, 28th inst., from the 9th tee, commencing at 4.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>The date of the completion of the first round of the handicap foursomes has
                        been postponed till May 8.</p>

                    <p>ATHLETIC SPORTS</p>
                    <p>The annual athletic sports of the Military School, Abbassieh, will take place
                        on the Observatory parade ground to-morrow afternoon, commencing at 3.30
                        p.m. The Countess of Cromer will distribute the prizes at the conclusion of
                        the sports. The Commandant of the Military School will be pleased to see all
                        officers of the rank of Sagcholaghassi and upwards at the Commandant’s
                        enclosure.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONSOLIDATED GOLD FIELDS OF EGYPT AND SUDAN, LTD.</head>
                    <p>Registered April 8th, by Ernest Salaam, Fort and Co., 12, Union Coart, E>C.
                        Capital, £1,000, in £1 shares. Objects: To acquire any mines, mining and
                        other rights and properties in Egypt; and the Sudan, or elsewhere in
                        Northern Africa, and to carry on the business of miners, explorers,
                        metallurgists, metal founders and workers, financiers, concessionnaires,
                        etc. No-initial public issue. The first directors (to number not less than
                        two nor more than seven) are to be appointed by the signatories.
                        Qualification, £250. Remuneration, £150 each per annum, and £450 for the
                        chairman. Registered office, 62, London Wall, E.C.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>§*. >11 PAY. WlWt IB^Sfro.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, APRIL 26, 1905.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LA DELEGATION MDNICIPALE</head>
                    <p>( C.mmunicativn Oficitll* ) ' 1a Ddiogatiun Mnnidpale i’*t rtanie la J avril
                        1904 k4 l p.m. sous 1a prudence de M. A.ium; FrdseuU : MM. Bresaohi,
                        Feuderl, Mansour Boy Youresf, Dr. 0. Vatensin, G. Zervorfaobi, membra*, W.P.
                        Chateway, admimstreteor, I. Sodky Boy, secretaire. La Do legation .tort un
                        avia favorable k on projot d’agrandissemeot do palate monidpal, toboro par
                        I’lngenieur on Chat et soomettre k U Commission Mnnidpale Ire orydits y
                        relatifs. Sts proud note da lacoeptation doonke par M.Audri, ingtooor
                        peysagisto, k l engagement . relatif k la ounfeotion da* davia at plan* poor
                        la ortetiou das nouToauY pares sor l’emplaoe moot lies aaciennea
                        fortifications daa dear olt trt de la Porta Roeatta. Vo rpprocbe da l'to et
                        par mesore de prt-oantion oontre lapparition d'dpidumies, l* Delegation, sur
                        la proposition de l’lnspooteor Sanitaire, decide l'intardiciiou du oommeroe
                        das chiffons, dan* un ddlai de 10 joors a partir das avis qui wront publics
                        k oet effrt dan* lea joornaux. 1a Delegation prend acta de la miae an
                        circulation de nouvelie* voiture* par la Compa-gnie des Tramway*</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOUVEMENT MARITIME DU PORT D’ALBXANDRIB</head>
                    <p>kiantm 35 avril Marseille ; 4 1/2, v*p. franq. Portugal, cap.Ga-letts, ton.
                        3363, sox Mess. Mar. Londree et Malta ; 4 j. 1/2, vap. ang. Perim, cap.
                        Kemp, ton. 851, k Tamvaoo. Cardiff; 1.6j. 1/2, vap. ang. Northam, c*p. Can
                        tell, ton. 2474, k Grace Co.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>Cheap Prepaid Advertisements.</head>
                    <p>Under this heading advertisements are inserted at the following rates:-</p>
                    <p>ONCE 3 TIMES 6 TIMES</p>
                    <p>15 words . . . P.T. 5 P.T. 10 P.T. 15</p>
                    <p>30 words ... „ 3 „ 16 „ 24</p>
                    <p>Every 10 words beyond 30. . . / ” 2 " 4 " 6</p>
                    <p>The address is counted. The advertisement must appear on consecutive days for
                        above rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged for advertisements not
                        appearing consecutively. All such advertisements most be prepaid, and to
                        this role no exception whatever will be made. Letters in reply to
                        advertisements will he posted to any address if a few stamps are sent by the
                        advertiser to cover postage.</p>

                    <p>ADVERTISING AGENTS.</p>
                    <p>—The best public Advertising sites in Alexandria belong to G. Vestri and Co.,
                        Advt Agents, St. Catherine's Square. Special rates for permanent clients.
                        Moderate terms. Prompt despatch. </p>

                    <p>A BARGAIN FOR SALE — Encyclopedia Britannica in latest edition, including NEW
                        Volumes, clothbound, with revolving oak case; valued £67/10, offered for £38
                        cash or £45 on terms. Apply, E.A.S., Poste Restante, Cairo. </p>

                    <p>ARE YOU FURNISHING! If so, see list of Bargains in elegant Household
                        furniture and fittings, the property of a gentleman proceeding on leave.
                        Apply early, E. A. S. Poete Restante, Cairo. </p>

                    <p>APPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German, to the Berlitz Schools, Alexandria
                        (26, Rue de l'Eglise Copte) ; Cairo Sharia Kamfel), Most rapid method Trial
                        lesson free. Evening classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per month.</p>

                    <p>BORMAN AND CO. have just recieved a further shipment of Summer CLoth, latest
                        patterns. Suits to measure by a first-class English Cutter, from P.T. 250.
                        Sole address, Cherif Pasha Street, Alexandria.</p>

                    <p>ENGLISHMAN, 22 years of age, with five years Banking experience, desires
                        situation in good firm. Speaks French fluently and good Correspondent. E.A.,
                        9 Acre Lane, London, S.W.</p>

                    <p>GOVERNESSES or lady's maids in want of situations may apply to Mary
                        Lambertini’s offices, Rue Cesar, 2, Knolls Miani, Alexandria. 258196-2</p>

                    <p>HOUSE TO LET, Ramleh, from July; close to sea ; 3 sitting-rooms ; 6 bedrooms
                        ; bathroom; hot and cold water; stabling for three; large garden. Apply, No.
                        25,813, "Egyptian Gazette" office. 26813-6-3</p>

                    <p>HOTEL ASSISTANT, knowing French, Italian, German, Greek, Turkish, Roumanian,
                        English, Russian, and Arabic, desires post as Dragoman, Porter, or Waiter in
                        Hotel or Restaurant. Apply, No. 25,840, "Egyptian Gazette" offices.</p>

                    <p>LORD CROMER'S REPORT.-Copies can be obtained of Borman and Co., Cherif
                        Pasha-Street, price P.T. 6 per copy. </p>

                    <p>LOST, Sunday, Fox Terrier dog, large saddle mark all black on back, tan about
                        the face; answers to the name "Flock." Finder rewarded. Apply to Rowden's
                        Stable, Port Rosette. Buyers are warned.</p>

                    <p>MR. J. P. BERNARD, the great French inventor of numerous medical products for
                        the cure of almost every chronic disease, has arrived at Alexandria and will
                        recieve patients free from 8 to 9 am. every day except Sunday, at 26, rue
                        Salah el Dine et Cheickh Aly el Lessi, Immeuble Ahmed Yassin </p>

                    <p>RESIDENCE—Wanted gentleman to share comfortable NORTH apartment on river bank
                        near MUSEUM: Electric light; or would let furnished for SUMMER months.
                        Apply, E.A.S., Paste Restante., Cairo. </p>

                    <p>SANDY MACDONALD, the famous 10 year old Scotch Whisky, can be obtained at the
                        Khedivial Opera House Buffet daring the Bandmann Opera Season. </p>

                    <p>TO LET, at Ibrahimieh (Ramleh), 5 minutes from the station, for the snmmer
                        season, a Furnished House of 7 rooms and a large garden in good condition.
                        Special terms for English families. Apply, No. 25,802, “Egyptian Gazette”
                        offices. </p>

                    <p>TO BE LET to the snmmer a well-furnished House situated in the Boulevard
                        Ramleh, facing the sea and close to the Ramleh station; containing 8 rooms,
                        bathroom, etc., and telephone. For full particulars, address H. J. L.,
                        Khedivial Club, Alexandria. 25835-61</p>

                    <p>WANTED immediately a reliable Book-keeper; must know thoroughly English and
                        French. One who can typewrite preferred. Address, No. 25,886, offioe of the
                        "Egyptian Gazette”.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Daira Sanieh Company, Limited.</head>
                    <p>NOTICE IS HEREBY GIVEN that the Seventh Oridnary General Meeting of the above
                        Company will be held at the National Bank of Egypt, Sharia Kasr-El-Nil,
                        Cairo, Egypt, on Saturday the 29th April at 12 a.m. for th epurpose of
                        considering the Statementt of Accounts and Balance Sheet to 31st December
                        1904, the Auditors' Report theron, and the Report of the Directors, for the
                        Decleration of a Dividend, and the transaction of the ordinary buisness of
                        the Company.</p>
                    <p> The Transfer Books of the Company will be closed from the 16th to the 29th
                        April 1905, both inclusive.</p>
                    <p> By order of the Board,</p>
                    <p> S. DE Bilinsky,</p>
                    <p> Secretary.</p>
                    <p>Sharia-Kasr-El-Nil,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO,</p>
                    <p>8th April 1905.</p>
                    <p>Shareholders holding Share Warrants to Bearer who wish to attend the General
                        Meeting of the Company must first deposit their Bearer Warrants together
                        with a statement of their names and addresses:-</p>
                    <p>In London, with The National Bank of Egypt, 4 and 5 King William Street,
                        E.C., ten clear days before the date of the General Meeting (vix., not later
                        than the 18th of April)</p>
                    <p>In Egypt, two clear days before the date of the General Meeting (vic., not
                        later than the 27th of April:-)</p>
                    <p>At the National Bank of Egypt, Cairo. At the National Bank of Egypt,
                        Alexandira. At the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Imperial Ottoman Bank, Credit
                        Lyonnais, Bank of Egypt in Cairo or Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The share warrants remaining so deposited until after the general meting
                        shall have been held.</p>
                    <p> Each depositor will recieve a Certificate of Deposit in exchange for the
                        Share Warrants deposited, and a Ticket of Admission (which must be produced
                        by the holder attending the Meeting) and a Form of Proxy.</p>
                    <p> If the Depositor does not intend personally to attend the Meeting, a Proxy
                        in favour of the person producing the Certificate must be lodged with the
                        Company at its Cairo Office not less that 48 hours before the Meeting. </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>National Bank of Egypt</head>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>To the holders of Share Warrants to Bearer of THE EGYPTIAN DELTA LIGHT
                        RAILWAYS, LIMITED. Proposed issue or 19,308 further 5 1/2 % Cumulative
                        Preference Shares or £10 each.</head>

                    <p>The Board of Directors of the above company are proposing to ofer the above
                        Shares at the price of 12.20.0 per share pro rata to those exisitng
                        Proprietors who are known to the Company in the proportion of one new SHare
                        for every five shares already held. In order that a form of offer with full
                        particulars only filled in with form of acceptance attached may be issued to
                        holders Share Warrants to bearer, those holders of Warrants who wish to
                        participate are hereby notified that they must first deposit their Warrants
                        either at the London Office of the Company 211/214 Gresham House, Old Broad
                        Street, E.C. or at the National of Egypt, Cairo or Alexandria, or if that is
                        inconvenient the Warrants can be deposited with some registered Bankers who
                        will issue a Certificate in exchange stating that they hold the Warrants on
                        acoount of the Depositors with their names and addresses and the particulars
                        of the Warrants deposited and will continue to hold the same until after the
                        26th April, in which case such Banker’s Certificate can be lodged at the
                        London Office of the Company or at the National Bank of Egypt, Cairo or
                        Alexandria in lieu of the bearer Warrants themselves.</p>
                    <p>Deposits must be made in banking hours between the 15th April and the 26th
                        April j 1905 (both dates inclusive) when the form of offer above referred to
                        and form of acceptance attached, together with a reciept for the warrants or
                        Bankers certificate will be issued to the Depositor. Deposited Warrants will
                        be handed out against receipt at any time after the said 26th April 1905.
                        With the above mentioned acceptance , applications may also be made for any
                        surplus Shares not taken up by shareholders to the foil pro rata amount to
                        which they are entitled.</p>
                    <p>By order of the Board,</p>
                    <p>F.J. Horne,</p>
                    <p>Secretary.</p>
                </div>







                <div type="item">
                    <head>Municipality d’Alexandrie</head>
                    <p>A V I 8 Los candidate aux postes de stagiaires vacaute k la Municipality
                        d’Alexandrie sont prirt de se presenter au palais municipal jendi 37 avril
                        1905 k 10 heures da matin poor subir un oonooors. TAdministratoar W. P. C
                        hate way Alaxaadrie, lo 22 Avril 1905. Rational Bank of Egypt AVI8 AUX
                        ACT10NNA1RES. Messieurs les actionnaires de la National Bank of Bgypt sont
                        oonvoqufo en Assemble G4n4 rale Extraordinaire poor le Samedi six Mai 1905 k
                        4 heures de l’aprks-midi, au Sikge Social, au Cairo, afin de ddlibdrer sur
                        la proposition suivante: Aogrpontatioc du Capital Sooial at modification de
                        Particle 10 des Statute. Tout actionnaire poesydant au moins vingt actions a
                        droit de prendre part k l’Asedmbiye Gfthlralo k condition de dfposer see
                        action# dans Pan des lieux d-aprks dysignds oh il lm Mra dflivnl une carte
                        d’admission. En Bgypte, Cinq, jonrs au moins avant le jour de la rdunion,
                        soft le lor Mai, au plus terd: au Si kgs Social, au Cairo; k la Succursale k
                        Alexandria; aux Agenoee de la Banque k Assist, Assuan, Benha, Beni-Suef,
                        Chibin-el-Kom, Damanhur, Fayum, Keneh, Manaurah, Mini eh, Port-Said, Sohag,
                        Tacteh, Zagv zig et Muski (Cairo); k la Banque Impyriale Ottomane;) k
                        l’Ando- Egyptian Bank; I an Cairo an Credit Lyonnais; | ou k la Bank of
                        Bgypt; Jk Alexandria En Europe, an pins tard le 97 Avril: k Paris rt k
                        Marseille, aux bureaux de la “Somite Marseillaise" ; en Itehe, dans les
                        bureaux de la " Banos Commercials Italians " ; k Londree, k l’Ageooe de la
                        National Bank of Egypt, 4 et 5. King William Street EC. L’AseembWe, pour
                        pouvoir dyiibyror valable-ment devant rtanir la moitiy des actions ymises,
                        Messieurs les aetionnaires sont prite de (hire le dypOt de tontes ’ El win
                        Palmer. Le Cairo, le 5 Avril 1905. 95717-12. A-9 V inmtmD FROM Tbs w Ports)
                        *8Br a. n. 14 11 a. ■. 41 19 otm FwvfesW oftses It a To the holder* of Share
                        Warrants to Bearer of THE EGYPTIAN DELTA LIGHT BAILWAYS, LIMITED. Pboposkd
                        issoi or 19,308 FURTitxa 51% Cumulative PamaBECK Sharks ok £Kna\cu. jThe
                        Board of Dirootoraof the above Company are proposing to offer the above
                        Shares at the price of £12. 10. 0 per Share pro rate to those existing
                        Proprietor* Wn koiwa-.i theCorn-pany ia the proportion of one new Share for
                        every five shares (either Preference or Deferred) already held. In order
                        that a form of offer with foil particulars only filled in with form of
                        aooeptanoe attached may be issued to holder* of Share Warrants to bearer,
                        those holders of Warrant* who wish to participate are hereby notified that
                        they must first deposit their Warrants either at the London Offioe of the
                        Company 911/214 Gresham House, Old Broad Street, B.G. or at the National of
                        Egypt, Cairo or Alexandria, or if that is inconvenient the Warrants oan be
                        deposited with some raooguis ed Bankers who will issue a Certificate iu
                        exchange stating that they hold the Warrants on aooonnt of the Depositors
                        with their names and addresses and the particular* of the Warrants deposited
                        and will oontinue to hold the same until after the 26th April, in whieh case
                        such Banker’s Certificate oan be lodged at the London Offioe of the Company
                        or at the National Bank of Egypt, Cairo or Alexandria in lieu of the bearer
                        Warrants themselves. Deposits mast be made in banking hours between the 15th
                        April and the 9»th April 1906 (both fetff inquire) when tbt ftra of</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BOURSE KHEDIVIALE</head>
                    <p>CONTRATS Fluctuations de 10h. k lh. p.m. Cotent F.G.F.Br. Dans la matfoye;
                        prix plus haut pour mai tel 13 15/32 k —■/—; pins has poor mai 13 9/83 k
                        -I—. Grain*! de coton Dans la matin5e; prix pins haut pour mai P.T. 67 —/— k
                        —/—: plus has pour mai 56 20/40 k —/—. Remarques (De Midi k lb. p.m.) Co
                        ton*.—la Sublease s’ytait aoccntuke son* la prassion de* offres, mais vers
                        olfiture il y a eu un peu de soutien qui non* a vain l’affi-chage do oours
                        de 13 5/16 aohetenn poor le lal La position de la nonvelle ryedte est restye
                        Graines de ooton — Nouvelie ryoolte, calme et cours un pen plus foible*. *
                        Ryoolte aotuelle.—A fioi au plus has, avee peu d'affaires.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
