<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Daisy Vazquez --></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- November 7, 2016 --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- 1905-02-01 --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- 7,112 Alexandria. Wednesday, Febuary 1, 1905. Six pages  -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LOSS OF HEIKUTAI.</head>
                    <p> RUSSIAN POSITION.</p>
                    <p><placeName> Tokio,</placeName> January 31, The loss of Heikutai so weakens
                        the Russian positon that it will probably compel a material change of their
                        front in that neighbourhood. The Japanese now occupy Heikutai and are
                        holding the strong Russian works. It is impossible to build new works owing
                        to the frost. The Japanese have found at least 1,200 Russians dead since the
                        fighting on the 25th inst. The Russians admit a loss of about 10,000.
                        (Reuter). </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WARSAW ATTACKS.</head>
                    <p>A SEARCHING ENQUIRY.</p>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> January 31. Count Lamsdorff has
                        informed Sir C. Hardinge that he has ordered a searching enquiry into the
                        question of the Warsaw attacks. He has also ordered the complete effacement
                        of the placards at Moscow and Libau, and has expressed unqualified
                        disapproval of the Moscow Prefect's conduct. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName> Warsaw,</placeName> January 31. Further disorders have taken
                        place. 160 persons have been killed or wounded. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>Lemberg,</placeName> January 31. Several arrests have been made in
                        consequence of some tumultuous demonstrations. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>Tiflus</placeName> January 31. A strike has broken out here.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PARIS DEMONSTRATIONS.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Paris,</placeName> January 31. Six thousand persons met here last
                        night in order to denounce the events in Russia. Extraordinary police
                        precautions were taken. As the people were leaving, a bomb was thrown and
                        two republican guards were wounded. Several arrests were made. Another bomb
                        was found outside the residence of Prince Trubetzkoi, Attache to the Russian
                        Embassy. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTH SEA COMMISSION.</head>
                    <p>CAPTAIN KLADO'S EVIDENCE.</p>
                    <p><placeName>Paris,</placeName> January 31. Captain Klado, in his evidence,
                        emphatically and circumstantially reiterated, his statement that
                        torpedo-boats were encountered. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH STEAMER CAPTURED.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Tokio,</placeName> January 31. The Japanese have captured the
                        British steamer “Wyefieid” carrying contraband, off Hokkaido Island.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRINCESS VICTORIA. OPERATED ON FOR APPENDICITIS.</head>
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> January 31. Princess Victoria has been
                        operated upon for appendicitis. She is progressing very satisfactorily.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRINCE EITEL’S CONDITION.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Berlin,</placeName> January 31. Prince Eitel’s condition, is
                        improving, (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Paris,</placeName> January 31. The Senate has terminated the
                        debate on the military law. The Chamber of Deputies has resumed the
                        discussion of the Budget. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>The Address of our Cairo Correspondent is now: P. P. Graves, Rossmore House,
                        Sharia el Madabergu.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRAND HOTEL BONNARD</head>
                    <p><placeName> Alexandria,</placeName> 8oz,PER DAY WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The National Bank inaugurates its existence as State Treasury today. Cairo
                        Agricultural Show will be held from the 13th to the 17th inst, inclusive.
                        The Brindist mail will be distributed at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 6:30
                        p.m. today.</p>
                    <p>Quarantine. — Arrivals from Breach in Egyptian ports are now subject to
                        quarantine. The Fitzner Quatuor give their first concert at the New
                        Khedivial Hotel this evening.</p>
                    <p>Hashish Seizure. — A large quantity of hashish has been seized by tho Coast
                        Guards in the desert beyond Dakhalch. A Hockey Match, A.S.C. Mr. Hunt’s XI,
                        will be played on the A.S.C. grounds this afternoon, commencing at 3
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Children’s Ball.—The Committee of Fetes has decided upon a children’s ball,
                        to be held between the 10th and 15th inst.</p>
                    <p>Cairo Streets - A credit of LE. 20,000 has been granted by the Ministry of
                        Finance for the asphalting of several streets in the native quarters of
                        Cairo.</p>
                    <p>The Charity Entertainment - given by Mme. de la Bouliniere at the French
                        Agency, Cairo, yesterday, was a great success. Particulars will appear in
                        tomorrow’s issue.</p>
                    <p>Post Office Notice.—From to-day, correspondence for all places on the
                        Cairo-Fayoum line will also be forwarded by trains No. 147 and 148, leaving
                        Cairo at 5.45 p.m. and Fayoum at 6.20 a m.</p>
                    <p>Leon Fehmy.—A report has recently been published that Leon Fehmy, who
                        recently returned to Egypt, had been arrested in consequence of the
                        publication of a newspaper entitled “La Justice.” We understand that the
                        report is untrue.</p>
                    <p>Cairo Gas.—M. Eugene Lebon, manager of the great French Gas Company, has
                        arrived at Cairo from Paris in order to open negotiations with the
                        Government in regard to the reduction in the price of gas for purposes of
                        lighting the streets and public places.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—23 vessels passed through the Canal on the 28th and 29th ulto.,
                        11 of which were British, 7 German, 1 Norwegian, 1 French, 2 Dutch, 1
                        Russian. The receipts for the two days were trs. 608,666.97 making, a total
                        from the 1st ulto. of frs. 10,463,037.65. The Annual Fancy Dress and Poudre
                        Ball will be given at the Ghezireh Palace Casino on Shrove Tuesday (7th
                        March). A fine of P.T. 40 will be levied on persons attending in evening
                        dress only, the proceeds being winded over to the S.P.C.A. Invitations will
                        be issued shortly.</p>
                    <p>National Discount Company.—We have pleasure in calling the attention of our
                        readers to the balance-sheet ot the National Discount Company, Limited,
                        which appears in our issue of to-day. The half-yearly meeting of this
                        prosperous company was held in London on the 18th ult., when the chairman,
                        Mr. Edmund Theodore Duxat, laid before the shareholders the most
                        satisfactory result ot the half year’s business and a dividend was declared
                        at the rate of 10 percent per annum, a balance of £11,148 14s. 7d. being
                        carried forward.</p>
                    <p> Abbas Helmy Theatre.—The extraordinary opera season at this theatre will
                        open tomorrow with La Traciata, in which the celebrated singer Signora
                        Belliucioni will appear in the leading role. It had been intended to open
                        with Fedora, but delay in the arrival of the stage properties necessary has
                        prevented this. No one should miss the rare opportunity of hearing one of
                        the finest singers which Italy has produced. Before coming to Egypt, Signora
                        Bellincioni gave a series of five performances at Venice before audieuces
                        who went frantic with excitement. We shall have more to say about this
                        charming artiste tomorrow. Meantime we may say that bookings for tomorrow
                        night's performance are very numerous. Signa. Svieher, with whose
                        extraordinary success at the Verdi Theatre, Cairo, our readers are
                        acquainted, will appear at the Abbas Helmy Theatre on Saturday in one of her
                        favourite roles, that of “Lucia di Lammermoor.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM.</head>
                    <p>Near Shepard's &amp; Continental Hotels. Turkish Baths, Plain Baths, Electric
                        Light Baths.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>XRAYS.</head>
                    <p>Medical Leaders. Dr. Professor Fornario &amp; Dr M. Roat.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL</head>
                    <p><placeName>CAIRO.</placeName> Open all the year round.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PILGRIMAGE. SEVERE COLD AT TOR.</head>
                    <p>Up to date over 9,000 pilgrims have passed through Tor. Dr. Ruffer, President
                        of the Quarantine Board, has returned from Tor after inspecting the pilgrim
                        camp. The arrangements of the camp, we learn, are excellent, but
                        modifications are necessary for next year as the pilgrimage will take place
                        in the middle of the cold season. Thanks to the liberality of the Ministry
                        of Finance the buildings for the Egyptian pilgrims have been completed, and
                        they will now be lodged in stone houses instead of tents, as heretofore.
                        Over 3,000 pilgrims can now be lodged in houses at the same time. There are
                        four great sections with houses each section being capable of accommodating
                        800 pilgrims. An experiment is in progress for draining one section. The
                        cold at Tor now is intense, and last week the thermometer registered two
                        degrees below zero ! Private advices from Mecca report that the pilgrims,
                        who arrive there in large numbers, are in good health. The sanitary
                        condition of Medina is also quite satisfactory. The Governor of the Hedjaz
                        and the Emir of Mecca have informed the Turkish Ministry of the Interior,
                        under date of the 19th ult., that in the grand procession, which takes place
                        before the ceremony of the pilgrimage to Medina, the pilgrims were mounted
                        on 3,507 camels. They offered up prayers for the Caliph. Their state of
                        health is satisfactory.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL</head>
                    <p>In reference to the letter of our correspondent “Observer,” in yesterday’s
                        issue, we may state that a large proportion of the treasure which
                        accompanies the Mahmal is devoted to religions and chartitable purposes. A
                        sum of close on L.E. 30,000 figures in the Budget lor 1905 os being expended
                        on gifts to the poor of Mecca and Medina, and the distribution of large
                        quantities of core among the needy inhabitants of these towns. The hire of
                        camels and steamers, the wages of guides, the payment to the Bedouins, and
                        the ordinary expenses of the voyage make up most of the remainder of the
                        total.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PLAGUE.</head>
                    <p>In consequence of no fresh cases of plague having occurred during the past
                        week, the quarantine restrictions imposed in Egyptian ports on the departure
                        of vessels have been removed. A fresh credit of LE. 10,000 has been opened
                        by the Finance Ministry for the Sanitary Department to defray the cost of
                        fighting the plague and bovine typhus.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive and the Khedivah are expected to return to Cairo on Thursday
                        evening.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BISHOP BLYTH'S VISIT.</head>
                    <p>Bishop Blyth purposes to leave Jerusalem for Egypt about March 4, when Canon
                        Dow. D.D, is expected to return from Australia to take up his work as Canon
                        Residentiary of St. George's Cathedral Church. On his way to Cairo the
                        Bishop will visit Port Said and perhaps Suez, holding a confirmation at the
                        former place. From Cairo, the Bishop will come to Alexandria, and he hopes
                        to be at St. Mark’s on the 2nd Sunday in Lent, March 19.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> PARTY ON RODAH ISLAND.</head>
                    <p>Dr. and Mrs. Keatinge gave a very successful party on Rodah Island yesterday
                        afternoon, on the occasion of the preliminary races of the “one-design”
                        class. The weather was not all that could be desired at the start, several
                        slight showers falling, but after 4 p.m. it cleared up well, though the
                        absence of wind was very much against racing. There was a great concourse of
                        visitors at the north end of the island, where a large marquee had been
                        erected in which excellent tea and refreshments were provided, Mr. Wild, of
                        the Savoy Hotel, presiding over their distribution, while the band of the
                        2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers played selections during the afternoon. An
                        Arab conjurer added to the amusement of those present, and the arrangements
                        for the transport of Dr. and Mrs. Keatinge’s guests to and from Rodah were
                        excellent, one of the fine new boats of the Cie des Bateaux Omnibus having
                        been chartered for the occasion. Altogether it was a most enjoyable and
                        representative gathering. Among those present were Lord and Lady Cromer, Sir
                        William Garstin, Lady Blomfield, the Hon. A. Davey, Dean and Mrs. Butcher,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Alban, Mr. P. W. Machell, Mrs. Hogg, Mr. and Mrs. Purvis Bey,
                        Mrs. Graham, Major and Mrs. Garner, Dr. Symmers, Dr. and Mrs. Nolan, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Sharman, Mrs. Brunyate, Mrs. Wylde, Mr. and Mrs. Marshall Hewat, Mr.
                        Courtenay Clifton, Milhem Shakour Bey and Miss Chakour, Capt Bigge, Mr.
                        Hooker, Mr. Allan Joseph, Mr. and Mrs. Tatten Browne, Dr. and Mrs. Phillips,
                        Mr. and Mrs. King-Lewis, Mr. Greville, Mr. Maudalay, and many other
                        well-known residents. The lack of wind unfortunately told against racing ;
                        it had been arranged that the four competing boats should race over a
                        triangular course to Ghizeh and back, but this proved impossible and a
                        course round two boats and back was substituted. Not all the boats finished,
                        Major Garner and Mr. Muntz proving winners by 80 seconds.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT</head>
                    <p>ALLEGED FIND OF COAL</p>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent). <placeName>Farshut,</placeName> January 29. The
                        Corporation of Western Egypt has selected Farshut as its base for the
                        development of the area of its concession, and has been despatching from
                        this town expeditions to tho Oasis of Khargeh. While some engineers lest
                        week wore on an expedition they came across what is believed to be a seam of
                        coal. Some samples of the mineral were to the end have been sent to Cairo. I
                        am informed that the analysis shows that it is pure coal. If this is really
                        the ease it is an event of the first importance in the history of the
                        industrial development of Egypt. But it must be accepted with caution, for
                        coal has been said before now to heve been found in the Sudan, though the
                        discovery has never led to anything, so judgment must be reserved for the
                        time being, as the coal may not repay the cost of working. The same
                        expedition also found a cave, where there were valuable deposits of
                        “colouring paints,” samples of which have ako been sent to Cairo for
                        analysis. Many trades of old mines hare also been found, which show that in
                        bygone times this part of the desert was inhabited. It is hoped that gold,
                        marble, and other valuable minerals will also be found. Farshut is a small
                        town and the inhabitants are looking forward to the future, for, owing to
                        the corporation having made it a base on the Nile for the operations in the
                        cases and the surrounding desert, it should grow into an important centre.
                        The traffic through the desert from Kordofan to Cairo will in time be
                        diverted by way of the cases to Farshut, so the gum, ostrich feathers,
                        ivory, and other products trill be brought to the river to be taken
                        northwards by way of Farshut, which will in time become the Alexandria of
                        this part of Egypt. On Tuesday Mr. Antoine and other leading spirits of the
                        Corporation of Western Egypt are expected to arrive here. The town of
                        Farshut is much in need of improvement! The people here inform me that they
                        want a post-office savings bank established here and they hope that Saba
                        Pasha, the Postmaster-General, will see his way to setting up such a useful
                        innovation. The corporation has bustled up the post-office here and has
                        greatly increased the postal work. Another deficiency is the non-stopping of
                        the sleeping car train at Farshut. It is a great hardship to the members and
                        employee of the corporation, who have to go up and down to Cairo very often,
                        to be obliged to take a slow train because the “train de luxe” passes here
                        without stopping. I have been commissioned by the people of Farshut to air
                        these two grievances in the columns of the "Egyptian Gazette” so that both
                        the Egyptian Railway Administration and the Post Office Administration may
                        at once bring about these trifling but much-needed improvements in the
                        amenities of civilized life at Farshut.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH Of LATIN PATRIARCH OF JERUSALEM.</head>
                    <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.) <placeName>Jerusalem,</placeName> January 26. The
                        Roman Catholic Church has just sustained a great loss by the death of one of
                        its distinguished prelates in the person of Monsignor Ludovic Piavi, Latin
                        Archbishop and Patriarch of Jerusalem, and Grand Master of the Order of the
                        Holy Sepulchre, who passed away in this city on the afternoon of 24th inst.,
                        in his 72nd year, from an acute attack of influenza, which be contracted
                        about a fortnight previously and which culminated fatally, having developed
                        into pneumonia. The deceased prelate belonged to the Franciscan Order, with
                        which be had associated himself since his youth, and took Orders fifty years
                        ago. He filled the difficult post of Apostolic Delegate Syria for nearly
                        sixteen years, a task which he accomplished with admirable tact amongst the
                        various Eastern seats united with the Church of Rome ; and in 1889 Pope Leo
                        XIII. He was selected to succeed the late Monsignor Vincenzo Braceo as
                        Patriarch in Jerusalem. He was a prominent figure among ecclesiastics, and
                        his imposing presence and great accomplishments as a conscientious man of
                        the world with liberal ideas and sensible actions, his affable add gentle
                        manners, as well as his benefits, made him very popular not only amongst his
                        own people and surroundings, but also among all sections of tbe population.
                        Mgr. Piavi was decoratod with the Grand Cordon of the Red Eagle on the
                        occasion of tbe Emperor William’s visit to the Holy City in 1898; and by the
                        Sultan of Turkey with both the Orders of the Osmanieh and the Medjidich of
                        the lst Class. He had, besides, other honors conferred on him by the
                        different Sovereigns of Roman Catholic countries. The interment of the
                        deceased prelate took place today within the church of the Patriarchate,
                        after an impressive funeral service, which was conducted by the Titular
                        Bishop of Capernaum, Mgr. Luigi Riccardo, and the Very Rev. Frediano
                        Giannini, Franciscan Custodian of the Holy Land, assisted by a large body of
                        clergy and priests of the various Catholic congregations and orders. It was
                        attended by the entire Consular Corps, with their staffs, as well as by
                        representative if the Turkish Government and the various Churches in
                        Jerusalem.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>THE S.S.“Tuscan Prince," from Antwerp afid Middlesbro', left Malta on Tuesday
                        last and is due here on Saturday, with passengers and general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>General Strossal and the officers of the Port Arthur garrison are due on the
                        10th first, at Port Said, where they will remain for a few hours previous to
                        embarking for Odessa on a Russian vessel. The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire
                        are probably leaving for the Riviera at the end of the week. The ex-Empress
                        Eugenue leaves Cairo for Luxor and Assouan on a dahabieh tomorrow.
                        Crooksbank Pasha, British controller of the Daira Senieh Administration, and
                        part left Rodah yesterday on the S.S. “Pelican". In compliance with a
                        request of the (Ecumenical Patriarch, the Turkish Government has authorised
                        Mgr. Sebastian} Metropolitan Of Uakub, to earns to Egypt for the benefit of
                        his health. His Imperial Majesty the Sultan has conferred the second class
                        of the Shefakat upon Anne Hadidje Quilliam and Mariain Quilliam, wives of
                        Abdullah Quilliam Effendi, head of the Mussulman community, at Liverpool.
                        His two daughters and Ali Quilliam, his uncle, have received the Medal of
                        Fine Arts. Among the passengers who arrived by the P.&amp; 0. “Macedonia”,
                        and left for Assoaan by the "Ramuses," is Miss L Manley, a lady well-known
                        in the educational world in Erignand, she being the prinicipal of the
                        Stockwell Training College, and a member of the cumulative committee of the
                        Board of Education, London. Miss Manley takes a deep interest in female
                        education in Egypt, having previously bad an Egyptian Mohamedan girl under
                        her charge at Stockwell College. The Rev. William Cowan, at present
                        assistant in St. Giles, Edinburgh, and formerly consular chaplain at
                        Alexandria, has been appointed minister of St Ninian's congregation,
                        Pleasance, Edinburgh. The following passengers leave Shellal today by the
                        P.S. “Memnon” for the Nile trip : Mr. Max Heumux, Mr. Jean Lefebvre, Mr. W.
                        H Sharpe, Mrs. Fred. Sharpe, Mr. Louis Vogeler, Mr. Fernand Morestman, Mr.
                        Bannister Fletcher, Mr, Mrs. and Miss Polynsen, Mrs. and Miss Begahew, Miss
                        Alice Noerbel, Miss Marta Cioognua, Miss P. Abraham. The death is annonunced
                        at Khartoum of Mgr. Gabriel Sfar, Maronite Patriarchal Vicar in Egypt, at
                        the age of 80. He had gone to Khartoum in connection with the foundation of
                        a school for the Maronita community of the Sudan. The following passengers
                        left Cairo on Monday by the P.S. "Cleopatra" for tbe Nile trip: Col. and
                        Mrs. Millner, Mr. and Mrs. W. Hamlyn. Mrs. and Miss Tatton Brown, Mrs.
                        Muuntoy Heygate, Capt Mounsey Heysham, Miss Mounsey, Mr. H. Gildemeistor,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Bivorta, Mr. and Mrs. H. Lincoln Tengye, Lady Donegall, Rev.
                        Bridgeman Boughton Leigh, Mr. Cottorell A W. Boughton-Leigh, Mr. and Mrs. T.
                        Meyer, Mr. and Mrs. James H. C. Crockett, Mr. Alderman John and Mrs.
                        Harrison, Miss Wells, Miss Cooney, Miss Spring, Mr. and Mrs. John Henry
                        Clark, Michalla Pacha, Mr. Sursock and party. In addition to the names of
                        the distinguished persons who were at Shepheard's Hotel on Monday night,
                        given in yesterday's issue, we may mention that the following dined in the
                        restaurant of the hotel prior to the hell: Prince Gustavos Adolphus of
                        Sweden and Norway and suite, Mr. Belinfante Ostberg, Consul-General for
                        Sweden and Norway, Comte Volesta Kocziedrociki, Diplomatic Agent for Austria
                        and Hungary, Sir Thomas Lipton and party, Vicomte de Fontarce, Comte
                        Sakakini Pasha and party of six, Mr. and Mrs. Granville Alexander, Mr. and
                        Mrs. E J. Milton, Mr. Em pain and party, Mr. and Mrs. Edw. Dain-gerfield and
                        family, Mrs. blather, Boron Schoeller, Dr. Madden and a party of six, Dr.
                        Joaunides and friends, Graf Holnstein, Marquis and Marchionaas de Cores,
                        etc. In the ball-room were the Marquis di Sorragna, Sir Edward find Lady
                        Zohrab, Mr. and Mrs. Leon, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSH TO EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The number of tourists arriving in Egypt via Port Said is enormous this year,
                        but Alexandria has also a great number passing through who arrive by the
                        White Star liners. The “Republic," which arrived here today, had an enormous
                        number of tourists, who left for Cairo at midday. The “Romantic,” her sister
                        ship, arrives on the 15th inst with a still larger number of passengers and
                        will also leave the next day. Every week until the end of tbe season two
                        Atlantic liners, of the White Star and North German Lloyd Lines, will
                        disembark tourists at Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>Par le paquebot-poste "Sydney" de la Messageries Maritimes parti hier pour
                        Mar Mjillft, avait a bord : M. Geo. Salomons, M. Chuxin, Mlle Fernet, M.
                        Neher, M. et Mme Hodeir. M. Fauquet, Mme Dermont et m sceur, M. Reeves, M.
                        Just, M. T. Hireohig. M. B. Tbeodoropoulo M. et Mme Zetky bey, et 18
                        passenegers de ime et ime classes. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDFOU NOTES: ROYAL VISITORS</head>
                    <p>On Saturday at 10 pm, the steamer "Ibis" bearing the Royal duca party up
                        river, passed by Edfou. Arrival had been previously made to illumnate the
                        river bank on the occassion of their arrival. The steamer on slackened speed
                        nd the crowds that lined the bank gave a warm salute, to whcih those on the
                        steamer graciously responded. The same day the Princess, accompanied by her
                        husband and three others (apparently belonging to the Khedivial
                        family),arrived here from Assousan. All the party wore European dress, and
                        they were taken at first for Europeans. They had a donkey drive from the
                        bank to the temple, which they visited after sundown. They then returned to
                        their dahabieh, accompanied by the Maniour and the Omideh, who were invited
                        to partake of coffee. Early in the morning they set off for Cairo.
                        Alexandria &amp; Ramleh Railway Cy. Ltd. The following is the report of the
                        Board of Directors of the Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Company Limited held
                        on Monday, the 16th of January. Nous venons vous soumettre les comptes del'
                        Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Company Limited de 1st Octobre 1903 an 30
                        Septembre 1904, at nous avons le plaisir de vous annoncer que les resultata
                        de cette annee pandant laquelle nous avonce commerce notre exploitation
                        electrique onte repondu a notre attente. La realisation de cette
                        transformation, qui avait preoccupe votre Compagnie depuis 1897, nous a
                        permis de dohner de nouvellee facilitee aux habitante de Ramleh et de la
                        ville, en augmentant le nombre de noe trains et en offrant an public de
                        frequents departs a toutes les heures du joir, sans avoir a se preoccuper
                        d'un horaire fixe. En effect, le nombre des trains a vapeur n'etait que de
                        50 par jour, dans chaque direction, a attent 300 departs d' Alexandrie, a
                        des intervalles de 3 a 5 minutes. De meme le nombre des gares a ete porte a
                        21 par l'ouverture de 5 nouvelles stations placees aux divers points
                        indiques par les exigences du trafic. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RECETTES</head>
                    <p>Les recettes de cette anne se sont elevees a P.T 4.824.565.12 Celles de
                        l'annee derniere avaient ete de 3.813.964.63 Soit un augmentation pour cette
                        annee de P.T. 1.010.600.49 Ces chiffres se repartissent de la maniere
                        auivante: 1902-1903 Recettes stations... ... P.T. 2.968.043.72 "
                        abonnements... ... " 646.939_ " diverses... ... " 198.981.91 Total ... P.T.
                        3.813.964.63 1903-1904 Recettes stations... ... P.T. 3.850.669.72 "
                        abonnements... ... " 796.509 " diverses... ... " 177.386.40 Total ... P.T.
                        4.824.565.12 Cette auguentation des recette est d'autant plus reinarquable
                        que la Compagne avait fait aubir une reduction de 12 1/2 % aux prix des
                        trajets simples de lere Classe et de 28% a ceux de 2eme Classe. Nous donnons
                        ici le tabeau comparatif du nombre de voyageurs transporte pendant le deux
                        derneires annes: 1902-1903 Voyageurs avec billets... ... 2.165.839 " "
                        abonnements (calcules a raison de 3 trajets par jour.) 896.910 3.062.749
                        1903-1904 Voyageurs avec billets... ... 3.237.555 " " abonnements (calcules
                        a raison de 3 trajets par jour.) 1.069.626 4.307.181 Soit une augmentation
                        de 1.233.432 voyageurs. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEPENSES</head>
                    <p>Les despenses totales de cette anneee so sont elevee a P.T. 2,931,611,24
                        Celles de l'annee derniere avaient ete de ... " 2,044,611,24 Soit une
                        augmentation pou cette annee de... ... P.T. 887,109.27 Cette augmentation de
                        depenses provient des 1,244,432 voyageurs que nous avons transportes en plus
                        de l'annee derniere d'un nombre de trains considerablement superieur et
                        aussi des depenses extraordinaires occasionnces par le changement due mode
                        de traction et d'exportation, depenses inherentes a tous debuts. Il a fallu,
                        en effet, pour ces diverses causes supporter un consommation presque
                        double.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL LUXOR</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Management. Moderate charges. Patronized by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
