<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Olivia Evanoff--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- 11/30/2016 --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- November 9,1905 --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, 11/09/1905, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA,Wednesday, November 9, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, Thursday, NOVEMBER 9 190S.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RUSSIAN HORRORS</head>
                        <head>“SURPASS IMAGINATION.”</head>
                        <head>VILLAGES BURNT.</head>
                        <p>St. Petebsburg, November 8. An official communique says that it is not to
                            be denied that, in some places, the local anthori- ties are hostile to
                            the reforms and have encouraged the recent excesses. A judicial enquiry
                            has been ordered in all the localities where it is suspected that such
                            has been the case. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Batoum, November 8. 120 Cossacks under the Governor of the district were
                            burning the villages in a turbulent district in the interior when they
                            were sur- rounded by armed rioters. 105 were killed after a desperate
                            resistance of 17 hours, (R)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Odessa, November 8. Yesterday 412 Jewish victims were buried in the
                            presence of vast crowds. They were buried, without coffins, in trenches
                            of seventy each. (R)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 8. Despite the general cessation of strikes, the
                            Railway Union has issued a significant circular to the railway men
                            saying that they must store their arms, and when the decisive mo- ment
                            comes rise as one man, and never lay them down until a complete victory
                            be won. The details of the horrors of the past ten days are gradually
                            leaking out. They surpass imagination. In one instance, at Minsk,
                            several detachments of troops poured a cross-fire into an unarmed crowd,
                            killing and wounding 400 in a few moments. It appears that 50,000 troops
                            with guns were landed by the warships at Helsingfors on the 3rd instaht.
                            The situation became most critical, when the Imperial manifesto arrived
                            and relieved the tension. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RELIEF ORGANISED BY JEWS.</head>
                        <p>New York, November 8. A mass meeting of Jews has formed a relief
                            committee in aid of the Russian sufferers ir- respective of religion.
                            56.800 dollars were received from Jews in London, Paris, and Berlin
                            offering to participate in an international relief organisation.
                            {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GRAND DUKE VLADIMIR.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 8. The Grand Duke Vladimir has resigned his
                            command of the Guard. (Hovaa)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>M. WITTE’S CABINET.</head>
                        <p>London, November 8. The "Times" learns from St. Petersburg that M. Witte
                            has completed his Cabinet. Prince Urosoff becomes Minister of the
                            Interior, Prince Eugene Trubetxski takes the portfolio of Public
                            Instruction, M. Shipoff that of Agriculture, while M. Nimjechaieff
                            becomes Minister of Railways. All bare liberal views. M. J. Sbipoff
                            takes the portfolio of Finance; the others are unchanged. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RAILWAY STRIKE IN AUSTRIA.</head>
                        <head>UNIVERSAL 8UPPRAGE MOVEMENT.</head>
                        <p>Vienna, November 8. Ten thousand Austrian railway employees have struck.
                            Their demands inclnde universal suffrage. The movement is spreading.
                            {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CRETAN INSURRECTION.</head>
                        <head>AMNESTY PROCLAIMED.</head>
                        <p>Canea, November 8. A proclamation has been issued by Colonel Benedetti,
                            chief of the international troops, calling upon the insurgents to lay
                            down their arms, and promising them an amnesty. (H)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH SQUADRON IN AMERICA.</head>
                        <p>Washington, November 8. After a week of the most cordial amenities from
                            naval and official circles here and at Annapolis, tbe British Squadron
                            went to Baltimore, where it was ovated by a crowd of 30,000, and thence
                            to New York. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TYPHOON IN JAPAN.</head>
                        <p>Tokio, November 8. A typhoon has ravaged the peninsula of Oshima.
                            (Hovas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>POWERS AND TURKEY.</head>
                        <head>NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                        <head>BLOCKADE OF DARDANELLES.</head>
                        <p>London, November 8. It is expected that the oombined fleets of tbe
                            Powers, composed of 15 worships, will appear in the Levant at the end of
                            the week. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Vienna, November 8. It is stated here that if the demonstration does not
                            modify the opposition of the Porte to the Macedonian reform scheme, the
                            pacific blockade of tbe Dardanelles will be proclaimed. {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                        <p>The Sanitary Administration is, we under- stand, in future to be known as
                            the Public Health Administration.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo-Alesandria Navigation, except-by way of the river, is at present
                            impracticable as the Bagonrieh Canal is closed for the time being.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Survey Department -The Finance Minis- try has opened a credit of L.E
                            4,0(0 for the Survey Department, in order to facilitate the land
                            survey.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>New Doctors—Abd-El-Arii Mohamed El- Ghamry, Dadd Suleiman Bulus, and
                            Shukri Khalil Maluf, doctors, have been authorised to follow their
                            profession in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Pilgrimage. — The Ministry of the Interior has selected the personnel
                            for the escort of the Mahmal. The Khedive will shortly nominate the Emir
                            el Hag.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Late Grand Mufti. -- The late Sheikh El Rafei left two works on the
                            Hsnifi rite, to which he put the finishing touches only a few weeks
                            before his death. His sons intend to publish those works after
                            Ramadan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Suez Canal.—29 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th and 5th inst.,
                            17 of which were British, 5 German, 3 French, 1 Austrian, 1 Dutch, 1
                            Swedish, 1 Egyptian. The receipts from the lst to the 5th inst were frs.
                            1,958,634.39.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Salt &amp; Soda Co., Ltd. —The sales of salt during Ootober produced L.B.
                            21,163 828, against L.E. 20,599 025 in October, 1901, the total sales
                            daring the ten months of each year being:—1905, LB. 209,216.165 ; 1904,
                            LE. 206,690.367.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Canal Cleaning.—All the canals in the Menoufieh and Gharbieh provinces
                            will have lower levels or will be closed to navigation by the 20th
                            December and navigation will be impossible, or at any rate very
                            difficult, from that date to the 20th Janaary, 1906.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Railway Fatality. - An express train was passing by E'phent station, at 1
                            a.m. on the 7th inst., when a native woman fell on to the line under the
                            train. Her head and hands were cat off. The next morning the doctor said
                            the moawen of Fashn marker examined the body, but it was not
                            identified.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo ‘ Zoo.”—By kind permission of the military authorities the Egyptian
                            Army In- fantry Band will play in tbe Ghizeh Zoolo- gical Gardens every
                            Sunday afternoon during this season, commencing on Sunday, 19th inst.
                            The Ghizeh Boys Band will play as usual in the Zoological Gardens every
                            Friday after- noon.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Affray with Robbers.—A party of night robbers broke into an ezbeh near
                            Da- lamsha, Bilbeis markaz, on Tuesday night, but were repelled by the
                            gbaffirs, who fired upon them, killing one. Tbe police com- ing rapidly
                            up, cut off the retreat of the remaining members of the gang, who are
                            now in prison</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Recruiting Department. — The Electorship of the Recruiting
                            Department, now vacant owing to the appointment of Sarhank Pasha to
                            succeed Lord Edward Cecil Pasha as Under-Secretary of State for War,
                            will probably be conferred on Miralai Mahmoud Bey Tewfik, head of the
                            Military College, who in his turn will be replaced by Hussein Bey
                            Jherif, chief of the Recruiting Department in be Gharbieh province.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KING’S BIRTHDAY REVIEW.</head>
                        <head>KHEDIVE PRESENT.</head>
                        <p>The presence of H.H. the Khedive and of Lord Cromer, the bright weather,
                            and the occasion of the 64th birthday of King Edward VII. drew large
                            numbers of sightseers to this morning's review on Abdeen-sqaaro, Cairo,
                            and though, as a spectacle, the sight was perhaps not as impressive as
                            in 1904, owing to the reduction of the Army of Occupation, there was
                            still any amount of oolour and life in the scene, and the troops bore
                            themselves admirably. Comparisons are of course odious, and we have no
                            intention of attempting them. We need only say that the parade movements
                            were very good, the marching, dressing, wheeling, etc., being
                            excellently carried out, and that the physique of the men was admirable.
                            The British soldier in Egypt is a far more satisfac- tory sight than too
                            many of the rank and file of tbe line battalions that one sees at home,
                            and which often appear to be composed of weedy boys. The police were in
                            readiness before 9 a.m., and the square, which had been cleared of
                            vehicles and loiterers, awaited the coming of tbe troops. At the
                            entrances of the streets leading to the square, except those that had
                            been kept free for the troops to enter and to leave by, large crowds
                            gathered betimes, and the enclosures filled up rapidly. By a
                            quarter-past nine all the troops had moved into the square and taken up
                            their posi- tions, facing westward, the Rifles being on the left nearest
                            the Palace, the Inniakillings next, and the Royal Engineers, Mounted
                            Infantry, and Royal Garrison Artillery on the right. At 9.80 Lord Cromer
                            drove up, the troops saluting to the strains of "God save the King,”
                            while the Royal Standard was hoisted. The British Consul-General, after
                            a short oonversa tion with Brig-General Bullock, then drove along tbe
                            rank, the troops presenting arms as he passed. H.H. the Khedive
                            afterwards arrived, escort- ed by his Body Gaard, and mounted on a
                            magnificent white Arab, tire bands playing the Khedivial Anthem as his
                            Highneea took up his position close to the Royal Stan- dard. A general
                            salute followed, the national anthem being played again, and the troops
                            gave three cheers for H.M. the King with great heartiness, to the
                            accompaniment of the guns in the CitadeL The troops then marched past,
                            H.H. the Khedive taking the salute, after which came the interesting
                            ceremony of trooping the colour. The review closed with the Khedivial
                            salute, alter which officers and men returned to barracks. We understand
                            that the Khedive expressed his great satisfaction to General Bollock at
                            the fine appearance and admirable drill of the troops.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CELEBRATION AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                        <p>At Alexandria, the usual parade took place on Mustapha Pasha
                            parade-gronnd at 10 a.m. a feu dejoie being fired by the Royal Dublin
                            Fusiliers. At the same time a salute of 21 guns was fired from Fort
                            Kom-el-Dik. The Royal Standard Boats over all stations occupied by
                            British troops to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>Immediately after the review this morning the Khedive returned to Abdeen
                            Palace, where he received the Russian Agent and Consul- General, who
                            presented his credentials in solemn audience.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LORD EDWARD CECIL</head>
                        <p>The following Order has been published by H.R the Sirdar :— H.B. the
                            Sirdar wishes to express the great- est regret at the retirement from
                            the Egyptian Army of El Lewa Lord Edward Cecil Pasha, D.S.O., who is
                            taking up a new appointment under the Egyptian Government as Under-
                            secretary of State in the Ministry of Finance, As Military Secretary,
                            Director of Intelligence, Agent-General, and Under-Secretary of State
                            for War, Lord Edward Cecil has shown most marked ability and tact, and
                            the excellenoe and brilliance of his work has been very con- spicuous.
                            The Sirdar desires to place on record his sincere appreciation of this
                            officer's most valuable services, and on behalf of the Army wishes him
                            every success in his future career.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                        <p>The Ministry of Finance has agreed to a credit of LB. 14,000 for the
                            sanitary and other measures to be taken on the return of tbe pilgrims
                            from Mecca and Medina.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Cunard S.S. Pavia arrived at Liverpool yesterday afternoon. The S.S.
                            Royal Prince, with passengers and general cargo, from London, left Malta
                            yester day, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Sanday. The Westcott
                            S.S. City of Dundee arrived last night from Newcastle, London, snd
                            Malts, with passengers snd general cargo. Tbe EIIeiman S.S. Andalusian
                            arrived yes- terday from Glasgow and Malta with general cargo. The
                            Ellerman S.S. Avon tails to-day for Liverpool direct.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
                        <head>LOCAL RECIPIENTS.</head>
                        <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                        <p>London, Thursday, Nov. 9. Among the recipients of Birthday honors are Dr.
                            Buffer and Harari Pasha, who have been made C.M.G.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EARL OF MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.) Port Said, Wednesday. The P. &amp; O. Victoria,
                            by which Lord and Lady Minto are travelling to India, has a large number
                            of prominent people on board, among whom are Major F. L Adam (Lord
                            Minto’s A.D.C.), Sir G. Arbothnot, Surgeon Lieut. Col. and Mrs. W. R.
                            Crooke-Lawlesa, Dr. K Dolman, Lord C. Dundas, Lady E Elliott, Lady R.
                            Elliott, Lady V. Elliott, Lady Fawkes, Hon. and Mrs. R Lyttleton, Sir
                            Francis and Lady MaoLean, with two daughters, Lord Francis Soott,
                            Lieot-Co. J. R. Dunlop Smith, Lady Sampson, and the Hon. Vansittart-
                            Lord Minto, with a large party of friends, dined at the Eastern Exchange
                            last night</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EXPRESS SERVICE TO EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>The Ellerman, Hall and City Lines announced a monthly express service
                            from Liverpool to Egypt Bombay, and Knrrachee. The service will commence
                            on December 14 with the Trafford Hall, a new steamer launched last week.
                            The average passage to Port Said is to be ten and a half days, and to
                            Bombay twenty-one days' sea passage, the Seer Canal excluded. The
                            steamers allocated to this service include the new steamer City of
                            Calcutta, which recently made a passage to Calcutta under twenty-six
                            days.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SALVAGE OF DERELICT CRANE.</head>
                        <p>During the homeward voyage of the New castle steamer Aureole, from the
                            Black Sea to Shields, the crew came across a self-propelling floating
                            crane, supported by means of a pontoon about 100ft long, used for ship
                            repairing in rivers or harbors. It was in the direct route of steamers
                            bound from Cape Matapan to Cape Pasoaro. The Aoreole took the pontoon in
                            tow with three 7in. hawsers. For a time some of the sailors remained
                            aboard the deraliot to bale out the water, but it labored so heavily in
                            tbe heavy seas that they were obliged to come on board tbeir own vessel.
                            The pontoon crane which was worth £l 5,000, was bound for Port Said, but
                            nothing is known as to wbat has beoome of its crew or the tag which
                            presumably bad charge of it. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO MIXED TRIBUNALS.</head>
                        <p>The Cairo Tribunal Correctional met yester- day morning under the
                            presidency of Judge Nyholm. supported by Judge Hexligera and Judge
                            Yonuef Axis The assessors were Dr. Voronoff, Dr. A. Schoober.and Messrs.
                            J. Payn, R. Bnriqoez, and Charles Batten berg, the Parqnet being
                            represented by Mahmond Bey Rashdy. Three appeals against sentences for
                            contra- ventions were heard, a British and Russian and a French snbject
                            having all got into trouble for keeping an establishment for hashish
                            smokers. In two cases the hearing of the appeal was pat off for a month
                            ; in the third the sentence was upheld by default. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Hooker, we learn, is only awaiting the dispositions of the London
                            board, before sever- ing his connection with the Egypt Land and General
                            Trnst Limited. Mr. A. P. Maok, a director of the Land and General Trust
                            left London on Tuesday last for Egypt, in connection with the business
                            of the Trust.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ROBBERY OF ANTIQUITIES.</head>
                        <p>There have been a large and increasing number of robberies at Karnak
                            lately among the workmen employed by M. Legrain in excavating on behalf
                            of the Department of Antiquities. The most honest and hardest workers
                            have one after the other been caught in the very act, and in every case
                            the theft was done to the temptations put in the way of the workmen by
                            the dealers in antiquities, who offer the men very high prices. At
                            Karnak there are agents paid by these dealers, who deliberately corrupt
                            the workmen and the night watchmen.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM MENA.</head>
                        <p>The following residents are staying at Mena Honse: Mrs. Sidney Carver and
                            Min Carver, Mrs. Madden and fsmily, Mr. C. F. Armstrong, Ugo La-ena Bey.
                            Mr. J. M. Dodd, Mr. C. N. Firth, Rev. and Mrs. Gordon Proctor. Dr. and
                            Mrs. BUiot Smith and Mr. P. 8. Anderson and family will spend the winter
                            at Mena Honse. Mr. James P. G. Hopkins and family are »lao booked for a
                            short stay there. Among others staying at Mena are Dr. and Mrs. Hayes,
                            Mr. Wright Henderson, Mr. 0- Crockett, Mrs. Charles Pease, Min Bewley,
                            and Herr Kart Wuttke.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                        <head>FRESH OUTBREAK IN SUDAN.</head>
                        <p>Cattle plague has again broken out in the Sudan. 8,000 doses of serum
                            have been dis- patched from Cairo, and it is hoped that the outbreak
                            will be oonfined to the small area at present infected. We learn that
                            several veterinary inspectors, who have up to the present been employed
                            on cattle plague work in Egypt, are to be transferred for duty in the
                            Sudan. The Serum Institute that was opened at Abassieh has been given up
                            altogether, the remaining bulls having been bled to death for serum. A
                            quantity of this rinderpest serum is now stored with the Nile Cold
                            Storage, Co., sufficient to keep within bounds any serious outbreak.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>IMPORTATION OF CATTLE.</head>
                        <p>The Quarantine Board has decided to with- draw, as from the 29nd inst.,
                            the decision to admit into the abattoirs is the interior of Egypt
                            bovidue coming from Syria, Asia Minor as for as the Dardanelles, Turkey
                            in Barope (Macedonia, Bulgaria), Ronmania, and Russia, and from any
                            other country which may not be recognised as healthy and free from any
                            suspicion of episooty. These bovidic, however, will be admitted at
                            Alexandria and Port Said, with a view to their slaughter in quarantine.
                            Bovide coming from the Somali coast and from the Eastern Sudan will be
                            landed at Suez. there to be slaughtered in quarantine. Tbe present
                            dispositions concerning sheep remain in force.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
                        <p>Another case of plague has been discovered at Alexandria, the patient
                            being a Greek pastry- cook of the Midan quarter. In consequence of this
                            case the usual qua- rantine measures on the departure of vessels from
                            Egyptian ports have been re-established.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FINANCE MINISTRY.</head>
                        <p>In all likelihood Lord R Cecil Pasha, as co-Under Secretary of State for
                            Finance with Mr. Mitchell Innes, will be allotted the Free State Land
                            and the Direct Taxes Departments. The remaining departments will be left
                            for Mr. Mitchell Innes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                        <p>Lieutenant G. Stewart, Coldstream Guards, has been specially selected for
                            service in the Egyptian Army. Leave of absence, on private affairs, has
                            been granted to El Lewa St. George C. Henry Pasha, O.B., Adjutant
                            General, B1 Kai" akam Bray Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Com- u ins
                            Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Ismail Bey Himmet, Beoraiting
                            Department. Bl Bim- ba«hi Clayton, Deputy Assistant Adjutant General,
                            and El Bimbashi Teacher, 19th Sudanese. The undermentioned offioers
                            passed the Intermediate Arabio Examination held on the 2nd Ootober: El
                            Bimbashi Feilden, Inspector, Bahr El Ghsztl Province, El Bimbashi Lewin,
                            Assistant Financial Secretary, El Bimbashi Carey, 16th Battalion, El
                            Bimbashi Nickerson, Inspector, Sennar Province, and El Bimbashi Jennings
                            Bramly, Cavalry.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STATE DOMAINS.</head>
                        <p>Messrs. N. M. Rothschild and Sons an- nouncee that a drawing amounting to
                            £29,800 nominal capital of the Egyptian State Domain Mortgage bonds will
                            take place this month in accordance with the terms of the general bond
                            of this loan. The numbers and descrip- tions of tbe bonds drawn will be
                            advertised, and all bonds so drawn will cease to bear interest from
                            December 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COTTON EXPORTS FROM EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>During the week ending the 29th October over 37,000 bales of cotton
                            reached tbe port of Manchester, of which 20,951 were from America and
                            the remainder from Egypt. American shipments of cotton to Manchester
                            this season have now reached 35,596 bales, a number behind the record of
                            1904. Tbe im- portations from Egypt show an increase over this
                            corresponding period of last year of about 3,000 bales.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCE.</head>
                        <p>A correspondent writes:- Some annoyance has recently been caused at Cairo
                            by the increases of that annoying class of bicyclists which prefers the
                            pavement to tbe road. Out at Gherireh, or beyond Shocbra and Abbasaieb,
                            there is, no doubt, less to be urged against tbe habit, but it is no
                            joke to walk on the pavements of, say, Suleiman Pasha-street, or the
                            streets leading toward tbe Ministries, if one is constantly called upon
                            to get ont of the way by the bells of youthful bicyclists, many of whom
                            seem to steer so badly that one easily understands why they avoid the
                            neighbourhood of the arabiyas. Of course, if one refuses to move the
                            cyclists must avoid the pedestrian, bnt he often steers so badly that it
                            is better to run no risks.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
                        <head>SERIOUS DAMAGE TO RAILWAY.</head>
                        <head>(From oub Correspondent.)</head>
                        <p>Suakin, November 1. Washouts have taken place on the Suakin- Athars line,
                            and serious damage has resulted in several places. Trains stopped
                            running from both ends between the 95th and 98th Ootober, when tbe line
                            was repaired and put in good order. Kaimakam Loogfield Bey, E.E.,
                            Asaristant Director of Railways, left hereby special train on the night
                            of the 98th ult on inspection duty and returned on the 80th, -after
                            having found everything in perfect working order. Mr. Thomas Purvis,
                            Suakin-Atbara Railway, returned from leave of absence by the Khedi- vial
                            mari steamer Neghileh on 80th nit, bringing with him Mrs. Purvis and
                            child. Dr. Crispin, S.M.O., Buskin Mondirieh, is leaving for Port Sudan.
                            He will organise the Mondirieb medical staff and hospital then. Dr.
                            Pahmy win remain here as S.M.O. in charge of the hospitals and the
                            Suakin railway employee. Among the signs of the development of the
                            Sudan, and the benefits resulting from the opening of the new port, I
                            may mention the fact that Messrs. Loremato Bros., a large firm of
                            merchants, who have branches at almost every port in the Red Sea, have
                            already established themselves af Port Sedan. Both there and at Buskin,
                            they are largely patronised by English people. Their goods come chiefly
                            from England and are in price. Mr. George Lorenxtato is the general
                            manager, and all orders pass through his hands and receive his personal
                            attention.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MYSORE CO. AND EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>In the report of tbe Mysore Reefs and General Exploration Company for the
                            year ended September 30, the directors propose another reconstruction.
                            Tbe present company was formed as recently as July, 1909, as a
                            reconstruction of tbe Mysore Reefs (Kangundy) Mining Company, but the
                            directors now explain that a large proportion of the capital is repre-
                            sented in the balance sheet by the property originally worked in India,
                            upon which opera- tions have been suspended, and they considsr that the
                            time has arrrived when this unproduc- tive expenditure should be dealt
                            with. They, therefore, propose to form "The Mysore Reefs and General
                            Explorers, limited," to take over the assets and liabilities of the
                            present company. The capital of the new company would be £50,000,
                            divided into 40,000 Preference and 160,000 Ordinary Shares of 6s each
                            thus providing for the allotment of one fully-paid Ordinary Share for
                            each old Ordinary Shan, and one fully-paid Preference Share for each old
                            Preference Share. Tbe existing shares are £l fully paid, and the
                            proposal is thus to write down the capital account by 76 per dent The
                            report shows a balance of profit for the year at £1,673.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <p>Princess Nazli Hanem arrived at Alexandria from Tonis early this morning
                            by the S.S. City of Dundee. On the vetsel being signalled the Governor
                            went ont to meet her in a Ports and lights tender, and her Highness then
                            landed. She is proceeding to Cairo to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lady Cromer arrived at Cairo at 5 o’clock yesterday afternoon from Port
                            Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. de Kerber, ex-President of the Council in Austria, is expected in
                            Egypt in a few days. He will make a lengthy stay in Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Baron de Villebois, the Dutch Agent and Consul-General at Cairo, is
                            expected to return on Saturday next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Connt G. de Zogheb has arrived in Cairo from Europe.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Captain Gedge, R.N., Deputy Controller of Ports and Lighthouses, returned
                            to Alexandria from leave yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Edmond Robertson, M.P., left London last week for Gibraltar and
                            Egypt</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The latest bulletin indicates a alight improve- ment in the condition of
                            Maitre Molteni.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. Mermont, chief inspector to the French Eastern Railways and Mine
                            Mermont have arrived in Cairo, where they an making a short stay
                            preparatory to visiting Laxor and Assouan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Robert Williams, F.R.I.B.A., consulting architect to the Central
                            Buildings Co, Ltd., has returned to. Alexandria from London, there he
                            was called on important business. among other matters being the mosque
                            which it is proposed to build in the Metropolis. Mr. Williams,
                            notwithstanding the immense cost of the scheme feels asnguine that it
                            will be arried out sooner or later. The chief difficulty appears to be
                            finding a suitable site in tbe City. Mr. Williams, who was at one time a
                            member of the London County Council, is an authority on the boating
                            ques- tion, and has published a very interesting work on the subject,
                            which deserves the persual of many who an interested those in this
                            oouatry, </p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
