<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2021-01-21">January 21, 2021</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-02-14/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-14">Tuesday, February 14, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/mode/1up" status="incomplete">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-ad-etc02"> The Eastern
                                Telegraph Company, Limited.<lb/> Le réseau de cable télégraphiques
                                sous-marins de cette compagnie<lb/> constitue le moyen de
                                communication le plus<lb/> direct et le plus rapide d'Egypte pour
                                l'Europe, l'Amérique<lb/> du Nord et du Sud, L,Afrique orientale,
                                méridionale<lb/> et occidentale, les Indes, l'Australie, la
                                Nouvelle-Zélande, la<lb/> Chine et le Japon.<lb/> Pour assurer une
                                transmission rapide, les télégrammes<lb/> doivent porter
                                l'indication <hi rend="bold">Viâ Eastern</hi>.<lb/> Voir le temps
                                moyen de transmission le plus récent jusqu'à<lb/> Londres au
                                belletin journalier publié dans ce journal.<lb/> STATIONS EN EGYPTE.
                                Alexandrie, le Caire, Suez,<lb/> Port-Tewfik, Port-Said, Suakin.
                                Bureau principal à Londres.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7123">7,123</measure>]</cell>
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 14, 1905.</cell>
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->

                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->

                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->

            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n1/mode/1up">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n2/mode/1up" status="verified">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WAR</head>
                        <head>RUSSIANS REPULSE INFANTRY ATTACK</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Sr. PETRUSBURG, February 13 </dateline>
                            <p>General Kurpaktin seposta dmi 300 Japanese cavalry bitücked the
                                railway bridge al t urg on the 12instaud dainaged una of the live.
                                Traffic was subsequently tel. The Japanese, on the 11th iul,
                                brianded the Russim. pušitions with sient 1. The Japanese i fantry
                                attack was</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STATE OF SIEGE IN VLADHOSTOK.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>CSI L'ETERSBURO, February 13, </dateline>
                            <p>It is atidance bere that a state of siena isbyen pauclusimed at
                                Viadin stuk. Part of le intrabitants have lurriedly left the
                                tủwn.</p>
                            <p>(llente</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THIRD BALTIC FLEET.</head>
                        <head>INSUBORDINATION AMONG MEN.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, February 13 A </dateline>
                            <p>certajer'amount of insubordination prevails mount the men of the
                                thiril Baltic Fleet A milor was shot on Saturday for stabbing a
                                lieutenant.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COLLIERS REFUSED JSTLUM.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>1: 143703. BA S ta), February 13.</dateline>
                            <p>The German ar Bulgariak" wid the Briti-l cuisi t osi'arived here.
                                "The ich athutties blete them to Batavia, where there to be lauded
                                and sold.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCOMOTIES FOR JAPAN.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>LADON, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The Japewe. Government has placed an irgent order in Glasgow for 30
                                locomotiven. (leuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY. SITTINGS RESUMED.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Paris, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The North Sea Commissioners resumed their sittings today. The parties
                                submitted their coriclusions, both strougly adhering to their
                                original statements. (Reuter.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>PARIS, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The North Sea Commission of Enquiry has heard the conclusions of
                                counsel for England and for Russia</p>
                            <p>The conclusions of the English counsel maintain the absence of
                                torpe-to-boats and declan the Russian fire to have been
                                unjustified.</p>
                            <p>The conclusions of the Russian counsel deciure that military reasons
                                justified the fin of the Russian ships. Russia, however, agree to
                                pay an indemnity, which would be fixed by the Hague Tribunal.
                                ...</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"DOWN WITH THE AUTOCRACY." DEMONSTRATION AT A THEATRE.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>SA PETERSBURG, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>There was # demonstration in the Mal Theatre bere last night, men
                                crying "Down with the autocracy and making use of persona învectives
                                against the Tur. The demonstrators were finally ejected, and the
                                performance i continued.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AMERICAN ARBITRATION. THE PRESIDENT AND SENATE.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>WASItingtox, February 13. - </dateline>
                            <p>President Roosevelt and the Senate have reached ad acute state of
                                disagreement concerning the arbitration treaties which Mr. Hay has
                                laboriously concluded with Japan, Great Britain, and syemal other
                                European Powers. In spite of strong pressure on the part of Mr.
                                Rooreveit, the Senate inserted an amendment in the treaties Securg
                                to it the right to intervene belore any question is submittest w
                                arbitration. In consequence, Mr. Roosevelt has resolved to drop the
                                treaties altogether,</p>
                            <p>Public opinion, apparently, endorsey the action of the Suuate.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS. AN HISTORICAL EVENT:</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Vissa, Pebruary 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The Emperor yesterday received Herr Kos. suth in connection with the
                                Hungarian crisis. It was a notable bistorical event as it was his
                                first entrance to the Palace to my homage to the Emperor who bad
                                condemned his father to death. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GERMANY AND ABYSSINIA. MISSION AT ADIS ABEBA.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>BERLIN, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The German mission, mentioned on the 6th December, has been received
                                by the Emperor Menelik at Adis Abeba. The mission will remain there
                                for 20 days. .. (Renter.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Tux AMERICAN STEAM </head>
                        <p>Yacur "Aloedo," lir. G. W. C. Drexel, owner, has arrived from</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FIELD DAY-- </head>
                        <p>A tactical field day will be held at ibhussieh for the Cairo garrison on
                            Thurs next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The KHEDIVE'- </head>
                        <p>Yacht the "Mahroussa," which arrived in the Clyde a firtnight ago, i. uw
                            moored close to. Meurs. Inglis' yard at Penthouse, where the alterations
                            will be carried out.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ALEXANDRIA SCANDAL. -</head>
                        <p>The Italian Consular Court of Alexandria pronounced judgment yesterday in
                            the divorce proceedings instituted by Mr. Ninci. Particulars will be
                            found on page 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The POWELL-COTON EXPEDITION </head>
                        <p>has left the Nile and arrived at the Zubesi. Accurd. Jing to the latest
                            advices received from Major</p>
                        <p>Powell Cotton he has started for an unexplored section of the Congo Stata
                            in -carch of the wlata rhinoceros.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PHE AMERICAN COLLEGE, BEYROUT. — </head>
                        <p>"An Eye witness" sends us details of some strange events, which are
                            alleged to have transpired at the American College at Beyrout on the 7th
                            and sth inst. As our orrespondent is anony mous we cannot publish his
                            statements.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAQUE.. </head>
                        <p>During the week ending Satunlay last, 7 deaths from bovine typhus were
                            reported throughout Egypt. During the corresponding week in 1904 5,949
                            deaths were notified. Since the beginning of the epidemic the total
                            number of deaths is 146 710.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW CATHEDRAL FOR CAIRO.- </head>
                        <p>The scheme for the erection of a Maronite Cathedral at Cairo bas taken
                            definite shape and L E. 10,000 has already been subscribed. Mgr. Darian,
                            the Maronite Archbish p. Chakour Pasha, Abdullah Bey Sfer, and many
                            other Syrian notables, are heartily supporting the scheme.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not had our strax for the responsable opinions expreso 1 ty car
                        correspondessta, lant wa wimb, spirit of fair pla to all, to purit - within
                        a scary limita fres d ansion.</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A RACE OF ARTIS IS.</head>
                        <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</p>
                        <p>Sir, I send a few of the smaller stones from the desert, which I think
                            you have not seen, and for which I hope I may claim your adiniration.
                            What, sir, would not gott or I give for that touch of hand and truth of
                            eye ! Look at the wonderful skill with I which they have been carved,
                            repeating again</p>
                        <p>and again the same idea, but almost always with the distinctive touch of
                            the individual worker,--just as in the pretty attractive cloth I word of
                            the Kabyle women, the pattern is not copied or mechanically repeated,
                            but each worker follows an instinct of her own. And so it was with this
                            old stone race. With some exceptions, some types ronghly
                            executed-perhaps of the earlier time, for it! was over an immense space
                            of time that they worked, -- and some few that merely repro dnced the
                            conventional pattern, the mass of the stones bear constant witness to
                            the free play of band and imagination. What gifts this desert people bad
                            i One may donbt--and I am not forgetting the story of Greece, which wa-
                            different in its kind if the world has ever yet produced a race with
                            such an artistic sense 1-o widely distributed--perhaps in Japan 'you
                            have had the nearest approach to it. In the artistic fancies of both
                            ruces - the love of the quaint and grotesque-the mixture of human and
                            demon-yet with a certain self-restraint, the half extravagance kept
                            within the limits of sobriety--you feel as if there were common
                            elements--as if the two races had shared some of the same gifts. I
                            should like to send a tow examples to Tokio for our Japanese friends to
                            pass judgment upon.</p>
                        <p>And now, sir, how goes it with my friends, the learned babes 1 Have they
                            mended their little wayward fashions, and grown in wisdom and stature!
                            Or is A.B.C. still the same sal trial, as it was, to their rebel souls 1
                            Do they Ixtill pont and sulk in their eyrtier? Do they still cry "can't,
                            shan't, won't” while the little fists are doubled up in the little eyes
                            and the little</p>
                        <p>feet stawp upon the flxer? Was there ever sich Ja hullabaloo and piece of
                            work in the nursery</p>
                        <p>all about learning A.B.C., which sooner or later must be learned. There
                            is no prissible escape from it. No amount of shan't and won't</p>
                        <p>can help them. Their fate is inexorably I written. And never was there a
                            prettier, pleasanter, more attractive A.B.C. for a babe to learn--an
                            A.B.C. that sh-uld never have cost a tear oz a whimper! And as soon as
                            they once humble the haughty little souls- just a touch wanted of the
                            penitent's redeeming grace--and set themselves with goodwill to the
                            task, what delight they will find in it, what revelations are waiting
                            for them! But I must not take up too much of your space. At</p>
                        <p>Rome, Trieste, Athens, and again at AlexJandria, I found after some
                            little hunting plenty</p>
                        <p>of traces of the same race. The stone was I much less favorable, ant the
                            work consequently much rougher ; but the lealing types were the same.
                            Some day we ought to be able to trace with considerable exnotness the
                            march of this great people--for really great they | were. You cannot
                            live amongst their work, and with hold your admiration from them.I am,
                            eto,</p>
                        <byline>AUBEBON HERBERT. Tewfik Palace Hotel, Helouan,</byline>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROYAL VISIT TO KHARTOUM.</head>
                    <head>REVIEW OF TROOPS.</head>
                    <byline>(From our CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Khartoum, February 4. </dateline>
                    <p>A review of all the troops in the station I was held this morning on the
                        parade ground at| Khartoum. At 8 o'clock H.R.H. the Duchess of Connanght,
                        with the Princesses, accompanied by Lady Wingate, arrived ina landau at the
                        Royal| stand. A few minntes later H.R. H. the Duke, | accompanied by H.E.
                        the Sirlar and Governor| General, General Sir J. Maxwell, and the staff,
                        followed on the parade-ground, and the Royal Standard was at once boisted
                        near the enclosure. | After the inspection, the troops began to file past
                        his H.R.H., performing the various evolutions, the Rifle Brigade being
                        specially smart and showing they had marched over Sudan sands once before.
                        The cavalry, and notably the artillery, appear to bave been I quite up to
                        the mark, and H.R.H. was pleased to express his entire satisfaction with the
                        bearing of the troops and the evolutions effected.</p>
                    <p>I learn that the Duke of Connaught expressed the opinion that trousers for
                        the native troups, shaped Zouave fashion, would perhaps be more suitable for
                        this climate than the ordinary trou-ers now in use.</p>
                    <p>In the after on, the Royal party, accompanied by the whole staff, crossed
                        over on a visit to Omdurman.</p>
                    <p>In the evening there was a military tattoo in front of Government baildings,
                        at which the Royal party were present. Bimbashi Franklin, director of mu-io,
                        was bonored with a few words of thanks from H. R. H. for his services on the
                        occasion. ROYAL PARTY AT DIVINE SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Khartoum, February 5. </p>
                    <p>The Royal party attended divine service this morning in the temporary church
                        room in the Palace.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VISIT TO GORDON COLLEGE.</head>
                    <dateline>Khartoum, February 6. </dateline>
                    <p>T. R. H. the Duke and Duchess of Con. naught, with the Princesses, and
                        accompanied by H. E. the Governor General, Lady Wingate, and snite, visited
                        Gordon College to-day and then drove round the town of Khartoum. The natives
                        turned out and gave the Royal party a hearty greeting. The annual regatta
                        took | place in the afternoon in front of the Palace, and at 10.30 p.m. the
                        Royal party left for the North. I may mention that the police arrange ments
                        throughout the Royal visit were perfect.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASSOUAN DAM VISITED.</head>
                    <dateline>Assouan, Tuesday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Dake and Duchess of Connaught arriv. ed at Assouan this moruing and will
                        visit the dam in the afternoon accompanied by Sir Willinn Garstin, Mr. A. L.
                        Webb, Mr. Clowes, and Mr. Macdonald.</p>
                    <p>The R val party will leave Luxor on Thursday by a special train leaving at
                        6.50 p.m. which will bring them to Cairo at 9.10 a.m. ou Friday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Today H. H. the Khedive visited the Mosque at Koubbeh for prayer on the
                        opening of Kourban Beyram. Salvoes of 21 guns were fired from the Citadel
                        and at Abbassieh on the arrival and departure of his Highness.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon, his Highness received Ally Pasha Yaghen, Governor of
                        Cairo, and all the principal functionaries or notables who received
                        promotion or decorations on the occasion of the anniversary of H. H.'s
                        accession.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL STOESSEL AT SUEZ.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes 8.8. “Australien," by which Gen. Stoessel is a
                        passenger, is due to arrive at Suez to-morrow at 10 a.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PLAGUE ON STEAMER.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Saez, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Austrian Lloyd 8.S. "Imperator," from Bombay, arrived at Suez yesterday.
                        Owing to her having landed a case of plagne at Aden, she was put in
                        quarantine at this port, and after being disinfected entered the Canal in
                        quarantine. Passengers for Suez were conveyed to Moses' Wells to purge two
                        days' quarantine</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXPORT OF GUM ARABIC.</head>
                    <p>Daring the month of December last, 1,031,614 kilus of gum arabic, valued at
                        LE.23,217, were exported from Egypt. In the same month of 1903 the experts
                        were 574,359 kilos, of the value of L.E.12,967, showing an increase in 1904
                        of 457,255 kilos, value LE 10,250.</p>
                    <p>During the year 1904, the exports show increases of 1,989,571 kilos in weight
                        and of LE. 11,394 in amount as compared with 1903, the respective figures
                        being as follows:- 1904, 10,402,054 kilos, value L.E.234,060 ; 1903,
                        8.412,483 kilos, value L.E.192,666.</p>
                    <p>Of the above, the export to England and her Mediterranean possessions was
                        2.220,528 kilos, valno LE 49,960; Germany, 1,740,096 kilos, value LE. 39,159
                        ; Austria-Hungary, 702,815 kilos, value L.E.15,810 ; France and Algeria,
                        2,711,811 kilos, value L.B. 60,990; Italy, 286,086 kilos, value LE 6,424 ;
                        Turkey, 12,303 kilos, value L.E.269; America, 1,438, 424 kilos, value
                        L.E.32,364, and to other countries 1,290,992 kilos, value L.E.29,084,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER'S TRIP.</head>
                    <head>VISIT TO KENEH.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</byline>
                    <p>Keneh, Saturday. . Lord and Lady Cromer, accompanied by Lady Beatrice Thyone,
                        arrived at keneh by steamer at 1 p.m, to-day. Among those awaiting their
                        arrival were the Moudir, the SubMoudir, all the heads of the Government de
                        partments, the consular agents, omdehs, sheikhs, and a guard of honor.</p>
                    <p>As the steamer accosted the landing stage, I Lord Cromer stepped out and
                        sbook hands with the Moudir, who introduced a number of those present to his
                        lordship. On Lord Cromer asking if anyone could speak English, the SubMoudir
                        replied in the affirmative, and his lordship proceeded to thank the
                        gathering for their reception, the Sub-Moudir acting as interpreter. Lord
                        Cromer said he regretted he bad no time to visit the town, as he was in al
                        burry to leave for the South</p>
                    <p>The steamer remained at the landing stage for some time ooaling and at 3.30
                        sailed for Kous, where the party will stop for the night. On the following
                        morning (Sunday) the steamer will leave at 6 o'olook for Mataang direct and
                        will make another stay there for the night. Erom Mataana the distinguished
                        party proceed to Silwa, from which place they will go to Kom Orabo, where
                        they will remain three hours. Leaving Kom Ombo they will reach Assouan on
                        the afternoon of Tuesday, the 14th | inst. Lord and Lady Cromer expect to be
                        back in Cairo on the 22nd inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE JUDGE KEILEY.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of the late Judge A. M. Kelley, formerly judge of the Mixed
                        Courts of Egypt, who was accidentally killed in the streets of Paris, took
                        place at Notre-Dame on Saturday, February 4. The American Consul-General was
                        present.</p>
                    <p>Owing to illness, neither the judge's son-inlaw, Captain Hall, nor his
                        daughter were able to be present, but the family was represented by Mr.
                        Arnold Hall and Miss Hall, who came | from England to assist at the
                        ceremony. -</p>
                    <p>A correspondent writes as followa to the “New York Herald” (Paris) :-I feel
                        that the death of so well- known an American as Judge A. M. Keiley deserves
                        a record. In your edition of Saturday, January 28, I found a short
                        paragraph, ovpied from a French paper, stating that a well-dressed man,
                        about sixty years of age, had been knocked down by a delivery van in the
                        place de la Concorde the day before, and had been carried to the hospital,
                        where he died that night. In his pocket was found a card bearing the name
                        and address of Judge Keiley, 49, Dover-street, Piccadilly-nothing more,</p>
                    <p>Jndge Keiley was a man well known at home and abroad. He had at various times
                        Atted several publio offices in his native city, vit., Louisville, Ky, and
                        for many years had represented the United States in the Mixed Courts of
                        Egypt. He lived in Alexandria until his wife died, two or three years ago,
                        when he resigned his position and went to London, to be near a married
                        daughter</p>
                    <p>Judge Keiley was a man of unusual attainments; he knew the classies as he did
                        the alphabet ; not only spoke half a dozen modern languages, but know their
                        literature as well. He know all good things and loved them. He oould tell a
                        story better than the next man, let him tell it never so well, and what is
                        more, could appreciate the point of the other fellow's story. He was
                        liberal, broad-minded, tenderhearted, full of sympathy for suffering :
                        genial and warm-hearted. He was a loyal, staunch friend, and I, who only
                        knew him casually, as it were, feel that I shall not soon look upon his like
                        again.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A PROPOS DE L'EAU.</head>
                    <p>Monsieur le Directeur</p>
                    <p>de "l'Egyptian Gazette." On fait grand bruit en ce moment, touchant la
                        pollution des eaux que nous vend fort cher "T'Alexandria Water Company
                        Limited" et ce n'est point la première fois que l'on crie que l'eau est
                        contaminée.</p>
                    <p>Après constatation des faits les services 88nitaires ne préconisent aucun
                        système pour stériliser les conduita et assurer enfin une enu moins chargée
                        de microbes.</p>
                    <p>Si les dits services poulaient prendre la peine d'analyser l'eau du
                        Mahmoudieh chaque jour et si le résultat de ce petit travail était
                        communiqué au public, celui-ci serait fort surpris d'apprendre quelle
                        quantité considé. rable de microbes il absorbe quotidiennement,</p>
                    <p>Quant au canal de dérivation qui alimente la Compagnie des Eaux, il est
                        installé dans toutes les conditions requises pour être contaminé en son
                        entier parcours.</p>
                    <p>En effet, dans tous les alentours du dit canal, il n'y a pas une fosse
                        d'aisances qui soit imperméable et cimentée conformément aux règlements
                        sanitaires.</p>
                    <p>D'autre part, le service Maritime et Quarantenaire ne fait aucune objection
                        quant à la fourniture de cette eau pour l'approvisionnement des navires et
                        ne prend aucune mesure pour leur procurer de l'eau saine. Le dernier congrès
                        sanitaire de Venise s'est pourtant 00enpé un tantinet de cette question
                        primordiale mais ici, au pays nilotique, la consigne est et sera encore
                        longtemps de dire : Malesch.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>De SaixT BONNET. Alexandrie, le 13 février 1905.</p>
                    <p>SIVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</p>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Manage ment Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerta twice daily.</p>
                    <p>#1941-18 PronuOM I Xornal &amp; Mannannt</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONDITION. OF HELOUAN. NO GOVERNMENT SUPPORT.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our CORRESPONDENT). ..</byline>
                    <p>* Helouan, February 12. An important meeting of the Municipal Commissioners
                        of Helouan has been held at the Gouvernorat under the presidency of H. E.
                        the Governor of Cairo. There were present the Tanzim delegate, Mr. Cartis,
                        the Sanitary Department delegate, Dr. Dryer, and the four elected
                        representative members of the town, M. Felix Suares, Hussein Bey Youssef,
                        Mahmoud Fehmy Pasha, and Dr. A. J. M.| Bentley. | The question of the
                        condition and wanta of the town of Helouan came before the meeting, After
                        some remarks from M. Suares, Hussein Bey Youssef, and Mahmoud Febmy Pasha,
                        on the unsatisfactory condition of the town and the miserable financial dole
                        voted to the Commission, Dr. Bentley addressed the Council as</p>
                    <p>follows. | Your Excellency, - You may remember that at our last meeting I
                        presented you with &amp; petition from the inhabitants of the town of
                        Helouen aoking that it might be read and considered by th: Council hefore
                        presenting it to the Government for their consideration. This your
                        Excellency did not see fit? to do, and the only course open to the
                        inhabitants was to go with it direct to the chiefs of the Ministries
                        interested, which petition was later on published in several of the
                        newspapers of Bgypt. This petition, I hear on good authority, was not
                        unfavorably received by the heads of tho various departments concerned. The
                        petition, I may call to your mind, dealt with the following points :(i). The
                        railway service ; (ü). The state of the roads and condition of the water
                        supplied for drinking ; (iii). The constitution of the Local Commission ;
                        (iv). The expenditure of the revenue derived from local taxation.--The
                        Railway (i) is now in the possession of the Delta Light Railway Company and
                        they have promised to carry out certain and, we believe, efficient reforms.
                        The matter of the drinking water and the roads (ii) concerns the Tanzim
                        Department. The allocation of the revenue (iv) derived from Helonan is a
                        financial matter and concerns the Ministry of Finance. The carrying out of
                        (ü), which is so urgently required, is</p>
                    <p>large matter, and it is absolutely impossible to deal with it satisfactorily
                        with the small amount of money allowed to this Commission. (iii The
                        constitution of the Commission is essentially an anomaly s elected partly by
                        public vote to carry out reforms, ithasabsolutely no power to accomplish
                        them. If suggestions are made to the Commission and they are not carried
                        out, the publie regard the failure as being due to its not having the power
                        to im prove, it still has to bear the blame. I propose, therefore, that in
                        the best interests of Helouan. and with a due regard to the dignity of this
                        Council, that the Municipal affairs of the town be placed again in the hands
                        of the Goverament, which alone is able to carry out those reforms so
                        necessary for the well-being of the town. This Commission has doubtless done
                        excellent work in its time, the Tanzim officials connected with it have
                        always been willing to do what they could for the improvement of the town,
                        but owing to the rapidly increasing importance of Helouan and its neigh
                        bourhood, and the urgent and large reforma needed, it is time that the
                        present system, with its very limited powers, should be abolished, and that
                        the municipal affairs should be placed in the hands of the Government, which
                        alone has the power to efficiently carry them out I appeal to your sense of
                        duty not to place any obstacle in the way, but rather to sink all
                        differences and personal feelings for the wellbeing of the town of Helovan,
                        and I further beg to suggest that to facilitate matters this Council should
                        delegate three or more of its members to consult with the Government to
                        ascertain ita views on this matter.</p>
                    <p>The president, in replying, stated that he had received official information
                        that the Finance Ministry had refused to sanction any further aid to Helovan
                        or to grant money to allow more water for the roads and trees. The tour
                        elected representative members there upon tendered their resignation in a
                        body, as a protest against the Government decision. * Later on they were,
                        however, induced by the president to withdraw their resignations
                        conditionally on his Excellenoy på mising to bring their protest before the
                        proper authorities. They, however, expressed very decided views to his
                        Excellency on the uselessness of holding | further meetings under existing
                        circum stances.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHEPHEARD'S SMALL DANCE.</head>
                    <p>Last night's small dance at Shepheard's met with the usual success. The
                        restaurant was quite fullat dinner time. Among many others dining there we
                        noticed Mr. and Mrs. Geo. W. | Drexel and party, Mr. B. Johnson and party,
                        including Mr. and Mrs. Thos Walsh and Miss Walsh, Baron von Oppenheim, Baron
                        Tiede mann-Seeheim and family, Mr. Pembroke Jones and family, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Fiedler, Mr. and Mrs. Granville Alexander, Mr. and Mrs. Enn. C. Zervudachi
                        and party, Mr. J. W. Mellor and Miss Mellor, Major Pirie and party, includ
                        ing Major Kenny Herbert, Mr. Carter Wilson and Major Harold ; Baron,
                        Baroness and Miss de Peteghem, Marquis de Corea and Comte Gabriel de Zogheh,
                        Mr. and Mrs. G.T. Rafferty and the Misses Rafferty, Mr. Mrs. and Misses
                        Abbott, Mrs. and the Misses Gelshenen, Prince Lichtenstein, Comte
                        Trautmannsdorf, General and Mrs. von Haewardt, General and Mrs. von Diest,
                        Baron Te-sin, Baron Vogel de Falkenstein, Mrs. Marion Spring and party, Mr.,
                        Mrs. and Miss Moss, Mr. and Mrs. Brsley and Mr. Horley, Mr., Mrs., and Miss
                        Pinkerton and Miss Bessie Jordan, Mr. and Mrs. Robinson, eto,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item" feature="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <p>"HBLOUAN THIRD WINTER</p>
                    <p>MEETING</p>
                    <p>The following are the entries for the above meeting, to be held at flelouah
                        on Priday, 17th inst, at 2.80 pm. :</p>
                    <p>FIRST RACE, 2.80 p.. Mapex Poxy RAÇe. Value PT. 2,500, 2nd borse to receive
                        P.L. 300, and 3rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Arab ponies, chat
                        have never won a race of any desoription. Weight for ago and inches Distance
                        1 for longa : - Saleh Bey. Yughan's ide, 10.7. Moharrem Pasha Chebin'a Vali,
                        9.18. Ibrahima Bey Cherif's Amour, 10.7. • Ishak Boy Hansein and Hassan. Bey
                        Kheir el-Din's Rais, 10.7, Saleh Bey. Chérits Ragan, 10.7. ...</p>
                    <p>SECOND RACE, 3 p.m.. MAIDEX GAILOMAX. Valús P.T. 2,500,-And borse to receive
                        P.T. 300, and 3rd P.I. out of the stake For Arabs, Weight for Age and
                        incben. Distande about mila-badi Bey Cherifs Arabi, 10.7, and Panda, 9.18.
                        Saleh Bey Yaghen's Munir, 9,18, and Sibame: 9.13. Mobarrem Pasha Chahin's
                        Bibioo, 8.7. Omar Bey Sultan' and Ahmed Bey Belai's Sayad II., 10.8. ME N.
                        Sogaja and Kaapel Effendi Maber's Social Life, 10.3.3</p>
                    <p>THIRD RACE, 3.30 p.m. The ARAB HANDICAP. ValueP.T. 2,500, And horse to
                        receive P.T. 300, and 3rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For all Arabe.
                        Distance 1 1 mile.--Soleh Bey. Yaghen's London and Mashkour II., Mobatrem,
                        Pasha Chelvin's Mizzaud, Mr. P. W. Stout's Shewiman, ishek Bey. Hussein's
                        Rapid, Omar Bey Balian and Ahmed . Bay el Bakri's Rachid... E FOURTH RACE, 4
                        «p.m...</p>
                    <p>TRIAL PLATE. Value P.T. 2,500, 9nd horse to receive P.T. 300, and 3rd horae
                        P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Amb horses, that have never won a race of
                        any description (Gymkhanas excepted). Weight for age. Distance mile.-Ibrahim
                        Bey Cherif s· Arabi, 10.7, Moharrem Pasha Chetin's 'The Prince, 10:0, Capt.
                        G. B. Byme's Chinaman, 10.7, Ishak Bey Hussein's Fargh, 10.0, Mr. N.
                        Yoanovitch's Napo, 10.7.</p>
                    <p>FIFTH RACE, 1.30 p.m. THE PONY HANDICAP. Value P.T. 2,800, 2nd horse to
                        receive P.T. 800, and 3rd horse P.T. 200, out of the stakes. For Arab
                        ponies.. Distance 7 furlongs.-Ishak Bey Hussein's and Hassan Bey
                        Kheir-el-Din's Rais, Moharrem Pasba Chehin's Bibico, Saleh. Bey Inghen's
                        Ide.</p>
                    <p>. SIXTH RACE, 5 p.m., 3 BEDOUIN STAKES. Value P.T. 2,500, 2nd horse to
                        receive P. T. 300 and &amp;rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Arabs
                        that have never won a race of any description. Open to all members and
                        non-members wbo do not keep maging horses. Catch weights over 10st | 7lbs.
                        for Horses, rost. for Galloways and 9st 7lbs. for Ponies. Those previously
                        placed in any race to carry 7lbs. extra. Distance 1 mile. Nouridin Effendi's
                        Nasseeb (late Peacock), Daoud Sultan's Murseel, Soliman Sultan's Hattem,
                        Mahboul Khourdar's Said and Sewiteo, Kharkour Elia's Kattarchorak, Moh.
                        Abdel Kalik Ramsi's Farhan (late Ayanit), Humberto Carrozzo'sGigia, Padgan
                        al-Dabawi's Minsbar and Yakzan..</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB.</p>
                    <p>3rd WINTER MBETING. - The Kasr, al-Nil Steeplechase will be a Handicap and
                        not as advertised.</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</p>
                    <p>The annual general meeting of the Khedi: vial Yacht Club will be held at the
                        Khedivial Club, Alexandra, ou the 27th inst</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The King has been pleseed to give and grant unto Robert Lang Anderson, Faq.,
                        Manager of the Aboukir Landa Reclamation Company, His Majesty's Royal
                        licence and authority that he may accept and wear the Insignia of the Third
                        Class of the Imperial | Ottoman Order of the Osmanish, conferred | upon him
                        by H.H. the Khedive of Bgypt, authorised by H.I.M. the Sultan of Turkey, in
                        recognition of valuable services rendered by him to His Highness.</p>
                    <p>Colonel and Mrs. C. Roadew Barn have left for Egypt, and will join the yacht
                        "Miranda" at the end of March. They do not expect to returú till May.</p>
                    <p>Baron Angust Twickl is leaving Rome this week for Egypt.</p>
                    <p>The marriage arranged between M. Henry Thierrard and Mélita, danghter of M.
                        and Mme. S. Caffari, will take place at St. Catherine's Cathedral,
                        Alexandria, on Saturday, 18th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to J. ELEURENT, I. MIGALLE Bolo Arant;</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL:</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st Class and most comfortablo Hotel iz Alexandr fach Come position.
                        Onder Anglia 11-11-24</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n3/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n4/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n5/mode/1up">
            <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>For HULL, by the 8.8. "Kolpino", siled on the 3rd February </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd, 575 tons cotton seed </p>
                    <p>Carver Bros, &amp; Co. Lad, 521 </p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co, 430 </p>
                    <p>J. Gour &amp; Son, 483, </p>
                    <p>B.J. Conry &amp; Co., 408, </p>
                    <p>Tadros Ghirghis, 1,000 quarters beans </p>
                    <p>L. Heller, 50 barrels molasses </p>
                    <p>O. K. Levick, 1,198 bags onions </p>
                    <p>Crambani, 1 case cigarettes </p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 1 case cigarettes </p>
                    <p>H. Bindarnegal, 60 balas cotton </p>
                    <p>B. Bortolotti &amp; Co., 37 . </p>
                    <p>B. Mallison &amp; Co., 40</p>
                    <p>137 bales cotton - </p>
                    <p>Pour CANDIE, par le bateau hell. "Athènes", parti le 4 février : </p>
                    <p>Divers, 937 sacs riz, 401 saca sucre, 18 saas fèves, 25 balles coton, 518
                        barils vides, 228 colis peaux, 15 colis divers </p>
                    <p>For MALTA and LIVERPOOL, by the 8.8. "Alexandria", sailed on the 4th February
                        : : </p>
                    <p>T. Ghirghis, 370 bales cotton </p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 125 , . </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Lank Ltd 76, </p>
                    <p>H. Bindernagel, 535 .</p>
                    <p>R. &amp;0. Lindemann, 660 </p>
                    <p>B. 3. Coury &amp; Co., 188</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co. 100</p>
                    <p>F. Andres, 85 </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 527 </p>
                    <p>J. Planta &amp; Co., 337</p>
                    <p>N. G. Casulli, 51</p>
                    <p>G. Pranger &amp; Co., 140</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Ltd, 1,367 </p>
                    <p>P. O. Baines &amp; Co., 100</p>
                    <p>Botton Bortolotti &amp; Co., 22</p>
                    <p>Ravelli &amp; Co., 20 </p>
                    <p>E. Toriel &amp; Son, 44</p>
                    <p>W. Getty &amp; Co. 10 .</p>
                    <p>4,757 bales cotton </p>
                    <p>Tadros Ghirghis, 1,000 quarters beans </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd. 1,000 quarters beang, 810 tona cotton seed </p>
                    <p>G. Brach &amp; Co, 62 bags gum </p>
                    <p>L-Onofrio, 718 cases bones </p>
                    <p>Kyriazi fr. 3 cases cigarettes </p>
                    <p>Alex, Bonded Stores, 1 </p>
                    <p>Kevork Ipekian, 1 </p>
                    <p>M. G. Hagan, 80 casas eggs </p>
                    <p>Fix &amp; David, 164</p>
                    <p>L. Onofrio, 250 </p>
                    <p>A: Panzieri, 53</p>
                    <p>G. M. Ades, 150</p>
                    <p>R. Mortin, 96</p>
                    <p>Hadjès &amp; Co., 130 </p>
                    <p>"Bank of Egypt, 345 bags sugar </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 13 canes furniture </p>
                    <p>E. Minotto, 6,941 cases oranges </p>
                    <p>Chorami, Benachi &amp; Co., 6 cases sweets </p>
                    <p>B. Tilobe &amp; Son, 270 cases bronze powder </p>
                    <p>A. Panzieri, 451 bags onions </p>
                    <p>B. Minotto, 88 cases onions, 106 begs dari seed, 25 bags acorns </p>
                    <p>Varions, 2 packages sundries </p>
                    <p>For PORT-SAID and SYRIA, by the 8.8. "El-Kahira", sailed on the 4th February
                        : </p>
                    <p>Various, 1,360 bags rice, 925 begs sugar, 344 bags coffee, 100 baga natron,
                        83 bags cotton - seed, 12 bags henna, 61 packages vegetables, 10 packages
                        skins, 825 packages sundries</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
