<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Cassandra Frederick</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-17">October 17, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-09">May 09, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7193] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, MAY 09, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WAR CRISIS. FRANCE’S NEUTRALITY QUESTIONED INDIGNATION IN JAPAN. BRITISH
                        REPRESENTATIONS. FRENCH OFFICIAL DENIAL.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, May 5. A section of the Japanese Press is urging the Government to
                        take the strongest measures in consequence of the stay of the Baltic Fleet
                        Even responsible organs are calling for prompt and independent action.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>London, May 8. The "Times" reports from Tokio that the indignation in Japan
                        is increasing. Even the soberest journals declare that France has vir-
                        tually taken up arms against Japan and plainly state England's duty to
                        prevent the interference of third parties.</p>
                    <p>The “Times," in a significant article, states that no more deplorable error
                        can be com- milted by France than to suppose that the complaints of Japan
                        will be treated lightly. While everything is done to provent the rup- ture
                        of the “entente," France must remember that England will have no choice but
                        to comply if the facts alleged by the Japanese are estab- lishedand Japan
                        asks us to fulfil the obligations of the alliance. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>London, May 8 The Markets are weak on account of the international situation
                        and the article in the “Times."</p>
                    <p>It is understood that Lord Lansdowne has made earnest representations to
                        France with reference to the necessity of a strict observance of
                        neutrality.</p>
                    <p>Reuter’s Agent learns from Tokio that the Japanese complaints are mainly
                        directed against the provisioning and equipping of the Baltic Fleet from
                        neutral shores. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, May 8. The official statement of the Government says that not only
                        have the most positive instructions been sent to the authorities in Indo
                        China to enforce the neutrality regula- tions, but that it has unremittingly
                        seen to the execution of these instructions. (Reuter.</p>
                    <p>Paris, May 8. The Japanese Minister had a prolonged inter- view with M.
                        Delcassé yesterday. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Paris, May 8. A note of the Havas Agency denies the allegations contained in
                        a telegram from Hong Kong, according to which France had com- mitted a
                        breach of the neutrality roles. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MANCHURIA. BRUSH WITH JAP CAVALRY.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 5. General Linievitch telegraphs that the Japa- nese
                        cavalry drove back our mounted outpost on the 4 th inst. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNKNOWN FLEET SIGHTED.</head>
                    <p>Labuan, May 8. Tho German S.S. “Chiengmai" passed on the 5th inst 70 miles to
                        the north-east, an unknown fleet composed of two divisions. It was
                        apparently coaling. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN TORPEDO-BOATS RELEASED.</head>
                    <p> Lubeck, May 8. The torpedo-boats have been released, the authorities
                        considering it will take six months to make them seaworthy. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANTI-SEMITISM AT WARSAW.</head>
                    <p> Warsaw, May 8. There is a strong anti-Semitic feeling here, in consequence
                        of the Jewish shopkeepers and cab drivers ignoring the Socialists. The pro
                        mine/indiscernible letter/t citizens are persuading the Governor to
                        investigate the disturbances of the 1st inst. with a view to allaying the
                        popular irrita- tion. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIRE IN NEWSKI SHIPBUILDING YARD.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 8. Fourteen buildings ip Newski shipbuilding yard were
                        destroyed by fire last night; six were also partly destroyed. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FREIGHTS TO CALCUTTA REDUCED</head>
                    <p>Liverpool, May 8. Owing to the war rates of insurance the Liverpool lines
                        have to day reduced freights for rough goods to Calcutta by 5s. per ton.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AUTOMOBILE BOAT RACE.</head>
                    <p>Port Mahon, May 8. “Fiat” (Italian) was first in the antomobile boat race.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>Sanitary Dept.—Dr. Philippe Paraschivas has been authorised to follow his
                        profession in Egypt. </p>
                    <p>Egyptian Estates, Limited.—It has been decided to hold a statutory meeting of
                        the above company on June 3.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Army.—The troops in Cairo and the cadets of the Military School
                        paraded at Mohamed Aly-square at 8 o’clock this morning.</p>
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Abdeen district of Cairo during
                        to-morrow night and dawn of Thursday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    <p>Mohamed Aly Centenary.— Subscriptions in Cairo for the celebration of the
                        Mohamed Aly centenary have already reached a total of L.E. 1,056. The
                        Ministers each subscribed L.E. 20.</p>
                    <p>Messageries Maritimes—The M. M. Com- pany reform us that as from this date
                        the de- parture of their mail steamer for Port Said and Syria will take
                        place on Thursday at 8 a.m. instead of noon.</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Rank, Limited.—The di- rectors have decided to pay an interim
                        divi- dend on June 1 of 5s. per share, being at the rate of 10 per cent, per
                        annum for the half- year ended February 28, 1905.</p>
                    <p>Exemption from Military Service. — The amount paid by conscripts for
                        exemption from military service during the past three months is L.E. 45,959,
                        as compared to L.E. 44,300 duriug the same period last year.</p>
                    <p>The Plague.—Last week, five cases of plague were reported throughout Egypt,
                        i.e., 1 at Port Said, 1 at Barchoum-ei-Soghra, 1 at Tant-el- Ghezireh, and
                        two at Kom-el-Atroun, Toukh district, province of Kalioubieh.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—12 vessels passed through the Canal on the 5th inst., 9 of which
                        were British, 1 French, 1 German, 1 Dutch. The day’s receipts were frs.
                        325,584.63, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 1,804,846.42.</p>
                    <p>Egypt is among the twenty-two different States that up to the present time
                        have noti- fied their adhesion to the King of Italy’s pro- posal to found an
                        Internatioual Institute of Agriculture, and have announced that they will
                        send delegates.</p>
                    <p>Quarantine Service.--Dr. U. Cano has been appointed physician for the
                        disinfection service at Suez and at Moses’ Wells, in place of Dr. Zirolio,
                        who has beeu appointed director of the bacteriological laboratory of the
                        Qua- rantine Service, at Port Said.</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Postal Communication will be considerably facilitated by the
                        Simplon Tunnel. When the mail takes that route instead of the present one by
                        way of the St. Gothard Pass, the mail between London and Egypt will arrive
                        five hours earlier.</p>
                    <p>Improvement of Mosques.—A draft decree opening a now credit for the
                        improvement of the internal service of the different mosques, has been
                        submitted for the approval of H. H. the Khedive, who has agreed to it in
                        principle and remitted it to the Wakfs Superior Council.</p>
                    <p>The Native Press.—Ahmed Abbasi and Raghib Hassan, the editors of the comic
                        paper, “El Khalaâ,” are to be tried before the Saïda Zeynab Court on the
                        15th inst, for publishing some libellous articles against Ahmed Bey Talaat,
                        the well-known native notable of Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Club.—On the occasion of the fête in Mohamed Aly-square on Saturday
                        next the Khedivial Club premises will be thrown open to ladies in the
                        evening. The club veran- dah is to be beautifully illuminated on that
                        evening and an orchestra has been engaged to play in the large reading room
                        of the club.</p>
                    <p>White Slave-Traffic.—At the meeting of the executive bureau of the Committee
                        for the Suppression of the White Slave Traffic, held at the Alexandria
                        Gouvernorat yesterday after- noon, the following officials were appointed :
                        Baron Jacques de Menasce, president; Mr. George Zervudachi, treasurer, and
                        Mr. Kreutschner, secretary.</p>
                    <p>Bank of Athens. — The business of the Bank of Athens at Alexandria and in
                        Egypt generally has so increased that a branch of this bank is shortly to be
                        opened at Cairo. Mr. Jean Joannides, the manager of the Alexan dria branch,
                        on returning from Europe, will proceed to Cairo in connection with the pro-
                        ject. Mr. Joannides and his wife are leaving Alexandria to-morrow by the
                        Florio-Rubattino packet for a six weeks' trip to Italy and Paris.</p>
                    <p>Exciting Scene at a Bank.—The Alex andria branch of the Credit Lyonnais was
                        the scene of some excitement this morning. A mad Arab, who is a well-known
                        character at Minet-el Bassal, entered the bank and went up to one of the
                        cashiers demanding that his wages should be paid. The cashier replied that
                        nothing was owing to him and that he was not in the employment of the bank.
                        The mad man retaliated by drawing a double barrelled pistol and discharging
                        the contents of both barrells at the cashier. An exciting scene ensued. The
                        bank, as usual, was crowded with customers and the unwonted discharge of
                        fire- arms caused considerable confusion. For- tunately the cashier was not
                        wounded and the madman was pinioned by one of the bank’s kavasses and handed
                        over to the custody of the police.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FAYOUM BRIGANDAGE. MAJOR ELGOOD INTERVIEWED.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Medinet el-Fayoum, Monday. In reference to the cases of brigandage which I
                        dealt with in my letter of Saturday last, I decided to pay a visit to Major
                        Elgood. Inspector in the Ministry of the Interior, to ascertain some facts
                        connected with the oc- currence. The Major, I am sorry to say, is suffering
                        from the sting of a fly which he got while on duty in the provinces. The
                        consequence was that a large carbuncle formed in the back of his neck, and
                        an opera- tion under chloroform was found necessary. When I visited him
                        yesterday he was better and out of danger. He could not, however, leave for
                        Cairo, as the Bishmo case was a source of great anxiety to him.</p>
                    <p>Major Elgood informed me that six of the band of desperadoes had already been
                        placed under arrest, and that one of them had con- fessed his guilt. He has
                        sent the Moudir to the Ghizeh province and the commandant of police to
                        Mehatela village to arrest the remainder of the band and its leader.</p>
                    <p>I have been informed that the leader of the brigand is Abbass Ezomer, a
                        celebrated brigand from Ghizeh province.</p>
                    <p>Much credit is due to Major Elgood and his men for their prompt discovery and
                        arrest of the members of this terrible gang, whose depredations are
                        well-known to the inhabitants of the three provinces.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A CAIRO BANKRUPTCY.</head>
                    <p>The tradespeople in Cairo are watching with great interest the proceedings in
                        the case of the firm of Dick&amp;Co, Sharia Kasr el Nil, French subjects, a
                        commercial judg- ment having been given on 29th April last declaring this
                        firm bankrupt. The interest is partly extrinsic, in view of the extraor-
                        dinary proceedings which obtained in the case of the Hamilton bankruptcy,
                        for it has been alleged that if Hamilton had not been a British subject, he
                        would have received far different treatment. M. P. Caloyanni, who was the
                        official receiver in the Hamilton bankruptcy, has been appointed to that
                        posi- tion in the present case, whilst Judge Tuck, who presided in the first
                        case, will also adjudi- cate in the instance of M. Dick&amp;Co.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A NEW EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday’s "Journal Officiel" contains the articles of association of the
                        Société Egyp- tienne d’Enterprises Urbaine et Rurales, which has been formed
                        with a capital of £300,000, divided into 75,000 shares of £4 each, to
                        undertake the business of the purchase of all house property, urban or
                        rural, the construc- tion of house property on urban lands, their rental,
                        the improvement and exploitation of rural lands, their resale, the
                        undertaking of works for third parties, and loans on mortgage. The share
                        capital has been entirely subscribed as follows :— Mr. Catmiz 10,000 shares
                        ; M. Green 8,500 shares; M. Felix B. de Menasce 18,000 shares; M. Alfred B.
                        de Menasce 18,300 shares ; M. Enrico Nahman 11,000 shares ; M. Piha Bey
                        8,000 shares ; M. Sauveur Tivoli 1,000 shares.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PORT SAID SALT ASSOCIATION.</head>
                    <p>We beg to draw the attention of our readers to the announcement of the Port
                        Said Salt Association’s new issue of 66,500 shares, which appears on our
                        fourth page. The sub- scription list opens to-morrow and as soon as the
                        shares are fully paid up,viz., after the 15th June, the bearer-warrants will
                        be delivered without any stamp duty.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PROSPERITY IN COTTON TRADE.</head>
                    <p>In a statement issued last week by Mr. William Tattersall of Manchester it is
                        stated that five large Lancashire cotton spinning con- cerns, which took
                        stock on Saturday week, have declared a total profit equal to 23 per cent,
                        per annum on share capital, after in- terest has been allowed for loans and
                        an adequate sum for depreciation of plant. The gain is equal to 10 per cent.
                        per annum on all capital employed, viz., £476,396.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ALLEGED POLICE OUTRAGE.</head>
                    <p>The member of the Alexandria City Police force, who is accused of having
                        committed an assault in Cherif Pasha-street on the morning of H.H. the
                        Khedive’s arrival at Alexandria, has been reduced in rank and fined, and
                        will be tried for assault</p>
                    <p>Our local confrères appear to labour under the impression that the policeman
                        exercised his authority on that occasion in order to keep the street clear
                        of traffic for the Khedivial cortège. This is not the case. The policeman
                        stopped the hand cart belonging to M. Schuler in accordance with the terms
                        of a local by-law prohibiting the passage of hand-carts through Cherif
                        Pasha-street. It is presumed that the Berberee servant of Mr. Schuler, who
                        was trundling the handcart did not make it clear to the policeman that he
                        was merely going to a shop in the street itself, and the policeman therefore
                        naturally concluded that the man wanted to push the hand-cart through Cherif
                        Pasha-street and consequently forbade him, -rather forcibly, it must be
                        admitted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL, CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Open all the year round. /indiscernable/</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PIGMIES AT CAIRO. PERMISSION GRANTED TO LEAVE.</head>
                    <p>The Foreign Office and Lord Cromer have withdrawn their prohibition of the
                        landing in England of the pigmies brought by Colonel Harrison from the Ituri
                        Forest. They will leave Cairo shortly for England.</p>
                    <p>It is the intention of Colonel Harrison to have the dwarfs conveyed to his
                        home, at Brandesburton Hull, near Hull. They will also go to Londesborough
                        Park, the country seat of the Earl and Countess of Londesbo- rough, and will
                        visit London and the principal provincial towns. Colonel Harrison has
                        promis- ed to take them back to their own country at the end of the summer.
                        He does not anticipate any difficulty with regard to their food. They have
                        already gained in weight.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRINCE COLIBRI.</head>
                    <p>It is somewhat singular to hear at the same time that we receive the news
                        that all objection is withdrawn to the sending of Colonel Harrison's pigmies
                        to London, that the impresario of the miniature man who has been on
                        exhibition at Cairo and Alexandria for some months has been prohibited to
                        remove his charge from this country. The party were to have sailed on
                        Wednesday last; all was in order, passages booked to Syria, and passports
                        obtain- ed, when the Russian Consul intervened by direction of the Russian
                        Ambassador in Paris, and prevented the Prince from going.</p>
                    <p>Probably the intervention is on account of the little man being of Finnish
                        birth, but as he has been in the care of his present foster-mother for some
                        eleven years, during which time he has freely moved about the world,
                        probably there is some reason for the procedure which does not appear on the
                        surface.</p>
                    <p>The intervention of the British Consul has been sought, and for the present
                        the matter is in abeyance.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUSIC HALL FOR ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>We are informed that a group of finan- ciers, on the initiative of Mr. George
                        Ralli, is in course of formation for the purpose of erecting a first class
                        music-hall on the site of the old terminus of the Alexandria and Ramleh
                        Railway.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>M. LUIGI CALISE’S CONCERT.</head>
                    <p>A grand vocal and instrumental concert was given by Professor Calise at the
                        New Khedivial Hotel on Sunday afternoon, and was attended by a large
                        audience which quite filled the room. The concert commenced with a Menuet du
                        XVIII. Siecle performed on two pianofortes by four players, Miles A. Boccia,
                        G. Dedes, B. Boccia, and G. Boccia. The performance was given with great
                        spirit and in excellent time. A tenor solo Mallinata, by Leoncavallo,
                        followed, sung by Mr. J. Calleja, whose powerful voice required a larger
                        space in which to give it full effect, its musical qualities quite failing
                        to show in this piece. Mme P. Calzetti sang the Cavatina I due Foscari by
                        Verdi and Gioconda (Suicidio) by Ponchinelli. In both these pieces her
                        flexible voice was heard to great advantage. She also sang the duet in the
                        grand finale to the second act of Verdi’s Aida with Mr. J. Calleja, a long
                        and trying performance that severely tested both of the voices, and in which
                        that of the tenor showed to greater advantage than in his solo (for which,
                        however, we omitted to say he received an encore). Mile G. Capozzi sang a
                        soprano air from Cavalleria Rusticana with great effect and an air from
                        Tosca by Puccini (Vissi d'arte). She has a sympathetic voice of great
                        freshness. Mr. J. Guittieres Pegna sang 2da da Mattinata by Tosti and Mr. L.
                        Bracha Tardi (mélodie) by Densa.</p>
                    <p>The instrumental part of the concert was greatly appreciated. In addition to
                        the double pianoforte duet which opened the concert and to which we have
                        alluded. M. A. Tempe- rino and Mlle Bonomi played two duets, for violin and
                        pianoforte one a Sympho- nic concertante by Mozart, the other Con- oerto No.
                        1 op. 16 by Beriot. Both pieces were well executed and were greatly
                        applauded. The second encore of the afternoon was gained by a brilliant
                        pianoforte solo, Scherzo, by Chopin, executed by Mlle M. Gianny. The concert
                        was a great and deserved success, reflecting the highest credit upon
                        Professor Calise.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Carib Prince" left Manchester on Saturday with passengers and
                        general cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Menes" sailed from Liver- pool on Sunday afternoon and is due
                        here about 21st inst, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Pharos" sailed from Con- stantinople on Sunday and is due
                        here about Thursday.</p>
                    <p>The Papayanni liner "Falernian” arrived at Liverpool this morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh. Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect.
                        Very /indescernible/ charges. Bulkily is the fashionable English
                        /indescernible/. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi Garber Station</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>BECK&amp;CO’S PILSENER BEER BREMEN.</head>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY N.B.-Inferior Brands now being
                        offered to Man- ager of certain good /indescernible/; Beware of evilly
                        disposed competitors running down this very Superior Brand of Beer</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER’S TRIP. RETURN TO CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Cromer arrived at Zagazig at 11 a.m. yesterday on a steamer
                        belonging to the Irrigation Department. The Moudir and Mr. Felice, H.B.M.’s
                        Vice-Consul, at once went on board to pay their respects. In the after noon
                        Lord and Lady Cromer landed and visited the town and at 3 p.m. called on Mr.
                        Felice and afterwards on the Moudir.At 4 p.m. a reception of the omdehs and
                        notables was held in the Irrigation Department’s building. Tea was taken in
                        Mr. Langley's apartment and the Moudir and Mr. Felice had the honour of
                        partaking of tea in company with Lord and Lady Cromer.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer showed great interest in local questions and made close enquiries
                        about the condition of the people, crops, irrigation, etc. Lady Cromer
                        received the Superior and English Sister of the African Mission School. Lord
                        and Lady Cromer left Zagazig at 4.80 p.m. for Cairo by canal. They are
                        expected to arrive at the Barrage to-day.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY.</head>
                    <p>The following is the ordre du jour of next Wednesday’s meeting of the
                        Municipal Com- mission:-</p>
                    <p>1° Communications diverses.</p>
                    <p>2° Centenaire do Mehemet Aly et demande de crédits supplémentaires.</p>
                    <p>3° Interpellation de M. Escoffier au sujet de la construction d’une baraque
                        vis-à-vis du ter- minus de la gare de Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>4° Question relative à l’application d’amen- des à divers fournisseurs et
                        entrepreneurs.</p>
                    <p>5° Accord avec l’entreprise Almagià au sujes de la réception des travaux et
                        de la question des pierres extraites des carrières.</p>
                    <p>6° Projet de règlement intérieur.</p>
                    <p>7° Proposition du Comité du Musée pour la construction d’un batiment en ville
                        pour la Bibliothèque Municipale.</p>
                    <p>8° Demande de crédits de: a)L.E. 2,200 pour l'agrandissement du palais
                        municipal (Délégation du 25 avril 1905). b)L.E. 190 pour la capture des
                        chiens et le service épizootique (Délégation du 25 avril 1905). c) L.E. 100
                        pour frais judiciaires.</p>
                    <p>9° Lettre du 6 avril de S.E. le Ministre de l’Intérieur relative à la demande
                        de la Munici- palité tendant à la gestion des biens libres.</p>
                    <p>10° Rapport du Comité d’examen pour le poste d'ingénieur.</p>
                    <p>11° Excédents et emprises. (Délégation du 25 avril 1905).</p>
                    <p>12° Proposition de M. de Menasce tendant à prescrire certaines mesures de
                        protection aux points d'intersection de deux lignes électriques
                        aériennes.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Saba Pasha, Postmaster-General, is going on leave on the 20th inst.</p>
                    <p>M. A. Leronx, director of the Sucreries et Raffineries d'Egypte, and Mme.
                        Leroux left for Europe on Friday on leave.</p>
                    <p>Among the many visitors staying at the Hotel Beau-Rivage, Ramleh, we notice :
                        Mr. and Mrs. A. Miller and family, Mr. J. W. Dart, Mr. and Mrs. Jules May,
                        Mr. and Mrs. L. Davis, Mr. and Mrs. H. Tilseau, M. and Mme. Basile G.
                        Galouta, Dr. and Mme. Amb. G. Ralli, Capt. and Mrs. W. H. Ratheram, Mrs. T.
                        H. Farrar and courier, the Misses Farrar, Mr. and Mrs. H. Linant, Miss M.
                        Young, Dr. Wakeling, Miss Lewis-Stewart, Miss L. Wor- mer, Mr. R. Ahrab,
                        Miss A. Mason, Mr. and Mrs. F. Smith, and Miss M. Soulic.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS. ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. "Schleswig,” arrived yesterday from Marseilles and Naples :—</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. W. T. Waterlow, Herr Houpert, Mr. and Mrs. E. Mors, Mr. Jos.
                        Valenzia.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Sénégal” des Messageries Maritimes arrivé de Marseille avait à
                        bord :-</p>
                    <p>M. H. Ebady Bey, Mme Doneau, Mme Lely et enfant, Mme Salama, Mlle Gabet, Mlle
                        Desbordes, M. I. Antaki, Mme C. Prinea, Mrs. Miguel Hadoc et A. Maron, M.
                        Armitage, M. Byave Raphael, M. Delaygue, Mme Chabat, M. Renton, Mme Royet,
                        M. et Mme Guimet, Miss Mary, Mme de Coral Gauthier.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>BATHS OF YVERDON. SWITZERLAND.</head>
                    <p>Noted su’phurous Water containing Sodium. Treatment for Rheumatism, Gout,
                        Eczema and the Throat, etc. Masseurs and Masseuses from Aix-les-Bains. Great
                        Comfort,- Splendid Park -Concerts.- Catholic, Protestant, and English
                        Church. Doctor Walter Buhlmann The Direction. 25026-6°-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>Windsor Pharmacy</head>
                    <p>Kasr-el-Nil Square, CAIRO. BEST CHEMICAL PRODUCTS. English and Foreign
                        Prescriptions carefully prepared by Certified Chemists. ALWAYS IN STOCK
                        LARGE ASSORTMENT OF ENGLISH PROPRIETARY ARTICLES &amp;SPECIALTIES</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp;HOTEL COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA &amp;CAIRO Thres Salllnge a-
                        Week. Agents at Alexandria :— ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LD.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE JUDICIAIRE COUR D’APPEL MIXTE</head>
                    <p>L’Affaire Stagni-Salinas</p>
                    <p>(Arret du S mai. — Suite et fin)</p>
                    <p>Il est nécessaire de distinguer (Allig. Les bourses de valeurs) entre les
                        bourses oh les in- térêts des valeurs sont cotés en dedans et celles où ils
                        sont comptés en dehors ou à part.</p>
                    <p>Dans lea premières (Paris, Londres, Rome, Genève, Lisbonne, Milan, Gênes,
                        Alexan- drie etc.) les intérêts courus sont compris dans les cours. Ainsi la
                        personne qui schète comp- tant des titres de rente française 3% au début de
                        Mars, c.a.d. un mois avant l’échéance du coupon trimestriel d’Avril, n’a
                        pas, en plus du prix payé, à rembourser l’intérêt couru en janvier et en
                        février. Il en a été tenu compte dans la fixation des cours. On peut
                        conclure que toutes choses égales d’ailleurs et toute autre influence
                        cessant de s’exercer sur la fixation des cours, le prix d’une valeur, au
                        moment de l’échéance, devra être supérieur du montant du coupon, au cours de
                        cette valeur au lendemain de l’é- chéance précédente.</p>
                    <p>Dans les bourses germaniques, aux usages desquelles Stagni figli voudraient
                        soumettre l’opération dont s’agit, les explications précé- dentes ne
                        a’appliquent point. A Berlin, les in- térêts sont calculés en dehors,
                        e’est-a-dire que la valour du coupon courant n'entre pas dans la fixation du
                        cours. L'acheteur en rembourse, à part, la valeur qu’il atteint au jour de
                        la livraison.</p>
                    <p>Attendu cependant qu'il s’agit d’une vente de titres d’une société Egyptienne
                        dont le siège est au Caire, d’une affaire traitée en Egypte, puer i
                        tatremise d’un courtier de ls place d’Alex- andrie, paiement en Egypte,
                        livraison en Egypte de titres régulièrement cotés en Egypte (quoi- qu’en
                        pu?sent dire Stagni figli) comme il est établi psr les 17 bulletins
                        hebdomadaires de /?/iation des courtiers on valeurs d'Alex- ndrie, produits
                        par les parties ;</p>
                    <p>Que dans ces conditions on ne saurait ad- mettre que, par le seul fait que
                        l’émission des obligations Kéneh-Assouan a été faite à Berlin, et parce que
                        les titres vendus se trouvaient à Berlin, l’opération dont s'agit dût être
                        sou- mise aux usages et aux règles de la Bourse de Berlin, sans une
                        déclaration formelle de la part des vendeurs; </p>
                    <p>Que d’ailleurs ces titres sont vendus à la Bourse d‘Alexandrie d’après les
                        usages, cou- pons compris. Il résulte d’une lettre du Prési- dent de
                        l’association des courtiers que le 23 novembre 1902 il a été vendu £ 1000
                        obliga- tions Kéneh à 95 3/4 coup. n° 17 attaché, jouissance ler juillet
                        1902 ; et d’une déclara- tion de l'Anglo-Egyptian Bank, qu’à la date du 25
                        novembre 1903, la même Banque a vendu, par l’entremise de la maison de
                        courtage Reid &amp;Barnard des obligations Kéneh à 95 3/4, coupon du ler
                        janvier attaché.</p>
                    <p>Que l’on s'expliquerait encore l'insistance de la part de Stagni figli
                        d’invoquer les usages et les règles de Berlin, si l’on prouvait en même
                        temps que le prix convenu de 97 % repré sentait le cours à Berlin au moment
                        de l’opéra- tion et que c’était, par conséquent, ce cours qui aurait
                        déterminé les parties à fixer leur prix; mais que tel n’est pas le cas,
                        puisqu’il résulte de la seu e production faite par Stagni figli,
                        relativement aux cours de Berlin, que les oblige- ions Kéneh-Assouan n’ont
                        pas été cotées du tout à Berlin pendant tout le mois de juin 1903, et
                        qu’elles ont atteint le cours de 96 au 9 juillet, cours qui pourrait
                        s’expliquer peut- être par la vente Stagni, laquelle comprenait a moitié
                        environ de toute l’émission, qui était ainsi enlevée à la place de
                        Berlin.</p>
                    <p>Qu’il n’est pas établi que les titres en ques- tion aient jamais attaint, à
                        Berlin, le cours de 97 ex.</p>
                    <p>Que si, par conséquent, le prix de 97 était indépendant de tout cours coté à
                        Berlin, "et ne répondait à aucun cours de Bourse, mais était exigé par
                        Stagni figli d’après des consi- dérations personnelles et des exigences pro-
                        pres", comme ils allèguent, les usages de Berlin n’avaient que fairs dans la
                        décision de l’affaire, et la nécessité de s’expliquer sur le coupon
                        s'imposait davantage, alors surtout que la cote de la place d’Alexandrie
                        n’était que de 95, d'après le bulletin hebdomadaire de l'as- sociation des
                        courtiers du 26 join 1903, soit de 4 jours avant l’opération.</p>
                    <p>Attendu que Stagni figli soutiennent qu’en tous cas les tratelli Salinas
                        savaient qu'ils ne voulaient pas vendre au-dessous de 97 ex, puisqn’à deux
                        reprises ils s’étaient chargés de la vente de ces titres, et que le fait
                        bien signi- ficatif qu’à toute époque de l’année le prix était toujours le
                        même de 97, démontrerait clairement que le coupon était toujours exclu;</p>
                    <p>Qu’il est à remarquer que des pourparlers avaient eu lieu en novembre 1902,
                        alors que l’échéance du coupon approchait et que le prix à Alexandrie était
                        de 95 3/4 et à Berlin de 94,90 ce qui résulte d’une lettre en date du 21
                        novembre 1902 de Robert Warshauer &amp;Cie, banquiers à Berlin, qui ont fait
                        partie du syndicat du chemin de fer Kéneh-Assouan, lesquels expliquent que
                        ces obligations étaient traitées à 94 et qu'elles avaient atteint le cours
                        de 94,90 à cause d'un petit achat, mais que ces cours s’entendaient pour das
                        titres livrables à Berlin, et munis du timbre alle- mand; que dans ces
                        conditions il est difficile d'admettre que le prix de 97 fut ex-coupon. que
                        l’autre tentative de vente avait eu lieu en été 1901, expression assez
                        vague, qui permet de supposer que l’on traitait avant l’échéance du coupon
                        du ler juillet 1901; qu’en tous cas on ignore les cours avant et après le
                        détache- ment du coupon.</p>
                    <p>Attendu, d’autre part, que, quand mâme Stagni figli auraient déclaré à
                        Salinas qu'ils ne voulaient pas vendre au-dessons du prix de revient — 96
                        8/4 — il aurait fallu que Salinas aient eu aussi connaissance de la data
                        d’acqni- sition dee titres, des conditions établies quans au coupon et au
                        taux d’émission, et /?/</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
