<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kedric Heyward</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-28">November 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-21">June 21, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7220] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, WEDNESDAY, JUNE 21 1905. [SIX PAGES
                    P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, WEDNESDAY, JUNE 21 1905. </head>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VICTORIOUS ADVANCE OF JAPANESE. RUSSIANS COMPLETELY OUTFLANKED. JOYFUL NEWS EXPECTED..</head>

                    <p>London, June 21. The “Daily Telegraph” learns from Tokio that the Japanese
                        are continuing their victorious advance. The Russians are com- \ pletely
                        outflanked on both wings. Joyful news is shortly expected. (Reuter.) PEACE
                        CONFERENCE.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEGOTIATIONS PROGRESSING.</head>
                    <p>Washington, June 20. Mr. Takahira has informed President Roose-velt that the
                        Japanese plenipotentiaries will be able to reach Washington by the 1st
                        August. If acceptable to Russia the conference will be convened for about
                        that day. Count Cassini subsequently called at the White House and said that
                        negotiations are progressing. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOPE FOR RUSSIA. TSAR’S NEW ATTITUDE.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 20. The Tsar's gracious reception of the mem- t bers of
                        the Zemstvos, and his emphatic promise of reformed institutions, is regarded
                        as a tum-ing point in history, and has produced the best effect. {Reuter.)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN ARMY. MEETING OF OFFICERS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 20. Several hundred officers met in the mess room at
                        Kransnoe Selo on the 15th inst to discuss the situation of the-Army in view
                        of recent events. General Rehbinder appeared on the scene and ordered the
                        officers to disperse, the meeting being illegal. A group of officers then
                        stepped forward and declared that they t were all faithful subjects of the
                        Sovereign, but were unable to continue to act as military i police, which
                        completely isolated them from anything. society, in which they were regarded
                        as butchers. General Rehbinder promised them an opportunity of meeting
                        legally. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CASE OF THE “ST. KILDA." GREAT BRITAIN’S POSITION</head>
                    <p>LONDON June 20. House of Commons.—Mr. Balfour said that Great Britain took
                        immediate steps with regard to the sinking of the “St. Kilda” by a Russian
                        cruiser. Correspondence is proceeding between the British and Russian
                        Governments, as this is a matter of which Great Britain takes a very grave
                        view, because we had received the most specific assurance that no such
                        action would be again taken by Russian cruisers. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWEDEN AND NORWAY. ABSENCE OF ANIMOSITY.</head>
                    <p>Christiania, June 20. The Storthing has addressed the King,declaring that
                        Norway is devoid of any animosity and appeals to Sweden to recognise the new
                        State of Norway as an independent State, which it is believed will lead to
                        the development of good relations for the defence of mutual interests.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION. HOPEFUL OUTLOOK.</head>
                    <p>Paris, June 20. It is understood that England is prepared to follow the lead
                        of France if the latter accepts a conference. It is pointed out that Great
                        Britain only refused the invitation of Morocco, and did not make any
                        representation to Germany on the matter, which will simplify the solution.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, June 20. M. Rouvier has acquainted the Council of Ministers with the
                        progress of negotiations with Germany, which are proceeding through the
                        exchange of notes. ( Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPANISH CABINET CRISIS</head>
                    <p>Madrid, June 20. The Chamber has refused its confidence to the Cabinet, which
                        has therefore resigned. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RACING.</head>
                    <p>London, June 20 Ascot Stakes. ; Sand Boy ; 2, Karakoul; 8, Pradella.</p>
                    <p>The Prince of Wales Stakes. 1, Plum centre; 2, Stadtholder; 3, Ritchie.</p>
                    <p>Royal Hunt Cup. Betting: 4 to 1 against Daniel; 15 to 2 Whitechapel; 10 to 1
                        Pharissee and Chardas 100 to 8 Donnetta and 100 to 7 Challenger.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 9.30
                            p.m. today.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Reduced Cable Rates</head>
                        <p>It is expected that the reduced cable rate between Egypt and Europe will
                            come into force on July 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Red Sea Lighthouses</head>
                        <p>We have to acknowledge receipt. of a parcal of magazines from Mr. Douglas
                            Allen for the Red Sea light-keepers.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Khamsin wind prevails at Alexandria today, where the thermometer at
                            noon registered over 100 degrees Fahrenheit in the shade.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Council of Ministers will meet under the presidency of the Regent, H.
                            E. Mustapha Pasha Fehmy; tomorrow at the San Stefano Casino.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sudden Death</head>
                        <p>An Armenian local subject aged 70 years dropped dead from heart disease
                            yesterday in a café near the Eastern Telegraph Company’s offices.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Darb el Ahmar district of Cairo
                            during tomorrow night and at daybreak on Friday will be poisoned by the
                            police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Accident.</head>
                        <p>On Monday an Arab, while crossing the Matarieh line at Manshiet El. Sadr
                            station, was caught between two trains and fatally injured.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Port SAID Cotton Export</head>
                        <p>Up to date only 3,800 bales of cotton have been exported from Port Said
                            since September, 1904, most of which have arrived from Matarieh by boats
                            sailing across the Menzaeh Lake.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records a fresh case and a death in hospital at Alex
                            andria, and two cases at Damanhour. The case at Alexandria was that of a
                            native groom who had been employed in various stables in town.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ramleh Boulevard Burglary.</head>
                        <p>The watchman belonging to the ghaffir service of the Alexandria
                            Gouvernorat employed by Mr. Caffari is under arrest on suspicion of
                            complicity in the recent burglary, but has not confessed anything.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>17 vessels passed through the Canal on the 17th and 18th inst, 7 of which
                            were British, 3 German, 3 Dutch, 2 French, 1 Austrian, 1 Norwegian. The
                            receipts for the two days were frs. 451,565.88, making the total from
                            the 1st inst. frs. 4,969, 230. 63.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Burning Passion</head>
                        <p>The judgment passed by the Court of 1st Instance on Fauzi Chelabi, who
                            proved the strength of his affection for the well-known Arab singer El
                            Serafieh, by setting her house on fire in a fit of jealousy, has been
                            confirmed by the Court of Appeal.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fire</head>
                        <p>A very serious fire, which lasted ten hours, destroyed a mercantile
                            establishment at Keneh yesterday. The damage is estimated at L.E. 6,000,
                            and would have been much more considerable but for the zeal and energy
                            displayed by the fire brigade.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>A grand night fete has been arranged to take place on the terrace of the
                            casino next Saturday evening. The terrace and verandah will be
                            illuminated d la Venitienne, and there will be a display of fire works,
                            which have been brought specially from Europe. The Bracle orchestra will
                            perform from 9 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>An ANCIENT EGYPTIAN Flea</head>
                        <p>The American Press gives long accounts of Mr. Davies’s recent discovery
                            at Thebes. In one of our transatlantic contemporaries’ accounts it is
                            stated that at the bottom of one of the vases in the tomb was some
                            honey, in which floated a flea, which certainly goes to prove that it is
                            true that there is nothing new under the sun, and shows ns also that the
                            early Egyptian had his trials.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suicide</head>
                        <p>A Syrian shoemaker, called George Hanna Akouri, committed suicide at
                            about 9 a m. to day. After going to his shop near the Cafe d’Europe, in
                            Frank-Street, he closed the doors and blew out his brains with a
                            revolver. The Menshieh caracol was warned, but the un fortunate man was
                            dead when the police arrived. An inquiry has been opened by Hadaya Roy
                            at the hospital. Nothing has yet transpired as to the cause that drove
                            the unfortunate man to take his life.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The DISTRIBUTION of Prizes</head>
                        <p>to the pupils of the various Christian Brothers’ schools in Cairo will
                            take place on the following dates : at the Ismailia College on Saturday,
                            24th inst, at the Shoubra College on Monday, 26th inst., at the Daher
                            and Bonlac Colleges on Tuesday, 27th Inst., at the Free School, Rue
                            Ramleh, on the 28th, and on the 29th at the Koronfish College. M. de la
                            Bouliniere and M. A. Bousquet will take tarns in presiding over the
                            prize-givings. The exhibition of handicraft and book-keeping by pupils
                            of the secondary modern course will be open to the public between 5 and
                            7 p.m. from June 25 to June 28 inclusive at the Koronfish College.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO EXPRESS DERAILED. ACCIDENT NEAR TEWFIKIEH</head>
                    <p>An accident, which might have had very serious consequences, took place about
                        two hundred yards from the Tewfikieh station, between Teh-el-Baroud and
                        Kafrel Zayat, at 11.28 a.m. yesterday. The last five carriages of the
                        Cairo-Alexandria express left the rails, tearing up the track, which was
                        considerably damaged. One Arab woman was injured and most of the passengers
                        of the five second and third class carriages which were involved in the
                        accident were shaken and alarmed. A wire was at once sent to Tantah, but the
                        | station-master was unable to give any assistance owing to the down line
                        being blocked.</p>
                    <p>As soon as the news reached Alexandria a relief train was sent up which
                        arrived at 2 p.m. and brought the passengers into Alexandria at 4.10
                        p.m.—three and a quarter hours late.</p>
                    <p>An official enquiry is being held into the cause of the accident, which might
                        have had most serious consequences. Had the derailed carriages turned over
                        the loss of life must have been considerable as the train was travelling at
                        a high rate of speed.</p>
                    <p>A Katr el Zayat correspondent informs ns that it is suspected that the gang
                        which was at work “renewing” on the upline extended their operations to the
                        down line, and not being warned by signal of the approach of tire express,
                        failed to replace the bolts of the fishplates properly, with the result that
                        the rails gave way when the train passed over them.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW NAVIGATION COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>The rumours of the flotation of a new company entitled the Red Sea and Asia
                        Minor Navigation Company are, to say the least, somewhat premature. We are
                        informed that pourparlers are taking place on the subject, but that nothing
                        has been definitely decided.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BOURSE LANE.</head>
                    <p>A few days ago we mentioned the extraordinarily scandalous state of the lane
                        by the Alexandria Bourse leading from Cherif Pasha-street to Tewfik
                        Pasha-street. The cause of the congestion of this small but important
                        thoroughfare is due entirely to the slackness of the Alexandria
                        Municipality, whose services, for reasons best known to themselves, allow a
                        horde of disorderly hawkers to ply their callings there all day long and far
                        into the night. The booths of the fruit-sellers, fish-mongers, florists,
                        bean-Vendors, etc., are kept open until an early hour in the morning and the
                        lane has become a noisy, dirty, and disorderly market, which is often the
                        scene of disorder, the most foul language-being used from early noon to dewy
                        eve. We have been asked by many persons to draw the attention of the
                        Municipality to this disgraceful state of things,but it appears to be
                        useless, for up to now nothing has been done to remedy matters.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO DEACONESSES’ HOSPITAL</head>
                    <p>The many improvements and alterations that have been going on at the above
                        hospital for several months past are now all completed and the new first and
                        second class wards for patients of European nationality on the second floor
                        that has been added are now ready for occupation. This extra accommodation
                        comprises 8 rooms for females and 7 for males, in all 22 beds, besides a
                        sitting-room for the former, 1 service-room with lift to the kitchen, and 2
                        bath-rooms ; a fine broad verandah running the whole length of the building
                        on each of four sides has been added also. On the same floor there-has
                        likewise been erected a room for aseptic operations with two ante-rooms
                        adjoining. The installation of this portion of the new storey, i.e, all the
                        instruments operating-table, sterilisators,is the gift Of Dr. Wild, the
                        principal medical officer, who has connected with the hospital for the past
                        21 years, since its foundation, in fact.</p>
                    <p>The first floor has been entirely repainted and greatly improved, and a lift,
                        which was much needed, has been fitted to communicate with the two upper
                        stories.</p>
                    <p>The whole of these alterations and additions have cost close upon £6,000; as
                        the committee, which is composed of English, American, and German gentlemen,
                        had only a portion of that sum in hand they were compelled to borrow from a
                        local bank the sum of £1,500, which has been guaranteed by three members of
                        the committee until such time as the funds of the institution permit of the
                        liquidation of this loan.</p>
                    <p>The Victoria Hospital of the Deaconesses is pleasantly situated opposite the
                        Cairo Waterworks and in close proximity to the new and fine Abbas boulevard.
                        It was opened in 1884, and during the 21 years of its existence this
                        deserving institution has relieved quite an army of patients of every
                        nationality and creed, for, besides the accommodation for in-patients, there
                        is an out-patients' department where large numbers of the poorer sick crowd
                        daily for medical advice and medicines. The building for the out-patients is
                        at present much too small for the ever-increasing work, and it is hoped next
                        year, should funds permit, to demolish it and erect larger and more suitable
                        premises.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-whr01">

                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>

                    <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>

                    <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M</p>

                    <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>

                </div>

                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POST OFFICE THEFT. ROBBERY OF £800.</head>
                    <p>A daring theft of a registered letter containing banknotes to the value of
                        L.E. 800 has been reported to the General Post Office in Alexandria. Borton
                        Bey is at present at Cairo in connection with the matter, making the
                        necessary investigation before proceeding to Deyrout, in Upper Egypt, to
                        which place the missing letter was addressed.</p>
                    <p>We learn that the letter was sent registered by the National Bank at Cairo on
                        Saturday, and on Sunday news was sent by the post office at the
                        above-mentioned place that the letter had not reached there.</p>
                    <p>The postal authorities inform us that the following are the numbers of the
                        missing notes ; — (for L.E. 100) : 14469 ; 14470 ; 14471 ; 14472; (for L.E.
                        50) : 2783 ; 5874 ; 5355; 3870. Persons into whose possession these notes
                        may come are requested to return them to the National Bank.</p>
                    <p>Our readers will recollect that some six weeks ago another registered letter
                        sent by the same bank from Cairo, and containing L.E. 1,000 in notes, also
                        mysteriously disappeared in the same way, between the Capital and Ghirgeh,
                        and no trace of it whatever has been found since.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POST OFFICE CHANGES AND TRANSFERS.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Musso, local director at Cairo, is leaving there today or tomorrow on
                        sick leave and will spend a few weeks at Ras-el-Bar to recu perate his
                        health after his recent long illness, Daring Mr. Musso’s absence, Mr. A. O.
                        Williams will officiate as Postmaster besides performing the duties of
                        acting Inspector of Cairo District.</p>
                    <p>Mr. H. Harrington, local director of Suez Post Office, has been temporarily
                        transferred to Port Said daring the absence on leave of Mr. Claudins, but it
                        is expected that the transfer will become permanent In the mean while Mr.
                        Henry Zarb, chef de bureau, officiates as local director.</p>
                    <p>Naoum Effendi Ghirghis, formerly in charge of the Cairo, inquiry office, has
                        been appointed secretary to the local direction, after 15 years’ service in
                        the Pout Office and three in the Finance Ministry.</p>
                    <p>Nahla Effendi Tadrous, lately in charge of the branch post office at Mesara
                        Thos. Cook and Son's offices, near Shepheard's Hotel, will assume charge of
                        the new postal office that will be opened on the 1st July on the ground
                        floor of the Ministry of Finance, at Nasrieh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THEFT FROM THE MAHMAL.</head>
                    <p>The case of the theft from the Mahmal is at present receiving the full
                        attention of the Native Parquet, and there is every appearance that the
                        guilt of the four arrested men, whose names we gave in last Saturday's issue
                        of the “Gazette," will be established. The police have arrested one of
                        Androus’s brothers on a charge of complicity in the crime.</p>
                    <p>The Parquet has decided to question the chief of the porters of the Mahmal,
                        who is said to have been intimate with Andraous Meloka. Some suspicious
                        marks have been found on the door of the van which contained the treasure.
                        Two fresh witnesses attendants in a Turkish bath, are to be called, It
                        appears that Meloka showed cuts on the side and neck directly after the
                        theft, but told his acquaintances that he had hurt himself in a bath. The
                        attendants assert that when he stripped for his bath he bore quite recent
                        injuries.</p>
                    <p>The Parquet is investigating this clue.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SYRIA AND PALESTINE.</head>
                    <p>Our Syrian readers may be interested to hear that we propose to publish in a
                        few days a series of articles on the present political situation of Syria
                        and Palestine in relation to Germany, Great Britain, and Egypt. Our
                        contributors are au courant with the politics of this most fascinating
                        region, and their opportunities for the study of its political and social
                        conditions have been quite exceptional.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ISLAM AND JAPAN.</head>
                    <p>In “East and West" there is an interesting article on the Caliphate. The
                        author, Mr. Ab dullah A. M. Sohraworthy, concludes with the following
                        significant hint: — A cultured Japanese (Mr. Okakura)has recently defined
                        Islam as “Confucianism on horseback, sword in hand." The Land of the Rising
                        Sun may produce the hero who, by a simple process, would weld the conquering
                        Japs and the warlike Moslems into one brotherhood, and direct the fanatical
                        forces that lie looked up in the wilds of Asia into the paths of peace and
                        progress, or perhaps of new conquests.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Cyprian Prince" left Antwerp yesterday with passengers and general
                        cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">

                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>

                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>

                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo
                        alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>

                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>

                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>

                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">

                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>

                    <p>BREMEN.</p>

                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>

                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>

                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>

                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>

                </div>


                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ON THE HEDJAZ RAILWAY.</head>
                    <byline>BY P.P.G.</byline>
                    <p>It is not difficult to get up at an unearthly hour of the morning when yon
                        are bound on a long and interesting journey. My packing was done : the
                        excellent Pietro refused to hear a word of my bill till I returned from Ma’a
                        “And when you come back,” he added, “you will please take off all your
                        clothes before you come into the hotel, and I will have a bath made ready
                        for you.” “Is it as bad as that ?" quoth I, but Pietro held up his hands
                        with a gesture in which pity for my ignorance and abhorrence of the
                        conditions of travel in a troop train were sublimely blended. Then I got
                        into an arabiya and drove off.</p>
                    <p>A good many of my readers must have seen Damascus, so I will spare them any
                        description of my drive. I passed through a variety of bazaars which Murray
                        and Baedeker have made celebrated, and saw many of the types which every
                        self-respecting traveller sees. Circassians, Druses, Kurds, Israelites,
                        Bedawin, and the “shy Bedawin women stealing along with their tattooed faces
                        uncovered.”—I quote somebody's guide book from memory,—who seemed to me to
                        be no more shy than the good ladies who accompany gipsy caravans at
                        home.</p>
                    <p>Eventually I arrived at the station, and here I realised for the first time
                        what the Hedjaz line was. There was no platform here and no sort of order
                        whatever. All sorts of boxes and bales lay about in the sand and all sorts
                        of officials in uniforms gesticulated and bellowed. In the station shed some
                        fifteen persons surrounded an Effendi who wrote the tickets out Tickets, as
                        we know them, are not to be found on the Hamidie-Hedjaz line, and yon get
                        instead a paper with your destination and a number of other particulars
                        scrawled on it by the booking office clerk. My turn came at last and I asked
                        for Ma’an. An awkward panse followed, but a letter—the letter—was in my
                        pocket I drew it out, I am afraid with the same gesture with which the hero
                        of the “Family Herald” roman ces draws his revolver and reduces the villain
                        to au impotent and raging silence, and in two minutes I had my ticket and
                        was preparing to board the train.</p>
                    <p>There were further difficulties to surmount. Porters do not abound on the
                        Hedjaz line; one individual whom I asked to help me with my camp—bed and
                        packs, said with some heat that he was a sergeant, at which I was properly
                        abashed.</p>
                    <p>At this moment the carriages of the Railway Commission came bumping up to the
                        station, Mr. Meissner the Director in Chief of the Construction of the whole
                        line, whom I had already met and admired, hastened to invite me to accompany
                        the Commission which was bound for Deraa and, after mildly upbraiding me for
                        bringing no servant, banded my baggage over to an orderly, and presented me
                        to the Os manli members of the Commission H. E. Raif Pasha, Marshal and
                        Chief of the Staff of the Vth Army Corps, now seconded for service as
                        Military Head of the Railway Commission and his lieutenants.</p>
                    <p>The Pasha was a vigorous looking man of about fifty years, with a heavy but
                        intelligent face. He spoke French well and his knowledge of the military
                        aide of Railway Engineering was evidently considerable. With him were two
                        very pleasant and intelligent officers, one a Turk, the other of Arab origin
                        on one side at least, who were to point out a vast number of interesting
                        objects to me in the course of the next few hours.</p>
                    <p>At last the baggage was on board. The guard blew a long blast on a bugle, and
                        we started with a terrific bump in fairly good time. Dera was to be reached
                        at about 2 p.m. and from 10.0 a.m. to 2 pm. the train ran through the Hauran
                        Plain, one of the most fertile and interesting districts in Palestine. (To
                        be continued)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Mr. F. G. Freeman, H.B.M.'s Vice-Consnl at Alexandria, returns to Egypt via
                        Port Said in the first week of July by the S.S. “Aston Hall.” Mr. Freeman
                        was married on the 12th inst. and is bringing his bride out with him.</p>
                    <p>The marriage of Captain C.W. Maclean, of the Lancashire Fusiliers, attached
                        to the Egyp. tian Army, and Miss Gladys Royle, daughter of Mr. and Mrs.
                        George Royle, of Ghezireh, Cairo, will take place at St. George’s,
                        Hanover-square, on the 12th Ju]y.</p>
                    <p>Captain Riach,. R.A.M.C., who has been suffering from enteric fever for some
                        time past at the Military Hospital, Ras-el-Tin, is making favorable
                        progress.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Critchley, manager of the Imperial Ottoman Bank at Alexandria, is
                        returning from London in the first week of July.</p>
                    <p>Mr, Laurence Meany, manager of the Cairo branch of Caffari's stores, has left
                        for Ireland on a holiday of about two months. Mr. Caffari himself will not
                        absent himself from Egypt this year.</p>
                    <p>The following visitors are staying at the Beau-Rivage Hotel, Ramleh : Mr. and
                        Mrs. Moore and family, Mrs. N. Berry, Mr. and Mrs. L. Davis, Mr. and Mrs.
                        McPherson Grant, Mr. and Mrs. N. Langhlin, Mr. and Mme. Jacques Press and
                        family, Miss G. Temple, Mr. S. Burey, Mr. and Mme. Alb. Simha, Miss M. Kay,
                        Judge Nyholm, Mr. and Mme A, David, Mrs. L. Reill.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="chroniqueFinanciere">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE (8-20 Juin)</head>
                    <p>Cette dernière quinzaine n'a pas été brillante. Non seulement lés positions
                        de beaucoup se trouvaient surchargées, ainsi que nous l'avions prévu, mais
                        une foule d’autres circonstances ont contribué à affaiblir le marché : la
                        qu'on croyait imminente demeure encore problématique ; le malentendu
                        franco-allemand, qui à sa période aiguë a produit un malaise général, n'est
                        pas encore définitivement ap-plani ; les capitalistes partant en
                        villégiature liquident leurs positions et ceux qui restent attendent des
                        jours meilleurs ; enfin les banques elles-mêmes se montrent plus difficiles
                        pour les avances et ne prêtent pas sur les titres nouveaux. Voilà plus de
                        motifs qu'il n'en faut pour expliquer l'état actuel du marché. La petite
                        spéculation, qui avait jusqu'ici sacrifié ses gros titres pour ne pas se
                        défaire des petits avec une perte énorme, n’a pu tenir plas long-temps et a
                        du liquider au mieux, ce qui n’a pas été facile, car aucun capitaliste
                        n’était là pour sauver la situation en absorbant d’un seul coup tout le
                        flottant. C’est donc moins aux titres eux-mêmes qu’aux circonstances
                        défavorables actuelles qu’il fout attribuer la baisse de ces derniers
                        jours.</p>
                    <p>Parmi les valeurs qui se sont maintenues le plus ferme, il fout placer en
                        première ligne l’Agricole, dont le cours débute à 18 11/16 atteint 13 7/8
                        pour clôturer à 13 21/32 ven deurs. La prochaine émission est pour beau-coup
                        dans ce soutien relatif.</p>
                    <p>De 26 3/4 la National Bank ancienne émission fléchit graduellement à 26 9/32
                        ex-droit, prix auquel elle clôture, tandis que la nouvelle émission est
                        demandée à 26 1/2. Cet ecart que rien ne justifie, puisque l’ancienne
                        émission a seule droit an coupon jette un nouveau jour sur la situation de
                        notre place ; il suffit, en effet, qu’on ait peu d’argent à verser pour
                        qu’une valeur y soit aussitôt recherchée et hausse contre toutes les règles
                        du bon sens. Aussi faut-il s’attendre à un revirement dès qu’une
                        amélioration se produira.</p>
                    <p>La Land Bank fluctue entre 9 et 9 3/16, prix auquel elle clôture
                        acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>De 28 11/16 la Daïra fléchit à 28 5/16 pour reprendre un peu plus tard à 28
                        19/32 et finir à 28 7/16. On ne sait rien encore de précis sur la
                        liquidation dont on ne connaîtra les clauses détaillées que vers la
                        mi-juillet.</p>
                    <p>L’action Crédit Foncier fléchit de 823 à 812.</p>
                    <p>L’Investment débute à 1 11/16 pour tomber graduellement jusqu'à 1 5/16, cours
                        auquel on clôture acheteurs. Bon nombre de remisiers et de leurs clients qui
                        avaient fait des reports pour le 15 de ce mois ont été contraints de
                        liquider au mieux ; les acheteurs voyant les ventes continuer se tiennent
                        naturellement sur la réserve. Ou a fait circuler la rumeur de la démission
                        d'un administrateur de cette société, mais cette nouvelle a été de suite
                        officiellement démentie.</p>
                    <p>De 1 1/4 le Trust a baissé un moment jusqu’à 1 1/8 pour reprendre eu clôture
                        à 1 3/16. Nombre de détenteurs de lettres de répartition n’ayant pas encore
                        reçu leurs certificats au porteur se trouvent dans l’impossi bilité de
                        livrer leurs titres, tandis qu’ils sont contraints d’en recevoir des paquets
                        de déten teurs plus favorisés.</p>
                    <p>D'importantes opérations ont eu lieu en Estâtes entre 7/8 et 15/16. Le prix
                        de cloture est 7/8.</p>
                    <p>La Béhéra monte de 45 1/2 à 45 3/4 pour finir à 45.</p>
                    <p>Très soutenue d’abord à 124 1/2, la Banque d’Athènes clôture plus faible à
                        120 par suite de la commotion politique produite par l’assassinat de M.
                        Delyannis.</p>
                    <p>De 2 1/2 la Delta Dand fléchit à 2 1/4 vendeurs.</p>
                    <p>L’Anglo-American Nile ouvre à 5 11/16, cote 5 5/16 ex-coupon et finit à 5 1/4
                        vendeurs.</p>
                    <p>La Salt and Soda retombe de 35/6 à 33. On s’attend à une sérieuse reprise sur
                        cette valeur au retour des capitalistes.</p>
                    <p>La Delta Light monte de 12 15/16 à 13 1/16, mais ne tarde pas à retomber à 12
                        7/8 pour finir à 12 11/16. Ia Deferred baisse de 14 1/2 à 14 1/8 sans
                        affaires.</p>
                    <p>De 7 3/4 la Ramleh Railway à 7 3/8 avec un chiffre d'affaires restreint</p>
                    <p>Les Privilégiées Tramways fluctuent entre 152 et 153 pour finir très
                        soutenues à 152 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Les Dividendes sont plus faibles à 348.</p>
                    <p>L’Urbaine ouvre à 4 5/8, atteint 4 7/8, mais fléchit avec tout le reste à 4
                        5/8 vendeurs. Cette société serait déjà engagée, parait-il, dans plusieurs
                        affaires de premier ordre.</p>
                    <p>Les Splendid Hotels fluctuent entre 4 3/8 et 4 9/16 pour finir à 4 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Les Eaux d’Alexandrie débutent à 15 3/4, cotent 15 1/4 ex-coupon et clôturent
                        à 15 1/8.</p>
                    <p>De 1,130, les Baux du Caire tombent à 1,120 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>Les Egyptian Markets se maintiennent à 22/3 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>En Filature on ouvre à 11/16, atteint 25/32 pour retomber en clôture à 11/16,
                        avec nombreuses transactions.</p>
                    <p>L’Obligation Crédit Foncier fléchit de 318 à 314 1/2.</p>
                    <p>En somme, la situation n’est pas brillante, comme on vient de. le voir.
                        Certaines valeurs pourraient même fléchir encore davantage avec la
                        liquidation dè fin de mois, à moins qu'un événement favorable imprévu ne
                        vienne changer la face des choses.</p>
                    <p>Le marché a été calme jusque vers midi. A ce moment d’importants rachats ont
                        eu lieu en Investment dont le cours a haussé rapidement de 1 5/16 à 1 7/16
                        forts acheteurs. On a fait 4 à 5000 actions à ce prix. Les positions
                        surchargées étant à peu près liquidées, le mouvement ascensionnel a dos
                        chances de s'accentuer.</p>
                    <p>Certaines valeurs ont profité de cette reprise, mais en général les
                        changements indiquent une baisse : La National Bank fléchit de 26 5/16 à 26
                        1/4, l'Alexandria Water de 15 1/4 à 15, la Delta Light de 12 11/16 à 12 5/8
                        et la Ramleh Railway de 7 5/8 à 7 7/16.</p>
                    <p>Seule la Salt and Soda reprend légèrement de 33 à 83/8 et l’action Crédit
                        Foncier de 813 à 813.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
