<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Emma Taylor</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-05">November 5, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-18">November 18, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>

                <head type="sub">No. 7349] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JULY 18, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS. THINGS GETTING WORSE. M. WITTE’S APPEAL.</head>
                    <p>London, November 17.</p>
                    <p> News received from Rossis tends generally to show that things are getting
                        worse in the capital and provinces, except at Moscow, where the workmen do
                        not favor the strike on acount of sympathy with Poland. There is no sign of
                        the determination of the strikers weak- ening. The council of workmen’s
                        delegates at St. Petersburg has resolved to continue the strike
                        indefinitely, scoffing at M. Witte’appeal. Russians are selling Russian
                        securities at any price for foreign gold which they immediately send
                        abroad.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 17.</p>
                    <p>A Ukase gives orders to facilitate the re- demption of land by peasants. The
                        redemption tax now paid by the peasants will be abolished in 1907.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KING’S ACCIDENT. H.M.'s CONDITION SATISFACTORY.</head>
                    <p>London, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The King tore a tendon above his ankle. His Majesty fell with such foroe as
                        to splinter the stock of his gun. He is doing well, and not suffering more
                        pain than is to be expected. Sir Frederick Treves visited him yesterday
                        morn- ing. There are no bulletins.</p>
                    <p>Sir Frederick Treves returned to Windsor in the evening, but the King's
                        condition continues satisfactory. To-night His Majesty attends a family
                        dinner at St. George's Hall, and after- wards a Melba concert in the drawing
                        room.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REJOICINGS IN NORWAY. THE NEW KING'S COMING.</head>
                    <p>Christiana, November 17.</p>
                    <p>Great rejoicings prevail. Every coast town in Norway sends vessels to
                        accompany the men-of-war bringing their Majesties the King and Queen from
                        Copenhagen.</p>
                    <p>{Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN NAVY. MORE SHIPS TO BE BUILT. </head>
                    <p>Berlin, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The Bundesrath has approved a bill provid- ing for the construction of six
                        additional cruisers and 8 divisions of torpedo boats, of greatly enlarged
                        dimensions, in accordance with the lessons tanght by the war. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH GENERAL PUNISHED. REFUSES TO SALUTE.</head>
                    <p>Paris, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The French Cabinet has ordered the Com- mander-in-Chief, General Brugere, a
                        fortnight's arrest for publishing an account of an interview with the
                        Minister of War, to which be had been summoned for refusing to salute the
                        General implicated in the informing scandals.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Paris, November 17.</p>
                    <p>M. Etienne, Minister of War, has sentenced General Brugere to fifteen days’
                        detention for having communicated the conversation regard- ing his refusal
                        to salute General Percin.</p>
                    <p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FRENCH STRIKE.</head>
                    <p>Paris, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies, by 436 votes against 68, has approved of the action
                        of the Government in denying the right to a strike which compromises the
                        national defences. (H.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FUND FOR RUSSIAN JEWS.</head>
                    <p>London, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The fund for the Russian Jews, includ- ing remittances from America, amounts
                        to £124,000.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF PRINCE PHILIPPE.</head>
                    <p>Brussels, November 17.</p>
                    <p>Prince Philippe, Count of Flanders, is dead.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>The Count of Flanders, the brother of the King of the Belgians, was born at
                        Leeken in 1887 and married Mary, Princess of Hohen- sollern, in 1867, by
                        whom he had two daughters and a son.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POWERS’ NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                    <p>Vienna, November 17.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Ripper will be in command of the demonstration of squadrons against
                        Turkey.</p>
                    <p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SERIOUS COMPLICATION. LUXEMBURG SUCCESSION. GRAND DUKE'S DEATH</head>
                    <p>Luxemburg, November 17.</p>
                    <p>The Grand Dnke of Luxemburg is dead.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter</p>
                    <p>The death of the Grand Duke Adolphus may not improbably lead to serious
                        difficulties,as for some time past, owing to the advanced age or the Grand
                        Duke, the question of the succession has been a matter of considerable
                        concern to Belgium and will possibly become a European question. The late
                        Grand Duke by his two marriages only left one son, Prince William, who is in
                        bad health and has only daughters by his marriage with a Princess of
                        Braganza. The Salio law holds good in Luxemburg, otherwise the Grand Duchy
                        would have passed in 1890 to Queen Wilhelmina of Holland, at the death of
                        her father the late Grand Duke. One feeble life thus stands between
                        Luxemburg and a serious crisis, for Germany it is well known desires to
                        incorporate the little State in the Empire. This, however, could scarcely be
                        permitted by France, who, as long ago as 1867, protested against such an
                        absorption on the part of Germany. Belgium, too, powerless as she is, would
                        view with the greatest objec- tion a German ontpost on her frontiers. The
                        Belgians argue the matter thus: both France and Germany wish to have the
                        Grand Duchy but neither will allow the other to get posses- sion of it
                        without the most serious protests. The obvious solution they say is to give
                        it to Belgium, to whom it belonged until 1839. The two States are closely
                        united in every way, and the annexation oould be carried out without the
                        slightest trouble or disturbance.</p>
                    <p>The late Grand Duke of Luxemburg was born at Biebrich, July 24, 1817, and
                        married, at Dessau, April 23, 1851, his second wife, Princess Adelaide of
                        Anhalt; his first wife, the Grand Duchess Elisabeth Michailovna of Russia,
                        having died in 1845 withont issue. His only daughter, Princess Hilda, was
                        married to the Crown Prince Frederick of Baden in 1885; a grandson of the
                        Emperor William 1., with a settlement of a million sterling. The Hereditary
                        Prince Alexander is likewise an only son, born in 1852, and serves as major-
                        general in the Austrian army. Should his sister die without issue her dower
                        will ultimately revert to him, and he will be one of the wealthiest princes
                        in Europe, his father having possessed, in addition to a fortune of at least
                        three millions sterling, vast estates in Austria and Germany. Prince
                        Alexander married on June 21, 1893, Marie-Anne, Princess of Braganza.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>Quarantine.</p>
                    <p>Quarantine restrictions as against arrivals from Porbander have been
                        removed.</p>
                    <p>H.H.S. Aida.</p>
                    <p>The Ports and Lighthouses S.S. Aida return- ed to Alexandria yesterday from
                        the Red Sea.</p>
                    <p>Wakfs Administration.</p>
                    <p>The receipts of the Wakfs Administration in the Budget for 1906 show an
                        increase of L.E. 100,000.</p>
                    <p>Stray Dogs.</p>
                    <p>Stray and ownerless dogs found in the Boulsc district of Cairo during the
                        night of ‘he 19th inst and at Abbassieh during the night of the 20th will be
                        poisoned by the police.</p>
                    <p>England in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Of all the enterprises which Great Britain has been engaged in for the past
                        fifty years, her protectorate over Egypt is, perhaps, the one which redounds
                        most to her oredit. — "Press," Nagasaki.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.</p>
                    <p>Eleven vessels passed through the Canal on the 14th inst, of which 5 were
                        British, 2 Ger- man, 1 Austrian, 1 French, 1 Italian, 1 Turk- ish. The total
                        receipts from the 1st to the 14th inst. amounted to frs. 4,708,967.67.</p>
                    <p>Cairo Brokers.</p>
                    <p>An extraordinary meeting of the Cairo stockbrokers will be held on Monday
                        next in order to choose six members of the committee in place of Messrs.
                        Morters, Reid, Ammar De Vries, Salinse, and Negrin,who have retired.</p>
                    <p>Discovery of Coins.</p>
                    <p>While some workmen were excavating in the Wakfs ruins beyond the new Sanieh
                        School at Cairo, they discovered some very old Arabic coins of great value.
                        This numismatical treasure-trove bas been handed over to the
                        authorities.</p>
                    <p>Coal Imports.</p>
                    <p>From the 1st of January to the 16th inst 953,787 tons of ooal were imported
                        into Egypt Wales sent 514,625, Newcastle 221,413, Scotland 117,140,
                        Yorkshire 64,308, and other places 36,306. During the same period last year
                        933,647 tons were received.</p>
                    <p>"Orient and Occident.”</p>
                    <p>Our weekly Cairo contemporary, in its current issue, gives an interesting
                        account of the life and labours of the late Dr Barnardo, quoting some
                        excellent poetry, "In Memoriam" from "Punch." These lines remind one of the
                        fine stanzas published by our comic oontemporary on the oooasion of the
                        death of President Lincoln, and are equally worthy of the occasion.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>railway administration. SOMe INTERESTING FIGURES.</head>
                    <p>The following details regarding the general traffic on the Egyptian State
                        Railways during the past ten months shonld be of some interest to our
                        readers. We understand that during that period 4,884,000 tons of goods of
                        all kinds have been carried, against 8,625,000 durirg the corresponding
                        period last year, an increase of 21 1/2 per cent, though the increase in the
                        carrying oapacity of the rolling stock brought about by the supply of new
                        trucks, etc, only amounts to 13 per cent This increase is the more
                        remarkable in that the traffic to Alexandria has remained almost stationary,
                        while tbe traffic from that piece has increased about 16 per oent and is now
                        more than double that in tbe opposite direction, with the result that quite
                        half the trucks going up from Alexandria have to be sent back empty. The
                        average load of the trucks loaded here has increased from 82 to 84 per cent
                        of their nominal carrying capacity,—a remarkably high figure, as trucks will
                        only take about 60 % of their nominal load when laden with timber and less
                        still when carrying "tibn,” which has now become quite a common article of
                        transport, owing to the great scarcity of fodder and cereals in parts of the
                        country which now grow nothing but cotton, and many other commodities.</p>
                    <p>Though the traffic which does not touch Alexandria is to the Alexandria
                        traffic nearly as 5 to 3, on an average every truck on the Egyptian State
                        lines takes a load out of Gabbary every 12 days. The increase of traffic has
                        resulted in an increase of earnings, the figures working out at about 9s. 1
                        1/2d. per goods train mile against 9s. Od. in 1904. It follows from all this
                        that not only has the rolling stock been increased, but that the
                        administration now gets more work out of each truck than formerly, while new
                        trucks are added as fast as it is possible to get them put together. Up to
                        date every track has on an average run a trip once every three days, and as
                        merchants frequently take a full day to load and another day to unload,
                        while many trips cannot be made in much under two days, it seems obvious
                        that there has been very little margin left for avoidable delays.</p>
                    <p>As for the passenger traffic, for the ten months of 1905 it shows an increase
                        in number of 1,836,000, twelve per cent. more than in 190<unclear/>, a
                        remarkable sign of the increasing prosperity of the country. If this fact be
                        considered along with the increase of goods traffic, which has been most
                        extraordinary, it will be realised that the Railway Administration has had a
                        very heavy task during the present year. There are doubtless some points
                        where improvement is desirable, but it deserves great credit for its
                        success.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW RAILWAY BOARD.</head>
                    <p>We understand that Capt. Lyons will be one of the two British members of the
                        Conseil Superieur of the Railway Administration. Mustapha Pasha Fehmy will
                        be president, and M. Barois and Scandar Pasha Fehmy will sit on the
                        board.</p>
                    <p>Major L’Estrange Johnstone, as we have already stated, will be
                        director-general of the administration.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS.</head>
                    <p>The scheme for the classification of the officials of the Egyptian Government
                        will not be put into force until the Financial Adviser has received the
                        opinions of the various heads of Government departments on the subject. The
                        officials of the Religious and Mixed Courts will not be included.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALE OF HOTEL ABBAT.</head>
                    <p>The well-known Alexandrian hostelry, the Hotel Abbat, has been sold for L.E
                        30,000, inclusive of the site and building, but not the furniture. This
                        works out at the rate of L.E 10 per pic, as the site comprises a superficies
                        of about 3,000 pics.The purchaser is M. Hannaux Owing to the central
                        position of the site the price is considered moderate. It has not yet been
                        decided by M. Hannaux as to what he intends to do with the building, but we
                        under stand that he has already reoeived a number of offers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SPHINX.</head>
                    <p>The first issue of the "Sphinx” for the current season will appear on
                        Saturday, December 2. Many changes have been made in order to add to the
                        attractiveness of the periodical. A lady correspondent has been attached to
                        the staff and will contribute items of especial interest to lady readers.
                        The contents will also include articles of general and local interest to
                        residents and visitors, reliable financial news, full accounts of the latest
                        social events in Egypt and abroad, several columns of personal references,
                        up-to- date visitors’ lists of the principal hotels of Cairo, Helouan,
                        Luxor, Assouan, Alexandria, and Port Said, much valuable information for
                        visitors, a useful Arabic vocabulary, etc, etc. The price of the "Sphinx"
                        will remain at two piastres tarif (5d.) per copy, but sub- scribers payirg
                        in advanoe can obtain one oopy weekly, throughout the sesson, for
                        twenty-five piastres tarif in Egypt, and forty piastres tarif abroad, post
                        free.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA'S NEW QUAY. THE SALES OF LAND.</head>
                    <p>No date has as yet been decided upon for the sales of building land on the
                        new quay at Alexandria. It is to be hoped that the Municipality will soon
                        fix an early date, as the public expectation is very eager and the looal
                        capitalists have for some time past been girding themselves for the fray at
                        the forthcoming sale. </p>
                    <p>The lands must, according to the regulations of the Municipal Free State
                        Lands Department, be revalued every year, and this year’s valuation will be
                        the reserve price of the land. It was thought advisable to have the valtion
                        as and the sales during the winter, when the Municipal Council is at its
                        full and the local capitalists have returned. </p>
                    <p>We have reason to believe that the question of selling the lands will soon be
                        decided by the Municipality. The valuation of the remaining portion of the
                        land can easily be made, and in all,probability it will be put up to anotion
                        early in the year. </p>
                    <p>The most interesting question in regard to the new quay estates is as to
                        whether the centre of the city will be shifted from that part of the Mohamed
                        Aly-square, where is the Bourse, to the great artery of traffic to the quay,
                        which is to be at the Plaoe des Consuls. 1 There will be the Gonvernorat,
                        the Government and Ministerial buildings, etc., and many believe that that
                        part will beoome the hub of Alexandria. But this is a very doubtful theory,
                        for where the Bourse now is will be a far more central, and commerce is
                        notoriously conservative in its movements. The quay will not succeed in
                        displacing Cherif Pasha-street for many years to come.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW JUDGES.</head>
                    <p>It has been decided that of the two Mixed Court judges who are to be
                        appointed, the French judge will be nominated to the Mixed Court at
                        Alexandria and the Greek judge to that at Mansourah.</p>
                    <p>Negotiations in regard to the appointments are still proceeding between the
                        Egyptian and French and Greek Governments.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MECCA PILGRIMAGE. </head>
                    <p>The Alexandria correspondent of the "Man cheater Guardian" writes as follows
                        to his paper:- </p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Government announces an increased scale of charges to be levied
                        on all Egyptian pilgrims accompanying the Holy Carpet in the approaohing
                        pilgrimage to Mecca. In justification of this measure it is stated that the
                        accounts of the last pilgrimage kept in the Ministry of the Interior
                        disclose a considerable deficit between the receipts derived from the
                        pilgrims and the Governmental expenses. There is no doubt that the cost of
                        this religions obligation is becoming every year more onerons for the
                        individual Moslem. As an example of this fact, if Egypt is not declared free
                        from plague by the time the Hedjaz caravans set out on their journey a poll
                        of £E 50 (?) from every pilgrim is exacted by the regulations of the
                        Sanitary Board of Constantinople for purposes of hygienic supervision and
                        disinfection.</p>
                    <p>The Western world least ot all has cause to criticise regulations such as
                        these, however stringent they may seem, for they are eminently preventive in
                        character, and their observance by the rude Hags who form the mass of the
                        caravans is one of the best guarantees that the former agglomerations of
                        pestiferous humanity —a menace to the well-being of three conti- nents—is at
                        an end.</p>
                    <p>As regards the charges assessed on the pilgrims travelling under the escort
                        of the Holy Carpet, the Bedouin hostilities during the last two pilgrimages
                        more than vindicate the despatch of a strong force, well armed and equipped,
                        for the protection of the caravan. The Egyptian Government can scarcely be
                        blamed for declining to cover the deficit from the funds of the State, since
                        the native taxpayers of Egypt number probably as many Copts as Mussulmans.
                        It is, moreover, questionable whether the pilgrims who journey on their own
                        account and not under military protection fare at all so well in the end,
                        either with respect to individual comfort or pecuniary outlay.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Baron von Humboldt-Daohroeden, German Consul at Alexandria, returned from
                        Europe to-day by the S.S. Maria Teresa.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left by the P. S. Hatasoo, yesterday, for tbe Nile
                        trip:— Mrs. and Miss Ravan, Mr. Ch. Victor Thomas, Mr. Hans Mettler, Mr.
                        Stefan v. Breyovay, Mr. and Mrs. J. Stern, Rev. A. W. and Mrs. Gross, Miss
                        C. Gibbs, Mr. R. Adams, Mr. G. Raphael, Miss Socolis.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck and CO.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Joseph Comas</head>
                </div>



                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO RACE SEASON BEGINS K.S.C. FIRST MEETING.</head>
                    <p>Excellent weather marked the opening meeting of the K.S.C.’s 1905-6 season
                        yesterday. The fields were quite good and there were some excellent
                        finishes, especially in the third race, which, after a most exciting
                        struggle, ended in a dead heat. The fourth race was also well contested, as
                        was the fifth and last of the day. Of the owners, Khalil Pasha Khayat opened
                        the season admirably with three wins— one of them a dead heat. Ibrahim Bey
                        Cherif with several horses running, was unlacky. The attendance was
                        moderately good; there was, of course, a marked absence of the tourist
                        element, but a good many well-known residents were present, among whom we
                        noticed the Hon. F. O. Lindley,Gen. Bullock, Mr. Machell, Mr. Mitchell
                        Innes, Mr. Webb, Mr. Carter Wilson, Mrs. Hunter, Col. Friend, Major and Mrs.
                        Herbert, Mr. Crawley, Capt McMurdo, Mr. and Mrs. Astley Friend, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Royle, Judge Tuck, Capt and Mrs. Maclean, Mr. and Mrs. Stoat, Mrs. and Miss
                        Rees, Mme and Mlle de Codt, Mme Vernon, Capt. Gillson, Major and Mrs.
                        Dalavoye, Johnson Pasha and Mrs. JohnsoD, Mr. Langley, Mr. and Mrs. Marshall
                        Hewat, Omar Bey Sultan, Ahmed Bey Bakri, Mr. A J. Michaelides and many
                        others. Lord and Lady Waterford were also among the spectators.</p>
                    <p>POLO SCURRY of P.T. 1,500, 2nd horse P.T. 300 and 3rd horse P.T. 200 ont of
                        the stakes. For Polo Ponies, 14 hands and under 12 st, over 14 hands 12.7.
                        Distance 8 furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Capt Protheroe-Smith'e g.a.h, Samhane, 12.0 Mr. Schrelber. 1</p>
                    <p>Mr. Mellor’s g.b.g. Fils de Rsvachol, 12.7. Owner. 2</p>
                    <p>Mr. E. P. Blencowe's g.a.b. Ameer, 12.7. Mr. Reid. 3</p>
                    <p>Capt. Bartlett’s g.a.h. Pierrot, 12.0. Owner. 0</p>
                    <p>Capt Bailey's g.s.h. Tableaux, 12.7. Mr. Starkey. 0</p>
                    <p>Mr. G. Dalby's g.a.g. Angelo V.. 12.7. Owner. 0</p>
                    <p>Mr. J. B. Jenkinson's ch.a.b. Shieldrake, 12.7. Owner. 0</p>
                    <p> Betting was all in favor of Samhanne, who came away early from the crowd and
                        was only challenged by Fi's de Ravachol in the last 300 yards. After a good
                        race the favorite got home by half a length. Ameer was a length behind the
                        second horse. Time: 45 seconds.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. — on winner and P.T. 25, 24, and 36 for places.</p>
                    <p>NOVEMBER TRIAL PLATE of P.T. 1,500, 2nd horse P.T. 300,3rd horse P.T. 200.
                        For Maiden Arabs. Weight for age and inches. Winners of L.E. 20 and over to
                        carry 10 lbs extra. Distance 7 furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's ch.a.h. Suheil, 9.13 Jenkins. 1 Moharrem Pasha’s g.a.h.
                        Massoud, 11.1. H Suleiman. 2 Ibrahim Bey Cherif and Kamel Eff. Maber's
                        g.a.b. Vandal, 9.13. Kamel Effendi. 3 Capt Gillson’s g.a.h Sirur, 9.13.
                        Johnson. 0 Hussein Bey Sioufi's g.a.h. Abou Nadarat 9.13. 0 Hussein Bey
                        Sioufi’s b.a.h. Mitwalli, 11.1. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherif's g.a.h. Massoud, 11.1
                        Bonser. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s ch.a.h. Gladiator II, 9.13. 0 Ishak Bey
                        Hussein's g.a.h. Kismat, 10.7 Stillwell. 0 Mr. Moberly's ch.a.h. Last
                        Chance, 11.1 Parsvicini. 0 Saleh Bey Yaghen's g.a.h. Tokar, 10.5. Fenwick. 0
                        Mr. Tueni'e ch.a.h. Voyageur, 11.1. Mathews. 0</p>
                    <p>Mitwalli and Voyageur were in front at the start, with Vandal and Massoud
                        well-up. Vandal soon took the lead and went ahead at the first corner, only
                        to be challenged by Suheil and Massoud. At the turn the race was clearly
                        Suheil’s and he won pretty easily, Massoud being a moderate seoond and
                        Vandal a fair third. Time : 1 38.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. .34 on winner and P.T. 19, 38, and 33 for places.</p>
                    <p>HURDLE RACE of P.T. 1,500, 2nd horse P.T. 300, 3rd horse P.T. 200, for Arabs
                        that have never won a race, Hurdle Race or Steeplechase value L.E. 20.
                        Weight for age and inches. 2 miles over 8 flights of hurdles.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's b.a.h. Hadeed, 11.5. Lillamans. Mr. Tueni's g.a.h.
                        Petrone, [ dead best 10.13. Mathews. Hussein Bey Sioufi's ch.a.b. Peacock,
                        10.5 Capt Bassett. Hussein Bey Sioufi’s b.a.h. Mitwalli, 12.1 Mr. Reid.
                        Ibrahim Bey Cherit's g.a.h. Saclawi, 11.1 Bonser. </p>
                    <p>Saclawi, who was well backed, led and for the first part of race ran first,
                        with Peacock and Metwalli close to him, Petrone and Hadeed waiting. Then
                        Peacock drew ahead but Petrone now made a great effort and coming rapidly
                        up, overhauled the leader only to be himself challenged by Hadeed. At the
                        grand-stand Petrone looked beaten by a head but a last effort brought him
                        level at the finish. Peacock wss a good third. Time: 4 8</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 60 on Hadeed and P.T 43 on Petrone, and P.T. 30, 25,
                        and 19 for places.</p>
                    <p>THE AUTUMN STAKES of P.T. 1,500 2nd horse P T. 800, 3rd horse P.T. 200. For
                        Maiden Arab ponies. Weight for age and inches.Winners of £E. 20 and over to
                        carry lOlbs extra. Distanoe 1 mile.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Kayat's g.a.h. Kawkab, 10.7. Jenkins. Mr. Emin Karam's , h.a.h
                        Nimrod, 10.7. Makkah. 2</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Hussein Bey Shofi’s g.a.b. Aboa Nadarat, 10.7. 3 CaptGillson’s b.a.b.Ji hn
                        Peel, 10.7. Johnson. 0 Hussein Bey S:oufi’s b.a.h. Atragoak, 10.7. 0 Ibrahim
                        Bey Cherifs oh.a.h. Gladiator IL, 10.7. Bonser. o Ibrahim Bey Cherifs g.a.h.
                        Sattame, 10.7. 0 Ishak Bey Hussein's b*.h. Nuerut, 10.7. Stillwell. i> Kamel
                        Eff. Maher’s bjub. Gioochi, 10.81 Owner. o Baron J. E de Msnasce's tha.b.
                        R.diuu. 10.7. 0 Saleh Bey Yagbeu’a g.a.b.Tokar.10.7 Hasran.O</p>
                    <p>Another good race, the horses getting off well, Sattame ahead. He was unable
                        to keep up the paoe and one leader succeeded another, the rest keeping close
                        up for some way, till Aboa Nadara got in front and was caught by Nimrod in
                        the last quarter. Kawkab came up very strongly at the finish and beat Nimrod
                        by a neck, Aboa Nadara being 2/3rds of a length behind. Time : 1.56.</p>
                    <p>An unpleasant incident followed this race, the well-known jockey, Jenkins,
                        being suspend- ed until further notice for fouling Nimrod and Abou Nadara.
                        The stakes were therefore awarded to the second horse.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 28 on'Wimer and P.T. 24, 54, and 99 for places.</p>
                    <p>AMATEUR HALF-MILE HANDICAP of P.T. 1,500, 2nd horse P.T. 200, open to Arabs
                        the property of British Members of the K.8.C. Distance 1/2 mile.</p>
                    <p>Capt ProthErofrSmith’s g.a.h. Samhane, 10.9. Jenkins. 1 Messrs.
                        MellorandSoh’eiber’s b b.a-.b.h.Merlin, 12.7. Schraiber. 9 Mr. A.
                        Sohreiber’s chjib. Fits, 19.7. Mr. Cale. 8 Mr. G. H. Barker's b.a.h. Effie,
                        12.7. Mr. Mel'or. 0 Capt Bartlett’s g.a.h. Bohhme, 11.10, Owner. 0 Mr. E. P.
                        Blenoowe’s g a. L Ameer, 10.0. Mr. Donsdale. 0 Msj. Delavoye'a b.ajL Fellah,
                        11.0. 0 Capt Gillson’s g.a.L Toe Clown. 10.*. 0 Messrs.|Higgins and
                        Greville's b.a.h.Faik,11.8. ParaTiem. Mr. J. B. Jenkinson's bb.ar.b.h.
                        Rabah, 19.7.J£ Owner. o Mr. Moberley’s ch.ah. tat Chance, 10.7.‘ Mathew. 0
                        Capt. Protheroe-Smith’e b.a.b. Eibioo, 10.6. Oapt Ba*satt. 0 Mr. P. W.
                        Stoat’s g.a.h. Shewiman, 11.9. Mr. Reed. 0</p>
                    <p>In a failing light, whioh made things hard to see, this raoe ended inawin'for
                        Samhane by nnder half a length, Martin being only bea'en in the last 60
                        yards and F tz being a goad third. Time : l. 8$. Totalisator paid P.T. 85 on
                        winner and P.T. 68, 80, and 88 for p'aoes.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FASHIONS AT GHEZIREH. A WOMAN’S POINT OF VIEW.</head>
                    <p>(Special to the Gazette)</p>
                    <p>With the first meeting of the Khedivial Sporting Club yesterday, the Cairo
                        season of 1905 may be said to commence ; and from a woman’s point of view it
                        already promises well. Certainly there was no dearth of fresh and pretty
                        frocks; snd there were several excellent examples of the prevailing fashion.
                        Naturally one of the most striking figures present Was that of Mrs. Mc Lean,
                        the bride of the moment. She was wearing a fine blue embroidered muslin robe
                        with insertions and under sleeves of white lace, and a large veil of the
                        same hue encircled her wide-brimmed hat. Her mother, Mrs. Royle, was also
                        looking her best in a dark blue spotted silk muslin, made over and relieved
                        with white. Mrs. Crookshank wore white with handsome insertions of white
                        lace. There were many white frocks of course, and some especially handsome
                        ones with edgings and insertions of broiderie anglaise, or very heavy lace.
                        A very handsome French woman was wearing a tight- fitting three-quarter coat
                        of broiderie anglaise, ornamented with large embroidered buttons. The
                        embroidery also appeared at the hem of the well-cut short white skirt, and
                        the hat was made of the same embroidery with masses of pink roses tucked
                        beneath the brim, and an enormous pink veil floating round it.</p>
                    <p>Miss Rees was well turned ont, as usual, and wore a soft grey frock, the
                        short bolero showing lace above the waist line and in the vest. Her lace
                        toque, turned high from the head at one side, was lined with black ; a black
                        feather rested on her pretty hair. Mrs.de Codt had on a trim fitting blue
                        dress adorned with edgings of tightly pleated lace, and there were several
                        dainty frocks of tiny checked taffatas, the prettiest perhaps being in
                        silver grey with tucks and ruchings of the same, and a soft folded waist
                        band of a very soft shade of blue. Mrs.Hunter was in white with black at the
                        waist and black wings in her hat; and with her was her sister, Mrs. Herbert;
                        and also Mrs.Satow, the last mentioned in the palest softest blue skirt with
                        corsage of Paris tinted lace. A very dainty frock of deep ivory voile was
                        adorned with appliques of Oriental design in brown and blue; and with this
                        was worn a large hat of shaded brown with tiny pink roses. Another beautiful
                        gown was of palest champagne coloured cloth, the trailing skirt enriched
                        with lace outlined with mole coloured velvet,which velvet also draped the
                        slender waist and adorned the corsage. Originality was the leading note in a
                        soft white silk lined with heliotrope. The corsage had a small pointed
                        basque, and opened in the front to show the deep pointed and draped ceinture
                        of the heliotrope. Feathers of the same shade appeared on the toque; and
                        indead many shaded ostrich plumes were being worn in accordance with the
                        latest decrees of fashion.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Carlton Hotel</head>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
