<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">September 19, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-09">September 19, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 9, 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REVOLT IN CAUCASUS. TURKISH AGITATORS ACTIVE. BALAKHANY BURNT DOWN. BRITISH SUBJECTS BESIEGED.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 8. The revolt in the Caucasus was planned long ago
                        and carefully organised. It is fomented by Turkish agitators bearing the
                        green standard. Bands of peasants are invading the domains of the nobles and
                        seizing firearms. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Baku, September 8. The British subjects have escaped on board the steamers.
                        It is believed that the Russian authorities are now paying dearly for their
                        policy in inciting the Tartars against the Armenians. The former are now
                        attacking all the Christians. Four British subjects are besieged in a house
                        at Balakhany. The Governor of Baku declares that he is powerless to help
                        them. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>TIFLIS, September 8. The Tartars are surrounding Baku. Balakhany has been
                        totally destroyed by fire.(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TOKIO RIOTS. MARTIAL LAW PROCLAIMED.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, September 8. Martial law has been proclaimed. The disorders were
                        resumed yesterday evening. The troops are guarding the Foreign
                        Legations.(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, September 8. The newspapers deplore the excesses committed here, which
                        contrast with the admirable serenity shown during the war. The town was
                        quiet to-day and no serious disturbances took place anywhere during the
                        night The party leaders met and agreed to urge the Cabinet to call a special
                        Diet as the best means of restoring quietness. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, September 8. A state of siege has been declared here.(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TERRIBLE EARTHQUAKE IN ITALY. THREE TOWNS DESTROYED.</head>
                    <p>Rome, September 8. A violent earthquake took place this morning throughout
                        Italy, and particularly in Calabria where there were many deaths The towns
                        of Pizzo, Monteleone, and Martirano have been almost completely destroyed.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Catanzaro, September 8. 347 persons were killed in Calabria owing to the
                        earthquake. More than a down towns and villages were partially wrecked.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Rome, September 8. An earthquake in Calabria has killed several hundreds of
                        persons.(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION. ROUVIER AND ROSEN MEET.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 8. M. Rouvier and M. Rosen have commenced their conferences
                        over the Morocco question.(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FAMINE IN RUSSIA. MEANS OF RELIEF.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 8. The first sitting of the Ministerial Conference
                        to consider the question of granting relief to the famine stricken
                        provinces, recommended the Treasury to assign £4,000,000 for the purchase of
                        cereals.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KING EDWARD AT MARIENBAD.</head>
                    <p>London, September 8. King Edward has left Marienbad. His health has much
                        improved.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Vienna, September 8. The Khedive has left for Constantinople.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHANNEL SQUADRON.</head>
                    <p>Copenhagen, September 8. The Channel Squadron has arrived here.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sanitary Department</head>
                        <p>Dr. Jacob Daond baa been authorised to practise his profession in
                            Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOUND DROWNED</head>
                        <p>The body of a European, aged about forty, was picked up on the eastern
                            beach yesterday morning.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>Yesterday bulletin reports the admission to hospital of a shawish of the
                            Labban quarter, Alexandria. One recovery is also reported.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cart Accident</head>
                        <p>A boy named Zehi Moham-ed was run over by a cart yesterday near the
                            Custom House and will require three weeks medical treatment</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Mouski district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn
                            of the 11th inst will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Theft by a Moawkn</head>
                        <p>The moawen of Teh el Baroud poet office has been sentenced to two years
                            imprisonment by the Alexandria Assize Courts for having stolen a sum of
                            L.E. 81, which was deposited in the post office savings</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>82 vessels passed through the Canal on the 5th and 6th inst., 14 of which
                            were British, 5 German, 1 French, 2 Dutch. The receipts for the two days
                            were frs. 605,595.76, making the total from the 1st inst frs.
                            1,756,207.58.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Brindisi Mail</head>
                        <p>will be made up at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8-30 a.m. on Monday for
                            ordinary correspondence. Registered letters must be banded in by 9 p.m.
                            on Sunday, and insured articles, money orders, and parcels by noon on
                            that day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Theft at Cairo Station</head>
                        <p>A purse containing £10 was stolen from the pocket of Sheikh Abdul Rahmin
                            Selim, inspector of kuttabs, Ministry of Public Instruction, at Cairo
                            station yesterday. The police are making every endeavour to discover the
                            pickpocket.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Quarrel Ends in Bloodshed</head>
                        <p>Hassanein Mohamed and Ramadan Muni, a Sais, quarel- at Ramleh yesterday.
                            The first named being in liquor stabbed bis enemy in the ride inflicting
                            very serious injuries. The culprit has been arrested.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sanitary Inspection</head>
                        <p>Our Akhmin Correspondent informs us that Dr. Garner, chief inspector of
                            Upper Egypt in the Sanitary Department, arrived there on Tuesday and
                            made a visit of inspection round the town and at the offices of the
                            administration. He toft for Sohag on the conclusion of his
                            inspection.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>Cesareo's five-act tragedy Francesca da Rimini is billed for this
                            evening, and this will be the first occasion upon which the company has
                            presented it in Alexandria. The tragedy will be followed by a farce,
                            entitled La Vedova delle Camelie. At tomorrow afternoon's matinée,
                            commencing at 3 p.m., Prestame tua Moglie will be staged, and at the
                            evening performance Strega Bianca e Strega Nera and El Catino di
                            Campagna will be played.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sax Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>To-night is the oo-oasion of the grand fete at San Stefano Casino. The
                            programme includes an orchestral and vocal concert, firework display,
                            and, at 11 p.m. a small dance. The vocal part of the concert which
                            commences at 10 p.m., will include the whole of the third act of
                            Puccini's La Boheme, and the trio and finale of the third act of Verdi's
                            Ernani. On Sunday the last of the vocal concerts will be given, and will
                            consist of those pieces which have proved the most popular at previous
                            concerts</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alexandria Tramways</head>
                        <p>We are asked to give notice that the tramcars running on the St Catherine
                            Karmous line will, from the 15th inst., leave the two terminal points
                            every ten minutes, instead of every twenty as heretofore. From the same
                            date, the half feres will be supressed, and the charges will be 10
                            millièmes first elan and 5 millièmes second class. There will also be a
                            modification in the evening timetable of the Mex line from the 18th
                            inst, after which date the last departure from Rond-Point for Max will
                            be at 9 p.m., for Gabbari at 9 30 p.m., and from Mex to the town at 10
                            p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of
                            the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with
                            the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services
                            of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring
                            information on trade matters generally, including the question of
                            appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is
                            obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become
                            members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription
                            is merely the nominal one of £1. 'The latter payment also includes a
                            copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber Home inquirers can
                            obtain further particulars from our London office, 36 New Broad-street,
                            which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SOCIETE DES SUCRERIES. HON. A J, DAVEY INTERVIEWED.</head>
                    <p>Through the courtesy of the Hon. A. J. Davey we are enabled to place before
                        our readers the exact position at this moment of the above company, whose
                        shares have been so greatly depreciated on our, local bourses since the
                        receipt of the news of the tragic end of its late chairman. When this became
                        known several sinister rumours wore set afloat, and, as we stated in a
                        previous issue, the fact that no definite news was forthcoming at that time
                        as to whether the Sucreries would eventually be losers by the catastrophe
                        that had led to M. Cronier’s sad suicide brought about the great and sudden
                        depreciation of the shares which took place. Up to the present the company
                        has paid regular and handsome dividends, the last being at the rate of 8 per
                        cent, and carrying over about £2,600 to this year’s account. The net profit
                        for the twelve months ending 31st October last was no less than L.E. 76,780,
                        after payment of interest on the debentures and all other charges, so that
                        until M. Cronier’s failure, the company’s affairs were in a prosperous
                        state. In reply to enquiries made by our representative, Mr. Davey said that
                        as regards the bills for some 24 million francs drawn on the Sucreries by
                        the succession Henri Say, the company would probably contest their validity,
                        and the question was one for the law courts to decide. In the meanwhile the
                        Hon. A. Davey acting in the capacity of general manager, and in the name of
                        the company, had applied for a concordat preventif, or a stay of execution,
                        and the Commercial Chamber of the Mixed Tribunal in Cairo will meet on the
                        19th instant to consider the application. In the meanwhile there are ample
                        funds in hands to meet all payments, a sum of no less than £12,000 haring
                        been disbursed only two days back, which fact completely refutes the adverse
                        rumours spread that the company's offers were empty. Monsieur Girard, the
                        head accountant, is busily engaged preparing a full and detailed statement
                        to be presented to the pretiding judge of the Commercial Chamber on the date
                        when the application will come up for consideration. Until then every
                        account as it becomes due will be met at once in cash, and Mr. Davey has
                        given orders that the utmost economy most be practised in every department
                        until the decision of the Court becomes known. "It would be unfortunate,
                        indeed, it would in fact be nothing less than a calamity,” said Mr. Davey,
                        “should the company at this juncture have to suspend operations, for the
                        very good and simple reason that its suspension would spell ruin to many
                        cultivators of sugar cane in Upper Egypt. Once its factories were closed the
                        next crop would be practically valueless. The company bad entered into a
                        contract with the Dalra Sanieh Co., for the supply of 12 million cantars of
                        cane at P.T. 3 per kantar, to be delivered between now and March next, and
                        this large quantity, as well as that of private individuals, would be lost”
                        It does great credit to Mr. Davey to bave temporarily withdrawn his
                        resignation, which he had sent in before the Cromer crash occur-red, now
                        that the company is in temporary difficulties. As regards the resignation of
                        Messrs. A. Leroux and de La Bouglise which has been rumoured of late,
                        nothing is yet known at the head office in Cairo. Maltre Carton de Wiart the
                        company's legal adviser, is expected back in a few days and it is hoped that
                        with his advent everything will be arranged to enable the Société des
                        Sucreries to continue its career, and this hope we most sincerely endorse,
                        as much in the interest of the shareholders as in that of the fellaheen, who
                        supply the cane for the factories. We may add that if the concordat is
                        granted the names of Sir Elwin Palmer, Harari Pasha, and probably M.
                        Dubourg, a French gentleman well known in Cairo, will be submitted as
                        liquidators. It would, in oar opinion, be impossible to make a better
                        choice.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="councilMinisters"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
                    <p>The Council of Ministers, meeting on the 7th inst. at San Stefano, declared
                        the following undertakings to be of public utility :- The construction of
                        light railway lines, from Kuesfa to Minet el Gamh in the Sharkieh and
                        Dakhalieh provinces, and from Sakha to Sidi Salem in Gharbieh province. The
                        construction of a branch line between Nag Hamadi and the Nile in Keneh
                        province. The bridging of the Ibrahimieh canal, Assiout province, at the
                        three villages of Manfalout, Narali Ganouleh and Beni Korreh. Other
                        decisions deal with the expropriation etc. of land, and do not possess any
                        great public interest</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE CAPTAIN REES.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of Captain Rees, chief signaller at Kom-el Nadours, took place at
                        9.30 am. this morning. The funeral service was held at St. Mark’s Church,
                        the Rev. R. Wormell, M.A.,officiating. The coffin was then taken to the
                        cemetery, the bearers for part of the way being European employés at the
                        signal station. H.B.M’s Vice-Consul, Sir R M. Blomfield, Mr. Sergeant of the
                        Khedivial Mail S.S. Co., Mr. Percy Smith, of the Prince S.S. Line, Mr.
                        Roberta, Mr. Orsi, representing Lloyd’s Agency, and many others were present
                        at the red ceremony, with a guard of honor con- sisting of about twenty
                        tailors of the Porta and Lights Administration and the Khedivial Mail S.S
                        Co.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONSULAR REPORTS ON EGYPT. PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>In his report on the trade of Port Said in 1904 Mr. Cameron, after giving
                        tables of exports and imports, to some of which we will revert later,
                        remark* that the ohief point of interest in the export tables is the steady
                        increase of the quantity of cotton exported. In 1901 8,066 kantars of a
                        value of LE. 5,246 left Port Said and Ismailia. The export increased
                        enormously in 1902, and in 1904 amounted no less than 89,480 kantars valued
                        at L.E. 244,790. This cotton came from the Sharkieh province, being brought
                        from Zsgazig, as a rule, down the sweet-water canal to Ismailia and being
                        then put on board steamers on Lake Timsah. An increase of rolling stock and
                        the opening of the new boat service across Lake Menzaleh will probably bring
                        cotton to Port said in quantities sufficient to justify shippers in
                        chartering steamers, many of which would be available after discharging coal
                        at the port. The total import trade of Port Said in 1904 amounted in value
                        to LE. 1,869,290. Turkey with a trade of LE. 466,490 was the leading
                        contributer, followed by the United Kingdom (L E. 287.280) and France (LE.
                        197,200). We need not inform our readers that almost the whole export trade
                        of Palestine, Syria, and Southern Asia Minor comes to Port Said, which
                        explains the preponderance of Ottoman imports, which at first sight is a
                        little perplexing. Coal imports showed an increase of some 70,000 tons, and
                        the author of the report notes the increased proportion of German coal in
                        that supplied by the Deutsches Kohlen Deput of Bremen to the principal
                        German lines of steamers in transit Of the exports in 1904 some 55 % went to
                        the United Kingdom, Germany with about 31 % coming second. In discussing the
                        future of the port, Mr. Cameron makes the following interesting re marks
                        -.—“With the opening of the ordinary gauge government railway on June 1,
                        1904, a new ere of prosperity has begun for Port Said. The journey to Cairo
                        has been -shortened to fire hours and the number of daily trains has been
                        increased both for goods and passengers, thus enabling the town to cope with
                        the large and increasing demands of the traffic in connection with the
                        thousands of tourists who pass through Port Said in the winter season.
                        Another important project is approaching completion ; the New Egyptian and
                        the Men-xaleh Canal and Navigation Companies have obtained a concession for
                        making a deep and wide channel across the shallow water of Lake Menzalaeh,
                        in order to establish a daily service of steam ferry boats of shallow
                        draught between Kharputi (Port Said) and Matarieh, the eastern point of the
                        fertile district of Mansou-rah rah. The journey would take about throe
                        hours, and in co-operation with the light railway which has its termination
                        at Matarieh, this proposed route across the lake ought to prove of the
                        greatest value in connecting Port Said with the interior of the Delta.” In
                        discusing the transit of belligerent vessels, during the war that has just
                        closed, Mr. Cameron states that the total Russian force that passed through
                        the canal amounted to three battleships, three coast defence ships, seven
                        cruisers, eleven destroyers and seventeen transports. Very few merchantmen
                        were actually detained by their passage, and those that were detained at
                        Suez when homeward bound, were granted extra facilities through the canal on
                        the following day. The work of deepening the canal progresses steadily, as
                        may be shown by the increase of the maximum draught allowed. Till the end of
                        1901 this did not exceed 95 feet 7 inches. On January 1901, the maximum
                        draught was raised to 8 metres (26 feet 3 inches) and on January 1 1906 it
                        will be raised to 27 feet On the same date the tariff for laden ships will
                        be reduced to 7 francs 75 c. The conclusions at which the author arrives re
                        British shipping are very satisfactory. The percentage of British vessels
                        using the canal has risen from 56 percent, in 1901 to 63-2per cent in 1904,
                        and their net tonnage from 57-8 per cent in 1901 to 65.9 per cent. last
                        year. These figures apply only to the general total of 4,937 vessels ; but
                        if we consider only mer-chant vessels, the British percentages have risen
                        daring the last four years from 67 to 74 per cent in number and from 71 to
                        76 per cent in net tonnage, or three-quarters of the mercantile traffic of
                        the Canal. During the last three years the percentages of German vessels
                        have been 12-9 per cent in 1902, 13-1 per cent in 1903 and 19-8 per cent in
                        1904 ; and of their net tonnage 15-2 per cent in 1909, 14 9 in 1903 and 14-7
                        in 1904. France, the Netherlands, Norway. Austria-Hungary, and Italy
                        combined furnish a total of 10.5 per cent of the vessels and 8.7 per cent,
                        of the tonnage These facts are reassuring, and show that the British
                        mercantile marine is more than holding its own in the Canal traffic. A proof
                        of this may be seen in the table of the great companies which use the Canal
                        Of these 40, 27 are British, 5 German, 3 French, 9 Dutch, and 1 each
                        Autro-Hunga-rian, Italian, and Spanish.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL. Restaurant.</head>
                    <p>Table d'Hete Luncheons and Dinners served on the Terrace ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO
                        11.30 PM </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SMYRNA CONSPIRACY. THE DISCOVERY OF BOMBS.</head>
                    <p>The "Eastern Press,” an Armenian weekly paper, published in Smyrna, gives the
                        following details of the discovery of bombs in that city Thanks to the
                        vigilance of the Governor of Smyrna, H.E. Kiamil Pasha, the Armenian
                        revolutionary movement was detected before any great harm had been done, and
                        what promised to become a series of bomb outrages has been checked. The
                        police, who had discovered the meeting place of the revolutionaries,
                        surrounded the house, which is situated in the Greek quarter, Tabahine, but
                        word had reached the conspirators, and they managed to escape. The house was
                        however, searched by the police, and eighty large bombs, with chemicals and
                        apparatus, and three clock-work wore found on the premises. All of there
                        were seized and taken to the palace for examination. Several searches were
                        subsequently made in houses in the St. Dimitri Greek quarter, and several
                        person* were arrested on suspicion of having manufactured these infernal
                        machines. A spatial committee, under the presidency of Kiamil Pasha, has
                        been appointed to con-duct investigations into the characters of inspected
                        persons and to march houses. One hundred and eighty persons have been
                        arrested up to the present, but eighty of there were released after being
                        examined. The reports appearing in the Athens papers describing the arrest
                        of two thousand are grossly exaggerated. As the result of the investigations
                        it is con-oluded that the movement is entirely a revo-lutionary one
                        instigated by Armenians from other countries and that they hope to excite
                        the sympathy of their fellow countrymen in Smyrna by this means, but the
                        Armenians here are, as a rule, loyal subjects of the Sultan. The people can
                        rest assured that the Government will do all in their power to put a stop to
                        this state of affairs and restore the normal tranquillity of the city. The
                        assassin of the late Baliozian has been hung as an example to other
                        plotters. The number of police agents has been increased by fifty, so that
                        the work of checking attempt* at outrage may be more effectively carried
                        out. Many of them bare left for the villages inland by special train
                        accompanied by the chief of the police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NILE FLOOD.</head>
                    <p>The condition of the Nile flood has improved distinctly in the last month,
                        and though it cannot be regarded as a high Nile, the readings of the various
                        gauges, which we receive, do not compare unfavorably with those of last
                        year. In some cases higher readings are shown, whilst in others they are
                        somewhat lower, but the difference in no instance is remarkable. The
                        measures which have been taken by the Ministry of Public Works will happily,
                        avert any danger of the country suffering from a shortage of crops and the
                        perfection to which the irrigation of the country has been brought is of
                        great credit to Sir William Garstin, Mr. Webb, Mr. Verschoyle, and their
                        subor-dinates.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>We are glad to be able to report that Mr. Rowland Snelling, editor and
                        manager of the "Egyptian Gazette” is making rapid strides towards a complete
                        recovery, and is expected to return to Egypt early in October at the
                        latest.</p>
                    <p>M. A. Chelu Bey left for Marseilles yesterday by the M M. Senegal</p>
                    <p>A contemporary announces that M. Charles Labusiere, formerly agent of the
                        Messageries Maritimes S.S. Co., in Cairo, has been made Knight of the Legion
                        of Honor.</p>
                    <p>Mr. J. Caftari left for Europe yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The following visitors are staying at the Beau-Rivage Hotel Ramleh : Mr. and
                        Mrs. John Bell, Major and Mrs. W.H. Rotheram, Mr. and Mrs. Nicolas Bey
                        Boutros, Mr. and Mrs. H. Nacghton, Mr. R. Dracopoulos, Miss W. Sells, Mire L
                        Crowther, H Khaloussi Bey, M. Refand Bey, Mr. and Mrs. M.. Materia, Miss L
                        Stevens, Mme N. Rhally, Miss F. Scholthausen, Miss R Tedeschi, Mr. and Mrs.
                        H. Dasso, Mr. and Mrs LM. Ades and family, Mr. G. Métrai Mr. P.
                        Denerias.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>Passenger List</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot Sénégal des Messageries Maritimes parti hier pour Marseille avait
                        a bord : M.M. A. Cbelu Bey.Moh. Amin. Mme J. P. Davies, lient Langlois,
                        lient Leodos.. Sami Torudini, R. P. Domon. B. P. Bernard,Bourget, Sohambrial
                        Soné, Penaud et Nou risse, Cbelu Bey fiU, Loub Favre Ameen G Korenm,
                        Bourgeois, Boyaub J. B.. Caffari, Mire L. Osman, Sednaoui. Stephany, Mme
                        Gaty, R.P. Guitton, Bonot San ton, de Belinay, Gaillard et Dallai Frère G.
                        Lallemand, Axkdaki, Emile Fanons, Axis Ibrahim et 31 passengers de se et 4e
                        classes.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="chroniqueFinanciere"><head>CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE</head>
                    <p>La conclusion de la paix ruaso-japonaise avait deja amené la banne et
                        l’activité dans les bonnes da monde sotisr, lorsque la krach des Sucreries
                        est venu soudain démoraliser la spéculation, particulièrement à Paris et en
                        Egypte Le marasme et b réaction ont auasiu.t succédé à l’animation naisante.
                        Les valanrs étrangère. ribs-reérecs en out subi le contrecoup Comme la
                        publie égyptien ne s est guère engagé dans les Sucreries qu’à partir du
                        cours da 170 jusqu’à 990 pour se faire une moyenne lorsque la prix est tombé
                        à 150, on évalue les pertes subies ici à deux ou trois cent y'iu livras.
                        Plusieurs banques en ont raresati la leooores, mais oomma la presque
                        totalité de leur clients sont solvables, il leur suffire de prendre patience
                        pour rentrer dan* leurs fonds, Il va sans dire qu’avec une liquidation
                        fotoée las actionnaires n trouveraient rectifiée, qu'avec la oonoordat
                        préventif, que tout le monda repère, les ohosas s' arrangeront au mieux dre
                        intérêts non reniement des actionnaires mais encore de tout le marché. qui
                        dans. ce cas ne tardera pas à se relever. Les Banques continuent à faire
                        qualques difficultés pour accorder des avances sur titres, la saison
                        cotonnière s'annon cant comma excep-tionnellement favorable. L’Agricole
                        ouvre à U 1/32, atteint 14 7/16 pour retomber vers la fin à 14 5/16
                        achetaurs. De 9 9/16 la Nouvelle flechit à 9 1/2. L’ex-right monte de 9
                        13/16 à 9 29/32 pour revenir à 9 13/16 en clôture. Comme avant la nouvelle
                        émission l’Agricole était à 11 £, nombre de spéculateurs trouvent que le
                        prix de 10 ou 10 1/2 n’au rait en oe moment rien d'exagéré. Si, en effet, le
                        Capital action a été doublé, la capital obligation* l’a été également. II
                        n’y a donc rien de changé dans la situation antérieure, da nature à
                        justifier la bas prix actuel et il y a tout lieu da croire qu’une poussee
                        s'effectuera à la rentrée des capitalistes d’Europe. De 27 1/2 la Banque
                        Nationale hausse à 97 8/4 pour retomber an cluture à 27 6/8. L'éoart entre
                        la nouvelle et l’aneiame au profit da celle-ci, passe da 1/8 à 8/16 et ne
                        tardera pas à prendre dre proportions plus importantes A Londres la National
                        est toujours en faveur à 27 3/4. Les Actions Crédit Foncier fléchissent de
                        891 à 816 pour reprendre à 890, aveo à la hausse. Après avoir fléchi un
                        moment de 180 à 178, la Came di Soonto ne tarde pas à ne relever jusqu'à
                        183. La Banque d'Athènes fluctue entre 127 1/9 et 198 et clôture ferme à 197
                        1/9. De très importantes transactions plusieurs milliers par jour, ont eu
                        lieu en Estates à un oours variant da 1 7/32 à 1 9/32. Ia clôture a'effectue
                        à 1 1/4 acheteure. De plus hants prix sont an perspective. Le Trust art
                        également en bonne tendance à 1 8/8 vendeurs. Pa oontre, l'Investment est.
                        plutôt faible Le cours tombe de 1 9/32 à 1 7/32 pour finir kl 1/4
                        D'excellentes affaires auraient été, dit-on, faites per la New Egyptien,
                        dont la prix hausse de 31/ à 33/9 pour finir è 33 acheteurs, aveotendance à
                        la hausse. La Salt and Soda monte de 34/6 à 35/3 et cloture à 35. La Markets
                        sont très soutenus entre 24/1 1/2 et 24/4 1/2 prix auquel on clôture
                        acheteurs. La peste bovine étant sur le point de disparaître du pays, on dit
                        que la réouverture des marchés à bestiaux ne serait plu qu'une De 5/4 la
                        Cotton Mills remontent à 5/10 1/2 et 6. On clôture à 5/9 acheteurs.Les Eaux
                        du Caire fléchissent de 1175 à 1165. La Behera réactionne également da 43
                        1/2 à 49 1/2 sans transactions. Après-avoir fléchi de 6 1/4 a 5 3/16,
                        l’Uihaias remonta à 6 11/22 en clôture. Tandis que U Nungovieh tombe de 10
                        7/16 à 10 5/16 l’Upper Egypt monte da 5 1/16 à 5 3/16. Il convient cependant
                        dire que le cours est inférieur de 1/8 pou cette derniere valeur, si b prix
                        de l’action est intégralment versé. L'Anglo American Nile est ferme a 5 1/2.
                        La Khédivial Mail Ordinary monta de 90/6 à 22/- en clôture. De 213 b Crown
                        Brewery reprend rare la fin à 220. Après avoir repris un moment de 27 1/2 à
                        27 7/8 la Daira retombe en clôtnre à 27 5/8. En somme, ou derniers jours
                        n’ont pu été suai brillante que b faisait entrevoir b oon otosion de b paix,
                        mais comme b ceua de cette situation provient nniquemaut du Krach des
                        Suoreriss, une reprise est certaine dès que les premières difficultés auront
                        été surmontées.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>(Auiourd i midi d demie)</p>
                    <p>Ce matin notre marché est beaoooop mieux sou tou les rapporte. Ia plupart des
                        valeur* •ont en hausse et ont donné ben à un mouvement arecs actif. On
                        aohète b National Bank à 97 6/8 l’an-etane rt 971/9 b nouvelle, et b Delta
                        Iigfatà 18 5/16. Las Estâtes gagnent toujours du tanin at sont plu que
                        jamais recherchés à 1 1/4. Les noüvelles sont excellentes. Les actions
                        Crédit Foncier s'avancait de 817 à 890,l’Agricole de U 3/16 à 14 3/8, b
                        Banque d'Athènes de 197 .1/9 à 199 1/4, b New-Egyptien da 32/3 à 33/3
                        l’Ordinary Khédivial Mail à 22/3. b Privilégiée Tramways d’Alexandrie de 160
                        à 161 et b Ramleh Raüway de 7 1/16 à 7 8/16 acheteurs Par contre, les
                        Markets fléehisreut de 24/6 h 24/3 et b Daim de 97 5/8 à 27 19/39. Un reeul
                        aanribb a lieu pour las Sucruies de 52 a 46 ; le cours reaetienne également
                        a Paris jusqu'à 51.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
