<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kedric Heyward</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-30">November 30, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-23">June 23, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7222] ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, JUNE 23, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>"DOWN WITH DESPOTISM." RUSSIAN WORKMEN’S DEMONSTRATION. BRUTALITY OF COSSACKS.</head>
                    <p>Lodz, June 22. A great demonstration of workmen has taken place here to
                        protest against the brutality of the Cossacks. 50,000 men paraded the
                        streets shouting, "Down with Despotism !” Suddenly the Cossacks and Dragoons
                        rushed out of side Streets and, fired a volley on the crowd, which they
                        dispersed. There were 18 killed and 100 wounded. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMENIAN MASSACRES. MOSLEMS DEVASTATING VILLAGES.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 22. 37,000 Moslem insurgents are devastating Armenian
                        villages in the Nakhitchevan district of the province of Erivan, and are
                        committing terrible atrocities. One village repulsed the attack, killing
                        100. A force of troops besieged in another beat off the insurgents, and took
                        870 prisoners.5,000 Cossacks are proceeding from Baku to the troubled
                        districts. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 22. Massacres and atrocities are reported from various
                        localities of the Erivan province. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSO-JAPANESE WAR. JAPS OCCUPY KANSONG.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, June 22. A Japanese detachment in the north of Korea completely
                        occupied Kangsong last Tuesday. Some thousands of Russians, with artillery,
                        retired towards Siou-song, 12 miles northward. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN STEAMER STOPPED BY RUSSIAN CRUISER.</head>
                    <p>Sydney, June 22. The Russian cruiser “Dnieper” stopped the German S.S. “Prinz
                        Sigisimund” to the North of Luzon on the 1st inst., and after haying
                        examined her papers, permitted her to continue her course. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PEACE NEGOTIATIONS. THE RUSSIAN PLENIPOTENTIARY.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 22. M. Nelidoff has definitely been chosen as Russian
                        plenipotentiary. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION. FRENCH NOTE TO GERMANY.</head>
                    <p>Paris, June 22. It is understood that M. Rouvier has handed a note to Prince
                        Radolin, declaring that France is disposed to accept a conference with
                        regard to Morocco, but she must first know the points which are to be
                        considered. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, June 22. M. Rouvier has handed the note on Morocco to Prince Radolin.
                        In this note M. Rouvier neither accepts nor declines the conference. He
                        confines himself to setting forth the situation. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ITALIAN NAVY. INCREASED ESTIMATES APPROVED.</head>
                    <p>Rome, June 22. The announcement that the Chamber had rejected the increased
                        Navy Estimates was wrong ; as a matter of fact it approved them.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREEK CABINET CRISIS. DISSOLUTION PROBABLE.</head>
                    <p>Athens, June 22. The negotiations with M. Ralli for the reconstruction of the
                        Cabinet have failed, owing to the Ministers insisting on carrying out the
                        programme of M. Delyannis unchanged. The ministers have resigned and M.
                        Ralli is form-ing a new Cabinet A dissolution is probable. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LOSS OF THE A8. DECISION OF COURT-MARTIAL.</head>
                    <p>London, June 22 The court-martial held on the survivors of the submarine A8
                        has decided that she foundered through an unexplained alteration in her
                        buoyancy. It is regretted that the commanding officer did not stop the
                        engine sooner, but the officers and survivors are acquitted and exonerated
                        of all blame. (Reuter )</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN COTTON CROP. ESTIMATES OF YEILDS.</head>
                    <p>New Orleans, June 23. The reports of correspondents of the South ern Cotton
                        Association indicate that the new crop will be 10,285;876 commercial bales.
                        The leading American Bolls predict 9,500,000. (R)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH SILK CUSTOMS DUES.</head>
                    <p>Paris, June 22. The French Chamber has postponed the consideration of the
                        increase in Custom dues (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Khalifa district of Cairo daring
                            the night of Saturday and at daylight on Sunday will be poisoned by the
                            police. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>9 vessels passed through the Canal on the 20th inst., of which 6 were
                            British 2 German, 1 Dutch. The receipts for the day wore frs.
                            285,468.67, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 5,406,695.82.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The GHIRGEH Scandal</head>
                        <p>The Procureur-General has concluded his report on the Ghirgeh case, which
                            he will submit to the Ministry of the Interior, the Adviser of that
                            department, and the Judicial Adviser.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>We are asked by the management of the Casino to remind members of the
                            club that they must show their membership cards at the entrance on the
                            occasion of the night fete on Saturday. Entrance to the club will be
                            strictly reserved to members and their families.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records two fatal cases at Alexandria, the victims
                            being a native workman at Kom el Shougafa and a Dative boy at Abou
                            Choucha. Both cases were bubonic and the victims were found dead in
                            their houses. A case is reported from Damanhour and a recovery from Mit
                            Ghamr.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Eden Theatre</head>
                        <p>There was a large audience at this theatre last night to witness the
                            marvellous performance by Prof. de Lafon-taine and his Creole mediums,
                            the public being thoroughly mystified by the achievements of the latter.
                            The entertainment consisted of mental suggestion and thought-reading,
                            and is well worth a visit to the theatre. A second seance will be given
                            on Sunday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fire at Tantah</head>
                        <p>At about 2.30 p.m. on Wednesday a fire broke out near Al Khan-street,
                            Tantah. The fire brigade quickly appeared on the scene and under the
                            able guidance of Amin Eff., Tantah city mulahiz,. succeeded in
                            preventing any serious extension of the conflagration. As it was, the
                            damage done probably amounts to £500. The Moudir of Gharbieh and the
                            Mamour of Tantah arrived before the fire was got under, and helped in
                            the work of extinguishing the flames. An enquiry failed to ascertain the
                            cause of the outbreak, which was probably attributable to the practice
                            of using so much dry stalk and weed in covering the wooden roofs of
                            houses.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Motor Car Accident in Cairo</head>
                        <p>Between half-past twelve (midnight) and one o’olock on Wednesday morning
                            a native woman was run over by the large motor-omnibus of the Brasseries
                            des Pyramides in Cairo and killed. The omnibus was returning from its
                            nightly excursion to Ghizeh and as it approached the corner of
                            Boulac-street, which leads into Tewfikieh-square, a group of three
                            native men and three women was observed, and they all appeared to be
                            more or less in a state of intoxication. As the omnibus drew nearer one
                            of the women went into the middle of the road and began to dance. The
                            chauffeur immediately slowed down and tried to avoid running into her,
                            but one of the lamps caught the woman’s head and threw her down. The
                            machine passed over her, killing her on the spot.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>A writer in the “Daily News” says “1 have been told that Lord Cromer is one
                        of the most thorough students of the Bible whom we have among public men.
                        Probably the Old Testament has a special interest for him, seeing that he
                        has such a wide knowledge of Egypt Thirty-three years ago he became private
                        secretary to the late Earl of Northbrook, and he was also a deep student of
                        the Bible. One of Lord Northbrook’s tasks in bis later years was the
                        publication of a small book entitled “The Teaching of Jesus Christ in His
                        Own Words,” which was intended to be a special help to the natives of India,
                        for whose welfare he had such sympathy ever since he had held the office of
                        Viceroy."</p>
                    <p>Major C. J. L. Davidson, D. S. O., 2nd Battalion R. Inniskilling Fusiliers,
                        has been granted leave of absence for three months.</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will take p'ace at the end of this year,
                        between Miss Marguerite Nungovich, eldest, daughter of George Nungovich Bey
                        of Cairo, and Captain R. C. Wilson, R.A.M.C., son of R. J. Wilson, Esq.,
                        Dublin.</p>
                    <p>The British Embassy at Constantinople has moved in the matter of the
                        arbitrary arrest at Beyront of Mobi Eldine Bey Hamada.</p>
                    <p>Mr. A. Gamsaragan has contributed P.T. 100 to the funds of the Rudolph Asile
                        in memory of the late Mlle Marie-Antoniette Valadien</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="section" element="councilMinisters"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS. YESTERDAY’S DECISIONS.</head>
                    <p>A Council of Ministers was held yesterday at the San Stefano Casino, under
                        the presidency of H. E. Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, the Regent.</p>
                    <p>Among other decisions come to was that concerning the increase of the fees at
                        all the Government schools except the primary schools of Esneh, Edfou, and
                        Assouan, and the redaction of the period of study at the secondary schools
                        from four to three years. The fees in the primary schools will be raised
                        from L.E. 5 to L.E. 6 for day scholars and L E. 8 to L.E. 10 for
                        half-boarders. In the secondary schools the fees will be increased from L.E.
                        30 to L.E. 40 for boarders and from L.E. 20 to L.E. 25 for Mansourah school,
                        from L.E. 15 to L.E.20 for the Khedivial Law School, and from L.E. 15 to
                        L.E. 25 for the Sanieh school (boarders) and from L.E. 7 1/2 to L.E. 13 1/2
                        (day-scholars).</p>
                    <p>It was decided to suppress the primary education certificate and replace it
                        by a certificate of aptitude for Government service. The minimum salary of
                        Government employes in possession of superior diplomas was fixed at L.E.
                        12.</p>
                    <p>It was decided to convoke the provincial councils of Beni Souef and Minieh
                        for the 2nd and 3rd July next, for the purpose of approving the creation of
                        agricultural roads in these provinces.</p>
                    <p>It was decided to bring three professors from Europe (one French and two
                        English) for the Khedivial Law School.</p>
                    <p>The note of the Ministry of Public Instruction asking for the addition of
                        L.E. 40,000 to the budget for 1906 of this Department will be submitted to
                        the next Cabinet Council.</p>
                    <p>The following decrees were passed :—</p>
                    <p>A decree with reference to the regulations as to the irrigation of ‘Sharaki’
                        which will be put into force immediately after insertion in the “Journal
                        Officiel.”</p>
                    <p>A decree referring to measures to be taken against rabies.</p>
                    <p>Decrees for the appropriation of land at Melig, Menoufieh, for the
                        construction of the El Gori Masraf, and for prolonging the dyke from the
                        Government Hospital to Wabour Hamza Boy El Tokhi at Mansourah, the dyke to
                        be used as an agricultural road.</p>
                    <p>Other decrees deal with the modification of the regulations dealing with
                        motors at Alexandria, the recognition of a company to be known as the
                        “Financial and Commercial Company,” and the construction of cemeteries in
                        Dakahlieh and Behera provinces.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive is expected to arrive at Divonne for his annual cure on
                        Sunday next.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL LAW SCHOOL.</head>
                    <p>We learn from our Arabic contemporaries that the Ministry of Public
                        Instruction, having great difficulty in finding a competent successor to
                        Omar Bey Loutfi to teach the Penal Code in the Khedivial Law School, has
                        decided that-the instruction on this subject shall henceforth be given in
                        French and English.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A NEW BIG BUILDING PROJECT.</head>
                    <p>The Caisse Hypothecaire d’Egypte purchased a short time ago a property
                        consisting of 20 feddans of land at Mahmashah, a suburb of Cairo situated at
                        about one kilometre from the central station at Bab el-Hadid, a part of the
                        land fronting the Ismailieh canal. The price paid was close upon £1,600 the
                        feddan, or about P.T. 37 to P.T. 40 the square metre. The company has now
                        laid out the whole property in plots tor building and has made two fine
                        boulevards and several streets through it Several of the sites have been
                        sold at prices ranging from P.T. 45 to P.T. 120 per metre, so that when the
                        whole of the plots are disposed of the company will have reaped a handsome
                        profit on the investment. There is already a carriage road from the railway
                        station to Mahmashah, but when the new Abbas boulevard is completed there
                        will be another fine approach from that direction.</p>
                    <p>The place is considered exceedingly healthy, and it is likely to become a
                        favorite residential suburb, on account of its proximity to the city.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WORK FOR THE NILE.</head>
                    <p>The success of the Assouan reservoir, which was completed in 1902, has turned
                        people’s attention to the question of the practicability of some
                        comprehensive scheme which would settle the irrigation needs of Egypt once
                        for all. The irrigable area of the country, according to “Engineering,” is 6
                        1/4 million acres, and an ample supply of water is at hand in the Nile
                        without diminishing the navigability of the river, provided that the
                        superfluous flood-water is stored for use in the dry season. A quarter of a
                        million acres lying along the edge of the deserts must remain only irrigated
                        in flood time, as at present, as otherwise the desert sand would encroach
                        upon the fertile valley. Four million acres are now perennially irrigated,
                        and have an average value of 55l. par acre. The remaining two million acres
                        remain to be dealt with.Two-thirds of this area are only irrigated in flood,
                        and the remainder not irrigated at all. These two million acres have a mean
                        value of 25l. per acre ; but if they were perennially irrigated their value
                        would bo raised at once to 55l. per acre—an increase of 60,000,000l. in the
                        wealth of the country.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL ROBBERY. STORY OF THE THEFT.</head>
                    <p>The Parquet is still occupied with the Mahmal theft, and in the meantime
                        specula tion is rife as to how the theft was committed It is supposed by
                        many that this daring act of robbery was performed whilst the train was
                        travelling from Cairo to Suez and that Androus Meloka leaped on to the foot
                        board whilst the train was running at or about full-speed, broke the seals,
                        opened the door with a master-key with which he had provided himself and
                        having obtained his booty, jumped off again and re joined his accomplices.
                        Such a supposition certainly lends colour to the telling of the story, and
                        imparts to ita greater degree of sensationalism, but we are inclined to
                        think that snob feats of agility are only performed by heroes of
                        “penny-dreadfuls,” and we would offer a much simpler and more probable
                        solution to the problem of the mode of committal of the theft.</p>
                    <p>Before the train from which the money was stolen left for Suez it was drawn
                        up at Abbassieh station, where it received its load of baggage, including
                        the boxes of gold and papers. These boxes were placed at one end of the van
                        in three rows of 7, 7, and 5, respectively, and two others were placed a
                        little apart and to one side, one of these latter two containing tickets and
                        papers and the other one £3,700 in gold. The doors of the van were locked
                        and sealed, the train was shunted on to a parallel line, leaving another
                        line between the train and the platform, and one solitary soldier was left
                        to guard its treasure for the several hours whioh elapsed before its
                        departure for Cairo. On one side of the train was this sentinel, on the
                        other nothing but the wooden shanties of platelayers, and it was from this
                        side that the entrance was effected. The thief had doubtless obtained a key
                        of the van and therefore no difficulty presented itself : he had but to
                        break the seal, open the door, and walk in ; so long as he did not disturb
                        the sentinel, he was safe and had apparently no difficulty in performing his
                        task in silence. When he had got inside the van he went about his work with
                        cunning, and selected a box from the middle of the second row of seven,
                        twisting the two adjacent boxes round so that they almost occupied the space
                        of the three, and a cursory glance would not detect the fact that one box
                        was missing.</p>
                    <p>Such is our solution of the way in which the theft was committed, and though
                        we do not assert it as a positive fact, it is certainly the most probable
                        solution, as well as the simplest The police themselves have not yet
                        discovered where the robbery took place. The question naturally arises as to
                        why one sentinel was left alone to guard a train containing such a sum of
                        money, and why the authorities had not sufficient foresight to recognize
                        that one man cannot keep watch over both sides of a train at the same time,
                        and we ask these questions ourselves. Doubtless the van will be properly
                        guarded in future years, but it is certainly a ease of locking the stable
                        door after the mare has been stolen.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KAFR ZAYAT RAILWAY ACCIDENT.</head>
                    <p>Our Kafr Zayat Correspondent writes The accident at Tewfikieh is now known to
                        have been caused by the carelessness of a gang. Orders had been given to the
                        effect that two hours were to be spent on “renewing” the up line near
                        Tewfikieh station and that the up and down lines were to be connected by a
                        switch taking off Dear the bridge S. of the station. The foreman of the
                        gang, after working on the down line near the bridge to get his points in,
                        did not screw down the bolts properly. The down train tore up the track and
                        appears to have actually crossed the bridge on the sleepers. Under the
                        circumstances the escape of the passengers from a fall into the canal was
                        literally providential.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL BREACH OF PROMISE CASE.</head>
                    <p>An action for breach of promise of marriage was decided yesterday at Cairo
                        before the Tribunal Sommaire, presided over by Judge Wierdels. The
                        plaintiff, a young French lady who keeps an establishment in the Sharia
                        Manakh, sued a Belgian gentleman, an engineer, for breaking off a
                        matrimonial engagement of some months’ duration, and claimed one franc
                        damages, assigning as a reason for the smallness of the sum that she merely
                        wished to obtain judgment against her faithless lover and to let the world
                        know of his base action.</p>
                    <p>The defendant, on receiving the citation of the court, had at once tendered
                        the frano claimed through his lawyer, and offered to defray the lady’s legal
                        expenses, amounting to P.T. 150. The offer being indignantly declined the
                        two sums were deposited at the greffier’s office and the case was pleaded a
                        fortnight ago, the plaintiff being represented by Maitre Guelhanmon, and the
                        defendant by Maitre Neghib Ayoub, who in a long and able speech proved to
                        the satisfaction of the Court that the young lady had sustained no
                        prejudice, neither material nor moral, by the action of his client.</p>
                    <p>The presiding judge gave judgment for the defendant and condemned the young
                        lady to pay costs. As the amount of the claim was only one franc there is no
                        appeal against this decision.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. “Syrian Prince,” from Manchester, left Malta on Thursday and is due
                        Here on Monday next with passengers and general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ON THE HEDJAZ RAILWAY </head><byline>BY P.P.G. III.</byline>
                    <p>The methods of agriculture employed to Haurani folk are primitive enough but
                        the soil, decomposed volcante rock, is excellent and only requires water to
                        be productive. There is practically no irrigation in the whole district, and
                        the farmers depend on the white and spring rains, which are usually heavy
                        enough to ensure a good harvest in the summer. Last winter and the early
                        spring of the present year were most favorable to the growers, though they
                        were not in the least appreciated by the poor reservists who went down to
                        Ma’an in open trucks.</p>
                    <p>From the tailboard of the carriage. I got a wide view of the country on both
                        sides of the line. Here and there were rooky districts where grey boulders
                        were scattered over the plain and thistles flourished. But as a rule the
                        country was one great green expanse, flanked by low yellow hills on the side
                        of the Jordan, by a formidable chain of black mountains to the east. At the
                        foot of the range was a dark broken region that gradually neared the line.
                        When we were within six or seven miles of it I could see that it was a
                        chaotic maze of rooks and defiles, dull and black, barely dusted with green
                        in a few areas where, I suppose, there were springs or water-holes. “That is
                        the Leja,” said the A.D.C., and added that the country was most difficult
                        for campaigning— which was fairly obvious. He had taken part in the Druse
                        war when fighting took place all over the Hauran and the Leja was the hiding
                        place of large numbers of Druses, who inflicted heavy losses on the Ottoman
                        troops before they had to succumb to forces that were much superior in
                        strength. Their losses were very heavy—a large proportion of their fighting
                        men being killed or wounded—but the women and children appear to have been
                        little molest ed by the Turks proper, though I expect their Circassian and
                        Bedouin auxiliaries were less humane.</p>
                    <p>Running in a south-easterly direction the railway soon neared the edge of the
                        Leja. The contrast between the country on the east and west of the line was
                        most remarkable. On one side the ground was covered with reefs and boulders
                        for a couple of miles, and then the lava plateau rose some 50 feet above the
                        plain and extended for miles eastward like a petrified sea.To the west lay
                        the corn land stretching at least twenty miles, flat and green, its monotony
                        only broken by an occasional village or one of the trim little red roofed
                        stations of the French Damascus-Mzerib line. The villages-seemed substantial
                        enough : they were built of black lava blocks instead of mud, and their
                        walls were strong enough, if well defended, to repel attack. It is not so
                        long since the Bedonint used to raid the villages of the Hauran plain; and
                        the Druses, when they had a quarrel with the Government, were formidable
                        neighbours for the fellaheen.</p>
                    <p>The Leja is a huge triangle, its apex pointing almost due north, its base
                        line running some 30 miles from west to east. At Ezraa we reached its
                        western basal angle, where the rocks and ravines ran right up to the
                        railway, We had a short wait here and I was able to see something of the
                        plateau : beyond the barracks of the Turkish battalion stationed here and
                        the sombre black village, lay a maze of rock, seamed with gullies and
                        depressions, broken here and there into deep clefts with precipitous sides.
                        No country is better adapted for guerilla warfare : water exists in the Leja
                        but it is hard to find : troops are ambushed in the ravines and are sniped
                        at night from cliffs which they cannot scale, while the undulating broken
                        ground enables even swordsmen to come to close quarters. Every army that has
                        fought here has paid a heavy toll : even Ibrahim Pasha failed to reduce a
                        few thousand Druses, and lost 12,000 men in the attempt, and it was only by
                        the process of attrition that the Turks finally subjugated the district in
                        the Hauran War.</p>
                    <p>Happily the relations between Druse and Turks are now improving, thanks to
                        the conciliatory attitude of Nazim Pasha, the excellent Wali of Damascus,
                        though the Druses continue to arm themselves with the best modern rifles to
                        an extent that suggests the possibility of further trouble. (To be
                        continued)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <div type="item" xml:lang="fr">
                        <head>Departures.</head>
                        <p>Le paquebot “Perseo” de la Cie Florio Rubattino parti hier pour Messine
                            et Genes avait bord-:</p>
                        <p>M.M. E. Bargarella, Consolo et famile Raf. Rieti, Hage, Ing. et Mme
                            Stupenengo, Salv. Leoni, Alf. Foli, A. Greek et fam., Comm. Prampolino
                            et fils, M. et Mme Janni, A. Husson, fils Janui, C. Massiah et fils, Mme
                            V. Chiccico, Mlle Sciplini, C. Tkekerian, W. Borg, Stevens, Fam.
                            Tekerian, E. Coen, M. et Mme F. Lepori, Pere Goffredo, Mme I. Bircher et
                            bebe, Mme Gillibert, Taylor, Bat cheller, M. et Mme G. Pariente, A.
                            Hupeisen, Answell, Page, C. Frangini, Messulam, A. Strappafava, Mme
                            Fabricius pacha, M. Goldenthal, Mme Staticelli et fils, Prof.S.
                            Pollaroli, F. Feis, Sbigoli et fils. G. Aglietti, Mme Torani et fam., G.
                            Dagnino, S. Ramaz-zotti, N. Malousian, B. Halles, Mme Baerlacher, A.
                            Montano, Mme Daguino et fille, G. Conomo, M. et Mme Maggio Jarois, M. et
                            Mme Kamel Chehata, Leon Hallag, Elia Jabes, A. Mires, S. Iuglessi, Mlle
                            Thier, A. Faraoneet Mme Illiesko, Elie Ackaswolli, Mme Schmoltz et fam.,
                            Schulze et fam., Mme Uziel et 2 fils, Mme Perera, M. et Mme Shehcan bey,
                            Dr. et Mme Wilson, Comm. Moriondo, Mme Weiss, Merton, Wolkend et fam.,
                            Siletti, Eumes, Mme Wekerly, et 139 passagers de sme classe.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID</head>
                    <head>ARRIVAL OP BRITISH WARSHIPS.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent); Port Said Thursday, The first-class armoured
                        cruisers “Suffolk.” Capt. Beath D.S.O. and “Lan aster," Capt. H Loftus
                        Tottenham of the Essex” class arrived at Port Said this morning from Malta
                        and are now coaling. It is uncertain how long they will stay or what their
                        movements will be.</p>
                    <p>The former commander will be remembered as having been attached for some
                        years to the Nile flotilla, and the latter as commanding the “Furious,”
                        which vessel was stationed here some time during last year.</p>
                    <p>The battleships, “Goliath” and "Canopus," homeward bound, are expected to
                        arrive at Port Said next week, followed by four or five others from the
                        China station.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WEATHER</head>
                    <p>The weather here the last day or two has been unbearably hot and damp; strong
                        east erly winds all yesterday and khamseer today. The thermometer has
                        frequently registered as high as 104" F. in the shade.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" element="comingEvents">

                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>

                    <table cols="2" xml:id="deg-ta-coce01">

                        <row role="label">

                            <cell cols="2">ALEXANDRIA.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>June.</cell>

                            <cell/>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Fri. 22</cell>

                            <cell>Windsor Hotel Orchestra 6 to 11 pm.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Mex Prinea's Restaraunt des Bains. Roumattian orchesta, every
                                afternoon. Sundays morning.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Alhambra. Italian operetta company in <hi rend="italic">La
                                    Principessa di Trebisonda</hi>. 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Pyramids Theatre. Gatti's Circus Troupe. 9.15 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Sat. 24</cell>

                            <cell>A.C.C. Grounds. Cricket "Alexandria" "Cairo" 1.30 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Mustafa Rifle Range. Practice by B.R.C. 3p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>A.S.C Gymkhana 3.30 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Marina Alexandria Swimming Club members meet 4 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>San Stefano Venetian fete 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Sun. 25</cell>

                            <cell>San Stefano Cassino Concert at 10 a.m. and 5 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Eden Theatre Prof de Lafountaine Hypnotist 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Wed. 28</cell>

                            <cell>Khedieval Yatch Club Regatta</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>July Sat. 15</cell>

                            <cell>A.S.C Skye Meeting</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row role="label">

                            <cell cols="2">CAIRO</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>June.</cell>

                            <cell/>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Sat. 24</cell>

                            <cell>Theatre des Ambassadeurs. 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Theatre des Nouveautés. 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Esbekieh Theatre. Italian Comedy Company. 9 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>


                        <row>

                            <cell>Tues. 27</cell>

                            <cell>Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                                p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Fri. 30</cell>

                            <cell>Zoological Gardens. Performance by Ghizeh Boys’ Band in
                                afternoon.</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell/>

                            <cell>Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                                p.m</cell>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>July.</cell>

                            <cell/>

                        </row>

                        <row>

                            <cell>Sat. 8</cell>

                            <cell>Credit Foncier Eygiptian Extroidinary meeting 4 p.m.</cell>

                        </row>

                    </table>

                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">

                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>

                    <p>BREMEN.</p>

                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>

                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>

                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>

                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>

                </div>

                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">

                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>

                    <p>2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>

                    <p>22855-16.7</p>

                </div>


            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
