<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BATTLE OF HEI-KOU-TAI. FURTHER FIGHTING. GEN. GRIPENBERG RECALLED.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Tokio,</placeName> February 3. The battle of Hei-kou-tai was more
                        extensive and desperate was originally indicated. The result of the battle
                        hung in the balance. After four days of fighting, the Japanese were in a
                        critical position and outnumbered. Oyama finally ordered night attacks by
                        all the columns on the 28th ult, which the Russians were unable to
                        withstand. The latter began to retreat, whereupon the Japanese charged and
                        occupied Hei-kou-tai on the morning of the 29th. ult (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>Tokio,</placeName> February 3. Marshal Oyana reports that the
                        Japanese casualties from the 33th to the 29th January last were 7,000. The
                        Russians had at least 10,000. The prisoners state that four infantry
                        regiments were nearly annihilated (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 3. General Kuropatkin reports
                        that the Japanese on the 1st inst, after a hot bombardment, attacked
                        Djantankenam, on the left bank of the Hun-Hor and drove out the Russians.
                        The litter, having been reinforced, recaptured the village. It is stated
                        here that General Gripenberg, who comm the troops at Hei-kou-tai, has
                        relinquished his command on the ground of ill health. General Oyloff
                        succeeds him. (R.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 5. General Gripenberg has
                        been recalled for reasons of health. (Havas).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN DISTURBANCES. THE WARSAW CASUALTIIES TROUBLES AT LODZ. </head>
                    <p><placeName>Warsaw,</placeName> February 3. There is now no doubt that the
                        casualties at Warsaw far exceeded those of the Capital. The dead were buried
                        at night guarded by troops. The looting was due to Hooligans, who wore
                        incited by the police in order to discredit the movement. A hand of workmen
                        yesterday entered the Hooligan quarter and killed all whom they found in
                        possession of plunder. (Reuter).</p>
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> February 3. A strike has broken out in the
                        coal district of Dombrova and Sosnowic, on which Warsaw and Lodz depend for
                        their entire coal supply. (Reuter).</p>
                    <p><placeName>Lodz,</placeName> February 3. Serious disturbances have taken
                        place hen today, where the strikers number 250,000. The mob fought the
                        troops with revolvers. There were many killed and wounded. (R.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>Warsaw,</placeName> February 3. It is estimated that in the recent
                        trouble-600 people were killed or wounded. (R).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TSAR’S UKASE.</head>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 3 With reference to one
                        section of the Tsar's Ukase relating to the reforms, the Committee of
                        Ministers decided to recommend a series of measures for limiting individual
                        initiative of Ministers with the Tsar, and specially as regards the
                        alteration and suspension of laws, for increasing the control and the
                        initiative of the Senate in this latter connection, for facilitating the
                        prosecution of officials by private persons fur illegalities, for the
                        establishing of local courts in connection with the Senate, and for the
                        provision of educated jurymen where the question of the loss of civil rights
                        is involved. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. MOVEMENTS OP SQUADRONS.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Djibouti,</placeName> February 3. Admiral Botrovosky's squadron
                        has left for Madagascar, is German colliers are following the squadron.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> February 3. Lloyd's learns from Mauritius that
                        the Baltic Fleet was still at Nossi Be on the 28th January. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>Manila,</placeName> February 3. The American Fleet has left for
                        the south of the archipelago in order to maintain neutrality there. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BECK CO’S PILSENER BEER BREMEN.</head>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria and the
                        Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Mahmal arrived at Jeddah yesterday. Tin Brindisi Mail closes at the G. P.
                        0. Alexandria, at 3 p m. tomorrow. The Fitzer Quatuor will give two more
                        rentals at the New Khedivial Hotel, Alexandria, on the 17th and 24th
                        inst.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal- On the 1st inst 6 vessels, all British, passed through the Canal,
                        the dues from which amounted to fr. 244,396.36.</p>
                    <p>National Bank or Egtpt. — The new agencies of this bank at Benha, Damanhour,
                        Shebin el-Kom, Beni Souef, Keneh, Sohag, aud Assouan have commenced working
                        this week.</p>
                    <p>The Pirates of Penzance."— The performance of "The Pirates of Penzance," we
                        are informed, is to take place in Cairo ou the 22nd iust, aud not on tbe
                        17th, as the Duke of Connaught not arrive in Cairo until the 17th inst. An
                        Important Postal Innovation will come into force on April 1, when a postal
                        order service will be established between Egypt and Great Britain and her
                        colonies. No other country has such a system in vogue in connection with the
                        Egyptian Postal Administration.</p>
                    <p>The Freres' Case.—The “Chambre Correctionuele” of the Appeal Court at Aix
                        will hear the appeal of M. Leon Yayon against the judgment given by the
                        French Consular Coart at Cairo against him for libelling the Christian
                        Brothers, on the 9th inst.</p>
                    <p>Coal Imports.—The quantity of coal imported from 1st January to 2nd inst was
                        32,338 tons, as against 60,417 for the same period last year. Newcastle sent
                        5,833 tons, the Welsh districts 19,804, Scotch 4,668, Yorkshire 1,786, other
                        districts 247.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Institute.—There will be a meeting of the Egyptian Institute on
                        Monday afternoon next at 3 o’clock. Yacoub Pasha Artin will lecture on "8ome
                        Artistic Curios of the Fourteenth Century," and Dr. Apostolidis will discuss
                        "Hellenism in Egypt before the Macedonian Age.” There will be some elections
                        of new members after the meeting.</p>
                    <p>Mysterious Disappearance.—We regret to learn that Raoul Sakakiui, second son
                        of Sakakiui Boy, of Alexandria, has been missing since Thursday last. The
                        boy is 15 years of age and is a bright, intelligent lad, enjoying the best
                        of health. He left home on Thursday for a walk, and since then all the
                        efforts of the Alexandria police and detectives have been utterly unable to
                        trace his movements or discover his whereabouts. Lately, there have been
                        some other cases of the sudden disappearance of young boys from
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Armenian Benevolent Society. — The Zizinia Theatre was crowded last night on
                        the occassion of the special performance of "Le Petit Lord” tor the benefit
                        of the Armenian Benevolent Society of Alexandria. All the boxes were
                        decorated with flowers and the audience was representative of the cream of
                        Alexandrian society. The play was well acted. Miss Loyer as Cedric Errol was
                        charming and acted the part of little Poutleroy to perfection. M. Foamier as
                        the Duke of Dorincourt was also good End the minor porta were well filled.
                        After the play various artists recited. M. Plan, whose volume of poems is
                        criticised in another part of to-day’s issue, gave bis poem of “La Femme da
                        Marin” and the taste and emotion of his recital were greatly relished by the
                        audience. Miss Daussmond and Miss Loyer gave some pretty monologues and the
                        evening ended with Calmette’s farce “En Voitnre.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Aujourd’ hui a midi et damie) La reprise des cotons, en attirent lee specula
                        teurs a la corbeille dee manchandises, a en traine du mime coop la
                        depreciation et le de laissement de la oorbeille des valours. Aussi
                        avont-nous peu d’affaires a enregistrer quel qaes Oasis et denx ou trois
                        changes end autres valours, et o'est tout. Malgre cela, le marche se
                        maintient relative ment ferine.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ALEXANDRIA SCANDAL. END OP HEARING.</head>
                    <p>The further hearing of Mr. Ninci's petition fora judicial separation from his
                        wife, on the ground of her adultery with Judge Constantine Dimiaras, late
                        President of the Hellenic Consular Tribunal at Alexandria, was continued
                        yesterday afternoon at 4 o'clock before the Italian Consular Court, under
                        the presidency of Judge Palqui, assisted by Mr. Amabile Cumbo and Mr.
                        Arrera. Maltre Colucci, counsel for the petitioner, disputed the
                        authenticity of one of the letters read to the Court by Maltre Guidotti.
                        This letter was supposed to have been written by the wife's father,
                        complaining of her husband maltreatment. The Judge, on examining the
                        writing, pronounced it to be a forgery. Counsel for the wife then explained
                        I that the document in question not an original manuscript, but simply a
                        translation I from the Greek to Italian. He promised to bring the original
                        letter into Court.</p>
                    <p>Maltre Coluoci then began to controvert the arguments of the council for the
                        defence, and showed that the first line of defence was based on five points,
                        in order to prove I that the fault lay with the husband via, (R). </p>
                    <p>That Mr. Ninci neglected his wife when ill. (II). That he was a man of
                        depraved tastes. [III). That he had a very violent temper. (IV). That be
                        insulted his wife prior to the hear 1 ng of the case by inserting articles
                        in the Press. (R). </p>
                    <p>The Helouan incident Maltre Dolucei refuted each of these charges. He showed
                        that Mr. Ninoi wave loving and dutiful, and that many witnesses could be
                        brought into Court to prove that during his wife's illness his conduct had
                        been most sympathetic. The truth was that he idolized his wife, that the
                        responsible position which he now 1 bolds as the commercial manager here of
                        so important a company as that of the Rxffinerie d’Egypto, showed. That
                        laboured most seriously in order to enrich his wife. When he had attained
                        that i position, his wife had ruined his lile by her t flagrant infidelity.
                        As to the disgraceful allegations in regard to the perverted instincts of
                        his client, Maltre Coluoci said that such charges were always tramped up in
                        these matrimonial cases in order to blacken the husband’s character. She has
                        complained during the eight years of her married life, and she now, through
                        her counsel, declared that her husband began to display his deprived
                        character three days after the marriage ceremony. Maitre Coluoci then read
                        some very significant letters from the lady to her husband. He went on to
                        speak of her hypocritical and homeless conduct towards her husband, and that
                        if Mr. Ninci was guilty of violent behaviour, it was only natural
                        considering that , it had been tried so much, and as to the Helouan
                        incident, be had only smacked his wife. In regard to the second line of
                        defence, tamely, that the reconciliation of husband and his wife annulled
                        the claim of the husband to a official separation, Maitre Colucci declared
                        that the reconciliation was only of a tacit and thus did not invalidate the
                        subsequent claim for a separation. He then declared that the wife's conduct
                        was very like the rise of the heroine of Paul Bourget's "Cruelle Bnigme,”
                        for, although she loved her husband, yet she was unable to resist deceiving
                        him. Mr. Ninci loved his wife to distraction, and his passionate devotion to
                        her fully explained the alleged violence of his conduct and his weakness in
                        submitting to a momentary reconciliation at Helouan. Counsel then cited a
                        number of legal authorities, all showing that to divest a husband of his
                        right to a judicial separation, the reconciliation between him and his
                        erring wife should be tantamount to a complete resumption of marital
                        relations. But in the case in question this was not so but was merely a
                        trick of his wife’s lover, Judge Constantine Dimaras, who, knowing the
                        intricacies of the Italian aa well as of the Hollenio Code, had suggested to
                        his mistress that she should be temporarily reconciled with her husband, and
                        then provoke an incident, such as occurred at Helouan, in order that she
                        herself should be the first to ask for a judicial separation. The diabolical
                        ingenuity of the judge was successful. He pretended that he had a difference
                        with his mistress and left Egypt, but when the Helouan incident had taken
                        place he at once returned to Alexandria. I Mr. Ninci was not quite certain
                        of his wife's infidelity prior to the reconciliation; he merely I had very
                        strong suspicions, suggested by the discovery that his wife always wore a
                        scapular and a portrait of the judge concealed in her bosom, as well as by
                        the impassioned Greek poems ho had found in the house addressed to his wife
                        by the judge. Counsel then proved that Mr. Ninci was not certain of his
                        wife's misconduct at that time, because when Mr. Ninoi desired to have a
                        duel with the judge, the seconds came to an arrangement As the seconds were
                        very respectable gentlemen, it was impossible for them to oome to arrange
                        matters if there had been any certainty as to the adultery. Until the last
                        moment had continued her relations with the judge in a house in
                        Sesostris-street, and when the judge left for the Pinens last week, she had
                        a terrible attack of hysteria, which disturbed all the inhabitant# of the
                        opponent. This fully showed the "diabolical persistence” of her passion for
                        her lover. As to alimony, Maltre Coluoci declared that counsel for the
                        defence had erroneously stated that, even if the wife waa alone guilty, it
                        should be granted. LB. 15 was demanded, but any alimony was out of the
                        question, unless it could be shown that the wife was entirely innocent; in
                        the present, where the wife alone was to blame, obligatory | alimony will
                        quit. Maltre Coiaooi, his client was a man of feelings, and would not allow
                        his to starve. If however, the Court granted fixed sum, such as LE 16, the
                        wife would Mare Egypt, and go to live with the judge at h« husband’s
                        expense. He was prepared to give her an allowance of LE 6 monthly. In spite
                        of the protestations of Maltre Guidotti, Maltre Colucci declared that the
                        entire family of the wife, prior to her marriage, existed on LE 8 per month,
                        so that LE 6 for her alone was enough. This ended the speech of Maltre
                        Colnooi.and Maltre Guidotti then ruse to rejoin but was informed by the
                        judge that, as it was late, he should send his pleading to him and that
                        judgment would be given in a few days’ time.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will leave Montazah tomorrow for Cairo, and will return to
                        Alexandria on Friday next to attend the El Orwa el-Woaka Society’s benefit
                        performance at the Zizinia Theatre. All those who have recently been
                        promoted it decorated will be accorded an audience with H.H. the Khedive on
                        Monday, the 13th instant, at Abdeen Palace, at the following hours and in
                        the order indicated: 3.30 p.m. Governors and Moudirs. 3.45 p.m. Native
                        Tribunal and Native Bar. 4 p.m. Ministry of the Interior. Administration of
                        the Sanitary Service, General Inspectorate of Prisons, Sanitary, Maritime
                        and Quarantine Board, Slave Trade Reppression Department, Gouvernorate and
                        Moudiriehs, Municipal Commissions, Ministry of Finance, Customs
                        Administration, Administration of Porta and Lighthouses, Postal
                        Administration, Coast Guard Administration, Public Debt Department, Daira
                        Sanieh, Administration of Railways, Telegraphs and of the Port of
                        Alexandria, Ministry of Public Works, Ministry of Public Instruction,
                        Ministry of War, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Waifs Administration. 4.15
                        p.m. The officials who are entitled to a pension; the native and European
                        notables; the omdehs and the sheikhs. Military visitors at this reception
                        will appear in undress uniform and civilians in morning dress.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head>
                    <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught have arrived at Khartoum. They are due back
                        in Cairo on the 17th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER’S TRIP.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.) Medinet-el-Fayoum, Saturday, 1 p.m. Lord and Lady
                        Cromer and Lady Thynne arrived here to-day and were received by the Mondnieh
                        officials, judges, Bedouin chiefs, village headmen, and a great gathering of
                        other local notables. Lord Cromer made a speech touching on the cotton worm,
                        locusts, irrigation, alcoholism, and many other matters, which was greatly
                        appreciated. Our distinguished visitors leave for the South at 5.40
                        o’clock.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JUDICIAL COMMISSION.</head>
                    <p>This morning, the Lit meeting of the International Judicial Commission was
                        held at the Mixed Court, Alexandria, under the presidency of Boutroe Pasha
                        Ghali, Minister for Foreign Affaire. The Judicial Adviser and the Khedivial
                        Counsellors, Messrs. Bernard and Rocca Serra, were present. The work of the
                        Commission is now practically over. This morning’s conference was only
                        concerned with some comparatively unimportant details.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELLENIC CONSULAR COURT.</head>
                    <p>The new judge appointed by the Greek Government as president of the Hellenic
                        Consular Court at Alexandria, in succession to Judge Dimaras, is Mr.
                        Xenophon Stellakia, at present president of the Hellenic Consular Court at
                        Smyrna. The Greek Government has taken this step in consequence of the
                        scandals associated with Judge Dim area. The matrimonial case in which he is
                        mixed up is reported in another column of today’s issue.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE S.S “FORTUNA."</head>
                    <p>Our Suez Correspondent informs us that there is no truth in the rumour that
                        the S.S. "Fortuna" has been wrecked in the Bed Sea. He adds that he saw the
                        vessel anchored yesterday morning in the Suez roads loading cargo for
                        tour.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Indian Prince” left Manchester on Thursday with passengers and
                        general cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS</head>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo on Friday by the P.S."Nefortari" for the
                        Nile trip: Mrs. M. A. Crosley, Mrs. John R Bell, Mis. E M. and Miss E
                        Bishop, Mr. and Mrs. N. P. Wheeler, Miss Rachel Wheeler, Miss M. Culbertson,
                        Mrs. H. L Perry, Miss C. Franciscos, Mr. Gardner, Mr. Gardner Jur.X Mr. W.
                        Wandelt, Prod Koroer, Miss Nitache. Miss Sehroeder, Mrs. Amstricher Jseger,
                        Miss Stracker, M. Landrat von der Beck, Mrs. Bohm, Mr. and Mrs. C. W.
                        Chiity, Dr. A. H. and Mrs. Ebrman, Major General Nusoh, Mr. Ramm, Mr. Gomel,
                        Mr. Bohm, Mr. Schilling, Mr. IttoBobu.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY. MENA HOUSE GYMKHANA.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon’s pleasant fixture, the Mena House Gymkhana, was attended
                        by a large and fashionable gathering. A number of visitors came out early to
                        Mena to lunch at the hotel before the races began at 3 o'clock, and the
                        hospitality of Men's House was taxed to its utmost to provide lunch for the
                        members who flocked out in the morning. The following is a list of
                        prize-winners:— „ Donkey Ram for Gentlemen. — 1. Mr. Wright Anderson, 2. Mr.
                        Paton, 3. Capt Curey.</p>
                    <p>Flat Race for Ponies. — 1. Ibrahim Bey Cherif 2. Mr. Fox, 3. Dr. Nolan.</p>
                    <p>General Post Stakes on Horses.—1. Mrs. Wood, 2. Mrs. Nolan.</p>
                    <p>Camel Race for Gentlemen —1. Mr. littlewood, 9. Ahmed Pareg Bey. 3. Mr.
                        Vernon.</p>
                    <p>Ladies’ Pony Race. — 1. Mrs. Wood, 2. Mrs. Nolan.</p>
                    <p>Hubdu Race. — 1. Ibrahim Bey Cberif) 2. Ahmed Bey Cheri 3. Mr. Starkey. </p>
                    <p>Lamas Donkey Rat*.— 1. Miss Babs. HackRack—1. Mr. Colton Pox, 9. Mohamed
                        Pouad Nomad, 3. Ahmed Pang Bey.</p>
                    <p>An extra event was for Arabs riding their own camel*. There was a field of
                        eight Ramadam came in first, followed by Soldi and Kamel. The presentation
                        of prizes took plaoe on the terrace of the hotel.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POINT-TO-POINT RACES.</head>
                    <p>The Abbassieh Hunt point-to-point race meeting was held yesterday at Bshet
                        Goorgi Zigada on the left bank of the Menonfieh Canal, near the Delta
                        Barrage. A special train left Cairo at 11.20 am. with about 75 passengers
                        for the races, and many others came down by launch from Cairo. The
                        enclosure, which commanded a very good view of the course, was decorated
                        with flags, and detachments of police and ghaffirs were drawn up on the bank
                        of the canal, at the point where the launches and barge stopped. Mr. Machell
                        gave a large lunch party on the “Scout” and Sir William Gore tin also
                        entertained a party on board one of the launches of the Irrigation
                        Department. Among those present were the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire,
                        Lady Londesborough, Lord and lady Dalhonsie, Major General Slade and Miss
                        Slade, Sir William Garstin, Mr. Macbell, Mr. M. de C. Findlay, Mr. H. E
                        Verschoyle, Mr. A. L Webb, Mr. and Mrs. Brunyate, Mr. Lockett, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Horn-blower, Mohamed Cboukri Pasha, the Misses Harley, Mrs. Crawley, Mr. H.
                        Rumbold, Capt the Hon. A. Stanley, Mr. and Mrs. Satow, Mr. and Mrs. Wyid,
                        Dr. Keatings, Mr. and Mrs. Graham, Mr. Carter Wilson, Capt Gillson, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Astley Friend, Mr. and Mrs. Scott-Dalgleish, Mr. aud Mrs. Drummood-Hay,
                        Capt. Biggs, B.K., Mr. Tod, Mr. Bowden-Smith, and many others. The racing
                        good and expeditiously managed, tbe starts being capital.There were some
                        tumbles bat no one came to any ham, aud the dust was the only thing that at
                        all interfered with the pleasure of the visitors. Tbe following are the
                        results</p>
                    <p>Landowness Race — This race resolved itself into a match between Mohamed
                        Salam el Shedid’s horse, a grey, and a chestnut owned by Hamad el Miftah el
                        Tabawi, who was beaten by a bare half-length. Beheri Bey Halawa won the
                        third prixe oat of five competitors.</p>
                    <p>Hunt Cup - There were five runners in the Hunt Cup Race, of whom Capt Cummins
                        was out of the race at the second corner owing to his hone coming down at a
                        fence. Mr. Stanlake-Lee, though riding an Arab that had never jumped before,
                        was in the first three till the third owner, where his mount refused a jump
                        and cost him a couple of bandied yards Capt. Lewin was the winner, Capt the
                        Hon. A. Stanley being a good second, and Capt Bartlett third.</p>
                    <p>Sheikhs’ Rack—Won after an amusing race by Sadi Bey Sbedid, Abdul Megib
                        Toulba being second, and Beheri Bey Hajawa third.</p>
                    <p>Own Rack—Woo fairly easily by Capt the Hon. A. Stanley, Capt Bartlett bring
                        second, and Mr. Lockett third, Mr. Tod dose behind.</p>
                    <p>Fellaheen Rack—There were eight entries for this race, but the bank and drain
                        near the enclosure put several of the riders temporarily out of action,
                        while others, after getting their hones over, were carried into bersim
                        fields by their steeds. Eventually Mob. Abd-el-Rahman won easily. Ali Mob.
                        Amr was second. Eizk Mati, in spite of a cropper at the obstacle
                        above-mentioned, came in third, the remaining riders failing to finish the
                        course.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Cairo v. Alexandria.</head>
                    <p>A cricket match, "Cairo” v. "Alexandria,’' will be played in Cairo on Friday,
                        17th inst, at 10.30 am. The teams are as follows</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOCKEY.</head>
                    <p>RT.C. v. Alderson's Garden. The hockey match on skates, which took place in
                        Alderson's Garden yesterday after noon, proved a very interesting fixture
                        arc drew a lam crowd of spectators. Play was very exciting. In the first
                        half it proved very quick and looked in favor of the RT.C, hot during the
                        second half Alderson’s Garden played up , well and won by 6 to A The
                        following wen , the teams:— RT.C.—Townsend, Barnes. and Collier. Alderson’s
                        Garden. - Douglas Alien, W Tookejr, end H. C. Tookey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>The Nile season this year has never been surpassed, and Cook’s and the
                        Anglo-American Line’s steamers are taking enormous numbers of tourists up
                        the river. The dahabiehs and privately chartered steamers are also being
                        well patronised. Among the distinguished departure from Cairo yesterday for
                        the river trip was Prince Gusts via Adolphus of Sweden and Norway, who left
                        by the S.S. "Cleopatra for Upper Egypt. The Empress Eugenie also left
                        yesterday for a river trip with her party, on board Cook’s S.S. "Nephtis."
                        The Empress will probably go as far at Khartoum. She was most pleased with
                        her stay it the Savoy Hotel where she will be beck in March. The Marquis di
                        Rudini was the guest of the evening last night at a banquet given at Cairo
                        by Prince Husaain Pasha Kamel. On Thursday evening' the ex-Prime Minister of
                        Italy was entertained to a banquet given by the Marquis and Marchioness
                        Salvago-Raggi at the Italian Diplomatic Agency at Cairo. Among the guests
                        were Prince Fuad Pasha, M.and Mme., de Martino Pasha, Marquis di Soragna,
                        Count Arrivmbene, etc. The Marquis leaves Egypt on Wednesday next for
                        Massowah. He will meet Sig. Martini Governor of Brythrea, at Snex. Mr. and
                        Mrs. Rochfort Maguire are accompanying the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire on
                        their dahabieh trip up the river. Sir Ernest Ceasel and party, including Sir
                        Edward and lady Colebrooke are to be in Cairo for some time. They are
                        staying at the Savoy Hotel Lady Sarah Wilson has gone up the Nile with Lord
                        and Lady Howe. Sir Benjamin Baker, Mr. Aird, and Mr. Blue are arriving at
                        Cairo next week.</p>
                    <p>The "At Home” given at the Carole International Mansoomh, Tuesday last, was
                        in every way a great success. Dancing commenced about 10 o'clock and went
                        merrily on anti! 3. There were about people present. Supper was served at 12
                        o’clock and amongst the 24 guests of the Moadir we noticed the British
                        Consul and Mrs. Murdoch, Mr, Mrs, and Miss Smith, the Rev. T. Perininger,
                        Mr, Mrs, and Miss Warner, Mr. Moberiy, Dr. Biring, Mr. Hopkins, Mr. and Mr*.
                        Kindynekos. The president of the dub. Makaod Bey, and the vice-president,
                        Mr. Midnatopdo, also entertained other guests. The health of the Moadir,
                        Mustaph* Maher Pasha, was drank with social honors, and after several
                        speeches dancing recommenced. Amongst other guests we noticed Mme. Commonoe,
                        Mme Gertsen, Mr. George and Miss Dood, Judge Bemsn, judge Hegaus, the
                        Russian Consul Mr. Hmkih Grets, etc. A great amounted of the success of the
                        evening was due to the untiring efforts of Maksud Bey. The evening closed
                        with “Should all acquaintance be forgot," “God Save the King” and the
                        Turkish national anthem.</p>
                    <p>The United States Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General Mr. Biddle; is giving a
                        large dinner party at the Savoy Hotel on 23rd fast. Count Kocxiebrodxki, the
                        new Austro-Hungarian Consul-General, received the members of the office at
                        the Savoy Hotel today.</p>
                    <p>Abdel Hamid Abaza entertained a party at diner at the Savoy Restaurant
                        yesterday evening, the guests including Prof. Mrs. Vail Ms. and Mrs. W. C.
                        Mackenzie. Mr. arid Mrs. Poaden, Mr. and Mrs. 8utro. Misses Houghton, Mr. H.
                        Lonaford, and Ismail Paaha A bare. At another table Mr. Hobhouse, M. P.Creok
                        shank Pasha, and the Maxtor of Elibank, to be seen. Baron von Kooning.
                        Chamberlain to the Tzar, had a select party of 7. Mr. and Mm. James Speyer,
                        Mr. ami Mrs Huntington, of New York, Mr. and Mrs. Ellerman, Mr. Joseph
                        Walton, M.P, Dr. and Mme. Attach larger have left the Savoy Hotel for
                        Europe. Mr. Antoine Saohtouris, Hellenic Vice Consul at Alexandria, has been
                        promoted to tbe rank of consul and transferred to Uskub, Macedonia. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Congo” des Messegeries Mari-times parti pour Marseille le 3
                        farrier avait a bord: M. Cotillon, M. Cornekmp, M. Coobard, M. Bandry, M.
                        Auerbach. M. Antoine Misk, Mme Grandjren, Mme A. Worms, Mme A. Bertonx. M.
                        Balks, et 19 pastogen de 3me et 4me classe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class snd most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Fading the
                        Central position. Under English management.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL LUXOR</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Management. Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
