<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-30">June 30, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bam01">
                    <head>Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</head>
                    <p>Despatch weekly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Mails
                        from Alexandria to Cyrpus and the Syrian Coast and vice-versa.</p>
                    <p>For particulars of freight, passage, etc., apply to the Agent Ed. A. Minotte.
                        1099-25.2.905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-iob01">
                    <head>IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK.</head>
                    <p>CAPITAL: £10,000,000.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFIOE IN CONSTANTINOPLE. CHIEF AGENCIES: LONDON &amp; PARIS.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES IN ALL THE PRINCIPAL TOWNS IN TURKEY.</p>
                    <p>Agencies in Egypt : ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, &amp; PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>Advances on Merchandise and Securities in current account and for fixed
                        periods. Purchase and sale of stocks and Shares on the London and
                        Continental exchanges, letters of credit issued, valuables reoeived in safe
                        custody. Drafts, cheques and telegraphic transfers issued on the principal
                        towns of the world. Foreign exchange purchased, bills discounted, bills,
                        invoices, annuities and dividends collected and every description of banking
                        business transacted. 18-4-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma04">
                    <p>Numbering Machines and Dating Stamps</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Cairo Bulac Road</p>
                    <p>Stationary Engraving and Printing Office</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-alf01">
                    <head>The IDEAL MILK FOODS for HOT CLIMATES. The 'Allenburys' Foods.</head>
                    <p>The "Allenburys" Foods give strength and Stamina, and supply all that is
                        required for the formation of firm flesh and bone. They promote perfect
                        health, and give freedom from digestive troubles and the disorders common to
                        children fed on farinaceous foods, condensed milk, or cow's milk. </p>
                    <p>ALLEN &amp; HANBURYS Ltd., LONDON, ENGLAND. </p>
                    <p>Depot in Cairo:— E. Dell Mar, 25, Août.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dlc01">
                    <head>D C L Scotch Whisky</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt &amp; Sudan</p>
                    <p>G. G Drossos &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Late Prazzica &amp; Drossos.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria. Cairo. Port-Said and Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>1080 31-5-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jbc01">
                    <head>John B. Caffari's "Economical Stores"</head>
                    <p>Cairo and Alexandria</p>
                    <p>The Perfection of Quality and Value.</p>
                    <p>In Sterling Silver, "Welbeck" &amp; Silver Plated Goods</p>
                    <p>Provisions, Wines, Cigars, Crockery, Brushes, &amp;c., &amp;c., at</p>
                    <p>Price List on Application.</p>
                    <p>16-11-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-vdt01">
                    <head>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE PAVING COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>Hamilton House, Bishopgate St Without, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>CONTRACTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE</p>
                    <p>Pyrimont-Seyssel, Servas (France) Ragusa (Sicily), Guanipa, (Venezuala), Mine
                        Owners.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN BRANCH - FIRST ASPHALT FACTORY ESTABLISHED IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Moharrem-Boy Factory, 171, Mahmoudieh Canal, Alexandria.- Office in Cairo:
                        Haret-el-Mashady (Ismailieh Quarter).</p>
                    <p>For Sales of Mastic Asphalte Blocks, Trinidad Refined Bitumen, Bricks in
                        Compressod Asphalte for Paving, Compressed Asphalte Roadways. — Contractors
                        for every description of Asphalte Works in the whole of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>25-45-14-7-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sde01">
                    <head>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED</head>
                    <p>KHARTOUM: CAIRO Office, Sharia Kasr-el-Nil.</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT. Six days White Nile Tourist Trip dep. Khartoum
                        Tuesdays. Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at all Cairo Tourist
                        Agents. - Special Steamers for private charter. - Trips arranged and
                        transport of goods undertaken to all places on White and Blue Niles within
                        navigation limits.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT. Shipyard for construction of sternwheel steamers,
                        barges, stream, motor launches, etc. Contractors for supply and erection of
                        all classes of machinery, buildings, irrigation pumps, etc.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENTS FOR Dudbridges Oil Engines from 1 to 25 B.H.P. as supplied to
                        Sudan Government. Seamless xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mil01">
                    <head>Milner's Safes</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt</p>
                    <p>G. Marcus &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Large Stock Kept in</p>
                    <p>Alexandria<lb/>Rue Constantinople Maison A. N. Abet</p>
                    <p>Cairo<lb/> Hoss Issa rue Neuve</p>
                    <p>Tanta<lb/>Sharia El Alail.</p>
                    <p>17 11-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                    <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                    <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                    <p>7-8-90</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah02">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria.)</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Patronized by the Elite.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber
                        Station.</p>
                    <p>21440-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cgg01">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>NICOLA G. SABBAG</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, 2, Rue de la Gare du Caire</p>
                    <p>Telephone; No. 559.</p>
                    <p>24528-15-3-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hbc01">
                    <head>HOTEL BRISTOL. CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Full South, Electric Light, opposite Esbekieh Gardens, Large Verandahs,
                        Moderate Charges,</p>
                    <p>CHAS. BAUER, Proprietor.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel is beautifully fitted up and is in the most central part of Cairo.
                        Terms for pension fare at the rate of ten shillings a day. Special terms for
                        officers of Army of Occupation. 24,882-31-10-5</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hdi02">
                    <head>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper</head>
                    <p>Made in 70 Colors</p>
                    <p>An artistic wall covering.</p>
                    <p>This celebrated water paint is made in two qualities for Inside and Outside
                        work</p>
                    <p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
                        tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only
                        requires the addition of water to make it ready for use. It is quickly and
                        easily applied with a whitewash brush, with half the labour and at one third
                        the cost of paint. HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing to
                        the eye. It appeals alike to artistic and practical house decoration.</p>
                    <p>HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special value in hot climates. Owing to its cool,
                        pleasing colours, great weather-resisting and germ-destroying properties, it
                        lends itself to every kind of wall, wood, brick or stone coating, possessing
                        all the advantages of paint, colour- wash, and disinfectant at one third the
                        cost of oil paint. It never blisters in the hottest sun, and the fact that
                        it can be washed adds greatly to its sanitary advantages.</p>
                    <p>Supplied in Tins and Iron Kegs.</p>
                    <p>Sole Manufacturers :</p>
                    <p>SISSONS BROTHERS &amp; CO., LTD., HULL.</p>
                    <p>Stocks are held In Cairo by Frank Ratcliffe, Sanitary Contractor and
                        Engineer, Sharia Saptieh.</p>
                    <p>In Alexandria by Ramadan Youssef, Sanitary Contractor, Rue Sesostris.</p>
                    <p>General Agents: George Morris &amp; Co.. Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun01">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>A great economiser and saver of time, health, and strength.</p>
                    <p>Laundry worries went out of woman's life when Sunlight Soap came into it.</p>
                    <p>It is the purest Soap going.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun02">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>WORK WELL DONE . . GIVES TIME FOR PLAY.</p>
                    <p>Hard work is not easy unless you use Sunlight Soap.</p>
                    <p>It shortens the wash-day and brings comfort.</p>
                    <p>It has the Largest Sale in the World.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-gwy01">
                    <head>GWYNNES, Limited.</head>
                    <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                    <p>Telegrams--GWYNNE, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Telephone--544 BANK</p>
                    <p>Codes-- ABC, 4th and 5th Editions, A1.</p>
                    <p>MORNING &amp; NEAL'S.</p>
                    <p>Trade Mark — “INVINCIBLE."</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
                        In the world, suitable fcr all purposes, including RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE,
                        IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL
                        MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                    <p>These Pumps can be driven by Steam, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other
                        power, for Lifts of from 1 ft. to 500ft., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a
                        Minute. Makers of the Mex Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Results Guaranteed.</p>
                    <p>Over 50 Years' Practical Experience.</p>
                    <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet
                        Egyptian requirements.</p>
                    <p>London Offices— 81, Cannon Street, London, E.C.</p>
                    <p>The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd: Rue de la Gare du Caire,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Works- Hammersmith, London, W</p>
                    <p>23362-11-12-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-rea01">
                    <head>ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>Incorporated A. D. 1720.</p>
                    <p>Chief Office: ROYAL EXCHANGE, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>FUNDS IN HAND EXCEED £4,500,000 CLAIMS PAID £40,000,000</p>
                    <table rows="2" cols="2">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>FIRE</cell>
                            <cell>MARINE</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</cell>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>CAIRO … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                            <cell>SUEZ … Mr. GEO. MEINECKE.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>21281-216905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-lea01">
                    <head>Lea and Perrins' Sauce.</head>
                    <p>By Royal Warrant to His Majesty the King.</p>
                    <p>The original and genuine Worchestershire.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ODESSA IN FLAMES. WORK OF MUTINEERS. REIGN OF TERROR. 300 RIOTERS KILLED.
                        HOSPITALS OVERFLOWING.</head>
                    <p>London, June 29. The "Standard" learns from Odessa that revolutionary mobs
                        yesterday evening set fire to the quarantine station, the warehouses and
                        other buildings of the harbour, and prevented the firemen from extinguishing
                        the Hemes. The troops are terrorised by the guns of the "Potemkin," which
                        late last night fired a shell at a Cossack piquet, killing and wound- ing
                        24. A torpedo-boat accompanying the "Potemkin" entered the harbour and
                        seized a Russian steamer with a cargo of 2,000 tons of coal. The Governor
                        has telegraphed to Sevastopol for the fleet, but it is feared that the
                        mutiny will spread, as all the crews are disaffected, and it is even
                        reported that four battleships have already mutinied, of which two are on
                        their way to Odessa. Grave anxiety is felt at Lloyd’s, as there are many
                        British ships in the harbour. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London, June 29. The latest news from Odessa shows that serious riots have
                        taken place. Hundreds ol people have been shot and the port is partially
                        destroyed by fire. Martial law has been pro- claimed. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Odessa, June 29. It is confirmed that all the officers of the "Potemkin" were
                        murdered except three. The sailors were prominent in yesterday's street
                        fighting. A battleship and a cruiser left Sevastopol in all haste for
                        Odessa. Before burning the ware- houses the mob carried off the goods. The
                        loss is estimated at 1,000,000 roubles. The city is enveloped in smoke. All
                        the shops are shat and traffic is suspended. The troops hold the main
                        streets and the hospitals are over- flowing. There are not sufficient
                        doctors to attend to the wounded. Many inhabitants are leaving the city. In
                        several instances yesterday the troops, who are mostly reservists, refused
                        to fire on the mob (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF ADMIRAL WALKER.</head>
                    <p>London, June 29 Admiral Sir Baldwin Wake Walker is dead (Reuter.) Rear
                        Admiral Sir Baldwin Wake Walker. 2nd Baronet and Pasha of the Turkish Em-
                        pire, was bom st Siessa, Tuscany, on Sep torn her 24, 1846, and succeeded to
                        the title on the death of his father in 1876. He entered ’be Royal Navy in
                        1859, was made lieutenant in 1868, and commander in 1880 He served in the
                        Egyptian war of 1889, and was one of the officers engage. 1 in the
                        protection of the New- foundland Fisheries, IR92. He was made C M 0 •n 1893
                        and C.V.O in the same year. He held the command of the Mediterranean
                        cruisers, and was in Alexandria last year on the occasion of the visit of
                        the Mediterranean Squadron.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Brindisi Mail</head>
                        <p>will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a m. on Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Ghezireh district of Cairo during the night of Sunday and at
                            daylight on Monday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>St. Andrew’s Church, Alexandria.</head>
                        <p>— The usual quarterly oclebration of the Lord’s Supper will take place in
                            this church on Sunday next at 10.30 a.m. Visitors and strangers are
                            cordially invited.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Cana</head>
                        <p>l —10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 27th inst, 6 of which were
                            British. 1 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Italian. The day’s receipts were frs.
                            275,422.47, making the total from the 1st inst frs. 7.506,192.22</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Harmonia Club.</head>
                        <p>—The "fete de tondation" of this club will take place to-morrow evening,
                            commencing at 9 o’clock precisely, when a very select concert programme
                            will be gone through, after which there will be a small dance.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Fall from Building.</head>
                        <p>— A native workman engaged in limewashing the walls of the third story of
                            the new building belonging to H.H. Prince Mohamed Ibrahim, in Moha- med
                            Aly-square, lost his balance yesterday and fall into the street He died
                            on being removed to hospital</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>—Yesterday's plague bulletin records one fresh case at Alexandria, one
                            recovery at Port Said, one fresh case at Toukh, and one death at
                            Ashmoun. There are now 21 cases under treatment Dr. W. MacCarthy
                            Morroghy has been temporarily appointed to plagne duty.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Lamp Explosion.</head>
                        <p>—An accident which, for- tunately, was not attended with serious conse-
                            quences, occurred yesterday to Mme. Myralda, a medium of Prof.
                            Lafontaiue, the hypnotist While in the act of lighting a paraffin oil
                            lamp the latter exploded and the lady was soon in flames. Thanks,
                            however, to prompt assistance all danger was averted. She merely
                            sustained a few slight bums.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mex Casino.</head>
                        <p>—A grand open-air file will be given at Mex Casino to-morrow evening by
                            the Margherita and Ernesto Rossi societies com- bined. The first part of
                            the programme will consist of a dramatic entertainment and the second of
                            a ball, which latter will commence at half-past midnight Tramcars will
                            run between Mex and the city during the whole of the eight for the
                            convenience of those attending the fete.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hotel Beau Rivage, Ramleh.</head>
                        <p>—An excep- tionally large number of visitors have patronis- ed daring the
                            early part of the season the fashionable Bean-Rivage Hotel, which has
                            been full op every week since May. The restaurant on the terrace facing
                            the sea is now open, and can accommodate 180 guests at small tables.
                            Meals in this open-air-restaurant are much appreciated, and many
                            banquets have been given daring June. Afternoon tea in the garden has
                            become quite popular, it being such a charming excursion from Alexandria
                            to the beau-Rivage The small dances which were such a great success will
                            soon be held regularly.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Carriage Accident.</head>
                        <p>—Yesterday a carriage accident that might have entailed serious
                            consequences took place at Cairo. Mohamed Bey Seif el Nasr, of the
                            Egyptian Army, had left his dogcart in Kernel-street to purchase some
                            cigarettes when the horse took fright and bolted with Miss Nasr, who was
                            sitting in the cart. The syce lost his head and dropped the bridle at
                            once and the horse rushed away. Near the Continental Hotel the dogcart
                            was upset by a collison,and Miss Nasr was flung out. She was immediately
                            removed to the Con- tinental Hotel where it proved that though much
                            shaken and frightened the had sustained</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Gardner-Brown Bioscope and Variety Co.</head>
                        <p>—This popular combination gave their opening performance at the Mustapha
                            Garrison Theatre last night to a house packed to its utmost capacity,
                            and soured an unqualified success, the audience showing their
                            appreciation by repeated calls for encores. Miss Annie Russell, a dainty
                            young soubrette, opened the show and pleased every one by her clever
                            rendering of a couple of songs in lighter vein. Mr. Geo. Gulliver, who
                            followed, proved an excellent ventriloquist, and caused roars of
                            laughter with the funny sayings and antics of his figures, whioh so
                            pleased the delighted audience that he was compelled to respond to an
                            encore. Miss Lottie Walton, who next appeared, possesses a very sweet
                            and sympathetic voice, and her rendering of the descriptive ballads was
                            greatly enjoyed, A series of animated pictures by the Gardner Brown
                            Bioscope followed ; these were very clear and steady, snd were
                            enthusiastically received, especially the scene depicting an incident at
                            the Battle of the Yale. The Sisters Romaine were very warmly received,
                            their singing and dancing, in addition to their youth and graceful
                            appearance, making them general favorites. Mr. Leo. Montague, an
                            exceptionally clever comedian, hugely delighted the audience with his
                            songs with topical allusions, and had to respond to an enthusiastic
                            encore. Illustrated songs by Mrs. Gardner Brown, and a wonderful
                            bioscopic production entitled The Poachers," brought to a conclusion a
                            most bright and sparkling entertainment during which there was not a
                            single doll moment The company perform at Mustapha tonight and Saturday,
                            and will give a special performance at the Railway Institute, Demanbour,
                            on Sunday.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE "DNIEPER" AT SUEZ "ST. HILDA'S" CREW ON BOARD. BRITISH CRUISERS IN HER
                        WAKE. (From our Correspondent). Suez, Friday. 8 a.m. The Russian cruiser
                        "Dnieper" has arrived here. She is followed by a British battleship, which
                        is presumably H.M.S. "Goliath." Parti- culars will follow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Suez Dock, Friday. 10.18a.m. The "Dnieper " will enter the Canal to day. The
                        crew f the British steamer "St. Hilda" are on board and will apparently land
                        at Port Said. I boarded the Russian cruiser bat the officers absolutely
                        refused to grant me an interview or to allow me to see the British prisoners
                        of the "St. Kildas' The battleship "Canopus" is entering the canal in the
                        forenoon. The battleship "Goliath" has been sighted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
                    <p>London, June 29. Sir B. H. Vincent Corbett and Mr. Malcolm Mollwraith have
                        been created K.C.M.G. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAILWAY COLLISION AT ASSIOUT.</head>
                    <p>(Prom our Correspondent). Tahta, Wednesday. The mail arrived yesterday five
                        hours behind time. The delay is due, I am informed by a passenger from
                        Assiout, to the negligence of the pointsman there. The two up and down
                        trains that start regularly from Asaiout at 6 o’clock in the morning were
                        maneuvering pre vious to departure when the two engines col- lided. The
                        locomotives were not attached to the carriages of the trains, and the
                        drivers, see- ing the danger they were in, jumped off and thus save 1 their
                        lives. The engines met with a terrific impact and were both derailed, one
                        falling on the left of the line and the other on the right. As the drivers
                        had tailed to shut off steam in their haste to save themselves, the engines
                        were still in motion and ploughed into the ground. It was with great
                        difficulty that the drivers were eventually able to stop the machinery.
                        Traffic was thus interrupted and the up and down passengers had to be
                        transferred from one train to another until, 10 hours afterwards, the line
                        was cleared.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA HARBOUR.</head>
                    <p>The breakwater in Alexandria harbour is about to be lengthened, and the work
                        htf already been commenced. The new works will extend from the red light on
                        the end of the breakwater to the pivot buoy (approx.) A buoy has been laid
                        down in 18 feet (approx.) to mark the 8.E edge of the 13 feet bank, which
                        lies to the west of the breakwater end. Other buoys will be laid down from
                        time to time along the line of work between the end of the breakwater and
                        the pivot buoy, and mariners are cautioned not to pass between these
                        points.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL. ACCUSED FOUND GUILTY.</head>
                    <p>The Rifaa case came up before the Native Court of Appeal at Cairo yesterday,
                        the hearing opening at 9 am. before the President of the Court, Hasaem Bey
                        Amin, and Aziz Bey Kahil and Ahmed Bey Ziwar, who acted as assessors, and
                        Aly Bey Abu-el-Fetuk, publio prosecutor. The morning was devoted to tho
                        hearing of the case for the prosecution. The Court adjourned at 1 p.m. for
                        two hours.The defence of the accuse was then heard,the pleadings lasting
                        till 6 p.m. The president then asked if they had anything to add to the
                        statements made by their counsel. On their answering in the negative the
                        Court retired to consider the verdict. At 7 p.m. the Court returned and the
                        pro didnt read out the verdict All the accused were found guilty. The
                        Mondir, the Cadi, and the Wekil of the Daira Rifaa were sentenced to two
                        years' imprisonment with hard labour, the young Rifaa to one year's
                        imprisonment wiw hard laboar, and the remainder of the accused to six
                        months' imprisonment. All the culprits were condemned to pay a fine of LE.
                        50, with the costs of the case.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TRADE OF EGYPT. MAY CUSTOMS RETURNS.</head>
                    <p>The Customs Administration has published its returns for the month of May.
                        The value of the imports to the fire ports of Egypt (Alexandria, Port-Said,
                        Suez, Damietta and Kosseir) amounts to L.E. 1,533,679, against LE. 1,451,949
                        in the corresponding month of 1904, while the total for the first five
                        months of the year shows an advance of LE 722,072 on last year’s figures.
                        The export statistics for the past month show a certain falling-off, the
                        difference being LE. 72,840 in favor of May 1904. The same decrease is to be
                        noticed in the figures for the period January 1-May 31, 190^, the total
                        value of the goods exported daring that period reaching LB. 8,293,341, as
                        against LB. 10,057,661 in the corresponding period last year. British
                        imports in May, 1905, amounted to LE 506,385 and to LB. 2,653,06* for the
                        first five months of the year, against LB. 504,501 and LE 2,467,478 for the
                        corresponding periods last year. Exports to Great Britain amounted to LE
                        617,439 in May, 1905, against LE 581,581 in May, 1904, and the first five
                        months of the present year show a total of LE. 4,244,697, against LR
                        4,989,264 in the corresponding period in 1904. For the past month Turkey
                        comes second to Groat Britain among the importing countries. Comparing the
                        export statistics for May 1906, with those for May, 1804. we notice a
                        decrease in cotton exports representing a sum of LE 232,674 and a slight
                        (and very natural) decrease in hides. The most remarkable increase comes
                        under the beading of rice and amounts to LB. 87,999. Onion exports (+86,909)
                        and cane sugar (+40,112) also show a gratifying increase, not for the past
                        month only, as in the case of rice, bat for the five months. Among the
                        imports the largest increase comes under the beading of floor (+49,700 for
                        May and +122,789 for the first five months of the year). Cotton goods and
                        iron articles also show an increase for the latter period.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A GREAT CAIRO SCANDAL</head>
                    <p>We would call the attention of the police authorities to a grave public
                        scandal that has been allowed to exist for too long, and which is a blot to
                        the Capital that should no longer be tolerated. We allude to the European
                        houses of ill-fame that are to be seen on all sides at the very entrance to
                        the city, at the commence- ment of the Rue Kamel and within a stone's throw
                        of Cook's office and Shepbeard'a, one of the most frequented parts of the
                        metropolis. Some three or four year ago, on the com plaint of the management
                        of the above hotel and several of its prominent visitors, a stop was put to
                        the assembling nightly during the winter season, on the pavements round
                        about this loyalty, of numbers of women from the adjacent houses of bad
                        repute, and it should not therefore be difficult for the local police to
                        have the occupants of these houses removed to a spot where they would not be
                        such a public scandal</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>LOST—A TORPEDO.</head>
                    <p>(Prom our Correspondent.) Port Said, Thursday. H. M. 8. "Suffolk," while at
                        «aa going through the regular firing practice on Monday, had the misfortune
                        to lose a torpedo valued at over £600, for which a reward of £5 is now being
                        offered. She returned to harbour after a successful day, at sunset</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHINA SQUADRON.</head>
                    <p>H.M. battleships "Goliath" and "Canopus," which wore at Aden on Friday last,
                        are ex- ported at Suez very shortly, to be followed by the remaining six
                        ships of the China Squa dron daring the second week in July.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CANAL COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>Comte de Serionne, accompanied by M. Tillier, arrived at Port Said yesterday
                        from Cairo, and put up at the Canal Company's "Residence." They are to
                        remain wily a day or so.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENTERTAINMENT ON "LANCASTER."</head>
                    <p>The crew of H. M. S. "Lancaster" are giving an evening entertainment to-night
                        to those of the "Suffolk," in return for one given by the latter at Malta.
                        The programme will consist of a sketch, a gymnastic display, and variety
                        show. The stage, which has bean erected in Navy House by the crews them-
                        selves, will be lit, as will all the decorations of the auditorium, by means
                        of electricity conveyed from the vessels through submarine cables. Fairy
                        lights and bunting will be the base of the deporations. (By Telegraph). Port
                        Said, Friday. The "Lancaster's" entertainment last night was a great
                        success. The programme comprised songs, sword and axe swinging, flying
                        rings, and a comic sketch entitled "Jaffin's Latchkey." The ship's band
                        performed during the evening. The manager of the entertainment was Lieu-
                        tenant Wilton.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="shareMarket">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
                    <byline>(Prom our Pimamoul Corrnsfondut)</byline>
                    <dateline>London, June 28.</dateline>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p> Had we bean writing our report yesterday we should have been able to say
                            that the undertone in the Stock Exchange was stronger, on the improved
                            condition of affairs both as regards the peace proposals and the Morocco
                            question, bat, alas, today the pessimists hare again got the upper hand.
                            Prices throughout the general list are very "wobbly," due to a report
                            that the German reply to the dig- nified Preach note is not
                            satisfactory.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Paris has been a busy seller of most of her specialities dealt in in this
                            market This has in turn reacted on prices generally.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Consols closed at 90* after opening 90Ai a foil of | on the day, and
                            there is very little businees doing in gilt-edged secu- rities
                            generally, the tone /being rather in favor of buyers than sellers.
                            German I %, which opened at 88 , close at 88 , and French Rentes show a
                            foil on the day of J at 98.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>There is no feature of interest to report in the market for Egyptian
                            securities. Prices show little or no change since oar lest report.
                            National Banks are slightly off and Mow at 25 J, and Agricultural Banks
                            are particularly firm at 18 |. In the mining section many of the
                            principal jobbers are absent owing to the A soot races, which are being
                            run is glorious weather. Nile valleys closed at i A A, Sudan Mines, Urn
                            Eos 1, and Balt and Soda 1.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>We regret to learn of the death, which Occurred yesterday, of Mr. Albert
                        Bensilum, manager for the 8alt and Soda Company, Limi- ted, at Wadi Nation.
                        The marriage of M. Benvenuto Campos to Mile Marcelle Aghion, daughter of M.
                        and Mme Benjamin Aghion, was celebrated at Mme. Joseph Campos, near the
                        Palace Station, Ramleh. There was a very Urge and fashionable attendance,
                        which included many of the leading representatives of Alexandrian society. A
                        re- ception was hdd after the religions ceremony bed been performed, and the
                        guests had time to admire the wedding presents, many of which were of
                        exceptional beauty. The buffet was much appreciated and the guests did not
                        leave till 8 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kearsley and Cunningham's Weekly Report. Liverpool, Jane 22. Since the Market
                        reopened after the holidays Egyptian has been in active demand and prices
                        for the superior grades of Brown are raised J per lb. , other descriptions
                        are un- changed. In Futures a fair business has been done and the following
                        are the dosing values:— June 6.67 Aug. 6.58 Oct 156 July 6.68 Sep. 6.66 Nov.
                        6.63 Dee. 6.46 Americas Future* We did not issue any report last week as the
                        Market wee interrupted owing to the Whitsuntide holidays. Sines our last
                        report there has been considers his activity, and a further material advance
                        in vainer, at one time amounting to about 40 peseta. The whole of the
                        advance has been maintained, but today's closing values are @ 8 points
                        higher then thaw of our last report on the 8th inst. The advance is chiefly
                        due to extensive "Ball" manipulation in the 8 merino markets, based upon the
                        scarcity of good grades, which hare bean heavily sold for forward deli very,
                        to continued unsatisfactory reports of the condi- tion of the Crop, which is
                        aggravated by its unusual lateness. It is possible that these influences may
                        compel higher prices, bat in the neighbourhood of 5d. per lb. we cannot
                        recommend purchases, unless on sharp re- actions. The following art the
                        latest quota- tions :— Jane 4.86 8ep./Oot. 4.84 Jam/Feb. 4.84</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The 88. "Asriout," of the Westoott and Laurence Line, left Malta on Wednesday
                        and is doe here Sanday afternoon or Moedey aton- ing, with general cargo
                        from Antwerp aad London.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS</head>
                    <head>DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>Le paqoebot "Singapore" do la Cie Florio Rubattino parti hiar pour Genes
                        avait k bord : MM. F. Dements, M. et Mme Levi, Carlo Foret, Dr et Mme
                        Oaetani, M. Simaika, Parag Tiab, M. et M me Msggio, ProlNelli, Motzoli, W a
                        genovork. Prof. Ribooi, A.Rizzo et fom., Dorn. Levi, P. Leguna, B. B.
                        Charles, M. et Mme Porto, P6re Agoetino, Mile Greglia, M. et Mme Ch.
                        Lipinas, Veeoova Va'destino et oompaguoo, D. Tasso et eomp.. Mound Eff. et
                        neveo, Milo Mellonoini, Mile Roooatagliata, Hag Mohamed Sellami. Baronne
                        Fllix do Meoaaee ot dom , Mme Halifa Sachs et fillee, Mme Ida Tilehe et
                        fom., Dr Camerini, M. Piha et fom, Salome, Dom. de la fom. Piha, Mme
                        Rimediotti, Q. Nestri. Mme Proli et * fils, M. et Mme Corelli, U. Bocoia et
                        fom., M Buries®, Mme Pilniato vaska, Pavero, M. et Mme Mitris, K. 8torn, A.
                        Pardo et fom., G. Maruooo et fom., Mme Moroni et file, Prof. Pasole, Mme De
                        8emo et fil», Cap. di Maio, Dr Gataky, A. Finardi et fom., Pfcre Borioo,
                        Phro Cardano, dom. dames Corelli, Mme Corelli et fils, J. Decern, G.
                        Stormiolo et 144 pemagerede 8me olasse. ARRIVALS. Par P. and 0. as. "Syria,"
                        arrived yesterday from London at Port Said —Mr. and Miss Fletcher, from
                        Malta :-Mre. Page.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <p>LES QUAIS DU/ORT(EST Lea travaux dm quais da port Est, and Alex andrie, etant
                    proique term it) «v)u Municipal! t- a adroiso k l'oatroprise Almagik,
                    oonoossioii naira de cos travaux, une lettro appronv, e and le miniature do
                    1’intdriear et .de laqusllo i rossort quo la nioeptioa definitive de tom le-
                    ouvragea a etd fix5d d an oommun acoord ai. 30 avril 1907. Le caotionoement sera
                    rendu comme soi k I’Eatrepriae: Ia moitie le 30 avril 1905 ; Uq quart le 30
                    avril 1906 ; Un quart le 30 avril 1907 ; 11 est enteudu quo la restitution de ce
                    dernier quart pourra it re rotard t-o jusqek ce quo l oatrepreueur ait bieu ot
                    oomplhto meat execute loa travaux d'eutretiea reconnus necessaires par la
                    Commission d'inginieurs dans sa reunion d’avril 1907, ou, en caa de disaccord,
                    par l'arbitre, le tout en conformity de l’art VI. page 14, du rapport
                    yuellonnec, communique k l Kutreprue, k parrir de l'ali- nia common ;ant par los
                    mote "lea travaux d'entretien a exicuter, etc.'' En mime temps la Commission est
                    d'aocord aveo l'eutteprise aur les points suivants : I. Aussitut la pierro
                    cassie repandue sur les ebausseos, memo si le couronuemeut du parapet u oat pas
                    termini 4 ce moment, les voies ferries ot materianx de toate sorts exis taut sur
                    los terrains des quais seront immidia tement onlovis par I'Entreprise. Le
                    nipandage s^ra.fait le plus tot possible, et l'enivement dea vaies suivra au fur
                    et it meaure. 9. Les dyblais it faire pour la oonfection de la forme das
                    chausa5ea seront exJQtda par l’En- treprise ot k $es frais. Cos dyblais pourront
                    6tre diposis sur les terrains adjaoonta ou dans les terrains on contra bas,
                    ItoTrle quail; t5 rehaussi. 3. L'Entreprise 6ora autorisie k conservor jufqu'k
                    la fih de la piriodb d'entretien son appoutemont actuel ainsi qu'une voie Decau-
                    villo soigneustonent posio entre cot apponto- ment et son chantior. 4. Les
                    emplacements suivants seront laissia a la disposition' do l'Eutreprise jusqo’k
                    la, fin de la periods d'entretien : ,i) terrain le long de la jeWe de Kait bey,
                    d'uno snperficie d’environ 8.800 m. carrds ; 6) terrain an dela de l’ancien
                    abattoir de SiUileh, d'one snperficie d'enyiroh 6 400 m. carris ; c) Chantier
                    actnel de I'Entreprise, et terrain ii l’Onest de oe chantier. L’emplacement da
                    chantier actnel oonti- nnera d’empiiter snr la roe paratlMe et s'iten-
                    dradn'o'-to 8nd josqn'an ttrtr-fenoomte et k la cloture existants.' Si la
                    Municipality le riclsme, le terrain et la rus k l’onest dn chantier Seront
                    dibarrassis et remis k la Manicipaliti dans tm dilai de deox mois apris avis
                    prialable. 5. A partir dd'ler mai 1905 josqu'au 30 avril 1907, date l laqaelfe
                    l'extractlon des pierrei des carriires do la Municipality pour compte de
                    l'Bntreprise davra cesser, oette der- niire paiera k la’ Municipality une
                    redevanco 'de 94 mfiliimes par mitre cube ponr tontes lee pierws de la camera
                    mnnicipale dicharg6ee snr lea quids du Port Est et k Chatby, et destinies i
                    d’abtres travanrqne oeux de lu Municipality. n est tonjours entendn qne lee
                    prescriptions dn oahior des clauses et conditions ginirales et les cuses
                    techniques de I’entreprifc, de mime qua les modifications qni ont sum sont
                    maintennea dans lenr intigraliti en tant qn’eiles'ne sont pas oontraires anx
                    prisantes. D autre part, et en pitivision de ce quo la municipality ponrrait
                    a4oir besoln des pierriw pour la crijLtion_d'un enrochement destiny k la defense
                    dertravanxHelarwS projetie de la > corniche on ponr d'autros besoins, il est
                    d’ores et dyjk entendn qua l'entreprise s’engagera k fournir k la municipality,
                    dans le terrain de Chatby, k promiire ‘ ff*|ui9ition, et dans nn dilai do six
                    mois, une quantity de moellons et de grOs eftroohements pduvant s'Slaver jasqa'k
                    44,000 mitres cubes, an prix et conditions I* proportion des gros eardchemonta
                    sera toot wi pins de la tacitly do la foarnitere totale, la commando rfera
                    donnie k f Enterprise a rant le ler aoht 1906. Le prix seront les suivants : r
                    Avant I'enlSvement de la ferrie abontissant k Chatby, moellons jusqfi’i 40
                    ’kilos, P. T. I6 p«r m. oohi; gros eriroehemont* an deesns de 200 kilos, P. T.
                    20 par1 tonne.1 a0 Apris l eabvement de la vote fence abontissant k Chatby,
                    moellons jniqa'a 40 kilos, P. T. 20 par mitre cube, gros onroohe- ments au
                    desins de 200 kik* P. T. 25 par tonne. ■ Le volume des ssoellons sera mesnri aox
                    wagons, lepoids des gros onrochements sera ; virifi6 par la basonle de 1*
                    carriire au M^x. La municipaliU sera toujonrs libre de iaire oh de ne pas faire
                    oette commando, l’Enterprise de son cM ny 4taut tonne qu’an caa oh
                    1'admiDistntion (1st CheHuins de far continnera ' de lui aooorder ies mAioes
                    conditions qn'sctAel- ' lement poor le transport des pierres deatitidei- aux
                    travaux dela municipality, de‘U‘ dar- riiredn post an Mex sk d# Max k-Khait bey.
                    BULLETIN DB LA BOUHSB (AukmrtfUi d midi et demie) L’ylan donny bier So march4
                    n'a pas 6t£ de longue darde. Ce matin on k on vert en bonne tendance trait on
                    n’a pas tardy k rTactionner U Nationals retorobe k 26 1/16, la Salt and Soda k
                    34,9, la DelU light k 12 9/16 rx- ooapon, eto. Le nombre des affaires a 6U
                    exoeesirement Les Egyptian Estates et leTli^Btrtieiits i llior a eu lien k la
                    Bourse la vonte de 800 Ertatos k 13/16-27/32- et de 200 Trusts k t 3/1G. .Co*
                    deux yaleurs opt tr6s yprou- vyos cos aorniera tempr.' Li fonlo des joaears on
                    Bourse e'en ytant emparys bonnq houre, oos titres1.' ont ytyi'o'bjot de
                    monvementa aussi (14 iordonrids qud ridionles. Aprds avoir attaint des prix quo
                    ridd'ho jostifialt, voifk m'ainte- nant qn'iis eontinjasteni®if dyprdciysi '
                    Ainsi none voyons les abtibhs des Eitates, one sociyty-qni a dty formfio sons
                    lea meillenrs anspicos, aveo nn board do premTer''ordro’ et dont les affaires en
                    Bgypte^ont odnfiAd k d'babilos financiers, M. Montagn-Sommer et Lang-Andersbn,
                    Directear' Se la Socidty d’A- bonkir, tombar an dosaons do "pair; abit k 16
                    sbyilings, alord quo chaque action Odt re- prysfetde dans les caisses de"Ia
                    socidti par one' sommo do 20 shellings, plus oh Oertiin benefico, si la Sociyid
                    riialisatt les brillantes affaires qu’elle a entreprisos et oonelnos jos- qu'icL
                    La byrisse des Estates a poor causes: 1° le bruit qni a oSrould' en Bonrse, il y
                    a plnsienra somainos, qne do ‘ gros ’ pa^neti do titros anraientyty veudus avec
                    prime par ace admi- nistrateur rysidant en Egypte, loquel so strait ensnito
                    engagy dans de inuvellea sociytys aveo nn but'simflaire, 2’ le iWbV des banqoes
                    en ginyral de faire des avanoes snr les 'actions de la Socidty. Bien quelled
                    prytendent quo o'oat pour mettro nn frein an lanooment Ido nouvollos 8ociyty» en
                    Egypte qu’elles ont pris oos mosnros, il n'ea est pas moins extraordi- naire de
                    lei voir refuser le 50 ^ d'ivancts snr le prix nominal d'actions de premidr
                    ordro alora qn'elloa avancont le 75 % sot le prig lactico do certains titros
                    dont la valear a 4td snrfiute snr le marchy, de telle aorte qu’olles so tronvent
                    avoir avanoy It double de la' tai lenr nominale de certaines actions. 3* le
                    dSga-j gementdes groi joueors et Tongagement imf pruvoyant des petite qni, ne
                    tronvent d'appui auprea d'anenue banquo, jettent snr le marchd les titres qn’ils
                    ne peuvant payer. 4‘ lei babi- tndes de notra Bourne cm le bonseosnepryvaut pas
                    toujonrs et Oh il eat de mode de ne re- cbereber quo les titres chars et de se
                    rndfier des titres qui baissent, Ainsi, k mosure qho los titros abondent, les
                    achoteurs ae. font rares, et tendent k devenir plntOt vendeurs, alors qne o'est
                    tout le coutraire qui devrait raisonnablo- ment avoir lieu. Dads le marasmo
                    actuel, la spycplation olair- voyan'te, qui n’esl malhenreusement repry- seutye
                    ici qae par un fort petit nombre de per- sonnos, a li nno belle oocasion pour
                    ramasser un titre de toot repos qui reboudira k sa vyri- tabio valear,
                    c'o«t-i-dire avec' une lygOre prime sur sou prix demission, snssitflt quelo
                    flottant, qui pise tant su* le marobe, sera absorby. L’Industrie Sucrlere
                    Egyptieane Wstatistiques douaniiius aocosent dans I’importatiou du sucre en
                    Egypte pour le mois de mai 1905 une elimination de,L E 1,627 par rapport ii la
                    pyriode correspoqdante de l’annye deruic-re, tandis quo les exportations ont
                    ang- meuty de L.E 40.112 duraut la rndme pc node. Depuis le oommeucemeut de
                    l'exercice actuel, 'a Society des Sucreries ot RifSnerie d’Egypte a ainsi
                    exportd du sucre pour LE 230,000 de plus qua l’annce derniOrc. Uue pareille
                    comta- tation fait ressortir 4 I'dvidenoe la proepyrity croissante de
                    l’industrie sucriire dgyptienne. Syria e^ort-Eaid : 16 h-.jap, franc. P^tagal,
                    C>infie ; 2 j. 1/2, rap. Wl. Byx^ntionj cap. ivTom»ti toov399v)tK3H*y*>- ? 30
                    juin .MaraeiUeet,Jaffa; Lj. 3/4, vap. .frans..Marie • jilirabeUi, cap. Bonafos,
                    ton, 787,.4lJ)iab. iludikswaU et Newcastle ; 24 j. 3/4, ^ ang. .Nunima, oap.
                    Thoren, ttm. l„881;i,ordre, JEnejte ey'atras; 2 j, 8/4, vap. aatr.. Amphi-
                    tiitei cap. Jomasaevioh. tcn.,2,342, an, Lloyd Auiriohien'. ptpaaxs 29 juiu
                    Port-Slid et Syria Jap. frao$. -Equatcar, oap. .Aillend. - ' Mowlno et Qfines ;
                    vap. itfJ.. Singapore, oap. - .Coesovioh. ' ° ' Hull; vap. ang. Clio, cap.
                    Young. Constantinople; vap. angJJioido, c. Brombley, sift lest. ' ' Catane; vap.
                    ital.Salvo, c..PidaUlla, snr. lest. Let-' 14 Imperial Ottoman Bgrik ' ',,— „ 26
                    * Nsrtt Bankrdf'B^yptr'— » „ — dtf I do »••>; New 26} M........... Fos. 807 —
                    CryditFon Lit 13 | Agnoultur Pcs. 120 '^iiqner'd1 .let 1 A Hgypt Investment Go.
                    „ 9 J . UmdJbinlciof Egypt — Fes. 1000 — Agrioi-Indoat. Bgrpt... , LE 44
                    BsheraCompany Administration des Chemins de Fer et del TelejfrApbes AVIS
                    L’Administration des Chemins de fer met an ocraoobrs deux, postes
                    d’aide-ingynienr de Dis-. trict au traitement de debat de LE 12 par mois
                    (hors-cadre). Les candidate poor ces postes devront 4tre 3gds de21 ahs an moins
                    et de 35 an!s au pins; Lea ypreuves qa'ils auront i subir porteront snr les
                    matferei Indiqnyes ci-apr£a : ' LangJC arabe ot anglaise ou Tran jaise (parler
                    et ycriroX ‘ '' ■“ ' *“ T,mi' *' \ £ Arihmytiquo, Algkbre per at 2e,degyy,\
                    Gcomytrie (plane ot dans l'ospaoe), Trigonomytrie, Notions de mdcaaique et de
                    rCsistanoe dea matyriaux, Pryparation d'un projet avoo dessin mytre et devb
                    eBtimstif, H-o-.-tq • Opyrations sur le terrain, levor de plans et nrvellemlt, •
                    . . • Calculs de terrassemeuts, ' Pratiqde dM'txaVabx,'ma^onueries,matyriani de
                    eonatroeflotr,' dtc. ‘ * '*1 "*!"**' ‘! Les Candidate qui sauront soulemeut
                    parler 1’ahibe sans le Ihe ut, Pycrfte ikiKift 4dmta‘ k CctfoouWr ; tonthfofs,
                    ofedif qdf 'saurorivle par- ter, rycrire et fe lire obUendronVun plus grand
                    nombre'de points. “ -1 ’ 4 ' ,R ‘ 1" Les yprehves commenoeront le Lundi 10
                    Jnniet lWs ah Berridh Central', de'li.' Vote' i I'k y.mf • '• * '1 "• •'‘ Les
                    demandes seront revues jasqa'i Samedi 8 Juillet '1905V midi ah pltii tahi ;
                    etled'de- vront itre envoydes 4 l'adresse Be Mr I'lcgd- nfeur fn Chef de la
                    VoilertWtrafih'i a. Cairo, et 8tre acoompsgnes ’/'J 1,1 ’ ' 1. d'nh oettifioat
                    do naia ranOe on d’on oerti- Scat yqnivilent, : u 2, d un oertificat de bonne
                    vie et moenrs, 3. des certificate d'ytude qne le eandidat 4. dea oertifioate des
                    emplois que le eandidat aurait dOji occapys. ’ Le programme dee yprenves sera
                    sffieby k 1'entrye do Servioq Central de la Voie avant le jour de l'examen. Le
                    Cairo, le 28 Join 1905. 26184-1 A/vTs Le Coneeil d'Administration a l'honnenr de
                    [ygrapbique de Quirgaeh seront de 8 h. a.tn.|4 -«h. p.m. sans interroptiem. - -
                    .1 — f LeCiire,l8 39'JuLul905, 26183-1 (6WA4T. dm 39. w- •lSI’OOKS and .shares
                    Cloting Prices, today at 1 p.m. i t f ’ * w xLb * dSSRj „ ( j Land Mortgage. ...
                    — „ 93 { .New Daira SaniwPond. 180 wM 9mL - — 23/32 AngloEgypL.Spinxtng • ?.»
                    t-_r ‘ ’xkfio- — „ 23 — Bonrse, Kh6di viale — — „ IS — lpref. Cairo Be wage *'
                    '.'TrafiAort'm 60. Pos. 200 — exCr.BrtrWoiy AMx. Pftnd. 103 i-r—:**■ ..116— do
                    ‘vCaaaJtood. .'f-.6tr.. Bh. -4/9 — Egypt, CottOu. Mills ._ — » «/- ~ Markpts....
                    -- lpO „ f 34 9 — ^ do jSaft.^ *nd 8oda Pos. 70— Ciments d'Egyptd!?' ‘... 15
                    Let. — Brfpt' Trnefc A Invest 1} . 7 i Katr-ei-Zayat Cot, Coy. 102} .9 Nonyvich
                    Hbtels g Let „ 4 A Khedirial Mail-3.8.o- ,v - ftOm-Jonde. .16.3 15 i OX Alex,.
                    Water . Company — let 18* Delta fiiht*-*"...'--... 100 „---------Delta Light
                    Det.......... * 14 „ 9 — Payoam.. .................. — ,, J6 t , KenahrAssouan
                    ... — Pos. 156 ( Alexandria Trams ... 480 — — 3d* ” ' „ Ponds. |45 Let 7 }
                    Ramleh Railway'.-.''*••0- Pumished by Reid « Bernard 10, 8t Marks
                    Boito-AkMidiK'M'AaiU'KaMWL Cairosiv»ho:tafdettake.fte;salq and-MumkaSe of ,3
                    looks and Shkraei o» jUo loos^ Bourne. *i>1 :s^tTs«bi» o.-u. ‘i BOURSE KHEDIVIA
                    T-w at.! > «i»*| COfTPRATS Plnotnation* ft itmiL 0.1 asfci Dhsla fnktin6e; prix
                    pins han iwii /—rT ptu ^w prix pins haut pour juiL P.T. 58 8/4 k —/—: plus Las
                    pour juil 58—/— k —/—. (WtefiSp.™.) ,(CptOM.T—La lourdonr qui n'a oessy de
                    righer pendant toate la matinye Vest' changye marquebpoorje juiUet, yohy noo qui
                    cjntinue 'Y Le rWrtmbre, a en relativemont one moil- Wnre teune et resto gagnant
                    de -l/8V en Uftture.' ’ r)' y ‘ t* « ■ L'avant-bourse de Liverpool a yty quelque
                    peu dyoourageante. GrafeWftie’Cotou.— A la dernifcre minute il yJa eu
                    eodtieb/mkis quand'"m6me les affaires n'ont etf aueone impirtanoe. Bsteaux
                    partis V 1 28, 'Midlothian, pour Leith, Ton. 120 94, „ AV6n,' '' Liverpool, „
                    600 29, ,. •’Clio, Hull, „ 2500 Bateaux sous ohargement: aE Ckbral,
                    "pou'r-Loudrea, Too. 8000 „ Qrtcian Prinfle,' Dfthkerqay, „ fSO „ Lorenro, „
                    Hull, „ 400 Bourse Kh6dirialo, lo 29 join 1905. E«f»2ayat.. _ ^ D«. P-T, 265
                    rantah. _ _ - „ M>;860 '^^85 Province Qalionbieh Benha.........De'KT. 130 — k250
                    — SECTION DBS GRAINES BTCERRALES stolTBaaooeiAnomr- naraflu itwm Grain os de
                    opten Afifi, Pff. 57; 1/4, ; hP.T. — „ Haute-Bgypte „ 66 — „ „ — Fives 8aldi „
                    96 — „ ;qu« 00TPNS oopie dela dipScho di L'auucaMDiua- cmsii raoDOCi mgff0*
                    UTIRPOOL OOnOB AflSOOULTIO* (Coora jratiqoys oe jonr k la Bonrse Khydif !! -
                    -flMl/16 " '‘NOvembro „ i'll 19/82 „ -Jkmrier . MarohVfanno J^yygM de oe.joar, k
                    JtjeetplsBsMal 'Srpoftarions poor l'Angleterro balles 3,161 ' ' ,7 ’ 1 to
                    Continent „ 3,45 „ „ 1'AmAriquo „ 6K Btook k MineUd-Bassal, cantara U/10,13t
                    (Goars pratiquys oe jour k la Bonrso Khy^i-i -'■TaL’18' 87/^i isvraison Juillet
                    ;, 14 8/f6 ' Aoftt „ 113*21/32 „ -Novembro ., 18.-9/16 -Janvier March A ferme
                    iUUGUB DK-MIN KT»EL-B ASS A L ——■ i 30 join 1905.—(llh.55 a.m.) ; Ooions —
                    Ototure du marohy du 29 join Marchy forme, saasxhangement dans les prix. P*"’ Ru
                    «•* rillTr fstopk Pair, Fully Fait,-flood Pair, FnUy Good Fair et Good
                    liSanschangemeat aasai ,J2jne quality, lrp quality .extra; Sans change* ®ent ^
                    UHMOVICU 2me quality, Ire quality extra: Sans change^ ' ’ But dn marchy de oe
                    jonr, ootons: Calmej umu .uuwuu. j ; Les arrirages de oe jonr se ohiffren^ par
                    cantara 516 oontre mime jonr. l’annye Tiok*-. ’ Mit-Afifi—57 1/2 Rian
                    Haute-Egypt*-—66 Rien ’ ‘iflfe-^Ptor rtalrivages . Q%alitd:Sdidi.*~GcaA. Saha
                    P.T. — k — • .• .. ,, 1W k 111 hansse gaha P.T. - .Oind. Saha P.T, 115 k 125
                    rfajfrjSrptv M k 62 —ffpaSmn ® ’^aihaP.T 92k 95 Informations Ces^pjsi^^
                    ep^rwaiont en viguear 1 Let prix luicanti amt tUpratUpUe oe jonr .flZwP?1) par
                    Csmtar Prorinoe Bybyra .Pamaahour. - AZ.f.90 Tp-p^TJS ^XOHA^GB ROTATIONS Banks'
                    Ban',,' * buying Selim** Lmdon cheque. -------97 A 9? ii „i;m;haakpeper.. - 97 A
                    97 s ,, 84l hodsc paper _ 96 }| - - Pans cheque _ _ _ _ 388 — 389 i „ 3m. bank
                    paper _ _ 386 j 387 1 8m. house paper — _ 385 } ---- r zslfl Germany cheque _
                    476 } 478 j „ 8m. banx paper _ 473 J _ _ Italian cheque . _ _ _ 888 — gOo —
                    Vienna 4 Waste cheque _ 405 4 *07 4 fS^s.^-Total des anltages depuis le lei
                    (topteinbrt(,1904-'jaAqti’k ee-jCar, eenttrs 8;199J806 ‘ ‘ ■■■>«-■*- Grain** de
                    ooton.—Total des amveges depuis -le ler septembre 1904 jusqu'k ce joar/Ard:
                    .3,476,629’ Contra mime jonr en 1904 : tasquRB xt omornra di m. Coton- -----
                    -,-iS/B — . Grained de ooton.. — — — sacs 702 JEaffir- _ - - _ "177 !f7. Byhy»
                    345 Fkveeflatdi- - - - - „ ' -750 1,; -Bybyra. — Chge _ 10 Leutillei — — — — — —
                    f)otcm*.—Tptal .des vrivagea .d^aia.Je. le •^ta^bra ^.jusqu’k ot^joai. otattj
                    Oratnee de colon.—Total des arrivages depui •tolM ^anbre 1903--joaqali 'W
                    joirAld CONTRAT8, (llb.55a.rn.) Corns de. k Bourse doiMiaeiol-Baesal Ooton
                    F.Q.F.Br. Norembra—N R TsJ. 13 11*16 k — Janvier - _ „ 13 19,32 „ —
                    Man...........- ,,.18.8/4 „— Juillet _ _ 13 31/32 „ — Aoht- - - „ ,14 7/82 - ...
                    P.T 6' 5/40 k — JtflHet.........‘ „ 5S. *V*» „ — 'Ahflt............., -59 rS,40
                    „ - .SHAK LIST lesoxD it tux "Asbociatiob db Conxnxau u Valium d'Alxxaxdxo".
                    ---- * Cldtura d|auk>uid'hul k 12h.45 p.m. MaSp-'f ■iT.-i** Ramleh Railway _ „ 7
                    } „ — _ Egyyttoto itolta Rail- -.f.nny — — „ 12 | „ ex coup le—Foe. 156 — „ 156
                    1 WRl El „ "712/ m - - V ~ ** -M/31 riv. Poe. 200 — „-- „ „ , Div. „ .105 — u
                    110 - „ dqCaito Priv. „ ‘*15 — „ 116- „------,, ' ‘Wv. „ 60 — „ 61 - Bgypt
                    -Cotton *141111 let 4/9 — „- .*eltAfldd«-‘ y 84/6 - ..84/9 - .OUig.AtodhiJhnoter
                    jgPjMfUrfr 816 J, -317 j- Aajlo-Amerioan Nile Let 5 | ---- Banque d’Athines —
                    Fee. 120 — „-- Defined Belt*.. - 1st 14 j „----- .Nuagorich- Hotel s _ „ 9 — „ —
                    } > 5/40 k - ?tv4) „ - • ..AtokrOet- - P.T. 91.1/4 k — BXXARQUZS Cotom:
                    Nonvelle' FSoolte.—Le norembra a ohvert k 13 S/6'ikhif «rraff«rmir-(W'»alte k IS
                    11/16. be marehy poortanf' o'ertr ptubien -actif. -'-■*•••' * • ‘ - ' ‘ ■
                    -Ryoolte aotunlle. Juillet a dyboMkUJ/|2, Oratnee de ecton: WootMla rtoolta- du
                    29 juin 1905 PBCpuntr BGYPTJBNB t ... '■'VyfaffAfcji-* - -fc Ooton: Btai dn
                    Ma'rcU.—Forme ^tyWWIVde hausae) AtotarxJoin: 7 ‘16/64 (8/64 ’dehaaue) -LlTXRXOhL
                    .................. BULL -JMft* epto^-^Mfln0 situation Ptoes.—Soptenuei Future
                    juiL-ao4f fWl^B points de hausse) m oot-nov.: 6.16 (3 points debausAe) . MW i»
                    l“5~) .,to8y*is5^^ter) Middling Uptorid^.Wfssus ohangemsut) WUllM
                    y^YiyphfatoMelidsw) •a noftt; 9.45 15 posutadedtoisse) Arrivages dq jour, bailee
                    10.000 ^C^dre..mlmajpur, ,l'a«i4q(^?uira. b*lle' la-'cheque— - 88 || per mills
                    brokerage. .. 60 — „ 61 - Lit 4/9 — „------------ I, 84/6 — „ 34/9 -
                    TrUrtlnySatinent — „ DOiraenk ............... Entreprisos Urbainee - U i 9 — „ 8
                    A .. 1 9/^2 9 — „ wU 4 A,. -k_ 1 11/32 _9 T ASSOCIATION, DBS COURTQaffl'Brr
                    MARCHANDISB3 ^ i >i i -^Aeix.^IRli) « ’ oot-»ov.: 5.13 Seoonde Dyp6ohe, lOh. 10
                    a.m. Future : juiL-aoht: 5.16 : „ oet-nov.: 5.15 TidisiAme DypAche, 10h.l5 am.
                    Future .-Juibnofft !'5.T9' otaswr: 6.18 Quatriime Dypccbe, 10b. 20 am. Future :
                    juillet-aoht: 5.22 „ oot.-aor.: 5.21 DHRNIBRB HBUIIB (GWture de
                    laBouaeihydiviale lb. p.m.) ; Cpinre.de 1‘Aaw^ifam^des Courtiere eu Ooton
                    F.O.FJ3r. Noveabre - TaL 13 27/32 k — 7/8 Jknrier . - —„ 13 8/4 „ — 25/32 1 Han
                    - - — „ 18 29/82 „ — 15/16 Juillet- _ _ „ 14 3/32 „ — 1/8 Aoht — — _ „ 14 11/82
                    „ — 3/8 . Orainet de coton N.-D.-J. - P.T. 60 10/40 k------------ Jurfiet... - -
                    „ 58 30/40 „----- Aoht - - ..........-3rSW/40 „ — 25/40 PT 96 3/4 ‘ 97 - C". L".
                    AVERAGE TIME oocupied in transmission of ' Egyptian telegrams from Bugland to
                    Alexandria on Thursday, 29th June, 1905. ......1 *" "OftrirARDe. MVMallioliKiS
                    UHus. udS jun. MXS8A0B ni AT PROM The "o£r'‘ w H. M. n. m. 12 27 Liverpool
                    Manchester 19 20 n Glasgow Other Provincial Offioas 1. 2 36 nilk .;
                    itrjr^.TX'Gra: ^4*6 “"im. 'i5.45 45.97 '46 46 "46.96 4*.46 46.93 •*46 46.91
                    ^4,6.44 45.91 >*.44 .4494 -46 46 46. 0 {46.47. 46. 2 45.47 46. 6 '46.64 46. 6
                    '"46.49 46. 6 *.64 46.12 "45.45 46.22 45 4 6 46.80 45.48 46.84 •45.47 , 46.40
                    45.52 46.48 46.54 46.45 '*46 '46.49 46.60 46.49 *69 46.49 * 56 46.49 *66 46.61
                    *'6 46.66 1 45.r0 46.72 ‘ 45.60 46.74 *68 46.76 ••*68 'HA76 f ’ - 46.74 IMA IMt
                    *11. 1 11. 5 11. 8 11. 7 11. 2 11.10 11. 3 11.11 It. 2 1112 11. 2 11.16 11. 2
                    11.17 11. 1 1118 11. 1 11.19 11. 1 11.21 11. 0 11.23 11. 0 12. 1 11. 1 12. 8 11.
                    2 12. 4 11. 1 12. 6 11. 1 12. 4 11. 1 12. 5 11. 0 12. 8 1 11. 0 12.12 10.23
                    12.18 11. 0 18. 1 11. 0 IS. 1 11. 1 13. 5 11. 1 18. 4 U. 2 ,18. 8 11. 1 IS. 8
                    14.50 14.56 14.50 14.62 14.50 14.66 14.50 14.69 14.50 14.72 14.50 14.76 14.50
                    14.79 14.49 14.81 14.60 14 85 14.60 14.89 14.48 14.94 14.60 14.97 14.60 1« 2
                    14.50 15. 4 14.50 15. 5 14.47 15. 1 14.48 15. 4 14.48 15.10 14.48 15.20 14.48
                    15.32 14.50 1346 14.60 16.50 14.50 15.50 14.60 15.50 14.50 15.50 14 50 15 50
                </p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, JUNE 30, 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOST ANCIENT TEMPLE AT THEBES</head>
                    <p>Was this a pyramid ? Not one like those at sakkara or Ghizeh. since the small
                        part of the casing that has been preserved does not slope like the -ides of
                        a pyramid, though it has a decided batter. Besides, a true pyramid is always
                        built of regular layers of stones or bricks, and does not contain loose
                        rubbish fid it contain, or at least conceal, a tomb as a true pyramid should
                        1 We made several sound -ings in the centre and at the comers , a pave- ment
                        of blocks of -hat Dr. Schweinfnrth pro- nounced to be rock salt was found,
                        everywhere else the rock, no tree* of a pit of any kind.</p>
                    <p>What is most probable is that it was a base- ment or platform with the usual
                        Egyptian cavetto cerrnoe and a torus or angleSad. each corner of thee we
                        have round frag- menu), on which was raised a further con- struction of some
                        kind. This cannot have been an altar or a sanctuary, as in this case we.</p>
                    <p>In them we found beautiful fragments of coloured sculpture, showing the
                        remarkable development of art under the Xlth dynasty, hie priestesses or
                        princesses are represen tod in relief in various scones ; offerings are
                        being made to thorn, and the holy xows and calve of llsthot are also
                        represented. It is worthy of remark that in each tomb was placed a skeleton
                        of a cow, the sacred animal of tho goddess to whose service the favorites of
                        Men- tudietep had boon devoted daring life Two breeds of cows seem to bo
                        represented ; one brown and homed, the other dappled and hornless.</p>
                    <p>For these priestesses were made tho lime- stone sarcophagi, mentioned above,
                        cf which three wore found intact Ono of those, being uninscribed and
                        unornamouted, was not worth removal from the tomb. A second, of the
                        priestess Henhonet, has also been loft in posi- tion. Another, which was
                        made in six separate pieces, is most beautifully sculptured, but not quite
                        finished, since it is evident that colour was intended to be added to the
                        engraving. The princess for whom it was mado, Kauit by name, is seen iu the
                        icpresentatious on its sides living what was supposod to be bor life in the
                        other world. Offerings are being mado to hor, while an attendant dressej Lcr
                        hair and artistically iusorta a hairpiu into the coiffure. A priest milks a
                        cow lor her, aud aftorwarda brings her the cup, saying, “This is for thee,
                        drink what I give." (On a finoly sculptured and ooloured slab from tho
                        shrine of another princess, named Sadhe, a priest or courtier brings the
                        deceased lady a bowl of beer, say- ing, "Beer for thy ghost I") This is the
                        first time that a sarcophagus has been found sculp- tured with scenes of
                        this kind. This boautiful and unique monument, tbo finest of its kind of the
                        Middle Empire period, and probably the finest relic yet fouud of tho Xlth
                        dynasty, is now in the Cairo Museum.</p>
                    <p>A fourth sarcophagus had be u broken into small pieces. This is most
                        unfortunate, as it was not only sculptured, but also painted within and
                        without. Tho fragments will be exhibited at the annual exhibition of the
                        Egypt Exploration Pund in July. It belonged to a priestess named Kemsit, who
                        was a negross. She is always depicted as black, not only on the fragments of
                        hor sarcophagus, but also on a band of fresco, which runs round the interior
                        of her tomb chamber. Her mummy, which has been brought back to England,
                        shows that hor cranium was of a negroid type. ( To be continued).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANCIENTS KNEW NILE SOURCES.</head>
                    <p>Few people realise the extraordinary riches | in the shape of literary
                        treasures that lie hidden away in the various old castles and chateaux of
                        Europe. In England a royal commission has been at work for years searching
                        and delving the muniment rooms and the archives of the ancient bouses of the
                        aristocracy with the most astonishing results, historical documents of
                        almost priceless value having been saved from the rats, from the insects,
                        from the carelessness of servants, and even from rubbish heaps. It is a pity
                        that no snch commission exists in Germany, where no systematic search has
                        been inaugurated, and where the investigations are oarried on by individual
                        students and scient- ists, either at the instance of the owners of the
                        castles, or else merely with their permusion. (Joe ol the grandest of these
                        old German castles is that of Wolfegg, in Wtlrtemberg, belonging to the
                        Prinoaof Wald burg, and com- manding a magnificent view over Upper 8ua- bia.
                        Rummaging in the immense library of this ■fiediieval stronghold, Professor
                        Pischer, ol Peldkircli, has discovered a German map of the year 1507, which,
                        bearing the name of a leading geographer ol the fifteenth and six- teenth
                        centuries, name-1 WaMsoemuller, de- lineates with amazing accuracy the two
                        great lakes that constitute the sources of the Nile, and which, according to
                        all modem geogra phioi, encyclopedias and other standard con- temporary
                        works of reference, were first dis- ooveied about forty aix years ago by
                        Speke, Grant and Sir Samuel Baker. Yet Aristotle, in speaking of the cranes
                        of Lower Egypt, declare- that they "migrate from the Soy thian regions to
                        tho lakes lying above Egypt, from which the Nile arises," and Hero- dotus
                        also makes mention of these lakes. Prom this it will be seen that there is
                        nothing new under the sun, and that the sources of the Nile were perfectly
                        well known at the time of the diaoovery of America, and that in some strange
                        way they became lost’ to the geo- graphers and scientists of the seventeenth
                        and ' eighteenth centuries, and had to be discovered [ afresh in the
                        nineteenth oentury by the ex- j plovers Speke and Grant.</p>
                    <p>Prince Waldburg is the hereditary grand master of the Court of Wurtemberg,
                        and as long as the holy Roman Empire was in exist- ence the chief of h:s
                        family was hereditary grand carver of the empire. The family traces b-ick
                        its deboent in an unbroken line to the year 1100, and is very wealthy.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COTTON INDUSTRY IN JAPAN.</head>
                    <p>Hi tbo.-lo a coving in Japan has been prin- cipally a home industry. The
                        number nf concerns wa- nrer 600.000 in 1*93, and at present there will
                        probably be lit.lo over half this number, the decrease being due, ofoourse,
                        to the gradual centralisation of the industry under the factory system. In
                        1903 there were 710,395 looma in Japan, 97 J per oent. of which were
                        hand-looms, the actual number of power looma being 17,898, and of these
                        about half wore in the weaving sheds of the Kobe dis- trict. Probably there
                        may now be rather more at tho present time. The value of the total
                        production of pieoe goods in 1902 was rather over lfiO.OOA.oi 0 yen, 46 per
                        oent of whioh were silki. 12 per cent half silks, and 37 per oent ootton
                        goods; the rest were woollens and flax goo Is in about equal amounts. It
                        must bs remembered, however, that 1903 was s very unfavorable year for the
                        ootton industry of Japan. In 1900 tho value of tho ootton pieoe goods
                        produoed in Japan was 60,000,000 yen, against 56,000,000 yen in 1902.</p>
                    <p>Apart from Aichi-ken, the ootton industry is chirfly developed in the Kobe
                        district The production there in 1902 was valued at 81 million yon, or about
                        56 per oent of the pro duction of the whole oountry. For export goods Osska
                        and Kioto are the principal centres. O-aka, with its neighbouring towns,
                        producol piece-goods valued at 7,791,180 yen in 1902, consisting of plain
                        whites, unbleached shirtings, flannelettes (raised on the back), drills, and
                        coloured goods. There were three largo mi’ls in the district The Osaka
                        Bosoke Kabusbiki Kwaitha, with a capital ot 1,000,000 yen, was originally a
                        spinning concern, but developed the weaving branch, and in 1901 had 1,200
                        power-looma and produced 15,000,000 yards ootton pieoe goods, with an
                        estimated value of 1,400,000 you. Tho Kanakin Seisho- ku Kaboahiki Kwaisha,
                        capital one million yen, in addition to yarn spinning produoed about 750,000
                        yards of shirtings, worth 67,300 yen, on 806 looma The Temma Orimono
                        Kabusbiki Kwaisha, capital 500,000 yen, makos shirtings and T-elotha, and in
                        1901 produced pieoe goods to the value of 750,000 yen. Tie total number of
                        workers employed by these three mills is returned at 6,286 (*0 per oent of
                        whom are woman), and about hall of thorn are employed in the spinning
                        branches of the first two firms. Of the three oon- cjrus named only the
                        second declared a divi- dend iu I9'3. The total number of weaving oiooeim in
                        the Osaka district, including those with lea* than 10 workpeople, may bs put
                        down at 350 (this being estimated from the number of members in the three
                        large ootton- weaving guilda) Their oondition cannot have been a very
                        brilliant one in 1903, but from the nature of the oaaa it ie impiasible to
                        form a correct judgment</p>
                    <p>The export ol pieoe goods from Japan in 1893 only amounted to i.nor.nss yea,-
                        oe about 7 per oent of the total production ; against this must be set
                        imports valued at 5.700.000 yen. After ten years (1903) the imports, in
                        spite of the constantly growing requirements of the people, were only about
                        double those of 1893, being estimated at 10.700.000 yen. On the other hand,
                        the exports were about five times those of 1893, amounting in 1903 to
                        8,270,191 yen. this being about 16 i*r cent of the total froduotion of the
                        oountry, which had doubled during these ten years There can bs no doubt that
                        this branch of the Japanese textile industry ie only at the beginning of its
                        development. The fol- lowing table shows the amount exported to the various
                        countries</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRICE OF TOWN LANDS.</head>
                    <p>The following letter by a correspondent to the "'rimes" in reference to land
                        in New York will be read with interest by land owners in this country, more
                        especially sinoe Cairo, the first town in Africa, has often been compared to
                        New York, in its eerlior days, as having similar possibilities :—</p>
                    <p>Comparisons have been made for many years of the selling value of land in
                        London and in New York. These are always based upon the prifies of small
                        plots of land.in certain restricted diatrjcta, that in New York being the
                        Wall- street or financial quarter. The latest illustra tion ia furnished by
                        the sale of a pieoe of ground at the oorner of Wall-street and Broad- way,
                        immediately opposite the ground of Trinity Churoh. lt has the advantage of
                        not only a frontage of 30ft. on Broadway, but of 39fL on Wall-street, thus
                        giving it the distinc- tion of being No. 1 of tho latter street. It is
                        covered by a four-storey brick building, and ia surrounded evorywhoro by
                        stool structures ranging from eight to 20 storeys in height The prioe paid
                        for these 1,170 square feet of land is 8700,000 ; the rental ia 825,000 a
                        year, to whioh are added the taxes on the property, making a total of about
                        833,000 a year. Toe prioe figuies ont at 8398,29 per square foot,or 84-15
                        per square inoh. To put the matter in another way, it means a value per acre
                        of 826,051,412.40, or about SJ million pounds sterling. When the first known
                        transfer of this property was made, early in the 18th oentury, the prioe was
                        £103. In February, 1748, its price had increased to £260. Ten yean later it
                        was sold for £400, and in 1780 for £1,000. The latest transfer before that
                        made the other day was mado on April 27,1827, when it was sold for 818,275.
                        Sinoe then the property has been in the same family. The reoent owner, the
                        late Benjamin D. Silliman, a New York lawyer, who died in 1901, reoeived
                        three years before hie death an ofler of of $400,000 for the property, and
                        aooopted, but at the last moment the proepeotive purchaser changed his mind.
                        Now, seven yean later, the prioe has risen to 8700,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JAPAN IN KOREA.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A MENDICANT ARMY.</head>
                    <p>Accounts reaching Paris from the Algerian border leave no room for donbt as
                        to the heavy blow which the French Government hts dealt to that of the
                        Sultan of Morocco by dosing the frontier against the passage of monitions
                        and supplies for the Shereefisn tropps in the Udjda region. The entire toree
                        has been thrown into entire disorganisation by •emistarvation. It is several
                        months sinoe even the European officers drew any pay. As for the native rank
                        and file, they have been rednoed to e mob of mendicants, varied only by bri-
                        gandage when circumktanoe* are propitious.</p>
                    <p>AOAMl/a INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES AND TRADE NARKS RMQIBTKR. - A ussfcl
                        bosinass dizwtorjr son mining siMnwss Of all important businas* firms of
                        Great Britain lha Ooolmait, aid Xgypl Oirenlating all ovar ■drops and
                        Amarira. Pries—On* pound Btsriing. AO AND B INTERNATIONAL HOTEL Q VIDE sanl
                        post free to all firet alasa Hotel* . Tha^ftk which England has done in
                        Ewjp* Japan is nVw oomg uTAtma, ana irom the ac- counts Whioh have just
                        reached Europe it would seem that they are doing it with all that grasp of
                        the problem before these end patient atten- tion to detail whioh, in other
                        spheres of their activity, have produoed euoh marvellous results. They hare
                        appointed competent ad risen to the Korean Government, who are infusing life
                        and energy into that almost moribund body, they have already reorganised the
                        polioe so well that order is almost as easily preserved now in Seoul as in
                        Tokio, and they have plaoed the army under the oontrol of a Japanese
                        general, who will, we hope, succeed in making as much out of the unpromising
                        material to his hand *8 fellah. They are replacing the debased cur- rency by
                        sound money, and are enoonraging the moat enterorisiag of their own people
                        to acquire and cultivate as much land as possible. Realising that facility
                        of oommonioation is perhaps the most powerful of all civilising agents, they
                        are everywhere building railways, though the nature of the oountry makes
                        frequent tunnels neoa*sary, and therefore adds greatly to the expense, and
                        they have thoroughly reorganised the whole of ths tele graphic, telephonic,
                        and postal servioe*. All this, be it observed, they have undertaken, and are
                        oarrying out with perfect success, while they are fighting the greatest war
                        in their history, and one of the greatest the world ha* ever known. It is a
                        truly wonderful reoord of achievement, and if she had nothing else to point
                        to, Japan baa an irresistible claim on this alone to be regarded as one of
                        the greatest of the oiviliting Powers. In Korea she is creating wealth and
                        making happiness . wbat more oen any nation olaim to have done for Humanity
                        1 IfTf*. Ths bss» rahraoss book 1or tnnUsrs. ADVERTISING AGENTS.—beatpublio
                        “ Advertising sites in Alexandria halnng to G. Vestri Co.. Advt Agents, St
                        Catherine's Square. Special rates for permanent clients. Moderate terms.
                        Prompt despatoh. 25642-81-12-905 ARABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian tutor
                        to Europeans. Apply M. Shefik, "Egyptian Gaiette offices. 26888- APPLY for
                        French, Italian, Arabic, German, *V to the Bor Lit* Schools, Alexandria (26.
                        Roe de l’Bglise Copte): Cairo Sharia Kamel), Most rapid method Trial lesson
                        free. Evening classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per month. 23069-80-9A-9 05
                        DLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9. No. T £11. W.T. Emmons, 99 Rue Attarine,
                        Alexandria, Address, Post OfSoe Box 85. 804-905* nHIBF ACCOUNTANT first rate
                        CmRrffiK want* occupation after office hoars. Apply to this paper, XV. 348.
                        26185 9-1 ENGLISH MASTER desire* post at tutor Aj during summer holiday*
                        Apply, L Vi- gour, English schoo', Cyprus. 26165-12-5 T AN CASTER HOUSE
                        Sharia Wabcur-el- D Moyah, Cairo. Comfortable apartments, with or without
                        board. Terms very reasonable. 25599-15* 6-905 1( OUNTAIN CAMP, for boys
                        daring sum- mer holidays. Apply, Percival Mayall, B A, Headmaster, English
                        School, Cyprus. rLBT, furnished, at Ibrehimieh (Ramleb), splendid villa ; 10
                        rooms (6 bedrooms), drawing-room, etc. ; large umbraged garden 3,000 pilu ;
                        electrio light, etc , etc. Apply to Mr. Have, Villa des Roses, Ibnhimieh,
                        near Doctor Cognard, or to the postoffioe. 26147-158 rLET, at Ibnhimieh
                        (RamlebX Furnished Plat; 5 rooms ; private entrance and roof Near sea,
                        tramwmy station, and Sporting dnb. Apply, C*pt. Gordon, Ibrahimieh, or Mr.
                        Camming, Turf Club, Cairo. 26166-6-6 r Sporting Station, self-con- e ; 5
                        room* ; bracing position ; A tlined House ; 5 rooms ; bracing position ;
                        July to September. Apply, No. 26,U8. "Egyp- tian Gaiette" offices. 26178 6-2
                        WANTED SITUATION. - Chief-eoooont- • i ant, cashier, corresponding linguist
                        ; bank ; English testimonials ; long practice.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <p>4 TH1 IQTFTIAir QAITT1, FEIUAIT, JUNE 3ft,. IMS. EXPORT MANIFESTS. Poar FIRES ot
                    ODESSA, p« la taU*u rilMe “Emp. Nicolespahi le«8 join : Divers, 195 sacs rir,
                    809'vvsd oigiibna, 10‘ctBs seen*, 252 oolis temstei, 4 oilis peaux, 11
                    oolB^irera Q. F ringer 4 Co., 70 blles 00toil For LIVERPOOL, by thrfSB. “Avon."
                    sailed on tie 21th Jiihe : Carver Bros. Co. Ltd, 600 tons ootton seed N. Huri,
                    517 balos ootton O. Riooken, 50 „ ,» H. Biudornagoi, 125 „ », X. Coostantinidis,
                    50 „ „ B. J. Coiiry Co., 193 „ Bank of Egypt Ltd, 157 „ „ Mohr 4 Fendorl, 281 „
                    T. Ghirghis ot fils, 170 „ „ Choremi, Benachi 4 Co., 205 „ ■■ Carver Bros. 4
                    Co." Ltd, 217 „ ■■ B. Barlri, 610......... Imp. Ottoman Bank, 233 „ „ " - wo.
                    100 bales senna ■onol h*ds« noonings Butterworth 4 Sdalley, 39G bags bones
                    Hadjes 4 Co., 754 bags bones Khedivial Mail, 305 bags grain G. Feinsteip, 63
                    bags boms Sncreriei et Raff., 2.000 begs sugar J. 4 A- Abonchanab, 1,055 bags
                    oil oake Butterworth 4 Smalley, 8 bags buttons B Nathan 4 Co., 17 bags gum
                    Various, 28 packages sundries Pour PORT-SAID et MA3SAWAH, par la bateau italien
                    "Enna,” parti le 25 join : Kustor-4 Co..'24-oolis ferronnerie Levi bt Lsgnado,
                    14 cais. ferronnerie L. Paleologo, 10 oolis provisions D. Liacachi, 25 „ „ F. G.
                    Cotsiomiti, 16 „ „ P. Papadakis, 20 „ Divers, 40 oolis divers Pour PIRfiB et
                    ODBS3A, parile heteeu roase “Tiar," parti le 27 juin : Divers. 90 sacs fix, 112
                    cais. cognac, 118 cai*. verrerie, 38 barils Tides G. Petraochi 4 Co., 25 bailee
                    ooton REUTER'S TELEGRAMS CLOSING REPORTS LnmrooL, Jude 29, 1:0 p.m. Sales bb the
                    day....- — bales 10,000 of which Egyptian ... .... 1,500 American (new crop)
                    Maiie Spot peroentel... ... ... — — oft Amer. futures(July-AugBst) ... 5.17 „ „
                    (Nov.-Dee.).. 5.16 >s'“ . ... .. 7**/•* „ „ „ (August) 7 12/64 1 . I .. . -
                    (Nov.) 7 5/64 Egypt. Brown fair per lb. d. — _ 6 6,16 good fair — — _ 7 2/16 „ ,
                    good _ — — 8 — ,, fhify good fldr.........7 7/16 Egyptian 8aidi Beans new (per
                    480 lbs.) 80/3 Nsw-Yobx, Jana 29. Spot Cotton... — — — 9.90 American Futures
                    (July) _ — — 9.26 „ (August) _ _ 932 „ ,. (November) . - 9.50 „ „ (DfiWb«)_ -
                    '9M Cable trmufcn _------— dol 4.87| Cotton day's reoeipte at all U.- Rrts.. _ _
                    _ -bales 10,000 LrrnpooL, June 29. Ammsn futures (July-August)... — 6.16 Lovdov,
                    June 29. Private discount (I month bills) _ 21% S3Sc = = Si Rio Tinto _ — — — —
                    ... 62 — Rand Minas New _ — — — 9 J Egyptian Unified • _ _ _ - 105 - „ Railway _
                    _ - — 101 * „ Domain. _ _ — — 101 — Ottoman Defenoe - - - - 108 1 Turkish
                    Unified — —. — — 87 * Nati^jJ Bank'of Egypt _ _ _ *6 j Delia Saaiab _ _ _ _ _
                    101 — 'Sew Daira... _ _ _ - - 28 1 Greek Moaopoie.. _ _ - _ 68 J mu**: z z t\L z
                    z z z | Nile Valley Gold Mine - New 1 } The Western Owit^Corporation | premium
                    8Si!a£et^ffj^y^2 JSSST Notes reserves £ :3S*.080 LWtfiOO Other securities „
                    33J26.000 „ 28,719,000 Bullion „1w!3ft.Jb0 „ 88,8*1,000 ProfKAtion of reserve to
                    liabilities 46{ % P«Lia, Juuo 29. Loti Tnraa. _ _ _ _ _ 182 — Credit Lyonnais _
                    _ _ _ 1096 — Ottoman Beak... _ _ ^ _ 607 — agw^a«g r r ”«I CrSSt
                    Foncier'Biyptien _ _ 809 — V.amne'd'Athlnes............. 119 — Land Bank of
                    Egypt .......... 227 - Alexsndria Mel Vareboase Cj. Ltd. 80CIRTR DBS BNTOBPOT8
                    D'ALBXANDRIR Prefermoe 8hare 6 % Payment of half-yearly Coupon. *-**+***•»*, mwi
                    TBLHGRAMMH HAVA'S BOUR3B da 29 join 1906 00DBA DU VALEUBS IUO, Cl/OTOIX PARIS
                    Rente FftliMlae-S / . ._ ... Pr. 98 67 ActioiUaeBhdx . - _ _ „ 4500 — Lots
                    Turns... ’ -i. ™ „ 132 — TnroDnifiA. - - - ... 88. $5 Detto Egyptienna
                    dJnifile.... 106 — Daira Sameh _ _ _ _ „ 101 20 CrABtFbnoitr Bfrptien- _ „ 801-
                    Obl BmiqneNat. de’Grtoe „------------- Banqno d'Athbnes, nonvolloa notions _ _ _
                    ‘190 — Mltropolitafn —— Basse oonsolidl.. — — — 88 — Sosnowioe— _ — —,— Change
                    snr Lon dies.. _ _ „ 25 16j Snore N' 3 disponible _ _ „----------- Sucre N* 8
                    lrrrable le 1 de mars ,---- LONDRES Consolidls anglais _ _ £ 90 —
                    Bsoomptos—Paris 3. Loudres 2i, Berlin 8. OBR’BAL M A R K‘B‘T ROD EL
                    FARAG(NaTiTOAi'RiSi’8SHt»aAH) Y E^rniDAT’s'FBreis Wheat, Tngari... Art. P.T. 112
                    to P.T. Ill Middling „ „ 116 „ „ 118 Mawsmi.. „ ,. 125 „ u 180 Beans, Tngari.!!
                    !,’ " 105 !! 107 „ Zawati............. 110 „ „ 112 „ Old.............. - » h -
                    Lentils, Tngan.... „ „ 95 „ „ 96 ./ Zawati „ „ 108 „ „ 114 Barley,
                    Tuguri.......... 72 „ „ 73 „ Zawati............. 76 „ 77 73 , 75 „ Hamawi.. „ „
                    — „ „ — Data »h«mi............. 102 „ „ 105 „ Rafia .... „ 97 „ „ 98 Helba......
                    — „ .. 180 „ „ 185 Tmls............... „ 70 „ 72 Hnmmoe ........ ,, „ 160 „ „
                    175 Ormu in Boat at Sahxl Wheat ._ ... Ard. 2000 Beane ........... 1500
                    Lentila.......... 200 Barley....... „ 300 „ Shami, „ 500 „ Hamawi „ — Data Shami
                    _ „ 50 „ Rafia _ „ 70 Helba _ _ » 50 Allen^ iMdierson Go X,I3VCITEII3. SOLE AND
                    -EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR l Misiu. KUSTON, BB0CT04 4 CO., LIMITED, Lisoolm. Piled
                    »nd PurtiUa ijtewa ead Oil Eeiiae. Com UiUe. Patou-Tibbon-making Thrashing
                    Machines. Musses. PLATT ‘BR0TH8M CO., LIMITED, Oldhaic. Cotton Ginning
                    Machinery. si Messes. JOHN FOWLER A CO., LIMITED, Lkbds. i Steam Ploughing
                    Machinery and Sundries. | THU OBNTKAL OYOLONK CO., LIMITED, Lo«oo». Grin dim and
                    Pulverising Machinery. 5 Messes. OAMMELL, LAIRD A.CO., LD., ok SHKyviELD. g
                    Stoel-BMb, eprings, buffers, 4c. — Patent,sand blast Wes. k. Messes.
                    ME^RYWEATHER A SONS, London. -Mkess. F. REDDAWA!Y. A CO., LD.,
                    BrnraiaroN.-MANouBSTRE. The Camel Brand Belting, eto., etc. Gflkes ‘Vortex;
                    Tnrinnee. Messes. A. RANSOMS ‘AOo., LIMT’l'BD, Niwauk-on-Teent. Wood
                    Working'M46hinery and Applianoes. MoOOKMIOK’S reapers a MOW'RRS. PLANBT JUNIOll
                    AUalCULTCILAL OIPLEMUNTa. Horae Horn, Seed, Drills, etc^ eto. OLIVER PLOUGHS.
                    Agont ttt Ottlro i i. A. FATTUCCI. Agont In Khortoum a RIKTl BKRTBLU. G. MARCUS
                    A Co. sons- Aaasra rot Motpt fob MILNERS SAFE COMPANY, LIMITED. Transatlantic
                    Fire Insuranoe Company, Limited OF BAMBDSQ. (OOVlKB ALSO BUBOLABY BlOggJ The
                    National Assurance Company of Irelaml. Fire InsqrMioe Policies granted on
                    all-approved Descriptions of Property, at moderate rates, ALEXANDRIA, Meteoo A.
                    N. Abut, Baa Oonrtentinople. OAIBO, Hifti Iree 17-1 La-906 Tie Egyptian Della
                    li^tMlviys Ltd. The Daira Sanieh Compiay, Limited. NOL1S
                    CtWales................Shgs. 1/3 k — Tourteaux.................. 4/6 „ — Grainee
                    de ooton.............. 5/ „ - Oignon*..................... — „ • LONDKZ8
                    ClnSales ... ...........Shgs. 1/6 h Tonrteeax................ „ 6/ „ jr~*
                    Giaines de ooton ........ „ 7/ Oignons.................... — — Graines de ooton
                    ......Shgs. • 8/6 - . 9/ ClrialoB....... — ........ 1/6 „ 1/2 UTUNOt
                    Coton..................Shgs. 11/ k — Clrlales................. „ 1/ „ —
                    Tohrtoanx.. ............. „ 6/ „ — Graines de ooton ........ „ 7/ „ — Oignons
                    ... ... .......... — „ — (nxirraT- doxkxkqux > Graines de ooton (Dunkerque) Fr.
                    10 k — „ „ (Nantee) ... „ 10* „ — Fives...................... „ 10 „ — Oignons _
                    ............. — „ — — Co ton -. Odessa, Trieste, Veniso, Glues Marseille Fr. 2.—
                    ") Beroelaoe.. .... 2.50 ir> Dunkerque ... „ 2.50 Ariven.......... ' 2.— 1
                    Hambonrg. ... „ 20.-- k 22.50 ; St-Pltennonrg „ *5.— (par-tom New-York ... „
                    25.— ( poids Bonfbay....... „ 80.— J Alexandria, le 29 jnin 1905 DIVIDEND
                    WARRANT No. 15 BEARER WARRANT COUPON No. 12. An Interim Dividend at the rate of
                    2 % for the half year ended 31st "March 1905, : (sabjeot to Inoome tax) on the
                    Preference Share Capital will be payable on and after '•« 23rd Joee 1905,
                    af-the-National,Bank ’wpt, iondon or Cairo and Alexandria, nrent rate of
                    exchange. ;t .ujreu Share' Dividend Warranta will iu: >bd pu the' 23rd Jane.
                    26171-5-3 ;i.-.terei Share ‘ Dividend ' ■:.red ou the 93rd Jane. par 100 kilog.
                    Municipality d’Alexandrie AVIS La MonioipaliU met an adjudication le dallage das
                    troia roes an qoartier Menayer. Le oaotionnement estfixl k LB. 65. L» oahier dee
                    eharges eat iMpoed an Beiean de la Voirie oh Q pent «tre eonxnlM par lee
                    mMiernfe ton* las jonrs de 9 h/k midi, lee jour* ftrila exoeptos. Lee offres
                    derront Itre adressdos sons pli cache to k Monrienr l’Admiiiiitmtanr de la
                    Monieipalito avani le 11 jaiUet 1905. RAMLBH RAILWAY COMPANY. RBCETTES da
                    dimanohe 18 join an samedi 21 join 1905 Gamete Billets Abonnaments et Divers
                    P.T. P.T. P.T. Annie oobr.87,867 — 15,890. „ der. 76,469 2,129 8,336. Augment
                    11,898 Diminution 2,422 7,551. Totacx.—Annie oourante 103,757 tanitteder- Tiihre
                    87,927; Augmentation 16-530 du lor octobre-WOl aa medi 91 join 1905 Carnets
                    Billets Abonnemants et Divert P.T P.T. ~ P.T. Annie ooor.t.SnBM 272,813 190,319.
                    „ der. 9,848010 615,806 218,888. Augment 192,181 171311.' Diminution 619,991
                    Toiaox.—Antile- oouiWrte' 8,800,568 : anode demihre 8,179,881ipA^pDontotion
                    120,874. ALEXANDRIA TRAMWAYCOMPANY da dimaooito 19 Jain an samedi 91 Jdim 1905
                    Billets eTDivers ’’Totami. p.T. p.t. At. Aandeoonr.127,161.1 15,628. 143,Q89.1 „
                    der. 112,639.3 16,120. 129/13F.9. Augment 14,821.8 Annie ooar.2,662,723.1
                    276,276.7 1,98 „ der. 9,822,611.8 228,677. 2^1 810,111.1 tUH.T TUB KUEDfYIAl
                    MAIL STEAMSHIP 1HD GRAVING DOCK COMPAMY LIMITED NOTICE is hereby given that
                    tfi#„ bail yearly % CoiBolstivf Prefsrenoe dividtf-jd coupon ffa id will Lo
                    i-aid by the Imperial Ottoman Bank, Alexm.uria, or Messrs. Olyn Mills Carrie 4
                    Ca, London, on and after June 80th 1905. 26167-6-5 NOTICB IS HEREBY DIVEN that
                    an RirainnniVkHV Gull UAL MXBtUTO of the i above Company will be held-at the
                    Offices or ’• the National Bank of Egypt Cairo, on Satnr- ® day the eighth day
                    of Jnly 1905 at-12 o’clock l noon, to consider and if thought fit oonfirm . the
                    following Resolutions whioh ware passed by. the requisite majority, at a
                    GeneralMeetiug U held on the tenth . June .1905 end whioh if 3 confirmed will
                    beoome and be Speoial Reaolu- _ tions, that is to say :— 1. That the Company be
                    wound up volun- tarily. ) 2. That F. T. Rowlatt Sub-Governor in Cairo, Egypt, or
                    toe national Bank of ”OTt “d A.G.M. Dickson, Sub-Go- d emc in Alexandria Egypt
                    of the il -V Bank of Egypt be and are n oiuted Liquidators, for the e . ‘-rpcsM
                    uch winding up with -foil 5 ’ointly or Mparately. i • Iii.b of Jane 1905. ■•I
                    .’*>"• ‘ tie Board, 8. DE BILL. £ 1 /-8±rma, Xgypt, | S tuKAUaxL CAIRO. 8T8VHNS,
                    sdanoo do1 la Ddldgation le mime jour k 5h.p.m. L’envoloppe * dhvra porter eo
                    outre la men- tion : '‘Sonmission pour Dallage de trois rues au qoartier
                    Meuaycr." Le oautionnemeut ou le re«a d'uno banque, d'aprhe las conditions du
                    oahier das ohargaa, dovra Itre remis toparlosnt au Service de la ComptobiHM
                    GlnWale avani 1‘oirrertare das offres et an plus tard'le 11 jnfilet k midi.
                    Touto offre qni ne remplit pas lea oonditions ci-dessua sera feartoe. ^ p_
                    CjlAXAWA Y. Alexandrie, le 27 join 1905. 26172-3-3 ATI 8 ' U Mtoiioipalito met
                    en adjudication la fonrnitora dee divbrs imprimis et registres □Icessaires k ees
                    services poor les annles l606rW0(J et 1908. Le canitonDemenb eat fix! k L.B.
                    cent Le eah^r des charges est dlposl au Service de hTGo^ptabilitl Gdndmle oh il
                    pent 4tre ooniultl par les interests tous les jours de 9 hi k-midi, les jours
                    flrils exoeptos. - Los -efkes devront fltre ad resales sous pli eseheto i
                    {Monsieur 1*Administrates de laJMa- nicipahte ftvant le 18 jaillet 1905.
                    --Btteiplurront Igalement Itre dlposles en slanoe de la Dlllgation le mime jour
                    k 5h.p.m. L’envoloppo devre porter en outre la men- tion: 'Roumission pour
                    l'lmpression dei divers Luprimlket registres.” vLeCoMtfonnement on le re^u d'une
                    banqno, d*aprts les conditions du oahier des charges, devra «tre remis
                    slpetomsnt au Servioe de la Comptabilito Glrtoode a rant l'ouverture des offres
                    et au plus tard le 18 jaillet k midi Tonte offre qai ne remplit pas les oondi
                    tions (Memo eera loartoe. L'Admiujetoatear. (rittto)'P.’W.CaiTAWAT. 571 Old
                    Beoal Stki LONDON, RC. Shareholder! holding C re Warrants to bearer who wish fi
                    attend ‘b vbove Meeting, must first deposit -their aser Warrants,
                    together_witha-stetoceitji sir names tand addresses,'either vritb ' m -IS .
                    ionaT Beak of EgJT?tinG«iT07Ji'Al*xs.-,di:\ . bo olear days before the' d%te of
                    the sad M - ting (vis : not later than the 6th Jaty) or with ho National Bank of
                    Egypt’in London, 4 and u King Wil- liam Street, RC., tm dear days before the
                    date of thi«ld4f«ting (vis : no: later than ^mSEK^kZStl Eaoh .depositor*,^
                    ,neeirea Uwtii:»ta,of deposit in esekiega lor-the. share. V- irrants deposited
                    and a tioket of admissi «hieh mastbe produeed by the holder attending the
                    Meeting, and a form of Proxy. If the depeaHo* dees not intend -p realty to
                    attend the Mpoticg a.PfflW, in. f-wor of lodged with the National Bank of Egypt
                    in Cairo or Alexandria - nob lorn them 18 bur. ■' pimSMiSafifeg 26127-8* I ;
                    ---------------------------------- —■ Egyptian Delta Light Railways Co.,
                    Limited. Connections made with the most important trains of the State Railway in
                    the Pmrir,,. Of Bohoxa, Uharbieh, DaltahlioU • Uarkioh. and. Oalioubieh Through
                    ter vice lor qoodt l»tw all stations of the Oompauy and over 100 principal
                    itaiions oj the State Railway in Upper u. I I.llDn. I— 1.1 ".• * HaaiI, -1m La
                    iKmimli 11 11.I—I t —. — —_ . ■ * .( " 1 1 Lower Egypt. Goods may also be
                    through-booked from or to any station on Heloua Railway. The Company has 70
                    stations opened for pubUo Telegraph Serrioojin oonjuuotion with ill offioes of
                    the Government Telegraph Department For time tablet, iartft and in/onnatim ipply
                    to the offioee at Cairo, Alexandria, Danmnhour, Tantah or Zagasig. 21116 31-12
                    'J')5 ( HpXOUAN (IWANCH. ) For line tablet, lartft and injomati,. _Tantah or
                    Zagasig. 21416 31-12:905 ilia Agents for Egypt and Sudan of
                    COMPTOIRMErAJLLUaGBJDB BQYPflBN HUMBOLDT BNQINBRIMfTwORKS CO ^ I
                    ^4tj.jriAX,CoLoqMi. *K HORNBY* SONaLTO^*0"**' GaAXTHAX1(Eaai-AHD). ^ KIROHNER 4
                    ,00., Lxipna. CARL-MEISaNaTSuiWM. OU M0 beau .an! laaocba*. ENGLISH AND AMERICAN
                    SYSTEMS OP STEAM PLOUGHING ENGINES TO PLOUGH 8 TO 80FRDDANS PER DAY. Titos. Cook
                    Son (Egypt), Ltd, xwanrKKK v boklac, xaiwo. Alexandria. MECHANICAL AND
                    ELECTRICAL ENGINEERS, ALSO .SHIPBUILDERS, 40, 40 All olassea of engineering work
                    and supply of stores undertaken. Pontoon Dock for miring vessels of .the largest
                    rise. BOULAO ENGINEJ.WORK8 Bbakouxs at Sharia Bab-Bl-Hadud (CAIROX ALEXANDRIA
                    AND KHARTOTM. SOLE AOKNTd 1ST XOYPT FOB RICHARD GARRBTT 4 SONS, LTD. SHAND,
                    MASON 4 CO. raunl Buam and lUcaal Fin Matfim. NOBEL’S EXPLOSIVES CO., LTD.
                    OaU0eu.BlaallwOaUa. dauoMara,a>fai>(aaa, aM. BJUaUia” ami "Houma" omridsaa. GEO.
                    ANGUS 4 CO., LTD. *»1Uo« *m*5jeamb.. rabbu. TANGYES LIMITED fSOLB VBNDOBS.)
                    STOHWASSBR 4 WINTER PUTTIE LEGGING 4 MILITARY EQUIPMENTS CORPORATION LTD.
                    Asaalafcr laauBun *U>. auaa aad OU XaK* Waeou. CHUBB 4 80N’S LOCK 4 SAPS GO. LTD
                    COCHRAN^4 CO. ANNAN, LTD. THB SEAMLESS STEEL BOAT CO., LTD. OROMPTON4 Ca, LTD.
                    fHB C00PBB 8TSAM DIQaKR °°’ LTD’ Draaaa, neaora Mad alaeerio maoblaaiv ot aU
                    Saaerlpeloa. Dloan Bad* ta> alaa Ko. t, a, • and 1A SrxciAunxa.—TANGYR3' GAS
                    ENGINES with. Prodnear Plants, OOOPBR PATENT STEAM DIGGER, specially suitable
                    for small landowners. Telegraphic Addrett: "ENGINEER, OAIBO”and “BNQINBBR,
                    ALEXANDRIA:' Works Office in town. Sharia Bab-Bl-Hadeed (Cano). 96298 Alexandria
                    Offioe and Stores, Aba Dirdar Street, No. 19. 10.12.905 GLEAN WALLS AND WHITE
                    GEILINGS ARE ALWAYS POSSIBLE AT A MINIMUM COST PiR(XVID.BD TOO US E (BEOD.)
                    F:RE:SjK.E-L“,i,j THE GREAT SANITARY WATER PAINT. ECONOMICAL - EFFECTIVE.
                    Composed of strictly first class non-poisonous materials, Thoroughly
                    incorporated ond finely ground. SHADE CAROS 4 CIRCULAR OIVINO FULL PARTICULARS
                    .ON APPUCATION TO THK MANUFACTURERS 08. HINSHKLWOOD k CO.. AE.STAKDS1A CREDIT
                    LYONNAIS CAPITAL 250,000,000 DE F ’.ANCS BsTltHEMKHT VEartfa Agenoee d'Rgypte:
                    LB CREDIT LYONNAIS fait tontes opera- tions de banque, tollee que -. Avanoee sur
                    titree ; Ouverture de oomptoe ooura .'.i xmtre d,t p5ts de valenre; Emission de
                    txaitee et o' lm- de lettres de Crtdit, paiem - toWpr,., ,« snr 1m prindpalea
                    villas dr ' 1 «noe at d«. Reoouvrement d’effete ear l'Brq.te et ‘WSit Lyonnais
                    remit des kti. oa an ooatpte da dlpOt et dUivw dm bon* 4 lahdtoee fixe sax taux
                    suivante: 9 % aax bans de 1 on et au-delk. -OHM . 9119—1 «%• TEINEMAKN, MABARDI
                    C° The Egyptian Engineering Stores. MilRGHANTS, CONTRACTORS MACHINERY IMPORTERS,
                    ALEXANDRIA. Sola Agents for. .Egypt, Asia^Minor and Syria for Masers. CLAYTON 4
                    SHUTTLBWORTH, Unooln, Portable 4 fixed Engines 4 Boiler*, Cora mills, abashing,.
                    Strwrbrnising. 4 .Cutting Maohines. Messrs. GALLOWAYS, LTD., Manchester.—The,
                    Vg0*1 Boiler Works in the World. WALTER A. WOOD, Mowing and Reaping Maohino Co.
                    Hooeick Falls,' N.Y. (Amenoa) Reapers, Mowers, Harvesters 4Rakoe. PIQUET 4 Co,
                    Lyons. — Frenoh Steam Engines. AVBLING PORTER, LIMITED, Rochester.—Steam Rollors
                    and Steam Ploughs. LES TANNERIES LY0NNAISE8, Oullins (Rhflne).—Best Leather
                    Belting. 15.8. HINDLBY, Burton, Dorset—^Vertical Engines and Boilers, specially
                    designed for driving Electric Dynamos 4 Centrifugal Pumps, eto., eto. ihLAIRET
                    HUGUEOT, Paris.—Electricians. gsgaasgai^aesuem___________________________»»»»»»
                    ^NOUVEAU REMEDE PUR GAT IF IDEAL BIHt prtral yem Wpts 0* MHUW ***</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
