<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kara Hofmeister</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-04">January 4, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 4, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 4, 1905</head>
            <div type="item">
            <head>PORT ARTHUR’S FALL</head>
            <head>CAPITULATION CONDITIONS</head>
            <head>RUSSIAN WRECKAGE.</head>
            <head>NEWS NOT KNOWN IN RUSSIA.</head>
            <p>Port Arthur, January 3.</p>
            <p>The capitulation of the town was signed at
            9.45 yesterday evening.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>St. Petersburg, January 3.</p>
            <p>The fall of Port Arthur is unknown to the
            general public. It has hitherto only been
            known to the official world, and to certain
            restricted private circles.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 3.</p>
            <p>In the conditions of the capitulation of Port
            Arthur, it is stipulated that the officers of the
            garrison will return to Russia on parole and
            the men will be sent to Japan as prisoners.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 3.</p>
            <p>The Russian officers will be permitted to
            return to Russia on parole. They will retain
            their swords. The Japanese occupied a number
            of forts to-day.</p>
            <p>The Japanese are very annoyed at the
            destruction of the ships arid the despatching
            of destroyers after the oiler to surrender. The
            newspapers, in consequence of such action,
            demand that the garrison shall receive severe
            treatment. It appears, however, that the
            destruction, etc., occurred after a Council of
            War had decided upon surrender but consider-
            ably before the Commissioners met.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 3.</p>
            <p>Three torpedo-launches have arrived from
            Port Arthur. There are now 7 Japanese
            destroyers in the harbour.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 3.</p>
            <p>Apparently all the Russian destroyers reach-
            ed Chi-Fu and Tsingtan safely. The Russians
            destroyed all the men-of-war, and wrecked the
            remaining forts, together with everything
            valuable.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>EUROPEAN PRESS OPINION</head>
            <p>London, January 3.</p>
            <p>All the comments of Europe and America
            agree that the fall of Port Arthur will conclude
            a military drama without parallel in history,
            on account of the valour and achievements of
            the victors, and the heroism and devotion of
            the vanquished. It is thought that the war
            will continue unabated.</p>
            <p>The Standard states that the end has been
            worthy of that marvelous conflict between men
            who were equally matched as regards an
            inexhaustible resource of unflinching courage
            and un ailing endurance.</p>
            <p>The Morning Post says that the capture of
            the fortress is one of the finest feat of arms on
            record.</p>
            <p>The Daily Telegraph states that the attack,
            demanding appalling sacrifices, has crowned
            the victors with glory.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BALTIC FLEET.</head>
            <head>MEETING OF TI1E SQUADRONS.</head>
            <p>Passandava Bay, January 3.</p>
            <p>Admiral Foelkersahm’s squadron is anchored
            here.</p>
            <p>Admiral Rodjtstvensky’s squadron is now at
            Autongil. Both squadrons are provisioning at
            Nossi Be, Mojanga, and Tamatave.</p>
            <p>It is believed their rendezvous will be Diego
            Suarez.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tananarive, January 3.</p>
            <p>Admiral Foelkersahm’s squadron has anchor-
            ed in Passandava Bay.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PEACE RUMOURS.</head>
            <p>London, January 3.</p>
            <p>Various inspired suggestions in the direction
            of peace are emanating from Washington, re-
            presenting Mr. Roosevelt as anxious to mediate
            but unable to move until approached by both
            the belligerents. Nothing whatever con-
            firmatory has been received here, and the
            peace rumours are not Credited. </p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>A MUNIFICENT GIFT.</head>
            <p>London, January 3.</p>
            <p>Lord Mount Stephen has given £200,000 to
            the King’s Hospital Fund.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
            <head>HELOUAN SPORTING CLUB.</head>
            <p>We are requested to state that Prince
            Mohamed Aly was present at the Helouan
            Sporting Club’s meeting and acted as judge.
            His Highness spared no paint to make the
            meeting a success. Prince Abbas Pasha Halim
            was also present.</p>
            <p>In the Sahara Stakes the order was: Bibieo
            1st, Sattam 2nd, and Aeolus 3rd, while in the
            Desert Handicap Mizzaud was 1st and Royalist
            last.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
            <p>Cairo Water Company.—Sir Elwin Palmer
            has been appointed member of the board of the
            Cairo Water Company, in succession to the
            late Tigrane Pasha.</p>
            <p>The French Gunboat “Raoce” arrived
            at Port Said from Algiers on Monday after-
            noon, and leaves for Djibouti on the 6th inst.
            She is commanded by Capt L Blanc.</p>
            <p>Judge Assessors. — The election of judge
            assessors for the Alexandria Mixed Courts will
            take place in the hall of the Alexandria Mixed
            Tribunal on Monday next at 3.30 p.m.</p>
            <p>Accession Day. — On the accession day of
            H.H. the Khedive, a fete will be held in the
            Ghezireh Gardens and a special performance
            will be given at the Khedivial Opera House,
            Cairo.</p>
            <p>Cairo Dogs.—Large numbers of dogs are
            being poisoned and shot by the Cairo police in
            the city, but as fast as they disappear others
            come from Ghizeh and Galioubieb, so that
            little effect is noticed.</p>
            <p>Another Record Cargo of live stock ar-
            rived here yesterday from Alexandretta by the
            Bell’s Asia Minor SS. “Bravo” (Capt J. M.
            Laron), viz, 3,177 sheep and 87 bullocks,
            besides about 450 packages of merchandise.</p>
            <p>Zizinia Theatre.—The performance of Tris
            tano e Isotta yesterday evening, though well
            given, received rather a cold reception at the
            hands of a fairly large audience. Adrienne Le-
            couereur to-night should draw a crowded house.</p>
            <p>Fire at Alexandria.— A fire broke out
            early this morning in a grocery and spirit shop
            in Sharia el-Warsha. The fire originated among
            a quantity of packets of matches, which ignited
            some mastic and paper. The damage is esti-
            mated at about L.E. 10.</p>
            <p>Shepheard’s.—The grand ootillon ball to be
            given to-night at Shepheard’s promises to be
            an enormous success, as over 800 persons are
            expected to be present, including many of the
            leading members of Cairo society. Persons who
            have not received invitations will not be
            admitted.</p>
            <p>Church Services.—On Friday next, the
            festival of the Epiphany, the services at St.
            Mark’s, Alexandria, and All Saints,’ Ramleh,
            will be as follows:</p>
            <p>St. Mark's.—8 am. Holy Communion.
            11 am. Morning Prayer.
            6.15 p.m. Evening Prayer.
            All Saints'.—8 a.m. Holy Communion.
            4.80 p.m. Evening Prayer.</p>
            <p>Double Murder for- P.T. 50.—The Keneh
            Native Court has passed sentence of death on
            one Hussein Darwish, of the village of Barak-
            ma, Keneh Markaz, who was found guilty of
            the murder of both his uncle and aunt. Some
            time ago he deposited with his victims the sum
            of P.T.50,for the return of which he had applied
            on more than one occasion. His uncle, being in
            poor circumstances, was unable to pay the
            money and always postponed the time for doing
            so. At last, when the man’s patience was ex-
            hausted, he took a knife, went to his uncle’s
            house, and murdered both him and his
            wife, afterwards confessing his guilt to the
            Parquet.</p>
            <p>St. Joseph’s Home, in the Moharrem Bey
            quarter of Alexandria, gave a delightful Christ-
            mas Tree fete yesterday. A large number of
            ladies were present including Mme. Girard,
            Mrs. Chataway, Countess de Zogheb, etc. The
            fine Christmas Tree was given by Mr. von
            Pitner. It was bedecked with innumerable
            toys and beautifully illuminated. The tree
            had been decorated by the ladies who organis-
            ed the fete. The delight of the children who
            are so well looked after at this excellent insti-
            tution was a treat to behold, and gave a well
            deserved pleasure to the lady patronesses,
            who had been at great pains to organise the
            fete for the children. The fete was in the
            first place due to the initiative of Mrs. G.
            Debbane, who was kindly assisted by the
            “Dames de l'Ouvroir des Mires Chretiennes”
            and by many young ladies of Alexandria.</p>
            <p>The Egyptian Slave Trade. — An Anglo-
            Egyptian abolitionist has passed away by the
            death in London a few days ago of Mr. Charles
            H. Allen, F.R.G.S., who was for 19 years secre-
            tary of the British and Foreign Anti-Slavery
            Society, in his 81st year. Mr. Allen came of a
            Quaker stock. Throughout his life he showed
            special interest in the development of Africa.
            At first his attention was largely concentrated
            on Egypt, where the British Government had,
            recently undertaken great responsibilities. He
            received invaluable assistance from General
            Gordon in pressing for the abolition of slavery
            and the slave-trade throughout the Egyptian
            dominions; and seldom did General Gordon
            come to London without visiting Mr. Allen to
            discuss some plan for the liberation of the mil
            lions in the Dark Continent. A warm coadjutor
            was found from the first in Lord Cromer, who
            rendered splendid help, both by his general
            policy and also by promoting individual
            schemes such as the Home for Freed Woman
            Slaves in Cairo.</p></div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p> 2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-1x.7</p>
                </div>
            <div type="item"> <head>OUR ROYAL VISITORS.</head>
            <head>DUKE OF'CONNAUGHT’S ARRIVAL</head>
            <p>It is now expected that H.M.S “Essex,”
            conveying T.R.H. the Duke and Duchess of
            Connaught to Egypt, will come to Alexandria,
            and not Port Said, as was originally reported.</p>
            <p>The Royal visitors will be met on their arri-
            val here by H.H. the Khedive, who will after-
            wards accompany them to Cairo.</p>
            <p>H.I.H. the Archduke Otto of Austria has
            left Cairo for a caravan trip in the Sinai
            peninsula, which will last for about three
            weeks.</p>
            <p>H.R.H. the Crown Prince of Norway and
            Sweden is expected at Shepheard's Hotel on
            the 10th inst</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
            <p>The Khedive has been paying a visit to his
            estates at Mariout.</p>
            <p>The State ball at Abdeen Palace will take
            place on or about the 20th inst.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>KHEDIVIAL HOUSEHOLD.</head>
            <p>The Khedivial Household has been reor
            ganised at follows : Ahmed Bey Chefik has
            been appointed director of the Arabic and
            European bureaux and Mohamed Bey Izzet is
            to be head of the Turkish section. The post of
            secretary-general is suppressed and replaced
            by that of first clerk to the Khedivial secretarist
            to be filled by Chawki Bey. Ravon Bey is to
            be chief of the archives department. Harris
            Bey Fahmy and M. Oudin Bey remain chief
            of the Arabic and European bureaux respec
            tively.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ACCESSION HONORS.</head>
            <p>The list of Accession Honors will be pu-
            blished in the next numbers of the Journal
            Official.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>HONOR FOR BREWSTER BEY.</head>
            <p>The announcement that the Khedive has
            bestowed the grade of Grand Officer (2nd
            class)of the Order of the Medjidieh on his
            English private secretary will be received with
            great pleasure by the members of the British
            colony, among whom Brewster Bey counts
            many friends. The Bey has been 35 years in
            the service of the Egyptian Government,
            having entered the Customs Administration
            and Coastguard Service in 1870. In 1879 he
            was appointed Director of Customs at Suakin
            by the late General Gordon. This post he held
            till 1882, when he served in the Egyptian
            campaign on the Commissarist stall (medal
            and bronze star). He returned to Suakin in
            1883, and served under Baker Pasha in the
            Intelligence and Commissarist Department
            and was subsequently appointed by the late
            Admiral Sir W.. Hewitt as Sub Governor, in
            addition to his duties at the Customs. In 1884
            he was appointed Commander of the Imperial
            Order of the Medjidieh, and in the following
            year he was lent to the Intelligence Depart-
            ment by the Egyptian Government, and was
            attached to General Graham’s force. He was
            present at several actions and at the taking of
            Tamai, being mentioned in despatches. He
            remained in Suakin as Director of Customs
            until 1890, when he was transferred to the
            Coastguard Service at Alexandria as Secretary
            and Controller. In 1891 he was selected by
            the Khedive Mohamed Tewtik as his Private
            Secretary, and acts now in the same capacity
            to the present Khedive, his son. He already
            holds the rank of Bey of the first class, and is
            Commander of the Imperial Ottoman Orders of
            Osmanieh and Medjidieh, and Chevalier of the
            Francois Joseph Order.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>MOTORS IN CAIRO.</head>
            <p>The motor car is becoming, more and more
            one of the regular features of the traffic of the
            Capital, and it is satisfactory to note that the
            drivers are showing a reasonable regard for the
            convenience and safety of the public. There is
            one point, however, as to which it seems
            desirable to draw their attention. This is that
            the mere fact of their having a good clear
            stretch of road before them does not justify
            their driving at high speeds in narrow streets
            or near footpaths occupied by pedestrians. At
            any moment a tyre may burst, with the im-
            mediate consequence of whirling the car sud-
            denly round to the right or left, and plunging
            it into the midst of a crowd of passers-by with-
            out leaving these a chance of escape. Several
            fatal accidents have already occurred in Europe
            in this way.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>SHOUBRA BRIDGE SUBWAY.</head>
            <p>The new subway under the railway, that
            was to have been opened for public use during
            last month, is still far from complete, and we
            shall in all probability be well on into the new
            year before it will, or indeed can, be opened,
            The roadway has been pierced and the side
            walls built, but the iron roofing has yet to be
            fixed and the approaches constructed, and this
            means no small amount of labor. That, when
            completed, it will prove a great relief to the
            foot traffic over the Shoubra Bridge there can
            be no doubt, but, if it is to be rendered really
            effective, it will have to be placed under
            constant supervision, both with regard to the
            uses it may be put to and for the prevention
            of obstructions and blocking. Very much of
            its utility will depend upon the approaches,
            as if these are not convoniently placed and
            arranged they will very largely discount the
            value of the accommodation the tunnel will
            afford.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PILGRIMAGE REGULATIONS.</head>
            <head>NOTE BY THIS GOVERNMENT.</head>
            <p>A Note has been issued by the Government
            of explaining its intentions in imposing the
            regulations of this year upon the pilgrimage.
            The Note points out that, so far from in any
            way exploiting the pilgrims for its own profit,
            it has to pay a considerable charge to the
            Khedivial Steamship Company, being obliged
            to guarantee a minimum number of pilgrim
            passengers in return for the reduction of their
            fare.</p>
            <p>The Government points out that the oscort
            of the Mahmal has been increased to 400 men,
            causing an additional expense of L.E. 5,000.
            The pilgrims, of whom 1,614 have expressed
            their desire to accompany tho Mahmal, will
            thus benefit by obtaining greater security and
            the best medical care that can be provided.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>Bubonic Plague</head>
            <p>Today’s bulletin records a fatal case and
            two deaths at Suez.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>CASE OF-PLAGUE ON STEAMER.</head>
            <p>The SS “City of Agra,” which arrived
            at Suez yesterday- from Calcutta, had on
            board a suspected case of plague. The steamer
            was disinfected by the quarantine authori
            ties and the patients were conveyed to Moses
            Wells for treatment.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>QUARANTINE IN TURKEY.</head>
            <p>Pera, January 3</p>
            <p>Vessels from Suez which have left since the
            1st inst, with pilgrims or passengers, undergo
            five days quarantine and disinfection, vessels
            without passengers or pilgrims 24 hours and
            disinfection. </p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EFFECT OF LONDON FOG.</head>
            <p>Port Said, Tuesday. — The P &amp; O. SS
            “Mongolia,” which in the ordinary course of
            her run should have reached Port Said today
            (Tuesday), is not now expected to arrive until
            Thursday morning, her starting time having
            been delayed by the  great London fog two
            days before Christmas.</p>
            <p>Tips will not affect the mails for Egypt as I
            the “Osiris" is due to arrive at the usual time
            to-morrow. Fortunately the speed capabilities
            of the "Mongolia" will enable her to make up
            for the delay before reaching Sydney.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head> NATIVE THEATRE AT SUEZ BURNT.</head>
            <p>Suez, Tuesday.—A few days ago, a native
            theatrical company came to Suez and erected
            in the centre of the town a wooden theatre
            covered with awnings. Last evening, at 7.30
            on the occasion of the first performance, a
            crowd of natives assembled at the theatre, but
            did not enjoy the play for very long, as a lamp
            set fire to the canvas and the whole place was
            in a very short time burnt to the ground.' A
            panic ensued amongst the spectators, but they
            all managed to escape uninjured. The Fire
            Brigade arrived on the scene promptly and
            rendered every assistance, but the engine
            could not be made use or as the firemen were
            unable to get up steam.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PORT-SAID CATHOLIC SEAMEN’S
            CLUB.</head>
            <p>On Thursday, 29th ult, a sumptuous tea
            and impromptu concert was given at the above
            club to the seamen in port. The rooms had
            been tastefully decorated for the occasion, and
            the tables were beautifully laid with large
            supplies of cake, sandwiches, and fruit. About
            40 seamen sat down to partake of the treat
            offered them. After the tea, which was served
            by lady, visitors, a concert followed, and the
            men cheerfully came forward to sing songs.
            During the concert cigars, cigarettes, sand-
            wiches, and refreshments were served, and the
            greatest cordiality and good feeling prevailed
            throughout, though the men were of divers
            nationalities, creeds, and color. The meeting
            broke up at 10p.m., all those present standing
            up to sing “God save the King.”</p>
            <p>The committee are deeply grateful to the
            ladies who so kindly volunteered their services,
            and also to several friends who contributed in
            other ways to the success of the evening.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>A NEW SUEZ CANAL.</head>
            <p>The Pall Mall Gazette makes the following
            remarks on the interview which we reproduced
            from the Standard on Monday last:- If any-
            thing were needed to confirm the rumours ,
            afloat regarding the construction of an altern- ,
            ative canal between the Mediterranean and
            Red Sea, we should imagine the interview
            with M. Bonnet, the secretary of the Suez Canal
            Company, published in the Standard, would,
            sufficient. This gentleman denies nothing, but
            in the course of a columm of commonplace
            remarks he asserts that his company has a
            monopoly for seventy years to come. Such a
            statement will cause not a little surprise in
            London, and, we should imagine, to the shade
            Mr. Gladstone. To those behind the scenes
            Mn Bonnet’s ingenuousness is quite refreshing,
            for the leaders of the agitation for a new
            1anal are hard at work upon their scheme.
            How long will it be before Prince d’Arenberg
            follows the example of the late M. de Lesseps,
            who, after protesting that he would concede
            nothing, came to London to find out on what
            terms shipowners would oonsont to make
            peace.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
            <p>The Moss liner “Tabor" arrived here this
            morning from Liverpool, via Gibraltar, Malta
            and Tripoli, with passengers, mails and general
            cargo.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>TRAGEDY AT ALEXANDRIA</head>
            <head>TWO MEN KILLED</head>
            <p>A fatal quarrel took place yesterday after-
            noon between three Greeks in a bar behind
            the Attarin Bazaar. The parties all hail
            from Smyrna, and tt appeara that the mur-
            derer loved a sister of his two victims, one
            of whom was a suitor for his own sister's
            hand. A discussion arose between the men
            and the murderer drew his knife and despatch-
            ed one at the brothers with a single stab. The
            other brother came to the rescue but received
            two stabs, to which he succumbed in the
            Greek Hospital at midnight.</p>
            <p>The murderer is a young man, about 20
            years of age, and is extraordinarily muscular.
            His name is Yanni Antonio Stigrigo, and he
            was arrested by tho polioe in front of Cairo
            Railway Station. He made no resistance to the
            police and allowed himself to be handcuffed
            quitely.</p>
            <p>He is a native subject and was taken before
            the Native Parquet at midday today.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>IMPORTANT DISCOVERY.</head>
            <p>The Service of Antiquities has recently
            undertaken excavations at the low stone
            pyramid of Zawyet el Arayan, which lies on
            the desert plateau between Ghizieh and Sak-
            karah. The site dates from the Ancient
            Empire and news has just been received of the
            discovery of a large granite mastaba or tomb.
            Strong hopes are entertained that a find of
            considerable magnitude is about to be un-
            covered. Extensive subterranean galleries
            were excavated some years ago, but, owing to
            the difficult descent at the entrance shaft,
            visitors rarely go down to these long passages
            under the desert.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PROF. MASPERO'S NEW
            TRANSLATION.</head>
            <p>M. Maspero has published a new translation
            of the stele of Userkaf (the Usercheres of
            Manetho) of the fifth dynasty, found by Prof.
            Petrie at Abydos. He thinks that if Prof.
            Petrie's copyist had been, as he says, “a
            professional Egyptologist," he (or she) might
            have been ablo to make a guess at many of the
            mutilated signs, and thus have oonsidorahly
            reduced the lacuna in the copy from which we
            now have to work. He does not agree with Mr.
            Griffith in the view that the inscription was
            originally written on papyrus, and afterwards
            transferred to stone, and he corrects the
            translation published by the last-named in
            'Abydos IL' in several particulars. M. Maspero
            has also given a criticism of Dr. Erman’s recent
            ’Aegyptisches Glosaar,' in which he laments
            that Dr. Erman refers his readers in certain
            cases to his grammar only, and not to the texts
            on which it is supposed to be founded. As M
            Maspero says, it is necessary for beginners
            even more than for more advanced scholars
            that they should have an opportunity of check-
            ing for themselves the theories of the Berlin
            school, without being forced jurare in verbum
            magistri. Perhaps the sting of his criticism
            ies in the concluding words that the 'Gloasar'
            should prove useful to students at German
            universities and beginners in other countries.</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>VERDI THEATRE DEBACLE.</head>
            <p>A Cairo correspondent writes:—</p>
            <p>I see that the Verdi Theatre performances
            are few and far between at present, that ap-
            patently the company are losing over the ven-
            ture, in short, that they are likely enough to
            give it all up. It is the greatest possible pity.
            Here we have good, an excellent opera com-
            pany giving us just the repertoire which should
            appeal to us. The weary resident and the gay
            visitor do not usually want overmuch Wagner
            or the like ; they prefer these lighter operas,
            and yet no one seems to go. I admit that the
            Verdi Theatre has had one or two off-nights,
            viz, and to wit, Gioconda for one; but Mignon,
            Aida, Carmen, Otello, all were excellent. They
            have a surprisingly good orchestra. They have
            five or six leading players who are good enough
            for anything—Signora Monti-Baldini, Signor
            Tomisani, Signora Popovici—and I was told
            that Signora Svicher was very good. I have not
            been, I admit, to all the performances—by no
            means—but I have heard about those I did
            not see.</p>
            <p>I will say at once that the raison d'etre
            of this article is not personal in any sense;
            it is more an expression of my wish to tell
            Cairo people in general (so far as they take any
            notice of my valued criticism) that if they
            wish to see a good light opera oompany,
            they havo the chance and I wish they would
            take it. It is pitiful to see the house emptier
            and emptier, and the performers less and less
            enthusiastic or inclined to do their best And
            I should imagine it is certain enough that if
            this Company gives up this their first attempt
            we shall get little enough chance of any
            further repetitions. I admit the locality is
            annoying, but the swift Cairo cabs make
            this of little account. Once in a way it may
            be said by some that they-let us put it so—
            prefer the environment, internal as well as
            external, of the Khedivial Opera House, but
            they can always take a box. And really it
            was the sight of those many empty boxes
            which moved me, as could no free seats
            or first-night suppers or other induce-
            ments (which same I haven’t had), to cover
            two sheets of paper — that, and the wish
            to hear the operas myself, for, O well-
            beloved visitors and residents, if you don’t en-
            courage the opera, the opera will vanish, and
            I shall have to go without! Invade the boxes,
            then, ye visitors and we, “poor devils on a
            fixed income," will, lessen our supply of ciga-
            rettes, and set apart the piastres necessary for
            our postri numerati, blessing you in that our
            economy is not unrewarded</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
            <p>General von Herwarth is expected at Shep-
            heard's Hotel shortly</p>
            <p> Mr. MaeMillan, the American explorer, will
            arrive at Khartoum from the South in a few
            day's time. Mr. Jesseu, who has been staying
            at Shepheard’s Hotel, will meet him at Khar-
            toum.</p>
            <p>M. Raoul Pugno, the celebrated French
            pianist is expected to pay a visit to Egypt
            shortly. He will give a few recitals at Cairo
            and Alexandira.</p>
            <p>The marriage of Mr. Antonio Huri to Mias
            Natalina Montano will take plaae at St Cathe-
            rine's Cathedral on Saturday, next.</p>
            <p>The following passengers left for the Nile
            trip by the “Rameses the Great" yesterday;
            Dr. and Mrs Aufschlager, Dr. and Mrs. Bell
            Pettigrew, Mr. F. H. and Miss Tucker, Mr.
            and Mrs Bentley Bridgewater, Mr. and Mrs.
            F. D. Davy, Miss Florence Abraham, Mr., Mrs
            and Miss Shannon, Mr. J. Trimborn, Mr. Lio
            nel Sutro, Mrs. and Miss Sutro, Mr. and Mss-
            Cross, Mr. and Mrs C. D. Vail, Misses Hough-
            ton, Mr. and Mrs Andre Ramel and Miss M.
            Ramel, Mr. and Mrs. Chas Baron, Mr. and
            Mrs Victor Mallein, Mr. and Mrs A. Frappier,
            Mr. and Mrs James Anderson, Mr A Pedro
            Andrade, Mr. Denison, Mr. C. E Harp, Mr D.
            Zamiatuin, Mr. E story, Miss Story, Mr. and
            Mrs. Percival Hart arid Miss Hart, Mrs T.
            and Miss Cloud, Mrs and Miss Adelaide Clay
            Evans, Miss McCourd, Mr R de Guvencourt
            Mr. Felix Collombier, Mr. J. W. Astley, Mr.
            J. B. Dickinson.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR</head>
            <p> We do not hold ourselves responsible for the
              opinions expressed by our correspondants, but we wish
              in a spirit of fair play to all to permit-withing certain
              necessary limits- free discourse. </p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ANGLO-AMERICAN HOSPITAL</head>
            <head>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
            <p>Sir,-was "Cariene's" object to drive my
            nails home, or stir up the dry bones in the
            almost forgotten valley of satire? Preeuming
            he latter, I pick up a bone here and there and
            offer you the “bouquet"</p>
            <p>Most decidedly,“Cairene,” the “philanthropic
            (why not philo-progenitive) labors" should
            have some “forthcoming,” and if the Anglo-
            American Hospital is to have the honor of
            presenting our dual community with fifteen
            new members “at one and the same time"
            more power to it (the hospital); long may
            it flourish (the hospital again); also the
            “fifteen at one and the same time" (A happy
            new year to them); also the thirty proud
            responsibilities (A happy new year to them
            too). But was it not as you infer, a little
            invidious to call upon the resident civilian
            community to share the responsibility and
            add another "embarrassment" fifteen of them
            to their “present financial" ones</p>
            <p>By all means “Cairene," agitate for State-
            aided lying-in hospitals, and impose penalties
            on those who do not make use of them, but
            why a private community, bachelors and bene-
            dicts alike, should be called upon. to “lay out”
            to the tune of fifteen ‘lying-in’’ embarrass-
            ments at a time, and which they had not bar-
            gained for, is just a little too much.</p>
            <p>And why, “Cairene,” do you laud and
            damn in the same breath the “recent opening
            of a similar establishment in Cairo,” when the
            “highest medical authorities have apparently
            fixed upen Ghezireh as the one and only site
            for an ideal fresh-air-lying-in-laying-out show.
            Come, come,—I mean “Go to” (no dash, Mr.
            Comp, please, I am quoting Shakespeare),
            Cairene.</p>
            <p>I am, etc,</p>
            <p>Medico.</p>
            <p>Cairo. January 1. </p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>VANDALISM AT CANOPUS</head>
            <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</p>
            <p>Sir,—Your criticisms on the lack of initiative
            of the Alexandria Archaeological Society to
            reference to the state of affairs prevailing on
            the property of Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun
            at Aboukir may be absolutely correct, but I
            should like to point out that the society suffers
            from a chronic impecuniosity, due to the fact
            that it is so poorly supported by the public of
            Alexandria. I use the phrase "chronic im-
            pecuniosity" in a comparative sense, for if the
            society's means were greater, it would indulge
            in far more extensive operations. Considering
            the grant that the Egyptian Government
            accords to the Museum Service, it is absurd
            that the Alexandria Archaeological Society
            should depend on private contributions.</p>
            <p>I am, etc,</p>
            <p>Von Clamantis</p>
            <p>Alexandria, January 3.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE TAWIL FAILURE.</head>
            <p>Mr. Selim Tawil himself has been asked to
            act as liquidator in conjunction with Messrs,
            Sofio, Gorra and Debbane.</p>
            <p>At a meeting held on Monday evening at the
            Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Alexandria, it was
            unanimously agreed that a liquidation “a
            l'amiable" should take place.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>RAMLEH RAILWAY.</head>
            <p>There is to be a meeting this evening at 8
            o'clock at the Theatre, Bacos Station, when
            the inhabitants of Alexandria and Ramleh
            will disucss the new railway tariff</p></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
