<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Gwen Lofman</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-10-04">October 4, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Wednesday, October 4, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 4 1905.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="Porte and Powers">
                    <head>PORTE AND POWERS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MACEDONIAN FINANCIAL CONTROL.</head>
                        <head type="sub">SULTAN'S INSTRUCT IONS</head>
                        <dateline>Constantinople. October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>The Porte's vote to the Ambassadors says that the Sultan is firmly resolved not to depart from his views as to the superfluity of financial control by the Powers in Macedonia, which constitutes an infraction on his Sovereign rights The authorities have been instructed not to recognise the financial delegates of the Powers, who have been sent to Salonika.</p>
                        <byline>(R)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JAPANS COMMERCE INTRODUCTION OF FOREIGN CAPITAL Tokyo October 3.</head>
                        <p>At the meeting of the Associated Chambers of Commerce here the Minister of Commerce intimated that the Government is preparing to improve the internal communications, and that the introduction of foreign capital will be facilitated. The Vice-Minister of Finance urged the merchants to do their utmost, for the development of foreign trade.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>another imperial ukase</head>
                        <head>ELECTION OF NATIONAL ASSEMBLY.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>St.</placeName> Petersburg, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>A Ukase orders the immediate preparation of regulations for the elections for the National Assembly.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FINNISH REVOLT.</head>
                        <p><placeName>St. Petersburg</placeName>, October 3. Depots of arms and munitions are continually being found in Finland.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GERMANY AND CHINA.</head>
                        THE COMMERCIAL TREATY.
                        <dateline><placeName>Berlin</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>Sheng Koung Pao, the Chinese representative of the Germano-Chinese commercial treaty negotiations, has arrived here. The negotiations will begin to morrow.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GERMANS AND CZECHS. POLICE QUASH DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>Brunn</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>In consequence of disputes between the Germans and Czechs the troops dispersed the demonstrators.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STRIKES IN BERLIN.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>Berlin</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>Thirty-eight thousand electricians have gone on strike. The tramway service is suffering.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE MANILA HURRICANE. TWO STEAMERS LOST.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>Manila</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>Two inter-insular steamers were lost in the recent hurricane in the Philippines, and 144 persons were drowned. The damage done to the hemp plantations and warehouses is estimated at a million sterling.	<byline>(Reuter)</byline></p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COUNT BRAZZA S FUNERAL.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>Paris</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>The State funeral of Count de Brazza took place yesterday and was largely attended.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DEATH OF A POET.</head>
                        <dateline><placeName>Paris</placeName>, October 3.</dateline>
                        <p>The poet Heredia is dead.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                        <p>Of Creole origin and Spanish tastes and sympathies, Joaé-Maria de Heredia was the most exotic of modern French poets in choice of subjects, the most sonorously Latin in style. Much might be written on the metrical and artistic merits of his work ; enough that be looked on life and history as a pageant, end was swift to seize every colour and every grouping that pleased his eye and to reproduce its beauty in stately verse. A master of metrical form, he was at his best in the sonnet. His series of poems on ancient Egypt, the sonnets that describe the loves of Antony and Cleopatra with the extraordinary battle-piece commencing his chock avait ele tres rude, les tribute" , are ____passed of their</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Austro-Hangarian diplomatic agency has transferred its offices to Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Gold for Egypt</head>
                        <p>We are informed that the Crédit Lyonnais has received one million of pounds sterling in gold.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Sucreries.</head>
                        <p>We hear that a number of the employes of the Sacrerios company have been dismissed for reasons of economy.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Bank or Egypt Ltd</head>
                        <p>We are informed that the Zagazig agency of the Bank of Egypt Ltd. is row represented by Messrs. Gustave Jullien and Cesar Giordano who will sign conjointly as agents.
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Council of Ministers.</head>
                        <p>The Council of  Ministers will meet on Monday next. Among  the agenda of the day will be the appointment of a successor to Hassan Bey Wassif, ex-Mondir of Girgeh, imprisoned for the part he played in the Rifaa affair.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Brindisi Mail, which arrived at Port Said early this morning, will be forwarded to Alexandria by the train arriving at 7.35 p.m. Letters will be distributed at a quarter past nine to-night, and newspapers, etc. by first delivery to-morrow morning.
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sudan Government.</head>
                        <p>Bimbashi <persName>A. A. C. Taylor</persName>, junior inspector, Bahr-el-Ghazal Province has been appointed junior inspector, Berber Province. Bimbashi <persName>H. W. Channer</persName>, 3rd Battalion, transferred to the Sudan Government, has been appointed junior inspector, Bahr-el-Ghazal Province, and Bimbashi <persName>F. C. Heneker</persName>, junior inspector, Kassala Province, is re-transferred to the Amy.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Cattle Plaque</head>
                        <p>The Sanitary Department has ordered the veterinary inspectors to make a careful and thorough inspection of all the districts comprised in the province of Fayoum and those which lie to the north with the view to ascertaining the state of the towns and villages and to make certain of the entire disappearance of the cattle plague. It is believed that these steps have been taken as a preliminary to granting the necessary permission for the re-opening of the markets belonging to the Egyptian Markets Company, which have now been closed tor over two years.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fsbekieh Gardens Theatre.</head>
                        <p>English playgoers in Cairo will be pleased to learn that Mr. <persName>Santini</persName> has obtained the necessary authorisation for a series of performances to be given by an English operetta and variety company, commencing from the 1st proximo. Mr. David B. Warwick, who came out to Egypt at the end of last month to make the preliminary arrangements, has now returned to England to bring out his troupe. Later in the season Mr. Leonidas, with his excellent variety company and performing animals, which performed with such success before the Cairene public in the beginning of last year, will return for a season of about one month. At present this troupe is performing at Constantinople and have appeared more than once at the Sultan's private theatre in Yildiz Kiosk.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>It is reported that H.H. the Khedive will visit the Mansourah Agricultural Show on the 20th and 31st inst. and return to Cairo on the 25th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p><persName ref='http://islamsci.mcgill.ca/RASI/BEA/Ahmad_Mukhtar_BEA.htm'>Ghazi Mukhtar</persName> Pasha will arrive at Alexandria by the Norddentscher Lloyd S S. Schleswig on Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Judicial Adviser is expected to arrive at Cairo to night from Port Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. M. de C. Findlay, C.M.G., acting British Agent, and Mr. Rumbold, 2nd Secretary to the British Agency, will return to Cairo next week.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p><persName>Adly Pasha Yeghen</persName>, Governor of Cairo, is expected to arrive in Egypt at the end of this month.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Amongst those arriving at Port Said this morning by the P. &amp; O. mail boat Isis were Sir Elwin Palmer, Governor of the National Bank Mr. McGillivary, and Captain McMurdo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Dr. Ruffer, President of the Quarantine Board, will return to Alexandria on October 8.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>We greatly regret to announce the death of Mr. Samuel Gurney Sheppard, Chairman of the Aboukir Company, Limited, which occurred yesterday morning.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lieutenant C. E. G. Woollcombe-Adams, Royal Artillery, who has arrived in Egypt from England, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank of Bimbaabi and is posted to the Artillery.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>El Bimbashi A. J. B. Percival, D. S. O, Camel Corps, has been appointed local Kaima kam, whilst acting officer commanding the 15th Sudanese.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M G. M. d'Ory, the new Spanish Minister to the Khédivial Government, is staying at Shepheards Hotel.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BRITISH ASSOCIATION.</head>
                        <head type="sub">ARRIVAL AT SUEZ.</head>
                        <p>( From a Correspondent ).</p>
                        <p>(By Telegraph).	</p>
                        <dateline>Suez, Wednesdays, 11.40 a.m.</dateline>
                        <p>The members of the British Association among whom I recognised Professor Berry and Six Benjamin Baker, arrived bore this morning from South Africa by tho S.S. Durham Castle. One hundred and eighty members of the party are leaving for Cairo by special train and after spending a few days in the Capital will reembark for London at Port Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PHARMACY REGULATIONS. !</head>
                        <p>A serions infringement of the pharmacy regulations, which have now been in operation for a little over a year is reported from Cairo. A Greek, named Pistis, applied last year for authorisation to open the Pharmacie Hellenique, and forwarded at the same time to the Sanitary Administration what purported to be the diploma of the chemist who was to be in charge. The diploma proving to be authentic, the necessary permission was granted in January, but in May, on receipt of an anonymous communcation, enquiries were set on foot by the police authorities, with the result that it was discovered that the diploma in question to  belonged to another man of the same nationality who had been dead since November, 1896. It is alleged that Pistis had purchased the deceased man's diploma from a local pharmacy where he hid been serving at the time of his death. The Parquet is now making fuller investigation before bringing the delinquent before the Native Tribunal for trial, hot in the meanwhile the accused has asked for an adjournment of the case for two months to enable him to prove his foreign nationality.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SERIOUS RAILWAY ACCIDENT.</head>
                        <p>A serions collision occured yesterday near Kassassin station between the passenger train which left Ismailia at 6.20 a.m. for Benha and another coming from the opposite direction. An official telegram recieved at the Ministry of the Interior stated that a third class carriage and several goods waggons were completely smashed, and that 23 persons had been more or less injured, one very seriously. On the news reaching Zagazig a special train was at once despatched to the scene of the accident, conveying the commandant of police, the substitute of the Parquet, and a medical officer. Most of the injured passengers were taken to the hospital at Ismailia.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO DRAINAGE.</head>
                        <p>The Sanitary Administration has decided to extend the drains for rain water which were commenced about three years ago, and is at present engaged upon studying the possibility of adopting some method whereby these drains can be made available when the time comes for a proper system of sewers for draining the houses to be undertaken. As the streets of the Capital that are not yet supplied with drains become impassable, sometimes for days, whenever there is a heavy rainfall, it is to be hoped that the work now in contemplation will be taken in hand without any farther delay. That the city was well drained one or two centuries ago was fully proved by the discoveries that were made at the time the first drains for rain water were being constructed, and which greatly simplified the task of the engineers and contractors entrusted with the work.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE NUBARIEH CANAL.</head>
                        <p>An official communication was sent yesterday to the Press bureau whereby the Ministry of Public Works notifies for public informaiton that the statement published recently by some of the local papers to the effect that it was intended to prolong the Nubarieh Canal, for the irrigation of some of the lands situated in the northern parte of Egypt, is incorrect ; and the Government thinks it its duty to declare that it intends to conform stirctly to the notification that appeared in the “Journal Officiel" of the 31st May last, to the effect that it has no intention of prolonging this canal in the near future. This decision was originally taken some months ago, when Sir William Garstin recommended that the sale of Government waste lands should be suspended until the question of a farther supply of water for irrigation purposes has been finally settled.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The S.S. Persian Prince from Antwerp, left Malta yesterday with a general cargo and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Saturday.</p>
                        <p>The Khedivial express mail steamship El Kahira will leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on Saturday, Port-Said at 4 p.m on Sunday for Beyrouth, Tripoli, Meriana, Alexandretta, Larnaca, Limassol, Caiffa and Jaffa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item"><!-- ADVERTIESMENT? -->
                        <head>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                        <p>236 BRANCHES.</p>
                        <p>French, German, Italian, Greek, Arabic, etc. Private Lessons, Residence Lessons, taught by Native Masters.</p>
                        <p>ALEXANDRIA ; 26 Rue de l'Eglise Copte.</p>
                        <p>CAIRO :	1 Sharia Kamel.</p>
                        <p>TRIAL Lesson Free.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CHATHAM WRECKAGE</head>
                        (From our Correspondent.)
                        <dateline>Port Said Tuesday.</dateline>
                        <p>I notice several intereating bat absolutely ridiculous articles in local and other journals on the subject of the probability of there stillbeing quantities of explosives, lying loose as it were, at the bottom of the canal. After the explosion you will remember that certain rough roundings were taken which revealed little beyond the foot that the middle of the canal had been partially filled up, and that a large hole had been blown in the east bank. Careful and complete lines of soundings were made on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday, and since that date divers have lean engaged walking about the canal bed round kilometre 18, finding the pieces of ship which are scattered about. The thorough examinations made have shown that not a single trace of the forward part of the vessel is now to be found anywhere near the spot where the vessel originally lay ; the desert for a mile round the scene of the explosion is smothered in pieces of steel torn out of the ship, and coke and pig iron, of which the major part of the Chatham’s cargo was composed, cover the canal banks in all directions. Bearing these foots in mind, is it likely or even probable that even a portion of a case remains anywhere near the spot to testify to the explosion </p>
                        <p>The divers who have been sent from France are now engaged breaking op the largest pieces of plate and frame which have been found; explosives are being used, and I hear that it is hoped that the worst part of the work will be all over by Thursday. The dredgers, of which there are six on the spot, are working behind the six divers and their accompanying derricks and shear legs, removing upwards of 5,000 cubic metres of sand per day. The largest piece of metal which has been so far lifted from the canal bed measures the astonishing length of over 80 feet and weighs something over 80 tons. Again, is it possible that any cases of explosives remain anywhere near where this unfortunate ship lay before she was blown up. The idea is ridiculous and absurd in the extreme.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CONGESTED HARBOUR.</head>
                        <p>The harbour of Port Said now shows signs of congestion in a marked degree. Besides the colliers there are no lees than 27 large vessels now in the harbour, several of which, for want of space, are being made fast to each other. The ships now here, in their order of arrival, are as follows :—Ping Sney, Rugia, Menelaus, Avoca, Mahratta and Meeton Hall (arrived 28th ulto); Staat_-Kratke, Persia, Weissenfels, and Langdale (arrived 29th). Statesman and Oxos, (arrived 30th). Ataka,Brida, Sicilia and Donally (arrived 1st inst) ; Yarra, Siam, Palermo, Sachsen and Arabistan (arrived 2nd inst) ; Goentor, Flores, Africa, and another arrived to-day. Counting coasting ships of the various kinds we have here to-day no less than 40 ships and still they come.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SUNKEN DREDGER.</head>
                        <p>The work in connection with the salvage of the dredger Pharaon II. is at a standstill. It will be remembered that a mouth ago efforts were made to raise her, but that they were stultified owing to the collapse of ore of the double lighters. These are now all ready, and much improved, being internally strengthened, but the remains of the Chatham claim all the attention of the engineers staff, and it will probably be some time before this unfortunate craft sees the full light of day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE AUSTRIAN CONSUL.</head>
                        <p>The Austrian Lloyd Africa which arrived to-day had on board the Austrian Consul, who returns after three month’s leave.</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE DANGERS OF THE RED SEA.</head>
                        <p>A Board of Trade inquiry was concluded at Newosa le-on-Tyne on Saturday the 16th ult. into the circumstances attending the stranding of the steam ship Foyle, of London, in the Red Sea, on June 13. The vessel struck on the Mushejera Beef, 6 1/6 miles out of the intended course, and the master believed that she must have been set to the westward by a current. He was, he said, familiar with the Admiralty sailing directions, which said “Strong currents occasionally set across the Red Sea, so a good berth should be given to outlying reefs and shoals. That is the more necessary because the strength of those currents increases rapidly as the shoals are neared, and they form one of the chief obstacles to the safe navigation of the Red Sea, and to them are to be attributed the losses of several steamers daring recent years. A knowledge of their existence should impress mariners with the necessity of constant vigilance.” The Court found that the courses set and steered were safe and proper. The vessel was not navigated at too great a rate of speed. The most probable cause of the causalty was an unusually strong current setting the vessel to the westward alter she had passed Mokhah light, causing her to strand on Mushajera Island, whereby she sustained serious damage. The vessel was navigated with proper and seamanlike care, and the Court found that the master (Captain Alfred Thomas Page) and the officers were not in fault</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>ARCHÆOLOGY IN TURKEY.</head>
                    <div type="item>"
                        <head>A SHORT REVIEW</head>
                        <p>(From a Constantinople Correspondent).</p>
                        <p>( Concluded. )</p>
                        <p>The numismatic department contains 70,000 coins of all kinds. The curator of the museum is Hamdi Boy, a very energetic and enlightened Turkish gentleman, thanks to whom a Dumber of valuable relics, which would otherwise have been neglected, have been preserved. As excavator he discovered the Sidon sarcophagi, and as a writer on archaeological subjects he is well known to most archæologists visiting Turkey, and in him they have a friend whose enthusiasm in the cause of research is a real help to their labours.</p>
                        <p>The collection in the new building is divided into sarcophagi and bas reliefs, which,coming from very different places and belonging to as varied epochs, form a complete series of ancient necrology. The sarcophagi are in an unbroken series ranging from the Ionian primitive period to that of the Byzantine era. The archaic period is represented by three sarcophagi of baked, colonred earthenware from Clozomeræ (now a plague lazaretto on the Golf of Smyrna) which, together with the two in the Louvre at Paris are the only complete specimens of the style.</p>
                        <p>The sarcophagi of Sidon belong to the fifth and sixth centuries of Greek art To this same period, and to the third century also, belongs another interesting series of anthropoid sarcophagi.</p>
                        <p>There are two sarcophagi which have scenes borrowed from the legend of Phsedrus and are good specimens of Graeco-Roman art Amongst other Byzantine relica, mast be mentioned a fragment which very probably belonged to the sarcophagus of Constantine I. and his mother Helen.</p>
                        <p>But that which gives to the museum its especial character is the unique series of Phœnician sarcophagi from Sidon.</p>
                        <p>Here two hypogœi side by side, hewn out of a bed of sandstone, the Ramleh of the Arabs, were laid bare and explored. One contained a diorite tomb of Tabnith, son of Eshmuuazar, King of Sidon. The other, divided into seven sepulchres, contained seventeen sarcophagi, one of which is that beautiful masterpiece, the tomb of Alexander. This sarcophagus, unique for its perfect preservation, is in an elongated form of a Greek temple. It is of Pentelic marble and is 3.18 metres long, 2.18 metres from base to roof, and 1.67 metres broad The base, on whioh it stands, juts out 14 centimeters; this base consists of a border surmounted by a moulding (torus) adorned with tresses, then a lintel, a scotia, a row of heart shapes, and a row of pearls. The cornice, projecting 065 metres from the body, consists of a double meander surmounting a row of ovals and pearls. This ornamentation in which plain surfaces alternate with the richest mouldings has been sculptured with a delicacy which gives the profile of the tomb an incomparable beauty of style. Between the pedestal and the cornice is the body of the sarcophagus properly speaking. It is 58 centimeters high, and is adorned with beautiful reliefs emblematical of the life and character of the great warrior to whose memory the tomb is evidently dedicated, one of these representing a cavalry engagement (probably that of Issus or Arbela). This beautiful shrine is in one hall of the building, and forms the centre of attraction to all corner. In the hall on the other side there is a sarcophagus, also from the royal necropolis of Saida, which rot so gloriously beautiful, may, nevertheless, for perfect work and life-like expression take the next place It is that of the Weepers. Unfortunately par of the roofing, the side, and a head, have been broken off. Like that of Alexander it is in the form of a Greek temple, and instead of the frieze sculptured on its ride has Iconic columns, five on the large sides, and two on the small. In between these columns, are figures, in relief, of women in every expression and posture of grief. The ornamentation is not at all so profuse as in that of Alexander, but it is the perfectly natural expression and pose of the figures, wonderfully done, which contitutes the beauty of the tomb. The set includes an Egyptian sarcophagus in black marble of a very fine grain, — the tomb of a woman, belonging to the fifth century. It is polished and was originally covered with hieroglyphics, which have since been obliterated. Although similar to the Egyptian style in the matter of shape, it differs as to the material, which is in this instance marble, whereas the Egyptian tomb was usally of wood.</p>
                        <p>One of the most noteworthy features of these monumnets is the variety of the style, which is peculiar to such different epochs and countries. For in these contiguous hypoœi were found Egyptian and Phoenician tombs; others snob as that of Alexander, and three other email sarcophagi which probably came from Attica ; another is undoubtedly, from Lycia ; the tomb of the Satrap came from an Ionian school of sculpture; while the ‘Weepers’’ is the work of an Athenian. Moreover, as regards date, the “Satrap” tomb belongs to the early part of the 5th century; the Lycian to the end of that century, while the “Weepers” and the tomb of Alexander belong respectively to the beginning and end of the 4th century. Thus this collection of monuments, containing as it does relics of such a diversity as regards data and origin, is valuable inasmuch as it provides information concerning the funeral customs of the Phœnicians, who, as is known, had no art of their own. They often appropriated tombs made in other lands, as in tin case of King Tabnith, who bought in Egypt for his own use, a sarcophagus which had been need by an Egyptian general.</p>
                        <p>On this tomb is the following inscription in Phoenician "It is I, Tabnith, Priest of Astarte, King of the Sidonians, who lie in this tomb. O man I whoever thou art that shall discover this tomb, do not open my sepulchral chamber; nor trouble me For there is neither silver, gold, nor treasure</p>
                        <p>beside me. I alone lie in this tomb. Open not this sepulcrhal chamber, as such an act is an abomination in the eyes of Astarte. If thou shouldst open my sepulcrhal chamber and shouldst come to trouble me, mayest thou never have posterity amongst the living under the son, nor bed among the dead.” The King has been removed from his "sepulchral” chamber, and is exposed under a glass case not far from the empty sarcophagus, and despite the course and abomination unto Astarte, no harm teems to have befallen Hamdi Bey for the desecration.</p>
                        <p>A study of these monuments, taken alone, is of great aid in treeing the development of Greek style. Firstly, what has been a veritable revelation for science is the existence, at the brilliant epoch of Greek art, the fifth and fourth centuries B. C. of sarcophagi, in the form of temples decorated with bas reliefs. The most ancient sarcophagi of this style, which are known, are those of the Amazons, at present in the Vienna Museum (a moulding of which is in the Stamboul institution), and belong to the third century ; all the others are of Graeco-Roman style. Moreover the Sidon tombs may be considered the most perfect of funeral sculpture of the fifth and fourth centuries B.C. Finally each marks a date in the history of Greek sculpture.  The sarcophagus of the Satrap is the most perfect specimen of an art which must have flourished on the coasts of Ionia from the middle of the fourth century until the time of the Median Wars and of which the explorations at Eoheaus and Mitylene give one but faint impressions.</p>
                        <p>The sarcophagus of "the Weepers” is the most beautiful example of the funeral art which inspired the sculptors of the fourth and third centuries.</p>
                        <p>Finally although tbs sarcophagus of Alexander has only definitely decided the question as to the polychrome of Greek sculpture and shown us to what perfection the masters of the end of the fourth centery, the contemporaries of Lysippus and Bryaxs had brought the art of decorative composition ; it, must be said that this sarcophagus is the greatest achievement of the art of the century for explaining the history of ancient sculpture.</p>
                        <p>The series of antrhopic sarcophagi, embracing more than four centuries, worthily completes this collection of Phœnician monuments and deserves profound study. In this series one traces the growth of the art from the time when the sculptor sought to imitate the mummy coffin with a more hardy substance than wood, that is to ray, in stone and marble ; then his attempts to give his work the form of a statue and portrait and then even to give it a human form reproducing the members and even adding an expression of natural detail ; finally, the Egyptian art and realistic work are abandoned for the pare conventional Greek type, in the formation of which the influence of Polycletian sculpture is noticeable.</p>
                        <p>As the last representative of Phoenician funeral art attention must be drawn to the lead sarcophagi of which the museum has a large number; they have nearly all been brought from Lebanon and Homs, a town in southern Syria, and belong to Phoenicia.</p>
                        <p>They were cast in moulds of sandstone, so that the ornamentation on their faces is in relief and elegant; and, varied as it is, shows a mixture of Phœnician and Graeco Roman art All belong to either the first years of the Christian era or to the last of the B.C. period.</p>
                        <p>Mention must be made of a funeral stela coming from Symi (Sporades), belonging to the series of funeral stelae of the primitive art of the fourth and fifth centuries of the Archipelago and Attica of which tbs warrior of Marathon is the most famous representative.</p>
                        <p>There is also a very full series of bas-reliefs representing fanerai banquets and family scenes; the former represent funeral banquets held on the tomb of the divine dead, ana the latter represent, for instances, a family divided by death and reunited in the next life, but all of these are of very rough workmanship sod very hastily sculptured.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item"><!-- SPORTS TABLE -->
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                        <head type="sub">E. T. C. SENIORS v. JUNIORS.</head>
                        <p>This return match was played yesterday, and ended in a somewhat easy win for the Juniors by 146 runs. For the Juniors, Byrne played a fine innings of 103, not out. The Seniors did not do at all well against the bowling of Messrs. Harvey and Byrne, and were all out close on time for 73, Steele being top scorer with 26. Scores :— Juniors.</p>
                        <table>
                            Mr. Harrison c. Hanley, b. R. McLean... 24 „ Henley c. Stacey, b. R.. McLean... 6
                            „ Byrne not out... 	  108
                            „ Chessman b. Steele..................	 ...	26
                            „ Blythman c. Lowell, b. R. McLean...	2
                            „ Thurston not out................................. 43
                            „ Harvey Scarth	|
                            „ Lees	 did not bat
                            „ Lester „ Garfiled
                            Extras ...................... 15
                            Total for 4 wk's............. 219
                        </table>
                        <head>Bowling</head>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY OCTOBER 4, 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head><persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Saltin</persName> PASHA &amp; THE SUDAN.</haed>
                    <p>awakened, like the fellaheen in Upper Egypt, to the advantages of money, and realise that they can only obtain it by the sweat of then brows. "Hence," says <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha, “with tin</p>
                    <p>We recently published an interview with Sir R. von <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha by a "Standard” correspondent, and we now add the leading article which that paper devoted to the work of the Inspector General of the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Among the men of our own time, none, we think, has a more romantic record than <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha, the gallant Austrian appointed by General Gordon to be Governor of Darfur, who afterwards fell into the Mahdi's hands, and survived the tortures of his long captivity to become Inspector General, under Sir Reginald <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/36977'>Wingate</persName>, of the region over which his conqueror had exercised a ruthless terrorism. It is with great pleasure that we have published, the account of a long conversation held by our representative with a modern hero as '‘much-enduring" as Odysseus himself. Restored to the civilisation which he has help ed to construct, Sir Radolph <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> shows no more trace of his sufferings and travail than the Ithacan wanderer, and has addressed himself to administrative problems with as fresh an energy and as alert an intelligence as any hopeful novice fresh from his examination for the Indian Civil Servie. The man who was dragged in chains by the Mahdi's horse, a symbol and victim of the False Prophet's fleeting triumph, has at his finger’s ends all the latest statistics as to the revenue of the reconquered provinces. He describes, with the concentrated interest of a practical philanthropist, the elaborate measures which have been taken or are being prepared for the improvement of railway and motor communication between the interior and the coast and for the irrigation of a thirsty land. It has been the privilege and delight of Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/30583?docPos=1'>Cromer</persName> to enlist and instruct many zealous and intelligent subalterns in the great work of civilisations to which the least favorable critics of Great Britain yield unstinted praise; but no member of that memorable band has rendered better service or given shrewder counsel to his chief than the quiet, thoughtful gentleman who in twenty years has passed from imminent jeopardy of a living death back again to a career of beneficent activity. For the details of the industrial development which <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha supervises we may refer our readers to his own words, which present, in a concentrated form, the essence of the yearly reports published under Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/30583?docPos=1'>Cromer</persName>'s authority. It is to the human aspect of his story that we weald direct especial attention, because this illustrates the signal success which, in every part of the world, attends British colonisers in their dealings with races of inferior or retarded development. Take, for instance, the missionary question. How do the Anglo-Egyptian authorities face that always thorny problem <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha explains, in a few sentences, the principle on which they proceed. Roughly, the Sudan is divided into two political regions. The northern part is inhabited mainly, if not entirely, by Moslems, and on their fanatical faith and stereotyped stage of culture it has hitherto been found impossible for the evangelists of Christianity to make any sensible impression. As to the future, it would be inexcusable to hazard a general prophecy, but, at the present time, and in the Northern Sudan, it would endanger the permanent interests of civilisation if the Government were to sanction proselytising efforts which would surely be interpreted as an insidious and especially hateful form of political aggression. We must work more patiently, and be content with intermediate revolts. There are missionary schools established at Kharatoum for the children of Christian residents, and we are glad to learn that these are attended by young Moslems. But it is well understood—and the compact is faithfully observed—that these institutions are maintained for the purposes of general education, and not with a view to undermine the ancient religion of the people. In the southern districts of the Sudan the conditions are different, and another rule is observed. The people are pagans of a rather low type, and, knowing the Moslems chiefly as slave raiders, bear no affection for the faith of their persecutors. There the field is comparatively open to missionary enterprise, and has already yielded a certain spiritual harvest But the more prudent pioneers, of that light which the Western races are giving back to the Oriental source from which it was borrowed are content to move slowly, step by step. They make no raid on the polygamous custom which is the base of a primitive morality. To insist on the dismissal of all but s single — probably the most elderly — wife would not merely be a sacrifice that would appal the hesitating convert. It would also shake the social system of the tribe, deprive innocent women of their reoognieed status, and brand innumerable children with an unintelligible illegitimacy.</p>
                    <p>Similar caution had at first to be observed in the treatment of another "domestic institution.” The barbarities of the slave trade have been summarily suppressed throughout the Sudan. "There is no raiding on a big scale,” says <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha. Isolated revivals are attempted in remote spots and kidnapping is sometimes reported. But the delinquents are sharply punched, and the dangers that attend the sport—for that is the light in which it presents itself to Arab adventurers — are generally understood. “The traffic in human flesh," we are told, "has practically ceased." We would not aver that it is nowhere possible to purchase a slave-girl, but the business has become clandestine and is rapidly dying away. Nevertheless, the absolute abolition of slavery, which was decreed after Lord Kitchener’s re-conquest of the Sudan, was not without its drawbacks. As in our West Indies and in the United States, a race which had hitherto worked only under compulsion did not easily take to voluntary labour. By degrees, however, the lazy, easy-going but not unintelligent negroes have agreement and assistance of the Arab population, we are gradually changing the status of slavery into one of paid labour.' This, ha adds, "will be liked by both master and servant” For that revolution of sentiment we must be content to wait a generation. It is not in human nature either for employers to relish paying money for work that they used to get for nothing, or for employes to have their reward proportioned to the amount of energy that they put into their task. We have our wages problems and labour troubles even in this enlightened land. Other discontent in the Sudan there seems to be none—none, at least, of a dangerous kind. There are trilab feuds which the Government has to check with a cold, impartial hand. And not long ago crack-brained pretender tried to set up a new religion and proclaimed himself to be the "Prophet Jesus.” We have witnessed similar phenomena nearer home. It is interesting to note that the Sudanese impostor only suceeded in winning eleven disciples. <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha does not describe the methods of reconversion adopted by the Government We infer, however, that the action taken was short, sharp, and decisive.</p>
                    <p>Not the least interesting passage in Sir Rudolph’s account of his personal experiences relates to an interview that he held with a number of sheikhs representative of the nomad Arab tribes. They object to paying tribute— contributing to the expenses of public administration—but the reason which they put forward may seem paradoxical to the western mind. They understand and acknowledge the authority of superior strength. It is the principle by which they have justified their secular exploitation of weaker or less intelligent races. In the British they have met with a greater power than their own, and they are content to submit to what they regard as the logical oonsequences. "I am willing," said a consistent upholder of the ancien regime, to pay yon tribute because you are the stronger. The lion has a right to take toll of the herd because he is king of the forest. But I am not willing to pay tribute tor being protected." Ha could protect himself! What, of course, he meant was that he objected to being protected under a system which protected others against himself. That, in fact was what ho practically confessed. The Arabs, he declared, are a fighting race, and the Pax Britannica had "taken all the spice out of their life." Nor are these unabashed champions of the "good old role, the simple plan,” quite ignorant of contemporary events in the civilised world. The echoes of oru quarrels reverberate to the inner Sudan. <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/39736'>Slatin</persName> Pasha was hard put to it to find a convincing answer when his Arab interrogator asked him whether we do not sometimes have wars in Europe. All he could plead in reply was the vague formula about "reasons of State." "It’s all the same,” was the almost pathetic rejoinder; "you have the sport and fun of fighting." There was no more to be said. The point of view was too hopelessly different Protesting his loyally, the aggrieved sheikh went his way, not without regretting that he "had been made like a woman.” Undoubtedly, the problem which his valdediction presents will not be solved within a few years. The Arabs, who stand for the higher, though abruptly arrested, type of social evolution in Africa, are not without certain aptitudes for civilised life. They are versed in all the arts of barter and exchange. As merchants and distributors of native products the better class may accommodate themselves to modern conditions, and the lower grade, especially when they have been crossed with negro blood, are not specially faithless or inefficient in domestic service. But for steady industrial toil they have been unfitted by centuries of idleness in the open air. Fighting is the one serious profession which appeals to their genius, and evokes their best, as well as their worst, qualities. The process of adaptation to peaceful and monotonous usefulness has hardly commenced, and it will not be completed within the lifetime of any living person. The best hope of eventual civilisation lies in their readiness to assimilate some elements of European culture. The schools and colleges which have been set at work at various centres in the Sudan may, in course of time, revive the dormant intellectual gifts of a race which at one time preserved the learning that had almost expired in the dark ages of European history Author Avrrhous may arise from the city which less than ten years ago was the unapproachable stronghold of tyranny and brutish ignorance.</p>
                    <p>British Chamber of Commerce.—We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring information on trade matters generally, including the question of appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain farther particulars from our Loudon office, 36, New Broad-street, which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> Anglo-American Nile Steiners &amp; HOTEL COMPANY. </head>
                    <p>After transport OF goods between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    Alexandria Banker Warehouse BR, LB, Is NOT a Makeshift NOR a Substitute but simply Pure Mountain Pasture CREAM. Guaranteed free from Preservative and  put up in Sterilized Tins. Keeps good IN ANY CLIMATE for MANY  MONTHS. On sale almost everywhere, but if any difficulty in procuring it, apply to</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    McLAREN’S STEAM PLOUGHS
                    BRIDGE'S
                    NoShock
                    J. &amp; H.,McLAREN
                    J. &amp; F. HOWARD, Bedford, England,
                    Brass Door Plate
                    With Mahogany Block Ready for FIxing to Door
                    Wall or Gate
                    Bulac Road .
                    COMPLETE CLUTCH Cearing And hauling
                    200 Page Catalogue Free
                    DAVID BRIDGE &amp; Co.,
                    Cairo Works,
                    Castleton, Manchester, ENGLAND.
                    24773.12.5
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PROMISE AND FULFILMENT.</head>
                    <p>The story told of Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/32680'>Curzon</persName>, when leaving Eton, promising to make a schoolfellow Chancellor of the Exchequer when himself Prime Minister, will be borne in mind, with a view to seeing if fulfilment attend the pledge, and when Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/32680'>Curzon</persName> realises his own boyish ambition. Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/35612'>Rosebery</persName> as a boy declared for the Premiership and the Derby, and has enjoyed the honors of both and is not yet old. Lord <persName ref='http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/32680'>Curzon</persName>'s horoscope, cast by a learned Hindu, includes the Premiership; hence his old-time friend may hope on. Boys' promises are easily made, and still more easily forgotten; still, some of them are redeemed. Said Disraeli to Chochare-Baillie, his school chum, "When I am Prime Minister of England, Cocky, I'll make you a peer.” And he did, and the present baron is the second holder of the title promised by a boy and given by a statesman.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AFRICA'S FUTURE RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>Great progress is being made in the opening up of the French Niger country. The railway has been carried as far as Koulikoro, on the Niger, and a steamer service has for the first time been established between this point and Timbuctoo, the river journey occupying three days. From Paris, Timbuctoo can now be reached in 15 days. It is one of the dreams of French expansion that steady improvement of the means of access may render the Niger as much a winter resort as the Nile now is.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOR SALE.</head>
                    <p>Abont 8 tons of used tents also a quantity of wood and iron, all of whioh can be seen at the Ordonance Depot, Mustapha Barracks, where a detailed list of each Lot can also be obtained.</p>
                    <p>The offers to be marked Confidential and addressed to the Chief Ordonance Officer British Head Quarters Cairo, so as to reach him on or before the 10th October, 1905.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    26499-1
                    <head>SOCIETE ANONYME DES EAUX DU CAIRE</head>
                    <p>A.	Paiement de coupons.</p>
                    <p>B.	Fracionnement des actions.</p>
                    <p>A partir. du ler octobre prochain, la Societe payera le solde du dividende de l'Exercice 1904, savoir:</p>
                    action de capital, coupon N. 32, L.E 0.427m/m jouissance, „ „ 22, „ 0.434 „
                    Part de fondateur, „	„ 32, „ 0.616 „
                    <p>et procedera en mem temps a l'excange des nouvelles actions contre celles actuelles dont le fractionnement a ete decide par l'Assemblee generale extraordinaire du  <dateline>9 Mars 1905.<dateline></p>
                    <p>Las interesses auront done a presenter lean titres en meme temps quo les bordereaux numeriques des coupons.</p>
                    <p>Les coupons mentionnes ci-dessus ne devront pas etre detaches. Ils resteront attaches aux titres presentes.</p>
                    <p>Le montant des bordereaux sera paye de suite. Quant aux titres nouveax, en raison du travail que cette operation d'exchange exigera, ils seront deliveres ulferieuremant ; les actions a exchanger seront deposees contre recepisses.</p>
                    <p>La remise dee titres nouveaux aura lieu, aussitot que possible, sur presentation de ces recepisses.</p>
                    <p>L'exchange des action sere fait sans conformite de numero.</p>
                    <p>Le paiement des coupons, ainsi que l'echange des titres, sera effectue an siege de la Societe au Caire et aux guichets du Credit Lyonnais a Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Il est rappele que le fractionnement dee titres decide par l'Assemblde generale precitee, se fera comme suit:</p>
                    <p>a) L’action actuelle de capital sera exchangee contre quatre actions de "jouissance” et une aotion de "capital" — cette derniere d'une valeur nominale de 125 Fr. donnant droit a un intere fixe de 4 % et remboursable par voie de tirages annuels.</p>
                    <p>b) L'action actuelle de "jouissance" sera exchange contre quatre actions de "jouissance."</p>
                    <p>c) Le fracctionement des "Parts de fondateur" en diximes, a ete egalement decide, mais il est facultatif et le porteur qui en fera la demande aura a payer les frais de confection des nouveaux titres.</p>
                    <p>Le Directeur p.i.</p>
                    <p>L Galvin.</p>
                    <dateline>Le Cairo,le 14 Septembre 1905. 26428-6-4</dateline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SELLING OFF SURPLUS DRAPERY STOCK OF MAGASINS VICTORIA.</head>
                    <p>Premises lately occupied by “Papeterie Commerciale," Rue Sesostris, 3 doors from Cherif Pasha Street. For particulars see</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BUTTER-SCOTCH</div>
                    <p>(The Celebrated Sweet for Children).</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Tanured Bonniui &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>The Patisserie De La Bourse,</p>
                    <p>Manufactory: London. England.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BON-ACCORD</head>
                    <p>Centrifugal Pumps,</p>
                    <p>Patent Friction Clutches.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Cairo &amp; Alexander</head>
                    <p>NB.—This Whisky is the same as supplied to the Bed Cross Society, Loudon, for use by the invalided troops and hospitals in 8outh Africa, to the House of Lords and House of Commons.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE PAVING COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                    Hamilton House, Bishopgate St. Without LONDON E.C. CONTRAOTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE
                    Pyrimont-Seyesel, Servas (France) Ragusa (Sicily), Guanipa. (Venezuela), Mine Owners
                    Egyptian BRANCH - FIR8T ASPHALT FACTORY ESTABLISHED IN EGYPT.
                    The Best Drink for Hot Countries is WATER.
                    The Best Way to make Barley Water it to use
                    It can be obtained in One Pound Tins at the Local Store,
                    Manufacturers:
                    KEEN. ROBINSON &amp; Co., Ltd., LONDON. ENGLAND.
                    Makers of ROBINSON's PATENT GROATS.
                    STEAM, ELECTRICITY, GAS. OIL OR BELT,
                    FOR
                    IRRIGATION, DRAINAGE, DOCKS, etc.
                    Apply in Egypt, Cairo and Alexandria,
                    A. ABOAF &amp; C°. (where a stock is kept.)
                    DRYSDALE &amp; Co.
                    Manufacturers
                    Bon-Accord Engine Works, Glasgow.
                    Telegrams :	Telephone :
                    "BON-ACCORD, GLASGOW." A B C &amp; LIEBER'S	2505 NATIONAL.
                    24386-7-1	COOES. Y 279 CORPORATION.
                    Agents
                    EXPORT OFFICE, wanted through Egypt.
                    ENGLISH MADE PLOUGHS
                    FOR ALL COUNTRIES AND ALL PURPOSES.
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
