<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-03">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-20">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, MAY 20 1905.</head>
<head>THE BALTIC FLEET TRANSFER OF COMMAND.</head>
St. Petersburg, May 19.
Admiral BiriletT was received in audience by
the Tsar yesterday prior to his leaving for
Vladivostok in order to take command of the
naval forces in the Far East.
The reports that; he will assume immediate
command ol the Baltio Fleet are unfounded.
Admiral ltodjestvensky will conduct all the
pending operations.	(Reuter.)
» Saigon, May 19.
The gunboat "Caronade” is watching 43
transports, mostly Russian and Merman, off
A'babe, and the "ITAsa as” is watching 20
more off Cape St. Jacques.	(Reuter.)
St. Petersburg, May 19.
Numeroua correspondents affirm that Ad-
miral Kodjeatvensky is suffering from an
internal disease and nervous breakdown. He
hopes to take the fleet to Vladivostok and
then resign and return to Russia. (Reuter.)
St. Petersburg, May 19.
As Admiral Kodjeatvensky is ill, he will
hand over the command of the fleet at Vladi-
vostok to Admiral Birileff.	( Havas, j
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
Survet Department. — The Government
has decided to open a credit ol L.E. 6,000 for
the Survey Department to make preliminary
studies of the Nile falls.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
Abdeen district of Cairo during the night of
Sunday and at dawn on Monday will be
poisoned by the police.
The Arc op Meridian. — The Egyptian
Government will shortly undertake preparations
for the measurement of an are of Meridian, as
recommended by the International Geodetio
Congress.
Found Drowned.—The corpse of a young
native boy was found floating in the Mah-
moudieh Canal yesterday. The post mortem
examination shows that death was due to
drowning.
Street Asphaltino. — The Alexandria
Municipal Delegation has given the contract
for the asphalting of a number of streets in
Alexandria to the Val de Travers Asphalte
Paving Company.
Mr. A.E. Shellard, dental surgeon to the
Army of Occupation, 32, Rue Rosette, Alexan-
dria, receives patients during the summer
mouths from 9 a.m. to 6 p.m. except Saturdays,
9 a.m. till noon.
<head>VLADIVOSTOK PREPARING FOR SIEGE</head>
.St. Petersburg, May 19.
All foreign commercial agents have been re-
quested to leave Vladivostok. A similar mea-
sure was taken at Port Arthur prior to the
investment.	(Reuter.)
Alhambra Theatre.—The production of
Ali Baba, or The Forty Thieves, last night at
the Alhambra was a great success. The piece
will be repeated to-night, and two performances
will be given to-morrow.
“HOIST WITH HIS OWN PETARD.’’
The Old Bourse Palace, which was recently
bought from Mr. Laurens by an Egyptian
Pasha, of Cairo, has since been pre-empted by
Baron Jacques de Menasce, representing the
syndicate owning the adjoining property.
<head>CURIOUS BOMB EXPLOSION.</head>
Warsaw, May 19.
Just as General Maximovitch, Governor
General of Warsaw, was about to leave the
Cathedral, after the Tsar’s birthday service, a
workman in attempting to evade two detectives
slipped on the kerb and fell, causing a bomb in
his pocket to explode. The workman, the two
detectives, and a bystanding Jew were blown
to atoms. Many others were injured. The
neighbouring buildings were wrecked. \U.)
Warsaw, May 19.
A workman who was carrying a bomb
slipped and fell. The explosion that followed
killed tho man and two policeman, and wound-
ed 17 persons. It is believed that the bomb
was intended for the Governor, who was present
at the Tsar’s birthday commemoration. (U.j
<head>JAP INVASION OF INDO-CHINA.M. DELONCLE’S REPORT.</head>
Paris, May 19.
M. Deloncle has drafted an exhaustive un-
official report concerning the contingency of a
Japanese invasion of IndoChina. It de-
monstrates in the plainest language the in-
ability of the French to resist (Router.)
<head>FRANCE AND SIAM THE FRONTIER QUESTION.</head>
Paris, .May 19.
M. Delcassl announced that Siam has accept-
ed the frontier demanded by France. The
frontier will consequently be carried back from
Cape Lending to the Paugaleng River. {R )
POLICEMEN’S STRIKE AT LYONS.
Lyons, May 19.
Some of the policemen hero have gone on
strike.	(Havas.)
GERMAN MISSION TO MOROCCO.
Tangier, May 19.
Count Tattenbach has paid a visit to the
Sultan.	(Havat.)
<head>CRICKET APPEARANCE IN MINIBH.</head>
A telegram received from Minieh Province
yesterday reports the discovery of deposits of
fresh locust eggs at Zawiet el Gadsma, Magha-
gha Marks z, on the east bank of the Nile. The
necessary steps are being taken to destroy
(hem and to search for similar deposits. Mr.
Melville is acting as inspector of Minieh pro-
vince, and is being assisted by Mr. Charman
in Beni Mazar and by Capt. Wilkinson in
About Ghirgis Markaz.
Although a considerable number of locusts
have been observed in Upper Egypt since
May 13 they are not in anything like the
quantities that arrived last year, and it
appears that only a certain number are being
carried across, probably from Arabia, by the
recent S. and S. E. wind. The prevailing strong
N. wind of last week has been most favorable
for preventing the locusts from settling long
enough to deposit eggs, and though the in-
habitants are searching most diligently wher-
ever their flights have been seen, none so far
have been discovered except at Zawiet el
Gadama.
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
H.H the Khedive will, it is expected, be the
guest of the King for five days in London.
The suite of his Highness will oonsist of
Zeky Pasha, Chefik Pasha, and Major Watson.
<head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
Suez Canal.—7 vessels passed through the
Canal on the 17th inst., 4 of which were
British, 1 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Norwegian.
The day's receipts were frs. 189,264.08, making
the total from the 1st inst. frs. 5,230,532.38.
Coal Imports.—From 1st Jan. to 18th May
312,082 tons of coal were imported into
Egypt Tho Welsh districts sent 173,769 tons,
Newcastle 68,434, the Scotch districts 38,670,
Yorkshire 17,466 and other districts 13,743
tons. For the same period last year the
quantity imported was 388,787 tons.
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
Saba Pasha is leaving this afternoon for
Trieste en route to Gratz. .During the absence
of the Postmaster-General in Europe Peake
Bey will be acting Postmaster-General.
Boghos Pasha Nubar is leaving Egypt en
route tor Paris.
Mr. McKillop, of the Inspectorate of the
Finance Ministry, is going on leave on June 6.
Mr. H. W. Tite, chief inspector of the Inter-
national Sleeping Car Co., Egypt, and Mrs.
Tite left for Cyprus yesterday.
Colonel D. F. Lewis is now in Egypt on
important financial business but it was offi-
cially announced that he had been selected to
proceed to Manchuria as Military Attache
with the Japanese army, and support was
given the statement by the fact that the offi-
cer’s name was withdrawn from the page of the
monthly “Army List”—on which it has ap-
peared since September, 1900—appropriated
to colonels on the active half-pay list The
Secretary of the War Office now writes to say
that someone in the War Office has blundered,
and that there has been confusion between
Colonel D. F. Lewis and Colonel J. P. Lewis,
and that all will be made right when the June
“Army List” appears. The explanation was
necessary, for in the "Army List” for May not
only is the name of Colonel D. F. Lewis con-
supicuous by its absence from the half-pay list,
but in column 117 it is distinctly said that he
is "attached to the Japanese army.”
<head>VISITORS LIST.</head>
London, May 19.
Surrey beat Sussex by an innings and 184
runs. Lancashire beat Derbyshire by 165 runs.
(Reuter.)
ALDERSONS GARDEN. BULKELEY.
BRAND HOTEL BONNARD,
AL1ZANDB1A.
THE LOJUST PLAGUE-
ALEXANDRIA-ODESSA.
(From our Correspondent).
Constantinople, May 16.
It is announced to-day, that some capitalists
of the Pincus have decided to found a new
navigation oompany, with a direct service
betwen Alexandria, Pirruas,Constantinople and
Odessa. The founders of this oompany are
Messrs. Stamatiad&s, Domestinia, Bayad&s and
Righinos. A steamer, with a capacity of 1,600
tons, has already been purchased for the fleet
<head>ZAGAZIG NOTES.</head>
A Council of Ministers was held this morn-
ing at Ras-el-Tin Palace under the presidency
of the Khedive.
A decree was signed by the Khedive con-
ferring the Regency on Mustapha Pasha Feh-
my, during his Highness’s absence in Europe.
Another decree was signed authorising Fuad
Pasha, Minister of Justice, to act as Minister
for Foreign Affairs during the absence of
Boutros Pasha Ghali.
The Council also received intimation from
the Public Works Ministry as to the appoint-
ment ol Mr. London to the Inspectorate of
the Irrigation Department The Council decided
to levy a house tax at Luxor from the be-
ginning of 1906.
Approbation was given to the scheme for the
construction of four drainage canals through
the Daiia Sanieh’s estates at Arment
The Council agreed to the project if the
Railway Administration for enlarging Minieh
station and authorised the creation of an inland
navigation company for the Delta and Upper
Egypt, and an Egyptian Cigarettes Company.
<head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCES.</head>
(From our Correspondent).
Zagaxig, Thursday.
The cotton worm has appeared on some
lands in the Sharkieh Province. The Ministry of
the Interior has already appointed some
officials to destroy the eggs, but more officials
are wanted.
The clover worm is prevalent on the Khartema
lands near the Ismailieh Canal. The Moudirieh
is taking measures to destroy the pest.
Yesterday afternoon two carts laden with
onions,were run over by a train while crossing
the railway line by El Mina. The carts were
broken and the four horses were horribly
mangled. The police arrested the engine river.
A private carriage belonging to Count
Shedid, a Coptio notable with a European
title, ran over a native woman. The poiioe
arrested the coachman and are investigating
the matter.
<head>TECHNICAL EDUCATION AT ASSIOUT.</head>
A correspondent writes :—"Many letters
have of late been written to the newspapers
by Cairenes complaining of the noise which
prevails in the streets of the city almost con-
tinuously throughout the night The disturb-
ance complained of is chiefly caused by noisy
Berboreen who, after regaling themselves at their
favourite cafes to counteract the effect of the
day’s work, make their way homewards at an
early hour of the morning singing, shouting,
and often quarrelling. One group of these
noisy Berboreen follows another with but short
interval, some with and some without musical
instruments, and the peaceful inhabitant only
falls asleep to be re-awakened time after time.
After the last of these noisy groups has passed
one may perhaps be able to indulge in a short
hour’s sleep, when the beating of carpets close
at hand or the hideous yell of some hawker in
the streets below robs one of all further chance
of rest
"To expect that the shawish should stop
these noises on his own initiative is to expect
too much, for the native policeman never
notices a noise; he lives in an atmosphere of
it, it never disturbs him, and as often as not
he creates or greatly adds to it in the carry-
ing out of his duties. The necessary step to be
taken to put a stop to such disturbances is
for the police authorities to issue spexial
instructions to the polixe to arrest anyone
singing or shouting in the streets during the
night, and should complaints continue to be
made, to punish in some way the shawish in
charge of the quarter from which the complaint
comes. Notice should also be given to house-
holders that the beating of carpets at an hour
when the city is supposed to sleep, is creating
a public disturbance for which they are liable
to be summoned.
<head>NEW STEAMSHIP LINE.</head>
(From o
Mr. A. Hodgson, metal work instructor
under the London County Council, has been
selected by Sir Philip Magnus, at the request
of Johnson Pasha, for appointment under the
Egyptian Government as foreman instructor in
the engineering section of the model workshop
at the new school at Assiout about to be
opened. Mr. Hodgson has arrived at Alex-
andria.
The Assiout Model Workshop when finished
will cost £16,000. It will be in its main line
based on the model workshop at Cairo, over
which Johnson Pasha is presiding with such
success. The only other institutions of a similar
kind are the industrial school at Abou Tig,
founded by the liberality and public spirit of
Mohamed Suleiman Pasha, a leading member
of the Legislative Council, and the industrial
school which is being built by the Moslem
Benevolent Society at Alexandria.
<head>HIGH CAPACITY BOGIE WAGONS FOR EGYPT A SUCCESSFUL EXPEDITION.</head>
Khartoum.—The first detachment of the
Niam-Niam expedition, which has arrived at
Khartoum, report that all is quiet in the
Southern part of the Bahr-el-Gazal. The whole
trouble had arisen from the opposition of an
old chief, named Yambio, who opposed the
Government at every turn and influenced his
sons and nephews and the chiefs of all the
tribes in his district More than once they
attempted to ambush some small detachments
on duty, and the climax was reached in
March, 1904, when Captain Haynes was
killed. An expedition was then despatched
under the command of Major Boulnois, and
Yambio’s village was reached on February 7.
Every possible chance was given to Yambio
to come in. He sent his son Gangasa to
palaver, but was afraid to come himself.
After two days of palavering by messenger,
Lieutenant Fell, R. N., now inspector in the
province, was sent out to interview Yambio,
who had by this time retired to the extreme
end of his village, six miles off. The old chief
was evidently acting treacherously, for a large
force of spearmen was found in the village, and
his eldest son was stationed on the Yubbo to
oppose the advance. Lieutenant Fell offered to
talk with Yambio If his men would lay down
their spears. This they agreed to do, but took
them up again as soon as our people approach-
ed. On their doing this the second time, and
after full warning, two or three volleys were
fired, and the enemy bolted. A couple of days
later some prisoners undertook to show
Yambio’s hiding place. He was surprised and
caught and brought in by Captain Carter. It
appeared that he had been badly wounded in
the wrist and knee. Everything was done to
save him, but either through shock or fear,
<head>THE CLEARING OF THE SPHINX.</head>
WINDSOR HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA
Mr. B. Chasse, Mr. Alfred Burke Honan,
Mr. Gustave Jullien, Aerout Bey, Mr. Valadier,
Saleh Bey Yaghen, Mr. Robert Angel, Mr.
Const Papadakhis, Mr. G. Diaoono, Miss
Crother, Mr. Benzia, Mr. Wilson, Mr. Lakah,
Mr. Forster, Baron de Palm, Mr. N. Matzoukis,
Mr. Ernest Stofiler, Mr. M. Marsh, Mr.
Turabian and family, Mr. Chrysoooidis, Mr.
Cooper, Mr. Vogel, Mr. Alberti and family,
Mr. J. Taylor, Mr. Robert Angee, Mr. Faul-
conbridge, Mr. H. Ramsay, Miss Shirmer, Mr.
Thyss, Mr: G. Dahan, Mr. Pearson, Mr. Nor-
mandean, Mr. V. S. Sdvosly, Mr. Drankoff,
Mr. Boulad, Mr. Mathiopoulos, Mr. Coidan,
Mr. ReutoD, Sabry Bey, Yaooub Bey, Mr.
Borton, Mr. Monis, Mr. N. Proya, Mr. Achagi,
Mrs. Yamos, Mr. Cooper, Count Bizzo Noris,
Mr. Valenzia, Mr. Pbotiue Vlandis, Mr. A
Vin^n (Albert).
A meeting of the oommittee whioh was
appointed to consider the scheme for the
excavation of the Sphinx and which it will be
remembered consisted of Judge Royle, Mr.
Courtnay Clifton, and Mr. Allan Joseph was
held at Judge Royle’s house at 5 p.m. yester-
day. Mr. Dow Covington, who is acting iD
co-operation with the committee, was also
present.
On the proposition of Judge Royle Dr.
Ibrahim Pasha Hassan was added to the
committee, and also Judge Tuck, on the pro-
position of Mr. Allan Joseph.
It was decided to approach the Government
about the granting of a conditional concession
before any general appeal for funds was made
to the public.
In the evolution of modem Egypt, with its
many conflicting interests and influences,
changes in the types of rolling stock have been
frequent, and the result has been that the types
used are often strangely assorted. Little by
little, however, the rolling stock is beginning to
sort itself out into distinct types,and the rapid
increase in the requirements of the country
have brought hume the fact to the authorities
that the best is the cheapest in the long run.
Quite recently the Leeds Forge Company
delivered to Alexandria six each of two types
of “high capacity” coal and grain bogie wagons.
As the Egyptian Railways have just placed a
further order for thirty of each of these types,
it is quite clear that they may be looked upon
as the standard wagons for handling coal,grain,
and kindred products on a large scale on the
more important lines, at all events, of Lower
Egypt. It should be noted, however, that with
regard to the covered wagons, the repeat order
provides for an extra 18 ins. in the height of the
roof. One of the types is a thirty-ton coal wagon,
with a length over buffers of 37 ft. and a height
from rail level of 7ft. 6ins. The inside dimensions
are :—Length, 34 ft ; width, 8 ft 9 ins. ; and
depth, 4 ft., which gives a cubic capacity of
1,185 ft It has a tare of 12 tons 18 oats.,
which gives a ratio of tare to the gross load
of rather over 30 per cent
The other type is a thirty-ton covered wagon,
destined more particularly for carrying grain
and kindred goods. The length over buffers is
87 ft and i in. The height from rail level to
top of roof at centre is 10 ft 2 J ins. The inside
dimensions are Length, 34 ft ; width, 8 ft.
9 ins. ; and depth, 6 ft 4 13-16 ins., which
gives a cubic capacity of 1,900 ft It has a tare
of 14 tons 1} oats., which gives a ratio of tare
to tho gross load of just under 32 per cent
The covered wagons are fitted with two sliding
doors on each side, these doors having a width
of 4ft 9} ins., and a height of 5 ft 10} ins.
The under frames are of the Fox's patent com-
pressed steel type. The bogie centre castings
are provided with exceptionally large wearing
surfaces on account of the sand and dust so
prevalent in Egypt. The wheels have a diame-
ter on the tread of 2 ft 9 ins., a wheel base of
5 ft 6 ins., and the distance between bogie
centres is 23 ft
The Leeds Forge Company, in addition to
the above, have on order for the Egyptian
State Railways thirty bogie platform wagons
with steel floors, but without sides and ends,
and ten thirty-ton oil tank wagons. All of these
will be fitted with under-frames and bogies
similar in construction and dimensions to
those above described.
TYROL.-
TVUGI - Weissenatein Castle 841
1 I AwL. ft First-class private
hotel near Windisch-Matrei; Station, Lienz
(reached from Venioe or Trieste). Good
mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best
June and September. Prospectuses and Pho-
tographs, " Egyptian Gazette ” offioe, Cairo.
158M-48M5
<head>AMONG THE NIAM-NIAMS THE EGYPTIAN QUESTION.M. DE FREYCINET’S VIEWS.</head>
A treatise on the Egyptian question by M.
de Freycinet is about to be published. The
ex-Premier recognises the magnitude of the
work aooompliahed by England, but he"con-
siders that her domination over Egypt must
sooner or later come to an end. The Powers
have done nothing to cut short the British
occupation, but at the same time they have
not formally approved it From a legal point
of view England’s exceptional transitory po-
sition, to use the late Marquis of Salisbury's
expression, remains unaltered. It is unaffected
by the Franoo-English Agreement of 1904.
Europe may at any time bring up the question
and demand a settlement in conformity with
equal rights.
M. de Freyoinet thinks, however, that Eng-
land will eventually relinquish Egypt sponta-
neously in exchange for the full possession
of the Sudan, so that here undisputed sover-
eignty would extend from the Second Cataraot
to Victoria Nyanza. He suggests that Germany’s
apparent support of the British claims in 1896
was inspired by a desire to perpetuate a source
of friction between France and England.
<head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
( From our Corrbfondint ).
Port Said, Friday.
THE ORIENT MAIL
Yesterday the Orient Line S.8. "Ortona”
arrived over 4 } hours late, and this in spite
of perfect weather. I was informed on board
that the lateness of her arrival is directly due
to the new clause in the Australian Govern-
ment Mail contract, which compels the ships to
carry a white crew in the stokehold as well as
on deck. last year, with three boilers and
native stokers, these ships always arrived be-
fore daylight, and the "Ortona" yesterday,
with four boilers and white men below, lost 5
hours in 8 days' steaming.
ELECTRIC LIGHT IN PORT SAID.
The original monopoly contract, by which
the Gas Company here, have the sole right to
provide municipal and private lighting for the
town of Port Said, controls the "at some near
date” laying and installing of electric lighting
plant This plant is now in full working order
throughout the European quarter, but the
odds are, for the present at any rate, in favor
of gas, for, although the latter is of exception-
ally bad quality and a source of constant an-
noyanoe to its unhappy users, it is certainly
less costly than the decided luxury of
electricity.
The question of the monopoly is freely dis-
cussed here, and the arguments always return
to the same point, vis.; how is it that the sole
right to supply gas, electric, or any other arti-
ficial lighting, was granted to one syndicate 1
The result is, of course, the prohibitive cost of
electricity and the extraordinarily bad quality
of gas, against either of which no user has the
slightest redress 1
THE^AIDA.”
H.H.3. “Aida” arrived here from Alexandria
at 11 am. yesterday and moored at the buoys
in front of the Lighthouse Department’s local
office. She is to proceed to Suez en route for
the Rod Sea lighthouses to-day.
LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.
A SOIREE NOIRE AT CAIRO.
To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir,—I was glad to see the protest in your
issue of yesterday against the recent "Soifee
Noire" at the Nouveautds Theatre here. Why
the police allow such exhibitions I do not
know, for they are a disgrace to Cairo, and
no theatre that has any claim to be consi-
dered a respectable place of entertainment
ought to try to attract an audience by such
means. The Government in the interests of
purity ought, if it be prevented from putting
a stop altogether to these entertainments in
virtue of the Capitulations, at least to
let it be known that no officials should
attend a "Soifee Noire.” I regret to hear that
some young Anglo-Egyptian officials were
present, but I can hardly believe this. Surely
the youthful English officials in the service of
the Egyptian Government could find a more
improving way of spending an evening than
in attending a "Soirde Noire.”—I am, etc.,
“An Englishman."
Cairo, May 19.
<head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
The Moss liner "Tabor” arrived at Liver-
pool on Thursday morning.
The Moss liner “Seti" sailed Thursday
aiternoon for Liverpool, vih Malta, with pas-
sengers, mails, and general cargo, including
2,086 bales cotton.
<head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
The following is the programme to be per-
formed by the Bracale Orchestra to-morrow
morning commencing at 10 o'olook.
} oanna.
Ourortare—M Ignoo-Tbomaa.
Japo Nlalaarla-Cliapul*.
Anglo-American Mile Steamer,
RIVER TRANSPORT OF OOUHTBETltEI AlOAIORU A OAIRJ
Three Ulnae e-Weak.
<head>THE COTTON MARKET</head>
Kxabslby and Cunningham's Weekly Repor!
Liverpool, May 11.
Egyptian cotton has been w good demand
this week, and a good business has been put
through. The market however has been freely
supplied.
Quotations of the current qualities of Brown
are raised 3/16, Fine 1/8, and all Upper Egyp-
tian 1/16 per lb. There has been a fairly
active business in futures, the following being
the latest values:—
May 6 51 July 6.43 Sep. 6.38
June 6.46 Ang. 6.40 Oct 6.37 Nov. 6.82
American Futures.—The market this week
has again been fairly active, and prices have
experienced constant fluctuations, with the
tendenoy however to higher values. To-day’s
dosing rates are 11 @ 14 points above those
of last Thursday.
There is no special feature, the weather
conditions are cot much improved, and the
government weekly report again emphasises
Die fact that a considerable area in Texas,
Arkansas, and Mississipi Valley is still un-
plan ted ; this and the general lateness of the
crop may easily cause anxiety, unless there is
a quick change to favorable weather condi-
tions throughout. Speculation is at present
held in check by the heavy crop movements
and the acknowledged large surplus to be
carried forward, bat unless the growing crop
prospects quickly become decidedly more favor-
able, speculation will develop and prices ex-
perience a further advance.
The following are the dosing quotations,
Delivery:
May 4.19 Aug./8ep. 4.23 Deo./Jan. 4.27
May/June 4.19 Sep./Oot 4.24 Jan./Feb. 4.28
June/July 4.2s) Oct/Nov. 4.25 Feb./Mar. 4.29
July/Aug. 4.21 Nov./Deo. 4.26 Mar./ApL 4.81
Calendar of Coming Events
ALEX AN DRIA.
May.
Sat 20 Raoe from 8idi'Gaber to Alexandria
by pupils of Scotch School. 6a.m.
A. C. C. grounds. Crioket Gap
rison XI v. A. C. C. 1.30 p.m.
Mustapha Rifle Range. Praotioe
by B. R. C. 2.30 p.m.
Alhambra. Italian operetta oom-
pany in Ali Baba. 9 p.m.
New Khedivial Hotel. Conoert
Rodolfo Chimienti. 9 p.m.
San Stefano Casino. Opening Ball
of Season. 10 p.m.
Son. 21 San Stefano Casino. Conoert 10 eon.
Gabbari. Pigeon Shooting. 2.80 p.m.
Tues. 23 Cricket E. T. C. v. Sergeants of
the Berks. Commence 2 p.m. on
A. C. C.
San Stefano Casino. A. L M. &
D. 8. Conoert 9.16 p.m.
Than. 25 A S. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting. 3.30 p.m.
Conoert at Sailors’ and 8oldiers’
Institute. 8 p.m.
8at 87 A. R C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting. 8.80 p.m.
OAI RO.
Toes. 28 Esbekioh Gardens. Performance by
British Military Band. 9 to 11
p.m.
Wed. 24 Masonio Hall. Meeting Idris Lodge.
8.80 p.m.
ARISTON AERATED WATERS
Guaranteed Dlertlllod.
ALEXANDRIA:	1,^	w*.
T, BwlsUPwfc. I </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
