<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, DECEMBER 14 1905.</head>
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TSAR’S ARMY FAITHFUL.</head>
                    <head>WITTE NOT TO RESIGN.</head>
                    <head>RUSSIAN FINANCES SOUND</head>
                    <p>(Gazette's Special Service).</p>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Count Witte declares that the Russian army is still faithful to the Tsar, in spite of the many mutinies which have broken out. The finances of the country are, he states, perfectly sound, and he asserts that the interest on the Russian bonds will be faithfully and punctually paid. Count Witte adds that he has no intention whatever of resigning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PLOT AGAINST THE TSAR.</head>
                    <head>WORK OF ZEMSTVOS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg. December 13.</p>
                    <p>Governors of provinces and districts where until now martial law has not been enforced have been invested with practically dictatorial powers for three months.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Warsaw, December 13.</p>
                    <p>The police in the first arrondissement have gone on strike.</p>
                    <p>It is rumoured that the Zemstvos have plotted to overthrow the Tsar in favor of a constitutional monarch.</p>	 <p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MACEDONIAN REFORM SCHEME.</head>
                    <head> THE PORTE’S REPLY.</head>
                    <p>Paris, December 13.</p>
                    <p>In its reply the Porte accepts the financial regulation of Macedonia and makes reserves concerning the military budget, based on a previous arrangement with the Ottoman Bank approved by the Ambassadors.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREAT BRITAIN AND GERMANY.</head>
                    <head>COMMERCIAL ARRANGEMENT.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, December 13.</p>
                    <p>The Reichstag has agreed to the extension of the provisional commercial arrangement with Great Britain.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF BRITISH GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>London, December 13.</p>
                    <p>General Robert Younghusband is dead.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>The late General Robert Romer Younghus-band was born in 1819, and entered the army in 1837, being made General in 1877. He served in Scinde and Beloochistan in 1840-42 and was with the Light Battalion at Candahar. He was Brigade-Major in the battles of Meanee and Hyderabad from 1843-48 and of the Raj-pootana Field Force, 1852-54. He was Assistant Adjutant General at Scinde from 1854 to 1856 and Deputy Adjutant General, Persian Expeditionary  Force, from 1856 to 1857 (medal with clasp and C.B.). From 1862 to 1866 he was Brigadier-General commanding at Nusse-rabad.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Lieut. Colonel R. C. C. Cox, commanding, and officers 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will perform the following programme of music on the terrace, National Hotel, Cairo to-morrow (Friday) from 4 to 6 p.m:—</p>
                    <p>March... "Consellation"...F. Clarke</p>
                    <p>Overture..."The Village Festival"...O'Keefe</p>
                    <p>Air ..‘‘La Cinquantaine"...Muller</p>
                    <p>Selection..."The Gondoliers"...sullivan</p>
                    <p>Spanish Valse..."Torero"...Translateur</p>
                    <p>Bascarolle..."seur le Lido"...Thony</p>
                    <p>Selection .."Boccaccio"...suppé</p>
                    <p>Porto Rican Dance..."Rosita"...Misaud</p>
                    <p>Regimental March - Khedivial Anthem..</p>
                    <p>God Save the King</p>
                    <p>R. Watson Ramser, Bandmaster.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel. Patronised by the elite.Full pension from P.T. 40 a day. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Built in 1904. Modern House. Splendid situation. Electric Light Lift. Pension P.T. 50. Arrangements for families.</p>
                    <p>and Breakfast P.T. 25.---Meals a la carte.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-xx-xxx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. </p>
                    <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                    <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
                    <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Conservatoire of Music.</p>
                    <p>The committee of the Alexandria Conservatoire  have decided on opening a singing class for young girls in the morning.</p>
                    <p>Khedive's Accession Fetes.</p>
                    <p>The subscriptions collected for the celebration of the anniversary of the Khedive’s accession now amount to L E. 565.</p>
                    <p>American Mission.</p>
                    <p>Ismail Bey Asem, the Cairo advocate, will speak on the subject of temperance at the American Mission church to-night at 8 o’clock.</p>
                    <p>Kasr-el-Nil Bridge.</p>
                    <p>From Friday, 15th inst, and until further notice the Kasr el Nil Bridge will be open to navigation and closed to traffic from 1.30 to 3 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Execution.</p>
                    <p>A nonogenarian criminal will be executed in a few days time. Mohamed Aboa El Ghali, such is his name, is 90 years of age and was found guilty of poisoning five of his nephews and nieces.</p>
                    <p>National Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Every Friday afternoon during the season, the band of the 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, under the bA on of Mr. R. Watson Ramsey, will perform a programme of music on the terrace of this hotel from 4 to 6 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sanitary Dept.</p>
                    <p>MM. Charles Vermeulen, Herbert Bill Han-son, Max Zaccar and Abdallah Y. Meraeb, physicians Dimitri Comanios, pharmacist, and. Wahiba Mohamed, Bamba Said and Lambrini Phlokioti, midwives, have been authorized to practise in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>All Saints', Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>A vocal and instrumental concert will be held on Friday, 29th inst., at 9 p.m, in the Parish Room, the Parsonage, Bulkeley, in aid of church expenses of All Saints,' Ramleh. The following have kindly offered their assistance : Messrs. M. A. Ruffer, Ehrlich and Artelli, Mr-. Edward Miss, Miss Violet Alderson, Miss Harden, and Mr. H.V. Hall. In addition, Lira Lehmann’s song-cycle, entitled "The Daisy Chain," will be given by the following ladies and gentlemen : Mrs W. R. Williams. Miss Carver, Mr. J. Purvis, and Rev. R. F Rynd. Tickets, P.T. 20 each (no reserved seats), can be obtained from F. Mellor and Co., Old Bourse Street, Alexandria, and D. Stein and Co. (near tram station), Bulkeley, or from the clergy.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Prince Auguste and Prince Pierre d’Aren-berg, with Count de Choiseul, Coant de Se-rionne, and M. Tillier, left Port Said for Ismailia on Tuesday. The party will stay a few days at Ismailia before leaving for Mombasa and Lake Victoria.</p>
                    <p>The Earl and Countess of Carnarvon are to spend a few weeks in Egypt in the New Year, and will leave Marseilles on January 12.</p>
                    <p>Sir Malcolm Mollwraith arrived at Assiout on Tuesday and opened his inspection of the native tribunals yesterday.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Machell, Adviser to the Ministry of the Interior, is leaving England for Egypt on the 21st inst.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at Shepheard's Hotel are Sir William and Lady Goulding. Sir William is the Chairman of the Great Southern and Western Railway of Ireland.</p>
                    <p>Mr. W. R. Bousfield, KC., M.P , contra dicta the statement that he is going for a tour in Greece and Egypt next spring.</p>
                    <p>Herr Kehren, who has been till now attached to the German Consulate at Antwerp, has been appointed Vice Consul at Cairo, to replace Dr. Rhomberg, who has been transferred to Barcelona. Herr Kehren is expected to arrive towards the end of the month.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Wells, Chief Inspector of Mines to the Ministry of Finance, has left for Edfon with Mr. Mitchell Innes. The Undersecretary of State for Finance will accompany Mr. Wells on a ten days’ inspecting trip in the mining districts between the Nile and the Red Sea.</p>
                    <p>Mustapha Pasha Kamel editor of "Al Lewa," has been admitted as "Stagiaire” at the Cairo Mixed Bar by the Mixed Court of Appeal.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice Comte de Miramon, Comtesse de Miramon, Mr. H. C. Bryant, Mr. and Mrs. Chanter, Mr. Mitcheson, Mr. and Mme Stenapholi, Frl Huffner, Frl. von Carls brog, Mr. H. Broadhurst, Crook shank Pasha. Bimbashi Edgeworth, B.A., Lady Nesta Fitz-Gerald, Mr. Meredith, Mr. Star, Mr. Christian and party, Mr. Hanna.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said are Mr. M. Kar-minski, Mr. W. R, B. Briscoe, Mr. R, S. Nicholson, Mr. G. W. Parker, Miss J. Smith, Mr. H. Whiteside, Mrs. Whiteside, Mr. W. Wilson, Mrs. Wilson. Purvis Bey, M. G. Pellegrini, the New Italian Vice-Consul at Port-Said, Mr. C. T. Morris, and Mr. A. Eaman.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GOLD IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <head>THE RECENT IMPORTANT FINDS.</head>
                    <p>The recent discovery of gold in the western oases is of the first importance not only to the interests of the Corporation of Western Egypt but to the general development of the mining industry of the country. It affords a first indication of the actual direction in which the gold has drifted that must have been eroded from the eastern hills daring vast geological periods before man appeared in the Nile Valley, and also of the probable manner of its deposition.</p>
                    <p>So far as the immediate interests of the Corporation are concerned,2 dwts. per ton may not seem, at first sight, to be very important; but it is to be remembered that the gold is contained in pyrites which form generally more than one-tenth of the phosphate rook. This rook must in any case be powdered to be commercially useful, and when this is done the pyrites can be separated with very little expense, while the richness and commercial value of the phosphates are greatly enhanced by its removal.</p>
                    <p>The separated pyrites should then carry from half an ounce to an ounce per ton. and will be valuable as a source of sulphur and sulphuric acid, in addition to yielding this amount of gold. It will also be necessary to enquire what has become of the gold that has weathered out of the extensive phosphate outcrops  since the oases were first formed or since their formation commenced.</p>
                    <p>It is impossible to say at present exactly where it may be found, but it is at least permissible  to hope that it is held within the oases area. Another point to be considered is what indication this discovery may give to aid in tracing and discovering the “deep leads” which very possibly exist between the gold belts of the Eastern hills and the oases. The discovery of such leads would give a new impulse to Egyptian mining, and might result in most important developments.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASSOUAN RESERVOIR.</head>
                    <p>The adjudication on tenders for.the protec-tive works downstream of the looks at Assouan Reservoir has been settled in favor of the following contractors : —</p>
                    <p>L.E.
                        Urquhart and Williamson .... 4.889 G. Mitchell and Mohamed Ibrahim . . 8,033
                        G. H. West............................6,722
                        W. H. Williamson...................... 3 350</p>
                    <p>The tender of Messrs. Urqnhart and William-son  for the supply of atone facings in hewn granite for the talus works downstream of the looks at Assouan Reservoir baa been accepted. It is for LE 10,200.</p>
                    <p>The above works are the result of 8ir Benjamin Baker's visit last season. Whenhe visited the work last winter, he recommended extensive protective works on the talus downstream of the dam, where the severe action of the water through he sluices had eroded even the sound granite. The P. W. D. had recognised the necessity of these protective works and had already commenced them, and had in 1901 completed the repairs of certain of the worst places, and were intending to spend a further sum of L.E 50,000 in 1905. Sir Benjamin, however, recommended protective works upon a still larger scale than this, which will involve an expenditure of something like a quarter of a million of money, and take two years to complete.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXPEDITION FOR STUDYING THE NILE CATARACTS.</head>
                    <p>It has been decided to make a complete and detailed survey of the Nile cataracts, south of Wady-Halfa, and to study the possibility of constructing another dam and reservoir , somewhere to the south of the existing one. Such a supplementary work will probably be necessary, under any circumstances, even should the Assouan dam be raised, as the future wants of Egypt will necessitate a very large amount of water being stored, In any work of the kind, constructed south of Wady-Halfa, a navigation channel and looks may be omitted, as, with the railway from Wady-Halfa to Khartoum, no through river traffic is likely to arise, more especially as, on this reach of the river, it must always be difficult and dangerous, and only possible during flood.</p>
                    <p>The survey parties commenced work this autumn.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAMPING OUT IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>There is some probability of the neighbourhood of the Ghizeh pyramids becoming a favorite site for a residential European tent dwelling colony. The Public Security Department of the Ministry of the Interior has determined that these squatters should not be permitted to pitch their tents there just as they please, and a notice has been issued wherein it is stated that it is forbidden to erect tents in the vicinity of the Ghizeh pyramids without a permit from the Ministry of tbs Interior.</p>
                    <p>Applications for such permits most be addressed to the Minister of the Interior. The name and surname of the Applicant, nationality, occupation and residence, together. with the number of tents, the site on which they are to be erected, and the period for which the permit is required, must be mentioned in the application.</p>
                    <p>This regulation is also to apply to the erection of tents in the neighbourhood of monuments of the past at Assouan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUIET AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <head>ACTION OF AUTHORITIES.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday no incident occurred at Alexandria to disturb public security, but the state of mind of a large portion of the European population is by no means tranquil. As an example of this feeling of insecurity we may instance the run on the shops of the gunsmiths yesterday. The police authorities thought that yesterday the panic had to all appearances so much subsided that it would be permissible to allow the gunsmiths' establishments to be reopened. But as soon as the decision of the authorities became known, there was a great rush to buy arms on the part of Europeans and a big trade was done in revolvers end other weapons. The authorities decided therefore to again order the closing of these shops, and this morning all of the gunsmiths were shut up and will remain so until further notice.</p>
                    <p>The police authorities ere quite satisfied that the attitude of the natives is peaceful, and they are in fact quite cowed. But the authorities state that they are afraid of the Europeans in their present excited state, and believe that if there is any renewal of the disturbance it will be provoked by the Europeans.</p>
                    <p>Morice Bey, Inspector of the Parquet at the Ministry of Justice, has arrived from Cairo in connection with the forthcoming trials of the persons accused of having taken part in the riot on Sunday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Up to now no death has occurred among the Europeans and natives injured in the disorders. Mr. Marsden, the sub-manager of the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, is recovering from his wound, and will in all probability be able to resume his duties next week.</p>
                    <p>CONVOCATION OF SHEIKHS.</p>
                    <p>This morning and yesterday afternoon there were two important meetings of all the religious sheikha, who are accustomed to preach in the mosques at Alexandria. These meetings were convened by the order of Mahmoud Pasha 8idky, Governor of Alexandria, and all who were summoned attended. The Governor addressed the sheikhs on the subject of the recent disturbance and laid strict injunctions upon them all to use their best endeavours in their religious addresses to impress upon their hearers the need for calmness, as unless the populace preserved its self-control public security would again be disturbed. His Excellency's earnest exhortations had a great effect on his audience and all the sheikhs present this morning and at yesterday's meeting promised the Governor that they would be untiring in their efforts to use their religious influence in the interests of public tranquillity.</p>
                    <p>EUROPEAN CLERICAL INFLUENCE</p>
                    <p>His Holiness Photius, the Greek Orthodox Patriarch of Alexandria, has informed the Governor that he will in his sermon on Sunday next dwell upon the necessity of peace and harmony between the Orthodox Greek population and the natives. His Holiness has also enjoined the Orthodox clergy throughout Alexandria , to endeavour to pacify any excitement  among members of their congregations.</p>
                    <p>The Latin Archbishop of Alexandria has also undertaken to use his influence in the same direction.</p>
                    <p>FEARS FOR THE FUTURE.</p>
                    <p>Nervous people have been considerably alarmed by the very widespread rumours as to a forthcoming renewal of the disturbance which it is alleged has been timed to take place on Sunday next But the authorities are fully prepared for any such renewal of the troubles and all precautions have been taken to prevent any disorders again breaking out so there is not the slightest need for any alarm.</p>
                    <p>TELEGRAM FROM MUSTAPHA PASHA KAMEL</p>
                    <p>The following telegram was received by us yesterday, too late for inclusion in our issue of that day:--</p>
                    <p>Please read what I have written in the "Reforme" yesterday, so that yon may know that I had always preached the harmony of the.Eyptians and the Europeans residents, and that the accusing of the Egyptians and the leaders of the public opinion in Egypt with fanatism is an absurd thing which promotes discord and dissension. I believe that the difference in political opinions does not tend to instigate the holders of such opinions to accuse themselves injustly. I see that the interest of my country lies in the preservance of peace and tranquillity. No one can say that I have said or done the reverse. I affected that you will turn a deaf ear to the fabricated and alarming reports promoted by the alarmists for personal prejudices and especial designs and to interpret with great care what is published in the Mohamedan newspapers about the Macedonian crisis before giving any decision about their attitude. Had you done so you would have seen that the "Al Lewa” is the mildest and most of all in exerting efforts to cultivate agreement between the different nationalities in Egypt I am much astonished for yon have not written any blaming word to the foreign rabbles who were the cause of the Alexandrian disturbance. I believe that the only remedy to such inconveniences is the allowing the Mixed Tribunals to settle criminal cases committed by or against the foreigners for it is the only thing which preserves the public security,—Mustapha Kamel Pasha.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LAST SUNDAY'S RIOT.</head>
                    <head>CORRESPONDENT’S VIEWS</head>
                    <p>A well-known resident at Alexandria writes:—I would express the view, if you will kindly permit me to do so through you, that it would be safer not to belittle last Sunday’s disturbances. It is quite possible that had your paper been rather more of an alarmist, you might have moved the authorities to have been bettor prepared, and that, as a  consequence, last Sunday’s riot would have been suppressed with such promptitude and energy as to have justified you in assuring the public now that no repetition of such recurrences need be feared. As it is, rumour has it, in spite of everything that the papers say, that next Sunday is to be the witness of a far more grave state of things than last Sunday was, and this is repeated with such assurance by so many months that many people are becoming seriously alarmed. Of what use is it to be satisfied to merely state that there is no farther occasion for alarm and to make other such like statements, as the papers are now doing. These statements do not reassure people in the least, they are simply a repeti tion of those made in 1882. What people want to know is what precautions are being taken by the authorities against a repetition of Sunday’s disturbances. They want to see there mentioned by newspapers, such as your own, after due enquiry has been made. They want to learn if it is. intended to deal severely and promptly with all disturbers' of the peace, and, if so, they want such intentions to be made generally known. They want to know if such enquiries are being made as to the original cause of last Sunday’s rioting as will lead to the detection of the persons responsible for the feeling which caused a mere gambling quarrel to assume the proportions it did. They want aall this to be mads generally known in order not only to judge if tranquillity has really been assured for the present, but to serve as a lesson to persons interested in creating discord and riot that their acts, however carefully hidden, will be certainly traced and brought home to them with the utmost severity.</p>
                    <p>The foregoing, I venture to submit, will do more to allay toe fears of nervous people than mere assurance and pooh-poohing the gravity of what has taken place. It is quite correct to reassure our visitors the tourists, but residents who are in continual touch with the natives' and know what is really going on also require some consideration, and mere state menu that all is now quiet will hardly satisfy them. The natives themselves, those who desire law and order, require to be reassured also ; they are far from being so at present Many of my native friends openly tell me they are much afraid of farther disturbances business is also affected by the present state of things. As to the villages, I fear that unless the authorities show a firm hand and the intention to use most severe measures there may be trouble there also.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAPITULATIONS.</head>
                    <p>The disturbance on Sunday has led to a discussion of the part the Capitulations played as a secondary cause.</p>
                    <p>"Al Moayad" is of opinion that the Capitula-tions are greatly to be blamed for the outbreak at Alexandria, and it urges the Government to prevent Europeans from carrying arms.</p>
                    <p>"Al Abram" says that the English want to use the disturbance as a lever to obtain more power than before, and both "Al Lewa” and "Al Ahram” claim that the Mixed Courts should be made competent in the case of European criminals. His view is opposed to that of Lord Cromer, who states in his last Report that "‘The proposal to transfer criminal jurisdiction over Europeans from the consular to the Mixed Courts is not one which the British Government could, under present circumstances , view with favor, nor one which they could advise the Egyptian Government to accept."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                    <p>There have been many rumours since Sunday as to an approaching increase in the strength of the Army of Occupation, especially as regards the garrison at Alexandria. We have, however, been unable to obtain any official confirmation of these rumours.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. MARK’S AND ALL SAINTS</head>
                    <p>The Rev. A. H. Longley, B. A., late mathematical scholar of Corpus Christi College, Cambridge, now chaplain in St George's Collegiate Church, Jerusalem, has accepted the post of assistant chaplain and will leave for Alexandria at the end of this month.</p>
                    <p>The Rev. R. Wormell has accepted from the India Office a chaplaincy in the Bombay Ecclesiastical Establishment.</p> 	<p>Algernon Ward.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The M.M. steamer Portugal arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria yesterday morning.</p>
                    <p>The S.S.. Egyptian (Westcott and Lauranoe Line) left Malta yesterday and is doe here next Sunday, with general cargo from Antwerp and London.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Bloemfontein (Westcott and Lau-rance Line) left Malta yesterday and is due here Sunday next with general cargo from Antwerp and London, and coals from New castle.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE.</head>
                    <head>10% DIVIDEND DECLARED.</head>
                    <p>The directors-ofthe Khedivial Mail Steam ship and Graving Dock Company, Limited, will present a very satisfactory report at the -eighth ordinary general meeting of the share- holders which is to he held to-morrow at Winchester House, Old Broad Street, London, EC.</p>
                    <p>The statement of accounts for the year ending 30th of June last is as follows:--The trading profit for the year, including  Government subsidies, and after charging insurance of steamers, all salaries, office and general expenses, has amounted to 76,985,17.7, to which is added for transfer fees £2,12.6, making together £76,988.10.2. From which is deducted :
                        D benture interest, depreciation, directors’ and auditors' remuneration, £18,875.10.0, leaving a balance of £58,113.0.1. The balance brought forward from the previous year is £2,228.18.6, making a total of £60,841.18.7. Of this sum dividends have been paid on the Preference shares for two-and-a half years to 31st December , 1904, amounting to £37,491.9.6, leaving a balance of £32,850.9.1. A farther dividend on Preference shares for the half-year ending 30th June last was paid on September 30th, amounting to £ 1,497.16.0, leaving a balance available for appropriation of £27,352.13.1.</p>
                    <p>The directors now recommend the payment of a dividend at the rate of 10 per cent, on the Ordinary shares, payable on December 31st, which would absorb £10,000.0.0, leaving a balance to be carried forward to next account of £17,352.13.1.</p>
                    <p>The directors are pleased to report that doting the past year the vessels have been well kept up. They have run free from any serious accidents, and all services have been regularly maintained.</p>
                    <p>Owing to the increased volume of business the directors have contracted with Messrs. Swan, Hunter and Wigham Richardson, Limited, for a new passenger steamer, with all modern improvements, and calculated to maintain speed of from 17 to 18 knots at sea. The directors hope that the new vessel will be a profitable acquisition to the company's fleet, She is to be finished and delivered in July next. Since the close of last year, two vessels, the Keneh, of 1,581 tons, and the Kosseir, of 1,851. tons, have been purchased and added to the company’s fleet.</p>
                    <p>To meet the requirements of the Egyptian authorities, a regular direct service has been established between Suez and Suakin in connection with the new railway, Suakin to Khartoum. Under an agreement with the Egyptian Government a subsidy of £5,000 per annum (for five years) will be paid to the company in consideration of its services in regard to this line.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL.</head>
                    <p>The Legislative Council meets today to consider the draft Budget for 1906 and the attached note of the Committee of Finance, which it will then transmit to the Council of Ministers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL</head>
                    <p>It is always difficult for a single artist to hold the attention of his audience throughout the programme, and M. Pierre Loredan has to be congratulated on the very excellent recital he gave at the Savoy yesterday afternoon. It is only to be regretted that his concert  had not been more widely advertised, for though he early claimed the sympathies of his audience the hall was never really full. M. Pierre Loredan plays with much taste and subtle feeling, and his execution is excellent. He gave a very fine rendering of Mendelssohn's "Rondo capriccioso,” and Chopin’s "Beroeuse” was a delightful achievement. His "Il Tremolo,” by Gottsohalk, was excellent is every way, his phrasing of the highest order. Perhaps it was the length of the performance or a slight want of sympathy that prevented his doing full justice to Raff's "Fileuse,” for his rendering of that delicate "Gazouillement du printemps” by Sinding had been particularly graceful and happy.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN.</head>
                    <p>The Tewfik Palace Hotel have inaugurated this season a fortnightly trip by river to the Barrage. The launches used on these trips belong to the Anglo-American Nile 8teamer and Hotel Company, and passengers are conveyed from the hotel to the river, where the launches await them. Lunch and tea are to be had on board, but on the return journey passengers will be landed at the Kasr-el-Nil Bridge in order that they may arrive back at Helouan in time for dinner. The first trip was made yesterday, and the next one is arranged for Wednesday, 27th inst.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Hergel, who has contributed during the past two years by no means a small part towards the rising popularity of the Tewfik Palace Hotel, distinguishes himself as manager by giving an excellent cuisine, so as to content the most refined epicures. His object is to combine the advantageous position of the hotel with an excellent table, and we can only say he quite realises his ambition and thereby con-siderably adds to the inner comforts of those choosing the late Khedive's Palace as a winter resort.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The office of Messrs. Cumming and Calleja have been removed to the 2nd floor of No. 2, Sursock Buildings, Old Bouse Street, behind the Eastern Telegraph Co.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
