<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brayan Barbosa</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-12-08</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-07-28</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

                <div type="section">
                    <head>JAPANESE SUCCESS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDROVSK SEIZED. ATTACK ON TIUMEN.</head>
                        <p>Tokio, July 27. The Japanese have seized Alexandrovsk (Saghalien). There
                            are no losses.</p>
                        <p>(Later). The Russians at Alexandrovsk consisted of a newly arrived
                            battalion and several hundred volunteers, with 8 guns. The Japanese
                            landed in the vicinity and attacked the place on the 24th. 200 prisoners
                            were taken. The redoubts to the east of the town stubbornly resisted but
                            were re-attacked and then captured on the 25th instant. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, July 27. General Linievitch reports that the Japanese on
                            the 24th inst. lended a battalion at Castries Bay, to the south of the
                            mouth of the Amur. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>Osaka, July 27. It is announced that several thousand Japa- nese are
                            vigorously attacking the Russian positions at Tiumen. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>Tokio, July 27. The Japanese have captured Alexandrovsk. The telegraph
                            line is cut between Saghalien and the continent. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAUSES OF THE WAR. M. WITTE'S OPINION.</head>
                        <p>London, July 27. Reuter's Agency learns from St Petersburg that M. Witte,
                            in an interview which has been published, is reported to have declared
                            that the institution of the Vice-royalty in the Far East was one of the
                            principal causes of the war, for it was a provocation to China, Japan,
                            Great Britain, and the United States, and corresponded neither to the
                            real strength nor the true interest of Russia in the Far East, and
                            particularly in the Pacific Ocean, where, properly speaking, she has no
                            interests. (R.)</p>
                        <p>Cherbourg, July 27. M. Witte has sailed. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PEACE COMMISSION. MOVEMENTS OF DELEGATES.</head>
                        <p>New York, July 27. It has been definitely arranged that the peace
                            delegates will sail for Oyster Bay on board a cruiser on the morning of
                            the 5th August. They will lunch with President Roosevelt and will sail
                            again in the afternoon in despatch boats, convoyed by a cruiser,
                            arriving at Portsmouth on the 7th August. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIAN FAMINE THREATENED. CROPS FAILING.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, July 27. Famine threatens the greater portion of Russia.
                            Good to medium crops are reported only in Poland and the Ural provinces.
                            In the steppes of the Caucasus and in Siberia the peasants have no means
                            of subsistence. (R)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ODESSA RIOTS. JEWS HELD RESPONSIBLE.</head>
                        <p>Odessa, July 27. The Governor has issued a proclamation declaring that
                            the Jews are answerable for all the recent troubles here. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIAN CRUISER STOPS BRITISH VESSEL.</head>
                        <p>Aden, July 27. The Russian cruiser Kuban stopped and examined the papers
                            of the British S.S. Fazilka in the Red Sea on Tuesday. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NORWAY AND SWEDEN. DISUNION APPROVED IN PRINCIPLE.</head>
                        <p>Stockholm, July 27. Both Houses of the Riksdag have approved the report
                            of the special Committee, concurring in principle in disunion with
                            Norway, provided that it is first submitted to the Norwegian plebiscite
                            or to a specially elected Storthing. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE NORWEGIAN CROWN. HOHENZOLLERN PRINCE PROPOSED.</head>
                        <p>Berlin, July 27. It is reported that the Emperor William is proposing a
                            Hohenzollern Prince for the Norwegian Crown. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHANNEL SQUADRON. TO CRUISE IN BALTIC SEA.</head>
                        <p>London, July 27. The Admiralty has decided that the Channel Squadron will
                            make a cruise in the Baltic sea during August and September, and will
                            visit the Scandinavian ports. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STAMBOUL AMBASSADORS THREATENED.</head>
                        <p>CONSTANTINOPLE, July 27. Several ambassadors have received anonym- ous
                            letters containing threats. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>THE PLAGUE.—Yesterdays bulletin records a fresh case at Alexandria, that of a
                        native workman living at Hont Zanieh el Kabanieh, and a recovery at
                        Toukh.</p>
                    <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the Abdeen district of Cairo during the
                        night of Saturday and at daylight on Sunday will be poisoned by the
                        police.</p>
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL.—14 vessels passed through the Canal on the 25th inst., 8 of which
                        were British, 2 German, 1 Italian, 3 Dutch. The receipts for the day were
                        frs. 313,447.80, making the total from the 1st inst. francs 7,123,450.55</p>
                    <p>THE MURDER OF M. GEROSA—The Italian Consular Court of Cairo, composed Of M.
                        Fal- qui-Cao, presiding judge, and MM. Biagiotti and Taffrani, has found
                        Fabio Ninci, the murderer of the unfortunate engineer, M. Egidio Gerosn,
                        guilty of premeditated homicide. The dossier of the case has been sent to
                        the Royal Produreur General at Ancona, who will order the prisoner to appear
                        before the Assize Court.</p>
                    <p>ADULTERATION PUNISHED. — Mustapha Bey Rifat, Judge of the Native Tribunal at
                        Sohag, has condemned 23 women to two months’ im- prisonment for adding a
                        large proportion of water to the milk which they sold. We hope other judges
                        will follow this excellent example. BICYCLE THIEF CAUGHT. - A French
                        subject, named Emile Chalantier, seeing a bicycle standing unguarded in
                        Sieters-street, mounted it and made off. An Arab who had watched the
                        performance followed him, and sprinting rigorously, overtook the thief in a
                        block of traffic in Hammamil-street.</p>
                    <p>THE CAIRO TRAMWAYS COMPANY has inform- ed the Ministry of the Interior that
                        first-class cars will run on all its lines from the 1st January, 1906. We
                        congratulate the company on their action, which will please all but the
                        arbagis, and none more than the wives and daughters of Europeans and
                        Syrians, who, being unable to afford carriages, were often exposed to the
                        insulting remarks and gestures of Moslems of the lower classes, many of whom
                        would be furious if a non-Moslem merely spoke to their wives and daughters,
                        but see no reason why they should not pester or insult unveiled women to
                        their heart’s content</p>
                    <p>CHURCH OF SCOTLAND SCHOOLS.—The closing exhibition of the boys’ school took
                        place on Wednesday at 4 p.m. at the High School in the Missala quarter. A
                        large marquee was erected behind the school for the accommodation of the
                        parents and friends of the pupils, and its capacity was fully taxed. A
                        varied programme was submitted, and was greatly enjoyed by the audience. A
                        most exemplary programme it was, as each piece was both short and under-
                        stood by the pupils ; it was evident they were not merely repeating by
                        heart, but that pains had bean taken to make the children understand the
                        meaning of what they were saying. It is needless almost to add that the
                        pupils acquitted themselves with great distinc- tion, and their appearance
                        and their work reflect the greatest credit upon Mr. Buchanan had his staff,
                        a credit that is all the greater as we are given to understand that, owing
                        to circumstances beyond the control of the ma- nagement, the school has been
                        understaffed for some time. We hear that this defect will be remedied in
                        October, when the school re-opens; MrT William Thom having been appointed to
                        the place of Mr. James Gordon, who was transferred to Beyrout After the
                        programme had been submitted, a table literally groaning with prizes was
                        lifted to the platform, and these were kindly presented to the boys by Mrs.
                        H.P. Reid. The dux of the school was L. Rosenberg, who, in addition to five
                        book prizes, carried off: the silver medal given by Major Allan,of Glasgow,
                        for Scripture knowledge. The medallist for painting was George Potins, and
                        the other Scripture medallist was L. Loulloup. The other chief prizetakers
                        were Frances Burigans, Giacomo Benveniste, and Rinaldo Benveniste. The whole
                        proceedings were carried through in less than two hours, and the management
                        are to be heartily con- gratulated upon it At the close Mr. Buchanan invited
                        the audience to pass into one of the rooms in the school to inspect the work
                        of the pupils, and from this one could understand what an infinite amount of
                        pains and care are taken in the education of the children.</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer.</head>
                        <p>hotel company</p>
                        <p>over transport of goods between alexandria cairo</p>
                        <p>Three Sellings a-Week</p>
                        <p>Agents of Alexandria:-</p>
                        <p>Alexandria runded warehouse co. ld.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BECK CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
                        <p>Bremen</p>
                        <p>fears no honest competition for quality</p>
                        <p>N.B.- Inferior brands now being offered to man</p>
                        <p>ages of certain good</p>
                        <p>beware of evily imposed</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>NEW HARBOUR WORKS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DESCRIPTION OF IMPROVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The new pass into the harbour, which is now being dredged to a depth of
                            37 feet by the St Lawrence, will be 600 feet in breadth, and something
                            over half a mile in length. It will pass quite close to the wreck of the
                            Cairo and bears on the light near Mex at an angle of 61°E.</p>
                        <p>It is hoped that the new pass will be ready for steamer traffic in two
                            years’ time ; about 1,000 feet by 200 have been dredged so far, and the
                            sand and silt brought up are being dropped to the south of the
                            breakwater. The reason for this is the necessity of facilitating the
                            prolongation of the breakwater, Which will be carried on for some 800
                            yards to within a short distance of the red gas buoy.</p>
                        <p>A new breakwater is to be earned out from the abattoir mole which is now
                            under con- struction. This mole will form a harbour where vessels of
                            deep draught carrying cattle can accost at the side of the quay, and the
                            cattle can be driven over gangways straight to the abattoir, while the
                            profungating of the mole for some 200 yards will screen the port from
                            N.-westerly gales much more effectually than has hitherto been
                            possible.</p>
                        <p>Altogether about L.R. 120,000 is to be spent on the new moles and nearly
                            £100,000 on dredging in the near future, but these sums do not exhaust
                            the list of credits voted for har- bour improvements. Beyond the
                            abattoir six now timber quays are to be commenced in the quarantine
                            anehotegh, and a line Of railway carried from'thèsé quays to Gabbari.
                            The old port of Omsk Kabebe is to be levelled, the shallows between the
                            site of the proposed quays and the shore reclaimed, and more quays will
                            probably be taken in hand after the completion of the first six.</p>
                        <p>The coal quay is to be widened, and the present “bottle neck,” where half
                            a dozen lines of rails cross in bewildering confusion, will be at least
                            trebled in breadth by reclama- tion on the S.W. ride of the quay. Five
                            new quay berths are also to be constructed on the same side of the coal
                            quay beyond the "bottle neck.”</p>
                        <p>Finally, Quay “K” is to be prolonged and widened, so as to close the
                            southern entrance into the careening basin, the isolated mole opposite
                            being in part joined to it and in part removed, so as to allow vessels
                            entering the Arsenal basin to enter the careening basin with the minimum
                            of difficulty. To effect this the N.E. end of this isolated mole, which
                            commences opposite the Khediviad Mail S.S. Company’s berth, is to be
                            done away with. About £8,000 is to be spent on this and on the widening
                            of Quay “K,” while about £180,000 has been allowed for the construc-
                            tion of the six timber quays off the quarantine anchorage.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>REGIMENTAL SPORTS.</head>
                        <p>A very enjoyable afternoon was spent yesterday at Mustapha barracks, when
                            the 2nd Battalion Royal Berkshire Regiment held their annual athletic
                            sports on the anniversary of the battle of Maiwand, where the regiment
                            displayed such conspicuous bravery. The events were varied and amusing,
                            and the proceedings were only finished at 6.45 p.m., when Mrs. Cave gave
                            away the prizes.</p>
                        <p>Amongst those present we noticed Mr. and Mrs. Mansfield de C. Findlay,
                            Admiral and Lady Blomfield, Mr. and Mrs. McPherson-Grant, Mr. Mitchell
                            Innes, Mr. Higgins, Mr. Haytor, Mrs. Gordon, Mrs. Cave, Mrs. Finch, Mrs.
                            Harvey, Mrs. Moore, Mrs. Crawley, Miss Massey, Mr. and Mrs. Herbert
                            Carver, Mr. and Mrs. Kelham.</p>
                        <p>We hear this battalion leaves for Khartoum and Cairo early in October and
                            will probably be replaced by the 2nd Battalion Dublin Fusiliers, at
                            present stationed at Buttevant.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                        <p>Another success was scored at the Casino yesterday with the second vocal
                            concert of the season. The programme gave ample scope for the display of
                            the artistes’ talents. The duet from Cavalleria Rusticana sung by Sig.
                            Giovanelli and Signa. Cantoni was exceedingly well rendered and had to
                            be repeated. We may remind our readers of the Verdi Festival to be given
                            on Sunday morning. The programme includes the well-known trio from
                            Lombardi, preceded by the famous violin solo.</p>
                        <p>The following is the menu of the dinner to be served on Saturday on the
                            occasion of the small dance :—</p>
                        <p>Mock Turtle</p>
                        <p>Bar d'Alexandrie à la Parisienna</p>
                        <p>Quartier à l’Egyptienna</p>
                        <p>Terrine de foie gras de Strasbourg</p>
                        <p>Harioots vests an beurre d’isigny</p>
                        <p>Faisal de boherne rosi grande obasse</p>
                        <p>MSalade de laitue</p>
                        <p>Punch a la Romaine</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CALENDAR OF THE WEEK.</head>
                        <p>(Coptic and Mohamedan.)</p>
                        <p>Sun. 23 The sun in Leo. The interior of the earth is cooled. </p>
                        <p>Mon. 24 Grapes and figs in full season.</p>
                        <p>Tues. 25 Heliacal rising of Sirius.</p>
                        <p>Wed. 26 It is good to take cold baths.</p>
                        <p>Thurs. 27 Gamret el-Kaiz. Extreme heat</p>
                        <p>Fri. 28 Clothes must not be washed for seven days. Chicory sown.</p>
                        <p>Sat. 29 Good season for marriages. Mustard Seed gathered.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>ROBBERY ON THE ASSOUAN.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ONE THOUSAND POUNDS STOLEN.</head>
                        <p>The Khedivial S.S. Assouan, which left Beyrout on Tuesday, has been the
                            scene of a daring and ingenious theft. After leaving Jaffa on Wednesday
                            evening, the steward discovered that the strong-room of the vessel had
                            been forced and that £1,000 in gold and specie had disappeared. It was
                            remarked afterwards that a first-class passenger, believed to be a
                            European, who had embarked at Beyrout and booked a passage for Egypt,
                            had disappeared at Port Said, where he went ashore with many other
                            passengers, leaving behind all, or almost all, his personal effects.</p>
                        <p>As soon as the theft was discovered careful inquires were made on board
                            and the captain communicated with the Egyptian police autho- rities.</p>
                        <p>When the Assouan arrived in harbour this morning, she was boarded by Mr.
                            Freeman, H.B.M.’s Vice-Consul, and the secret police. We are assured
                            that the steward of the Assouan, on being shown a photograph by the
                            police, recognised the missing first class pas- senger, in spite of the
                            fact that the suspect, While on board, wore bandages which partly
                            concealed his face, as,if he had sustained some disfiguring injury.</p>
                        <p>The police confidently expect to be able to lay hands on the supposed
                            thief within a very short time.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KUBAN AT SUEZ.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)</p>
                        <p>Suez;Friday, 12.10 p.m. The Russian cruiser Kuban has arrived from the
                            South.</p>
                        <p>[This is the cruiser which is reported by Reuter this morning as having
                            stopped and examined the papers of the British S.S. Farilka in the Red
                            Sea on Tuesday last.]</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EUROPEAN CABLE RATES REDUCED.</head>
                        <p>The rate for telegrams between Egypt and Europe will be reduced to one
                            shilling per Word as from the 1st August next. This reduction will not,
                            however, be applied until further notice for telegrams to France,
                            Algeria, and Tunis.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AKHMIN NOTES.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)</p>
                        <p>Akhmim, July 96. Thé omdeh of El Awama reported to the Markas authorities
                            here yesterday that a murder had taken place in his village. The mamour
                            el markaz, Mohamed Effendi Fehmy, went to the spot and learned that the
                            sheikh of the ghaffirs met a fellah who had just stolen a sheep and
                            questioned him as to how he came by the animal. The father of the thief
                            then same up and threatened to shoot the sheikh it he did not leave his
                            son alone and then, in spite of the entreaties of a bystander, fired
                            point blank at the unfortunate man and killed him. The culprit has been
                            arrested.</p>
                        <p>Abdallah Bey Wahby who replaced Hussein Bey Wassif of the Irrigation
                            Department, during that official’s absence, inspected the work done by
                            the Markaz engineer, Mohamed Effendi Khalid, to-day and expressed his
                            approval thereof.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>OBITUARY MRS. H. MACLOUGHLIN.</head>
                        <p>It is with the greatest regret that we learn of the death of Mrs. H.
                            MacLoughlin, wife of the acting manager of the Cairo branch of the
                            Imperial Ottoman Bank, which has occurred at Castlebar, County Mayo,
                            Ireland. Mr. and Mrs. MacLoughlin were only married in September last.
                            After spending the winter with her husband in Cairo Mrs. MacLoughlin
                            went to Castlebar to spend the summer there, and about a fortnight ago
                            gave birth to a daughter. The many friends of Mr. MacLoughlin will
                            sympathise most deeply with him in his sad loss, and we offer to him our
                            most sincere condolences.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PASSENGER LIST DEPARTURES.</head>
                        <p>Le paquebot Memfi de la Cié florfo-Rubat- tino parti hier pour Gènes
                            avait à bord : M.M. G. Patrita, Lukardo, H. Grillis, Fam. Zangbi,
                            Haufman, Halze, Catremades, H. Ba- vastre, Bortoktti et fam., Cap. Art.
                            Levi, H. H. Ritter, E. T. Malhame et fils, V. Sabatelli et fam,
                            Azzopardi et fam., Mme Tonti et fille, Dom. Baldevino, Maria Savignoni
                            et fille, R. Marzo, Henry Abram, L Stone, Warcham, Glem, pire Lodovico,
                            Ànisani, Mgr. Rois et suite, Baron de Bulow, Normendean, A. Voc- coli,
                            ing. Camiz, M. et Mme Ch. Salama, J. Ghezoski, M. et Mme Friendo, U.
                            Colloridi, A. Cacace, S. di G. Salama, Halifa Sacks, G. Nor- sa Bey,
                            Cap. Cav. Felice Baldovino et fam., av. R Bigiavi, M. et Mme'
                            Industrioso, A. Ferre et fam., R Cajo et fam., Mme et Mlle Zarb R.
                            Essayie, C. Finardi, G. Torta, A. Hauf et fam., Mme Richard et filles,
                            Michel Bey Saleh et fam., G. Bordiga et fam., F. Lan- teires, A. Muchet
                            et fils. L. Bosassa, G. Ser- vadis, M. et Mme Dessalles, A. P. Scott,
                            Scroeder et 67 passenger de sme classe.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>A DANGER TO EGYPT</head>
                    <p>ENGLAND, GERMANY AND TURKEY IN THE NEAR EAST.</p>
                    <p>BY WILHELM MEISTER. Translated</p>
                    <p>II.-(Continued from July 25). We must now take note of the forces that are
                        capable of preventing the fulfilment of such a scheme. Dangerous yesterday
                        and irresistible to-morrow, whether considered in- dividually and
                        collectively, for the moment they constitute the mere unsubstantial shadow
                        of an obstacle and may almost be said to favor decisive action on the part
                        of Great Britain. These forces are five in number, bach of which represents
                        a European Power, and first and foremost we must consider Turkey, as the
                        Power most interested. Then come Germany, Russia, France, and Italy. At the
                        present mo- meant the two last-named elements would greet either of the
                        solutions— Occupation or Neutral- isation—with satisfaction. The remaining
                        powers could effect nothing by their own re- sources, as I propose to
                        demonstrate.</p>
                    <p>First let us take Turkey and consider what resistance she could offer to the
                        amputation of Syria from her political organism. In the pre- sent incomplete
                        condition of the Syrian railway system, not yet linked with Diarbekir and
                        the great central trunk line, the idea of an offensive movement against
                        Egypt is chimerical, and the Turks, in case of war, would be hard put to it
                        to make head against the Christian popula- tion of the mountains, openly
                        revolting and found in arms and munitions of war by the masters of the
                        seas.</p>
                    <p>The sea-routes,till now used by the Ottoman Government in the suppression of
                        all revolu- tionary or separatist movements in the distant provinces of the
                        Empire, by which it is now dispatching soldiers to the Yemen, and which
                        enabled it six years ago to transport forces against the Druses of the
                        Hauran, would be closed in case of war with a naval Power, and it is
                        difficult to see how the communications between Syria and Asia Minor could
                        be main- tained in default of roads and railways, or practicable passes
                        through the formidable carrier of the Taurus and its Eastern gorges.</p>
                    <p>Assuming that the present garrison of Syria composed of the forces quartered
                        in the districts of Damascus and Aleppo would suffice if aided by a corps of
                        Redifs raised in the province, for in offensive movement to the south, how
                        could the provisioning and the supply of these forces be assured? The
                        Ottoman soldier can exist on the scantiest nations, but his rifles require
                        as many cartridges, and his field guns as many shells, as those of other
                        nations. An officer of the Turkish General Staff stationed at Da- mascus
                        informed the writer, whom he met at Djevad Pashe’s house and with whom he
                        became intimate, this in spite of all efforts the military reforms could not
                        be properly applied in Syria till their first article had been carried out,
                        and the first article and condition of the reform scheme is the construction
                        of a complete railway system in Syria, Mesopotamia, and Asia Minor. For the
                        moment the Syrian Corps d’Armée, in spite of the ability of their com-
                        manding officer, are armies in the rough, and brave and soldierly as is the
                        human material of these forces, they lack, and must lack, till the military
                        reforms are finally carried out, the immense extrinsic value conferred by
                        modern armament and organisation</p>
                    <p>This being the case it is hard to see how the above mentioned forces, the
                        Nizam of Aleppo and Damascus and the Redifs of Syria, could undertake an
                        offensive campaign against Egypt, before the completion of the strategic
                        railways and advance through desolate or mountainous regions while their
                        communications were harassed by the Christians and Druses of the Lebanon and
                        the Hauran, and their rear was threatened by the menace of a disembarkation
                        of an expedition dispatched after the begin- ning of the war from England or
                        Idia. The offensive being therefore a physical impos- suability, we have to
                        consider what rule these forces could play on the defensive. Anyone who
                        knows the coast strip that formed the Phoenicia of the ancients, its people
                        and their history, will be ready enough to admit that from the opening of
                        hostilities, that is, at the first gleam bringing a hope, however distant,
                        of freedom from a detested yoke, these people, whose narrow and rugged home
                        borders the sea for its whole length, would instantly im- provide forces and
                        take the field against the Turks under British officers. The mountainous
                        ridge of the Lebanon would be fortified on both tis flanks, on the west or
                        maritime side, to aid the warships to prevent any movement of the enemy
                        along the coast road, and on the eastern side, which commands the depression
                        of the B’aka or Coele-Syria, to aid the guerrillas of the hills to check any
                        movement along the plain below them. The defending forces stationed on the
                        coast between Tripoli and Tyre would be condemned to inaction — or
                        extermination. Those echeloned in the Coelesyrian depres- sion would be
                        exposed to constant guerilla attacks and virtually isolated from their base.
                        These fractions, representing a good third of the central forces, and the
                        central force itself, its effective strength reduced, deprived of
                        ammunitions and of a proper transport service, would have no other
                        alternative but to cling to their cantonments and waste away there or to
                        dash themselves in reckless assaults upon the artillery that would guard the
                        passes of the unsurveyed and dangerous mountain barrier, in whose dangerous
                        clefts and am- bushes many an army has been swallowed up.</p>

                    <p>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</p>
                    <p>GUARANTEED DISTILLED.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria: Dairo:</p>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                        correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit —
                        within certain necessary limits — free discussion. </p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH AND FOREIGN STEEL GIRDERS IN EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Dear Sir - Some years ago the
                            Krupp firm had a contract with the Egyptian Government at a little over
                            half the coat of supplying the same quality of rails to their own
                            government. In Germany rails were delivered by Krupp’s factory to the
                            german Government at about $9 per ton, the government paying all trans-
                            port charges. The same firm supplied the Egyptian Government with rails
                            at about $5 a ton, franco to Gabbari, paying every penny for freights,
                            transport, unloading, etc. Surely this startling difference in the
                            prices is entirely due to the imposition of a protective tariff, as the
                            Krupp firm has nothing to fear in Ger- many from foreign competition in
                            Egypt or elsewhere at excessively low prices.</p>
                        <p>Gumbok. Alexandria, July 27.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A BATHING NUISANCE.</head>
                        <p>To the editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Dear Editor,- I should like to
                            bring the following to your notice. I live at Halte 1, Ramleh, ad have
                            hired a bathing box for the season down at a small bay near a Coastguard
                            station immediately behind this station. I had the intention of bathing
                            there most after- noons but unfortunately I am hindered from so doing by
                            the following most revolting circumstances. Every afternoon about ten
                            Arab families congregate there and bathe, the children naked, the
                            mothers can boast of some little clothing which is hardly a shade better
                            than nothing, they leave their clothes and babies lying over the beach
                            where space is very limited, and they are very unclean in their habits,
                            consequently the beach is pervaded by most unpleasant odours.</p>
                        <p>A low class of Europeans also frequent this same small bay ; they undress
                            promiscuously on the beach, on the rocks and behind the bathing boxes.
                            Is this right? Should not the owners of the bathing boxes be considered,
                            who pay rent or hire for the erection of the You will understand how
                            limited space is when I tell you that there is only room for six boxes,
                            including my own. These people, besides crowding us out, make use of our
                            boxes to undress themselves behind them and to screen their uncleanness.
                            What is Egypt doing to allow this filthy state of affairs? I hear
                            complaints from many that the coast from Ibrahimieh to San Stefano and
                            beyond is made unbearable for the respectable European residents. No
                            decent woman can at any time of the afternoon walk along the shore
                            without being insulted and seeing indecent sights. Egypt is no doubt
                            improving for the Egyptians, but the Egyptians are not improving it.
                            Among the many things that lord Cromer is having taught to the Egyptians
                            might it not be advisable to include decency !!! A. Mermaid. Hate 1,
                            Ramleh, July 25.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                        <p>During the absence on leave of Yacoub Artin Pasha, Mr. Dunlop will act as
                            Under Secretary of State to the ministry of Public Instruction. Mr.
                            Cobbe, Assistant Commandant of the Alexandria City Police, arrived
                            yesterday. The following visitors are staying at the Beau-Rivage Hotel,
                            Ramleh : Col. G. Harvey Pasha, Mr. and Mrs. John Ades and family, Mr.
                            and Mr.s W. Page, Mr. and Mrs. H. Pa- pasian, Cav. and Mme Ugo Luzzatto
                            and family, Mr. and Mrs. L Pally and family, Miss L. Ste- tens, Mr. and
                            Mrs. L. Loucas and family, Mr. E. Klein, Mr. and Mrs. Marc Matatia, Mr.
                            and Mrs. H. Daffa and family, Mr.and Mrs. E. Barozzi and family, Mr. and
                            Mrs. Nicolas Bey Boustros, Mr. and Mrs. H. Hughes, Miss L. Isler, Miss
                            M. Daring, Mr. W. S. Smith, Mr. and Mrs. H. Sanders, Mr. S. G. Henein,
                            Mr. H. Harfez, mr. and Mrs. Jacques Press and Family, Mme Virginia de
                            Castro.</p>
                        <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice :
                            Capt. Riach, Mr. MacClure Speakmann, Miss Kembon, Miss Shavorn, Mr. R.
                            A. Colvini, Mr. L. N. Cooper, Mr. T. L. Bennetts, M. Tippetts, mr.
                            Lowther, Mr. B. T. Watts, Mr. G. B. Kerr, M. and Mme Victor Mosseri, Mr.
                            and Mrs. Fend Bey, Mr. L. E. Bury, M. Joseph Mondolro, M. Mill-
                            ward.</p>
                        <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are
                            mr. M. Schei- dig, mr. and Mrs. P. R. Borwell, Mr. M. Stubbs, Mr. J.
                            Leonard, Mr. M. de Lavalette, Canon Ward, Mrs. E. M. Ward, Mr. O. von
                            Mohl, Miss von Mohl, Mme Sasdik Bey, M. Hilmy Effendi, M. Chata Efferdi,
                            Sir H. Pitching Pasha, Lt. Col. and Mrs. H. G. L. Wortabel, Mr. W. N. B.
                            Bricos, Mr. and Mrs. A. D. Alban, Mr. A. H. Stafes, and Mrs. Hardy.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
