
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Christian Ragland</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-10-10">October 10, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head></div>
                <div type="section"> 
                </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, OCTOBER 1O 1905</head></div>
                    <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSO-CHINESE FRONTIER.</head>
                        
                        <head>RUSSIAN DEFENSIVE MEASURES</head>
                            
                            <head>3O0,OOO TROOPS TO BE STATIONED THERE.</head></div>
                                <div type="item">
                                    <p>St. Petersburg, October 9.</p>
                                    
                                    <p>It is reported tbnt thero will be 3OO,OOO Russian troops stationed on the Chinese frontier after the formal signature of peace, partly because the Government is apprehensive that these men might join the malcon tents at home, and partly with a view of intimidating the Chinese.	(Reuter)</p>
                                </div>  
                                    <div type="item">
                                   
                                        <head>PROFESSOR BEHRING'S REMEDY.</head></div>
                                            
                                    <div type="item">
                                        <head>MEDICAL OPINION.</head></div>
                                    
                                    <div type="item">
                                    <head>(From our London Correspondent).</head></div>
                                    <div type="item">
                                    <head>London, October 9th</head></div>
                                    
                                    <div type="item">
                                    <p>Sir William Broadbent, the King's eminent physician, says that Professpr Behring's statement of the discovery of a cure for tuberculosis commands the respect and attention of the entire world, as emanating from the discoverer of the antidiphtheric serum and a man of high scientific reputation. His announcement of a curative agents only amounts as yet to conviction and awaits demonstration. It is hoped, however, that this newest tuberculin will not share the fate of its predecessors.</p></div>
                                                   <div type="item">
                                                        <p>Paris, October 9.</p>
                                                        
                                                        <p>It is the opinion of medical men that it will be a long time before Professor Behring’s remedy for phthisis will reach a practical stage, although the merits of his researches are undisputed. (Reutner)</p>
                                                   </div>  
                                                        <div type="item">
                                                        <head>THE MOSCOW STRIKES.</head></div>
                                                        
                                                        <div type="item">
                                                        <head>BRUTAL REPRESSIVE MEASURES.</head></div>
                                                                    
                                                        <div type="item">
                                                        <p>Moscow, October 9.</p></div>
                                                        
                                                        <div type="item">
                                                        <p>The strike is spreading. There was rioting last night in which there were many killed and wounded including some Cossacks. The populace is exasperated by the brutality of the repressive measures.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                        <p>Moscow, October 9.</p>
                                                                    
                                                                        <p>A large military force occupies the main squares and streets here.	(Reuter)</p>
                                                                    </div>
                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                            <p>Moscow, October.9.</p>
                                                                            
                                                                            <p>The strikes of the tramway workmen, compositors, and bakers continue. There is a great deal of disorder and the Cossacks have killed ten demonstrators.	(Havas</p>
                                                                        </div>
                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head></div>
                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                        <head>M. DELCASSE AND THE ‘MATIN."</head>
                                                                                            
                                                                                            <p>Paris, October 9th</p>
                                                                                            <p>It is believed that the articles published by the "Matin" were inspired by M. Deleasse. They have caused a profound sensation in France and will tend to augment the animosity of France towards, Germany. The English newspapers are sceptical. (Reuter)</p>
                                                                                    </div>
                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                        <head>TROUBLE IN RIFLIS.</head></div>
                                                                                        
                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                        <head>BOMBS AND PANIC.</head></div>
                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                <p>London, October 9.</p>
                                                                                                                <p>Telegrams from Tiflis report, that several bombs were thrown on a detachment of Cossacks. The troops fired on the crowd and there are many killed and wounded. Panic is prevailing.	(Reuter)</p>
                                                                                        </div>
                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                    <head>THE ARGENTINE REPUBLIC.</head></div>
                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                            <head>MARTIAL LAW PROCLAIMED.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                    <p>Buenos Ayres, October 9</p>
                                                                                                                                        <p>Martial law has been proclaimed throughout tho Argentine Republic owing to the imminence of a general strike.	(Renter)</p></div>
                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                            <head>THE YEMEN REBELLION.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                    <head>TURKS OCCUPY HAJJE.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                            <p>Djeddah, Ootober 9.</p>
                                                                                                                                                            <p>The Turka in the Yemen have occupied Hajje unopposed. The next advance will be upon the Imam's stronghold of Sada. (R.)</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                <head>FERJERVARY MINISTRY FOR HUNGARY.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                        <p>Budapest, October 9</p>
                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The appointment of a Ferjervary Ministry appears to be decided.	(Havas)</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                            <head>THE MANCHURIAN ARMY.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                
                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Khahbin, October 9.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Indiscipline prevails in the Manchurian army.	(Havas)</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>THE LATE GENERAL KONDRATENKO.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                            <head>IMPOSING MILITARY FUNERAL.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                                
                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>St. Petersburg, October 9.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>The remains of General Kondratenko, the defender of Port Arthur, have arrived here. Several Grand Dukes and civil and military dignitaries were present at the imposing military funeral.	(Reuter)</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                        </div>
                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                            <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Stray ask Ownerless Dogs found in Old Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 12th will be poisoned by the police,</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>State Telegraphs.—A credit of L.E. 2,500 has been granted by the Ministry of Finance for the improvement of the telegraphic service.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Unsuccessful Examination. — We learn that the Board of Sheikh of Al-Alzhar University, Cairo, have examined forty students who were terminating their studies; two only have succeeded in passing and 38 failed! The fortunate two are Sheikh Mahmoud Ismail and Sheikh Mahrouss Sharaf.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Bubonic Plague. — Only one case of bubonic plague was notified at Alexandria last week, there being no case in any other town in Egypt, and the number under treatment is now three. From the 1st of January to Saturday last 160 cases had in all been notified as against 812 during the corresponding period of last year.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Garrison Directory.- Our readers will be pleased to learn that it has been decided to issue a new edition of this useful publication about the end of next month. Any corrections desired or the insertion of the addresses of residents must be sent in before the 31st October to the clerk in charge, Garrison Directory, Headquarters office, Cairo.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Turkish Triumphs.—Marshal Faizi Pasba, commander in-chief of the Ottoman troops at Yemen, has despatched a telegram to his Government informing it that the Sultan’s troops had marched with triumph to Breem and occupied that town on the 22nd ultimo. The population are said to have been submitted without resistance, and to have prayed and beseeched Heaven to protect the Khalif and keep him victorious.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Prisoners by Deputy. — “Al Mokattsm" learns that two men of Meiet E! Ajeil, of Talkha markaz, Gbarbieh, who were recently imprisoned for some petty crime, proved to have replaced the real culprits. Both prisoners were identified as brothers of tho condemned men. These four brothers are said to he on bad terms with the omdeh of their village, and to be relatives of the ghaffir, who perhaps had a hand in arranging the interchange of the prisoners.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>Bedouin Brigandage. — "A1 Mokattam” states that a band of Kadeirah Bedouin under their chief Azad el Kediri recently carried off fourteen camels belonging to a native named Odeh Melhoos close to El Arish. Their owner, terrified by the Bedoaiu, made no resistance, but informed the Governer af El Arish, begging that his camels should be recovered. Our contemporary adds that no measures have yet been taken tor the recovery of the animals.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Arment Teftish.—In our issue of tho 2nd instant we mentioned that the Government had, in response to a petition from the inhabitants of four villages comprised in the Ament teftish, decided upon returning the lands in question, which had hitherto formed part of the Daira Sanieh Administration, to the pet tioners on certain conditions. We are now informed that the price of sale has been fixed at £35 per feddan payable in 20 equal yearly instalments with interest at 5 1/2 per cent. per annum, and that the Agricultural Bank has keen entrusted with the collection of the annuities as they become due.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Orwat-el-Woska Schools— H.E. Risz Pasha recently paid a visit to the school which bears his name at Bacos, Ramleh, and expressed himself highly pleased with the excellent discipline maintained in tho school and with the progress and tidiness of the pupils. We learn that the Pasha not only publicly complemented the head master and the teachers on the results of their care and attention, but communicated with the President of the Orwat-e!-Woska Benevolent Society, announcing his intention of presenting each of them with a sum equal to a month's salary.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Sanitary Department. — The Direction General of the Sanitary Administration will remove next month to the large and commodious premises in the groups of of the Ministry of Public Works that are now approaching completion and cost some £4,500 to build. The present offices will in future be used for the auxiliary services and stores. Sir Horace Pinching and Professor Bitter, director of the Hygienic Institute, who have been representing the Egyptian Government at the Tuberculosis Congress in Paris, are returning by the French mail of next Tuesday. A director from the Pasteur Institute for the new Anti-Rubic Institute now being constructed by the Government, is shortly expected from Paris. This new Institute will replace the one which has until now been attached to the Italian Hospital at Abbassieb, and towards the maintenance of which the Government contributes a yearly sum.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <head>Anglo-American Nile Steamers</head>                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <head>THE PRINCES' CASE.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>FIRST AUDIENCE TO-MORROW.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>The first audience in connection with the proces des Princes will come before the Judge de Refere at the Mixed Tribunal in Cairo tomorrow. The Daira Sanieh, Daira Sanieh Co., and the Credit Foncier together with the claiments—heirs of the late Khedive Ismail—have been summoned to appear and show cause why the sum of £2,000,000, the portion due to tho Government out of the payment which is to be made on the 16th instant to the holders of Daira Sanieh shares, should not be handed over to the Finance Ministry in spite of the attachment made by the Princes. Unless the attachment is removed by the judge, the monies will be paid in court and the Princes will be held responsible for the interest, viz : about £100,000 a year. The total amount that is to be paid to the shareholders and holders of founders' shares amounts to about the same sum that the Government claims.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>H.H. the Khedive will visit the mosque of Sidi Bishr, Ramleh, for prayers on Friday morning. In the afternoon he will visit the Khedivial Yacht Club.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <head>SUICIDE OF A BRITISH SOLDIER.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>An inquest was opened yesterday at the British Consulate in Cairo before Mr. Pio Sciortino, Pro-Consul, to enquire into the circumstances attending the death of Private Charles Harris of E. Company of the Rifle Brigade, stationed at the Citadel, who shot himself in the head with his rifle while on sentry duty between the hours of 4 And 6 p.m. that day. The jury was composed of Messrs. D. Macdonald, A. Gregory,and A.G. K. Levick. After being sworn they proceeded to view the body at the Citadel, and on their return to court they heard the evidence of Private Alcoyne Bayliss, of the same company, who deposed how the deceased, on receiving a letter from England on Saturday and reading it, appeared depressed and more reticent than usual, and how he found the body near the tennis court with the rifle by the side and marks of blood on the ground, caused by the wound from the bullet, which entered the month and came out at the back of the neck. At this stage the enquiry was adjourned to this morning, for the purpose of hearing medical and other evidence.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>DISMISSAL OF A VALI.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Our readers have doubtless remarked the numerous arrests and perquisitions effected by the Khafieh or Ottoman secret police in Syria at the expense of Egyptians or persons in frequent communication with Egypt during the spring and summer of the present year, to which we have given some prominences in our columns. It appears that the Turkish central authorities, alarmed by the temporary success of the revolt in the Yemen, and terrified by the reports of certain mischief-makers, who are unhappily domiciled in Egypt, of an impending Arab rising, have for some time past encouraged the local authorities to search houses for arms and seditions literature, to arrest sheikhs and notables, and in short to add fresh burdens to the lives of their subjects. It now appears that the Porte has begun to suspect the reports of its own agents, and an instructive story reaches us from Aleppo which goes far to support our view that the "Nahda Arabiya’’ bogy was used by unscrupulous agents to secure the Acquiescence of a frightened government in their corrupt and oppressive practices.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>It appears that the Vali of Aleppo recently informed the Mabein that he had seditious news and begged to be allowed to convey it to Constantinople. Leave was granted him and the nervous governor informed the Porte that a terrible Arab plot to seize Aleppo was maturing and could only be checked by prompt and severe measures. He therefore begged to be allowed to seize all weapons and search every house in the town. The Government, which was aware that Aleppo contained large numbers of wealthy merchants, showed a certain reluctance to commence operations without getting further details of the plot. Enquiries proved that the story of the conspiracy was based on the flimsiest evidence ; the nervous Vali was removed and Nazim Pasha, ex-Vali of Diarbekir, rules in his stead.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Ellerman S.S. Sardinia arrived at Liverpool yesterday.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Ellerman S.S., Avon sailed from Malta last night, and is due at Alexandria on Friday with general cargo.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Russian Steam Navigation Co’s S.S. Tearitza wills sail on Thursday for Odessa, touching at Pitaeus, Smyrna, Dardanelles, and Constantinople and connecting with the same Company’s mail hosts for  Sevastopol, the Anatolian, Crimean, and Sea of Azov ports.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The S.S. Creole Prince arrived at Manchester from Alexandria on Sunday.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Canard liner Pavis, is due at Alexandria on Thursday, and will immediately begin loading cargo for Liverpool and America.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The new Moss liner Menepthah sailed from Liverpool on last Sunday,is due at Alexandria about the 22nd inst. with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>The Moss liner Remeses arrived yesterday evening from Liverpool, vit Gibraltar and Malta with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>THE END OF THE BLOCK.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Suez, Monday.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>The first outward bound steamer to come out of the canal since the stoppage, was the M.M. mail steamer Yarra, which arrived at 7.35 p.m. yesterday, and was followed by 27 more steamers,the mail boats coming first. The distance between the steamers was a mile and the whole canal presented a rare sight owing to the numerous searchlights of the vessels.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>With the exception of a collision of the Austrian Lloyd steamer Africa with the Dutch Mail boat in the canal, all went on remarkably well, and by 5.20 this morning all the steamers were in the Suez bay. A few steamers are still detained at Suez, as they have not yet received tje electric light projector necessary for the passage of the Canal.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <head>THE NUBIA REFLOATED.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>The Anchor Liner Nubia was successfully refloated yesterday afternoon at 1.30 with the assistance of the Khedivial liners Fayoum and Calionbieh, and the pump is keeping Control over the leakage. She is expected to teach Suez in a day or two under her own team, where she will undergo the necessary repairs.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <head>PORT SAID HARBOUR.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>( From our Correspondent. )</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Port Said, Monday.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Thirty four boats have now arrived from Suez, this mail boats coming first. The harbour is still very full of vessels and it has been found to necessary to order six or seven incoming boats to anchor outside until the second batch of those which are in harbour have entered the canal, which will probably be about half past six to-night.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Sir William Garstin is progressing as well as could be expected after his recent operation. He is still confined to his room and at the Ministry of Public Works it is not expected that be will return to Egypt for some time to come, Sir William having been ordered to the South of France as soon as he is able to travel.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>H.R. Ghazi Mukhtar Pasha has arrived at Alexandria from Constantinople.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Among those who arrived yesterday by the Norddeutscher Lloyd S.S. Schleswig we noticed H. H. Prince Fouad Pasha, Sir Vincent Corbett, Marshal Ghazi Ahmed Pasha, Dr. and Mrs. Warnock, Mr. C. Baehler, Mme and Mile Tamvaco, M. Cesar Adda, M. and Mme Agathon Bey, Dr..and Mrs. Williams and others.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>Mr. Alban, British Consul in Cairo, arrived this morning at Port Said from Marseilles by the Bibby liner Cheshire.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>Kaimakam R.E. Sheehan Bey, director, Northern Directorate, Coast Guard Administration and Mrs. Sheehan have returned from Europe.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Lieut. A. Carton de Wiart, 4th Dragoon Guards, son of the well known Cairo advocate, has been appointed A.D.C. to General Sir H.J.T. Hildyard K.C.B, Commanding the forces in. South Africa. He will hold the local rank of Captain.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>H.I.M. the Sultan has conferred the rank of Haramein upon Mohamed Bey Neahar, son of the late Abmed Pasha Neshat of Cairo.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <p>Mr. R. J. Hughes of the stock department of the National Bank at Cairo, has been appointed to the credit and accounts office of tho State Railways.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <p>M. Ansaldi, acting director of the French Post Office, has been appointed controller of the Maritime Postal Service at Bordeaux, and is leaving Alexandria to-day to take op his new duties.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Windsor Hotel, Alexandria, we notice :-—</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <p>Lient. Cooke, Lieut. Franklin, Dr. Morogh, Dr. Goldslich, Dr. Faber, Lieut Grill, Mr. and Mrs. Hague, Mr. and. Mrs. Sarayanny, Mr. Buchanan, Waits Bey, Mr. Fischer, S.E Fathy Pasha, Dr. Boyd Carpenter, Mr. Crew, Dr. and Mrs. Antonopoulo, Mr. Adams, Mr. Shotham, Mr. Martin, Mr. Derrojs, Mr, Smith, Mr. Arditi, Mr. Smith, Mr. Maule, Mr. Balajian, Mr. Kiel, Mr. Sarrante, Mr. Sheldrick, Mr. Fany, Mr. Osborne Shepard, Mr. and Mrs. Tothill, Mr. J. Elias, Mr. Coming Mr. St. Claire de Ville, Mr. Wilson, Mr. Kulouk, Mr. Salmone, Mr. Norbert de Lem, Lient. Archibald, Mr. Weigall, Mr. P. Fortt, Mr. Wade, Mr. Bahary, Mr. Nabolty, Mr. and Mrs. Bigiavi, Mr. ard Mrs Gilsoul, Mr. Guits, Mr. Robert Sehmith, Mr. and Mrs. Wiliams, Dr. Smith Wekeisarke, Mr. A. W. Chistan, Dr. Loutfy Mr. Naar.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <head>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <head>SATURDAY’S AQUATIC SPORTS.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <div type="item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>The third annual aquatic sports of the Alexandria Swimming Club were held in the new Graving Dock, Gabbari, on Saturday afternoon before a large gathering of visitors which far excelled the attendance on previous occasions, and showing how much the club is  advancing. Among those present we noticed H.H. Prince Aziz Hassan, Rear-Admiral Sir R. Massie Blomfield, K.C.M.G., and Lady , Blomfield, Mr. Freeman, acting British Consul General, and Mrs. Freemau, Mr. Ambrose Ralli, Vice-President of the Municipality, Mr. Critchley, manager of the imperial Ottoman Bank, and Mrs. Critchley, Artin Bey Rizian, and many others of the elite of Alexandria.  During the coarse of the afternoon a telegram was received from H.E. Sir Reginald Wingate Pasha, regretting his inability to attend, and expressing his wishes for an entirely successful afternoon, and Mr. A. Mitchell Innes, Under Secretary of State, Ministry of Finance, also wrote regretting that a previous engagement prevented him being present and wishing the club every success in their meeting. The weather was delightful, but the burning sun was rather trying during the earlier part of the afternoon.  The want of a swimming bath is the more especially felt on these occasions, end we express the hope that at no very distant date the Municipality will make an effort to supply this long-felt want. There are a large number of swimmers and bathers in Alexandria, and during the hottest parts of the trying summer days the luxury of a bath is denied to the many who are unable to afford the time to go out to the covered baths at San Stefano or Mex. As we prophesied, some excellent swimming was witnessed, and so well were the handicaps framed that the spectators were more than once at a loss to distinguish between the winner and swimmer-np. The dock was very effectively decorated for the occasion with flags and, with the gay assembly, presented a very animated scene. Mounted and foot policemen, kindly provided by the authorities, kept the approaches and entrances clear; in fine everything had been most excellently arranged and the organising committee are to be congratulated upon the success with which their hard labour met.  Mr. Walter F. j Sarjeant, chairman of the club, showed himself to be a hard worker and able adviser ; Mr. H. S. Martin, hon. sec., who has devoted every moment of his spare time to the work since his return from leave, must be especially pleased at the reward of success, which was in a very large measure due to him; and we most not omit to mention Messrs. Purvis and Webb, under whose supervision the dock had been prepared to receive the members of the club and their guests. Mr. D. Dampergola's Orchestra helped to enliven the proceedings with a number of selections admirably rendered. But to turn to the sports themselves: these, though not astounding when compared with the world’s records, were nevertheless of a high class and showed what great good the formation of n swimming club in Alexandria had done.  The progress was marked and the performances of the juniors were especially creditable, and pleasing as promising a great future for the club. For event I., which consisted of the four preliminary heats of the 60 yards handicap for H. E. the Sirdar’s medal, seventeen competitors turned out.  In the first heat A. A. Eeclestone and N. W. Ames cameijn 1st and 2nd respectively, in the second heat W. Wood and C.S. Scarth ; in the third E.A. Darton and G. N. Cheeseman, aand in the fourth P.E. Harrison and W. 0. Mace.  Event II. was the 60 yards juniors' handicap for members under sixteen years of age. Five boys competed and the excellent handicapping was shown by the nearness of the race. Harry Ecclestone, a boy only just turned si. years, went off in nob’e style and the plucky little fellow kept his lead to the end amid loud shouts of "Go it, nipper."  W. H. Talbot, however, drew up to the leader very well and was closely followed by C. E. L. Randall, who had to give 85 seconds start to Elsworth, and between the first three competitors there was barely the difference of a "touch." Event III., 60 yards veterans’ handicap for members of 35 years of age and over, was won fairly easily by W. Wood, but only a few inches separated A. Jackman and M. B. Irvin, who came in 2nd and 3rd respectively. The final of the Sirdar’s medal handicap was then swum off, the competitors being W. Wood, G. N. Chessman, P. E. Harrison, N.	w. Ames, C. S. Scarth, E. A. Darton, W.O.	Mace and A. A. Ecclestone. Ecclestone was scratch, conceding seventeen seconds to the limit man, and he won the race in a splendid manner. Starting off with a clean and strong stroke he almost immediately gained ground, and as the winning point was approached he just managed to overhaul Darton. His excellent swim and graceful action excited general admiration, and he was hailed as winner with loud applause. Darton, too, made a splendid fight, gaining second place, and Cheeseman came in a very good third. The juniors diving championship, for which a cup was presented by the hen. sec., followed. The diving which was from 3.5, and 8 feet, was not of an exceptionally high order, but considering the ages of the competitors it was as good as could be expected. Randall secured the cup and Mitchinson and Harry Ecclestone were awarded 2nd and 3rd places respectively. Event VI plunging championship, followed. As in previous years much difficulty was experienced, in marking off the distances but the judge finally placed Ames, A.B. Collier, end Mace.  1st, 2nd, and 3rd in order of the names. The prizes for this event were very kindly presented by the Alexandria Tramway Company Ltd., while the cup was given by the Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Co. Event VIL was a pole watch between the Alexandria Swimming Club and the Eastern Telegraph Company which was very evenly contested, though the E.T.C. had not been been able to practice for the match. The club were the first to score, Darton throwing in with splendid aim very soon after play began. ei d half time was called with the iowe care ab 1 to niL On changing ends the E.T.C. did better and drew even with a good shot from Incledon but only a minute before time. Ecclastone scored for the club and thus secured them the verdict.  A ten minutes interval was then given but was not without some amusement; Mr. Martin, who bad been on dry land all this time, supervising and judging; was suddenly seized with a craving for the water and rushing along the spring board shoved off for a dive with the full force of his fourteen and a half stone; the board snapped and it was only the last fibers of wood which prevented it from accompanying him in his dive; he also gave some neat exhibition dives. The blindfold race insugurated the second half of the programme and afforded endless amusement. Some swam in circles, others returned to the starting point almost immediately, and not a few endeavoured to entangle themselves in tubs bad life-buoys which were placed on one side to await the obstacle race. Collier, swimming remerkably straight, won fairly easily and was followed by Mace and Lovell almost together. The seniors’ diving competition followed this and some very good diving was witnessed.  The winners were, in order, Collier Ecclestone and Darton. The first, two tying for first place, had to dive again, when Collier gained the verdict owing to Ecclestone turning over slightly. Darton was inclined to "buck” but just kept outside the limits of the definition and his neatness obtained him third place. The obstacle race was most amusing and exciting. The competitors had to pass through life-buoys and barrels and over and under poles and some curious struggles were witnessed. Irvin the limit man looked a certain winner but on his return he stuck in a barrel and, being of no slight build, it was with great difficulty that he managed to extricate himself. The 1st, 2nd, and 3rd places were awarded to Ecclestone, Mace, and Scarth respectively. The Military polo match between teams of the Departmental Corps and Royal Berks was well fought but the former were distinctly superior and won fairly easily by 4 goals to 1. The Royal Berks were rather weakened by the department of their best men for Khartoum but they made a splendid fight against a strong team and there was very little fouling. Each member of the winning team received a money prize. The juniors then “walked the pole" and for this event, Randall secured the only prize. The seniors followed and Collier was the only competitor to take the flag out of its socket and therefore gained the verdict.  When the military tug of war came off it was getting dark. The Departmental Corps and Royal Berks pulled against each other and as in the polo match the former won by two pulls to nil, and this was the concluding event.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Lady Btomfield then distributed the prizes supported by Prince Azic Hassan, Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, K.C M.G., Mr Waiter F. Sarjeant, and Mr. Martin, but be before we refer to this part of the programme we must mention that she was presented on her arrival at 4 p.m. with a beautiful bouquet by Mr. Walter F. Sarjeant, and at the conclusion she was asked to accept a very handsome silver card case from the club as a souvenir of the pccassion. After each successful competitor had reveived his reward Mr. Sarjeant made a short speech in which he thanked Lady Blomfield for her kindness and the interest which she took in the club as was shown by her presence there that afternoon at the centre of such a large gathering. H.H. Prinoe Aziz Haasan and Admiral Blomfield were, he said, very welcome guests. To Prince Aziz he had to offer the heartiest thanks on behalf of the club for the generosity whcch he had shown that afternoon in offering a prize for any race next year which the club might choose. It has since been decided that a 220 yards scratch race will be swum for the Prince's prize, which will be a valuable silver cup. Remarking upon the success of the club Mr. Sarjeant mentioned that when it was formed three years ago there was but a handful of members while now they numbered two hundred and seventy. Before the gathering broke up, Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield in a short speech proposed a vote of thanks to Mr. Sarjeant and the energetic committee who had organised the sports and expressed the great pleasure which it bad been to Lady Blomfield and himself to witness the excellent exhibition of the art of swimming which had taken place that afternoon. We must not omit to mention that the chairman of the Club has kindly given a silver cup for the seniors’ diving championship and that the captains of the merchant marine service trading to Alexandria have most generally promised to present a cup for a junior championship to be decided upon later.</p></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <div type= "item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head></div>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <div type= "item">
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <head>REGATTA.</head>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>The handicap for to-morrow’s race is the me as last week.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Class I. Course E.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>Class II. Course R.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>N.B. In Course R the Boghas Pass mark must be left on the starbord hand, not Port hand, as printed on the Charts</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>As on Friday next the 13th inst. H.H. the Khedive has promised to visit the club,a special regatta will be held in his honor when his challenge cup will raced for Class II. only.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>To-morrow at 4.30 and 5 p.m. respectively two preliminary heats will be rowed between the following clubs:-</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>1 Club Nautique Francais versus Club international Canotier.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>2 Alexandria Rowing CLub versus German Sport Verein.</p>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <p>If any of the sailing boats find themselves near the course of the rowing boats they are requested to keep out of their way, although the courses have been specially chosen to avoid collisions at breakwater elbow buoy, where the rowing boats start.</p>          </div>                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">   </div>  </text>                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             
            </body> 
    </text>
</TEI>
