<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIA’S LAST FIGHT. REVOLUTIONISTS' SWAY. </head>
                    <head>M. WITTE AND HIS CABINET.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 6. News of continual anti-Semitic and anti- liberal
                        riots continues to arrive from all parts, from Archangel to Tiflis and from
                        Poland to Tomsk. They are generally the result of what are called patriotic
                        or conservative manifesta- tions, which are organized under the auspices of
                        the police, and formed of mobs headed by the Imperial banner or by a
                        portrait of the Tsar. There have been hundreds oi killed and wounded at
                        Rostoff-on-Don and at Krement- chug. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 6. </head>
                    <p>The Tsar's manifesto restoring all the an- cient liberties of Finland has
                        been published at Helsingfors.The constitutionalists are sa- tisfied, but
                        the revolutionaries demand further concessions. The revolutionists have
                        proved their control over the masses by countermanding yester- day's
                        demonstration, announcing that they would choose their own day, and not
                        accept one of Trepoff's choosing, for the last fight. M. Witte has not made
                        the least progress in the formation of a Cabinet The Conservatives avoid him
                        ; the Liberals show themselves dis- trustful, while the reactionaries detest
                        him. A few weeks' full is expected, during which the revolutionary party
                        will perfect their organisation. A fresh manifesto assures the people that
                        the reforms will be inflexibly carried out despite the efforts of the
                        enemies of reform, but the Government must have the coopera- tion of the
                        pacific majority. {Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The day has been quiet here. In Odessa the troubles are decreasing. (Hovas)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AUSTRIA.</head>
                    <head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE WANTED</head>
                    <head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
                    <p>Great manifestations in favor of universal suffrage have taken place in the
                        principal cities of the Empire. At Prague they were the occasion of grave
                        rioting. ( Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MONTENEGRO.</head>
                    <head>PARLIAMENTARY GOVERNMENT ESTABLISHED. </head>
                    <head>Cettigne, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The Prince bes established, parliamentary government in Montenegro. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RING ALFONSO IN BERLIN.</head>
                    <head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The King of Spain has arrived on e visit to the Emperor. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
                    <p>King Alfonso has arrived and was greatly cheered. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SLAVO-ITALIAN CONFLICTS.</head>
                    <head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The conflicts between the Slavian and Italian students continue. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH BUDGET.</head>
                    <head>Paris, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies has commenced the debate on the Budget. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>G. AQUILINA</head>
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Quarantine in Malta.—Alexandria is no longer considered as an "infected
                        plaoe” by the authorities in Malta.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Suez Canal.—23 vessels passed throogh the Canal on the 1st and 2nd inst, the
                        amount of dues received being frs. 637,795.37.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Cairo Mixed Court.—The judges of the Cairo Mixed Court have held a general
                        meet- ing under the presidency of M. Prunieres, and approved the "reglement
                        do service” for the judicial year 1905-6.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>False Jewellery. - Some Alexandria jewel- lers have been arrested for selling
                        imitation gold ornaments falsely stamped as being real gold. Recently, also,
                        three Syrian brothers were imprisoned at Hadra for the same offence.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Native Benevolence. TLo “Mokattam” learns from Fayoum that the omdehs and
                        notables of that town held a meeting and decided to establish a benevolent
                        society, the object of which is to build a technical school. A subscription
                        on the spot realised £3,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Doctors. — Drs. Hassan Hosny Afifi, Kamel Fahmi, Mohamed Abdul Hamid,
                        Nassif Fahmy Mencarious, Mohamed Kamil Baradab, Tewfik Naguib, Abdel Hamid
                        Sami, Abdel Aziz Helmi, Riskalla Moussa, and Mohamed Sidky, have been
                        authorised to practise in Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Union Fonciered’Egypte.—It is announced that definitive share warrants to
                        bearer in the Union Fonciere d'Egypte are now ready for delivery, in
                        exchange for fully-paid allotment letters, at the Anglo-Foreign Banking Com-
                        pany, Limited, 2, Bishopsgate-street Within, London, E.C.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A. L M. &amp; D. S.—The annual general meet- ing of the members of the
                        Alexandria Literary, Musical and Dramatic Society has been fixed to take
                        place on Wednesday, 15th inst., at H.B.M.'s Consulate, at 6.30 p.m.
                        Business: 1.To pass ths acconuts for past session ; 2. To elect a oommittee
                        end office-bearers for ensuing session; 3. To prepare programme for next
                        season.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Revue Internationale D'Egypte —The November issue of the 'Revue Internatio-
                        nale d’Egypte” is as interesting as usual and contains the following
                        contributions:—L'Expe- dition d'Egypte: 1798-1801 (R.G.C.). Le Pay- sage
                        Egyptian (Louis Fieri), II Moderno Teatro Italiano (Giovanni Munduls), Les
                        Morta (J. M.), Le Bonheur (Henri Sarvee). Un Poete (Pierre Andibert).
                        Jose-Maria De Heredia (Georges Dumani), Fata Morgana (U. Fleres).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mysterious Murder —A servant of Abdel Latif Bey Faid was murdered in His
                        master’s house Cadabah village, Gharbieh, on the 2nd inst. by some unknown
                        persons. The mur- derers appear to bare first beaten him most savagely and
                        then strangled him, forcing the point of a stick which reached the brain
                        into his skull. Ths Kafr el Zayat authorities have opened an enquiry. Hassan
                        Effendi Faid, the omdeb, and some ghaffirs are suspected of the crime,
                        because, it is said, the omdeh was on bad terms with the murdered man. They
                        have been arrested, but as yet no proof has been advanced of their
                        guilt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Princess Nazli Hanem is expected to arrive here from Tunis next Wednesday
                        accompanied by her husband, in order to spend the winter season in Egypt.
                        They will, probably, proceed to Cairo on the same day by the evening
                        express.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>H. H. the Khedive will grant an andienoe to the Russian Agent and
                        Consul-General on Thursday next</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Marquis de Soragna has returned to Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>An extension of leave for one month has been granted to Harvey Pasha.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Norddentescher Lloyd S.S. Schleswig, which arrived at Alexandria last
                        night from Marseilles, had a large contingent of passen- gers. Among the
                        more prominent people on board we noticed General Djellal-el-Diu Pasha (who
                        was met on arrival by T. H. Prince Aziz and Prince Omar Toussoun, and drove
                        off in a motor car with them), Fouad Pasha, Hon. Mr. Iddings, the new
                        American Diplomatic Agent with Mrs. and Miss Iddings, Mustapha Pasha Kamel,
                        Count de Zogheb, Adly Pasha Yeghen Governor of Cairo, Baron E. de Menasce,
                        etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the passengers who arrived by the Messageries Maritimes steamer this
                        morning were Abani Pasha, Minister of War, the family of M. de la Bonliere,
                        French Diplomatic Agent, Mr. and Mrs. John Ross, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The King of Greece has bestowed the Cross of the Saviour on Mohamed Shafik
                        Bey, chief engineer of the Sharkieh Moudirich.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MR. STEAD ON SITUATION.</head>
                    <head>INTERVIEW WITH THE DOWAGER EMPRESS.</head>
                    <head>REFORMS TOO LATE.</head>
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service) London, Monday, Nov. 6.</head>
                    <p>Mr. W. T. Stead has arrived in Copenhagen from Helsingfors and has had a long
                        private interview with the Dowager Empress ot Russia, in which he said that
                        the gravity of the situa- tion in Russia cannot be overestimated. Mr. Stead
                        predicted gigantic massacres, and he believes that the reforms have oome too
                        late. Wireless telegraphy has been installed between Peterhof and Berlin.
                        The Kaiser has sent an autograph letter to the Tsar.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ACTIVE SERVICE IN CRETE.</head>
                    <p>The following order was issued yesterday by Brig.-General Bullock, C.B.
                        commanding the Army of Occupation :— The General Officer Commanding hereby
                        declares that, by reason of the recent exis- tence of active service in the
                        Island of Crete, it is, in his opinion, necessary for the Public Service
                        that the British Forces in the Island aforesaid shall continue temporarily
                        subject to the Army Act as if they were on active service, with effect from
                        31st October, 1905, and until 30th November, 1905, both dates inclusive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTI.</head>
                    <p>The new Grand Mufti, Sheikh Bakri Moha- med Ashour El Sedfi, has entered
                        immediately on his new post. He is a well-known personality among the Moslem
                        religious notables and a follower of the Hanafi rite. He was educated at Al
                        Azhar, where he became ulema after showing considerable theological
                        proficiency, and was for a long period Mufti to the now suppressed
                        Beit-el-Mal Administration. He was later appointed to the Mehkemeh High
                        Court as Cadi and showed such legal and theological acumen that he gained
                        the good opinion of the bulk of Egyptian Moslems. He was acting as Grand
                        Cadi in the place of Sheikh Yehia, who has gone on an important errand to
                        Constantinople, when the death of Sheikh Abdul Kader El Raffei threw open to
                        him the Grand Muftiship of Egypt. One of our Cairo contemporaries states
                        that the Ministry of Jnstice is at present discussing the question whether
                        the new Grand Mufti can still perform his functions of Grand Cadi per
                        interim, or whether some one else must be appointed to replace Sheikh Yehia
                        during his absence in Turkey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
                    <p> MM. Fourneron Bey and Sanpaolo, who returned last Friday night from their
                        visit to the Ibrahimieh sugar factories, left Cairo by the night train
                        yesterday for a fresh tour of inspection. This time the experts will examine
                        and report on the factories at Nag Hamadi, Arment, and Mataana, a task which
                        will, it is expected, employ their energies for at least another week. The
                        third and, let us hope, the final report of the experts is expected to be
                        completed by Thursday, the 18th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND ALLOTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Letters of allotment for the shares of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment
                        Company have been posted. The allotment was carried through by Messrs.
                        Russell and Kerr, chartered accountants, of Cairo. Dr. Axil Th. Preyer has
                        joined the board of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Co. Mr. Crewe, who was
                        till now agent for the National Bank of Egypt at the Mousky branch, Cairo,
                        has been appointed sub-manager to the Egyptian Land Allotment Co., under a
                        con contract of ten years, and with a salary of£720 per annum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTH EGYPT LAND CO.</head>
                    <p>With reference to the statement of a local contemporary in its issue of last
                        Saturday, re the North Egypt Land Co., L-d, we may point out that the
                        oompany are not wholly dependent on “providential rainfalls” for raising
                        their crops on their Mariout property, as there are already a number of
                        wells which irrigate the land, and many more are to be sunk. But leaving
                        aside the decision of the Irrigation Department not to extend the Nu- barieh
                        Canal for the present, there is another scheme about to be proposed to the
                        Govern- ment which will afford ample means for irrigat ing not only the
                        fifteen thousand feddans at present owned by the company, but a good deal
                        more.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. Britannia sailed from Malta on Sunday night and is expected
                        here on Friday morning with passengers, mails and general cargo. The Moss
                        liner Menes sailed from Liverpool on Saturday afternoon last, and is due
                        here on the 18th inst. with passengers, mails, an general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN GIRL SLAVE IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <head>HER HUSBAND'S TREACHERY.</head>
                    <p>We cull the following from a New York oontemponry :— The extraordinary case
                        of Mollie Katain who was married last July to Harry Liederer, No. 170
                        Delancey street taken by him to Egypt sold as a white slave into bondage,
                        and rescued by the efforts of the International Society for the Suppression
                        of the White Slave Trade, has just come to light through a letter sent by
                        the girl to her brothers in New York. Her courtship was a short one, and she
                        was married at her home, No. 132, Attorney street last July. Four weeks
                        later she disappeared and was not heard of until last weak, when the society
                        sent her to her brothers after they had rescued her. Her introduction to
                        Lederer, it was said, was brought about by Mrs. Nathan Weber, who lives at
                        No. 122, Suffolk street She had $300 in bank in her own name and this must
                        have been, withdrawn without her knowledge, for in her letter she asks that
                        her fare home may be paid out of this money. The letter to her brothers is
                        in her own handwriting and is as follows: “My Dear Brothers—I am unable to
                        express the sad position in which I find myself My husband has been
                        treacherous and has fooled me all along. He brought me to Alexandria and has
                        made me a prisoner of other men. I wish you to go to court and get
                        duplicates of the documents which show that I am his wife, as he has stolen
                        the original papers from me. Buy a ticket for me to return, for he has taken
                        all my money from me. Iam very sick and cannot write much more. Molfie.”
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW SUDAN AGENT.</head>
                    <p>Captain R. C. Owen has been appointed Director ot the Intelligence Department
                        and Sudan Agent at Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PHARMACY REGULATIONS.</head>
                    <p>We mentioned in our issue of the 16th ultimo two serious infringements of the
                        new pharmacy regulations which oome into ope- ration about a year ago. These
                        prove how necessary it is for the Sanitary Adminis- tration to use the
                        utmost vigilance for safe- guarding the public. In one case a Greek named
                        Pistis, when applying for permission to open a pharmacy, sent in a diploma
                        that was ascertained to have belonged to a man who had been dead since 1896!
                        In the other case three individuals sent in diplomas pur- porting to have
                        been issued by the Faculty of Medicine of Athens bat which, when subjected
                        to expert examination, were found to be forged. The officials of the
                        Department, since the new regulations came into operation, have taken in
                        hand the inspection of pharmacies but it seems they are greatly hampered by
                        the action of the Tribunals, who, when clear cases of irregularities are
                        brought to their notice, inflict such a ridioulously small punish- ment that
                        it cannot possibly act as a de- terrent. Recently, we are informed, at Man-
                        sourah, two individuals, one a Greek and the other an Italian, were summoned
                        for keeping a pharmacy open for three months without a certificated chemist.
                        The Tribunal Mixte de Contravention inflicted for this grave offence the
                        minimum fine of P.T. 5 in one case and P.T. 10 in the other!</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>The New Khedivial Hotel at Alexandria, whioh is at present being entirely
                        renovated, will be quite ready for occupation again by the coming Christmas.
                        It will, when completed, contain altogether 150 bedrooms and twenty suites
                        of special apartments fitted with bath- rooms, closets, and other
                        accommodation. The grill-room will be open on the 1st December, and
                        afternoon teas will be served in the new pavilion on the terrace. A fine
                        Tzigane band has been specially engaged for the hotel and will play three
                        times a day. A special feature of the hotel will be the residential
                        apartments for bachelors and fami- lies, who will be able to live at the
                        hotel at an inclusive and moderate cost for board and lodging.It is expected
                        that this innovation will be taken full advantage of, and owing to the poor
                        restaurants aud high rents at Alex- andria such accommodation will be a
                        great advantage to residents. Another special feature of the hotel will be
                        the cooking.The leading "chef” at the Metro- pole Hotel, Moote Carlo, has
                        been engaged, and arrived on Sunday last with an entire brigade of
                        gastronomic artists selected with the utmost care from among the leading
                        European hotels and restaurants. During the winter the Khedivial Hotel
                        management will give a ball once a fortnight, as is the custom in Cairo.
                        There is to be a grand “Reveillon” at the hotel at Christmas, which will be
                        the formal opening fete of the hotel. Every night when there is a
                        performance at the Zizinia Theatre there will be a special supper menu at a
                        fixed inclusive price, and a band will play from midnight until 2 p.m. A
                        large American bar is to be opened on December 1, which will be equal to the
                        finest bar in Egypt. The hotel is under the manage- ment of Mr. E. Fleury,
                        late manager of the Nonvel Hotel at Vichy and of the Alexandra Hotel at
                        Monte Carlo. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALL CAPITAL APPLIED FOR.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>London, Monday, Nor. 6.</head>
                    <p>The Berlin Bank fur Handel and Indus- trie has applied for 100,000 £5 shares
                        in the Bank of Abyssinia.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>London, November 6.</head>
                    <p>Tbe prospectus of tbe Bank of Abyssinia has been issued. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RODAH LAND SALE.</head>
                    <p>At the recent land sale at Rodah, according to 'Le Progres,” Dr. Nimr bade
                        L.E. 2,470 per feddan for tbe Menekley estate and this was the highest bid.
                        But owing to a dispute as to the validity of the bid it is possible that
                        Maitre Carton de Wiart's offer on behalf of an English group rail hold good.
                        The ques- tion will be decided at the next meeting of the Superior Council
                        of the Wakfs.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE VALLEY CO.</head>
                    <p>The "Financial News" is officially authoris- ed to deny tbe report that the
                        Nile Valley Company is to be reconstructed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WALKER AND MEIMARACHI.</head>
                    <p>The latest London papers contain the report of the proceedings at the meeting
                        of Walker and Meimarachi, Limited, held in London on Monday, Ootober 30.
                        This ia said to be the first English company founded in Egypt, and owing to
                        its good management we are sure that the shareholders will be pleased-to
                        hear that the capital is to be increased so that the company may be able to
                        develop its business throughout Egypt and the Sudan. The board of directors
                        will henceforth be in Cairo, with only two directors in London. The company
                        will remain an English company and the meetings will be held in London.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BIG FIRE AT ASSIOUT.</head>
                    <p>One of the wealthiest families at Assiout is the Khaehabah family, writes our
                        Assiout Correspondent. They had four large houses at Assiout. One was burnt
                        down four months ago, another two months ago, and the remain- ing two last
                        week. The fire broke out at 11 p.m. and in aboat two hours, the two houses
                        were a blazing mass. The loss is estimated at £8,000. It is a remarkable
                        coin- cidence that in all three cases the cause of this outbreak was
                        accidental. Our correspondent states that Assiout. is very badly supplied
                        with pumps. In the fire mentioned the house was burning for a whole hour
                        before the pumps arrived, and after they came it took another hour to put
                        them in working order. Thanks are due to Mr. Russell, the Interior
                        inspector, who worked hard all night, as on the previous occasions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW ENGLISH PAPERS.</head>
                    <p>A new illustrated political weekly, styled "The Oriental Truth,” has just
                        made its appearanoe at Cairo. It is dedicated to Oriental civillisation and
                        the editor and proprietor is Captain Joge Neokan y Weldberg. There is also
                        an Arabic and a Freneh part in addition to the English. Another new English
                        publication is “Egyp- tian Cotton,” published at Alexandria. We wish our new
                        contemporaries every success.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANCO DI ROMA</head>
                    <p>Ainsique nous l'avons deja publie, le conseil d'administration du "Banoo di
                        Roma” a decide de porter le capital de oet important eta blissement
                        financier de O a 30 millions. L’emission das cent mille actions au prix de
                        fr. 120,80, jouissance premier janvier -1905, aveo un dividende assure non
                        inferieur aux 7 francs ordinaires par action aura lieu du 6 au 9 novembre.
                        Les nouvelles actions sont donc souscrites a moins de 115 francs, car depuis
                        de nombreuses annees deja, le dividende du "Banco di Roma" eat consolide a
                        fr. 7; ce qui vent dire que ces actions presentent le rare avantage d’un
                        place- ment aussi sur que le consolide italien a plus da 6 pour cent. Les
                        noeveaux titres aeront offerts a option aux porteurs dos anciennes actions a
                        raison d’une nouvelle action contre deux anciennes. L’emission est garantie
                        an eotier par deux grands groupes feanciers. Cette augmentation du capital
                        da "Banco di Roma” s’explique par la croissante expansion de cet
                        etablissement financier non senlement en Italie maia encore a l’etranger. En
                        effet, les sieges de cette banque existant a Paris et a Alexandrie d’Egypte
                        ont donne des resultata si encourageante que de nouvelles succursales seront
                        instituees dans d'autrees pays d’Europe. Ce succes depend aurtout de la
                        prudence et de l'habilete financiere de la direction qui a su an quelques
                        annes faire d’une petite Banque una des plus puisantes organisations
                        financie- res d’ltalie.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA SANIEH</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAIN CLAIM.</head>
                    <p>Mr. H.E Garle again writes to the "Times" with references to the above, as
                        follows: Sir,—May I, in view of tbe references to this matter in your issue
                        of the 23td inst., again trespass upon your space. Tbe proceedings in
                        question had nothing whatever to do with the trial of the action and the
                        merits of the question were not even gone into. The next-of-kin’s legal
                        adviser in Egypt was of opinion that, in all the circumstances, the Egyptian
                        Courts should be asked to restrain any payment of the surplus in the hands
                        of the Daira Sanieh Limited to the Egyptian Govern- ment; and this is all
                        that was done, and is all that has failed The next-of-kin's main claim is
                        against the Egyptian Government and tho Daira Sanieh of H.H. the Khedive ;
                        it has not been tried, and will not be tried for some time to come. The
                        proceedings that have taken-place are in truth, little more than the
                        equivalent to a stop order in this country, and even so, are being appealed
                        against. I earnestly trust that you will see your way to give the same
                        prominence to this letter that you did to my last, for it is even more impor
                        tant that your statement in your issue of the 23rd inst. be answered than
                        that in your issue- of the 18th Inst. I am. Sir. your obedient servant H.
                        Ernest Garle Solicitor the next-of-kin. 61, Lincoln's inn-fields, London,
                        W.C,Oot 29. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN.</head>
                    <p>Sir Trevor Chichele Ohichele-Plowden, K.O.S.L,whose death was announced
                        yesterday, connects two famous names in his own person, while the marriage
                        of his daughter with the Earl of Lytton, end his own second marriage with a
                        Fitzherbert of Swynnerton, connect him with two other names of note.
                        Chichele began with the Archbishop, whose younger brother was Sheriff of
                        London, and father of the Admiral, and Master-General of Ordeuance. Plowden
                        has produced not only Sir Trevor and other Plowdens, familiar in the annals
                        of the Indian Civil Service but also Sir Trevor's elder brother, the Cadi of
                        Marylebone, the "scintillae juris” of whose, judgement east perennially
                        enliven the police reports.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Pasenger List</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Arrivals</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. Sohleewig, arrived at Alexandria yesterday frtm Marseilles end
                        Naples:-M, D. Arif Bey, M,-and Mme P. Agoapian, Miles Marie and Ketty
                        Agopian, Mile .E Dexarena M. and Mme Heinrich Bindernagel. M. Ludwig
                        Bindernagel, Milles llse and Freida Binder- nagel, Mme Ph. Back, Mme Cecilia
                        Buallachi, Mlle Olly Bolts, Mlle Beor, M. and Mme Leopold Blariaux, M. and
                        Mae D, Caedagli, Mme K. and Mlle M. E Cettier, M. and Mme Cherky Pachs, M.
                        Ahmed Checky Bey, Mlle Viseae, Dr. von Campe, Mrs. W. Cum- mings, General
                        Ahmed Djelaleddin Pasha, Miss Helen Denison, Mr. C. Duffield, M.L. Dombre,
                        M. Henry Dubois, Mme Ida Boy Edd, Fouad Pacha, Mr. and Ms. Percival Foster,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Edward R Hoyt, Ms. Rendal, Hoyt, Mr. and Mrs.Chas Humpers
                        Mr.Andre Humpers, Mrs. Hood, Mrs. W. Hammond Mr. F. Hinkley, Mr. A.
                        Hehanoff, Adly Yeghan, Pacha and Mme, Mmme Lamalun, Mme and Mlle Alfred
                        Ismalun, Gonaull General Mrs., and Miss Iddings, Mohamed Jaffer. Mme, J. G.
                        L Kooh, Mlle W. Kloes,. M. Aug, Kiene Muatafa Kamel Pasha, Col Hon. R. T.
                        Law- ley. Capt and Mme von Langadorf, Mr. Ri- chard Louth, Baron E de
                        Menace, Mrs, C. J. Milton, Mrs. Mahony, Mme. Idanka Mayer, Mlle Lina Mayer,,
                        Mrs. MacPherran, Noury Bey, Lieuteniant van Neumann, Mr. W. M. Noyes, Mr.
                        and Mrs. R. Neville, Emille Nagel, Mlle Johanne M. Naude, M. and Mme Emila
                        Paravioini, Mr. and Mrs. Parker, Miss Parker, Miss Peel, Mrs. and Miss. W.F
                        Peel M. Theodoore J. Rodocanachi, M. Mohsen Rifky, Mr. and Mrs. A. Robinson,
                        Sabit Bey, Mme Sabit, Mlle Leonnie, Gamille Sabit Bey, Mr. and Mme., M.M.
                        Scott, M. and Mme. Alfred Suares, M. J. Shute, M. Sursook, M. A. Stul- ken,
                        M. Georg. Schmidt,Mlle A. Dan. Sommer, Mile J. Sigert, M. Albert Tilohe,
                        Mlle Tilche, Cav. Uff. A. Tilche, Mme Tilche, Hon. J. C. Vessey, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Wyatt, M. and Mme. Wierdals, Mlle Wierdals, M. Wierdals, Mr. Watt, M.
                        Ed. Wantz, Comtesse de Zogheb, Mlle Jeanne de Zogheb, M. and Mme. Rhfoasd
                        Zander, Mlle Fanny Zander, Herr Oberburder- meister Becker, Frau Ghemalin
                        and Toohter, Mr. R Baezner,Dr. and Mme F. Borchardt,Mr. M. Billwiller, Mr.
                        Ghstdve Cattaui, Mlle J. Coczalmann, Mr. Cantalamesss, Mr. and Mme Drakidis,
                        Mr. J. Dobsult, Mr. Elie Francis, Baronesse Halkett, Mr. Chr. Hornatein,
                        Mlle Ismailoff, Herr Landrat Krietzler, Mr. Lepeoh- kine, Mr.Legoulles,Mr.
                        Uaseoo,Mtared*Ueti*, Said Mob. el Mokry, Said Mob. Benani, Mr. and Mae P.
                        Michel Mr.G. Madon.Mr. P. Mao chi, Aw. P. Maochi, Ms. Georges Malic, Mile
                        Momtt, Mre. Mdngerin, Mra E Matiuea, Mr. Neddi Meddin, Mr. E Nioholsde, Mr.
                        P. Philippo and family, Mr. G. Pbilippo. Mr. A. Percy, M. and Mme A. Rocha.
                        Mlle Rossi- Pran.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
