<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIGHTING AT SANDEPU. RUSSIAM RETREAT HEAVY LOSSES</head>
                    <p><placeName>Murden,</placeName> January 30. The Japanese losses at Sandepu
                        amounted to 5,000 and the Russian to 10,000. ( Havas. )</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> January 30. A despatch from General
                        Gripenberg shows that the Japanese have vigorously attacked the Russians.
                        General Koudratovitch has been wounded. (Reuter) Tokio, January 30. T The
                        Japanese estimate their losses during the recent fighting at 5,000 and the
                        Russians at 10,000. (Reuter).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> January 30. Router s correspondent with
                        General Kuroki says that after driving the Russians across the Hun-Ho the
                        Japanese bombarded the whole line. The Russian reply was feeble. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RIOTS AT WARSAW. TERRIBLE CARNAGE. OUTRAGE ON BRITISH CONSUL</head>
                    <p><placeName>Warsaw,</placeName> January 30. Serious riots occurred here on
                        Saturday. Many of the finest shops were sacked and burned. The cavalry
                        charged, and the troops fired, at several points of the town. Mr. Murray,
                        the British: Consul-General, and Mr. St. Clair, the Vice-Consul, were
                        separately charged by patrols. The Vice-Consul received terrible sword cute
                        in the face. (Reuter).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> January 30. Sir C. Hardinge has sent a
                        military attache to Warsaw in order to investigate the reported attacks on
                        the British Consul-General and Pro-consul by the soldiers. Sir C. Hardinge
                        has protested against the re-publication at Libau of the notices mentioned
                        on the 26tb inst, pointing out that such a step will seriously affect the
                        friendly relations between the two countries. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>Warsaw,</placeName> January 30. Disturbances have been renewed
                        to-day. There were 160 killed and wounded. The troops at Libau have been
                        reinforced as the situation is worse. (Reuter).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ECHO OF THE RUSSIAN REVOLT. OUTRAGE IN PARIS.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Paris,</placeName> January 30. At the close of the meeting
                        organised by M. Jaures to protest against the events in St Petersburg, an
                        infernal machine was thrown amidst the policemen, two of whom wen wounded.
                        Four arrests were made. The police found an infernal machine during the
                        night at the residence of Prince Troubzkoi, attache to the Russian Embassy
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR FRANCIS JEUNE. TO RECEIVE A PEERAGE.</head>
                    <p><placeName>London, </placeName>January 30 Sir Francis Jeune has resigned. He
                        is to receive a peerage. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WARING GILLOW, LIMITED. DECORATORS AND FURNISHERS TO HIS MAJESTY THE
                        KING.</head>
                    <p>Beg to announce to their clients that the director of their Paris House, Mr.
                        Cauldwell, is at present-at the New Khodivial Hotel, Alexandria, where he
                        can be seen by appointment by those desiring his artistic advice on all
                        matters connected with 'decoration and furnishing. Waring and Gillow lately
                        tarnished the Palace of Prince Nicholas of Greece at Athens. Mr. Cauldwell
                        will be at Shepherd’s Hotel, Cairo, after February 3rd to meet clients.
                        25373-6-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Gambling Den Raided.—On Sunday night the police of the Esbekieh kism made a
                        raid on a gambling house occupied by a Greek subject in the Sharia Weiget el
                        Birks.</p>
                    <p>New Doctors.—The Ministry of the Interior has licensed Messrs. Herbert
                        William Hughes Robert Brabant, physician, Jean Auaguosto-Poulo and Mohauied
                        Satnch, dentists, to practise in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Opera House.—It is stated that if it is decided to pull down the
                        Khedivial Opera House at Cairo, tho new theatre will be Obstructed, not in
                        the Khedivial Gardens, but in either the Ismail is or the Kasr-el-Nil
                        quarter. </p>
                    <p>Savot Small Dances—Next Saturday's dance at the Savoy Hotel promises to be as
                        successful as in predecessors. Most of the tables in jlio restaurant' are
                        already engaged for this evening. There will be an extra small dance next
                        Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Sporting Club.—The annual general meeting of the club will bo held
                        at the Khedivial Club on the 15th February at 9 p m , when the balance-sheet
                        and the accounts of the past year will be laid before the meeting and the
                        officers and the committee for the ensuing year elected.</p>
                    <p>Matinee Concert.—Mme. J. de Wronocka will give a vocal and instrumental
                        matinee concert on the 8th proxo at the Savoy Hotel, Cure. Mme. Wronocka has
                        given a very successful series of concerte in Franco and Italy. Tickets are
                        obtainable at the Savoy.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—30 vessels passed through the Canal on the 26th and 27th inst, of
                        which 17 were British, 4 German, 2 Norwegian, 1 Austrian, 2 French, 1 Dutch,
                        2 Turkish, 1 Dani-b. The receipt for the two days were frs. 739,195.76,
                        making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 9,854,370.68.</p>
                    <p>Tram Wires.—The electric wire at the Boulac train terminus snapped on Sunday,
                        some 20 metres coming down on the roadway. M. George Vayssi4 narrowly
                        escaped being struck, but coolly fended off the falling wire with his cane.
                        We congratulate him on his escape, but—might not the Tramway Company give us
                        guard-wires.</p>
                    <p>Popular University.—The second of the lectures organised under the patronage
                        of the Alexandria Archaeological Society will take place to-morrow at 9.15
                        p.m., when Dr. Brescia, Conservator of the Alexandria Museum, will speak on
                        “Greek Colonisation in Sicily." The lecture will be illustrated by lime
                        light view*. Entrance is tree.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGERS’ LISTS.</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. "HohetuoUern," arrived from Marseilles and Naples: — Mr. Conrad
                        Alborti-Sittenfeld, Countess Cara Amim, Mile. Wilholmnino Graeff, Mr. Kurt
                        Ba-uormanu, Mme. Carl Bannitiger, Mllc-Mari’e Wolf, Mr. Cramer, Mme.
                        Cramer-Sanuin, Mme-and Mile. H. Carbarn, Mr. L. Giffin Cauldwell, Mr. P.
                        Campbell, Mme. Danaacrt, M. J. Figueroa, Mr. H. Gamtilo, Mrs, and Miss
                        MacGregor, Dr. Heimburger, Mr. A. C. Hor»tuuum, Comte Charles and Comte-we
                        Eugenie de Holnstein, Mr. von Hemert, Mr. Frederioo Jacobs, Mr. Paul Jacobs,
                        Marquis de Jacome Corrta, Baron L de Knorring, Mr. and Mme. Leftvre, Mr. and
                        Mme. do Labry, .Mile. Marielle, Mr. Joseph Marx, Mme. and Mile. Niels, Mr 8.
                        L de N’ogueirm Pinto, General O’Connor, Mr. Ernest and Mile. Anna Rolin. Mr.
                        J. H. Robinson, Mr. A. SebiUeau, Lieutenant and Mme Schulr Dellwig, Mr. A.
                        W. Schmitt, Mr. Jorge L. 8ao-carello, Mr. Edmond Walton, Mme. Clara Walton.
                        MM. Prof. Zamara, Baltaxxi, Sabatino, Zia de Molk, Vial, Huber, R. Abdel*,
                        D. Romanc, E. Linzi, A, Agostini, P. Cioni, G. Vivarelli, A. CioDi, PiSters
                        ct Otto, Heller, Cav. Daninos, Baron Lutteroth. Per Moot S.S. “Menea,"
                        arrived on Sunday from Liverpool, Gibraltar, Algiers and Malta: Mias 8. A.
                        Cowan. Miss Gillon, Mias M. A. Wright, Mias L. Wright, Mr. John Adamson, Mr.
                        A. Adamson, Miss M. Adamson, Miss Lann, Miss Adamson, Miss A. Williams, Miss
                        Hastings, Mr. and Mrs. T. Ryder Mawda-ley, Mr. and Mm. Gentles and 3
                        children, Mw. Ribleon and 2 children, Miss Barralt, Miss G. Barratt Mr.
                        Moh-.med Bisheri, Mr. W. Man son, Mr. and Mr*. Menne*. Mias P. Monties, Mrs.
                        8tevena, Mr*. Hall, child and nurse, Miss Harofayne, Mr. W. Schwartz, Mr. L.
                        T. Bafferth, Mrs. Patterson, Mw. Palmer, Mr. and Mr*. Von Meyer, Mia* K R
                        Smith, Mr*. Bubagiar and 3 children, and 17 deck pessengers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, RAMIEH Ten minutes from Alexandria. First class in every respect.
                        Very moderate charges. Bulkeley is fashionable (C. Aguilina)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MIXED COURTS.</head>
                    <p>Renewal of powers. The existence of the Mixed Courts has been renewed for a
                        further term of five years, and not for one year only, as some newspapers
                        have stated. The date of the coming into force of the various reforms,
                        agreed upon by the Judicial Commission, has not yet been fixed upon.
                        Yesterday the Government informed the Appeal Court of the renewal of the
                        executive of the Mixed Court*. The new term of five year* begins tomorrow.
                        The Decree authorising the renewal of the functions of the Courts was signed
                        by the Khedive yesterday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                    <p>The Khedive is expected to return to Cairo from M-mtazah on Thursday next.
                        His Highness has been pleased to confer the following grade and
                        decorations:— Ramiek: Osman Anwar Mahfoux Bey, notable of Cairo. Medjidiek:
                        Commander (3rd class): M. Louis, Soul iAre, of the Paris police. Officer
                        (4th class): M. Francois Rameau, chief inspector, Paris police. M. Hally,
                        chef de bureau Prefecture of Paris police. Chevalier(5th class): M. Antonin
                        Guerra, M. Andres Paul; and M. Henri Chatelain, Paris police. Signor
                        Tihaldi, the violinist, played before the Khedivial in the Khedivial Palace
                        at Be-hek, on the Bosphorus, a few days ago. The Khedivah and her suite, who
                        were separated from Signor Tihaldi by a large screen, greatly appreciated
                        his playing. Before leaving the palace, the Khedivah presented Signor
                        Tihaldi with a magnificent stud oomposed of a huge emerald surrounded with
                        beautiful brilliants. She also presented Professor Selvelli with a set of
                        jewelled sleeve-links.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL.</head>
                    <p>The provincial councils of Keneh, Assiout, Beni Souef, Girgeh, and Ghizeh met
                        on Sunday morning at their respective Mondiriehs, and after taking the oath,
                        proceeded to elect their d-legates to the Legislative Council. The following
                        delegate was re-elected for Assistance: Mahmoud Pasha Suliman. Hassan Bey
                        Bakri was elected for Keneh, Mobamed Bey Tammam for Girzeh, Tamara Bey
                        Kussad for Beni Souef and Mohamed Buy El Maihi for Ghizeh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE NAVIGATION.</head>
                    <p>The Irrigation Service has decided to construct a sadd across the Rosetta
                        brooch of the Nile at Mehallet el Amir, kilometre 215 downstream on the
                        Delta Barrage. Navigation on the Rosette branch of the Nile will be
                        interrupted at the above-mentioned place during such time as the sadd will
                        be maintained there. A part of the above-mentioned sadd will be specially
                        affected to transhipment of goods arriving on boats. This transhiment will
                        be carried out at the risk and peril, at the expense, and by the care of tbe
                        owners of the Mats or the goods. The sadd will be dosed about the 10th
                        February and will be removed about the 15th August. The Irrigation Service
                        having decided to construct a sadd across the Nile at Farascour, near
                        Damietta, navigation on the Damietta branch at Farscour will be interrupted
                        between February 15 and August 15.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMLEH RAILWAY.</head>
                    <p>The plan of a station at the company’s new terminus on the Ramleh-boulevard
                        was submitted to the Municipality yesterday and will be examined by the
                        Delegation today. It is proposed to build the station of brick and it will
                        be of an artistic design. Meanwhile, a temporary wooden building has been
                        erected.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ORIENT LIKE.</head>
                    <p>The rumour that the steamers of the Orient-Pacific Line were about to
                        substitute the Cape route homeward bound for that of the Suez Canal is
                        incorrect. We learn that the steamers of the line continue to come home
                        through the Suez Canal as heretofore. The steamers will leave here every
                        fortnight, as before, and homeward-bound Egyptian passengers may rely upon
                        an equally good service this year as in the past. We may mention that the
                        "Oroya," leaving here about February 28, to the "Orizaba" inclusive, will
                        call at Malta in addition to the usual ports of call homeward bound, bat
                        there will be very little delay entitled by this extra call.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLISH CHURCH, MANSOURAH. SERVICES IN FEBRUARY.</head>
                    <p>5th (5th Sunday after Epiphany). Evensong at 6 p.m. 12th (6th Sunday after
                        Epiphany). Litany and H.C. at 11 am. 19th Septoagerima. Evensong at 6 p.m.
                        26th Sexagesima. H.C. at 8 am. Matina at 11 am. T. D. C. Firhinger,
                        Chaplain.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR</head>
                    <p>Beet and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Management. Moderate charges Patronised by office' of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WADY RAYAN AND MR. COPE WHITEHOUSE.</head>
                    <p>A correspondent writes: In regard to the article on Mr. Cope Whitehouse which
                        appeared in Friday's “Gazette,” I may mention that historians of the future
                        should not overlook the fact that there is one man to whom Egypt is much
                        indebted as to anyone for the Assouan dam, and that is Mr. Cope Whitehouse.
                        Ho is a man ot very great mental capacity, equally fitted to fill a
                        professorship of Greek or Natural Science. Twenty ago be foresaw the
                        necessity of storage rsaenoira for Egypt and proposed the Wady Rayan for
                        this purpose. His inveterate persistency caused the Irrigation Department to
                        face the alternative of either adopting his scheme or of bringing forward a
                        better one of their owe. That his scheme bad valuable features wm proved by
                        Colonel Western’s investigation, and Sir William Willeocks now strongly
                        supports it as a necessary complement of the existing Assocan dam. Without
                        the slightest doubt Mr. Cope Whitehouse’s advocacy of a reservoir, even
                        admitting a neglect of the maxim “Snaviter in modo, fortiW in re,’’ led to
                        Egypt having a reservoir at a mnoh earlier date than would otherwise have
                        occurred. Not long ago the representatives of M. De la Motte unsuccessfully
                        sued the Egyptian Government for a share of profit from the Assouan dam. The
                        De la Motte scheme was for a reservoir at Gebel 8ilseleh, but it was based
                        on date not adopted by the International Commission which stadied the whole
                        question of reservoir. Mr. Cope Whitehouse’s scheme in many respects stood
                        the test of searching technical engineer, and it may some day become a “fait
                        accompli." Be that as it may, Egypt is deeply indebted to him for forcing on
                        a solution of the reservoir question, even if his scheme was not the first
                        to be adopted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT.</head>
                    <p>An official notice has been issued by which Ahmed Bey Khaled has been
                        deprived of his functions as treasurer of the "Surra.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO TRAFFIC.</head>
                    <p>At last the work of asphalting Clot Beystreet,Cairo, has been finished and
                        the thorough. Care has been reopened to traffic. The improvement effected is
                        very great. Formerly the street was one of the worst in Cairo, and everybody
                        knows well what that means. A drive through it in an ordinary hackney
                        carriage, thanks to the ruts and boles that abounded, was not unlike having
                        a cruise in a small boat on a rough day, and the wear and tear on vehicles
                        of every kind was as disastrous to them as it was cruel to the unfortunate
                        animals that had to drag them over the broken roadway. So far as one can
                        judge from appearance the asphalting has been thoroughly well done and
                        promises to prove a success. The entire surface has been laid from footpath
                        to footpath, the only break in the asphalt being the lines of the Tramway
                        Company. Whether it would not have been better to have laid the spaces
                        between the tram lines with stone is a question that experience only can
                        decide, but there seems some danger of a rapid deterioration of the asphalt
                        by the breaking of the edges that it presents all along at both sides of
                        each of the tram lines. The resumption of the services of the Tramway
                        Company by this route has been accomplished without a hitch, and the great
                        pressure upon the traffic of the Esbekieh quarter of late has thus been
                        relieved. One result of the temporary service, however, has been to show
                        that there is a real need for a tram service connecting the A tabs el Khadra
                        and the railway station via Boulac-road, as this would enable travelers by
                        the cars to reach the centre of the Esbekieh district from all quarters of
                        the town, whereas by the now-existing routes this can only be done from the
                        Citadel or Boulac. This is a question well worthy the attention of the
                        company.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL CLUB DANCE.</head>
                    <p>The dance given last night by the members of the Khedivial Clob, Alexandria,
                        forming, u it did, one of the first large social functions of the season,
                        was a brilliant success in every respect. The palatial premises were most
                        profusely and tastefully decorated with innumerable plants and shrubs and
                        illuminated 1 jour by hundreds of electric lamps. The sitting rooms,
                        benefits, etc., were transformed into gardens and the billiard tables
                        covered with tastefully selected small plants. The floor and D’Ambra’s
                        orchestra were excellent and the large dancing room presented a brilliant
                        coup I ceil by 11.30 o’clock, when dancing was in mil awing. This was kept
                        up with great animation until 8.80 o’clock this morning. It would be a
                        difficult teak to give even a slight description of the beautiful view or
                        their brilliant effect. More than 300 guests were present, including almost
                        every leading representative of Alexandria and Ramleh society. the members
                        of the Consular Corps, Municipal Councillors, the Colonel and officers of
                        the Royal Berkshire Regiment, and the officers of the Royal Malta Artillery
                        and R. A. M. C., etc. Sapper was served in three different rooms, nicely
                        arranged for the occasion. The whole arrangement of the evening reflected
                        the greatest credit upon the committee and also upon their secretary, Mr.
                        Albert Cumbo, and hi* assistant, Mr. Borg, whose indefatigable energy had,
                        as usual, ensured the success which attended the evening's functions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL OPERA HOUSE.</head>
                    <p>We cannot say that Rigoletto was anything but a complete failure as given at
                        the Khedivial Opera House. We admit that the chorus was good and the staging
                        fine, but then this theatre can afford such luxuries. Signoi Andreini was
                        never pleasing, and not always in time: and his rendering of "La donna in
                        time" was the climax of exasperation, both inartistic and unmusical. Signora
                        Tromben should never have attempted the part of Gilda; she did all she
                        could, but it was far beyond her voice. We regret greatly that we should
                        have to criticise her, at it was so obvious that the did her. Vary beat in
                        “Caro nome,” and foiled hopelessly. Signor Nani was fairly good, be boa a
                        fine strong voice, and the part, on the whole, suite him ; but hit vibrato
                        is excessive and jarring at limes : a ban tone should, undoubtedly, be
                        something more than merely forcible. Still, his acting and singing were the
                        only redeeming features of the performance, and he deceived his encore in
                        Act IU. We cannot close this perfomance(it it fully borne out by the
                        attitude of the audience) without alluding to the for more excellent
                        performance of Rigvletto by tbe Verdi Theatre company. Signora Sricher is of
                        entree a phenomenon, and her rendering of “Caro nome” is unique: not only
                        did she exhibit a wonderful delicacy and clarity of tone, but she performed
                        the tour de fort of taking the final note in octavo I and that apparently
                        without effort. But the real reason for mentioning the Verdi Theatre is that
                        the other “principals" were to good. Signor Tomisani’s “La donna a mobile"
                        could not have been bettered for tone and phrasing: it was encored by an
                        audience who, we are certain, were distinctly prejudiced against him.
                        Signori Bad in and Baldelli were aa good and better than their own peers of
                        the Khedivial Theatre, as Rigolatto and the Bravo. And yet these three
                        gentlemen are probably quite unknown. We take this opportunity of informing
                        our reader* that it is quite possible the Verdi Theatre company will revisit
                        Cairo, after their stay in Alexandria, and we announce all who may not be
                        "abound” at the State Opera to go, just once or twice, to hear them. We are
                        certain they will confirm our opinion, and will not regret the expenditure
                        of half the sum exacted by the Khedivial Opera House, for an inferior
                        rendering at that 1 , Tristano e Ieotta was given for the second fame on
                        Thursday night Taking all things into consideration, it was a satisfactory
                        enough performance. Tristan himself and Hurrenaldo being both excellent,
                        though Tristan was hardly sufficiently audible in the 1st act To our
                        thinking Signore Pinto marred her part by excessive vibrato, though happily
                        this was less conspicuous in the 2nd act, which was the best part of the
                        performance. The Liebes Tod can hardly be pronounced a success: in foot,
                        Signora Pinto was scarcely audible, and indeed all through, though the
                        Orchestra was distinctly good, there was a certain neglect oi the proper
                        emphasis. The sailor’s chorus left much to be desired. However, we must not
                        apply German standards to an Italian company, to whom a Wagner opera is only
                        an incident in the announcement and so, keeping this foot in view, we can
                        pronounce’ the performance distinctly creditable.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHEPHEARD’S HOTEL</head>
                    <p>The grand cotillon ball at Shepheard’s Hotel last night was a splendid
                        success and reflected the greatest credit on the management of the hotel.
                        Among the many dinner parties given in the restaurant prior to the ball were
                        those of Mr. and Mrs. Scott-Dalgleish with a party of four, Count Sakakini
                        Pasha and party at six, Count Kocziedroczki, the Austro-Hungarian Diplomatic
                        Agent and Consul-general, and party of five, Baron de Wecker and friends,
                        Major Kenny Herbert and largo party, Major Lawson and party of four, Mr. D.
                        K. Reid and a party of eight, Mr. Meimareohi and a large party, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Geoffrey Milward and seven friends, Dr. and Mrs. Madden entertaining six
                        friends, Mr. A. G. Morton at the head of a table of four, Mr. Edgar Anderson
                        with a number of friends, and many others. The ball began at about 9.30
                        o’olook and lasted until an early hoar this morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS.</head>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo today by the “Ramoses": —Miss E A.
                        Atwater, Mrs. Geeland de la Bistarte, Mr. Blie Cattaui, Dr. Crawford, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Wm. D. Card, Mr. Augustus G. Cobh, Mr. Robert Clark, Miss M. C.
                        Crosfield, Mrs. I. N. and Master Ditten-hoefor, Mr. Newman Erb, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Chas. Bulhry, Mr. and Mrs. Karl von Eisenstaedter, Mr. and Mrs. Geo. H.
                        Fisher, Mite P. P. Fisher, Mr. Frederick Hurdle, Mr. and Mrs. Paul Haffter,
                        Mis* Heister, Mr. and Mrs. Nigel Hanbuiy, Miss Hornby, Min H*w-Innsoo, Mr.
                        H. M. Heister, Mr. M. T. Langhtin, Mr. F. D. and Miss A. F. Leoompte, Mr.
                        and Mrs. R. McLelland. Mr. and Mr*. C. W. and Min Melanaban, Mr., Mrs. and
                        Min d’Oudt Mooreghom, Miss L. Manley, Mrs. J. Miner, Min Jolia Manierre. Mr.
                        and Mr*. J. 0. MoCall, Mr. Samuel Price, Mrs. van den Peereboom, Mr. Tn Mrs.
                        Isabella and Min Maria Quagliotti, Mr. Gilbert A. Reoh, Mr. W. Henry Rider,
                        Mr. Isaac Sharp, Mr. H. Soamee, Min Lacre Sober, Miss Spalding, Mr. and Mr*.
                        R.P. Sullivan, Mines Snnn and Prenoes E. 8ullivan, Dr. Jerome and Mrs.
                        Stonborongh, Mr. and Mrs. Snmmerfield. Mr. and Mr*. C. 8. 8pear, Mrs. D.
                        Spence. Mr. and Mrs. Geo. a Tracey, Mrs. Leon van de Waive de Voraaclero,
                        Mr. Morris Leon, Mr.Wilbur, Mr. J.B, WObw(Jar.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Dalhourie entertained a party at dinner at the Savoy Rcteurent
                        yesterday evening. The guests including Sir WU-ham E Garetin, Capt. the Hoc
                        Stanley the Hon. and Mrs. 0. Stanley, etc. Mr. and lira. Coat* also had a
                        large party at dinner, among their guests being Count and Countess Wedal.
                        Among the passengers who arrived at Alexandria yesterday by Alex
                        “Hohensollern" were the Chamberlain to the Tsar, Baron L de Knorring, Count
                        and Countess da Hohenstein. The Marquis de Jacome Correa, Qeherel O’Connor,
                        Countess Care Aroim.-and a number of others whose names will be found in the
                        list of passengers in another column. Sir Thomas Lipton is leaving Cairo
                        today. Sir Thomas has been staying at the Savoy Hotel since last Tuesday,
                        and was in the Empress Eugenie’s party. The suite of the Empress Eugenia
                        contains two famous names in Napoleonic history. The Princess de la Moekowa
                        comes of the family of Napoleon’s great Marshal Ney, who received the title
                        of Prince of Moekowa for the part he played in the Battle of Borodino, which
                        was waged in the valley of the Kolotta, an affluent of the Moekowa. The
                        present head of the house of Ney is the Duke. Mile de Baasano, another of
                        the ex Empress’s suite, belongs to the dneal family of Bassano, the dukedom
                        having been bestowed in 190S on Maret, who was subsequently (1811-1814)
                        Minister of Foreign Affaire. Mr. Waldorf Astor is expected at the 8avof
                        Hotel next Tuesday. Sir Robert and Lady Harvey left the Savoy. Hotel
                        yesterday evening for Upper Egypt Mr. Joseph Walton, M.P., left for England
                        today by the. P. 0. steamer. Mr. Walton spent some time at the Savoy Hotel,
                        Cairo, and was also as for aa Khartoum. ^ ’ Yesterday's arrivals at the
                        8avoy Hotel include Baron von Knoring, Major General Sir Stanley, Clark,
                        Marches di Rudjni, Mr. A. a Horatmann, Mr. A. W. Sohmitx, Mr. Justice and
                        Mrs. Simpeon,Capt and Mia. H.C. French. Sir William Garetin is preparing for
                        a journey to the Sudan early in February. Lady Blomfield second musical
                        party took place yesterday afternoon and crowded with her friends of all
                        nationalities gathered to' hear the musical fore provided by her. We
                        announced amongst some 200 guests H- E the Governor of Alexandria,
                        Brig.-Geueroi Bullock, C.B, Col. McCracken and the offioers of the Royal
                        Berts, Mme. Girard, M» Gould, Baroness von HumboldtDacliroeden, Saba Pasha
                        and Miss Saba, Peake Key, Msjor Hopkinaon and the Hon. Mrs. Hopkinaon, Mrs.
                        Borchgrevink, Mrs. Sidney Carver, Mrs. Mantell, Mrs. Preston, Major and Mrs.
                        Gamble, (Jo un teas Zinnia, -Barones* Jacques de Menaaoe, Mr*. Chats way,
                        Mme. Emmanuel Zervudaehi, Mme George* Zervudachi, Mme. Michel Sinodino, Mare
                        Salvago, Mme. Miohel Salvago, Baron and Baroness Alfred de Menaaoe, Dr. uid
                        Mm# Brescia, Rev. Reginald Rynd, Rev. Ronald Wonnell, Mrs. Strickland, Mr
                        and Mrs. G. Williams, Mr. and Mrs. Adamson, etc. Tbe programme of 14 items
                        was varied and interesting and the Queen of Song of these porta, Mme.
                        Briend, outshone benefit and had to sing several gems out of her extensive
                        repertoire after the programme had been gone through, to satisfy her
                        enthusiastic admirers. Mr. H. Scott-Leslie has arrived at Lax or. We are
                        pleased to announce the- birth of a son to Mr. and Mrs. A. J. Cboremi. Both
                        mother and child are progressing The Horn Grevflle Nugent and Mrs: Nugent
                        are staying at the 8avoy Hotel, Luxor. Among other visitors at that hotel we
                        notice i Mr. and Mrs. Tamblyn, Mr. H. Allen, Mr. Murphy, Dr. Malvani, Mr.
                        and Miss Trefogli, Mr. Rova, Mr. M. Dahl, Mr. and Mrs. Hurl bat, Mrs. and
                        Miss Haldane, Mr. R. H. Hompson, Mrs. Napier Sturt, Mr. Wild* Mrs. Bogotioa,
                        Mr. and Mias Fagodios, Mr. and Mrs. Dr. 8tonic, Mia* Beresford, Mrs. Hugh
                        8mith, Copt, and Mrs. Baring, Ccmte de Malvezxi, Mr. Duval Paul, Mrs. M. da
                        la MaasoolAre, Mr. Alex. Sarrortianou. Mr. W. Actoo-Adams and Miss Edith
                        Collins are among the visitor* at GhezirSh Palace. Among the latest arrivals
                        at the Eastern. Exchange Hotel, Port 8aid, are Mia# 0. N. Rayne, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Botleazor, Mr. J. K Snelus, Mr. D. Lee, Mr. G. H. Malcolm, Hhu K J.
                        Cozed, Mrs. B. Babcock, Mr. KDawaon, Mr. A. Roraoni, Mr. M. De Uvalette, Mr.
                        M. Morduoovitcb, Mr. P. Harm, Capt Nicholson, Rev. and Mrs. P. J. Anderson,
                        Mr. K Jackson, Mr. W. Jackson, Mr. and Mrs. C. Wibberly and daughter, Mr. M.
                        Summer.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
