<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

<p>Epidemics—Typbus has broken out in the Assiout district and diphtheria in the Kous district.</p>

<p>The Garrisons of Crete and Cyprus will in future be furnished and managed from Egypt instead of from Malta.</p>

<p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in Zeitonn at daybreak to-morrow will be poisoned by the police.</p>

<p>New Pharmascists.— Messrs. Spyridon Tracadas and Jean Despotas have been authorized to follow the profession of pharmacist in Egypt.
</p>
<p>Public Debt Commission.—The summer quarters of the Public-Debt Commission from
June 1 will be in the Credit Lyonnais building, Alexandria.
</p>
<p>A Prince on Poetry.—This evening Prince Haidar Pasha will give a lecture at the New
Khedivial Hotel on the subject of poetry. The lecture will begin at 9.15 p.m.
</p>
<p>Suez Canal.—7 vessels.passed through the Canal on the 22nd inst. 5 of which were
British, 1 French, 1 Austrian. The receipts for the day were frs. 188,929.53, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 6,806,633.69. •
</p>
<p>Mahmoudieh Canal. — Barge traffic in the Mahmoudieh Canal will be stopped between the Kafr-Dawar and Alexandria locks, during the repairing and the repainting of those works from the 10th to the 30th June.
</p>
<p>The Capitulations.— A very interesting article on the Capitulations in Egypt from a
French print of view appears in the “Journal des Debats.” The main features of the article are reproduced on page 4 of today’s issue.
</p>
<p>Mohamed Aly Centenary.—The Khedive has signified to Prince Said Halim that he will be pleaded to be patron of the Mohamed Aly Educational Missions. The Princes Mohamed Bey Ibrahim and Omar Pasha Toussoun have each subscribed. L.E. 1,000 to this object.
</p>
<p>Mohamed Aly Square Outrage.—The Alexandria police arrested yesterday afternoon a Berberee of the name of Karar Aly El-Din, who is charged with having attempted to
assassinate the bowab of St. Mark's Small Building in Mohamed Aly-square yesterday
morning.</p>

<p>The Telegraph Wanted.—A correspondent writes pointing out that although Akhmim is one of the largest cities in Egypt, noted for its manufacturing industries,and has a population of about 45,000 souls, it possesses no telegraphic communication with the outside world. The business men of the town, he adds, feel the greater need of telegraphic connection with other cities and hope that in the near future the authorities will open an office there.
</p>
<p>Corporation of Western Egypt,Limited.— Permission has been given to the corporation
by the Egyptian Government to investigate the ancient Roman irrigation channels to the north of the Khargeh Oases. The district referred to is that recently visited by the official whose report thereon we published in our columns on the 20th inst, and runs from a point about 20 miles north of Khargeh town and 5 miles north of Ain el Hagar, from which a point it extends northwards to the extreme northern limit of the Oases of Khargeh.
</p>
<p>Alderson’s Garden. — Empire Day was celebrated at Mr.Alderson's Garden by a hockey match on skates and other amusements, finally ending up in a fine display of fireworks, in the hockey match Red (W. Tookey, H. Tookey and Anastas), defeated Blue (Miss A. Scherater, Townsend, and Collier) by 6 to 3, an exciting game being witnessed by a large crowd. The band of the 2nd R. Berks Regiment was, by kind permission of tho commanding officer, present and rendered a selection of music during the afternoon.
</p>
<p>Reuter's Telegram.—The report for 1904 states that the balance for distribution amounts to £4,915, including' £137 brought forward. The directors declare a dividend of 4s per share, or 2/1/2 per cent, making a total distribution of 5 per cent, for the year, the same as for several years past, and leaving £179 to be carried forward. A provisional agreement with the managing director for securing his services for a further period of twelve years will be submitted for confirmation by the shareholders. Dividend warrants will be payable on the 3rd of June.
</p>
<p>Motor Fire Engines.— We notice with interest the extraordinary development of the
motor fire engine that is taking place all over the world as the following list of orders Messrs. Merryweather & Sons, Limited, have recently secured shows. The advantages of the motor over horse-drawn engines is so apparent that there seems little doubt but that in time it will completely supercede them:— Penarth. S. Wales motor steam fire engine, 500 gallons capacity. Johannesburg, S. Africa, motor steam
fire engine. 500 gallons capacity; Aberdeen, Scotland, petrol motor hose tender; Melbourne Victoria, petrol motor fire engine, 450 gallons capacity and petrol motor chemical fire engine, with 2 cylinders of a combined capacity of 70 gallons; Rosario, Argentine, combined petrol fire pump, chemical fire engine, escape and tender petrol motor hose tender, and reel; Callao, Chili, petrol motor fire engine, 300 gallons capacity.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>NEW EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>

<head>IMPORTANT FLOTATION.</head>

<head>"EGYPT, LIMITED.”</head>

<p>Among the forthcoming Egyptian flotations there is one very important company, the prospectus of which will soon be set before the public. The company will be known by the comprehensive and attractive title of "Egypt, Limited." One of the advantages of this name is that the company will not be confused in the minds of the investors with the mass of other new companies whose founders have not shown any originality in their nomenclature. Egypt, Limited, is to have a capital of £250,000 with power to increase to a million. The London board of directors is composed of a number of business men, well-known in the world of commerce and finance. These include Mr. Callender, of telegraph and construction fame, whose products are well known hero, Mr. J. A. H. Drought, chairman of the United Lankat Plantations Company, which is one of the favorite industrial securities is the London market, Mr. John Waddington, the founder of Egyptian Options, and Mr. Doolette, chairman of the Oroya Brownhill Co., Limited, one of the premier Australian mining securities on the London market. One or two other well-known names will, it is understood, also appear on the prospectus. The entire capital has been guaranteed both in London and Egypt unlike the majority of companies having advisory boards here, the Egyptian directors,whose names we will announce shortly, will be represented by a delegation on the London board, and in this way will be able to exercise a salutary check on the London board in their Egyptian investments. The chief object of the company will be mortgage business, the
purchase and resale of land, the development of building estates, and the promotion and guaranteeing of new Egyptian enterprises. With regard to the last object Egypt, Limited, intends to promote another Egyptian mortgage company, which has already been guaranteed to the extent of over a million pounds sterling. It is needless to point out that the promotion profits of the parent company will b considerable.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

<p>Prince Ibrahim Pasha Halim, Latif Pasha Selim, and De Martino Pasha embarked for Europe yesterday by the North German Lloyd steamer.
</p>
<p>Sir Wm. and Lady Willcocks were among the passengers who left for Constantinople
yesterday by the S.S. "Prince Abbas.”
</p>
<p>Rear-Admiral W. West Hamilton, the new second in command of the China Station, who
is proceeding to the Far East, is arriving at Port Said this week by the P. and O. steamer “Marmora,” from Marseilles, accompanied by Captain the Hon. R. F. Boyle.
</p>
<p>Mgr. Haik, Maronite Patriarch of Bekerka, arrived at Alexandria this morning from Syria by the Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Congo." His Holinoss was received on disembarking by the Governor of Alexandria, the French vice-consul, and a large number of Maronite notables, residing at Alexandria and Cairo. The Quay Police, under Bimbashi Randall, formed a guard of honor for the distinguished prolate.
</p>
<p>Mr. Vincent Corbett, Financial Adviser, is leaving for Europe on Wednesday week.
</p>
<p>Dixon Bey arrived in Cairo on Tuesday and is stopping at Shepheard’s Hotel.
</p>
<p>We greatly regret to hear of the serious illness of Dr. Hayes, quarantine medical officer at Suez, who is suffering from meningitis.
</p>
<p>Mr. Alfred Lambart has been provisionally appointed secretary to the Under Secretary of State for Public Works.
</p>
<p>It is stated that in consequence of a difference of opinion with the director of Khedivial School of Law, Omar Bey Loutfy, the able native sub-director of that school, has sent in his resignation.	.
</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. Charlws Baehler have left
Cairo for Europe.
</p>
<p>We regret to state that Miss Nungovich, eldest daughter of Nungovich Bey, has had an attack of typhoid at Como. Her father and mother have left Cairo to join their sick
daughter.
</p>
<p>The marriage of Mr. Albert Cattaoui, son of M. and Mme. Joseph Cattaoui Bey was
celebrated on Tuesday afternoon at Cattaoui Bey's house in Cairo.
</p>
<p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice Mr. Eynard Edde
and family, Mr. Sigel, Mr, Hocart, Mr. and Mme. Lorderau, Mr. Curien, Mr. E. H. D
Nicolls, Mr. E. Delaval Cobham, Mr. A. Beer Mr. E. Ponzo, Mr. Martin de la Tour, Mrs.
Tattu, Mr. A. S. Slater, Mr. Petcovich, Mr. A. Monnerat, Mr. T. H. Russel, Messrs. Cassal, Crookshank Pasha, Nungovich Bey, Col. Magill, Major Hardy.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>ALEXANDRIA</head>

<head>ARCHAEOLOGICAL SOCIETY.</head>

<head>REPORT FOR 1904-1905.</head>

<p>Dr. Breccis, in his very interesting report, announces some very satisfactory results of the progress of the above society. The appereance of the Bulletins Nos. 6 and 7 have gained the esteem of other learned societies to such an extent that seventeen scientific associations have offered to make exchanges with that of the A. A. S., In this way its library will grow rapidly ; it already contains many important works. Several learned men connected with European Universities and Museums have promised to write articles for the Bulletin of the A. A. S. which will greatly help Dr. Breccia in bringing out a regular quarterly review. In answer to a request made by the last general meeting Dr. Breccia inaugurated a series of lectures at the Popular University on archeological subjects, two of which have been given already, one on
“The Recent Discoveries in Crete and Mycaenian Civilisation," and the other on “Greek and Arab Civilization in Sicily,” both illustrated with limelight views. They were so well attended that Dr. Breccia feels encouraged to continue the series in the Museum itself, where his audience can see the objects of interest to which he will refer. The excavations carried out at the expense of the A. S. S. Fund westt of the Victoria College were of great interest, but were unavoidably interrupted. The things, however, discovered there will be treated of in the next Bulletin in an article by Simond Bey and Dr. Breccia. The excavations at Hadra, in the Eastern Necropolis, also proved to be important as a rich series of loculi of the Ptolemaic period were discovered, the doors of which were painted in the style of that period in different colours and in some instances with the addition of inscriptions. Notwithstanding the friability of the stone several of those doors have been safely removed to the Museum. The attention of savants has been attracted lately to the connection between the Alexandria tomb paintings and those known as Pompeian and this similarity is strikingly noticeable in these tomb-doors lately found at Gabbari. Funeral urns and fragments of statuettes known, as Tanagrae were also found in the same place.
Excavations under the auspices of the Museum Committee have been also undertaken at Chatby in what has proved to be a Necropolis of tho 1st Ptoleinaic period, the results of which will be found in a separate notice in the next Bulletin, Members of the society meanwhile are invited to visit the Museum and see these latest discoveries. Excursions-having been proposed by the committee and approved of by the general meeting, the first come off on 17th April last, when the members went in great numbers to Aboukir to visit the mosaics discovered by H. H. Prince Omar Toussoun on his property and who has kindly offered them to the society. This excoursion was most successful and much appreciated by all who took part in it, and it is proposed to continue them from time to time. Dr. Schiess Bey, president of the Museum Committee, has invited members to promenade lectures in the Museum— where the conservator will hold peripatetic discourses. An excursion to Chalby will be organized later on with the approval of the general assembly, also to Taposiris Magna, Mariout, etc. H. H. Prince Omar Toussoun, having always taken a keen interest in the work of the A.A.S., was invited by the committee to become their honorary president, which he has graciously agreed to do, and presided at the last committee meeting. The dedicatory tablet to the memory of the late conservator, Dr. Botti, is not yet ready, but it is hoped that it will shortly be finished, so that the ceremony which has been for some time planned can then take place, i.e., of removing the remains of the learned professor and placing them in an ancient sarcophagus as a suitable monument. It was proposed by Simond Bey and Dr. Schiess Bey that Professor
Maspero should be begged by the A. A. S. to allow them to have two of the obelisks lying about amongst the rains of San presented to the city of Alexandria, and the Municipality promises to pay the cost of transport. Many
now members have joined lately, especially since the excursion to Aboukir, and donations have been received from Artin Pasha, Judge Batcheller, and others.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>

<p>The Khedive paid a visit this morning to the Mosque of Abou el-Abbas, where his
Highness was received by a large number of Ulema and native notables. The pupils of the mosque and the teaching staffs proceeded to Ras el-Tin Palace.
</p>
<p>The Khedive embarked on the Austrian Lloyd S.S. “Amphitrite" at 2 p.m. today for Constantinople accompanied by H. H. the Khedivah, the Prince and Princesses, besides Zeki Pasha and several other officials of the Khedevial household.
</p>
<p>Miralai Watson Bey, his Highness’s aide-de-camp, leaves to-morrow direct for London by the Messageries Maritimes steamer. Liwa Thurneyssen Pasha will follow, travelling
direct to London.</p>

<p>The Khedive will leave Constantinople on the 5th or 6th June by the Orient Express,
and is due in London on the 12th June to attend the Royal marriage three days afterwards.</p>

<p>His Highness will be the guest of the King
at Windsor Castle up to the 19th June.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
<p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
<p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect.</p>
<p>Very moderate charges. Bulkily is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors from Cairo Alight at Bidi Gaber Station.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CLEVER HASHISH SEIZURE.</head>

<head>1,070 KILOS OF THE DRUG FOUND.</head>

<p>A clever seizure of smuggled hashish was effected by a Coastguard patrol on Monday
at a point on the coast about 10 kilometers west of Rosetta lighthouse.</p>
<p>The hashish, which weighed no less than 1070 kilos and was packed in 16 sacks, had been landed on the previous evening by a blockade runner, and removed to its place of hiding, it evidently being the intention of the smuggler to take tho drug away into the interior the following night.
</p>
<p>Their intentions, however, were frustrated by the Coastguard patrol, consisting of one onbashi (corporal) and a tracker. Early on Monday morning the patrol found traces of the landing which had been made near a road much used by fishermen leading from the sea to Bossili. The patrol followed tire tracks and eventually,after some hours’ search, came to some sand dunes, wherein the hashish had been buried.
</p>
<p>Judging by the tracks on the sand, four camels were used to transport the hashish from the seashore, and the escort consisted of twenty men, one of whom was on horseback.
</p>
<p>The hashish seised is valued at something like £2,400. It will, in accordance with custom, be entirely destroyed. The lucky onbashi and his tracker come into a sum of over £100 as prize money for their seizure.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>QUARANTINE.</head>

<p>Quarantine restrictions m against plague are now applied to arrivals in Egyptian ports from Bahrain.
</p>
<p>A telegram from Constantinople states that five days’ quarantine, disinfection, and “deratisation" have been imposed on arrivals there from Bahrein.
</p>
<p>The telegram adds that measures against the passage through the Suez Canal of pilgrim
vessels have been suppressed.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>KHEDIVE AND BIBLE SOCIETY.</head>

<p>The Khedive has accepted a copy of an Arabic Bible, in three volumes, from the British
and Foreign Bible Society, as a memento of its centenary. His Highness, on receiving the presentation, expressed a hope that the society not with every facility for its work in this country, and emphasised his appreciation of the good being effected through its agency. His Highness has forwarded a large autographed portrait of himself to tho Bible-house in London.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>A. L. M. & D. S.</head>

<p>As we briefly stated in our issue of yesterday, Tuesday’s concert of the Alexandria
Literary, Musical & Dramatic Society was a great success. The programme was a long
and interesting one, and there was not a dull moment from beginning to end. It opened with an “andante maestoso" on the piano for four hands, excellentiy played by Misses
Giorgina and Gemma Fiteni, two little mites, who, with their equally small sister, Alice, delighted the audience with two more selections and an encore. We found them best in Suppe’s “onverture moderato" (paragraph 3), where they showed clever mechanism and a perfect understanding of the use of the pedal. Considering that the piano was anything but easy to play on, their performance was highly commendable. Miss Euna Lang Anderson,whose talent is not unknown to A.L.M & D.S. audiences, contributed two violin solos, and for her exquisite execution of Mariani’s “L’Abandono" secured a well deserved encore when she gave a spirited rendering of “Perpetuo Mobile." Miss MunGavin was in splendid voice and sang M. E. Dandridge’s
“One Flower” with great feeling and effect, her rendering of "My Heart is Weary"
from Nadeschda, in the second part, being likewise given in her usual finished style.
Mrs. F. Cree, who contributed two items, Godard’s "Jo ne veux pas d’autres choses” and Brahm's “Chansons Tziganes" (No 1), was also in good voice and fully maintained the reputation she has already gained as one of our host singers. Miss Helene Lulos, a young and promising pianist, showed to great advantage in Beethoven's “Adagio grazioso” and Liazt's well-known“Rhapsodie Hengroise.” Albeit having to deal with a most unsympathetic keyboard she played the latter number with all due softness and fully interpreted the spirit of the great composer. Mr. L.A. Johnson gave two selections from the Indian Lore Lyrics, (a) “The Temple Bells” and (b) "When
I wake," as well as“The Lute Player”(Allitsen), all of which he rendered with great taste and feeling. Mr. P. Byrne was also very successful in his two numbers, ‘The Slave Song” (Teresa del Riego) and “Queen of the Roses," from “Haddon Hall,” in the latter of which he appeared to greatest advantage. The accompanists to the singers were Mrs. MunGavin, Mme Foscolo, Miss Gibson, and M. Felix.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>

<p>The first small dance of the season will be given at the Casino on Saturday next. Following is the menu of the dinner to be served that evening:—
Fooubm rapcir
RocRw 4afotofTO* da IBwW*
SSmXm
MWaajbWca</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BIG DEAL IN CAIRO.</head>

<head>BUSINESS BOUGHT FOR £70,000.</head>
<p>A most important business transaction has
just taken place in Cairo whereby one of the largest retail drapery establishments in the Capital has changed hands. The vendors are Messrs. S. and S. Sednaoui, the very large Jewish firm of drapers in the Mousky, whose principals are Selim Bey Sednaoui and Mr. Samaan Sednaoui, and the puechasers are a new English limited liability company, which is being promoted for the purpose. The good will alone has been disposed, of for £70,000! Selim Bey Sednaoui will remain as director of
the business.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CAIRO'S WATER SUPPLY.</head>

<p>In regard to the complaints of a correspondent concerning the water supply of Cairo, which appeared in our issue of Tuesday, we find on making enquiries that the Water Company have for the last 15 days, pumped each day 2.000m.c. more water than daring tire corresponding days of last year. They have pumped with all their engines during 24 hours of each day. The enormous increase in consumption and the abnormal wave of heat can alone account for it but that the town has had the water the company say there is no doubt. On Sunday, part of the filtered supply was out off, as they were
connecting to their new works, but this was only for a few hours, after which the service was resumed.
</p>
<p>The company havo spent nearly £100,000 on their new installation during the last 18
months. This will come into work early next month, to assist the old installation, which will gradually be done away with.
</p>
<p>As regards ice, the company state that the price is never more than P.T. 3.5 the block, whatever the demand. Probably people who buy from Arabs in the street have to pay what the latter choose to ask.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.</head>

<p>The following counsel hare been engaged for the Ghirgeh scandal case, which is coming
before the Assiont Tribunal.
</p>
<p>Sawiris Eff. Mikhail for Kamil Eff. Wassif, Wekil of the Dairah. Nasr ed Din Bey Zaghloul and Ahmed Eff. Abdul Latif, for the Moudir.
</p>
<p>The Parquet will be represented by About Futuh Bey. The Judges appointed to try the
Case are Mohamed Bey Saleh, President of the Court, and Judges Hassan Bey Husny and
Abdul Aziz Bey Mohamed.
</p>
<p>The accused received tire "document d’acusation" six days ago and the sitting is
for the 4th June.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE ABYSSINIAN MISSION..</head>

<p>Two scientific members of the German Mission to Abyssinia, Messrs. Boch and Fleming, arrived at Alexandria from Cairo yesterday en route for Berlin. The other members
of the mission are due from Massowah towards the end of the mouth.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

<p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Senegal" arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria yesterday morning.
</p>
<p>The Westcott S.S. "Orestes" arrived here on Wednesday afternoon from Antwerp, London, and Malta with general cargo.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head>

<p>By kind permission of Major C. J. L Davidson, D.S.O., commanding, and officers 2nd
Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the band will perform the following selection of music in the Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Friday) at 9 p.m.
< aao*^«CUI.rav-SfJ>tCtU'r-S°1,1'4'
I Valaetiaa—Stout—Ooasod.
V Americanrk«tcb	Tui«—a-K*mlaa
Rofrlmeolai March.
Kbadlrlal Anlham.
God Caro ih. Kin*.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>TYROL -</head>
<p>Weissenstein Castle 341 ft. First-class private hotel near Windisch-Matrei; Station, Lienx (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September. Prospectuses and photographs, " Egyptian Gazette " office, Cairo.
25363 48*47</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA</head>

<p>Ha Urthalhnj bow Mm Km* tnd Inland b
u	- woo,
tuns safari. Hariri* UsU. Madam mniUUm,' Bomj
upsri,aloa* to *■> and firdOBS.	^</p>
</div>
<div type="item"><head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer,
& HOTEL COMPANY.</head>
<p>R!«R HUKPOflT Of 00008 iETWHI AUXAIOfflA A OAIBO
Throw Sailing* o-Wook.
Artmli at <Ii««ii4i Is
ALEXAMtU MME* WAR (HOUSE C*. IB.
to so*</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BECK A CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
<p>O	SMI ■ .laia^fTWia	^ Hs—« ■*■>!■ Firm</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>

<p>(From Our Financial Correspondent).</p>

<p>London, May 19.
</p>
<p>Things financial, like the Russian fleets,are “fighting shy”. Rumours, like phantom torpedo boats, give pause every few hours and the very mention of political complications of any kind is enough to make the few buyers turn tall. Until doubt is dispelled all will be nervous tension and paralysis. Of this state of things all are tired, and ask “how long can we bear this strain?
</p>
<p>Markets are still idle and awaiting events. The break at the end of last account cleared out, to a very large extent, any weak bull element which existed, and consequently the present position should be more healthy. The tendency is already firmer, and any good news would cause a sharp recovery in prices.
</p>
<p>As to the Egyptian market, prices there keep quietly steady, but without feature. Salt and 8oda are eerier at 33s. and Delta Preterenoe have gone back a shade to 13. Bank shares are firm. The latest new issue, the North Egypt Land Company,is quoted at 1/8 premium, and should the proposed irrigation scheme be sanctioned and the company’s application for the extension of the Nubarieh Canal be acceded to by the Egyptian Government, there ought to be a good future for the shares, of which 100,000 £1 shares out of 230,000 are now offered at par.
</p>
<p>The mining section is still weak from sheer want of interest. Prices continue to sag away, and ought certainly to be worth attention for looking up. Egyptians are inclined to be firmer, Nile Valley Block “E" attracting attention on the developments reported from the Dongola
Concession, a reef having been struck assaying, in the east shaft, 12 dwts. over 2ft. 3ins, and in the west shaft 1oz. over 1ft. Egyptian mines are also being bought at their present low level. Um Rus at just over £1 and Nile Valleys at 1/1/6/1/8 look really cheap.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>

<head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>

<head>REGATTA</head>

<p>The following is the result of yesterday's
regatta.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>Class I</head>
<p>Boat	Start	Finish Sailed by
1	Jinny	2.53.10	not taken. T. McClure
2 Banshee	3.06.17	4.47.35 S. Doriing
3 Agamy	3.09.25	4.48.10 Mr. Ravelli
  Celtic 2.56.10 4.48.11 Capt P. Evans
  Leman 3.02.08 4.49.25 Mr. de Planta
  Minnie 2.50.15 4.50.45 N.W.de Couroy
  Coot	2.57.05	4.33.22 Mr. Blagden</p>

<head>Class II</head>
<p>Boat	Start	Piniih Sailed by
1	Most	3.26.43	3.08.10 Mr. Fransis
2	St. George 3.26.25 3.08.40- Major Festham
3	Calypso 3.34.11 3.10.12 Mr. O. Werner
	Gumrook 3.25.12 5.11.00 Mr. Macanlay
	Shamrock 3.24.24 3.11.25 Mr. E. Gentilli
	Jessica 3.16.18 3.13.00 Grafton Bey
	Akraba 3.18.40 3.13.11 Sagh. Phillips
	Ironie	gave up	P. Girard</p>

<p>The wind was light from the N. In Class I the “Celtic”. was disqualified, for when on the port tack forcing the "Agamy” (on the starboard tack) to bear away to avoid a collision.
</p>
<p>The handicaps are now beginning to suit the different boats, as in Class I. 5 boats came in within 3 minutes, and in Class II. 7 boats
in 7 minutes. Next week will be the last of a series of three races only for the prize this time. In future the prizes will be given monthly for the highest number of points scored during the regattas of that month. This of course is in addition to the small tokens which are bring given weekly to the winner in each class. These have not yet strived from Europe.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>HORSE SHOW.</head>

<p>The entries for the Horse Show to be held at the Trotter Egyptian classe on the 30th
inst. We are requested to state that anyone who wishes to engage a table for lunch most inform the secretary of the Trotter Egyptian, Velodrome, Rond Point, not later than 1st June.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head>

<p>Members of the club will meet on the Marina on Saturday next at 3.30 p.m.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>

<p>(Aukmrikui à midi té émit)</p>

<p>S i l'on excepte nn mouvement restreint sur la Daira, la Banque Nationale et l’Agricole, le marché a été absolument calme at les tranasotions nulles.
</p>
<p>Vers la fin on a fait circuler à la Bourse une rumeur suivant laquelle la flotte japonaise enrait subi une défaite. Ce bruit, d’ailleurs sans fondement officiel a produit un certain-malaise.
</p>
<p>En hausse la Banque Nationale de 27 1/2 a 27 9/16, la Béhéra de 43 5/8 a 43 3/4, la Daira de 28 15/16 a 29 1/16, la Salt & Soda de 32/6 a 33 et les Privilégiées Tramways de 133 a 133 3/4
</p>
<p>Par contre, la Banque d'Athènes fléchit dé 123 1/4 a 121 1/2 et la Delta Light de 13 3/16 a 13 1/8.
</p>
<p>Les autres valeurs ont été complètement delsissaes.</p></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

