<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Cassandra Frederick</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-29">November 29, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-13">May 13, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7197] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, MAY 13, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WAR. JAPS RESUME DECISIVE OFFENSIVE.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 12. Several unimportant engagements are report- ed from
                        Manchuria. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 12. General Linievitch telegraphs on the 11th inst. that
                        the enemy resumed a decisive offen- sive against our right flank, but on the
                        7th inst. was repulsed (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE VLADIVOSTOK CRUISERS.</head>
                    <dateline>Tokio, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>It is confirmed that the Vladivostok cruisers "Rossia" and “Gromoboi”
                        appeared off Aomori on the 9th inst. Apparently they have not captured any
                        Japanese coasters. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW RUSSIAN WARSHIPS.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The new battleship “Andrei Peroswanni" and the gunboat “Chiwinez" were
                        launched here yesterday. The keel of the gunboat “Gilyak” has been laid.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE’S NEUTRALITY.</head>
                    <dateline>Tokio, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>France’s assurances have calmed popular feeling. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE OF RUSSIA. A SOP TO THE PEASANTS.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>With a view to allaying the agitation among the peasants the Russian
                        Government has prepared a scheme enabling them to acquire leases of Crown
                        lands, aggregating 250,000,000 acres, on the easiest terms. (R)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MR. BALFOUR’S SPEECH. REGARDED AS EPOCH-MAKING</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The newspapers regard Mr. Ballour’s declara- tions as epoch-making, showing
                        as they do for the first time that the whole scheme of Impe- rial defence
                        has been maturely weighed and de- termined upon by the Supreme Council,
                        which is superior to party. The view that the inva- sion of Britain is
                        impracticable is based on Lord Roberts's opinion that a minimum of 70,000
                        invaders would be requisite for the purpose. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ENTENTE CORDIALE. FRENCH FLEET’S VISIT.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The French fleet will visit Portsmouth from the 7th to the 13th August.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MISSION TO PERSIA.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>According to a telegram received here from Teheran on the 11th inst., Mr.
                        MacMahon’s mission has completed its labours and was leaving Persia in a few
                        days. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY AND MOROCCO.</head>
                    <dateline>Tangier, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The German commercial mission will pro- ceed to Fez to-day in order to
                        examine the commercial possibilities and the situation. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DOUBLING OF ITALIAN NAVY.</head>
                    <dateline>Rome, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The Minister of Marine has introduced a Bill providing for the doubling of
                        the Navy by 1908 and 1909. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CRETAN UNION IMPOSSIBLE.</head>
                    <dateline>Rome, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>Sig. Tittoni stated in the Chamber of Deputies that the annexation of Crete
                        to Greece was impossible owing to the effect it would have in the Balkans.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUICIDE AT KOREAN LEGATION, LONDON.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>Yi-Han-Sung, Korean charge d’affaires here, committed suicide this morning by
                        hanging himself at the Legation. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHICAGO EXPRESS COLLISION.</head>
                    <dateline>New York, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>There are 300 killed and injured at Snyder and 90 at Harrisburg.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 12.</dateline>
                    <p>Gloucestershire beat Middlesex by 9 wickets. Lancashire beat Warwickshire by
                        8 wickets. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Madhouse for Aboukir</head>
                        <p>According to the native Press, the Government intends to erect a lunatic
                            asylum at Aboukir.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Public Debt Commission</head>
                        <p>The staff of the Public Debt Commission will leave Cairo on the 1st June
                            to take up their summer quar- ters at Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fire at Simbellawen</head>
                        <p>A ginning factory at Siwbellawon, belonging to Ibrahim Adrai &amp; Co.,
                            has been burnt down. The loss is estimated at £5,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>8 vessels passed through the Canal on the 10th inst., 7 being British
                            and 1 German. The receipts for the day were frs. 207,531.65, making the
                            total from the 1st inst. frs. 3,073.675.19.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>The production of Saturnino Farandola last night was a huge spectacular
                            success. The piece will be repeated this evening. A matinee at reduced
                            prices will be given to-morrow afternoon.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Siwa Oasis</head>
                        <p>Some misunderstanding has arisen between the mamour of the Oasis of Siwa
                            and the natives there. The Ministry of the Interior has despatched a
                            commission thither to enquire into the matter.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal Co</head>
                        <p>M. Tillier, head of the transit service of the Suez Canal Company, is
                            about to retire on pension. Count de Serionne has chosen his successor
                            from among the pilots at present employed by the company.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ibrahiumieh Ploughing Company</head>
                        <p>Owing to the fact that the banks are closed to-day the date of closing of
                            the subscription list of the Ibrahimieh Ploughing Company has had to be
                            postponed from the 14th to the 16th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Government Printing Works</head>
                        <p>The Go- vernment has authorised Chelu Bey, director of the Government
                            Printing Works, to proceed to Europe to enquire into the latest
                            inventions and improvements in the art of printing with a view to
                            ameliorating the printing depart- ment.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports</head>
                        <p>From January 1 to May 11, 293,292 tons of coal were imported into Egypt
                            The Welsh districts sent 155,079 tons, Newcastle 68,434, the Scotch
                            districts 38,670, Yorkshire 17,466, and other districts 13,643 tons.
                            During the same period of 1904 382,891 tons were imported.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Property at Cairo</head>
                        <p>An instance of te rise in the value of real property in the neighbourhood
                            of Cairo was exemplified lately when the owner of two feddans at
                            Shoubra, which had been purchased twelve years ago for £400 per feddan,
                            was recently offered £7,500 per feddan for the same property.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>is waking up from its winter torpor, and already numbers of people are
                            to be soon enjoying the cool breezes out there. We may remind our
                            readers of the first ball of the season, which takes place on Saturday
                            next. The following day the first Sunday concert of the season will be
                            given at 10a.m.on the verandah.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Sohag Sensation</head>
                        <p>A young native girl of Sohag, belonging to a well-known family there, was
                            kidnapped two days ago on the eve of her marriage night together with
                            one of her relations. It is believed that the sons of a neighbouring
                            omdeh are concerned in the affair. The whereabouts of the girl are still
                            unknown.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Securities Investment List</head>
                        <p>Messrs. Reid and Barnard, the well-known stock and share brokers of
                            Alexandria and Cairo, have published a new edition of their useful
                            Egyptian Securities Investment List The highest and lowest prices
                            between July 1904, and March, 1905, are given, and owing to the recent
                            great developments in the share market the fluctuations afford
                            interesting read- ing.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Greeks in Egypt</head>
                        <p>The relations between Greece and Egypt have always been very close ever
                            since the dawn of history, and the Greeks are now the one foreign
                            nationality which may be said to be really at home in the valley of the
                            Nile According to Mr. John Lambrides, a publicist well known in Athens,
                            who has just published a book on his travels up the Nile, two things
                            strike the observer, and they are the numerical superiority of the
                            Greeks over the other foreign races in Egypt, and the deep root which
                            they have taken in the coun try. The statistics are somewhat misleading
                            as they only take notice of Greeks of the kingdom, while those who come
                            from Turkey are reckoned as natives, since they belong to the Ottoman
                            Empire. Out of over a hundred and twelve thousand foreigners the Greeks
                            of the kingdom number no fewer than thirty eight thousand, but it all
                            those who come from the European and Asiatic provinces of Turkey are
                            included the total number of Greeks amounts, at a moderate computation
                            to one hundred and fifty thousand, or several thousand more than the
                            peoples of other foreign nationalities put together.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the
                        Central position. Under English management</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY TODAY’S CELEBRATIONS.</head>
                    <p>Mohamed Aly-square, as well as Cherif Pasha-street, at Alexandria to-day
                        bears a very bright aspect, nearly every inhabitant of the vicinity having
                        responded to the request of the Municipality to assist in the scheme of
                        decoration. The Venetian masts from which the thousands of electric bulbs
                        are festooned are gay with the Ottoman colours, and flags are flying from
                        every building.</p>
                    <p>A large dais has been erected opposite the sta- tue of Mohamed Aly, where the
                        official ceromo- ny will take place at 4 p.m. to-day. Over the entrance
                        there has been placed a large triumphal arch which will be illuminated in
                        the evening.</p>
                    <p>The illuminations this evening promise to be of a grandiose character. The
                        Municipality have evidently spared no expense to make the celebration worthy
                        of the occasion, and the Gas Company’s electrical department have certainly
                        done their work well. Mohamed Aly- square to-night will be one blaze of
                        light, and it is expected that tout Alexandrie will be there to witness the
                        illuminations. It is to be hoped that the Alexandria police have taken
                        effectual measures to cope with any crush. One regulation is that carriages
                        will only be allowed to circulate in the square at a slow pace and in single
                        file, commencing from the entrance of Cherif Pasha-street down to the Cafe
                        d’Europe and from thence in the direction of Tewfik Pasha-street.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is to be represented at this afternoon’s ceremony at Alexandria
                        by Prince Aziz Pasha Hassan, Prince Omar Bey Tous- soum, and Prince Mohamed
                        Bey Ibrahim.</p>
                    <p>Sir Reginald Wingate,Deputy District Grand Master of Egypt and the Sudan, has
                        given permission to every individual Mason to- attend to-morrow's meeting to
                        commemorate the centenary at the Pyramids Masonic Hall, Alexandria, if
                        regularly held.</p>
                    <p>Prince Ibrahim Pasha Halim will represent the Khedive at the centenary
                        celebration at Cairo to-day.</p>
                    <p>The Cairo Fete Committee has purchased 1,500 okes of bread and will
                        distribute it to- morrow to the poor undergraduates of Al Azbar
                        University.</p>
                    <p>It is stated that the exact date on which the centenary should fall is the
                        18th June, as according to the historian, El Gabbarti, it was on that day a
                        hundred years ago that the firman, appointing Mohamed Aly Viceroy of Egypt,
                        was signed at Constantinople.</p>
                    <p>The subscriptions for the fetes at Cairo amounted yesterday to L.E.
                        1,404.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RETURN OF THE MAHMAL.</head>
                    <p>The ceremony of the return of the Mahmal took place at 9 o’clock this morning
                        at the Citadel, Cairo. H. H. the Khedive was re- presented by Mustapha Pasha
                        Fehmy, the Prime Minister, and all the other Ministers were in
                        attendance.</p>
                    <p>The line of route of the procession and the large open spaces at the foot of
                        the Citadel were thronged by even larger crowds than on the occasion of
                        former, similar cere- monies, as doubtless the encounter with the escort at
                        El Hamra is fresh in the memory of the populace, and great excitement
                        prevailed.</p>
                    <p>On the arrival of the Prime Minister at a quarter to nine, a salute of 21
                        guns was fired and this was repeated when the Mahmal arrived at 9 o’clock
                        headed by the Emir el- Hag.</p>
                    <p>The Emir el-Hag, Mahmoud Pasha Housni had a private interview with Mustapha
                        Pasha Fehmy, President of the Council of Minister yesterday in order to
                        explain to the Prime Minister the exact details of the El Hamra combat.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COTTON CROP.</head>
                    <p>The following, is a resume of the answer received in April by the Alexandria
                        General Produce Association:—</p>
                    <p>Sowing has taken place as usual during March and April Although the generally
                        cool temperature and rather frequent showers were not very propitious to the
                        cultures, the young plants are showing a healthy appearance. Some
                        backwardness, however, may be remarked.</p>
                    <p>Resowing has been trifling in many localities rather frequent in other
                        quarters, but always partial only. In the average, it was not more important
                        than other years, and materially less than last season.</p>
                    <p>The acreage is considered to be almost the same as last season, showing only
                        a slight increase of newly cultivated lands. Mitafifi continues to occupy
                        the largest proportion whereas Abbassi and Joannovich have been slightly
                        reduced this season.</p>
                    <p>With the exception of some districts in the north of Behera and Gharbieh, the
                        water has been sufficient. With the amelioration and de- velopment of the
                        irrigation system, hopes are entertained that it will remain sufficient
                        during the summer months; although the level of the Nile is very low and
                        application of the rotation system has already commenced.</p>
                    <p>Fayoum and Upper Egypt. In the Fayoum province cotton appears to occupy the
                        same area as last year.</p>
                    <p>A further increase is reported from Upper Egypt, especially in the Beni-Souef
                        and Minieh provinces.</p>
                    <p>Hitherto Upper Egypt has been slowly exclusively Ashmouny cotton, but we are
                        in- formed that larger trials of Abbassi and some of Mitafifi will be made
                        this year.</p>
                    <p>Cultures are in good condition, but rather backward.</p>
                    <p>The water is sufficient.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IMPORTANT FLOTATION. £3,000,000 CAPITAL.</head>
                    <p>A very important Anglo-Egyptian flotation is on the cards. The capital will
                        probably be £3,000,000 and of this sum £1,500,000 has been guaranteed by
                        some of the biggest financial houses. The board will comprise some of the
                        leading financial names in the City of London.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER NEW COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>In about a fortnight or three weeks’ time a new English company, whose sphere
                        of opera- tions will be in Egypt and the Sudan, will make its debut. The
                        whole of the capital has already been subscribed.</p>
                    <p>We understand that this company; has already the refusal of business which
                        will be enough to pay a considerable percentage on the capitalisation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN IMPROVEMENTS CORPORATION.</head>
                    <p>The announcement of the flotation of the Egyptian Improvements Corporation
                        will be found on page 6 of to-day's issue and we beg to draw our readers’
                        attention to this new company, which has a strong local board. An im-
                        portant detail, which should not be overlooked by the thoughtful investor,
                        is that there are no founders’ shares nor any promoter's profits. The
                        company is being formed with a capital of £100,000, divided into 25,000
                        shares of £4 each, for the purpose of undertaking all pro- perty operations,
                        and especially the purchase and sale of lands situated in the cities and
                        suburbs, and improvement of land, building operations, loans on mortgage,
                        etc. Several important schemes are being studied. Half the capital is now
                        offered for public subscription at par. As already stated, there will be no
                        Founders’ or Deferred shares or Debentures. The net profit, after deducting
                        10 % for the board, will be wholly available for dividends. The first board
                        consists of Messrs. Alexandre Rustovitz Bey, George Nusgovich Bey, George
                        Royle, Charles J. Nicole, Maxime Charvaut, Anthony S. Constantinidi, and
                        Demetrius K Casdagli. The managing director will be M. Charles J. Nicole, of
                        Messrs. Nicole and Naef, Geneva, of which firm he is one of the heads, and
                        which he has managed since its foundation in 1881. The firm is one of the
                        largest in that city and is engaged in property operations.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOCIETE EGYPTIENNE D’ENTREPRISES URBAINES ET RURALES.</head>
                    <p>The final announcement of the above flota- tion appears today and on Monday
                        next, 15th inst., the subscription list will be opened at the offices of
                        Messrs. J.L. Menasce, Figlio &amp; Co. Alexandria; as announced in our 8th
                        page.The capital of this company is £300,000 and the profits will be
                        allocated in the following pro- portions, according to the statutes of the
                        company : (1) 10 per cent to the reserve; (2) the sum necessary for the
                        distribution of a dividend of 5 per cent to the shareholders ; (3) 10 per
                        cent to the board of directors, and (4) the balance as follows : 85 per cent
                        to the shareholders, and 15 per cent. to the founders.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO BANKRUPTCIES.</head>
                    <p>The following bankruptcy notices have been issued at Cairo in one single day,
                        and will be dealt with on Monday next in the Commercial Chamber of the Mixed
                        Courts. The details of the announcement given below speaks for itself and
                        fully bear out our recent statements as to the severity of the trade crisis.
                        The notice is as follows:</p>
                    <p>Les créanciers dans lea faillites ci-apres sont convoques pour le lundi 15 du
                        mois courant a 9 h. du matin:</p>
                    <p>1. Mohamed Abdel Gani Mahmoud: verifi- cation et concordat</p>
                    <p>2. V. Friedmann : continuation verification des creances</p>
                    <p>3. Ibrahim Ismail: concordat preventif.</p>
                    <p>4. Hoirs feu Mohamed El Sadr: concords pteventif.</p>
                    <p>5. Raison sociale Dick et Cir: nomination syndic definitif.</p>
                    <p>6. Antoine Fotiades : continuation verifica- tion et-concordat</p>
                    <p>7. Bsarani fils: continuation verification creances.</p>
                    <p>8. A. Appel et fils: verification et concordat</p>
                    <p>9. Abdel Sayed Bichai et Erian Ibrahim verification creances.</p>
                    <p>10. Abdel Magaid Aboul Enen : concordat preventif.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE,</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will not attend the centenary celebrations in Mohamed Aly-square
                        this after noon.</p>
                    <p>His Highness is at Montarah to-day.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COIN FIND.</head>
                    <p>At the last meeting of the Royal Numis- matic Society of London the president
                        of the society exhibited on behalf of Signor Dattari, of Cairo, a small
                        selection of Roman coins mostly of the Constantine period, from a hoard of
                        about 30,000 recently discovered in Egypt. These coins, before being
                        cleaned, seemed not to differ in any respect from what are usually known as
                        “third-brass” coins: but on being cleaned by means of a much dilluted bath
                        of nitric acid, they presented all the appearance of silver coins. The
                        blanks seem to have been silvered, or perhaps more probably tinned, before
                        they were placed between the dies. Signor Dattari suggests that this may
                        have been done as a precaution against forgery by coins cast in a mould in
                        imitation of the original.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH BENEVOLENT FUND. ANNUAL REPORT FOR 1904.</head>
                    <p>The statement of accounts for the year 1904, which has just been issued,
                        shows that the cash balance in hand was on the 1st January, 1905, £180 12s
                        11d., as against £119 15s. 4d. last year; this includes, however, a special
                        donation of £40 given by the children and heirs of the late Shalom Tuby in
                        memory of their father. The amount subscribed by our community daring the
                        year has been £210 7s 6d., as against £219 18s 6d. last year. The
                        expenditure was under the following heads : Passages home, £41.7.7 ; cash,
                        £48.1.10 ; board and lodgiDg and' food at Sailors’ Home, Rudolph Asylum,
                        etc., £46.14.2 1/2-; hospital and funeral expen- ses, £73.6.7 ; assistance
                        to distressed Maltese, £41.5.6 ; ad venous to persons in distress on their
                        undertaking to repay the same, £26.2.0 ; clothing, £2.1.6 ; school fees,
                        £19.14.0 ; sun- dries, printing, postage, stationery, £5.17.8 ; total,
                        £204.9.10 1/2. The sum of £18 14s. Dd. was recovered from the Malta and
                        Indian Governments and £29 2s. 5 1/2 was refunded by private individuals to
                        whom temporary assistance had been given, making £4716s. 5 1/2d. The sum of
                        £62 6s. 3d., which had been expended on the relief of persons not belong-
                        ing to the Alexandria community, was also recovered from the Foreign Office.
                        Deducting these three sums (£110 2s. 8 1/2d,)from the total expenditure
                        leaves £194 7s. 2d. as having been spent on the relief of distressed persons
                        belong- ing to our own community. This is a much smaller sum than usual. The
                        greatest difference between this year and the average year is that the
                        number of persons for whom it has been necessary to provide passages home
                        has been less than usual. In 1903 the expense on this account amounted to
                        £185 19s. 10d., as against £41 7s. 7d. in 1904. On the other hand, hos-
                        pital expenses in 1904 have been £73 5s. 7d., as against £39 3s,8d. in 1903.
                        Financially, the not result ol the year’s work has been that the Fund has
                        increased its cash balance somewhat, but the committee cannot hope that the
                        amount required for passages home will remain at so low a sum as sufficed
                        this year. It is not satisfactory to note that though the resident British
                        community rapidly increases the total amount subscribed to the fund shows a
                        ten- dency to decrease. As this fund takes the place of the poor rate it is
                        hoped that all British subjects will subscribe something according to their
                        means.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TRIPLE MURDER AT KENEH.</head>
                    <p>( From Our Correspondent ). Keneh, Saturday A terrible tragedy has occurred
                        in this district, and has aroused considerable excite- ment throughout the
                        neighbourhood owing to the deliberate character of the crime.</p>
                    <p>A man of Makhadoora village, near Keneh, desired to poison some of his
                        cousins, and for this purpose he put a quantity of deadly poison into some
                        compressed dates. He gave the fruit to his relations, with the result that
                        three women, who partook of them, expired in great agony. Two men, whom the
                        murderer also intended to dispose of by this means, escaped, although they
                        also re ceived the poisoned dates.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellerman SS. “Athenian” sailed from Malta on Friday evening and is due
                        here or Tuesday morning.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Avon" sailed from Liverpool on Friday for Gibraltar,
                        Malta, and Alexandria with general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Cromer are expected at Alexandria to-day,coning by way of the
                        Mah-, moudieh Canal.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Landon, whose appointment to the Irrigation Department we announced in
                        our issue of Monday last, is to replace Mr. Dupuis as Inspector of the
                        Second Circle at a salary of £1,000 per annum. He is engaged for five years
                        and if dismissed before the end of that period, the Government will give him
                        an indemnity of £1,000. Mr. Landon arrives from India in a few weeks
                        time.</p>
                    <p>Colonel D. F. Lewis left Alexandria for Cairo this morning. He has come to
                        Egypt in connection with an important financial under- taking.</p>
                    <p>It is with great regret that we record the death of Captain Brown, resident
                        medical offi- cer of the Kasr-el-Ainy Hospital, Cairo, who has succumbed to
                        an attack by typhoid from which he had been suffering for some three
                        weeks.</p>
                    <p>M. E. C. Wellunscheg, first secretary and navy commissioner of the
                        Austro-Hungarian Consulate at Alexandria, has been transferred in the same
                        quality to the consulate at Port Said. He will be replaced by M.
                        Urbancie.</p>
                    <p>The funeral of Mme Beyerle took place at 4.30 o’clock yesterday afternoon.
                        The general meeting of the brokers of the Cairo Bourse, which should have
                        taken place yesterday after noon, was postponed to Monday, as a sign of
                        respect for the bereaved husband.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA</head>
                    <p>The best halfway house between Egypt and England is VIRAGO, near PISA Main
                        line express stop. Pine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                        English-Pension, Villa Shelley, Every home comfort. Electric light. Meters
                        sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY. </head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOOTBALL. CHALLENGE-MATCH.</head>
                        <head>M.M.P.,v. N.C.O.’s Service Companies INNISKILLINGS.</head>
                        <p>Teams representing the above met in a challenge match at Abbassieh. Both
                            teams have been undergoing special training, the Inniskillings under the
                            supervision of CpI. Tuck. They were in splendid trim, as also were the
                            M.M.P.’s, so that a good game was in store for those who lined the
                            ropes. The ground was in the pink of condition. About 1,700 spectators
                            were present when the referee’s whistle sounded for hostilities to
                            commence. The following lined out in the order mentioned : M.M.P.—Goal,
                            Sgt. Broad- hurst; backs, Cpl. Dunbar arid Cpl. Rafferty; halves, Cpl.
                            Wingate, Cpl. Burns, and Cpl. Philips ; forwards, Cpl. Carter, Cpl.
                            Goodman, Cpl. Hopkins (capt.), Cpl. Chandler, and Cpl. Field. N.C.O.'s
                            Service Companies Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers (Abbasaieh Contingent).
                            —Goal, Lce-Cpl. Murray; backs, Cpl. Behan (capt) and Lce-Cpl. Supple;
                            halves, Lce- Cpl. Dunlop, Lce-Cpl. Brennan and Lce-Cpl. Edgar; forwards,
                            Lce-Cpl. Russell, Lce-Cpl. Davidson, .Cpl. Rafferty. CpL Carey, and Lce-
                            Cpl. McLoughlin. Referree, Cpl. McClintock (M.M.P.)</p>
                        <p>Captain Behan won the toss and the attack on Port Arthur was commenced by
                            Hopkins kicking off for the M.M.P. The latter pressed but Behan relieved
                            and Russell getting pos- session raced along the wing and centred
                            beautifully into goal, where Rafferty got the sphere at his toe and
                            scored for the greenshirts amid cheers. On retaining the M.M.P.’s got
                            away and Field gave Murray a hot one to save, which he did well. A
                            corner to the M.M.P.’s proved unproductive. The horse soldiers now
                            pressed, but Dunlop was displaying some of his old farm and his (Bob
                            Milne) rushes were well worth watching. Still not to be denied the
                            police broke away, and some misunderstanding between the Fusiliers’
                            defence let the M. M. P.’s score their first goal. The M. M. P.’s still
                            kept the pressure up and were awarded a corner. This was well cleared by
                            Supple, the ball finding touch. Play now was of a very even nature until
                            Russell broke away, but Davidson sent past. On the kick off the greens
                            pressed, but Dunbar sent into touch. Touch was now the order for some
                            time until Rafferty got away on his own, but he was robbed when in a
                            good position. Play was now confined to midfield for a small period. The
                            M. M. P.’s now got away in fine style, Hopkins doing some good work, but
                            score they could not as Behan was playing the game of his life. Play now
                            became fast, each team doing its utmost. A handball against the
                            Fusiliers helped to put them on the defence. Carter, however, sent past.
                            On resuming the greens pressed and Broadhurst had an anxious time of it.
                            However he cleared in good style and Goodman receiving the sphere, made
                            a dash towards Murray, only to find the latter well barricaded. The
                            Fusiliers were now having the best of a good game, and Russell getting
                            away on his own, sent a daisy into Broadhurst, who saved weakly and
                            Carey rushing in had no trouble whatever in putting the boys in green
                            ahead. Both teams were now playing a great game, the pace being a hot
                            one. The excitement was at, fever heat as Carter missed by inches. The
                            referree’s whistle now announced half-time, the score standing</p>
                        <p>N. C. O.’s Service Companies Inniskillings 2 goals.</p>
                        <p>Military Mounted Police 1 goal.</p>
                        <p>SECOND HALF.</p>
                        <p>After the interval of five minutes both teams reappeared. Rafferty kicked
                            off for the Fusiliers. The M. M. P.’s at once took up the running and
                            Murray was called upon to handle, which he did well. Russell and
                            Davidson were now seen to advantage, the former making some good runs,
                            but the M. M. P.’s wore playing a steady game and retained the ball time
                            after time off side against Russell. Some good com- bination was now
                            shown by both sides. The centre forward of the M. M. P.’s was in good
                            form, and many runs were made by him, but over-eagerness spoiled all
                            chances. Behan, Supple, and Dunlop were conspicuous in re- pelling all
                            attacks. The M. M. P.’s now woke up and Carter got on a good run and
                            getting past Supple he passed to Hopkins, who with a splen- didly judged
                            shot sent up the equaliser amidst great cheers. This made both teams
                            play a lot better. A couple of hot scrimmages now took place around the
                            Fusiliers’ goal until Dunlop got possession and racing the length of the
                            field passed to McLoughlin, who sent a magnifi- cent grounder with the
                            custodian, who in saving conceded a corner. This was well taken by
                            Russell, a scrimmage ensuing. Wingate, however, cleared and Hopkins
                            getting pos- session raced down the wing at a tremen- dous pace, but
                            this parting shot went wide (excitement was the order for some time).
                            Both teams were playing a very fast game, The greenshirts now got
                            a-going, Russell and Davidson being a terror to the M. M. P.’s defence.
                            Both sides were playing the one back game, the consequences being that
                            many players were given off side. Shortly after the referee's whistle
                            sounded full-time, the score reading:</p>
                        <p>N.C.O's Service Companies Inniskillings 2 goals.</p>
                        <p>Military Mounted Police 2 goals.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>TYROL.-Weissenstein Castle 341 ft. First-class private hotel near
                        Windisch-Matrei; Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                        mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September.
                        Prospectuses and Pho- tographs, “Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
