<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Logan Wills</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-30">September 30, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 30 1905.</head>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLAND AND RUSSIA. PROPOSED ENTENTE.</head>

                    <p>Moscow, September 39. Count Lambsdorff has declared to an English notability
                        that the Tsar and himself wish for an agreement between Russia and England.
                        (Havas</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>AUSTRIA AND HUNGARY. REVISION LAW OP 1867.</head>

                    <p>Vienna, September 30. M. de GauUch announced in the Reichsrath that the
                        Government proposes that the re- spective Parliaments of Austria and Hungary
                        appoint deputations to meet in the spring to discuss the revision law of
                        1867, regulating the joint affairs of the two countries. He is
                        convinced,that such a revision would benefit both countries and Monarchy as
                        a whole. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUGAR COMPANY FAILURE. A DEPRESSED PARIS MARKET.</head>

                    <p>Paris, September 29. The market here is depressed owing to the the failure of
                        an important sugar company. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MANILA TYPHOON.</head>

                    <p>Manila, September 29. Eleven Americans and twenty-four natives were drowned
                        in the sinking of a gunboat during the typhoon. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE COUNT DE BRAZZA.</head>

                    <p>Marseilles, September 29. The mortal remains of Count de Brazza have arrived.
                        ( Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW LORD MAYOR.</head>

                    <p>London, September 29. Alderman Walter Vaughan Morgan has been elected Lord
                        Mayor. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Mr. Walter Vaughan Morgan, Lord Mayor elect of London, is a Welshman by birth
                        and descent. He was born on May 8,1831, being the sixth son of Thomas Morgan
                        of Glasbury, and Marianne, daughter of Mr.William Vaugh- an of Brecon.
                        Educated at Christ's Hospital, he entered the service of the National Pro-
                        vincial Bank ot England in 1846. In 1856 he retired as chief cashier of the
                        Manchester branch, to join his brothers in London in founding the firm of
                        Morgan Brothers, mer- chants and newspaper proprietors, and the Morgan
                        Crucible Company ; the firm consisted of six brothers who continued in
                        partnership for thirty years, and still so continue except that death has
                        reduced their number to three.</p>
                    <p>The new Lord Mayor, who is one of the proprietors of the "Chemist and
                        Druggist” and "The Ironmonger,” well-known trade journals, is a freemason of
                        many years standing. He was Grand Treasurer of the Grand Lodge of Eng- land
                        in 1897-98. After becoming an Alderman and Magistrate of the city of London,
                        he was appointed Sheriff of the city in 1900-01, and is one of H.M.’s
                        Lieutenants for the city. He is unmarried and a member of the Reform and
                        Gresham Clubs.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LIST DEPARTURES.</head>

                    <p>La paquebot Congo, des Messageries Mariti- mes, parti hier pour Marseille
                        avait à bord : Mme Doneau, Mlles Muthuon et Balmont, M. Moh. Soubhy, M.
                        Victor Bertrand, M. Sedg- wick, M. Leroux. M. L’abbé Jarrosson, M. Gaston
                        Piha, M. A. Meimarachi, Soenrs Adéo- not and Nérée, R. P. Paul Fontier, M.
                        Mob. O. Hussein El Khashab, M. Me Diaoomidès, Socur Emilieune, Mme Dalem née
                        Longé, M. Chyles Jean, M. Pitres, Père Bérend, Mme Paillarèa et sa fille,
                        Mrs Masson Fox et Cockerton, M. M. Sayad, M. Crod, Dr G. Anawati et 45 pas-
                        sagers de Sme et 4me classes.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>BECK and GO’S PILSENER BEER BREMEN</head>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria, and the Sudan
                        Otherwise apply to F.J Fleurent F. Micallef</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkily (near Alexandria) Ramble’s Fashionable Hotel Patronised By the Elite
                        Full Pension from P.T 60 a day. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber
                        Station</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

                    <p>Jewish Festival —To-day being the Hebrew New Year’s day many of the Jewish
                        business houses are closed.</p>

                    <p>Want of Space compels us to hold over the less important news which we have
                        received until our next issue.</p>

                    <p>Quarantine. A telegram from Pera an- nounces that arrivals from Aden will be
                        subjected to a medical visit.</p>

                    <p>The Greek Colony.— To-day being the name day of the Crown Princess Sophia of
                        Greece, thanksgiving services were held at the Greek Orthodox Churches of
                        Alexandria.</p>

                    <p>Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Co.— The sportsman’s train on the Aboukir line
                        will be suppressed from Monday next, and train No. 17 will resume its
                        ordinary service, the last departure from Aboukir being at 9 p.m.</p>

                    <p>The Alhambra Theatre.—The manage- ment of this theatre announced a matinée
                        for to-morrow when La Dame de chez Maxim will be staged. Monday evening’s
                        performance, for which Fourchambault is billed, will be devoted to the
                        benefit of Signor A. Maggi.</p>

                    <p>The Brindisi Mail will be made up at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a.m. on
                        Monday for ordinary correspondence. Registered letters must be handed in not
                        later than 9 p m. on Sunday, and insured articles, money orders, and
                        parcels, by noon on the latter day.</p>

                    <p>Suez Canal.—16 vessels passed through the canal on the 26th and 27th inst.,
                        previous to the temporary cessation of traffic, 6 of there were British, 5
                        German, 1 Dutch, 2 Italian, 2 French. The receipts for the two days were
                        frs. 542,013 28, making the total from the 1st inst. (which is not likely to
                        bé increased np to the end of September), frs. 7,798,405.25.</p>

                    <p>Coal Imports.—From the 1st of January to the 28th of September. 794,370 tons
                        of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 428,660, Newcastle 185,919.
                        Scotland 98.112, Yorkshire 52,686 and other places 29,953 tons. During the
                        same period last year 765,539 tons were received. This is the first time
                        that the return has shown an increase of the import of coal daring the
                        present year as compared with 1904.</p>

                    <p>Akhmin Greek Catholics.—Our Akhmin correspondent writes that the Patriarch
                        Hiro- los of the Greek Catholic Church paid a visit to that town on the 25th
                        inst. He came from Girgeh by steamer, and was met at the wharf by a large
                        crowd of people, who accompanied him to the church and listened with
                        interest to his solemn address. His Beatitude spent two days at Akhmin,
                        where he visited many families, and then left for Sohag.</p>

                    <p>A Few Facts. — The first Berlitz School was established in May, 1878. There
                        are now 235 branches all over the world. Among the students have been
                        members of the Royal families of England, Spain and Germany, of Presidents
                        of the United States, of the French Republic, as well as Ambassadors,
                        Ministers, Senators, Professors of the leading Universities, and famous
                        writers. The Berlitz Method has received the highest awards at all
                        International Exhibitions, and its prin- ciples were adopted by the Congress
                        of Modern Languages, Paris, 1900.</p>

                    <p>Fatal Fire at Gabbari.—At 5 a.m. today a fire broke out in the upper story of
                        a house in the Gabbari quarter. The fire bri- gade sent off an engine at
                        once on being called up, and were engaged in putting out the flames whom the
                        occupant of the house, a merchant named Abd el Rahim Hassan, threw himself
                        from a window without waiting or a fire escape or ladder to be put up and
                        received such severe injuries that he expired while being conveyed to
                        hospital. The flames were quickly extinguished, and an enquiry as to the
                        origin of the fire and the amount of damage done, is proceeding.</p>

                    <p>San Stefano Casino.— Yesterday after- noon's entertainment at the San Stefano
                        Casino in aid of the sufferers from the recent earth- quakes in Calabria was
                        an immense success. Amongst those present we noticed H.E. Khalil Hamdi Pasha
                        Hamada, the committee and a large number of members of the San Stefano Club,
                        Baron Acton, Consul General of Italy, H.B. Fakhry Pasha, Mr. Webb, M.
                        Scotidis, Hellenic Consul, Count Zizinia, and many others. The band of the
                        Customs porters’ chil- dren played several elections in an admirable manner,
                        and the dancing of Professor Longhi’s pupils was exceedingly well done and
                        made a very pretty sight The Brachale orchestra gave several selections from
                        Verdi's operas which were greatly appreciated, and at the conclusion of the
                        performance the management of the Casino very kindly distributed a number of
                        small presents amongst the children. The receipts of the fête amounted to
                        £60, and as all the expenses were defrayed by the San Stefano Casino and
                        H.E. Khalil Hamdi Pasha Hamada, the fall sum was handed over to Baron Acton
                        for his Calabrian relief fund.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES. M. DE LA BOUGLISE'S DEATH</head>

                    <p>It appears that the late M. de la Bouglise was found lying dead in the Sharia
                        Soliman Pasha by two Italians. He was evidently on his way back from the
                        Villa Victoria where be had called upon M. Leroux, when the disease, from
                        which he had long suffered, struck him down. The corpse was taken to the
                        Abdin caracol, where it was identified by M. Bertrand and MM. Leronx and
                        Naus.</p>
                    <p>The funeral, which left the French hospital at 4 p.m. yesterday, was attended
                        by M. Bertrand and the French consular staff, by many members of the French
                        colony, and the leading representatives of the Sucreries Com- pany. The body
                        of the late M. de la Bouglise was interred in a vault in tho Old Cairo ceme-
                        tery, pending instructions from the family of the deceased.</p>
                    <p>M. Leroux left Cairo for Europe yesterday, having received news of the
                        serious illness of his mother. He hopes to return to Egypt in a short
                        time.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA.</head>

                    <p>We learn that the action brought by the Princes, sons of the late Khedive
                        Ismail Pasha, against the Government for the restoration to them of the
                        remaining surplus of the Daira Sanieh will come before the Cairo Mixed
                        Courts on October 20.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUICIDE OF A BRITISH SUBJECT.</head>

                    <p>A European, believed to be an Englishman resident in Ceylon, shot himself
                        with a revolver at 8 p.m. yesterday on the beach near San Stefano. The
                        deceased, whose name appears to be T. Peters, had come up to San Stefano
                        from Alexandria for the afternoon We have thus far received no information
                        as to the history of the deceased or the cause of his suicide, the results
                        of the Consular inquest which opened at the Ras el Tin hospi- tal at midday
                        not having reached us before we went to press.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND ALLOTMENT COMPANY.</head>

                    <p>We published particulars in our issue of the 22nd instant of the now company
                        that has just been formed, with Sir William Willcocks as chairman, and which
                        will be brought out in the course of next month.</p>
                    <p>We are now informed that so favorably is this new undertaking viewed by both
                        the European and the Native communities that already more than the entire
                        capital of L B. 500,000 has been privately applied for, the applications
                        coming in from all parts of the country, and ranging from five shares to
                        several thousands. To comply with the rules of the local bourses a third of
                        the share capital will, however, have to be offered for public sub-
                        scription so as to obtain a quotation of the sharer of the company. Among
                        the satisfactory points to be noted are the following. No pro- motion money
                        will be paid in connection with the formation of the company but a certain
                        number of founders' shares will be created,and these wilt be allotted to the
                        promoters in lieu of payment in cash. The shareholders will moreover be
                        entitled to a prior and cumulative yearly dividend of four per cent, and the
                        founders’ shares only participate to the extent of thirty per cent of the
                        surplus profits, the balance of seventy per cent going to the share-
                        holders. In the meanwhile we may mention that the support the promoters have
                        so far received greatly exceeds their most sanguine anti- cipations.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>

                    <p>The following is the programme of music to be performed to morrow morning on
                        the terrace of tho Casino, commencing at 10 p.m. 1. Marche Mendelssohn—2.
                        Valse Ganna—3. SSinfornia Gu- gliolmo Tell Rossini—4. Fantaisic I’Arlesienne
                        Bizet-5. Danaa Macabre Saint Saena-6. Méditation Thala Masseuet—Ballet Faust
                        Gounod.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

                    <p>The S.S. Indian Prince left Middlesborough yesterday and is due to arrive at
                        Alexandria on or about October 15th. The S.S. Cyprian Prince left London on
                        Wednesday with general cargo and is due to arrive at Alexandria on or about
                        14th October. The Russian Steam Navigation Company's S.S. Nachimoff will
                        leave Alexandria on October 8 for Odessa, touching at Port Said, Jaffa,
                        Beyrouth, Tripoli, Ohio, Smyrna, Dardanelles, and Constantinople, and will
                        connect with the Black Sea service.</p>
                    <p>The Khédivial express mail steamship El Kahira will leave Alexandria at 4
                        p.m. on Wednesday for Piraeos, Smyrna, Mitylene, and Constantinople.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. City of Khios of the Papayanni Line left Malta yesterday evening and
                        is ex- pected to arrive at Alexandria on Tuesday morning with mails and
                        passengers.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Assiout of the Westcott and Laurence Line left Malta yesterday and
                        is due at Alexandria on Monday or Tuesday, with general cargo from London
                        and a cargo of coals from Newcastle.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. City of Cambridge arrived last night from Glasgow,
                        Liverpool, and Malta with passengers and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Eilerman S.S. Avon sailed from Liver- pool yesterday with general cargo
                        for Alex- andria direct.</p>
                    <p>The Westcott S.S. Egyptian sailed lest night for Odessa.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID. AFTER THE EXPLOSION. (From our
                        Correspondent).</head>
                    <p>Port Said, Friday. The consequences of the explosion yesterday, notably the
                        rapidly growing congestion of the harbour here,are beginning to make
                        themselves apparent There are thirteen ships now on the buoys and vessels
                        have been arriving steadily all day. The coal basin is to be utilised
                        shortly for ships as they come in from sea and the Dutch, or man-of-war
                        anchorage will be used for vessels of short' length. The big berths in front
                        of the main streets, Rue de Commerce and Quai Eugenie, are reserved for the
                        arrival of mail and passenger boats, in all, the har- bour, as it is at
                        present can accommodate with cue about 25 more vessels, and this number will
                        soon be reached, as a glance at the lists of ships due here will shew. There
                        is talk of moving the vessels now in harbour into the canal between here and
                        Ras el Bah,as the new arrivals make extra berthing space a necessity and I
                        should think that this will require to be done in a few days, as early
                        during next week several large passenger boats will arrive.</p>
                    <p>I have heard nothing of what arrangements are being made regarding the
                        transport of mails in the event of the canal still blocked when the Brindisi
                        boat comes in on Wednesday, but hopes have been expressed by competent
                        authorities that it may be possible to send vessels through the canal past
                        the Chatham’s remains by that time.</p>
                    <p>No strangers are allowed to go down the canal on any account, though frequent
                        requests have been made by residents and others for permission to view the
                        spot.</p>
                    <p>Work is being pushed on by night and day at kilometre 18.4 ; Arabs in
                        hundreds are busily engaged removing débris from the canal banks, and
                        redoing the chaos which reigned yesterday to some semblance of order and
                        system. Fish is their staple food, and these continue to come to the surface
                        in hundreds, porpoise, black fish, and mullet being the principal
                        species.</p>
                    <p>The sounding charts are practically com- pleted, and a consultation is to be
                        held the moment the soundings and examination of the state of the bottom of
                        the canal are com- pleted.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Harris is to remain here to give the Canal Company the benefit of his
                        knowledge in the matter of blowing up what remains of the now famous ship,
                        and two divers who are skilled in submarine mining are due here to morrow to
                        go on with what Mr. Harris suggests. It is probable that no new explosion
                        will be made for a while, it it is found that dredging will make the channel
                        clear enough to allow the accumulated ships to get through.</p>
                    <p>There are seventeen ships at Suez this afternoon but none are allowed to
                        enter the canal.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>(From Another Correspondent.)</head>
                    <p>Alexandria, September SO. As I passed the scene of the explosion on my return
                        home yesterday, few traces were visible of the destruction caused by
                        Thursday’s explosion. The train moved along slowly, thus enabling me easily
                        to see all there was to be seen. All that could be discerned on the east or
                        Asiatic bank was the gap caused by the explosion, and, at the distance from
                        which we saw it, this did not appear to be very extensive.</p>
                    <p>All that was to be seen of the unfortunate Chatham was a portion of the mast
                        in the water. Several dredgers were at work in the canal, and steam launches
                        and other vessels in the service of the company were also busily employed.
                        The fresh-water canal had no fish remaining on its surface, -this could
                        hardly be expected twenty-six hours after the shock that had killed them.
                        Probably at that time few remained uneaten. I cannot say that the inter of
                        this canal looked very inviting,in fact that of the maritime canal looked
                        far more fit for drinking purposes. It was perhaps as well that I did not
                        notice this water before reaching Port Said, for although when filtered it
                        was beautifully clear and palatable, its state as it flows between the banks
                        most certainly appears to leave much to be desired. The western bank of the
                        canal bears no traces whatever—apart from the pipes and other appliances
                        used- of the explosion, and no one would imagine even that the telegraph
                        wires had been interfered with. Nor did I see any broken glass about.</p>
                    <p>I had a short but interesting conversation with Captain Hill, of the Chatham,
                        on Thurs- day. It is not, I think, generally known that the cause of the
                        fire spreading so rapidly after the collision with the Clan Cumming was the
                        foot that the lamp (or lamps) upset set fire to some highly flammable
                        composition contain- ing naphtha, many drums of which were stored on board.
                        These Exploded one after another, reusing the rapid extension of the fire
                        which necessitated the flooding and consequent sinking of the vessel with
                        its dangerous cargo. As to this same composition it is stated that but for a
                        contravention of the law which abso- lutely prohibits the storing of such
                        stuff in confined spaces, and insists upon the drums being carried on the
                        open deck, free to the air, no serious results would have arisen from the
                        slight collision which took place. Such colli- sions,I hear, are of somewhat
                        frequent occurrence.</p>
                    <p>More work for the lawyers!! The gentlemen of the long robe will no doubt be
                        extremely busy for a time, and the ill wind of the disaster will blow them
                        at least much good in the shape of fees. In conversation with Mr, Hama
                        yesterday, that gentleman informed me that it was probable that his stay in
                        <cb/>Egypt might be a somewhat prolonged one, as his evidence might be
                        required in a pending notion respecting the dynamite which was exploded
                        under his direction at Aboukir in Jane last Litigation ! litigation ! when
                        will arbitration takes its place in the settle- ment of disputes? The
                        question is easily answered. Never ! so long as the lawyers are the power
                        they are at present, in every nation and in every clime. T. A.</p>

                    <p>We should like to state that the tele- gram received by our esteemed
                        contempo- rary "La Reforme” from its special corres- pondent at Port Said,
                        attributing to the "Egyptian Gazette” the statement that dyna- mite
                        cartridges remained in the canal after the explosion, has no foundation
                        whatever in fact.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM ASSIOUT. CRIME ON THE DESERT ROAD. (From our
                        Correspondent.)</head>

                    <p>Assiout, September 24. . It may not be too late to communicate to you a few
                        details of the crime committed on the road to the Oasis. As a matter of
                        fact, the examination of the witnesses ended only re- cently, and it was
                        useless to give details before ascertaining their truth.</p>
                    <p>The policeman, who returned to Assiout with the news of the crime, had
                        sustained three wounds in the head and shoulders, but these proved later to
                        have been self- inflicted. The reason for this self-mutilation was that he
                        himself was the murderer, his anger having been aroused by the fact that his
                        wife had been guilty of improper conduct with one of the camel drivers.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

                    <p>H.H. the Khedive, who attended Friday’s prayers at the Montazsh mosque, will
                        leave Montazah by a special train to-day to visit his Mariout estates.</p>

                    <p>Said Bay Shukair, director of accounts to the Sudan Administration, arrived
                        with his family yesterday by the Messageries boat and proceeded to
                        Cairo.</p>

                    <p>Milhem Shakoor Bey returned to Cairo from the Carlton Hotel, Ramleh,
                        yesterday.</p>

                    <p>Sir Augustus Hemming, who will be accom- panied by Lady and Miss Hemming,
                        will again winter in Egypt, leaving England at the end of October.</p>

                    <p>Our Hellenic contemporaries state that M. Pargalo, Judge of the Alexandria
                        Misted Courts, intends to resign his functions.</p>

                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy, Port Said, we notice : — Major
                        L’Estrange John- stone, Lord Edward Cecil, Captain Roberts, Captain Walker,
                        Charleton Bey, Mr. Wills, Dr. Hayward.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTER TO THE EDITOR. We do not hold ourselves responsible for the
                        opinions expressed by our correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair
                        play to all, to permit - within certain necessary limits - free discussion
                        THE CAIRO CITY POLICE.</head>

                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—It appears to be the fashion "all
                        the year round” for most people who know anything bad about the city police
                        to im- mediately communicate it nicely trimmed to the local press, while
                        those, if there be any, (and I think there must be one every now and then)
                        who happen to know anything good about the members of the force seem always
                        careful to keep it to themselves. I will ask you, if you think it worth
                        while, to give your read- ers particulars of the following case, which I
                        think, most of them will admit, reflects the greatest credit on the city
                        police, as well as on the Parquet and on the present existing ma- chinery
                        and its working, which enabled them to capture and bring the offender to
                        trial in such a very short time.</p>
                    <p>On the 13th inst I reported to the Cairo city police that some handkerchiefs
                        had been stolen from “An Dé Rouge.” Molazim Awal Ahmed Effendi Zeki of the
                        Mouski police dis- trict commenced an investigation of the case, in such a
                        keen, intelligent and effective man- ner, that in a very short time a man
                        was arrested when offering the stolen handkerchiefs for sale in the Fagallah
                        quarter, and another (a Sudan- ese) at the Cairo railway station. The police
                        investigation threw suspicion on a Sudanese servant employed by me. He
                        bolted, and although he lived near the Saida Bl Zeinab quarter, he was
                        cleverly arrested by a native shawish of the city police, when hiding
                        upstairs in a liquor shop off Clot Bey street.</p>
                    <p>To-day the three were brought to trial by the Parquet, and sent to prison
                        with hard labour for six months, i.e. in 15 days from the time the theft was
                        reported to the police. I am, Sir, etc. P. Plunkett Cairo, September 28.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE</head>

                    <p>Vendredi après-midi, 29 septembre Après aa débat relativement sctif, notre
                        marché dm valeurs n'a pas tardé à fléchir dés lundi ; et depuis ee jour, eh
                        .que liste aopvelk- uous a apporté une accentuation de le baisse,
                        jusqu’aojoard’boi où, Us non va) Iss étant mails Uares et la tension
                        monétaire en pleine décroîs sanoe, une reprise géoéraU e ee lien. Néan-
                        moins, l ensembU du marché olôturaau dessous de vendredi dernier.</p>
                    <p>Ce qui e U plus contribué eu mauvais état de notre corbeille durant la
                        semaine qui vient de a’éoouler, c’est sans oontredit la pénurie de
                        numéraire. Celle-ci était si prononcée h 1— que U taux d’moompte y a été
                        porté him det à S f pour oent loi la ri toad on m trouvait encore
                        ooropliquée de deux entres fontenis importants, l’approche de 1e saison
                        cotonnière qui aoreoare toujours h pareille épcqae sac grande partie de
                        l’ergsnt disponible sur pince et 1e nombre considérable de versements à
                        opérer à la fin de oe mois, sans oompèsr Iss liauidationa mensuelles.</p>
                    <p>Un antre nuage, quoique moins bien dessiné, pointait à l'horizon et pesait en
                        sur las valeurs ootém è le Bourse de Paris i le retord dans les négociations
                        frimim sllsmendm Ce nuage est disparu, puisque Iss dépêches nous annoncent
                        le signature de l’acoord. Le tension monétaire semble diminuer graduelle-
                        ment et, las versements de le fin du mois ne* fisis opérée, toot semble
                        faire présager un nouvel élan à la hausse poor la première quin- zaine du
                        mois proohein.</p>
                    <p>On ne sait rien encore de précis soi le situation dm Sacreriea M. Tuok vient
                        de nommer M. Willoocks oomme troisième expert en remplacement de M. Nourimon
                        Bay, qui c’est excusé. Les trois experts travaillent acti- vement à
                        débrouiller le comptabilité de le société, mais oomme ils ne seront
                        probablement pas en mesura de livrer leur rapport à rassem- blée du 4
                        proohaio, il n’est pas impossible qoe la ré ns ion soit renvoyée à une date
                        ultérieure, La valent e été pea échangée an bouse et k cours a fluctué entre
                        50 et 54 francos durant tonte la semaine, jusqu’à os matin où Q ait tombé è
                        42 à la nouvelle de la mort subite de M. de I Bouglise, pour reprendra an
                        clôture à 45 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>L’inauguration dn service de la Cie Men- zaleh entre Portfleïd et Matariah
                        est poor la première semaine de novembre. Cette nouvelle e produit an bon
                        effet sar k marché. Une assemblée dm administrateurs de le Hambnrg-Amerika
                        et de l’Angto-American Line enra lien la semaine prochaine à Londres. On
                        s’attend géuéralement à on accord entre las deux compagnies. Le cous de
                        1’Anglo- American clôture 4 6 5/8 acheteurs, en gaie de 1/16 «nr vendredi
                        passé. </p>
                    <p>La New-Egyptien Cy vient de terminer k vente d’une propriété qu’elk avait
                        achetée de la Dsïre Sanieh U y e an an et demie dans k Haute-Egypte. Le
                        profit net qu'elle a retiré de oette vente s'élève à £50,000. Pou k pre-
                        mière fois depuis la fondation de k société sa 1899, un dividende de 10 pour
                        cent sere dis- tribué à la fin du mois prochain. J</p>
                    <p>La Daira Sanieh qui avait baissé smuihk- maot à la suite du p-oeèa intenté
                        par las phrases de la famille Khédiviale, reprend gra- duellement jurqu'à 28
                        1/8, en dépit dt'i’étai général do marché. Cette hausse de 1/4 est attribuée
                        à l’attitude prim per Lord Cromer vis-à-vis des princes qui Ici demandèrent
                        son appui. Lord Cromer a répondu que noqjeuk- ment il ne les appuierait
                        pas,mais enoote qu'au oas où le gouvernement égyptien aooaeQlmait
                        favorablement leu demande.il m venait obligé de protester de la façon la
                        pins énergique dans l’intérêt do peuple égyptien etdeMontnboahles,</p>
                    <p>Parmi iei valeurs qui ont échappé eu marasme qui a prévalu dorant la asmsinn
                        éoonlée U faut signaler la Banqoe d'Athènes dont le oonrs a tonohé 140 à
                        Paris. loi k maximum atteint a été 187. In c'ôtnre s’effectue à 133 3/4
                        acheteurs. La hausse est attribuée à un projet d'augmentation du oapital pou
                        faire' faee aux nouvelles entreprises de la Banque et en particulier à
                        l’affaira dn monopole dm raisins eeoe.</p>
                    <p>Grâce à une plus-value considérable dm noettes, la Ramleh Railway s'avance de
                        7 1/8 à 7 5/16 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>En hausse également la Land Bank de 9 6/8 à 3 3/1- On annonce l'augmentation
                        prochaine du capital de £500,000 à £1,000,000 par l'émission de 100,000
                        action* nouvelles de £5, reserve aux actionnaires au prix de £7.</p>
                    <p>Après avoir fléchi d'un quart l'Agrioola remonte en clôture à 9 7/16
                        aobeteura.</p>
                    <p>La Banque Nationale olôtnre à 27 1/2, en réaction de 1/lfl»</p>
                    <p>La Delta L-ght reste immobile pendant toute la semaine entre 13 8/16 et 18
                        1/4. Bn dépit d’nne aagmenta4ion des mettes, les Tramways restent
                        stationnaires à 159 les Privilegiees et a 322-320 les Dividendes.</p>
                    <p>Les Baux dn Caire sont en baisse de 10 franos à 1155, tandis que l’Alexandria
                        Water est en hausse de 1/16 à 15 1/8.</p>
                    <p>Pour les Markets la semaine clôtura avec 3 pence en moins à 95-95/3.</p>
                    <p>Tandis que la Crown Brewery male à 908 la Privilégiée et à 111 la Dividende,
                        en réaction respective de 10 et 8 francs, la Brasserie dre Pyramides gsgne 1
                        frano sur la Privilégiée et ne perd'qu’un frano pour la Dividende.</p>
                    <p>Les Cotton Mills restent sansehengementài La Sait and Soda clôture à 88/9-84.
                        Quant à l’Investment et eu Trust leur situa- tion se résume par une perte de
                        1/16 eu ooun de 1 5/16.</p>
                    <p>Les plus éprouvés de ore petites valeurs per ’e réaction, les Estâtes ont été
                        les première h reprendre. Ce matin ils ont regagné tout k terrain perdu et
                        clôturé en forte demande à 14.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
