<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-11-16">November 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-13">13 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="international" source="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PEACE CONFERENCE. CHINESE INTERESTS. NOTE TO THE POWERS.</head>
                        <dateline>Peking, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>China has notified the Powers that she will refuse to recognise the
                            arrangements made by the Peace Conference concerning Chinese interests
                            unless she is consulted. Japan has replied that the notification will in
                            nowise affect her plan of action. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE JAPANESE LOAN.</head>

                        <dateline>Berlin, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>The German section of the Japanese loan is largely over-subscribed.
                            (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. FURTHER DISCUSSION.</head>
                        <dateline>Berlin, July 12. </dateline>
                        <p>It is asserted that, though the Franco-German negotiations are not
                            concluded, now that M. Rouvier has accepted the conference, Germany is
                            prepared to enter into a more detailed discussion as to her aims, and
                            the purpose of the conference. (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE “ENTENTE CORDIALE.” FESTIVITIES AT BREST.</head>
                        <dateline>Brest, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>The festivities are going on with extraordinary cordiality. The British
                            and French Admirals and officers are luncheoning and banqueting. The
                            crews are thronging the streets and fraternising in the cafes. (Reuter.)
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ENGLAND AND ABYSSINIA. FRONTIER DISPUTE ENDED.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>An arrangement has been concluded between Great Britain and Abyssinia by
                            which the long-standing dispute as to the western frontier is ended.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A NEW MAHDI.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>Reuter’s Agency learns that a new Mahdi has appeared on the coast in the
                            district to the east of Berbera. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ACCOUCHEMENT OF PRINCESS OF WALES.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>The Princess of Wales has given birth to a son. (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW RUSSIAN MARINE MINISTER.</head>
                        <dateline>St. Petersburg, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>Admiral Birileff has been appointed Minister of Marine. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SEIZURE OF BOMBS AT TIFLIS.</head>
                        <dateline>Batum, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>Four persons, possessing altogether 119 bombs, have been arrested
                            separately at Tiflis. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRENCH SENATE.</head>
                        <dateline>Paris, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>The Senate has adopted by 243 to 14 the amnesty mentioned on the 27th
                            June. (R.)</p>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Paris, July 12.</dateline>
                            <p>The Senate has voted the amnesty for those sentenced by the Haute
                                Cour. (Havas.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WALES COLLIERY EXPLOSION.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>There were 125 men killed at the colliery explosion at Wattstown.
                            (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FIRE IN A COLLIERY. </head>
                        <dateline>Dortmund, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>Thirty-nine men have been hopelessly entombed in a colliery here, on
                            account of a fire. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ACCIDENT ON H.M.S.“IMPLACABLE”</head>
                        <dateline>Gibraltar, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>Two men have been killed and seven injured by the bursting of a
                            steam-pipe on the battleship Implacable. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item" scope="sporting">
                        <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                        <p>The Players beat the Gentlemen by 140 runs. Australians beat Derbyshire
                            by 105 runs. Northamptonshire beat Hampshire by 231 runs. Sussex v.
                            Leicestershire drawn. (Reuter.) </p>
                        <cb/>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suakin Province.</head>
                        <p>The head-quarters of Suakin Province were moved to Erkowit (temporarily)
                            yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records a fatal case at Alexandria and another at
                            Port-Said. The former was that of a young native girl who was found dead
                            at her home at Tonbughie.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suicide.</head>
                        <p>A skin-seller named Salim Ghonaim, who is believed to have suffered from
                            domestic troubles, hanged himself at 3 a.m. yesterday at Mazar. An
                            inquiry has been opened.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>9 vessels passed through the Canal on the 10th inst., 4 of which were
                            British, 2 French, 2 German, 1 Spanish. The day’s receipts were frs. 278
                            625, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 2,920,349.34.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Land Bank.</head>
                        <p>The committee of the London Stock Exchange have been asked to appoint a
                            special settling day in Land Bank of Egypt—Bearer warrants for 95,000
                            ordinary shares of £5 each, fully paid.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Investment and Agency, Ltd.</head>
                        <p>A mortgage or charge, dated 15th June, 1905, to secure £50,000, has been
                            registered. Property charged—The whole of the company’s present uncalled
                            capital—namely, 15s. per share on 200,000 shares. Holders —
                            Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Ltd., Alexandria. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Mex Affair.</head>
                        <p>The owner of Al Hillal dispensary, the body of whose brother, Metri
                            Kanaan, was recently found near Mex and noted at the Government Hospital
                            as that of a Sudanese, has submitted a memorial to the Parquet with full
                            details of the disappearance of the dead man. We hear that Sir Horace
                            Pinching Pasha has been investigating the affair, and that the
                            responsibility for the error has been fixed.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>St. Andrew’s Girls’ Lower School.</head>
                        <p>The annual exhibition and prize distribution took place in this school
                            yesterday, when, before a large gathering of parents and friends, a
                            varied and interesting programme was submitted. The Rev. H. P. Reid
                            occupied the chair. Songs and recitations in English, French, Italian,
                            and Arabic elicited hearty applause, while a display of musical drill
                            was greatly appreciated. The whole performance was excellent, and
                            reflects the highest credit upon Mrs. Gibb and her assistants. Mrs. Reid
                            presented the prizes to the successful pupils, amongst whom we
                            especially mention C. Grilla, who won a medal for Scripture knowledge,
                            presented by Major Allan of Glasgow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cairo Tramways.</head>
                        <p>The Cairo Tramway Company’s steamer service between Rod el Farag and the
                            Delta Barrage has now been modified as follows : Departures take place
                            from Rod el Farag every Friday at 5 p.m. and Sunday at 8.30 a.m. and 5
                            p.m., and from the Barrage every Friday at 7.15 p.m. and Sunday at 11
                            a.m. and 7.15 p.m. Every Thursday and Saturday steamers leave Rod el
                            Farag at 2 p.m. for a two hours’ excursion on the Nile. From the 13th to
                            the 19th inst. inclusive there will be a moonlight service to the
                            Barrage, leaving Rod el Farag at 8.30 p.m. and the Barrage at 10.30 p.m.
                            On the above-mentioned dates trams will run on the Rod el Farag line
                            until the return of the boat. On the Pyramids line there will be a
                            moonlight service on the 14th, 15th, 16tn, and 17th inst., the last tram
                            leaving Kasr-el-Nil at 10 and 11 p.m. and the Pyramids at 10.50 and
                            11.50 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="sporting">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <head type="sub">KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB. REGATTA.</head>
                    <p>The following is the result of yesterday’s regatta :—</p>
                    <table rows="6" cols="4">
                        <head>Class I.</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>Boat.</cell>
                            <cell>Start.</cell>
                            <cell>Finish.</cell>
                            <cell>Sailed by</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell role="label">1 Minnie</cell>
                            <cell>3.30.06</cell>
                            <cell>4.59.49</cell>
                            <cell>N.W.deCourcy</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Coot</cell>
                            <cell>3.34.11</cell>
                            <cell>5.01.37</cell>
                            <cell>A. S. Preston</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Sans Pareille</cell>
                            <cell>3.52.04</cell>
                            <cell>5.01.50</cell>
                            <cell>Mr. de Tchudi</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Banshee</cell>
                            <cell>3.46.20</cell>
                            <cell>5.02.40</cell>
                            <cell>I. McClure</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Leman</cell>
                            <cell>3.42.15</cell>
                            <cell>5.42.15</cell>
                            <cell>Mr. de Planta</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table rows="6" cols="2">
                        <head>Class II.</head>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Derpbil</cell>
                            <cell>3.55.12</cell>
                            <cell>5.30.13</cell>
                            <cell>Prince Aziz</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Akraba</cell>
                            <cell>3.58.22</cell>
                            <cell>5.31.40</cell>
                            <cell>Sagh. Phillips</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Masr</cell>
                            <cell>4.08.19</cell>
                            <cell>5.34.42</cell>
                            <cell>Mr. Ravelli</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Calypso</cell>
                            <cell>4.14.24</cell>
                            <cell>5.35.53</cell>
                            <cell>" O. Werner</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Shamrock</cell>
                            <cell>4.04.45</cell>
                            <cell>5.35.57</cell>
                            <cell>Lieut. Basset</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tanta</cell>
                            <cell>4.04.57</cell>
                            <cell>5.37.20</cell>
                            <cell>Mr. E. Gentili</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The Jessica, when rounding Gabbary buoy on a wind, was unfortunately run into
                        on the port bow and out down to the water line by the Celtic, of Class I.,
                        which was coming down before the wind to round the same buoy. </p>
                    <p>Assistance was rendered by the Celtic and Tier-el-Mina and both of these
                        boats of course lost their race. </p>
                    <p>The gap cut in the Jessica was stopped up with canvas and she put into
                        dry-dock at Gabbary, where she discharged all her ballast. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the
                        Terrace. ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.
                        BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEEF BREMEN. Obtainable from every Respectable Firm
                        In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the Sudan. Otherwise apply to V. J. FLEURENT,
                        Cairo F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE YEMEN RISING.</head>
                    <head type="sub">ADVANCE OF TURKS IN FORCE.</head>
                    <dateline>Aden, July 12.</dateline>
                    <p>The Turks are preparing to advance in great force from Hodeida and Tais
                        simultaneously against Sanaa. It is feared that the rising will become
                        general. (Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>“Die Post” gives the following summary of the position in the Yemen :— </p>
                    <p>The insurrectionary movement in the Yemen has given the Ottoman authorities
                        more trouble than ever, though the military authorities appear to be acting
                        with the necessary energy to prevent any further extension and continuation
                        of the troubles, which might lead to a most serious situation in conjunction
                        with the disturbances in the European portion of the Empire. A Turkish
                        officer who has returned from Arabia gives the following interesting details
                        which are not marked by any excessive optimism. </p>
                    <p>He states that the number of the followers of tho insurgent Sheikh Mohamed
                        Yehya, instead of reaching 150,000 men, does not greatly exceed 40,000. At
                        the opening of the campaign not more than four or five thousand armed
                        guerillas were in the field, but their numbers rose rapidly as the Arab
                        troops of the Turkish Expeditionary Corps surrendered to them and the
                        Yemenis, emboldened by each of their successes and especially by the capture
                        of Sanaa, joined them. The present strength of the rebels is formidable
                        enough, if the climatic conditions, from which the Turkish soldier suffers
                        terribly, are taken into account, </p>
                    <p>Tho present Turkish force consists of three full brigades — Albanians, Lazes,
                        and Turks, who are absolutely reliable, unlike the Syrian and Arab
                        conscripts. The despatch of soldiers to the front continues. Meantime the
                        communications and transport of the force are being assured and a large
                        number of transport mules are being sent from the Syrian Coast to the
                        Arabian ports. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>MESOPOTAMIA. SIR Wm. WILLCOCKS’S SCHEME.</head>
                    <p>Sir William Willcocks’s scheme for the irrigation of Mesopotamia is made the
                        excuse for a letter in the “National Zeitung," again pleading for the
                        participation of British capital in the construction of the Bagdad Railway.
                        The letter declares that the English see in the irrigation scheme a
                        possibility of obtaining the construction of the Bagdad-Basra section of the
                        line, which, the writer asserts, will be cheaper than the southern (?
                        northern) portion, as it presents no natural difficulties, and, therefore,
                        Germany must not allow it to fall into British hands. The letter continues:—
                        “In view of the Emperor's great personal influence in the East, Sir William
                        Willcocks will not prevail with the Sultan; but I am convinced that if Great
                        Britain and Germany combined their interests, the desired concession would
                        be granted.” The writer then expatiates on the beneficial effects to be
                        expected from irrigation in Mesopotamia by promoting cotton-growing and the
                        cultivation of corn, barley, dates and tobacco. These benefits, he thinks,
                        would be felt by the Bagdad Railway, which would profit by the increased
                        passenger and goods traffic. He concludes by expressing the hope that Sir
                        William Willcocks’s scheme may be amalgamated with the Bagdad Railway, so
                        that Germany, France (who is already interested to the extent of 40 per
                        cent. of the capital), and Great Britain would take part in it. He declares,
                        however, that the management of the whole undertaking must remain in German
                        hands.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE RION AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Thursday.</dateline>
                    <p>The Russian cruiser Rion arrived here at six o’clock last evening and sails
                        for Libau at four o’clock to-day. She has taken on 500 tons of coal besides
                        water and provisions. Her armament consist of 14 4.7-in. guns and 21 of
                        smaller calibre. She has collision mats and hydraulic ammunition lifts, and
                        has naval officers and crew on board. Visits were exchanged to-day between
                        the commander of the cruiser and that of H.M.S. Suffolk. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>SUDAN APPOINTMENTS.</head>
                    <p>El Kaimakam Angus Cameron Bey, Acting Senior Inspector, Upper Nile Province,
                        has been appointed a magistrate of the first class under the Criminal
                        Procedure Code. </p>
                    <p>El Miralai A. Sutherland Bey has been named Acting Governor, Bahr-el-Ghazal
                        Province. </p>
                    <p>Mr. G. C. Kerr, Deputy Inspector, to be Junior Inspector, Suakin Province. </p>
                    <p>Mr. C. E. Lyall, Deputy Inspector, to be Junior Inspector, Kordofan Province. </p>
                    <p>Mr. S. Skirmunt is appointed Deputy Inspector, Woods and Forests Department.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. Equated arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria
                        yesterday morning. </p>
                    <p>The Westcott S.S. Joshua Nicholson left Malta yesterday and is due here on
                        Sunday from Antwerp and London. </p>
                    <p>The Papayanni S.S. Austrian left Malta this morning and is due at this port
                        on Sunday. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE LATE GRAND MUFTI. IMPOSING FUNERAL.</head>
                    <p>A large crowd assembled at the Cairo station about 2 o’clock yesterday
                        afternoon to await the arrival of the special train conveying the mortal
                        remains of the late Sheikh Mohamed Abdou from Alexandria for interment in
                        the Capital. The train drew up at platform No. 1. exactly at 2.36 p.m. and
                        as soon as it came to a standstill the many who had accompanied the body
                        from Alexandria dismounted and swelled the number who were waiting on the
                        platform. The large assembly then gathered round the carriage in which the
                        coffin had been placed. When the doors were opened, and the bearers had
                        mournfully raised the bier on their shoulders the crowd parted and silently
                        stood aside to admit the passage of the coffin, which was carried to a room
                        opening on to the platform, there to await the appointed hour-of four
                        o'clock when the funeral cortege would leave the station. The room in which
                        the coffin lay was closed and guarded by four policemen. </p>
                    <p>Meanwhile the crowd grew larger and larger, but the people were not admitted
                        to the platform, which was reserved for those who were to form the cortege,
                        and the entrance soon became so crowded that access to the platform was a
                        matter of considerable difficulty. Shortly after half-past three the
                        mourners began to arrive and increased in numbers continuously until 4 p.m.
                        Every Ministry and public office was fully represented ; Egyptian and
                        English officials alike had come to pay their last homage to a man who had
                        played throughout his public life an eventful part in the Mohamedan world of
                        Egypt, and who had gained the respect and admiration of all who came in
                        contact with him, even of those who actively opposed his ideas and schemes. </p>
                    <p>At four o’clock the coffin was carried out of the room where it had been laid
                        and the procession, leaving the station by the side exit, started on its way
                        to the place of burial. The procession was headed by an officer of the
                        mounted police, and after him came twelve other mounted police, who were
                        followed by fifty foot police in double file. Next came the coffin, a simple
                        bier without adornment, and only covered by a cloth, as is the custom with
                        those belonging to the Mohamedan religion, and this was carried by ten men,
                        several of whom wore the green turban. The bier was followed by a large
                        number of the students of the University of Al Azhar, and these were
                        followed by the lawyers and judges of the Native Tribunals in their robes of
                        office. The English representatives of the various Ministries and public
                        offices and of the Army of Occupation followed. Mr. P. W. Machell, Adviser
                        to the Ministry of the Interior, the Hon. C. James, Mr. Moberley, Mansfield
                        Pasha, Commandant of Police, Brig.-General Bollock, Sir H. Pinching,
                        Director General of the Sanitary Department, Mr. Goodman, Mr. W. Swanson,
                        representing the Ministry of Public Instruction, and many others had come to
                        take part in this procession, and behind these was a large number of those
                        who have been connected with the work of the deceased. </p>
                    <p>It was an immense and most impressive and solemn cortege, and as it passed
                        along it was swelled by the crowds who lined the streets. All traffic in the
                        streets through which the procession passed was stopped, and the huge crowds
                        stood silent and respectful until it had passed them. It appeared indeed as
                        if the whole native population of Cairo had come to pay their last respects
                        to the great Sheikh, and Europeans were also present in large numbers. The
                        procession passed along Sharia Bab-el-Hadid, Sharia Kamel and Opera-square,
                        where the English representatives left it, and it then continued across
                        Ataba el-Khadra-square, the Mousky, and Sikkat Guedidah to the Mosque of Al
                        Azhar, where the customary ceremony previous to interment took place, and
                        there the procession was reformed and wended its way to the cemetery of
                        Megawreen, where the body was laid in its final resting place. </p>
                    <p>Our Tahta correspondent telegraphs :--The death of the Grand Mufti has caused
                        unspeakable lamentation here. All the people condole with each other for the
                        irreparable loss and implore the divine blessing on the dead sheikh. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Prince and Princess Arisugawa of Japan, who have been on a visit to England,
                        left London on Tuesday on their return to Japan by the Norddeutscher Lloyd
                        S.S. Preussen, which is due at Port Said on the 24th inst. </p>
                    <p>We are glad to hear that Miss Odeh, daughter of Rev. and Mrs. N. Odeh, who
                        has been resident at the Cheltenham Ladies College for the last three years,
                        has been awarded by the council of the college a Hay Scholarship, of £30 a
                        year, tenable for three years at St. Hilda’s Hall, Oxford, beginning next
                        term. She hopes to prepare for the Final Honor School of Modern History. </p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Carlton Hotel, Ramlen, we notice : Mr. S.
                        Ades, Major and Mrs. Cave, Mr. and Mrs. P. Adamopoulo, M. and Mme B. J.
                        Moussalli Bey and family, Mr. and Mrs. Calamaro and family. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA. 2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>MACLEAN-ROYLE WEDDING. CEREMONY IN LONDON YESTERDAY.</head>
                    <byline>( From our Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <dateline>London, July 12.</dateline>
                    <p>A very pretty wedding took place to-day at St. George’s Church,
                        Hanover-square. where Captain Charles Wilberforce Maclean, of the Lancashire
                        Fusiliers, (attached to the Egyptian Army), son of the late Colonel Allan
                        Maclean, R. A., and grandson of the late General Maclean, of Rowlands,
                        Wimborne, and Lazoneby Hall, Cumberland, was married to Miss Gladys Royle,
                        only daughter of Mr. and Mrs. George Royle, of Cairo. </p>
                    <p>St. George’s Church, Hanover-square, specially popular for smart weddings,
                        and within the past month both the King and Queen, with Princess Victoria,
                        were present there for Lady Alexandra Acheson’s marriage with the Earl of
                        Derby’s son. The music and singing are of a very high-class order, and Dr.
                        Jolly, the organist, played finely at to-day’s wedding, as he has done at
                        previous ceremonies, his choir acquitting themselves admirably. The hymns
                        sung were, “Lead us, heavenly Father, lead us” and “O perfect Love!” While
                        the register was being signed Mendelssohn’s anthem from Elijah, “He shall
                        give His Angels charge over thee,” rendered beautifully, and the Wedding
                        March was a splendid finale. Mr. Douglas Morice and Mr. Maclean, the
                        bridegroom’s brother, acted as ushers and the numerous guests were shown to
                        the seats appointed for them without the slightest confusion or delay. </p>
                    <p>The ceremony was performed by the Rev. David Anderson, Rector of St.
                        George’s, who at the head of the choir met the bride at the entrance of the
                        church and preceded her to the altar. There the bridegroom was waiting
                        attended by his best man, Major Hawker, Coldstream Guards. Miss Royle, who
                        was given away by her father, wore a lovely Princess robe of rich Brussels
                        applique lace over silvered net, and trimmed at the foot with a Vandyck
                        flounce, from which branches of embroidered raised silver lilies tapered to
                        the waist, the leaves of the flowers being edged with a tiny lace frill. A
                        spray of the embroidery crossed the corsage, which was softened by a large
                        square lace collar, and there were pretty lace elbow sleeves. With this robe
                        was worn a courttrain of gauged spot net each gauging separated by a band of
                        fine old point de Gaze lace, and garlands of the embroidered silver lilies
                        were introduced, matching the embroidery on the robe. The bride wore no
                        ornaments. Her tulle veil fell over a chaplet of orange blossoms and she
                        carried a sheaf of white lilies. The brides maids were Miss Victoria Royle,
                        Miss Hermie and Miss Violet Beauchamp (the bride’s cousins), Miss Daisy and
                        Miss Gertrude Maclean (sisters of the bridegroom), Miss Margaret Maclean
                        (his cousin), Miss Ella Rayne, and Miss Ethel Lambert. They wore charming
                        gowns of white blonde lace on soft white satin, the bottom of the skirts
                        trimmed with Empire wreaths of pink chiffon roses, set in by garlands of
                        blue ribbon, run through the lace. The tops of the bodices were
                        transparent,—and two bretelles of blue ribbon, veiled in lace, crossed the
                        shoulders and finished under a deep folded belt of blue satin, trimmed at
                        the back with little rosettes and short folded ends. A butterfly bow of lace
                        was fastened in the front of the bodice with festoons of the pink rose; with
                        small green foliage falling at each side. The elbow sleeves were in two
                        puffs, divided by a bracelet of blue ribbon and a single pink rose, and
                        terminated in lace ruffles. The pretty hats were made of white tulle,
                        narrowly frilled with blonde lace. The round brims were very much raised off
                        the face in front, and to one side, and out away at the back, which was
                        filled in with a bow, and ends of wide blue ribbon edged with lace. The
                        crowns were encircled by a band of blue ribbon and inside on the raised brim
                        were a large cluster of little pink roses and foliage and a blue bow. The
                        bridegroom gave the bridesmaids bouquets of pink banksia roses tied with
                        blue streamers, and turquoise and pearl pendants- dresses, hats, bouquets
                        and ornaments making a beautiful harmony of delicate pompadour colouring. </p>
                    <p> After the ceremony, Mrs. Royle held a reception at 22, Charles St.,
                        Barkeley-sqnare, kindly lent by Miss Warmald, which was numerously and
                        fashionably attended. Among those present were: —Sir F.R. and Lady Wingate,
                        Sir Ronald and Lady Lane, Sir George and Lady Faudel Phillips, Col. Allan
                        Maclean, Sir James and Lady Heath, Judge Royle, Capt. and Mrs Middleman, Sir
                        Fitzroy Donald and Lady and Miss Maclean, Mr. and Mrs. Douglas Morice, Capt.
                        Gaisford, Sir Gerald Fitzgerald, Mr. and Mrs. Greville Palmer, Col. Friend,
                        Capt. St. Clair MacEwen, Mr. and Mrs. Scott-Dalgleish, Capt. and Mrs. George
                        Hunter, Baroness Malortie, Capt. C. H. Leveson, Col. and Mrs. St. John Gore,
                        Sir Charles and Lady Cayzer, Capt. O’Sullivan, Capt. and Mrs. Hay, Col. and
                        Mrs. Bernard, Capt. and Mrs. Muter, Capt. and Mrs. Way, Mrs. H. Dudgeon, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Barton Stewart, Capt. C. McKay, Sir Thomas and Lady Sutherland, Mr.
                        Rosing, Mr. and Mrs. Favarger, Capt McLeod, Viscount Errington, Mrs. Cassel,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Snow, General, Mrs. and Miss Slade, Hon. Arthur and Mrs. Davey,
                        Sir John and Lady Denison Pender, Mr. Joseph, Mrs. Dilberoglue, Dr. and Mrs.
                        Warnock, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Mond, Sir Auckland Colvin, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Shakoor, Dr. and Mrs. Sandwith, Sir William and Lady Willcocks, Col. A.
                        Harington. Capt. Percival, Judge and Mrs. Satow, Maj.-General Kekewich, Mr.
                        Somerset Maclean, Major and Mrs. Delavoye, Sir Eldon and Lady Gorst, Colonel
                        Nason, Captain Charlton, Major Garcia, Sir John and Lady Rogers, General Sir
                        A. Lyttleton Annesley, etc. </p>
                    <p>Later in the afternoon the bride and bridegroom left for Haywood-park,
                        Maidenhead (lent for the honeymoon by Mr. Granville Palmer), the bride
                        wearing a soft white </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>CAIRO WATER SUPPLY. DR. BITTER'S REPORT.</head>
                    <p>We have received from the Cairo Water Company Dr. Bitter’s report upon the
                        water as at present supplied to the greater number of the Cairo districts
                        from the artesian wells at Rod-el-Farag, and we give below a translation of
                        this report:— </p>
                    <p>“The water of the wells is absolutely clear and limpid and without colour. It
                        has no smell and is of a very pleasant taste. Its temperature is 23 Cent.
                        The water contains no bacteria and is sterile. </p>
                    <p>“In comparing the chemical analysis of the well-water and of the Nile water
                        one sees that there is no very pronounced difference between the two. There
                        is only the hydrometric degree which was greater in the case of the
                        well-water. </p>
                    <p>“During the time of the high Nile the well-water is about twice as hard as
                        the Nile water, but this difference decreases during low Nile, to such an
                        extent that, during the month of May for example, the rates of hydrometric
                        degree of the two waters is reduced to 7 : 5. </p>
                    <p>“The high hydrometric degree of the well water is due to the presence of a
                        larger quantity of calcium bicarbonate and magnesium bicarbonate, and not to
                        an increase in the quantity of calcium sulphate. On the contrary, the
                        well-water contains less sulphuric acid than the Nile water, especially when
                        the Nile is at low-water mark. </p>
                    <p>“In other respects the hydrometric degree of the well-water is very moderated
                        and the water of the Embabeh wells can be considered as a very sweet water.
                        A considerable amount of the water used for drinking in the large towns of
                        England, Germany, and France him the same degree of hardness or is even
                        still harder. A water is generally considered as distinctly hard only when
                        its hydrometric degree exceeds 30 French degrees, and the hydrometric degree
                        of the well-water of Embabeh is about 20. </p>
                    <p>“The calcium contained in the well-water is almost exclusively in the form of
                        calcium bicarbonate and gives to this water a particularly fresh and
                        agreeable taste, which we are accustomed to find in good water springs. This
                        constitutes a real advantage in comparison with Nile water, which contains
                        much less carbonic acid. The well water also contains less sodium chloride
                        than the Nile water. During low Nile the amount of salt found in Nile water
                        is about 2 1/2 times as great as that found in the well-water. </p>
                    <p>One can consider the well-water as having the same origin as the Nile water,
                        i.e., as a Nile water naturally filtered through beds of soil. But this
                        filtration has not taken place in the proximity of the wells; it must have
                        traversed for a considerable length the underground beds, as is proved by
                        the differences in the chemical analyses and by the constant temperature of
                        the well-water (a temperature equal to the annual mean temperature). It may
                        thus be described as the water of the subterranean Nile which accompanies
                        the superficial Nile and has the same origin as the latter. </p>
                    <p>“The taste of the Nile water does not differ sensibly from that of the
                        well-water. Most people, and especially the Arabs, are unable to distinguish
                        with certainty the two waters, as I have been able to prove by direct
                        experiments. </p>
                    <p>“The well-water is a drinkable water of the first quality as much from the
                        point of chemical analysis as from the point of taste, and especially from
                        the fact that it is absolutely free of living germs. </p>
                    <p>“Being given the geological configuration of the aquiferous beds and the
                        construction of the wells it is absolutely impossible for this water to
                        become contaminated by the filration of unhealthy water. During the three
                        years that two of these wells have been worked almost continuously day and
                        night to the amount of about 4,000 cubic metres each per day, the chemical
                        composition of the water has remained unchanged. </p>
                    <p>“The water of the Embabeh wells ranks, therefore, amongst the best of the
                        natural drinking waters known, and the town Cairo may be congratulated on
                        possessing a supply of drinkable water which is no way inferior to the best
                        waters of the whole world.” </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <p>mousseline de soie richly incrusted with renaissance lace in handsome design.
                        The bodice was draped en bolero with front of the mousseline de soie,
                        inserted with lace, and there was a folded belt of soft white satin, the
                        belt and bodice trimmed prettily with little satin bows. The picture hat was
                        of white tulle in soft cloudy frills, and with a wreath of pink heather and
                        roses round the crown, tied at the back with a blue ribbon bow. Mrs. Boyle
                        wore a most becoming gown made of light blue satin veiled in blue chiffon
                        and again in chiffon of a rich tone of purple. The skirt was finely gauged
                        and trimmed at the foot with garlands of chiffon. An effective touch was a
                        band of wide chene ribbon at the foot on the blue chiffon underskirt,
                        showing through with charming result. The gauged bodice had frills of creamy
                        silk lace about the neck, and a bow of blue and silver shot tissue was
                        fastened at the bust, and the waistband was of purple ribbon. On the
                        graceful sleeves, the pale blue chiffon appeared as small puffs under a
                        loose elbow sleeve veiled by the darker fabric. The toque, smartly turned up
                        at the wide back, was slightly pealed in front, and made of tulle matching
                        the gown, embroidered with ribbon straw to match ribbon and finished by a
                        handsome purple ostrich feather. Mrs. Murray Cookesley, who gave the bride
                        her fine painting of “Circe resplendens” as a wedding present, wore a
                        picturesque dress designed by herself, made of pearl great voile, under a
                        tunic of rare gold lace, the bodice embroidered with pearls. A pearl fringe
                        finished the white satin sleeves, and there was a belt of the same satin.
                        The toque was composed of grey ostrich feathers and white roses.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
