<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> <div type="item">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. TUESDAY APRIL 25,1905.</head></div>
<div type="item">
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

<p>A Bedouin's Hut at Hadra was destroyed
by fire on Saturday.</p>

<p>An Irish Dinner will be held at Shepheard's
Hotel on Saturday next.</p>

<p>Automobile Accident.</p><p>—A native was run over and serioudy injured by an automobile in Rosetta road on Sunday.</p>

<p>Al Azhar.</p><p> Ahmed Ronfayi, of the Majekite rite, has been appointed member of the University board.</p>

<p>Tramway Accident.</p><p>—A young native girl of 2 years was run over by a tramcar at Minet-el Bassal and had her left leg crushed.</p>

<p>A Clean Sheet</p><p> - During the last 24 hours, no incident occured at Alexandria which called for the intervention of the police.</p>

<p>Sanitary Department:</p><p> —Dr. Khalil Ibrahim Meskakah and Anne Samara, midwife, have been authorised to follow their professions in Egypt.</p>

<p>Senaar Province.</p><p>—The headquarters of the Senaar Province are to be transferred to Singa, which is much nearer the frontier of Abyssinia.</p>

<p>Egyptian Army.</p><p> -The 7th Battalion will arrive at Alexandria from Cairo on the 29th inst. and will be stationed at Ras-el-Tin during the Khedive's stay at Alexandria.</p>   

<p>Marsa Matrouh.</p><p>—The Legislative Council has postponed all consideration of the administrative regulations regarding Marsa Matrouh until next month.</p>

<p>Rain fell at Cairo yesterday evening and the weather was delightfully cool after the terrific beat that lasted from Wednesday last till Saturday night.</p>

<p>Asile Runolph.</p><p>—The Alexandria Shooting Club at Round Point have sent 149 pigeons for the use of the Home Piot Bey has presented the aisle with four lamps.</p>

<p>Bandmann Opra Company.</p><p> — "The Duchess of Dantzig" will be given on Saturday, and Saturday's piece ("Veronique”) will be transferred to Thursday, on which date it is hoped that H.H. the Khedive will visit the Opera House.</p>

<p>"The Cyprus Journal" for April contains contributions on “Agricultural Banks,” “Effects of Irrigation,” ‘ Sheep-pox and Quarter-ill,” “Sweet Potatoes as a Stock Food,” etc.</p>

<p>Gatti’s Circus</p><p> -A special performance, reserved to members of the British colony, is to be given by the troupe at the Albambra on Thursday afternoon at 4 o’clock. The programme will contain tome special attractions.</p>

<p>Record Shipment.</p><p>—543 fowls and 13,960 eggs were exported to Egypt on 31st March by the mail steamer from Cyprus. Such a shipment from Cyprus has hitherto been unknown</p>

<p>Suez Canal</p><p> —23 vessels passed through the Canal on the 20th and 21st inst. Of these 17 were British, 2 German, 1 Austrian, 1 Dutch, 1 French, 1 Norwegian. The receipts for the two days were frs. 662,271.81, making the total from the 1st inst frs. 7,136,801.40.</p>

<p>Stray and Ownerless Doos found in the Esbekieh quarter of Cairo during to-night and at dawn to-morrow, and in the Abdeen diatrict during to-morrow night and dawn on Thursday, will be poisoned by the police.</p>

<p>Railway Reforms.</p><p>—The Finance Ministry has opened a credit of L. E. 950,000 out of the total of L. E. 4,000,000 for the E.R.A. No less than ninety sets of lavatories are to be set up at various stations, at an average cost of L. E. 100 each.</p>

<p>National Bank.</p><p>—The London Stock Exchange Committee have ordered the undermentioned security to be quoted in the Official List: National Bank of Egypt, further issue of 50,000 shares of £10 each, fully paid, Nos. 200,001 to 250,000.</p>

<p>Alexandria Police.</p><p>—About a hundred pupils from the Police School at Boulac have arrived at Alexandria in order to be incorporated in the different kisms, with the rank of non-comissioned officers. They were reviewed at the Gouvernorat this morning.</p>

<p>War Office.</p><p>—By decision of the council of discipline and sentence of the special court of discipline, two 4th class employes, Nasser Eff. Husni and Said Effendi El Zeini, of the Financial Secretary's Office, have been discharged for behaviour unbecoming to Government employes.</p>

<p>Concert.</p><p>—A vocal and instrumental concert will be given at the New Khedivial Hotel, Alexandria, on Sunday, May 7, at 5 p,m., by Prof. Luigi Calise, singing master, who will be assisted by a number of well-known local vocalists and instrumentalists. The programme is a well-chosen one, containing such names as Mozart, Chopin, Massenet, Verdi, Mascagni, Leoncavallo, Puccini, Tosti, etc.  </p>

<p>Alhambra Theatre.</p><p>—The Magnani operetta company is due to arrive at Alexandria from Italy on Sunday next and will open at this theatre a few days afterwards. The company numbers some well-known, artistes, and the repertory coutains such pieces as Ali Baba, La Modella, In Cerca di Felicita, II Giro del Mondo, Primavera Scapigliata, besides all the favorites.</p>

<p>The Sultan’s Rule</p><p> —Mrs. G. King Lewis has written a book entitied “Critical Times in Turkey and England’s Responsibility." The publisher's advertisement states ”No one could for a moment suspeot her of exaggerating or building up a tale. All the more terrible is the conclusion to which her narrative forces us, that the half has not been told of the atrocities of the Sultan's rule.”</p>

<p>Important Trial.</p><p>—The Alexandria Native Tribunal, at its sitting on May 2, will have to try seventeen persons implicated in a serious brawl at El Kamaies (Marsa Matrouh). The accused are all incarcerated in Hadra prison. Some of them are charged with a double murder and two attempted murders, while the rest have to answer a of killing one man and wounding two others. The affray arose out of a dispute over the ownership of a plot of land, which in reality belonged to the Government.</p>

<p>Suicide, from Love.</p><p> — An Italian girl, belonging to a respectable artisan family living in Anastasi street, Alexandria, committed suicide early this morning. For some time past she had loved a compatriot and her passion had been reciprocated, but her parents looked coldly on the young man's suit. The girl therefore proceeded to the latrine this morning aud imbibed a dose of poison to which she succumbed. She was about 20 years of age and of prepossessing appearance.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN MINING.
THE UM RUS CRUSHING.</head>
<p>As the Egyptian Market was sorely in need of a pick-me-up, the first results of crushing operations on the Um Rus were doubly welcome in London last week. Certainly for a beginner the mine makes a very creditable showing. In fact, market anticipations have been well exceeded, as, instead of a 10-dwt. average as expected, the total yield of 351 ozs. from the 445 tons of ore put through the mill gives an average value of 15 dwis. to the ton, besides which, it is stated, there are an extra 3 dwts. in the tailings. As a good 6 dwts. may be reckoned to have been lost over the new plates, under proper working conditions there is every justification for the belief that the Um Rus will turn out a 1-oz. proposition.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN TRUST AND INVESTMENT.</head>
<p>We are authorised by the general manager of the Egyptian Trust aud Investment, Limited, to state that the excess cheques in respect to applications marked 1,001 to 1,500, Alexandria, are now ready at the offices of the company and can be obtained between the hours of 9 a.m. and 12 noon.</p>
<p>The excess cheques in respect to applications marked 1,501 and upwards will be ready at the offices of tho company, 6 rue de I'aucienne Bourse, to-morrow morning and can also be obtained between the hours of 9 a.m. and 12 noon.</p>
<p>The applicants must present their receipts duly filled up with the amouuts due to them, and it is also necessary that they present at the same time their allotment letters as a proof ot identity.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>CREDIT LYONNAIS</head>
<p>The report of the Credit Lyonnais for the past year, recently presented to the shareholders at the general meeting, introduces us to figures which are truly remarkable. Deposits (including current accounts) are £66,500,000, comparing with £54,800,000 in December, 1903 ; acceptances £3,700,000, as against £3,000,000; cash in hand and at banks £5,500,000 against £4,600,000;bills recievable, £41.000,000 against £33,400,000 ; current accounts, £19,100,000 against £14,100,000; and loans against securities and contangoes, £21,400,000 against £21,000,000. The net profits for this year amount to the exceedingly comfortable sum of £1,285,000. The Credit Lyonnais is, of course, a French institution, pure and simple, but the London agency is a greater factor in our own markets than most people suppose. The report states that London has made no less a contribution to the success of the bank during the past year than during former financial periods. The figures we have quoted are a certain indication of sustained progress and capable direction.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>ANGLO-AMERICAN CO.</head>
<p>The following extract from the second article of the statutes of the Upper Egypt Hotel Company, Limited, will show how the Anglo-American Nile Steamer and Hotel Company is protected by the former company from competition :—</p>
<p>Elle pourra s’associw ou ee fusionner avee d’autres entrepriscs similairee, les acqudrir ou les annexer. Cependant clle ne pourra Cairo auoune entreprise de navigation sur le Nil au sod du Cairo, ni a’iutlreaser dans aucune entreprise de ce genre. Ella ne pourra non plus, soit directement soit par ses administrate urn, fono-tionnaires ou employes, agir comme agents d’aticune compagnie ou administration de chemins de fer ou de navigation fonotionnant en Egypte on silleurs.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>A COSTLY BLUNDER.
CANAL CO.’S DREDGER SINKS.
(From our Correspondent).</head>
<p>Port Said, Monday.</p>
<p>The Suez Canal Company's dredger "Pharoh II," which was lying in the entrance of the Cherit Basin, was taking in coal on Saturday night preparatory to starting work this morning, and by some strange oversight all her sluices and side-scuttles were left open, with the natural result that as she got lower in the water owing to the extra weight, she began to fill on all sides, and before anything could be done to save her, she sank bodily. As she sank her superior top-weight caused her to roll over on her sides, and her mast, funnel, and upper works wore broken away, so that she does not appear above water-line. She is an almost new dredger, worth some £35,000, and was only brought out to Port Said last summer to be used in connection with harbour alterations. Salvage operations have been commeuced by the Canal Company.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>SINKING OF THE "CONGAL."
(From our Correspondent).</head>
<p>Port Said, Monday.</p>
<p>The managers and owners of the J. and C. Harrison Steamship Company, to which the “Craftsman” belongs, will arrive here next week in their private steam-launch in connection with tie claim made by the owners of the Norwegian steamer “Congal,” which was sunk by the "Craftsman” some two months ago.</p>   </div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<p>The Khedive, who is at present on his Ismailia estates, is not expectod to arrive at Abdeen Palace till Thursday.</p>
<p>His Highness gave audience at Koubbeh Palace yesterday to Sheikh Abd-el-Rahim El-Demerdashi.</p>
<p>The Khedive's final reception before leaving Cairo for Alexandria will be held at Abdeen Palace on Tuesday, 2nd proxo, commencing at 8.30 a.m.</p>
<p>On the same day the Khedivah will hold a reception at Koubbeh Palace commencing at 9 a.m.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>DECORATIONS.</head>
<p>The King has pleased to give and grant unto the undermentioned officers and gentle-men his Majesty's Royal liscense and authority to accept and wear decorations (as stated against their respective names)' which have been conferred upon them by his Highness the Khedive, authorised by his imperial Majesty the Sultan of Turkey, in recogutuon of valuable services rendered to his Highness:</p><p> Imperial Ottoman Order op the Osmanieh,</p> <p>Third Class.</p>
<p>Captain Robert Byron Drury Blakeney, D.S.O., R.E., Traffic Manager of the Egyptian State Railways.</p>
<p>William Cosaar Mackenzie, Esq., Principal of the Egyptian Polytechnic School of Engineering and of the School of Agriculture.</p> <p>Imperial Ottoman Order of ten Osmanieh,</p> <p>Fourth Class.</p>
<p>Cecil Longuoville Snow, Esq., Stall Inspector in the Egyptian Coastguard Service.</p>
<p>Imperial Ottoman Order op the Medjidieh, </p><p>Fourth Class.</p>
<p>Captain Alfred Chevallier Parker, Royal Sussex Regiment.</p>
<p>Graham Campbell Kerr, Esq., Inspector under the Sudan Government.</p>
<p>The King has been pleased to give and grant unto Arthur George Milton Dickson, Esq , formerly Manager and General Inspector of branches of the Ionian Bank in Greece, his Majesty's Royal liscene and authority that he may accept and wear the Cross of “Officier" of the Royal Order of the Redeemer, conferred upon him by his Majesty the King of the Hollenes in recognition of valuable services rendered to his Majesty.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>SUPREME CONSULAR COURT.</head>
<p>Mr. R. B. P. Cator, Judge of the High Court at Mombasa, East Africa, has been appointed, under date of April 1, 1905, Judge of H.M.'s Supreme Consular Court for the Ottoman Dominions, Mr. H. W. de Sausmarez, the late Judge, having been promoted to be Judge of H.M.'s Supreme Court for China and Corea.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
<p>The Moss liner ‘Tabor" arrived on Sunday morning from Liverpool, via Gibraltar, Algiers, and Malta, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
<p>The Ellerman S.S. "Britannia" sailed from Malta on Monday evening and is due here on Friday morning with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
<p>The 8.8. “Ararat" arrived at Liverpool on Saturday and the S.S. ‘Flavian” this morning.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
<p>Largest 1st class and most comfortanle  Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
Central position. Under English management.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer</head>
<p>AND HOTEL COMPANY. RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO THREE SAILINGS A WEEK. Agents at Alexandria: ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LD.</p> </div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN ARMY. 
WELL-KNOWN OFFICERS RETIRE.</head>
<p>El Lewa F. J. Nason Pasha, D.S.O., has been struck off the strength of the Egyptian Army. The Sirdar, in a Special Army Order, express his great regret at the retirement from the Army of Nason Pasha, who has served with his Highness’s troops for nearly eleven years, during which time he has taken a prominent part in the following campaigns and actions in which the Egyptian Army has been engaged: —Sudan 1889, action of Arguin (wounded); expedition to Dougola, 1896, Nile expedition, 1897 ; Nile expedition, 1898, battle of Atbara and Khartoum aud defeat of Ahmed Fedil's army, Nile expedition, 1899. El Lewa Nason Pasha has held the appointment of Brigade Major, Dongola expedition, officer commanding 15th Battalion, officer commanding 10th Sudanese, Governor and officer commanding troops at Berber, Secretary General Sudan Government. in each of these appointments the excellence of his work has been most conspicuous. The Sirdar feels sure that he is expressing the feelings of the whole Egyptian Army in wishing Nason Pasha every success in the future.</p>
<p>El Lewa the Hon. M. G. Talbot Pasha has also been struck off the Egyptian Army. The Sirdar likewise expresses his great regret at the retirement of Talbot Pasha from the Army of his Highness the Khedive, with which he has served for over eight years. During this period he waa Direotor of Military Intelligence, E.A., Director of Surveys, Sudan Government, and in the first instance Special Servioe officer. The Boundary Commission, the Trigtonometrical Survey, and the astronomical observations, planned and executed throughout the Sudan and on its frontiers, by Lewa the Hon. M. G. Talbot Pasha, are a lasting testimony of the excellence and thoroughness of his work. The Sirdar desires, in the name of the Egyptian Army, to wish Talbot Pasha every success in his future career.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>SUDAN APPOINTMENTS.</head>
<p>Kaimakam H. D. Palmer Bey, A.A.G., has been promoted to be Financial Secretary, Sudan Government; Kaimakam C. H. Townsend,
commanding 2nd Battalion, to be A.A.G.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE COTTON WORM.</head>
<p>The Ministry of the Interior having been informed that the cotton worm had appeared on the Kasr el-Aly estate, near Itai el-Baroud, Mr. Machell went to the spot on Sunday. But the worm is not the cotton worm (Prodenis lilloratis) but the agrotes. In the Tantah markaz the worm was discovered in various bersim fields, which had been planted with cotton last year.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY.</head>
<p>The following questions have been added to the ordre du jour of to-morrow's meeting of the Municipal Commission:-</p>
<p>1.   Interpellations de M. Escoffier an sujet:</p>
<p>a)   du plan de lotissement des terrains de Chatby.</p>
<p>b)   de la construction d'une baroque en plants sur le terrain do quai vis-4-vis du terminus de Kamloh.</p>
<p>2.   Proposition de Ahmed Bey Yehia pour la contribution de la Municipality dans les fetes du oentouaire de l'Avenemeat an Trine de Mebemet Aly.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>ST. MARK’S DAY.</head>
<p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>
<p>Sir,—"Many are the curious customs” (says the late Augustas J. C. Hare*) “which attend St. Mark’s Day, especially that of the 'bocciolo' or rosebud, which every one gives to her he loves best.”</p>
<p>It is a pleasing and appropriate idea to associate St. Mark’s on Tuesday next with love in both old and young, and especially for the latter, who may be looking forward to being united in the bonds of holy matrimony, on some happy day, beneath the flag of the Church of England. — Yours, and c.,</p>
<p>Verbum Sap.</p>
<p>Alexandria, April 22.</p>
<p>Venice, 4th ed. 1868, h.p. 40.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>PAPAYANNI LINE.</head>
<p> “City of Cambridge,” 8,844 tons; will sail for Liverpool on or about the 6th May and will be followed by the "City of Oxford,” 4,019 tons, on or about the 10th May. Both ships have excellent first-class accommodation amidships and are fitted throughout with electric light. Fare £14 single and £24 return. Special terms for officers of the Army of Occupation and Government officials.</p>
<p>For further particulars apply to the Agents,</p> <p>Barker and Co.,</p>
<p>Alexandria.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA</head>
<p>The best halfway house between Egypt and England is</p> <p>VIAREGGIO, near PISA.</p>
<p>Main line expresses stop. Pine woods, Sands, Sea bathing, mild climate, English Pension, Villa Shelley, Every home comfort. Electric light. Modern sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>CARLTON HOTEL.
Bulkeley. Ramleh.
agSsagjBgS8'</head></div>
<div type="item">
<head>SUCCESSFUL CAIRO INSTITUTE
BRITISH RECREATION CLUB.</head>
<p>The second annual general meeting of the club was held in the club premises in the Tewfikieh quarter, on Saturday at 6 p.m., under the presidency of Crookshank, Pasha. In spite of the hot weather a large number of members were present: several members, including the Very Rev. Dean Butcher, sent their regrets for non-attendance, and a telegram was received from Assouan from Mr. E. A. Harrison, the late president, wishing the club a prosperous new year. The audited balance sheet for the year ending 31st March, showing a balance in hand of £179, was then read by the secretary and passed unanimously. Crookshank Pasha then gave an interesting review of the past year’s work, which was listened to with great attention and frequently interrupted by enthuastic cheers. When his Excellency undertook the presidency of the club last April, its financial condition was bad, the club being over $706 in debt, whilst the petty jealousies, quarrelling and bad feeling among various members of the club, very nearly wrecked the institution. A new committee, consisting principally of buisness members of the club, ably presided over by Dr. Madden, was elected, and thanks to the pecuniary support of personal friends of the president, and the determination of the members of the club to work unitedly and harmoniously together in the interests of inch a much-needed British institution in Cairo, the year has proved a great suooess, and the general tone of the club leaves nothing to be desired. There are now 800 subscribing members (P.T. 120 per annum) and 129 of than are new members since April 1904. The profits from all sources for the last six months amounted to over £300, so that the club may now be considered a good going and paying concern. During the year a second tennis court, a miniature rifle range, and a bowling alley have been built. Several tennis tournaments were held, for which the prizes presented by the members, and the competition, being open to ladies, was thoroughly appreciated by all those who were able take part. The main hall of the club was wooden floored during the summer, and the fortnightly dances which took place through the winter were well patronised and proved very succeessful. Several river excursions got up during the warm weather and were thoroughly enjoyed by all those who were able to join in them. A change was made in the internal administration of the club. An hon. secretary (Mr. Holmes) and a resident steward were appointed, who managed the affairs of the club under the direction of the committee, and a hearty vote of thanks was given to the hon. treasurer, Mr. A. V. Thomson, the hon. secretary, Mr. Holmes, the chairman, Dr. Madden, and the members of the committee for their excellent services during the past year. The rules and bye laws of the club have been printed and distributed to every member of the club. Several very successfull concerts, got up entirely by members of the club, and two entertainments, given by Mr. Scott Leslie, were held during the winter and drew good audience on every oocasion. The Christmas festivities induded an excellent tea, followed up by a huge ’Xmas Tree and a liberal distribution of toys suitable for all ages, from the baby in arms to the young boys and girls of 13 years, and was a great success. Nearly 400 people were present. Lord and Lady Cromer graciously favored the club with their presence, and after taking tea with the members, remained to witness the distribution of the presents to the young people, and the club owes a debt of gratitude to Lord and Lady Cromer for thus showing their personal interest in its wellfare. Wednesday, the "ladies' day," was by far the most successful of the week,and a large number of the wives and children of members avail themselves of the privileges of the club during the afternoon and evening. The sale of teas during these afternoons is undertaken by two lady members in turn, with excellent results financially and otherwise. Taking into consideration the number of families living in flats and small rooms, without a garden open space for children to play in, the president hoped the committee would see their way to have two ladies’ days a week instead of Wednesday only, especially during the long, hot summer months. Two very well attended classes, one for ladies and the other for gentlemen, for instruction in first aid to the sick and injured, under the auspices of the 8t John of Jerusalem Ambulance Association, were held by Dr. Madden. The president at the close of his address presented the successful candidates of the class, 10 ladies and 8 gentlemen, with the certificates for passing the final examination. He also presented Dr. Madden with 6 handsome volumes of the “Arabian Nights,” subscribed for by the members of the gentlemen’s class, for his voluntary services as their lecturer.</p>
<p>In accordance with Art. 14 the president and four members of committee resigned. Dr. Madden then proposed that Crooksbank Pasha be reelected president for the ensuing year, which was carried unanimously, with loud cheers. Several new members for the vacancies on the committee having been duly proposed and seconded, a ballot was taken and the following members were elected to fill the four vacancies caused by the retiring members. Dr. Madden, Messrs. Blake, Curtis and Ratcliffe. The president after thanking the members for reelecting him for another year, accepted the position the more willingly as, having already steered the club over troublous waters, he was anxious to see her in a safe harbour where she would be permanently moored. They had recently received a notification from the Egyptian Government authorities that the premises they at present occupied would be required in the near future for services of public utility.
When they started the club two years ago they knew that their possession of the land they occupiad was only temporary, and they now had to face the fact that, in about 12 months time they would have to go elsewhere. "The Egyptian Government, on whom we had no claims whatever for compensation in the removal
of the club, had very generously come forwars and offered the club a piece of ground in perpetuity on the opposite side of the canal in the main Boulac road, covering the same area as the club at present occupied and valued at £10,000 to £l2,000-which would remain as a valuable asset to the club. It is true we have sunk, about £1,700 capital in the building of the present club, and that a portion of this, such as price of labour, etc., is absolutely lost. We have, however, no claim for damages or loss against the Egyptian Government, and the generous valuable asset of which they make us a gift in the new premises, obliges us to look for other methods in raising the necessary funds for the transfer and building of the new Recreation Club. I am authorised to state that if every other method fails Mr. Maohell, whose interest in the club is unflagging, and myself will find the money required.”</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>Baron Acton, Italian Consul-General, is expected back from Leghorn on Sunday next.</p>   </div>
<div type="item">
<p>Lord Cromer's cousin, Major the Hon. Everard Baring, has nnexpectedly resigned his loaition as Military Secretary to the Viceroy of India, and is now on his way home. He is the third surviving son of the first Lord Revelstoke. He served in the Sudan expedition of 1897, and fought also at Atbara and Khartoum in 1898, signally distinguishing himself throughout, and gaining his brevet of Major in the 10th Hussars. Major Baring married in the early autumn of last year lady Ulrica Duncombe, youngest daughter of the Earl of Feversham.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>The late Under Secretary of State for Finance to the Egyptian Government and Lady Dawkins have left London for, the Italian lakes for several weeks.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Commander Schwank, Russian naval attache at Constantinople, who came here to escort the Russian squadron through the Canat, has
left for Constantinople again.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Maitre Carton de Wiart left for London on Sunday by tha P.and 0. steamer from Port Said.  </p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Frank Stout, the English International and Gloucestershire captain, has arrived in Egypt, where he will very shortly take up an appointment. His brother Percy, who several years ago was also famous as an International three-quarter, has resided in Egypt for several years.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Dr. Briend inspector of the Quarantine Board, has returned from Suez, where he had gone on inspection duty.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Cavalier Falqui, president of the Italian coasular tribunal at Alexandria, leaves for Italy on leave to-morrow.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Capt. M. Bitte, Mrs. H. W. Mayow, Mr. J. Mandslay, Mr. and Mrs. R. J. Micklam, Rev. R. A. Jones, Mr. and Mrs. Dunlop, Mr. A. Percy, Mr. V. Tedeschi, Mr. E Brindisi, Mr. James Ison, Mr. Warwick Major, Mr. M. De Lavalette, Mr. A.W. Raydn, Miss Arbuthnot, Mr. J. Langley, Mr. E. R. Lloyd, Mr. F. Powell, Mr. G. C. Black and brother.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<p>The following visitore are staying at the Bean-Rivage Hotel, Ramleh:.Mr. J. R. Goyder. Miss Lilian M. Balfour, Miss E Tindall, Mr.
J' W. Dart, Oapt* and Mrs. W. H. Rothmam, Mr. end Mme Fleury-Monteoado, Mr. and Mrs. F. Burley, Mr. Geozge Qube, Mr. red Master Ange Chaim is, CoL and Mrs. H. Davidson, Miss T. H. Bird, Mr. and Mr* Jonhs W. H. Quintons, Mr. red Mrs. R’ Herbert, C. K. Linant Bey, Mr, ami Mrs. L. Davis, Mrs.' T.H. Farrar and courier, the Misses Farrar, Miss M. Young, Dr. Wakeling, Miss M. Soulic, Mr. R. Ahrab, Miss L. Wormer.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.
KHEDIVIAL 8PORTING CLUB.</head>
<p>Owners are reminded that subscriptions for the Jubilee Stakes, value L.E. 500; and the Eclipse Stakes, value L.R. 500, must be taken on or before Saturday next, 29th inst.</p>   </div>
<div type="item">
<head>DELTA RAILWAY SPORTS.</head>
<p>The Delta Light Railway Company’s annual sports were held at Damanhour on Saturday last, and notwithstanding the vigour of the khamseen, were very successful. There was a large and fashionable gathering of Europeans, including a number of visitors from Alexandria, Cairo, and Tantah. The sports were held on the company’s grounds and were enlivened by the band of the Royal Berkshire Regiment, kindly lent by the O. C. The sports began at 2 P.M. and continued without interruption until 7 pm. The championship was won by Mr. R. M. Ross. Mr. Spencer Whiteman unfortunately broke his collar bone in the sack race, After winning three events this was very unfortunate as he would otherwise have given a good account of himself and have run Mr. Boss very close for ths championship. Mrs. Aitken gave away the prises, which were both handsome and costly.</p></div></div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>