<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-09"> February 9, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, FEBRUARY 9, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<div type="item">
<head>CONDITION OF RUSSIA.</head>
<head>ACADEMIC ANARCHY</head>
<head>DAWN OF REFORM</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, February 8
General Trepoff summoned the curator 
of the education department before him and 
informed him that he was determined to put down
the academic anarchy.  All students refusing to 
return to their studies in a tranquil manner
will be summarily expelled.  If the professors
sympathise with the students, education in st. 
petersburg will cease.
A decree of the tsar appoints M. Kobebo, 
a councillor of the empire, as president of an
influential committee to revise the censorship
and the press laws.  (Reuter.)</p>
<p>St. Petersburg, February 8
The finance minister has submitted to the 
tsar a report asking for reforms in favor of
the workmen.  
The strike is dying out in poland. (havas.)</p>
<p>St. petersburg, February 8
The Tsar has approved, and referred to
Committee of Ministers for immediate legisla-
tion, a series of most literal proposals. The
Minister of Finance is dealing with the condi-
tions of labour, He recognises notably
workmen's right to strike, which has hitherto
been a crime.	(Reuter.)</p>
</div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FATHER GAPON</head>
                    <head>REFUGED IN SWITZERLAND</head>
                    <p>St petersburn, February 8.
                    Father Gapon is known to be in Switzerland.  (Reuter.)</p>
                   <p>St. Petersburg, February 8. 
                   Pope Gapon has taken refuge in switzerland.  (Havas.)</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN GENERALS.</head>
                    <head>PROMISED REVELATIONS</head>
                    <p>Irkutsk, February 8
                    General Gripenberg and his staff have arrived 
                    here en route for St. Petersburn.  A rumour is
                    current to the effect that general gripensberg
                    is going to St. Petersburg for the purpose of
                    accusing General Kuropatkin of leaving him
                    in the lurch, and of general inertis.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ADMIRAL TOGO</head>
                        <p>Kure, February 8
                        Admiral togo arrived here and immediately hoisted his 
                        flag on the mikasa.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>BRITISH STEAMER CAPTURED</head>
                            <p>Tokio, february 8
                            The british steamer eastry, laden with
                            coal for Bladivostok, has been captured on 
                            Hokkaido Island.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN VICTORY IN STAMBOUL</head>
                    <head>THE PROJECTED NEW LOAN</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, February 8
                    The remarkable struggle between the German
                    and french embassies here, with the object of
                    inducing the porte to expend a considerable
                    proportion of the porjected new loan of
                    $5,000,000 from the imperial ottoman bank
                    upon guns in their respective countries, ended 
                    in a victory for germany.  The porte consented 
                    to buy krupp guns.  M. Constans, the french
                    ambassador here, there upon notified the porte 
                    that the paris market would be closed against
                    the new loan.  The ottoman bank consequently
                    withdrew from the whole transaction.  The 
                    Deutsch bank is now offering to assist the 
                    treasury.    (Reuter.)</p> </div>
                    <div type="item"> 
                 <head>GERMANY AND ENGLAND</head>
                 <head>MR. LEE'S SPEECH</head>    
                 <p>London, February 8.
                 Mr. lee, speaking again at eastleigh, referred
                 to the extra ordinary outcry which had been
                 raised over his last speech.  the latter was a
                 plain recital of certain naval reforms, but a
                 meaning had been read into it that never
                 existed.  he had suggested no threat to which 
                 any foreign power could take exception.  (R.)</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PLAGUE AT LIVERPOOL</head>
                    <p>Liverpool, February 8.
                    A fatal case of plague has occured here on 
                    board the S.S. "crewe hall" from rangoon.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
          <div type="item">   
              <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
              <p>Rudolph home- mr. eugene nahman has 
              sent $1 to the rudolph home, alexandria, in
              memory of mrs. bauer</p>
              <p>American mission- The english service 
              at the american mission in tantah will be
              omitted next sabbath, but will be held as
              usual two weeks from that day.</p>
              <p>Suez canal- 14 vessels passed through 
              the canal on the 6th inst., viz., 9 british
              1 dutch, 2 german, 2 austrian.  The reciepts for
              the day were frs. 369,345.60, making the total
              up to the 6th inst. frs. 2,325,331.82</p>
              <p>The band of the tourah prison negro boys
              will play in the Helouan sporting clubs
              enclosure adjoining the tewfik palace hotel, 
              tomorrow from 5 to 5.30 p.m. The boys will 
              also give an exhibition of drill.  Members, 
              visitors, and residents are invited.  Entrance free</p>
              <p>A dementi- Mr. Aquilina, manager of the
              twefik palace hotel at helouan, writes to us
              on the subject of the incorrect statement made
              in a cairo morning newspaper to the effect
              that he has been appointed manager of the
              national hotel at cairo.  He writes : I shall
              feel obliged if you will make it public that 
              circumstances caused me to decline the kind 
              offer made to me to work the above hote.</p>
              <p>The cretan murderer- the enquiry into
              the circumstances attending the murder of a 
              cretan lawyer, zagaki, by the cretan poet and
              patriot, menegakis, began this morning at the
              helenic consular court at alexandria.  The
              tragedy took place here a few months ago but
              the nationality of the assassin was unsettled
              until the last few days.  Menegakis has made
              a complete confession of his crime, which appears
              to have been of a purely political character,
              the victim having, it is alleged, betrayed
              the cause of the islanders to the sultan in the
              late insurrection.</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
            <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
            <p>Liet, Gen Sir T Kelly-Kenny left london yesterday 
            week for egypt.</p>
            <p>We regret to announce the death of Mme.
            Beuve sarah bauer, which occurred at alexandria 
            yesterday.  The funeral will take place
            this afternoon from deceaseds residence at 
            4 o clock</p>
               <p>Capt W G Huskisson A. S. C. and Lieut
               H. L. Mackworth, D.S.O., R. E., have 
               reported their arrival in egypt and been
               taken on the strenght of the egyptian army, 
               with the rank of bumbashi.  The former has
               been posted to the department of supplies and
               the latter to the sudan government</p>
                    <p>the following passengers have left Cairo by the
                        S. S. "Rameses 111." for the Nile trip : Prince
                        athensburg, Maiquls aud Alaiquise do la
                        begasiere, Mr. aud Mrs. A. M. Druwu, Messrs.
                        E.G. aud J. H. Doxter, Airs. Ivaxter, Mr. aud
                        Mrs. Benfis, Mr. and Mrs. Dugart, Aliases tuiny
                         and Anna n. Riounead, Air. H. Ganns, Miss
                        H. Core, Air. nuil Alls. G. B. Cruukstoil, Miss
                        K. Drunimolid, llev. J. A. aud Mrs. Duuuar-
                        niuimar, Airs. K. At. tvaits, Air. .Nath. ElsUup
                        tanar, Alls. R. E. Foster, Jlr. and Mrs. R. b.
                        gregory, Misses Eleanur aud Rutb Gicgory,
                        Mrs. and Aliss Guiniau, Air. R. M. Ring, airs,
                        vou Klouneu, Alias fanny Gebr, Miss A. C.
                        lain, Dr. J. tJ. and Airs. Merreui, Mr., Mrs. aud
                        Alias L. AlcDoiiaid, Mr. li. G. Miber, Mrs.
                        I AicKmlay, Mr. aud Airs. G. Malcolm, Miss
                        llelolse Meyer, Mrs. McCollum, Mr. Jas Rowan,
                        .Misses Florence aud Alice Kowau, Countess do
                        iorionne, Miss E. Bmelne, Miss Auuie Bteveus,
                        Airs. Joseph Buckney, Miss Adebude Bpotfurd,
                        Mr. and Mrs. W. R. Btiritug, Misses Dorothy,
                        May and Jeou W. tuning, Miss Tboruburn,
                        Air. 1. Thompson, Miss V. Whyte, Mr. aud
                        .Mrs. J. T. Walton, Miss Florence Walton,
                        Mr. J. II. Williams.</p>
                    <p>Amongst the late arrivals at the savoy 
                    hotel, port said, we notice sir benjamin
                    baker, sir hohn aird, mr. franz bayer, mr
                    and mrs B. Heller, Lt. Col. Morton Duckelt,
                    Mr john smith, mr G.F. and miss bird, mr
                    and mrs N.P. cairnes, mr. bernheim and
                    family, mrs and miss clayton</p>
                    <p>the following passengers left shellal today, 
                    by the P.S. Memnon.  Dr. Hugo and Mrs 
                    hinze, mr and mrs H. lincoln tangye, lady
                    donegall, rev b boughton leigh, Mr. E w 
                    boughton leigh, mr p f casaretto, mr 
                    h phelps stokes, mr h arrowsmith, mr 
                    lansing reed, mr and mrs john w stewart, 
                    dr. ludwin and mrs korn, mr h gildemesiter
                    baron and baronness podesta</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALDERSONS GARD N, BULKELEY</head>
                    <p>Friday february 10 at 6pm
                    grand variety entertainment by the 
                    royal tookey family
                    concluding eith the grand pantomime
                    ructions
                    dancing after the concert
                    god save the king</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Eden palace hotel</head>
                    <p>cairo
                    open all the year round
                    electric light-lift-moderate charges</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAD DEATH OF JUDGE KEILLY</head>
              <p>We regret to announce the death, under
              painful circumstances, of jedge keilly, late
              american judge in the mixed court of appeal.
              who had resided in egypt for twenty years.
              the accident by which he met his death is
              thus reported in the new york herald
              paris of january 29- a well dressed man
              appearing to be about sixty years of age, was
              knocked down by a delivery van on the place
              de la concorde yesterday.  He was taken to the 
              beaujon hospital, where he died in the evening.
              In his pocketbook was found a card with the address, 
              Judge Keily, 49, dover street, piccadilly, london.
              The late judge was appointed to the court of
              1st instance at cairo in the khediviate of 
              twefik pasha and was promoted to the court
              of appeal some years afterwards.  Bothe he and his 
              wife had a large circle of friends in egypt,
              for they were most genial and hospitable.
              Judge keilly leaves two sous and a daughter.
              the latter is married to captain hall, of the irish
              rifles.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                    <p>The khedive will hold the kourban beyram
                    reception at abdeen palace on tuesday next, 
                    14th inst. The order of the reception will be 
                    published in our issue of saturday next.
                    His highness has bewtowed the following 
                    distinctions on the undermentioned officials on 
                    the occasion of their retirement from the
                    service of the egyptian government:
                    Salissah: Mohammed Effendi aly, late 
                    moawenidara mondirieh of hirrgen
                    Rabea: Takla eflendi matta, late of the
                    railway administration
                    Medjidieh commander 3rd class: Dr. 
                    Symmers, late professor of pathology at 
                    the school of medicine</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MINISTRY OF JUSTICE</head>
                    <p>Mr. Hervey Wedgwood Vaughan Williams
                    barrister at law has been appointed substiture
                    au contentieux.
                    Mr. Michael harvey rafferty, barrister at
                    law and licencie en droit of paris, has been
                    appointed inspector on the surveilance committee
                    both these appointments are a rirte d'essai 
                    for one year</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANKING IN EGYPT</head>
                    <p>The comptoir national d'escompte de paris
                    expects to have its alexandria branch opened
                    for working by next jume
                    the bank of romes new branch at alexandria
                    will open here in about two months time.
                    The credito italiano is considering the
                    advisability of establishing a branch here, but 
                    has come to no definite decision on the matter
                    as yet.
                    The new german greek orient bank will
                    establish branches in egypt, but not immediately, 
                    as it will start operation first at athens
                    and constantinople.
                    Our constantinople correspondent sends us 
                    the following details on this new levantine 
                    bank: In greece the branches of the national
                    bank will be at the disposal of the orient
                    bank, so it will not be necessary to open new
                    branches in that country.  But in proportion
                    with the development of business, the orient
                    bank will establish branches in various towns
                    of turkey, egypt, and other countries in the 
                    east.  With regard to the capital, the national bank 
                    for deutschland, of berlin, and the national
                    bank of greece have taken all the 
                    shares, the value of which is 10 million francs.
                    They have reserved to themselves the right to
                    make a public issue within three years.  M. 
                    Witting, manager of the national bank for deutschland
                    and one of those interested in the oriend bank,
                    has stated in an interview, that the aim of the new
                    financial establishment is to facilitate the 
                    importation of helllenic products into germanly.
                    It will advance money on bills of lading.  M. witting
                    also said that the orient bank would establish in 
                    greece storehouses for wares which the proprietor
                    does not wish to export immediately and on
                    which the orient bank will also advance money.
                    The bank will endeabour to come to an
                    understanding with the deutshe-levante
                    lanie to facilitate the export trade.
                    </p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES</head>
                    <p>The export of Egyptian cigarettes during
                        the past year has greatly increased. In 1903
                        the total export of cigarettes from this country
                        amounted to 531,199 kilos, of the value of LE.
                        423,332. During 1904 the amount exported
                        was 620,476 kilos, of the value of LB. 494,964,
                        an increase on the previous year of 89,277 kilos
                        and L.E.71,632. The export to Knglaud last
                        year amounted to LE. 79,478, as against LB.
                        78,208 in 1903. The principal figures for the
                        other countries were as follows: Germany, LB.
                        247,236, as agaiust LE. 195,010 iu 1903, Aus-
                        tria, LE.38,101, as against LE.26,875 in 1903
                        PranoeLB. 8,797, as against LE. 13,166 in
                        1903. China and the For East, LE. 18,221 as
                        against LE. 12,555 in 1903, British Possessions
                        in the Far East, LK. 57,693 as against LE
                        65.558 in 1903, Swedeu.LB. 10,743 as against
                        Ck 11,107 in 1903, Switzerland, LE. 6,891 as
                        against 6,620 in 1903, Belgium, LE 9,182 as
                        against 8,115 in 1903.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable
                    hotel in alexandria.  Facing the central
                    position.  under english management</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>MARQUIS DI RUDINIS VISIT</head>
                    <p>Suez, february 8.
                    The marquis di rudini, ex-prime minister of italy, arrived
                    at suez this afternoon by the 
                    4 20 train from cairo en route to massowah.
                    at the station he was met by mr. luigi deperais,
                    italian vice consul at suez, mr. aug. 
                    pacho and other members of the italian community.
                    shortly afterwards, the florio-rubattino steam-launched
                    conveyed the marquison board the steamer teve, which sailed in
                    the evening for massowah
                    </p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>COLLSION IN THE CANAL</head>
                    <p>The british steamer goorkha collided in
                    the canal last sunday afternoon, near shaluf
                    station, with the S.S. solo, which was moored
                    at the time.  both steamers sustained some 
                    damage over the water line</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>WIRELESS TELEGRAPHY AT SUEZ</head>
                        <p>It is expected that lloyds wireless telegraphy 
                        station at port twefik will be completed by the
                        end of march, when suez will be in communication
                        with steamers in the red sea having wireless
                        apparatus on board, as well as with port said</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>PILGRIM STEAMER ASHORE</head>
                        <p>The greek steamer kilikia bound to jeddah 
                        with a large number of turkish pilgrims
                        on board, grounded in the canal in the small
                        bitter lake, and was refloated yesterday with the
                        assistance of a canal companys tug.  The 
                        kilikia sustained no damage whatever, and
                        proceeded on her journey</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE LAST OF THE PILGRIMS</head>
                        <p>The khedival mail line, with a view to cleraing
                        out the remaining foreign pilgrims at
                        suez, who had not the means to proceed on their 
                        hourney, sent their S.S. menzalah to suez.  The 
                        vellsel sailed for jeddah yesterday afternoon 
                        after taking on board 600 pilgrims at a very 
                        low rate and 300, who were not in a position to pay, were carried
                        absolutely free.  These are the last pilgrims this year on 
                        their way to the holy city via suez</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DEVELOPMENT OF FARSHUT</head>
                        <p>our farshut correspondent states that the 
                        postmaster general had decided to open a 
                        branch of the post office savings bank at
                        farshut in consequence of the petition of the
                        inhabitants, which he voiced in our columns.  
                        The inhavitants are delighted with saba
                        pahas promptness in hearkening to their wishes
                        The employes of the corporation of western
                        egypt are still hoping that the railway
                        administration will grant their request and stop
                        the train de luxe at farshut station</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>HELOUAN RAILWAY</head>
                        <p>Since the delta light railway company has taken
                        over the cairo helouan line, great
                        satisfaction has been evinced at the reforms
                        that the company has introduced.  We extract
                        the following passage from our vernacular
                        contemporary Misr:
                        We are requested by several people inhabiting
                        helouan to express their warmest thanks for
                        the many and various reforms brought 
                        about by the delta company on the line which 
                        before long they expect to become one of the
                        most orderly and the least dangerous of lines.
                        the reason that some are conducting a virulent
                        campaing against the company, despite its
                        recent existence, is due to the mere fact that they are 
                        not willing to squander money in the 
                        same say as the former company with the view
                        to preventing hypocrites from exhibiting 
                        their crying and manifold defects.  The object
                        of the new company is reforems in the full 
                        sense of the word, and no babbling or nonsense
                        whatever on the part of ill intentioned people 
                        is to deter them from attaining this most
                        commendable object</p></div></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TRADE WITH CYPRUS</head>
                    <p>Statement or Cheif Exports from Larnaca 
                        to Egypt, December, 1904.	by
                        Wheat kiles	14000         Eggs         
                        Barley	- "	22,647        Lambs
                        Bran	-	okes  10,965  meat	-	„	665	
                        Potatoes	-	 49,34    Oxen	-	„	204	
                        Onions	-	„	24,530	  Sheep	-	„	143	
                        Linseed	•	„	19,336	  Pigs	-	"	149
                        Blackseed-	„	430       Goats -	"	34
                        Almonds •	„	770       Turkeys-	"	339	
                        Wine	•	„	2,199	  Fowls	-	"	1,892
                        Raisins	-	„	1,014	  Mules	-	"	71	
                        Caroubs -kantars 40       Camels - "	18 
                        Lemons	No.	30,600        Horses .	"	1
                        Gypsum -	Tons 441.5    Donkeys-	"	13</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The SS Perim, of the wescott and
                    laurance line, left malta yesterday and is
                    due here on sunday with a general cargo from
                    london.
                    The ellerman SS Avon sailed hence 
                    yesterday afternoon direct from liverpool, with
                    general cargo, including 2,635 bales of cotton.
                    The Moss liner Rameses sailed yesterday
                    morning from malta and is due here on saturday
                    afternoon, with passengers, mails, and general cargo
                    The SS Britannis of the papayanni
                    line, left liverpool yesterday afternoon and is
                    expected to arrive, with mails and passengers,
                    on or about the 26th inst.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM</head>
                    <p>near shepheards and continental hotels.
                    Turkish baths, plain baths, electric light baths</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FEDORA AT THE ABBAS</head>
                    <head>SIGNA. BELLINCIONIS SECOND APPEARANCE</head>
                    <p>the performance of fedora at the abbas
                    helmy theatre yesterday evening, with signa.
                    bennincioni in the title role, was undoubtedly
                    an event in the local theatrical world.  A
                    more finished performance it would be 
                    impossible to imagine on any stage, and the
                    result was a repetition of the great artistes
                    triumph of saturday last.  Gedora is an exceeding
                    interesting opera, in that the orchestral
                    treatment is very distinct from that accepted
                    in most works of the kind: it has a curious
                    reminiscence of wagner, notable of tristan,
                    in certain parts.  The libretto, known to most
                    people through M. V. Sardou, is certainly
                    calculated to furnish good dramatic singing, and 
                    no artiste is better fitted to bring out to the full
                    the dramatic points in which it abounds
                    than signora bennincioni.  Her performance
                    was one of the most remarkable achievements
                    in the art of music-drama that we have ever
                    witnessed.  She knew how to work towards a 
                    climax, both in particular and in general
                    when she first of all realised the imprisonment
                    of the great depths of her passion, and when
                    she later realised the ripeness and fulness of her
                    ultimate despair.  She ws, in a word, 
                    magnificent; and her every action betrayed
                    the consumate actress that she is.  The
                    womanly love and devotion to the husband
                    who is slain, her cunning in compassing her 
                    terrible revenge, her passion for her lover, 
                    are depicted with masterly skill and darling 
                    fedelity.  With what exquisite gentleness and
                    feeling she wins the affection of her lover;
                    with what overpowering force and majesty she
                    faces and vanquishes the murderer of her
                    husband.  The infinite pathos of the concluding
                    act, the pathetic picture of the desperate
                    woman who flies to poison as a relief from her
                    mental agony, with the face of a madonna, 
                    and the great, sad eyes full of a sorrow for
                    which there can be no alleviation are, in truth, 
                    things that no one who has witnessed them
                    will ever forget.  Fedora is a character that
                    exactly suits the temperament, the personality, 
                    and the splendid talent of the great italian
                    actress and singer.  She was well seconded in 
                    her trying role by Sig. Pagani as conte loris,
                    as well as by the other performers.  Sig pagani
                    is a tenor with a future and shared in signora
                    bellincionis great triumph.  He sang with 
                    taste and no little dramatic power, although
                    at times he seemed rather nervous, which was 
                    probably due to the presence and personality 
                    of signora bellincioni.  The orchestra did full
                    and the chorus worked well.  The staging of 
                    the opera left nothing to be desired, both the 
                    acenery and costumes being excellent.  Signora 
                    bellincionis dresses were nothing less than
                    superb</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MISS HOESLIS CONCERT</head>
                    <p>Miss hoeslis concert at the new khedivial
                    hotel last night was a great success.  there 
                    was a large audience in spite of the bad weather.  The 
                    talented swiss lady was assisted
                    by the distinguished amateurs, messrs. foscolo,
                    jacot des combes, weedon, and ehrlich.
                    The concert began with handels well known
                    largo in g major, sung by miss hoesli, assist
                    by mr ehrlich at the piano and mr weedon
                    with the violin.  Miss hoeslis voice was
                    beautifully modulated to suit this difficult
                    piece.  It was much applauded by a critical
                    audience.  M Fascolo followed with a violin
                    duet by sinving, in which he was assisted
                    by a friend, whose name was not on the 
                    programme.  This intricate piece was executed
                    with marvellous facility.  The accompaniment
                    was cleverly given by Mrs Foscolo.  Three
                    romances were next sung by miss hoesli, an 
                    die nacht (bohm), Chant hindou (bemberg),
                    and Lievesfeier (weingartner). The last time
                    was especially appreciated and was given with
                    great depth of feeling and perfect harmony.
                    beethovens adagio was well given by messrs
                    weedon, des combes, and ehrlich, followed
                    by two solos by mr foscolo.  Schuberts
                    L'abeille was excellently played and had to
                    be given agian to satisfy the demands for an
                    encore.  Miss hoesli then sang xavier lerouxs
                    Le nil, accompanied by M Des Combes on the cello 
                    and Mr. Ehrlich on the piano. 
                    The cello adapted itself very well to
                    miss hoeslis powerful voice.  The concert,
                    which closed with three romances sung by miss
                    hoesli, again showed the variety of the ladys
                    talents and the bouquets and applause she
                    recieved showed how much her splendid vocal 
                    gifts are appreciatd by the connoisseurs of
                    alexandra</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VISITORS LISTS</head>
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL ASSOUAN.
                        M. Emil Ghika and family, Roumania; Mrs. 
                        and Miss Paxton, Mr. and Mrs. Goydon, Rev.
                        Arthur Jones, Mr. and Mrs. Adoook, Mrs.
                        pitt and Mrs. Pool, Mr. and Mrs. Wood, Miss 
                        leman, Mr. Alfr. Hudd, Mr. Gerald Wain-
                        wright, Mr. Kirkpatrike, Mr. G. Graham, 
                        miss Bellman, Mrs. and Miss Swan, Mr. and 
                        mrss. Poxcroft and family, Mr. and Mrs.
                        couldery and family, Mjs« Biworth, Mr. and
                       mrs. Bond, Bngland; Mrs. and Miss Wild, Mr.
                        Mrs. Clausen, Misses Harrell and Ross,
                        mr. and Mrs. John Wood, Mr. and mrs
                         Signoretti, Cavaliere Pose, Commeodatore
                        poma, Italy; Mme. Dumeillet, France ; Herr
                        vonn Winningen, Dr. Herr von Lang Munchen, 
                       herr Hahrath MUuehen, Herr Poensgen and 
                        family, Herr Franz Kohn, Herr and Fran
                        shlesinger, Messrs. Alfr. and David Kappel
                        herr von Uechtrits. Herr Wehmann, Herr
                        othe, Geheimer Modicinalrath von Kiln
                        gelhaffer, Mrs. von Klingelhkffer, Mr. and Mrs.
                        pohlman, Mr. and mrs wiesenthal, germany</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET</head>
                    <p>(From our financial correspondent)
                    London, february 3
                    The present week has been characterised by 
                    cheerfulness in our stock markets, owing in a 
                    great measure to the growing belief that russia
                    cannot much longer continue the war, and 
                    also to the hope that the tsar is beginning to 
                    have his own way in reference to the reforms.
                    The paris and berlin financiers have been
                    making the most of the amelioration of the
                    trouble in st petersburg and hoisted up
                    the price of russian fours to over 90 agian.
                    Of stocks and shares there  is little to report
                    this week of interest to your readers.  As far
                    as the mining section is concerned, business in
                    south africans seems to be at a complete 
                    standstill at present, with a drooping tendency
                    in prices.  Egyptian mining properties, inlike
                    the other egyptian companies, are not yet 
                    independent and are still under the wing of the 
                    south african market, and consequently
                    they suffer with kaffirs when the latter are
                    weak.  Nile valleys have dropped to 2.1/16.5
                    at the present moment, a price which may
                    tempt speculative investors, not forgetting
                    that the company is to a large extent in the
                    hands of teh south african magnate who specifically
                    acquired a large and controlling interest.
                    United africans at 1.9/16 should be worth
                    attention.  It is evident that the market
                    anticipate an active future, for a special book
                    of reference has just been published "the 
                    egypt and sudan mining handbook." other
                    egyptian stocks are steady and hold their prices
                    well generally.  Bank shares are a strong
                    point, especially national banks, which are in demand
                    at 26 in anticipation of the dividend.
                    the market expects a distribution of 15s per
                    share.   some say under, but 15s is the general
                    idea.  Agriculturals are firm at 10 7/8, other
                    prices are steady with little or no change on
                    the week, except egyptian markets, which
                    have fallen back to 1.   All paris stocks have
                    been wonderfully well supported, especially 
                    russians, which they manage to keep up to
                    the level of 90; it is really wonderful how little
                    of this stock comes out at this price, for it
                    certainly should tempt holders.  Japanese stocks
                    keep strong.  Money is cheap and the investment
                    market is strong, though not an active one, and
                    consols keep firm at 881.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGERS LISTS</head>
                    <p>Departures
                        Per S.S. “Schleswig,” sailed yesterday from
                            Alexandria for Naples and Marseilles:—
                            lady Grace lavison Gower, Mr. and Mrs.
                            Oppenheim, Mr. A. Le Bran, Mr. Frank de la
                            Lome, Mr. von dor Planitx, Mr. von Watadorf,
                            Mr. and Mrs. Calame, Mr. Hyde Kennard,
                            Mr. Max Trinkaoa, Mrs. GertrudeScheele, Mrs.
                            Yale, Miss Thompson, Mr. and Mrs. Dupee,
                            Mr. and Mrs. Beckham, Mrs. and Miss Col-
                            thorp, Mr. and Mrs. G. H. Umpeon, Mr. and
                            Mrs. Wheatley, Mrs. Goebel, Mr. Turner, Mr.
                            and Mrs. H. S. Bond, Mrs. W. H. King, Mrs.
                            J. L Johnson, the Misses Baker, Air. EL Mack-
                            intoeh, Mr. Robertson, Mr. and Bin. and
                            Miss Heydebrand, Herr von Herder, Bln. and
                            Miss Hurst, Miss von Watzdorf; Frau Ober-
                            loutnant von Planitz, Mr. J. Birkenrutb, Mr.
                            Fierro Verazzi, Mr. Bigeler, Mr. H«ll| Hadid,
                            Earl and Lady Potter (sic), Mrs. Lemge, Mr.
                            Mr. Ht V. Hawknes, Rev. A. E Conolly, Rev.
                            Gray, Mr. H. S. Saoeville, Mr. Rom.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>CALENDAR OF COMING EVENTS</head>
                    <p>Alexandria
                    February thursday 9- ziznia theatre.  french comedy
                    company in les affaires sont les affaires. 9pm
                    abbas helmy theatre.  italian opera company in i puritani
                    9.15 pm
                    Fre 10- aldersons garden.  Variety entertainment 4pm
                    rasel tin grounds football school v. mr stranges xl 330pm
                    zizinia theatre.  Le monde ou ion sennuie, in aid of
                    orwa el wosks 9pm
                    Cairo
                    February thurs 9-khedivial opera house.  Italian
                    opera company in fedora 9pm verdi theatre.  Italian
                    operetta company 9pm theatre des nouveantes.  Variety
                    entertainment 9.30pm Trocadero variety entertainment
                    9.30pm ghezireh palace hotel.  Small dance 10pm</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Anglo american nile steamer and hotel company</head>
                    <p>River transport of coods between alexandria and cairo.  
                    three sailings a week.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck and co's pilsner beer bremen</head>
                    <p>fears no honest competition for quality</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Savoy hotel luxor</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its 
                    position on nile bank.  Under german management. 
                    Moderate charges.  Patronised by officer
                    of army of occupation. Concerts twice daily.</p></div>
    </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
