<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA,Wednesday, November 8, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 8,1905</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JEW EXTERMINATION.</head>
                    <head>MORE TERRIBLE SCENES IN RUSSIA</head>
                    <head>THE NEW CABINET</head>
                    <head>QUIET IN ST. PETERSBURG</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 7 The strikes in Finland are ended. The total killed
                        during the recent riots in Odessa number 964. Tho number of the excesses
                        committed in the provinces is diminishing, which indicates that the tardy
                        orders of the Government for the suppression, of disorders are being carried
                        out. The St. Petersburg. Gazette annonnces that M. Witte has been appointed
                        President of the Coancil. of Ministers, which had been reorganised. It is
                        stated that M. Shipoff, chief of the Moscow Congress of Zsmstvos, has
                        accepted the post of Controller General of the Empire and Minister of the
                        interior. It is also stated that occupants have been found for the
                        portfolios of finance and Communications. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>St.Petersburg, November 7. (Official). M. Witte has been • appointed
                        President of the Council. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London, November 7 The Chief Rabbir has received a. telegram from a leading
                        Russian Jew stating that many Jewish communities have been entirely de-
                        stroyed, and asking for help. Tho Rothechilds and others are concerning
                        measnres. A meeting of the leading Jews was held at Rothechilds this
                        afternoon. It was decided to appeal for funds lor the relief of the victims
                        in Russia. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>St. Petersburg November 7. M.Witte, has prepared a new electoral franchise
                        for the National Assembly, increas- ing its members to 600, inclnding 25
                        workmen, greatly reducing tho property qoa’ifiations, and widening the
                        suffarage generally. Numbers of shops and banks are being re- opened, and
                        ordinary life is being resumed here and at Moscow, Helsingfors, and else-
                        where. There are, however, still terrible scenes being enacted in the
                        neighbouring villages and at Odessa, where all the houses of Jews have been
                        destroyed. The killed number many hundreds, and thousands are wounded and
                        starving. (Reuter),</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABYSSINIAN BANK.</head>
                    <head>SUBSCRIPTION LIST CLOSED. .</head>
                    <p> London, November 7. Subscriptions to the Abyssinian Bank open- ed to-day,
                        and closed at noon, over subscribed. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNITED KINGDOM’S TRADE RETURNS.</head>
                    <p>London, November 7. The imports for the ten months ending Ootober show an
                        increase of £11,000,000, the exports an increase of £50,000,000.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF LADY FLORENCE DIXIE</head>
                    <p>London. November 7. Lady Florence Dixie is dead. (Reuter) Lady Florence Dixie
                        was a daughter of the seventh Marquis of Queensberry and was born in 1857.
                        She was married in 1875 to Sir Bean mint Dixie. §he acted as war
                        correspondent for the “Morning Post" during tbe Boer War.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KAISER AND KING ALFONSO.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, November17. Cordial toasts were exchanged between the Emporor and
                        King Alfonso. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
                    <p> Paris, November 7.- The new elections to the Senate have been fixed for
                        January 7. The Chamber has passed a vote of confi- dence in M.
                        Rouvier,refusing State employes the right to strike. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE.NEW ZEALANDERS’ SCORE.</head>
                    <head>OXFORD BEATEN.</head>
                    <p>London,November 7.. Football. The New ZsaUnders' beat Oxford by 47 to 0. The
                        total more until now is 540 against 15. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JOSEPH COMAS. TECHNICAL ENGINEER</head>
                    <p>Surveyor and Constructor in shipping. Take charge of Engines and Boilers.
                        Undertakes repairs of same, guaranteeing success. First tvalues references.
                        Address: Rue fl Warsha Maison Gabriel, ALEXANDRIA. 26685-J2A1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Frindisi Mail will arrive at Alex- andria at 3 pm. to-day and will be
                        distributed at tbe G.P.O. at 5 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Quarantine in Italy.—Quarantine restric- tions against arrivals from
                        AUxandria in Ita- lian ports have been removed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Abdeen district of Cairo daring the
                        night of Thursday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Greek Immigration. — A large number of Greek immigrants from the Turkish
                        islands in tbe Arcbipelago have arrived at Alexandria within the past few
                        weeks.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Veterinary College—Nine pupils have been admitted this year to the college,
                        which now numbers 31 students. Tbe curriculum will henceforth require four
                        instead of three years’ study.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Egyptian Institute held its opening meeting of the season yesterday.
                        Professor Maspero delivered a eulogy of tbe late M. Oppert, and M. Legrain
                        read a detailed aoconnt of the latest excavations at Lexor.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Alhamrba Theatre. — The Crepy Simons French operetta company will commence a
                        series of 60 performances at this theatre on December 1 next. The company’s
                        repertoire includes all the latest creations.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fatality —A native workman, remedies a bouk Hassan, while digging yesterday
                        in a pit at Roud Point, Alexandria, was buried under a heavy mass of earth
                        which fell upon him. The unfortunate man succumbed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London Stock Exchange— Application has, been made to the comittees of ths
                        London Stock Exchange to grant a settling day for - Eridea (Egypt) Exploring
                        Company, Limited. —10/07 shares of £1 each fully paid (Noe. 1 to 8 and
                        65,008 to 75,007).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Zizinia Theatre—Mr. A. Lamtert, fils, the celebrated French actor, opens at
                        tbe Zizinia Theatre this evening in Emilo Angier 4-act comedy,
                        L'Aventuriere. M. Lambert, it will be remembered, represented the French
                        stage at tbe funeral of tbe late Sir Henry Irving.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kask el Nil.—Owing to the increase in the river traffic it has beea decided
                        to alter the hours at Kasr el Nil Bridge for traffic. From Friday next, 10th
                        inst., the bridge will be open to admit the passage of river traffic from
                        1:15 to 3 p.m., instead of from 1:30 to 3 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>King’s Birthday.—To-morrow (Thursday) will be observed as a holiday in the
                        Army, in honor of the anniversary of the birthday of H.M. the King, and all
                        offices and schools wil be closed. Tbe headquarters offices will be opened
                        for business of an urgent nature from 7.15 a.m. to 8.15 a.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Khedivial Hotel - Among the im provements which are being made in tbe New
                        Khedivial Hotel, we omitted to mention in yesterday’s article on the
                        subject,that a feature of tbe hotel which will be much appreciated will be
                        tbe private dining-rooms. This will meet a much-felt want in Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>British Chamber or Commerce. — The November issue of the Journal of tbe
                        British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt has appeared The contents include:
                        Points for Manufactu- rers, Egypt's trade in Explosives, Acceleration of,
                        weekly Brindisi Mail for Alexandria.Customs Returns, Imports during
                        September, Manches- ter Goods, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Walker A Meimarchi — In reference to the paragraph on Messrs. Walker &amp;
                        Meimarachi, Limited, which we published yes terday, we are authorised to
                        state that this company has decided to remain in its present business
                        premises at Alexandria and Cairo. So there is no need for brokers and house
                        agents to apply to the firm with offers of new offices eligible sites, etc.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New British Club.—A sufficient number of replies having been receivad to
                        warrant the formation of the new British Club at Alexan- dria, a general
                        meeting of those who have signified their intention of joining will be held
                        at tbe Eastern Telegraph Company’s head quarters on Weinesdiy, 15th inst.,
                        at 9:15 p.m. Business: Election of Permanent Com mitee; Selection of
                        suitable premises (plan will be submitted).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOOTBALL.</head>
                    <p>There will be a football match tomorrow at Mostapba between the E.T.C and
                        ”D." Compy. Royal Dublin Fusiliers. Kick off at 3:30.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NO CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                    <head>DISAPPEARANCE OF DISEASE</head>
                    <p>The reports sent in by the inspectors of the Sanitary Department regarding
                        tbe cattle plague in tbe provinces are unanimous in declaring that the
                        malady has completely disappeared.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OPENING OF CATTLE MARKETS.</head>
                    <p>No cases of cattle plague having been report- ed since August 14, it has been
                        decided, should no further case occur, to open the cattle mar- kets on the
                        22nd inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTL</head>
                    <p>We hear that it has been decided that Sheikh Bakri el Sedfi, the new Grand
                        Mufti of Egypt, may continue to act as Grand Cadi till the return of Sheikh
                        Yehia from Turkey. The Grand Mufti has officially called upon the Ministers
                        since his appointment</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GRAND CADI.</head>
                    <p>The Grand Cadi of Egypt has wired to his household in Cairo, informing them
                        that he has arrived at Constantinople in safety. It is said, declares “Al
                        Moayad,” that the Grand Cadi promised his family before his departure that,
                        if no troubles were in store for him in the Capital,he would let them have
                        each a telegram. Although the Saltan's summons to tbe Cadi is still a
                        mystery,continues “A1 Moayad,” the romoor to the effect that he had been
                        called to Stamboul in order to go into tbe question of tbe Caliphate, in
                        other words, the question of the succession to the Ottoman Throne is quite
                        baseless. The Cadi of Egypt has nothing to do with such a question so long
                        as the Sheikh-ul-Islam and the other Ulema of high standing reside in
                        Constantinople. If the Sultan wishes tbe succession to pass to tbe sons
                        instead of to tbe eldest Prince he matteresn be settled at once by a single
                        1 sign from his Majesty.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR WILLIAM GARSTIN.</head>
                    <p>We understand that Sir William Garstin, aocording to the latest accounts
                        received by his friends, is making most satisfactory pro- gress and will
                        almost certainly be in Egypt before tbe new year.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VITALITY STATISTICS.</head>
                    <p>From the latest returns of tbe Statistical Department in Cairo we find that
                        the total number of births in that city during the week ending 28th Ootober
                        was 563, including 7 of foreign parentage; this being equal to a rate of 47
                        per thousand of the estimated population. For the week ended last Saturday
                        the births were 527, of which 9 were of foreign parentage, the rate being
                        44.3 per mile. The deaths for the first week under review numbered 411,
                        inoluding 24 of foreign nationality; this is equivalent to a rate of 32.7
                        per thousand for the native and 35.4 for the European portion of the inha-
                        bitants. For the week ending the 4th instant the deaths were 402, which
                        included 16 foreig- ners, and the ratios 33.0 and 23.0 per mile for the
                        native and foreign portions respec- tively. At Alexandria the births for the
                        first week were 295, which was inclusive of 15 children of foreign
                        parentage, the rate per thousand being 46.0. Last week there was registered
                        329 births, of which 17 were of the latter category. During the week ending
                        tbe 28th ult. the mortality returns were 202 natives and 12 foreigners and
                        the ratios 33.2 and 13.5 per thousand. For the week ending on Saturday last
                        the figures were 207 natives and 18 Euro- peans, the rates being 34.4 and
                        20.3 per mile respectively. For tbe guidance of those of our readers who are
                        interested in statistics, we may men- tion that according to the official
                        table recently published tbe native population of Cairo and its suburbs was
                        estimated on the 1st July last at 615,152. No exact esti- mate can, however,
                        be made of the foreign resident inhabitants of either Cairo or Alex- andria,
                        as no returns are obtainable from the Consulates. The last census of June
                        1897 gave the foreign element at 25,219 and 46,118 for each of the above
                        cities respectively but, of course, these figures must have been
                        considerably augmented since then by im- migration and excess of births over
                        deaths. The same tables give the estimated number of the native population
                        of Alexandria on the date above mentioned as 316.639.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The new Moss liner Menepthah sailed hence yesterday afternoon for Liverpool,
                        via Malts with passengers, mails and general cargo. The S.S. Asiatic Princa
                        from Antwerp and Middlesbrorgh, left Malta yesterday, and doe to arrive at
                        Alexandria on Saturday next.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck &amp; Co s Pilsener Beei BREMEN.</head>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable firm IN CAIRO, ALEXANDRIA AND THE SUDAN.
                        Otherwise apply to E J. FLEURENT, F. MICALLEF, sole agent</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LIFE OF M. WITTE THREATENED.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TREPOFFS REMOVAL DEMANDED.</head>
                    <p>(Gazette's Special Service). London, Tuesday, Nov. 7. Quiet continues to
                        prevail in St. Petersburg. The Tsar’s manifesto abolishing exclusive laws is
                        unconfirmed. The Duma is to consist of 600 members, elected on the basis of
                        property, education, and class representation. MWitte’s appointment as
                        Premier of Russia’s first Cabinet has beea gazetted. The revolutionary
                        leaders have threatened to take the life of M. Witte if General Trepoff is
                        not removed from his post within three days. M. Witte is residing in the
                        Winter Palace. The Tsar is expected in St. Petersburg on Friday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.) Port Said, Tuesday. Lord Minto, the new Viceroy of
                        India arrived here to-day by tbe P.&amp; O. mail S.S. Victoria on his way to
                        India.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H. H. the Khedive spent yesterday at Koubbeh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA.</head>
                    <p>The legal department of the Finance Minis- try has sent a note to the
                        Under-Secretary of State for Finanoe on the subject of the Khedi- vial
                        Princes’ claims re the Daira Sanieh. The note shows that the Princes have
                        little chance n of winning their case.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NATIVE APPEAL COURT.</head>
                    <p>The Ministry of Justice has decided to create a new judgeship in the Native
                        Court of Appeal at Cairo. Hussein Bey Rouchdy, a judge ot the Cairo Mixed
                        Bench, has been selected for this post and will enter on his new duties on
                        the 1st January.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW INSECT PEST.</head>
                    <p>Considerable damage has been done in one or two local idea in Upper Egypt to
                        the pome- granate by the larva of a small but pretty butterfly
                        scientifically known as Dendoriz livia and a relative of the' well known
                        “blues” and “copeprs.” It seems that the caterpillar, to which usually
                        devours tbe pods of the “fitneh” accacia enters the pomegranate immediately
                        after leaving the egg and eats long tunnels into tbe fruit Three galleries
                        get rapidly filled with mildew and the "frass” of the insect, and the fruit
                        is spoiled.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PISANI CASE.</head>
                    <p>The hearing of the Pisani case, which took place at H.B,M.’s Consulate Cairo,
                        yesterday resulted in the defendant being ordered to appear for trial before
                        the judge of the Supreme Consular Court, who is expected to arrive in Cairo
                        in about ten days to a fortnight’s time. The accused was allowed to find
                        bail, gua- ranteed by two sureties of j£160 eaoh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE VALLEY OPERATIONS.</head>
                    <p>The following report, dated Ootober 14, has been received from the Mine:-No.
                        1 shaft, 900 ft level.—North drive—This drive is now a total length of 27
                        ft. from the centre of the shaft. South drive.—The face of this drive is 18
                        ft 6 ins from the centre of the shaft. No. 5 shaft, 2nd leveL—North
                        drive.—This drive is now a total leng’h of 212 ft 3 ins from the cross-cut.
                        Tbe face of this drive is now some 20 ft north of point at which the ore
                        pinched out in the level above and is directly under the point at which the
                        cross-head cut off the fisure. Occasional specks of gold are met with. No. 7
                        shaft, 2nd level.—South drive.- This drive has again advanced to 216 ft 6
                        ins. from the cross-cut. Battery. The consignment of oil arrived on Sunday
                        morning last, since when the battery has been running steadily night and
                        day, the ore crushed being from development. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Col H.F.M. Wilson and the officers, tbe band of the 2nd
                        Batt. Rifle Brigade will play the following program- me at the Continental
                        Hotel to-morrow (Thursday) at 8 p.m, on the occassion of the King’s
                        Birthday. 1. March- Long live the King - Hume. 2. Overture- Festival-
                        Lenteur. 3. Selection- The Dancing Doll- Bayer. 4. Funeral March of a
                        Marionette- Gounod 5. Intermezo- Rendezvous- Aletter 6. Selection- Faust-
                        Gounod 7. Landler- Grossumtterchan- Lungey. 8. Velze- Morgenblatter- Trauss
                        Khedivial Anthem- God Save the King R. Wood, Bandmaster </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> BRITISH GARRISON. </head>
                    <head>NOW COMMANDED BY SIRDAR.</head>
                    <p>The British troops stationed at Khartoum have been placed under the command
                        of his Excellency the Governor-General of the Sudan, and have been struck
                        off the strength of tbe Egyptian Command with effect from 6th inst,
                        inclusive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMBLEH'S WATER SUPPLY</head>
                    <p>To the Editor or the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—As everybody is aware, we have
                        had two fires at Ramleh within the last month, and at both of these the Fire
                        Brigade promptly turned up ,but was quite useless as there was no water.
                        This news has already appeared in the columns of the “Gazette,” but we have
                        had no reply or contradiction from the Alex- andria Water Company, which
                        turns off the Ramleh water supply about 5 p.m. Fortanately on eaoh of the
                        nights on which the fires occured there was no wind. Otherwise in the case
                        of tbe fire at Bacos, all that thickly populated part of Ramleh might have
                        devastated. I presume that nothing will be done to remedy this deplorable
                        state of things until the palatial residence of some Municipal Councillor or
                        of one of the Kbedivial Princes is completely gutted. Then, and not till
                        then, will pressure be brought to bear on the Alexandria Water Company.
                        Meanwhile, all the inhabitants of Ramleh must go to bed every night with the
                        apprehension that if their home does gat on fire, all they can do is to
                        watch it burn—Truly yurs, A Ramlehite. Balkeley, 7th November.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO STREET PERILS.</head>
                    <p>Dear Sir,—I was recently told the following story by a friend, which I repeat
                        in the hope that those to whom we vaguely refer as “the proper authorities”
                        will read, mark, and learn. My informant was walking slowly one after- noon
                        along one of Cairo’s streets—and by no means its meanest—and found time to
                        pause for an instant and admire the demeanour of two Arabs who were walking
                        along tbe pavement hand in hand cleanly dressed, silent—for a wonder—and
                        their faces illumined with an abject and ruatio happiness which was worth
                        going miles to see. Suddenly a loud gargling noise came from overhead, and
                        from a spout that project- ed apparently aimlessly from a third story a jet
                        of soapy water descended on the pair. They first exhibited a wild surprise
                        and then in- dulged for a couple of minutes in excusable, if unrestrained,
                        profanity, after which they wiped their garments and moved on, still
                        cursing, amid demonstrations of amused sym- pathy from the passers-by. Now,
                        Sir, I like a harlequinade as much as any man—the spectacle of a policeman
                        falling through a trap door or coming in contact with a red hot poker has
                        always and will always please me. There is a strenuous humour ia the
                        oartoons of eighteenth century caricaturist that also appeals to me, and the
                        decent of a tub-full of soap suds on an immaculately dressed passer-by has
                        been immortalised by their pencils. But I frankly admit that I dslike
                        practical jokes when they are directed against me ; my motto is flat ex-
                        perimentum in corpore vili, and I now make a detour whenever I notice one of
                        these projecting spouts which, I hear, carry away the overflow of baths and
                        washhouses. If our city authori- ties can do something to prevent their
                        being need in this way they will earn the gratitude of many besides.
                        Meticulous. Cairo, November 7.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Adly Pasha Yaghen called upon the Prime Minister yesterday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The salary of Lord Edward Cecil Pasha as Under Secretary of State for Finance
                        has been fixed at L.E. 2,000 per aonum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>M. de la Bouliniere arrived at Cairo from Alexandria at 8 p.m. yesterday and
                        was met at the station by MM. Bonin, Bonequet, and the remaining members of
                        the personnel of the French Agency and Consulate.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among tbose leaving for Egypt on the India at the end of the month are the
                        Dow- ager Lady Kensington and Miss Winifred Edwardes, Lady Messsrene and Sir
                        W.E. Cooper.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Count A. Gouzaga will pay a short visit to Jerusalem in tbe near future.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. E. W. P. Foster have retruned to Alexandria from Europe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>M. Saint Saena the emirent composer, in- tends paying a visit to Egypt in
                        December or January next. In February he goes to Monte Carlo to attend the
                        rehearsals of his new opera, L’Ancetre.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>We regret to hear that Me. Molteni had a paralytic stroke late on Monday
                        night, and that his condition, in spite of unremitting medical watchfulness
                        and care, gives rise to very serious anxiety.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr.Reeves has arrived at the Carlton Hotel Balkeley.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCBERIES CRASH.</head>
                    <head>M. Poutrel v. Hon. A.J Davey</head>
                    <p>On Monday the action brought by M. Poutret against the Hon. A.J. Davey came
                        before tbe Cairo Mizel Tribunal the hearing wu put back to the role special.
                        M. Poutrel claims one franc damages costs and the in- sertion of the verdict
                        in three Egyptian and three French newspapers, on the ground that tbe Hon.
                        A. J. Davey dismissed him unjus- tifiably from the service of the Suceries
                        Company on the charge of having kept him in ignorance of tbe Say operations,
                        and that there is no foundation whatever for the charge. Tbe plaintiff's
                        assignation contains an elaborate summary of the reasons go to prove his own
                        innocence in the matter. We extract the* following passages from the
                        assignation:-- Attendu que par lettre du 29 septembre 1905, le sieur Davey a
                        licencie le sieur Poutrol du service de la Societe des Sucraries. Attendu
                        que les motifs mis en avant par Davey consistent en des imputations de plu-
                        sieurs faite ayant tous eu pour but an dire de Davey, de le tenir lui Davey
                        dans l'ignorance de operations Say (io)... Attendu que si ion comprend tres
                        bien I'in- teret que pent avoir. Davey dane les ciroons- tances sotuelles a
                        se faire considerdere comme etant reste dans lignorance deadites opera-
                        tions, il est impossible pourtant qu'il cherche a faire cela an detriment
                        d’un employe dont la eonduito a toojours e e absolument correcte, et a se
                        constituer ainsi les elemnts d’un “alibi moral” preventif. Or attendu que
                        Poutrel ne pouvalt avoir I’idee de tenir Davey dans l'gnorances de ces
                        operations (acceptions on antres) par la rai- son toute simple qu’il ne
                        pouvait venir a l'ide de personne que Davey put les ignore. Attendu quo pour
                        supposer que Davey les ignonorait, il aurait tallu supposer ches ledit Davey
                        une dose d’ingenuite equivalant a l'in- conscience. Attendu en effet que ces
                        operations out toutes e e passeces regulierement en comptabi- . lite et
                        figurent en toutes lettres ettons chiffres dans les livres de la societe.
                        Attendu, en consequence qu'a moins de ne pas saior lire ou de ne pas vouloir
                        voir, toute pereonne jetont les yeux sur les livres (et Davey avait ce
                        pouvoir et ce devoir) etait ne- cessairement mis au courant des dites opera-
                        tions. Attendu que dans ces conditions, suppose Davey non au courant des
                        acceptations Say, ce serait admettre ohez lui ou bien la desertion abeolue
                        de son devoir et la meconnaissanbe eotiere de son mandat, ou bien une
                        attitude speciale a la plus invetere et a la plus son- pable des ignorances.
                        Attendu qne bien loin de vouloir cacher a quiconque ces operations Say, que
                        Davey repudie maintenant, cest Pontrel lui-meme qui, entre en fonetions, a
                        donne personnel- lement des ordres pour que ces operations, tenues
                        jurqualora en dehors de la compta- bilite se ent desormais passees
                        reguliere- ment et integralement dans la comptabilite generale. Attendu
                        qu'ainsi passees integralament ces operations ni rien de ce quis’y rap-
                        portait ne ponvait etre cache qu’il fant done pour pretendre avoir ete tanu
                        dans l’ignorance et recourir a de si pauvres pre- textes faire appal aux
                        ressources fertiles d’une imagination complaisante plutot quiaux saines
                        lumieires de la raison. Attendu d’ailleurs que Davey est reste siul
                        administrateur present en Egypte en l'ete 1903, (le requerant etant aussi
                        absent a cette epoque); que dans ces conditions personne n’etant la pour lui
                        maintenir de force le bandeau sur les yeux, il eat impes- sible que Davey
                        u'ait pas ete mis par M, Boinet, son securiaire particulier, choisi per
                        lui-meme et charge depouillement de la correspindance sinon au courant da
                        moine aur la piste de ces operations qu'il ignorait et core apres 5 ans
                        passes par lui a la Di- rection de la societe. Attendu que dans le courrant
                        de la presente. annes, dans une instance engages contre la Societe, il a ete
                        depose par le sieur Talbot, l'adversaire de la societe, un memoire dont les
                        echos meme affaibliset aisent encore assez suggestifs. Que ce meme memoire a
                        sans doute ete au moins parcouro par l’avocat de la Societe, pui que ledit
                        ayocayat a demande dans ses con- clusions qu’il ful ecarle des debata comme
                        iejurieux (sic), a certainement ete communique par cet avocat aux
                        administrateura delegues (dont M. Davey) a moins que de ce chef encore ce
                        dernier n'accuse l'honorable Me Carton de l'avoir lui aussi maintenu dans
                        son etat d'ignorance chronique. Attendu done que Poutrol ne pouvant meme pas
                        soupenner que Davey put ignorer les ope- rations Say, il a'envuit qu’il
                        n’alien pa faire pour eotretenir une ignorance qui, a ses yeux, n’existant
                        pas. Attendu que dans ces conditions le licen- ciement dont Poutrol a ete
                        victime est aussi arbitraire qu’injustice. Attendu que ce
                        licenciement,injuriex pour Poutrel, est deriicA k raisra durir^buioea ' nn
                        qootid ra do matin. Qaa oette inisrtioa, eommandAe A Hem- nut par oslai l*
                        mfime qui svalt btfirfit k ; %Tgu„ do son ignorance dee folts, 0 encore
                        ^gmtA, k raison do eon oarao’tro quasi-’ ' dAtietoeux. b nsponsabilitA prop
                        re et pmeoa* nolle do Davey, rospoosabilitAdAjk emit pot
                        fosagisaeatnttntmen*lonta.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
