<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kara Hofmeister</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-03">January 3, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, JANUARY 3, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. TUESDAY, JANUARY 3, 1905.</head>
            <div type="item">
            <head>PORT ARTHUR FALLS.
            SUUKENDER OF GARRISON
            HOSTILITIES SUSPENDED.
            SHIPS BLOWN UP
            TOKIO REJOICINGS.
            MIKADO’S TRIBUTE TO STOESSEL.</head>
            <p>Tokio, January 2.</p>
            <p>General Nogi reports that he has received a
            letter from General Stoessel relating to tho
            surrender of the fortress.
            Tho Japanese stormed and captured Wantai
            Fort yesterday.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 2.</p>
            <p>It is understood that hostilities at Port
            Arthur are suspended to-day, and the Russian
            and Japanese Chiefs of the Staff are to meet at
            noon at Shunshiying, in order to discuss the
            question of the surrender.</p>
            <p>General Stoessel has written to General
            Nogi saying that any further resistance is
            useless.</p>
            <p>The Mikado has telegraphed to General
            Nogi extolling General Stoessel and ordering
            that all military honors be shown to him.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 1.</p>
            <p>General Stoessel has proposed to General
            Nogi, and the latter has accepted, to negotiate
            the surrender of the place.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 2</p>
            <p>General Stoessel wrote yesterday to General
            Nogi saying that all further resistance was
            useless and asked to capitulate.</p>
            <p>The Russian and Japanese negotiators met
            at noon and separated at 4 o'clock.</p>
            <p>The Russians accept the conditions proposed.</p>
            <p>Hostilities are suspended.</p>
            <p>The Russians blew up several forts and ships
            in the morning.</p>
            <p>(Havas) </p>
            <p>Tokio, January 2.</p>
            <p>Immense rejoicings are taking place in the
            town.</p>
            <p>(Reuter) </p>
            <p>Tokio, January 2.</p>
            <p>The capitulation of Port Arthur is causing
            great enthusiasm.</p>
            <p>The Mikado has ordered homage to be paid
            to General Stoessel.</p>
            <p>(Havas)</p>
            <p>Tokio, January 2.</p>
            <p>General Nogi informed General Stoessel that
            he agreed to appoint negotiators provided that
            the commissioners on both sides have full
            powers to sign an immediate capitulation.
            Meanwhile, hostilities have been suspended.</p>
            <p>(Later). The negotiations lasted from noon
            until 4.30 p.m. Arrangements have been con-
            cluded to sign an act of capitulation. The
            Japanese terms have been accepted.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>AWFUL CONDITION OP THE TOWN.</head>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 2.</p>
            <p>(Midnight). The “Retvisan," the “Pol-
            tava,” and the “ Pallada " caught fire at Port
            Arthur in the morning; they were still burning
            during the afternoon. Tho Russians blew up
            the " Sevastopol.”</p>
            <p>The Russian officers state there are 15,000
            sick and wounded at Port Arthur. Many
            soldiers are lying in the streets, as the hospitals
            have been shattered by the shells. The garrison
            numbers 5,000, most of whom are convalescents.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>RUSSIAN SHIPS AT CHI-FU.</head>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 2.</p>
            <p>Four Russian destroyers and a launch enter-
            ed the harbour. A bundle of despatches was
            taken ashore.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 2.</p>
            <p>Three large Japanese destroyers have entered
            the harbour.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Chi-Fu, January 2.</p>
            <p>The Russian destroyers have disarmed, and
            the Japanese have consequently left the
            harbour.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
            <p>Tsinqtau, January 2.</p>
            <p>Two Russian destroyers and a merchantman
            with 800 soldiers have reached here.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>OPINION ON THE PALL</head>
            <p>London, January 2.</p>
            <p>The concensus of opinion in diplomatic
            circles is that the fall of Port Arthur will only
            be a fresh incentive to renew the struggle more '
            vigorously. Russia will not spare any efforts
            to recapture it, or compel its submission in-
            directly. The only reservation in this opinion
            is the internal condition of Russia, which is
            the dominant factor of the situation. (R.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
            <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable
            Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea,
            Central position. Under English management</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>BALTIC FLEET.
            ARRIVAL AT MADAGASCAR.</head>
            <p>Sainte Marie (Madagascar), January 2.</p>
            <p>Admiral Rodjoetvensky's squadron anchored
            Lore yesterday. The vessels are all in excellent
            condition despite violent storms after leaving
            the Cape.</p>
            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>LEGION OF HONOUR.
            LOCAL APPOINTMENTS.</head>
            <p>Paris, January 2.</p>
            <p>M.M. Provost and Chelu have been made
            Chevaliers of-the Legion of Honour.</p>
            <p>(Havas.)</p></div> 
            <div type="item"> <head>LOCAL AND_GENERAL</head>
            <p>The Battle or Flowers will take place
            at Ghezireh Palate on Thursday.</p>
            <p>Post Office—Ahmed Effendi Helwa, from
            the Cairo Post Office, has been appointed
            Inspector of Damanhour District</p>
            <p>The Maltese Benevolent Society has
            opened a subscription among the Maltese
            merchants at Alexandria for gifts in kind on
            the occasion of tho New Year.</p>
            <p>The Khedivial Yacht "Mahroussa" left
            Alexandria yesterday for Glasgow for the
            purpose of being fitted with turbines. She is
            expected to remain away for at least a year,
            during which time the yacht will be consider-
            ably improved.</p>
            <p>Suez Canal—16 vessels passed through the
            Canal on the 30th inst, the receipts for the day
            being frs. 447,650.46. 9 of the ships were Bri-
            tish, 1 Turkish, 1 Austrian, 1 French, 1 Nor-
            wegian, 3 German. The receipts from 1st to
            30th December were frs. 10,751,600.69.</p>
            <p>Merchant Seamen’s Homs.—Lady Blom-
            field begs to acknowledge the receipt from Mr.
            G. B. Alderson of three turkeys and plum
            puddings, and from Dr. and Mrs. Morrison of
            a turkey and a cake for the ’Xmas treat. Miss
            Swan acknowledges the following contribu-
            tions :—Mrs. Ambroise Zervudachi, £1; Miss
            Constantinides, £1 ; Mrs. Michel Sinadino,
            10s.; Mrs. A. Beuachi, 10s.; Mrs. Coroni, £1.</p>
            <p>New Year's Gifts.—On the occasion of the
            New Year, M. Niner director at Alexandria of
            the Sucreries et Raffinerie d'Egypie, presented a
            sack of sugar to each of the following institu-
            tions : Home for the Aged (Souers St. Charles
            Boromoee), German Catholic School (ditto),
            European Hospital, Greek Hospital, Jewish
            Hospital,Government Hospital,Rudolph Home,
            Girls' Orphanage (Soeurs St. Vincent de Paul),
            Boys' Orphanage (ditto), Foundlings’ Home,
            Moharrem Bey.</p>
            <p>Restriction or Street Traffic in Cairo.
            -The police no longer allow camels and heavily-
            laden trucks to obstruct Cairo's principal
            streets. The originator of this much-needed
            rule is to be highly commended. Many street
            obstructions have recently been modified
            through the efforts of the Tanzim Department,
            notably at the Round Point, Kasr-el-Nil Bridge
            entrance, Ghizereh, which had long been a
            nuisance to the hundreds of carriages which
            pass that point daily.</p>
            <p>Sailors and Soldiers' Institute. — The
            following contributed the presents which were
            competed for by the boys of the Berkshire
            Regiment at the Institute on Friday last:—
            Major and Mrs. Gamble, Major and Mrs.
            Finch, Egyptian Gazette, Mr. F. G. Preen inn.
            Rev. Egyptian Gazette, Mr. W. N. Perkins, Mr. J.
            F. Letts, Mr. F. M. Manley, Mr. J. Fleet, Mr.
            J. H. Marsden, Mrs. Lawrence, Mr. W. Che-
            valier, Mr. J. Stanley Dorling, Lee. Corpl
            H. Morley, Lee. Corpl. H. New, Mr. S. James
            Dawson, Mr. C. Pritchard, Mr. W. Rainbow,
            Miss Pattinson</p>
            <p>Amateur Theatricals.—The performance in
            Cairo of “The Pirates of Penzance” has been
            postponed, owing to the temporary absence of
            Lieut. Franklin, the musical director, in Khar-
            toum-. It will now probably take place about
            the third week in February. The respite is ap-
            preciated by the members of the troupe, as it
            was felt that the time allotted to the rehear-
            sals in the first instance was somewhat short.
            The delay will afford Major Delavoye more
            scope for the development of stage effects, and
            the performance will thus be as finished from a
            dramatic as from a musical point of view—a
            requirement not always sufficiently considered
            in the representation of comic operas by
            amateurs.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
            <p>The SB. “Octa,” of the Westcott and Lau-
            rance Line, left Malta yesterday and is due
            on Friday with general cargo from Antwerp
            and Loudon.</p>
            <p>The Canard SS. ‘Tyria" is due here to-
            morrow and will immediately begin loading
            cargo for Liverpool and American ports.
            The Ellerman S.S. “Avon" sailed from Malta
            this morning, and is expected in Alexandria
            on Friday evening with passengers, mails, and
            general cargo.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,
            CAIRO.
            Open all the year round.
            ELECTRIC LIGHT-LIFT-MODERATE CHARGES</head>
            <head> THE KHEDIVE</head>
            <p>The Khedive has been pleased to bestow the
            following ranks and decorations on the under-
            mentioned gentlemen :— </p>
            <p>Medjidieh, Grand Officer (2nd class): Brews-
            ter Bey.</p>
            <p>Medjidieh, Commander (3rd claas) : Ahmed
            Khairy Boy, master of ceremonies.</p>
            <p>Chevalier (5th class): Mohamed Ibrahim
            Effendi, Ahmad El-Azhari Effendi, Mohamed
            Abd-el-Wahed Effendi, of the Khedive's tele-
            graph office.</p>
            <p>Osmanieh, Officer (4th class): Dr. Hassan
            Moharram Bey and Dr. Sadek Ramadan Bey,
            of the Khedive's medical staff.</p>
            <p>Sanieh (Bey): Ahmed Ismail Bey, chief
            cashier to the Khedive.</p>
            <p>Salissah : Mohamed Cherif Effendi, secretary
            of the cabinet of ceremonies.</p>
            <p>On Accession Day (Sunday next) his High-
            ness will hold a reception at Abdeen Palace,
            commencing at 8.30 a.m.</p>
            <p>The Khedivah will also receive European
            ladies from 3.30 to 4 p.m. and the wives of
            diplomatic agents at 4.20 p.m., at Koubbeh
            Palace.</p>
            <p>The order of the reception will be published
            in to-morrow’s issue.</p> </div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE FINANCIAL^ADVISER.</head>
            <p>Our excellent confrere, the Phare d’ Alexan-
            dria, makes the following conciliatory--remarks
            on the statements as to tho Hellenio colony of
            Alexandria and hashish smuggling, contained
            in the report of the Financial Adviser-—</p>
            <p>“…on ce qui conoerno la criuquo indirecte
            adrosse'e par lo Conaeiller Financier A uno par- ^
            tie do la CumnmnauuS Helfeuique, il est tris ^
            certain qa’il ne taut voir Ik qu’ane fauto de
            style, uuo erreur de redaction. Nous savons ^
            misux quo personae oombien M. Corbett out .
            ami dos HeliAues et ddvoud k lour cause. 11 fut
            pendant plusieurs ounces commisaaire de la d
            Dotto A Athtues et a’y montre le plus chaleu- ^
            roux des PhilheilAnee. Ses sentiments n'ont g(
            pas varid depute; mais sa plume aura trehi sa
            peusdo. On pout le regretter; nous aorions ^
            mauvaiae grtce k l'eu critiquer.”</p></div>
           <div type="item"> <head>THE POSTMASTER GENERAL.</head>
            <p>We are officially authorised to state that the
            announcement made to-day by a Cairo morning
            paper “on very good authority" that Saba Pa-
            sha, the Postmaster General, had tendered his
            resignation, is absolutely without any founda-
            tion whatsoever.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>IMPORTANT APPOINTMENT.</head>
            <p>We learn that Dr. W. St. C. Symmers,
            professor of pathology and bacteriology at the
            school of Medicine at Kasr-el-Aini, is about
            to leave Egypt to take up an important
            appointment in pathology at Belfast. Tbs
            Egyptian Government will feel the loss of a
            valuable servant, for Dr. Symmers, daring his
            sojourn in this country, has established for
            Himself a well-earned reputation as a scientific
            worker of great capacity and thoroughness.
            For his work at the Serum Institute for bovine
            typhus at Abbassieh the country owes him a
            special debt of gratitude. H.H. the Khedive
            has already testified his appreciation of Dr.
            Symmers' services in this connection by
            presenting him with a handsome set of
            diamond solitaires. Dr. Symmers' many friends
            in Egypt will boar of his approaching departure
            with regret.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ASSIOUT TRAINING COLLEGE.</head>
            <p>The event of the Fall semester closing
            exercises of Assiout Training College was the
            contest between the Forum and Kiddonian
            Literary Societies. The representatives of the
            two societies, elected some months ago, contest-
            ed for honors in declamation, oration, and
            debate. The Kiddonian society won the oration
            and the debate, giving them five points out of
            six. The subjects of the two orations were
            “The Power of Oratory" and “Woman’s Power
            and Influence." 'The question for debate was
            “Resolved, that a final victory for Japan would
            be more beneficial to the world than a final
            victory for Russia.”</p>
            <p>A feature of the occasion was the music,
            vocal and instrumental, furnished by local
            talent, assisted by Miss Dysart of Cairo. The
            singing of the college glee club was thoroughly
            enjoyed by all, and showed a great advance
            over anything the club has given in public
            heretofore. </p>
            <p> A large number of the English-speaking
            community of Assiout were present,as the exercises
            were all in English. Every one was ready to
            congratulate the two societies and the college
            upon the great improvement in composition and style
            and delivery which was shown by the contest, since
            the orations and debate were entirely original
            productions by the students, with practically no changes
            made by the teachers. The two societies meet regularly
            each week, the results of careful drill and experience
            were quite manifest.</p>
            <p> The college has enjoyed a very prosperous session,
            with an attendance of 550 students. A large new dining-
            room is being erected for the better accommodation
            of the boarding department. The staff of instructors now
            numbers twenty-three regular teachers, even of whom
            are Americans. A valuable addition to the corps was made
            this Fall, in the college savings secured Miss Strutters,
            recently of Boston, for instruction in art and penmanship,
            and Miss Moore, of Pennsylvania, as matron. </p></div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good -----</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very ---- Brand of Beer</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x xx</p>
                </div>
           <div type="item"> <head>EGYPT’S TRADE.</head>
            <head>NOVEMBER RETURNS.</head>
            <p>The imports during the month kept up their
            usual rate of increase, which has been such a
            noticeable featereof this year’s customs returns.
            During November there was an increase of
            L.K. 794,898 over the figures for the cor-
            responding month lest year. Last November
            the imports amounted to L.E. 2,447,129, as
            against LE 1,653,231 in November, 1903. If
            December's imports showed a similar power of
            expansion the total imports for the year will
            show an increase of close upon L.R 4,000,000
            over last year. Up to the end of November
            the imports amounted to L.R 18,140,838, as
            against L.R 15,038,399, an increase of LE.
            8,107,439. The total exports during these
            eleven months amount to L.E. 18,201,952, an
            increase of L.R 1,705,341 over and above the
            figures for the corresponding period in 1903.
            The exports for November amounted to L.E.
            8,666,967, a decrease of Li 884,857 on
            November lest year. This falling off is mainly
            to cotton exports, which decreased to value to
            the extent of LE 284,589, and cotton seed
            exports, which decreased by LE 76,482 com-
            pared with the figures for the previous
            November.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>EGYPTIAN GOLD DEMAND.</head>
            <p>The Statist understands that the Egyptian
            demand for gold is practically satisfied, which
            is entirely contrary to the general anticipa-
            tion. For some years past Egypt has been
            taking larger and larger amounts, and has
            been sending back less and less. It was gene-
            rally supposed that she would do the same
            this past year. As a matter of fact, she has
            taken exceptionally little.</p>
            <p>The general explanation given is that
            Egyptian capitalists have been buying Egyp-
            tian bonds and Egyptian securities of all
            sorts in the London market upon a very large
            scale—upon so large a scale, in fact, that to
            all intents and purposes their purchases have
            counterbalanced the amount due to Egypt on
            account of her exports.</p>
            <p>If the explanation be correct, it is interest-
            ing from two points of view: firstly, from the
            evidence it affords of the growth of wealth in
            Egypt. In all countries which have debts held
            in large amounts abroad, the natives begin to
            buy back those debts as soon as they advance
            in prosperity. Egypt, apparently, is doing this
            now. In the second place, it relieves the London
            market from one drain for gold. True, gold
            shipments after the turn of the year will
            not cause as much inconvenience as they
            would have caused during the past two or
            three months. Still it is well that the demand
            for the metal for abroad should decline.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>THE TAWIL FAILURE</head>
            <p>It has been decided to have a liquidation
            “a l'amiable” to the case of the failure of Mr.
            Selim TawiL Messrs. Gorrs, Sofio, and Deb-
            bane have been appointed liquidators.</p>
            <p>It is estimated that the assets of Mr. Selim
            Tawil amount to LE 750,000 and the liabi-
            lities to LE 700,000. Even if this estimate
            is not correct it is thought that the liabilities
            will be sufficiently covered or even at the
            lowest estimate a dividend of 90 per cent, will
            be declared.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>ZIZINIA THEATRE.
            “ADRIANA LECOUVREUR.”</head>
            <p>There was a large house at the Zizinia on
            Saturday and again last night to witness the
            performance of Maestro Cilea’s new opera,
            which met with a huge success. Signs. Angelica
            Pandolfini's interpretation of the title role was
            one deserving of the highest commendation.
            Her singing and acting were imbued with a
            great degree of originality and intelligence, and
            her rendering of the death scene was admir-
            able. Signa. A. Pandolfinl was ably supported
            by Sig. Bravi, who mde an excellent Count
            de Saxe. Tho baritone Nani, in the role of
            Michonnet, also scored a distinct success. Sig.
            Galetti-Gianoli, as Prince de Bouillon, Signi.
            Sals, Foglia, and Rossini were also at their
            best. The "mise en scene” was as good as ever
            and the orchestra to fine form.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>“STRIKE" AT THE VERDI
            DEPARTURE OF THE ARTISTES.</head>
            <p>The strike of the artistes of the Verdi
            Theatre, Cairo, has terminated to a most un-
            satisfactory manner the majority of the com-
            pany having announced their determination to
            return to Italy as soon as possible and
            having refused to accept the modified
            terms offered by the management. In our
            opinion, they have had every reason to feel
            aggrieved at their treatment both by the
            direction and the Cairo public. The company
            was a vary strong one, containing artistes of
            really superior quality to any we have recently
            heard at the Khedivial Opera House, but
            none the less they failed almost entirely to
            attract the steady attendance of the music
            loving public. Certain performances drew
            large audiences, but in the main the results
            were disappointing to the extreme.</p>
            <p>We attribute this to part to the want of
            sufficient advertisement, and to the methods
            of the ticket-office, which were not always
            as courteous as might be wished, but
            the blame lies mainly on the public, who
            were very ready to applaud a performance
            given last night for the benefit of the artistes
            who are leaving Egypt, bot never gave them
            that continued support which would have made
            their departure unnecessary. Last night's per-
            formance was very successful. It consisted of the
            3rd act of Aida, which was excellently perform-
            ed, acts from Traviata and Trovatore, the Danza
            delle Ore from Gioconda, and the fourth act of
            Otello. The artistes were all at their best and
            we must again express our regret at the debacle
            so excellent a company.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>KHEDIVIAL AGRICULTURAL
            SOCIETY</head>
            <p>The following correspondence passed between
            the Minister of Finance and the President of
            the Khedivial Agricultural Society with
            regard to the new constitution of the latter;-</p>
            <p>Sir,—Since the formation, to 1898, of the
            Khedivial Agricultural Society, in which the
            Government took an active part, the interest
            shown by all classes of the community to the
            agricultural development of the country has
            largely increased. The various measures adopt-
            ed by the society—such as the organization of
            shows, the distribution of seed and manure,
            and the publicity given to kindred subjects
            through the medium of the Society's journal-
            have given a stimulus to all matters relating
            to the cultivation of the soil. Egypt being
            essentially an agricultural country, the general
            welfare of the cultivator most always be an
            object of the utmost solicitude to the Govern-
            ment, which during recent years has continued
            to aid the Society both financially and otherwise.</p>
            <p>From time to time, the desirability of creat-
            ing a Ministry of Agriculture has been urged,
            but the Government is of opinion that, for the
            present at all events, greater benefits will
            result from an extension of the work of the
            Society on certain lines. The principal defect
            in the past has lain to the fact that the central
            administration of the Society and the culti-
            vators were not in touch. In considering any
            new scheme of development, this point is one
            which should receive serious attention.</p>
            <p>After a careful study of the existing Sta-
            tutes of the Society, the Government has
            drafted, for the consideration of members, s
            series of revised Statutes of which I have
            the honor to enclose a copy. This document
            will be found to indicate generally the changes
            which, in the opinion of the Government, it
            is advisable to introduce into the organization
            of the Society.</p>
            <p>It is suggested that, to accordance with
            Article 21 of the present Statutes, a gene-
            ral meeting of members of the Society should
            be convoked, and that the proposed changes
            should be submitted to them for approval.
            Should the Statutes be adopted either to their
            entirety or with such modifications as the So-
            ciety may consider desirable and as the Go-
            vernment may approve, the Government is
            prepared to still further increase the annual
            subvention now granted to the Society, to
            order that they may be put into force.</p>
            <p>It is proposed that the Moudirieh Delega-
            tions to which reference is made to Articles 13,
            14 and 15 of the amended Statutes, should be
            substituted for those now existing in the
            Moudirieh towns of Gharbieh, Sharkia and
            Minia. Competent Secretaries for other
            Moudiriehs are not at present available, but
            as opportunities occur a gradual extension will
            be made to this direction, and the Govern-
            ment will, if necessary, consider the advisability
            of proportionately increasing the subvention.
            In the meantime, the society may engage
            students who have obtained their diplomas
            from the School of Agriculture: and these
            gentlemen, being placed on the Society’s experi-
            mental farms, and allowed to participate in the
            general work, will, in the course of a year or
            so, become competent to act as Secretaries to
            additional Moudirieh Delegations.</p>
            <p>The extension thus given to the work of ths
            society will necessitate the appointment of an
            assistant to the present Secretary, as well as
            that of a paid Accountant in the office. To
            meet this increase of expenditure, as well as to
            provide for the three Moudirieh Delegations
            to which allusion is made above, the Govern-
            ment is prepared to grant a sum of LE 3,000
            annually to addition to the subvention now
            accorded.</p>
            <p>The question of the establishment of a
            Statistical bureau, for the collection of infor-
            motion relating to crop areas and general
            agricultural returns, to which the Society is
            greatly interested, is at present occupying the
            attention of the Government</p>
            <p>The Government will be glad to learn in due
            course the result of tho deliberations or mem-
            bers, in order that the proposed changes, if
            adopted, may be put into force from January
            1st, 1905.</p>
            <p>I am to add that the Government would
            view with pleasure the election of Your High-
            ness as President of the Society and also of the
            Executive and General Committees ; of HH.
            Prince Ibrahim Pasha Hilmy and of H.E. Riaz
            Pasha as Vice-Presidents of the General Com-
            mittee ; of H.E. Chawarby Pasha and Mr. Gib-
            son as Vice-Presidents, and of Mr. Carey as
            Assistant Vice-President of the Executive Com-
            mittee. The Government would suggest the
            nomination of Mr. G. P. Fosden, the present
            Secretary of the society, as Secretary General</p>
            <p>I have the honour to be, etc
            signed: Ahmed Mazloum,
            Minister of Finance. </p>
            <p>(Translation).</p>
            <p>Excellency,</p>
            <p>I have the honour to acknowledge receipt of
            your letter No. 841, dated 23rd November,
            1904, containing the changes which the Go-
            vernment deems advisable to introduce into
            the Administration of the Society. This letter,
            together with the proposed new Statutes of
            the Society which accompanied it, formed the
            subject of deliberation at a meeting of our
            General Committee held under my presidency
            on December 3rd last The changes proposed
            were received with great satisfaction by the
            Society, and the Statutes, with the exception
            of one or two minor changes which the society
            thinks will render them more perfect, and
            which, under cover and separate letter I have
            communicated to your Excellency for considera-
            tion by the Government, were unanimously
            adopted.</p>
            <p>In accordance with the request contained to
            your Excellency’s letter, and in conformity with
            Art 21 of the existing Statutes of the Society,
            a general meeting of members was held on
            December 6th last at which the members
            cordially approved of the changes proposed
            and confirmed the decisions taken by the Com-
            mittee of the Society at its meeting of the 3rd
            inst. The society feels assured that the steps
            taken by the government to increase its sphere
            of usefulness will result in a  much greater
            interest being taken in its work by agricultur-
            its generally. Through the medium of the
            proposed Moudirieh Delegations, the steps
            taken by the society to aid cultivators in a
            practical manner will receive greater publicity
            and the society feels assured that greater ad-
            vantage will be taken of them. </p>
            <p>The members of the society view with great
            pleasure the continued interest which the
            Government takes in its work, and it is a great
            pleasure for me, as president of the society,
            to be the interpreter of the cordial votes and
            thanks which were passed at the meetings over
            which I had the honor to preside.</p>
            <p>I have the honor to be, etc.</p>
            <p>signed: Huessin Kamri, President.</p>
            <p>His excellency, The Minister of Finance, Cairo.</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
            <p>Judge Halton is staying at the Mena House
            Hotel.</p>
            <p>Over 100 tourists have arrived et Shep-
            heard’s Hotel from the North German Lloyd
            SS. "Friedrich der Grosse." Among them we
            notice Comte de Perigord, Hon. Mrs. Sackville
            West, Freiherr von Bernewits, Commerrienrath
            Schott and family, Mr. and Mrs. Clay Evans,
            Mr. R. A. Pinkerton and family, Mr. Jul.
            Rothschild, Mr. Luis de Sommers and family,
            Baron de la Huerta, Mr. J. P. Frank and Mrs.
            E R Frank, Mr. Lionel Sutro and family, Mr.
            and Mrs A. Frappier, Mr. and Mrs.L Donnel,
            etc. </p>
            <p>Captain E. M. K. Parsons, Governor Mili-
            tary Prison, Cairo, left for Khartoum on San-
            day on inspection duty.</p>
            <p>Mr. McPherson Grant, agent at Alexandria
            for the Sudan Government Railways, is re-
            turning with his bride to Egypt on the 15th
            inst.</p>
            <p>Mr. Arthur Fowler, of the firm of John
            Fowler &amp; Co. of Leeds, who paid a visit to
            Egypt last month, has arrived at Railhead on
            the Abyssinian Railway. He is on his way to
            pay a visit to the Emperor Menelik to order
            to advise the Negus on the subject of traction
            engines. Menelik had previously given this
            firm an order for a dozen traction engines.</p>
            <p>The appointments of Ravenscroft Bey, Mr.
            H. M. Anthony, Mr. Clowes, and Mr. Mac-
            donald are officially confirmed.</p>
            <p>Lieut A. C. K. Magill, 2nd Royal Innis-
            killing Fusiliers, has been appointed District
            Signalling Officer, Egypt</p>
            <p>Mr. Richmond, Inspector of Public Build-
            ings, has been appointed a member of the
            Superior Provincial Council, Ministry of the
            Interior.</p>
            <p>We are requested to state that Mr. Methold,
            and not Judge Ingle Joyce, was the barrister
            in whose chambers Judge Vaux read at
            Lincoln’s Inn.</p>
            <p>The following passengers left Cairo by the
            "Hotasoo" on Friday for the Nile trip:—
            Mr. and Mrs. Rankine, Mr. and Mrs. C.
            Guerin, Miss Milner, Miss Handley, Mr. and
            Mrs. H. Morel Journal. Mr. and Mrs. A. T
            Crompton, Miss S. R. Crompton. Mrs. J. B
            Webster, Miss N. M. Artindale. Miss Artindale,
            Mr. and Mrs Pace, Mrs Grotjohan, Mrs
            Gindre, Mr. R. F. Pearson, Mr. de Corts, Dr
            and Mrs. Goldschid, Dr. H. von Portheim.</p>
            <p>The following were the passengers by the
            “Prince Abbas," whcoh left Shellal on New
            Year’s Day: Mr. and Mrs H. Whitehouse,
            Miss Ringer, Miss M. Ringer, Mr. aid Mrs
            R W. Cooke Taylor, Col. and Mrs. Rolleston,
            Dr. A. Turati, Mr. Robert Hunter Dunn, Mr.
            H. Clover, Miss Chamberlain, Miss K. Cham-
            berlain, Mr. Joseph Walton, M. P., Mr. Max
            Scull, Mrs G. Scull, Miss J. E Muntz.</p>
            <p>Amongst the latest arrivals at the Eastern
            Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. P. F.
            Woodcock and family, Mr. and Mrs McNut,
            Mr. J. Grandy, Miss C. Barney, Mr. and Mrs.
            T. Roberts, Mr. A. Eeman, Mr. S. L. Washing-
            ton, Mr. J. Oldham, Mr. J. Bergmars, Mr. J.
            Grey, Mr. W. Summers, Capt C. C. Hook, Mr.
            and Mrs W. J. Powell, Mr. J. Swanson, Mr.
            J. M. Little, Mr. W. Abbot, Miss Wheels, Mr.
            B. B. Dickson, Capt Bennett</p></div>
            <div type="item"> <head>NOTICE.</head>
            <p>To All Whom it May Concern.
            The Grand Rabbi of Alexandria has pro-
            nounced a decree of divorce under date of
            December 28, 1904, between Mr. Silvio Rosen-
            berg and his wife nee Ernestine Polack.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten miniutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron
                        Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </div></body>
    </text>
</TEI>
