<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Thomas Corzo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-26">September 26, 2016</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-06-15/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-15">Thursday, June 15, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/mode/1up" status="incomplete"><div type="nameplate">
                <table cols="6">
                    <row>
                        <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01">The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                            Limited.<lb/> This Company's system of submarine telegraph
                            <lb/>cables is the most direct and quickest means of
                            <lb/>communication from Egypt to Europe, North and <lb/>South
                            America, East, South and West Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New
                            Zealand, China and Japan.<lb/> To secure quick transmission,
                            telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi rend="italic">Via
                                Eastern</hi>.For latest average time to London, see daily
                            <lb/>bulletin in this paper.<lb/> STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria,
                            Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik, Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office.
                            London.</cell>
                        <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                        <cell rows="2">The Eastern Telegraph Company, Limited.<lb/> This
                            Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the most
                            direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt to
                            Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West Africa,
                            <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.<lb/> To secure
                            quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.For latest average time to
                            London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in this paper.<lb/> STATIONS IN
                            EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik, Port-Saïd, Suakin.
                            Head <lb/>Office. London.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>No. <measure quantity="7215">7,215</measure>]</cell>
                        <cell>ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JUNE 15, 1905.</cell>
                        <cell>[SIX PAGES</cell>
                        <cell>P.T. 1</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
            </div></div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/page/n1/mode/1up" status="empty"/>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, Thursday, JUNE 15, 1905.</head>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROYAL WEDDING.. I UK GARDEN PARTY. DESCRIPTION OF CEREMONY. KHEDIVE PRESENT.</head>
                    <p>London, June 14. i mcial). King Edward has appointed the , — ,.1' Sweden and
                        Norway British Admiral. Windsor Castle is thronged with guests for royal
                        'wedding to morrow. Their Majesties ^ most brilliant, garden party to day.
                        I'■■weather was superb and thore were "si* isjuid present. (Reuter's
                        TKLKiH.Vjt)</p>
                    <p>London, June 14. Hie Khedivo travelled to Windsor with the p and Duchess of
                        Connaught and the bridal . i: j.le, to attend the weddiug. ( From our
                        Correspondent ).</p>
                    <p>WisieoR, Thursday, 1p.m. t he marriage of Prince Qustavus Adolphus : Sweden
                        and Norway, and Princess Margare. unaught took place to day in St George's i
                        impel, Windsor Castle, at ball-past twelve «k. Tho Archbishop of Canterbury
                        offi-elated. I'hore wero three State carriage proeos-- ns from Windsor
                        Castle to the west door : Sr. George's Chapel, in the Horseshoe ('misters.
                        First, the bridegroom and his sup-j rterr ; second, the King aud Queen with
                        t;-.e u-ember- of the Royal Family and the Jv«yai guests from-the Continent;
                        third,the bride and- the Duko of Conuaught, who gave her away. The members
                        of the Corps Diplomatique and the Ministers who were invited, and Jo other
                        guests from LondoD, left Pad-gton by special train at 10.45, and on arriving
                        at Windsor they proceeded to the west entrance of St. George's Chapel, and
                        thence to the choir, where the Gentlemen Ushers were in atteudanco to show
                        the company to their places. After the ceremony the bride and bridegroom and
                        the Royal party returned at once to the Castle, where the marriage register
                        was signed in the White Drawing-room before the dejeuner in the State
                        dining-room. The general company of guests proceeded to the Castle from the
                        Chapel for luncheon, which is now being served in St. George's Hall. The
                        Khedive was present and looked in the best of health. His Highness was
                        attended by Zeky Pasha, Chetik Pasha, and the newly-appointed English
                        aide-de camp, Major Watson. Among others present were the bridegroom's
                        mother, the Crown Princess of Sweden, attended by Countess Loewouhaupt and
                        Mme. Bull. Princess Margaret was atteuded by Baroness Falkenberg and Mme.
                        Wedell-Jarlsberg. The City of Christiania has decided to give a valuable
                        weddiug piesent to Prince Gustavos Adolphus of Sweden and Norway and
                        Princess Margaret of Connaught. A committee of pro lumen t Norwegians,
                        including M. Michelsen, Minister of Customs and Finance, ' and Dr. Nansen,
                        has been formed for the purpose of discussing what form the gift shall take.
                        Christiania's present will be handed to the young couple on their first
                        visit to Norway.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN MINES.</head>
                    <p>The licence of the 11th June, 1900, originally granted by the Governor
                        General of the Sudan to Mr. Archibald Knox Brown, and which subsequently
                        became vested in the iiqypt and Sudan Mining Syndicate, Limited, and the
                        renewal thereof, dated the 25th November, 190*2, was, with the consent of
                        the Governor General, assigned to the Sudan Gold Field, Limited, expired on
                        tho 31st August, 1904. Victoria Investment Corporation. The licence of June
                        22ud, 1901, granted to the Victoria Investment Corporation, Limited, has
                        been suriendcred. Sudan Gold Field, Ltd. A prospecting licence has been
                        granted for a period of three years over the area lying between latitudo 22
                        and 2J and longitude 32 aud 31 30. This is In renewal of the licences ct thu
                        11th Juue, 1900, aud 25th November, 1902. Tho licence gives the Sudan Gold
                        Field, Limited, the right under cortain conditions to obtain a further
                        extension over an area of 2,600 hectares. Sudan Mines, Ltd. A prospecting
                        licence has been granted for period of four years over the area lying
                        between latitude 22 and 20 and longitude 3G and the Red Sea Coast. This is
                        in substitution of the licence of the 22nd June, 1901. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="bandPerformance" status="incomplete">
                    <head>ESUKKIEli GARDENS.</head>
                    <p> By kind permission of Lient.-Colonel R. C. C. Cox, commanding, and officers
                        2nd Royal Cmiskilling Fusiliers, the band will play tlx-following selection
                        of music in the Esbektili Gardens to-morrow (Friday) at 9 p.m. f March-Tin
                        fju* rUawl-MjiMlnoa.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Fire, which broke out at Kafr Hassan Bey Hosny on the 11th inst,
                            destroyed eight houses.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"II GiornaCk."—</head>
                        <p>This resuscitated Italian newspapor will make its first Appearance in
                            Cairo on July 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>'D.C.L for the Sirdar</head>
                        <p>—'The University of Oxford has decided to bestow the degree o> D.C.L.,
                            honoris causa, on Sir Reginald Wingate. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Camilleri Cam.</head>
                        <p>is still occupying the attention of the British Consular Court at
                            Alexandria. Judgment had not been give we went to press. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Delta LanT> and Investment Co.</head>
                        <p>— This company's new issue of 100,000 shares at a premium of £1 has been
                            fully subscribed for Egypt and England. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Does</head>
                        <p>found in the Saida Zeyuub quarter of Cairo during tomorrow night and at
                            daylight on Saturday will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Land Comply.</head>
                        <p>— A native contemporary states that Lord Dormer has founded a company
                            with d capital of £250,000 for land development in the Sudan. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Delta Lftyir Railway Co.</head>
                        <p>—The new issue of 193,000 shares at £12.10s. by the Egyptian Delta Light
                            Railway Company, Limited, has entirely taken up by the shareholders.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Red Sea Lighthouses.</head>
                        <p>—Wo have to acknowledge with thanks the receipt of a parcel of magazines
                            from Mr. W. J. B. Webb, for the English keepers of tho Red Sea
                            lighthouses. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Dramatic Performance. —</head><p>The Ernesto Rossi dramatic club are giving a
                            performance of Giacometti's 4 act drama Ixi Marts Cicils in the Eden
                            Theatre on Saturday next, at 9 p.m. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        </div><div type="item"><head> roLtsti Sailor Drowned,—</head><p>An English seaman employed on board tho British
                            S.S. 'Clio," in Alexandria harbour, foil overboard yejtorday aud was
                            drowned. His body has not been recovered. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Late Trams.—</head><p>The Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Company will run electric
                            trams op to 1.15 o'clock to-morrow morning on the occasion of tho ball
                            at the Hotel Beau-Rivage to night, which promises to be a very brilliant
                            affair. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Uh Res.—</head><p>An application has been made to the London Stock Exchange
                            Committee to appoint a special settling day in "Urn Rus Gold Mines of
                            Egypt," further issue of 30,000 shares of £1 each, 5s. paid, Nos.
                            150,001 to 180,000. .</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Egyptian Irrigation Trusts.—</head><p>The Bank of England announce the numbers of
                            257 Four per oent Egyptian Government Irrigation Trust Certificates
                            which have been drawn for redemption on Jnly 1, 1905, when interest
                            thereon will cease. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        </div><div type="item"><head> Alhambra —</head><p>The performance to-night of the popular operetta Primavsra
                            Scapigliata will be for the benefit of the charming prima-donna Signs.
                            Ines Imbimbo, who deserves to have a hamper honso. Several additional
                            attractions are on the programme for^o-night</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> The Didot-Bottin.—</head><p>Mr. A. Burke Honan, foreign inspector-general of the
                            Didot-Bottin publishing company, has left Alexandria and entrusted the
                            agency for the famous French directory to Mr. George A. Adib,
                            Stambonl-street, for Alexandria, the villages, and the Sadan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p> Egypt is to bo well represented in the forthcoming new edition of the
                            "Anglo-African Who's Who," and it is to be hoped that the legion of
                            local notables will respond with alacrity to the editors' demand for
                            biographical items and send fall and aocurate details of their
                            careers.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        </div><div type="item"><head> Suez Canal. —</head><p> 22 vessels pasted through the Canal on the 10th and 11th
                            inst Of these 14 were British, 2 Italian, 1 German, 1 Austrian, 1
                            Spanish, 1 Norwegian, 1 Egyptian. The receipts for the two days were fra
                            557,336.41, makiog the total from ist inst fra 3,110,181.80.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Soiree Noire -Another entertainment of this description was given in the
                            NouveanWs Theatre, Cairo, on Tuesday evening. We have already expressed
                            oar opinion on snoh performances and therefore refrain from further
                            criticism, but we frost that the authorities sre taking note of tho
                            frequency with which thej are held, and that we shall soon have no
                            further need to protest. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> The Fire at Cairo.—</head><p>The amount of damage caused .by the big fire in the
                            Darb el Ahmar district of Cairo, of which we gave a full account in our
                            issue of the 13th inst, has been estimated at over £10,000, the printing
                            establishment in which the fire originated, suffering to the extent of
                            £9,000. Two women were badly burnt whilst attempting to save tome of the
                            oontents of one house, and the oondition of one of tfreae is
                            serious.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="section" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE. DATE OF LEAVING LONDON. </head>
                    <p>The Khedive is staying at Claridge's Hotel for a few days. Afterwards his
                        Highness will be the guest of Sir Ernest Cassel.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive is expected to arrive at Divonne-les-Bains on the 25th inst. His
                        Highness will undergo his usual "cure" there and will stay about six weeks
                        in Switzerland. From Divonne the Khedive will go to Paris and will take the
                        Orient Express thence to Vienna. Lowa Thurneysson Pasha, Equerry to the
                        Khedive, is leaving Alexandria to-morrow by tho Mewageries Maritimes S.S.
                        "Senegal" for Marseilles, en rente to join the Khedive at Divonne.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has bestowed the following gradei : Mnutamaiz: Ismail Soliman El
                        Maoossi Bey, notable of Macopse (Minieh). Sanjch : Elewah H ossein Bey,
                        notable of Abou Korka.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVE DECORATIONS.</head>
                    <p>Lieutenant-Colonel Albert Edward Wilfred, Count Gleicben, C.V.O., C.M.G.,
                        D.8.O., Extra Equerry to his Majesty, Military Attache a Berlin, has been
                        permitted to accept and wear the insignia of the Second Class of the
                        Medji-dieh.iconfuircd upon him by the Khedive, in recognition of valuable
                        services rendered by m to his Highness. </p>
                    <p>Major and Brevet Lieut.-CoL Lord E. H Cecil, D.S.O., Grenadier Guards, has
                        also been permitted to accept and wear the insignia of the Socond Class of
                        the Medjidieh, conferred upon him by the Khedive for his services with the
                        Egyptian Army. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PLAGUE.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday 's bulletin records a case at Alexandria and another at Damanhour.
                        The victim at Alexandria is a Greek grocer's sboy livihg Safer Pasha-street,
                        Goumrouk kism. He is under treatment at the Greek Hospital.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUARANTINE IN CYPRUS.</head>
                    <p>A telegram from Nicosia states that arrivals in Cyprus from Egypt are
                        submitted to a medical inspection and the disinfeetion of the s of deck
                        passengers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COTTON WORM.</head>
                    <p> Mr. Mat bell, Adviser to the Ministry of the Interior, is making's tour of
                        inspection in the Gharbieh province, where ho is viiiting the principal
                        districts in which the cotton-worm has appeared. lie will return to Cairo on
                        Friday. % . Mr. G. H. West has been appointed temporary sub-inspector for
                        cotton-worm duty in the Bebera province.</p>
                    <p>Our Minet el Kamh Correspondent says that the following are the places in the
                        Minet el Kamh Markaz in which the cotton worm has appeared daring the week
                        ending last Saturday: (1) The teftisb of Prince Ibrahim Helmy Pasha in
                        Bishot Amer ; (2) the tettish of Prinoe Mo-hamed Poy Ibrahim in Telbana ;
                        (3) Bauadf; (4) Okdeh ; (5) Karakra, and (6) Malamis. The villages of
                        Minet-el-Kamh Markaz in which the cotton worm has appeared now number
                        12.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WHITE SLAVE TRAFFIC.</head>
                    <p>The ramifications of this iniquitous traffic extend far and wide, as is
                        evidenced by the fact reported in our issue of last Saturday that a Japanese
                        girl had been rescued from the hands of those who would have wrought her
                        rain. This girl, an intelligent and apparently innocent young woman of 16,
                        is now at the Rudolph Home. There being no Japanese Consul in Alexandria,
                        the British Consn 1-Goneral, Mr. K B. Gould, I.S.U., has takon tho matter in
                        hand, and has oom municated with the British representative in Japan with a
                        view to the girl's restoration her own country. We understand that measures
                        have been taken by the recently appointed executive committee of the
                        repression society for the effective supervision of all incoming ships, and
                        it is to be hoped that by this means a stop will be put to a scandal which
                        has been prominently before the public of late.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="army">
                    <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                    <p>The following officers of the 2nd Royal Berkshire Regiment have been granted
                        leave of absence, on private affairs : Captain R. II. Collins, D.8.O.,
                        Lieut. L. Marten, Lieut. L. W. Bird, Lieut. C. W. Hemp, 2nd-Liout M. L. i la
                        tighter, and 2nd-Lieut A. G. M. Sharpe. The undermentioned officers and
                        N.C.O's. qualified at the examination of the 2S0th Tarty, at the School of
                        Musketry, Hythe, >n 30th May. (The numbers given represent the order of
                        merit) :—Lieut. J. G. Deveniah, 2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, (71),
                        lieut G. M. Jennings, 2nd Royal Inniskilling fusiliers, (62), Lient. R. H.
                        Waithman, 2nd Royal Sussex Regt, (56), Lieut C. F. de S. Murphy, 2nd R iyal
                        Berks. Regt, (28), Sorgt. J. Solomon, 2nd Royal Sussex Regt, (29). Nombers
                        examined-Officers 74, N.C.O's. 124. (The above does not inolude the
                        qualification to nstruct in the Maxim gun.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellermann S. 8. "Bulgarian" sailed from Malta last night and is doe here
                        on Sunday morning, with passengers and general cargo. The Meesageriee
                        Maritimes S.S. "Equateur" arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria yesterday
                        morning.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>"ABBASSIEH DESERT OASIS." MORE DETAILS.</head>
                    <p>Onj of the moet suspicions and inoompre hensible items in the Government's
                        agreement with Boghos Pasha Nubar and.M- Empain in regard to the "Abbassieh
                        Desert Oasis" iJ that the Government does not stipnlato for any share in the
                        profits, as has been invariably the case hitherto. In the esse of other
                        concessions the Government insists on a share in the profits, often oven a
                        half share. Another point is that these two gentlemen have obtained a
                        concession for 70 years, while in the casos of English oompanies'
                        oonoessions (such, for example, as the Egyptian Markets, the Helouan Railway
                        Company, and others), the concession is for a much more limited period, less
                        than half of the time given to the Abbassieh Oasis concessionaires.</p>
                    <p>A Cairo correspondent writes :—"The above remarkable transaction is causing
                        more than an uproar in Cairo, in view especially of the fret that only a few
                        months back an official notice issued by the Government stated emphatically
                        that no big areas of land would be disposed of in future. Directly opposed
                        to this, however, fifteen thousand feddans, i.e., sixty-threi million square
                        metres of land, eminently snitable for building purposes, in the immediate
                        vicinity to the north-west of the largest oity in Africa, is sold for L.K
                        15,000—ajbig deal and certainly the finest bargain from thepurohasers' point
                        of view ever reoorded here. The concession for quick elec trio communication
                        with the city granted at the same time to the two private buyers, a native
                        Pasha and a Belgian gentleman connected with the Cairo trams, will bring
                        this projected suburb within twenty minutes of Opera-square. For years it
                        has been known that the gentlemen at the head of the Cairo trams could get
                        anything from tho Government for the mere trouble of asking, bat the present
                        transaction really beats anything on record. </p>
                    <p>"It will be plain to everyone that the principal losers are first and
                        foremost the Egyptian Government, who could have asked and obtained with
                        ease a sum of at least one million sterling for the land in question. The
                        second to lose by the transaction is very obviously the Delta Light Railway,
                        who have just taken over at a heavy cost the Helouan line in spite of the
                        opposition of the Cairo trams. One can read between the lines, however, and
                        sec that the latter have now attained something towards taking from the
                        English oompany the laurels so dearly bought by it, which are now ' v this
                        strategical move as good as gone Iready, the new auborb of conree replacing
                        Helonan. The other factors affected by this deal, and by frr the most
                        interesting, will soon find their positi n anything but a pleasant</p>
                    <p>"It is not probable that land on the Nile, as has been hinted, will be mnch
                        depreciated in value—the oity is bound to extend over the river, and if land
                        is now worth L.E. 30 a metre near the Credit Lyonnais, L.K 45 a metre on the
                        Opera square, L.R 20 near the National Bank, and L.R 5 or 6 a metre near
                        Kaar-el-Nil, there is still ample room for profitable investment at
                        Gbezireh, Ghizeb, Embabeb, and Bonlac-Dacroar, especially as the Abbas
                        bridge will very soon span the river. But what opinion are we to form of the
                        British trustee-of Egyptian lands t They have not even the lame excuse of
                        having blundered in favor of British investors!</p>
                    <p>Another Cairo correspondent writes:—"With referonoe to th'q leading article
                        in yonr issue of the 12th inst, regarding the. "Abbassieh Desert^' your
                        surmise is perfectly correct, aud I may tell you that I am in a position to
                        state that the fall in the price of land at Abbassieh is solely due to this
                        enormous sale of Government land to a very few people, and at a ridiculous
                        figure. It may bo of interest to your readers * know that several large and
                        bond fide deals ... land at Abbassieh have recently fallen through purely on
                        the grounds that the large sales were whispered tonnd, and if some persons
                        can purchase a few feddans at £1 a feddan, what is the good of paying a mnch
                        greater ■ price per metre t Far better to wait until these speculators have
                        brought the value of ground down to the lowest point But in the meanwhile
                        what are the bond fide land-owners going to do t Calmly sit still and make
                        no effort with the Government to urge them to be just and true in all their
                        dealings, or let the few favored ones bring them to ruin !"</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWEDISH-NORWEGIAN CRISIS.</head>
                    <p>Mr. BSrker, the Swedish and Norwegian Consnl at Alexandria, has been
                        officially informed that the consulate here is to pursue its funotioDB as
                        heretofore and to oomplotely ignore the Norwegians' "revolutionary
                        decisions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MARIOUT LANDS.</head>
                    <p>The following official note has been issued by the Press Bureau :— II resolte
                        dea decisions judioiaires inter-ennea quo des cultures d'orge anx eaox de la
                        plnie, sur les terrains du Mariout, n'ont qu'nn caractere prtcaire et
                        discontenu et no sanraient Hre oonsiddtoea oomme constituent des actes de
                        possession legale ponvant conduire leurs auteurs a l'aoquisi-tion de la
                        propridtd, on memo lenr donner droit d'6tre reiuttSgrds ou maintonus dans la
                        possession d'immenbles dont ils ont 5td ex-pnls4a par 1'Etat
                        propridtairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>"BUILDING LANDS OF EGYPT."</head>
                    <p>An Egyptian company, called the Bnilding Lands ot Egypt, has been formed,
                        with a capital of £150,000, divided into 87,500 shares of £1 each, which
                        have been fully subscribed by the promoters, as follows :—Jean Coury. 1,000
                        ; Pdriclds Glymenoponlo, 1,000 : Cost* Pilavachi, 1,000; Engine Mieli, 100 ;
                        Richard C. Abdy, 900 ; Thdodore Karnra, 1,000 ; Kian Investment Agency, Ld.,
                        32,000. There are to be. besides, 2,000 Founders' shares, which will be
                        distributed among them aooording to agreement The obiaotsof the company are
                        sufficiently indioated by its i and noed no explanation. </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head> PERSONAL AND SOCIAL: </head>
                    <p> It is stated that Prince Mohamed Aly, who is in Paris, intends to charter a
                        yacht and make a cruise to the Norwegian Fiords. </p>
                    <p> The Regent, Mustapha Pasha Pebmy, Abani Pasha, Minister of War, and Ermolli
                        Boy, private secretary to the Regent, arrived at San Stefano yesterday from
                        Cairo. </p>
                    <p> Mazloum Pasha, Minister of Finance, is expected at San Stefano to day. </p>
                    <p> Lord Cromer's elder son, Lord Brrington, will meet his father on the
                        latter's arrival in England. He arrived in London from St. Petersburg a few
                        days ago. </p>
                    <p> Sir Horace Pinching, Director-General of the Sanitary Department, returned
                        to Cairo on Tuesday evening from the Gharbieb province, where he has been
                        paying visits of inspection to various localities. </p>
                    <p> Owing to the state of his health, the Grand Mufti did not embark for Europe
                        yesterday, as he had intended. He now intends staying at Alexandria for a
                        week or two. </p>
                    <p> The portrait of Professor Flinders Petrie by the late Mr. Watts has been
                        bequeathed by that painter to the British pation. </p>
                    <p> The "Morning Post" announces that Mrs. Neville Borton has arrived at
                        Moorlands, Ascot, from Egypt. </p>
                    <p> Three and a half months' leave of absence has been granted to Mr. E. Martin,
                        director of stores, Ministry of the Interior, from the 19th inst. </p>
                    <p> Mr. W. Snow, who has so ably filled the post of local manager in Cairo to
                        Messrs. Thos, Cook &amp; Son (Egypt), Limited, for many years, is leaving
                        this country in the middle of next month to join the head office in
                        Ludgate-hill, London, and, as already-announced in these columns some time
                        back, will be replaced by Mr. Ashton, who came out to the Cairo office last
                        October. </p>
                    <p> Dr. Abraham G. Nachety has been authorised to practise as a physician in
                        Egypt. </p>
                    <p> The staff of the Imperial Ottoman Bank in Cairo will give a banquet ou
                        Saturday ovening to Mr. A. W. Goldenberg, head of the bill department, who
                        is retiring from the bank after eight years' service, and is leaving for
                        Europe previous to establishing himself in business in the Metropolis. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot <name>"Ismailia"</name> de la Cie Khedivial partis hier
                        aprta-midi pour le PinSe, <placeName>Smyrna</placeName>,
                            <placeName>Mdtelin</placeName>, <placeName>Dardanelles et
                            Constantinople</placeName>, avait a bord -.</p>
                    <p><persName>M. et Mme R A. Benachi</persName>, <persName>L A
                        Benachi</persName>, <persName>S. Corpi</persName>, <persName>M. A. Varouxie,
                            et famille</persName>, <persName>Mlles Poly-meres</persName>,
                            <persName>S. R Hussein Oassif pacha et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Rev. bt Mme A Sobneller</persName>, <persName>S.R Aly bey
                            Pehmy et famille</persName>, <persName>S.R Halil pacha
                        Hamada</persName>, <persName>Maitie Litzikas</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme
                            Constantin Constantinidis, et famille</persName>, <persName>Mlle Olga
                            Constantinidis</persName>, <persName>S.R Saleh bay Kamel</persName>,
                            <persName>Wm. Whitfield</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme A. Fonioopoulo
                            et femille</persName>, <persName>Mines Mercurian</persName>,
                            <persName>Mlles Manossoe</persName>
                        <persName>S.E. Hussein bey Husni</persName>, <persName>M. etMme C.
                            Emmanuel</persName>, <persName>M. Emmanuel</persName>, <persName>M. et
                            Mme Ca-bacakis, et famille</persName>, <persName>Mlle Marie
                            Gennadis</persName>, <persName>Antoine Comanos</persName>, <persName>M.
                            et Mme N. E. Grenet</persName>, <persName>Frederio Barker</persName>,
                            <persName>F.S. Holton</persName>, <persName>S. Pengelly</persName>,
                            <persName>Mme Voilas et famille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme Geo.
                            Pappa et famille</persName>, <persName>Mme R Badaros</persName>,
                            <persName>Mme et Mlle Angelos</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme D.
                            Cortesi</persName>, <persName>S. R Selim bey Rifrat</persName>,
                            <persName>M. et Mme F. W. Coming et famille</persName>, <persName>Pierre
                            P- Antonios</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme A. Aroondaris et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme U. Ricoi et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Mlle R Allen</persName>, <persName>S. R Mnstapha bey
                            Hussein</persName>, <persName>B. R Halil bey Hamdyet famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Hassan bey Damir</persName>, <persName>Abbas Damir</persName>,
                            <persName>Dick Vedova</persName>, <persName>F. Cazzicapidis</persName>,
                            <persName>D. Donras</persName>, <persName>Costia Maoris</persName>,
                            <persName>Osman Liutfi</persName>,Basile G. Stamatiadis,
                            <persName>Miltiades Comanos</persName>, <persName>Mme.
                            Workmeister</persName>, <persName>S. E. Moharrem bey</persName>,
                            <persName>Dr. N. Percival</persName>, <persName>C. S.
                            Demetracopoalo</persName>, <persName>Geo. Arghiris</persName>,
                            <persName>Arnado Pancera</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme Elie Cattaui et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>A.Dedeyan</persName>, <persName>Mme
                            Smith</persName>, <persName>Andrew Brown</persName>, <persName>Rev.
                            Archoveqoe Dioodinos</persName>, <persName>Geo. Geronssis</persName>,
                            <persName>S.E. Ahmed bey BrfrD</persName>, <persName>Ismail effendi
                            Fikhry</persName>, <persName>N. Tsounis</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme
                            Dimitri Galato?</persName>, <persName>W.S. Arghiris</persName>,
                            <persName>M. et Mme S. Alfieris et famille</persName>, <persName>Mlle
                            Lonvanis</persName>, <persName>S.R Mohamed bey Mabzar et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme Panayotti A. Rombotti et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>Archimandrite Cleopas</persName>,
                            <persName>Christo Ater-zis</persName>, <persName>Nasry
                            Aboussan</persName>, <persName>Jules Albina</persName>, <persName>M.
                            Yihva N. Roobioof)</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme Lewis Berger et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme El Said Mahmoud</persName>,
                            <persName>S. Alivitato</persName>, <persName>G. Iivierato</persName>,
                            <persName>Mohamed 8idki</persName>, <persName>Edward J.
                            Taylor</persName>, <persName>Ibrahim Zelri</persName>, <persName>Mme S.
                            Ventura et famille Soeur Marie</persName>, <persName>Rasdil, et Geloua
                            Hanem</persName>, <persName>Mme Catherine Pizzaohi</persName>,
                            <persName>Mme S. Stamps?</persName>, <persName>Mlle Sophie
                            Koffmar</persName>, <persName>Mines G. Pappadimas</persName>,
                            <persName>Ufezzopoulo et fils</persName>, <persName>N.
                            Rakagoilled</persName>, <persName>Adolf Braggiotti</persName> et 239
                        pas-sagers depont Anglo-American Nile Steamer, Sc HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIYIAL YACHT CLUB. REGATTA.</head>
                        <p>The following is the result of yesterday's regatta: <table rows="8"
                                cols="5">
                                <head/>
                                <row role="label">
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Boat </cell>
                                    <cell>8tart. </cell>
                                    <cell>Finish. </cell>
                                    <cell>Sailed by</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>1</cell>
                                    <cell>Sana-Pareille- </cell>
                                    <cell>3.47.19</cell>
                                    <cell>5.31.58</cell>
                                    <cell>R. L Delaqnis</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>2</cell>
                                    <cell> Leman </cell>
                                    <cell>3.42.22</cell>
                                    <cell> 5.39 16 </cell>
                                    <cell>Mr. de Planta</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>3</cell>
                                    <cell> Banshee </cell>
                                    <cell>3.46.09 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.42.24</cell>
                                    <cell>T. McClure</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Jenny ></cell>
                                    <cell>3.83.13 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.46.54</cell>
                                    <cell>8. Dorling</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Celtic </cell>
                                    <cell>3.35.16 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.53.30 </cell>
                                    <cell>Capt Evans</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Tier el Mina </cell>
                                    <cell>3.36.16 </cell>
                                    <cell>6.65.40 </cell>
                                    <cell>„ Borg</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Minnie </cell>
                                    <cell>3.30.15</cell>
                                    <cell>5.56.54 </cell>
                                    <cell>N.W.deCourcy</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Coot </cell>
                                    <cell>3.35.15 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.67.17</cell>
                                    <cell>Mr. Blagden</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Agamy </cell>
                                    <cell>3.48.85 </cell>
                                    <cell>gave up</cell>
                                    <cell>„ Ravelli </cell>
                                </row>
                            </table></p>
                        <p>The Agamy was disqualified for foaling the mark buoy.</p>
                        <p>
                            <table rows="7" cols="5">
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>St George </cell>
                                    <cell>4.04.10</cell>
                                    <cell>5.44.00 </cell>
                                    <cell>MgjorFeetham</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>1</cell>
                                    <cell> Calypso </cell>
                                    <cell>4.10.25</cell>
                                    <cell>5.45.65 </cell>
                                    <cell>0. Warner </cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>2</cell>
                                    <cell>Shamrock </cell>
                                    <cell>3.59.25 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.48.03 </cell>
                                    <cell>Lieut Bassett </cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell>3</cell>
                                    <cell>Masr </cell>
                                    <cell>4.02.54</cell>
                                    <cell>5.48.30</cell>
                                    <cell>A. Grafton</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Gomrook</cell>
                                    <cell> 4.04.28</cell>
                                    <cell> 5.48.45 </cell>
                                    <cell>Mr. Macaulay</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Tantah </cell>
                                    <cell>3.59.58 </cell>
                                    <cell>5.49.40</cell>
                                    <cell>J. Bally </cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Cattelaya </cell>
                                    <cell> 3 55.28</cell>
                                    <cell>5.50.39</cell>
                                    <cell>D. K. Reid</cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Jessica </cell>
                                    <cell>3.50.25</cell>
                                    <cell>5.53.32</cell>
                                    <cell> Grafton Bey </cell>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <cell/>
                                    <cell>Akraba </cell>
                                    <cell>3.56.40</cell>
                                    <cell>5.54.55</cell>
                                    <cell>8agh. Phillips </cell>
                                </row>
                            </table>
                        </p>
                        <p>The wind was light from the N. and N.N.R, it not being at all steady bnt
                            veering abont daring the afternoon. The SaiuhPareille, in Class I., of
                            course came in a long way ahvt again, as she is sore to do on this
                            handicap if well handled. In Class II. a very good race was again
                            witnessed all the way round, the first seven boats crossing the line
                            within 6$ minutes. Unfortunately, the St. George was disqualified in
                            accordance with Racing Rule 6, through having mode an alteration in her
                            sails and not having been remeasured for the same. POLO.</p>
                        <p>Owing to the raoes this afternoon polo will be played to-morrow afternoon
                            at 4.30, on the A.8.C. grounds. A. 8. C. Dr. Abraham G. Nachety has bean
                            authorised to practise as a physician in Egypt. The staff of the
                            Imperial Ottoman Bank in Cairo will give a banquet on Satnrday evening
                            to Mr. A. W. Goldenberg, head of the bill department, who is retiring
                            from the bank after eight years' service, and is leaving for Europe
                            previons to establishing himself ip business in the Metropolis. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAWN TBNNIS HANDICAP TOURNAMENT.</head>
                        <p>Mixed doubles to be played off before 21»t inst :—Mr. Harvey and Capt
                            Moore 415 play Miss R Allen and Capt. Harvey +Hk Miss H. Pitner and R.
                            Basset —} 15 pfry H. B. Carver and Miss G. Carver —} 30. Gentlemen's
                            8ingles. 1st and 2nd round to be played off before 22nd inst Millar
                            scratch bye Blythman —f 15 bye Chevalier —J 15 bye Percival—15 bye H. B.
                            Carver—15 bye Major Gamble—15 bye Gnarino—i 30 plays Byrne—J 15 C.
                            Birch+15 plays Alderson-f-15 N. Haselden — $15 bye Finney —15 bye Morne
                            scratch bye Tamvaoo +$15 bye Capt Harvey+$30 bye M. Fenderl —$ 15 bye
                            Wyart +$ 15 bye. Gentlemen's Doubles. Major Gamble and Percival —$30
                            bye, Basset and Capt Moore scratch bye, Guarino and Bally — $ 80 bye
                            Fenderl and Salome scratch play HaaalHa,, and Foster—$15 Tamvaoo and
                            Salome scratch bye Wyart and Crawley +15 bye Aldereon and Birch +15 bye
                            Carver and Finney —$ 30 bye. 1st and 2nd rounds to be played off before
                            22nd inst</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="cottonMarket">
                    <head>THE COTTON MARKET</head>
                    <p>Kearsley and Cunnikoham's Weekly Report. Liverpool, June 8. In Egyptian
                        Cotton only a moderate business has been done, and quotations are generally
                        reduced ^ d. @ £ d. per lb.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Futures bare been idle all the week and prioes show a decline of 18
                        points for Jane and 15 points fur other positions. The following are the
                        latest quotations, vis:— Jane 6.40 Aug. 6.42 Oot 6.37 July 6.44 8ep. 6.89
                        Nov. 6.34 Deo. 6.30</p>
                    <p>American Futures.—The market this week has been decidedly lees active and
                        prioes have experienced a sharp decline, amounting to 15 @17 points from
                        those of last Thursday. Near months have been pressed for sale and show tho
                        largest deoline. The sharp fall in prioes is chiefly due to improved weather
                        reports and to the Bureau report being better than expected, both as regards
                        the decrease in hcreage and also in the estimated condition of the crop.
                        Should the weather remain favorable throughout the month of June, we should
                        expect the Crop to recover much of its present lateness and also to make
                        good muoh of the reoent unfavorable condition. The price of 4id. per lb.,
                        seems for the moment to faifly represent/the situation, and the only (pinion
                        we can form, in a market which is so dependent upon daily Crop reports, is
                        that we are not likefcjo have any important movement in .prices but may
                        expect frequent fluctuations. The latest quotations are Delivery.— June 4.48
                        Sep./Oot 4.48 Jan./Peb. 4.50 June/July 4.48 Oct/Nov. 4.48 Feb^Mar. 4.51
                        July/Aug. 4.48 Nov./Deo. 4.48 Mar./ApL 4.59 Aug./Sep. 4.48 Dea/Jan. 4.49
                        Apr./May 4.58</p>
                </div>
                <!-- adverts -->
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/page/n3/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/page/n4/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-06-15/page/n5/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
          <head> EXPORT MANIFESTS. </head>
          <p>Pour BRINDISI et TRIESTE, par le bateau autr. "Buterpe", parti le 7 join
            :</p>
          <p>Divers, 964 sacs oignons, 86 colis divers</p>
          <p>Pour PORT-SAID, par le bateau ital. Nilo". parti le 7 juin :</p>
          <p>Divers, 31 colis divers</p>
          <p>Pour PORT SAID et SYRIE, par le bateau frang. "Sénégal", parti le 8 juin
            :</p>
          <p>Divers, 7 colis divers</p>
          <p>POUR YOKOHAMA</p>
          <p>H. Bindernagel, 300 balles coton</p>
          <p>Pour MARSEILLE, par le bateau français "Bquateur", parti le 9 juin :</p>
          <p>POUR MARSEILLE</p>
          <p>Sucreries et Raff., 188 cais. sucre raffiné, 1 lot appareils usagés</p>
          <p>Delaygive fils, 55 balles gomme</p>
          <p>B. Tilche figli, 145 sacs spath flour</p>
          <p>Sté Huileries, 12 barils huile</p>
          <p>B. Stross, 50 cais. mobilier,</p>
          <p>Vasdeki fr., 55 cais. aulx, 100 sacs oignons</p>
          <p>Griva fr., 160 sacs gomme</p>
          <p>L. Dollinger, 211 balles papier</p>
          <p>Divers, 60 colis divers</p>
          <p>Peel &amp; Co., 32 balles coton</p>
          <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 50 „ „</p>
          <p>Schmid &amp; Co., 93 „ „</p>
          <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 171 „ „</p>
          <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 62 „ „</p>
          <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Luul, 30 „ „</p>
          <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 30 „ „</p>
          <p>468 balles coton</p>
          <p>POUR LE HAVRE</p>
          <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 65 balles coton</p>
          <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 50 „ „</p>
          <p>115 balles coton</p>
          <p>Griva fr., 80 balles gomme</p>
          <p>A. Tedeschi, 4 cais. plumes</p>
          <p>POUR DUNKERQUE</p>
          <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 80 balles coton</p>
          <p>POUR BORDEAUX</p>
          <p>Griva fr., 60 balles gomme</p>
          <p>POUR LONDRES</p>
          <p>C. G. Bolonachi, 70 barils cognac</p>
          <p>POUR CETTE</p>
          <p>P. Trou, 9 futs vides</p>
          <p>Pour BARCELONE et MARSEILLE, par le bateau tranç, "Foria", parti le 9 juin
            :</p>
          <p>POUR BARCELONE</p>
          <p>Peel &amp; Co., 100 balles coton</p>
          <p>Birch &amp; Co., 100 „ „</p>
          <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 75 „ „</p>
          <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 100 „ „</p>
          <p>J. Planta &amp; Co., 95 „ „</p>
          <p>Cboremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 140 „ „</p>
          <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 140 „ „</p>
          <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 80 „ „</p>
          <p>E. Mallison &amp; Co, 70 „ „</p>
          <p>Moursi Brod, 168 „ „</p>
          <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 180 „ „</p>
          <p>B. Barki, 162 „ „</p>
          <p>A. Hess &amp; Co., 30 „ „</p>
          <p>1,440 balles coton</p>
          <p>M. L Carasso, 69 fardes gomme</p>
          <p>POUR MARSEILLE</p>
          <p>Behrend &amp; Co., 201 tonnes feves en vrac</p>
          <p>G. &amp; A. Geargapura, 20 ballots sacs vides</p>
          <p>A. Sirven, 15 futs vides en fer</p>
          <p>C. D. Moulet &amp; Cie., 159 ballots sacs vides</p>
          <p>A. Arbib e figli, 25. belles peaux</p>
          <p>Divers, 2 colis divers</p>
        </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
