<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-06">December 6, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-06">September 6, 2016</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7286] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 6, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES
                    P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, September 6, 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Peace Terms. CHINA AND MANCHURIA. DELAY IN SIGNING TREATY.</head>
                    <p>Portsmouth (N.H.), September 5.</p>
                    <p>An insignificant delay in the final drafting of the treaty prevented it from
                        being signed yesterday. It will be signed this afternoon.</p>
                    <p>A synopsis of the treaty has been published. There are fifteen articles of
                        which the gist is known. Each nation undertakes to employ its section of the
                        Manchurian Railway solely for commercial and industrial purposes and to
                        establish a junction at Quang Cheng, each will evacuate Manchria within 18
                        months, afterwards retaining 15 railway guards per kilometre, and each
                        engages to place no obstacles in the way of China for the development of
                        Manchuria. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Portsmouth (U.S.A.), September 6.</p>
                    <p>The peace treaty has been signed. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIA'S INTERNAL TROUBLES. COSSACKS CHARGE THE CROWD.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 5.</p>
                    <p>On the occasion of the departure of the reservists from Libau, the Cossacks
                        charged the hostile crowd and fired upon the houses in tho vicinity. There
                        are sixty killed and wonnd-ed and one hundred and fifty arrests have been
                        made. </p>
                    <p>The troops charged a Jewish funeral at Kishineff. There are many killed and
                        wounded.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 5.</p>
                    <p>Disorders continue in the interior. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. ROSEN TO GO TO PARIS.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 5.</p>
                    <p>Baron Rosen, the new German Minister to Morocco, is about to come here to
                        discuss with the French Government certain questions on which an undertaking
                        is necessary before the conference can meet. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MACEDONIAN ACTIVITY. REDIF BATTALIONS CALLED OUT.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, September 5.</p>
                    <p>The Porte is calling out a number of Redif battalions to strengthen the
                        troops in Macedonia. owing to a recrudescence of activity among the bands.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIGHTING AT BAKU. REINFORCEMENTS PROM TIFLIS.</head>
                    <p>Baku, September 5.</p>
                    <p>The fighting here continues, re-inforcements are being sent from Tifiia The
                        disturbance appears to be racial and religions, but reports are very
                        obscure. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Baku, September 6.</p>
                    <p>The Tartars and Armenians have been fighting since Saturday. Until now there
                        are 100 killed and wounded. The troops are engaged. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHOLERA EPIDEMIC. PRECAUTIONS IN ENGLAND.</head>
                    <p>Brest, September 5.</p>
                    <p>A case of cholera is reported here. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>London, September 5.</p>
                    <p>The Local Government Board has sent the Port Authorities a circular informing
                        them of the precautions to be taken against ships arriving from the porta of
                        the Baltic and North Seas infected with cholera. (Radar)</p>
                    <p>Paris, September 5.</p>
                    <p>The hygienic commissions declare that there is nothing to be feared from the
                        contagion of the cholera. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SHAH IN RUSSIA.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 5. The Shah is the object of much attention. It is
                        rumoured that he hopes to obtain a loan of £250,000. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUICIDE.</head>
                    <p>London, September 5.</p>
                    <p>Colonel Frederick Wardrop has committed suicide on account of monetary
                        troubles. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Brindisi Mail</head>
                        <p>arrived at Port Said at six o’clock this morning and will be distributed
                            at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 9.80 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suicide</head>
                        <p>M. Eustace Dahna, who was formerly cashier of the Alexandria branch of
                            the Imperial Ottoman Bank, committed suicide yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fall from a Scaffold</head>
                        <p>A native workman, named Mohamed Haikal, fell from a scaffold in the Rue
                            d’Allemagne yesterday. His injuries were serious, and he was immediately
                            sent to hospital</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Shoubra Bridge</head>
                        <p>It is reported that the Ministry of Public Works has decided to enlarge
                            the north end of the Shoubra bridge, so as to give the whole structure a
                            uniform width of fourteen metres.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>33 vessels passed through the Canal during the first three days of
                            September. 17 of these were British, 3 German, 9 French, 2 Austrian, 1
                            Italian, 1 Spanish. The amount received in dues was 718,168.07.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Cotton-Worm</head>
                        <p>During the week end ing last Saturday there were ten feddans of land in
                            the Behera moudirieh infected by the cotton-worm. These were cleared by
                            180 children, and the country is now pronounced free from the worm.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plaque</head>
                        <p>Yesterday's plague bulletin reports the admission to hospital of a Greek
                            boy from a grocery in the Menshieh quarter, and a native woman, who has
                            been isolated since the 31st. ult., owing to two members of her family
                            having been found dead on that date.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Quarry Accident</head>
                        <p>A workman employed in one of the quarrier on the Mokattam Hills above the
                            citadel was killed on Monday morning, while carrying a load. He appears
                            to have slipped or become suddenly giddy, with the result that he fell
                            over a cliff some eighty feet in height, and was killed on the spot.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Postal Van Accident</head>
                        <p>As a postal van was proceeding along Attarin Street, Alexandria,
                            yesterday, one of the wheels was wrenched off by violent contact with
                            the tramway line. The traffic was greatly impeded until the parcels had
                            been transferred to another van, and the damaged one could be got out of
                            the way.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Strange Story</head>
                        <p>A native of Damanhour was condemned to death to-day by the Assize Court
                            for the murder of his wife, Questioned by the judge he stated that at
                            the time of the murder be was dangerously ill, and fearing that his
                            wife, for whom he had a passionate and jealous affection, would marry
                            another after his death, he resolved to kill her himself.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“La Revue Internationale”</head>
                        <p>The September number of this review contains some excellent articles,
                            among them M. Iesieur’s interesting, if biassed, “1882, Souvenirs d'un
                            Port-Saldien." M. Henry Davray contributes an article on English monthly
                            and weekly periodicals of the day, and Mr. Pachundaki’s contribution on
                            "pre-historic man in Egypt” also deserves mention.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>A grand orchestral and vocal concert will be given on Saturday night on
                            the occasion of the night fete at San Stefano Casino. The vocal part of
                            the programme will include the execution of the whole of the third act
                            of Puccini's La Bohema. After the concert there will be a display of
                            fireworks and this will be followed by a small dance The whole programme
                            provides for an exceedingly enjoyable evening, and the fete should be
                            well attended.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A band of thieves</head>
                        <p>The El Rouei thieves recently arrested after one of their number bad shot
                            a secret policeman, prove to be the authors of the burglary committed on
                            the 10th ult. at the house of M. Chassesud in the Ismailieh quarter,
                            when £150 worth of jewels were carried off. The accused are at present
                            in the citadel prison, and the Italian Consular court will soon decide
                            whether they are to be tried at Cairo or must appear before the Ancona
                            Assize Court.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES AFFAIR. GENERAL MEETING DECIDED.</head>
                    <p>(From our London Correspondent.)</p>
                    <p>(By Telegraph.)</p>
                    <p>London, Tuesday, 3.15 p.m.</p>
                    <p>The managers of the Suereries et de la Raf-finerie d'Egypte continued their
                        adjourned meeting at Paris to day in consultation with Sir Ernest Cassel and
                        Maltre Carton de Wiart It was decided to convene a meeting of shareholders
                        for the earliest possible date in view of the urgency of the matter. The
                        secretary of the company started for Egypt to-day, and immediately on his
                        arrival he will make preparations for a concordat according to Egyptian law,
                        as such a course will be more profitable to the shareholders than winding up
                        under the French law.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOTOR ACCIDENT IN PARIS. COUNT ZOGHEB INJURED.</head>
                    <p>(From our London Correspondent.) </p>
                    <p>(By Telegraph.)</p>
                    <p>London, Tuesday, 11.15 am.</p>
                    <p>I have just learnt that while Count Antoine de Zogheb, Diplomatic Agent and
                        Consul General for Denmark at Cairo, was driving his motor-car in the Bois
                        de Boulogne, Paris, the car collided with a cab. The Count and five other
                        occupants of the car were thrown out, and all received more or less severe
                        injuries. We trust that Count Zogheb and his companions will speedily rearm
                        from the effects of the accident</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW NILE BRIDGES.</head>
                    <p>Through the kindness of Mr. Bakewell, the engineer in charge of the
                        construction of the new bridges at Rodah Island we have learnt some
                        interesting details concerning them. Mr. Bakewell has already been connected
                        with several other important undertakings in this country, having first come
                        out to Egypt in 1871, his last service being on the Assouan Reservoir, where
                        he was engaged for five years. This gentleman is supervising the
                        construction of the bridges on behalf of Sir William Arrol &amp; Co., the
                        contractors, and is assisted by Mr. Burnside, whilst Mr. Knowles acts on
                        behalf of the Government. There an also several English foremen employed by
                        the contractors.</p>
                    <p>The work is progressing very satisfactorily and it is fully expected that the
                        new bridges will be completed by 1st June, 1907, the date fixed by the
                        contract, as by the agreement entered into in June of last year between the
                        Govern-ment and the above firm it was stipulated that they were to be handed
                        over for traffic within 80 months, counting from the 1st December 1904, when
                        the approaches and other preparatory works are to be finished by the Cairo
                        Tanrim service. In the meanwhile we may remark, that the. land in the
                        vicinity of the bridges at Old Cairo has gone up in price 50 per cent.
                        within the past six months or so, and on the Island of Rodah it has doubled
                        twice over. The original contract price was £191,813, but this figure was
                        subsequently reduced by Sir William Arrol &amp; Co. by £8,850, bringing down
                        the price to £182,963. This reduction was agreed to in consideration of an
                        alteration in the mode of payment by the Ministry of Public Works to the
                        contractors, viz : in monthly instalments representing 90 per cent of the
                        work done. But by a special clause introduced into the original agreement an
                        additional sum of £3,000 may be added to the reduced cost of the bridges,
                        for the lowering of the levels of the bottom of the Ghizeh and Rodah
                        abutments.</p>
                    <p>The principal work in hand at present is the sinking of the cylinders, the
                        preparation of the girders for the main bridge across the Nile proper ; and
                        the sinking of the cylinders for the second bridge which is to connect Old
                        Cairo with the island. Mr. Thomas, of Kafr el Zayat, is doing part of the
                        cylinder sinking.</p>
                    <p>The larger bridge from Rodah to Ghiseh will be 535 metres long between the
                        abutments and 90 metres wide. Two new roads on the island have been made by
                        the Delta Light Railway Company, who brought the necessary earth and stones
                        from a hill near by.</p>
                    <p>The two permanent bridges alluded to and the road across the island that
                        connects them will form a straight drive of over a kilometre in length.
                        There will be in time a double tramway line laid on the bridge, connecting
                        the Old Cairo line with the Pyramids line, at a point nearly opposite the
                        Zoological Gardena For this purpose, and in order to relieve the traffic on
                        this new highway, a third bridge, 67 metres long, will be thrown across the
                        branch of the Nile about a mile further away, and will be connected with the
                        road across the island by another fine road 95 metres in width which is
                        already completed. At the main bridge is to be at one of the many pictures
                        que parts of the river it is intended to make the structure harmonise as for
                        at possible with the beauty of the landscape. The drive across the whole
                        length from Old Cairo to Ghizeh will become, no doubt, the most frequented
                        in Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. Syrian Prince left Malta yesterday with passengers and general
                        cargo, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Saturday.</p>
                    <p>The Kbedivial mail steamship Assouan will leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on
                        Sunday next and Port Said at 4 p m. on Monday for Bey-rout, Tripoli,
                        Mersina, Alexandrette, Larnaca, limassol, Caiffa, and Jaffa,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GANG ROBBERY AT SALWA. A SHAWISH KILLED.</head>
                    <p>(From our Edfou Correspondent.)</p>
                    <p>Edfou, Sunday.</p>
                    <p>On August 29. three robbers, all men of El Akaba village, surprised a fellah,
                        who was driving his seven camels to Luxor for sale, near Salwa. They told
                        him to give them all the money he carried and on his refusal, set upon him
                        and beat him with nabouts, stole a camel, his clothes, and the sum of thirty
                        three pounds, and made oft. One of the gang carried a gun which he
                        discharged at the moment of the robbery but the shot fortunately missed
                        its</p>
                    <p>The condition of the victim of this outrage gives rise to grave anxiety. He
                        has been most cruelly beaten and his right leg and left arm are broken by
                        the force of the blows.</p>
                    <p>The Omdeh of Salwa Bahari village, Dear which the crime was committed,
                        informed the marks z, and the police moawen of the markaz with a doctor,
                        after visiting the scene and seeing the wounded man, sent some Ababdeh
                        Bedouin to follow the trail left by the gang. The Ababdehs returned with the
                        news that they had come up with the robbers who fired on them and got safely
                        away on their camels.</p>
                    <p>On August 31 the moawen, having collected a force of seven policemen, with
                        some ghaffirs and Ababdeh, went into the desert, and after four hours march
                        found the gang in a cave near the top of Jebel Esh-Shaaghebeh. A drop-ping
                        fire was exchanged till 9 p.m. when shawish Ahmed Kenawi, who had climbed a
                        height to reconnoitre, was shot dead. There upon the moawen and his men drew
                        off the recovered camel and stolen clothes with them, and the robbers fled
                        in the night He po-lice commandant of the moudirieh then went in search of
                        the gang with four policemen, and after a day and a night found one of the
                        robbers and the wife of another of their number together in the cave. Both
                        confessed and gave the names of their accomplices, one of whom has since
                        been captured while the police are on the track of the other.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIRE AT BENHA.</head>
                    <p>( From a Correspondent. )</p>
                    <p>Benha, Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>A destructive fire, involving the total loss of the general stores of
                        Hassan-el-Harras Freres, the local agents of Messrs. Worms &amp; Co., of
                        Port Said, and which at times appeared in great danger of spreading further,
                        started here some time after midnight, and burnt oat towards daybreak. The
                        alum was apparently not given until the flames had obtained a firm hold over
                        the highly inflammable materials contained in the stores, so that little
                        could be done to save the adjacent premises. For-tunately no wind prevailed,
                        otherwise the flames, leaping many yards above the neighbouring buildings,
                        would have rapidly spread, while the means at hand for the work of
                        extinction would have been hopelessly inefficient.</p>
                    <p>The hakimdar and mulahiz of police were quickly on the scene, and, assisted
                        by the mudir's wakil and other residents, did all that was possible to
                        prevent the extension of the fire, and to maintain order in the large crowd
                        that rapidly assembled. The biasing ooal and wood contained in the ignited
                        building,however rendered any attempt at extinction with a small hand engine
                        futile, but the precautions taken to prevent the spread of the conflagration
                        were fortunately attended with success.</p>
                    <p>The prevention and extinction of fires in the provinces is a subject which
                        might well be given more attention than it has hitherto received. It should
                        not be necessary, for in-stance, to telegraph to Cairo for assistance, while
                        the efforts of volunteers might be better trained in order to prevent the
                        indiscrimate and hopeless pouring of stream of water into the heart of a
                        blazing furnace, while adjoining premises, in imminent danger from the
                        contact of the flames, us waiting what may possibly prove salvation ; and
                        those individuals who intercept the jets thrown by the hose, might also be
                        kept within bounds.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OBITUARY. COLONEL WARDROP.</head>
                    <p>The late, Col. Frederick Meyer Wardrop, C.B., whose death is announced by a
                        Renter’s \ telegram of yesterday’s date, was born in 1847, his father being
                        the late Henry Wardrop of Blackfaulds, Lanarkshire. Entering the 3rd Dragoon
                        Guardsin 1869 ,his military career was brilliant and his advancement rapid.
                        In the | Egyptian campaign be acted as A D.C., to Sit Garnet (now Lord)
                        Wolseley and was present at the actions of El Magfar, Tell el Mahuta, \
                        Ksssaeain and Tel el Kebir. He was mention- j ed in despatches, promoted to
                        the brevet rack of Major, and was granted the Egyptian medal with clasp, 4th
                        class of the Medjidieh and Khedive's star. Two years later in the expedi-
                        tion of 1884-5 he played a distinguished part as D.A.A.G. and Q.M.G., was
                        mentioned several , times in despatches, distinguished himself at Abu Klea
                        and was promoted to the rank of Brevet Lieut-Colonel. From 1895 to 1902 Col
                        . Wardrop was British Military attchae in Aus-tria-Hungary, Roumania and
                        Servia, and from 1899 to 1902 in Montenegro as well. Col. War-drop was
                        Colonel of the 18th Lancers and retired comparatively recently from the
                        army. He married in 1895 Miss Mary Brooks Close, daughter of the late Daniel
                        Paullin of Quincey Illinois, U.S.A. The deceased officer held numerous
                        foreign decorations, among them that of Commander of the Frans Joseph order
                        with star, and Commander of the Star of Rou-mania. He was an ardent rider
                        and fisherman and enjoyed great personal popularity.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOME PRESS COMMENTS. THE SULTAN'S ACCESSION.</head>
                    <p>From “Al Lewa."</p>
                    <p>“Every nation celebrates the succession days and birthdays of its Kings or
                        Sultans and the whole world of Islam from Bast to West joined in celebrating
                        the accession of Sultan Abdul Hamid. The recent fete day was more
                        conspi-cuously and splendidly honored than all that bad gone before since
                        our Sultan ascended the throne, for it was generally felt that the occasion
                        demanded exceptional rejoicing in honor of Hie Majesty's escape from the
                        dastardly attempt cm his life.</p>
                    <p>We need not go into particulars of the character of the Sultan. They are
                        known to all. Every kingdom has within its borders fixe hostile to the
                        common weal whose schemes mast be baffled by ministers and statesmen, but
                        our exalted empire contains many foes and there is no one to combat their
                        machinations but the Sultan himself. Vigilant, watchful, and active he has
                        not burdened his people with too many debts, successful in war, he can be
                        proud of hie victory over Greece which resulted in the recovery of an
                        indemnity end may well be compared to the triumph of Japan over Russia,
                        which like a tortoise has shrunk into its shell. His majesty has built
                        warships, schools, and hospitals and has opened technical and military
                        colleges, religions seminaries, and agricultural schools. He has constructed
                        the Hedjaz Railway which has caused rage and apprehension among the English,
                        and he is completing the railway to the Persian gulf, which will be of greet
                        econom-ic end military importance.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>"Levant Herald.”</head>
                    <p>The “Levant Herald'’ contains a long poem in French in honor of the occasion
                        from which we quote two characteristic verses,</p>
                    <p>On pourralt lh-casus denombrer bien des falts, De noble tolerance., la
                        Turqule, Oul, ches elle, Sout plus libres cont fols que dans tout
                        Tunivers.</p>
                    <p>Lorsqu'nn sinistre eclate, en un lieu de l'Empire. Par an noble bonte, l'on
                        voit nocher lon pleurs, Apures des maux le Ciel l'a m'a poor le reuxede. Et
                        de la Providence., icl, representant. Bon heureuse influence. e late a
                        chaque instant.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RECAPTURE OF SANA.</head>
                    <p>In a despatch dated August 25, Marshal Ahmed Fairi Pasha, then established at
                        Souk-el-Hamis, made the following report on the progress of the campaign end
                        the fighting in the passes</p>
                    <p>“I personally directed the operations undertaken against the rebels
                        entrenched on the summits of the Jebel Shaib range. These heights, which era
                        over 8,000 feet above sea-level commanded the position known as “Sinan
                        Pasha,” which is within five hours march of Sana. Our troops carried the
                        enemy's trenches after two days fighting, and have now established the Army
                        Head Quarters at Sinan Pasha, and sent detachments to other necessary
                        points. Marshal Shakir Pasha has left with a sufficient force to occupy
                        Bekti Redem, the principal rallying point of the insurgent</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The following is the programme of the vocal part of the concert to be given
                        tomorrow evening:—</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="letters">
                    <head>LETTER TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                        correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit
                        -within certain necessary limits- free discussion.</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RAILWAY ADMINISTRATION.</head>
                        <p>To the Editor or Tire Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                        <p>Sir,—I often read in your widely circulated paper reports not altogether
                            creditable to the administration of the Egyptian State Railways. In your
                            edition of October 8, 1908 you in published a forcible complaint from me
                            regarding the overcrowding of carriages, in which I pointed out that the
                            accommodation for ladies was insufficient. The railway authorities,
                            however, do not seem to pay any attention to complaints, no matter from
                            whom they originate. On Monday morning a family from Cairo, consisting
                            of five adults and one child, ordered a seoond-class comportment at Sidi
                            Gaber on the train leaving for Cairo at 7.9 a.m. Six full fares were
                            charged and paid for, and the station master telephoned to Alexandria
                            for a compartment to be reserved, and received an answer assuring him
                            that it would be done. On the arrival of the train at Sidi Gaber no
                            reserved compartment was to be found, and there was not even a vacant
                            seat After a great deal of trouble the family were accommodated in an
                            empty first-class carriage. A lady and little boy were leav-ing the same
                            station by the 8-1 p m. train on that day. and asked the porter to put
                            them in the ladies’ compartment, but on the arrival of the train it was
                            found to bo occupied mainly by native men and boys. None of the
                            officials would send any of them intruders into another to the
                            remonstrances of the lady or myself.</p>
                        <dateline>Bulkeley, August 30,</dateline>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                        <p>E.T.C. v. Mr. S. J. DAWSON’S A. C. C. XI.</p>
                        <p>Played yesterday on the A.C.C. ground, resulting in a draw. The XL going
                            in first declared after making 236 for seven wickets. Birley who played
                            an excellent not ret innings of 81 was highest scorer. He hit tan fours
                            in his innings and took rather more than an hour and a half to make his
                            runs. Capt. Moore and Murphy also scored wall, both hitting with great
                            freedom.</p>
                        <p>The E. T. C. began badly losing five wickets for 58, Stacey being the
                            only one of the early batamen to give much trouble At this point
                            Maclean, taking advantage of a bad let off at short slip, began to hit
                            and found a most useful partner in Henley. Eighty six runs were added
                            when Henley was bowled, after an innings which was most useful, if it
                            made no gnat figure re the score sheet. Maclean continued to hit hard
                            and often, his pulling bring remarkably severe and effective, and
                            carried hie bat for a fine innings of 108, which included two sues, and
                            fifteen boundary hits.</p>
                        <p>Full score and analysis :</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>The committee of the Alexandria Swimming Club asks us to announce that
                            the 3rd annual aquatic sports will take plan on the 7th</p>
                        <p>Members times will be taken on the 23rd instant and all those who intend
                            to are requested to be present.</p>
                        <p>The 60 yards juniors and 110 yds. seniors championships will take place
                            on the 30th instant.</p>
                        <p>The venue will be announced later. He following is a list of events,
                            which may be added to later</p>
                        <p>60 yds. juniors' handicap; 60 yds. seniors handicap ; 60 yds. veterans'
                            race; Plunging championship ; Military Polo Match ; Polo match,
                            Alexandria Swimming Club versus Rest of Alexandria; Military tug of war,
                            tour a side ; Blindfold race ; Diving Competition ; Obstacle race ;
                            Walking the pole; Military team race.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Mr. Webb, acting adviser to the Ministry of Public Works, retamed to Cairo
                        from Assouan on Monday. He arrived at Alexandria tart night and after
                        spending a short time here will return to Assouan on a visit of</p>
                    <p>Mr. Verschoyle. chief inspector of irrigations in Lower Egypt is at present
                        paying a visit of inspection in the province, and will return to Cairo on
                        Saturday.</p>
                    <p>Captain R.P. Crawley, A.S.C., has been granted leave of absence from the 21st
                        inst. till November 20.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to hear that Mr. J.D. Wallieh, who left Egypt on July 22 on
                        ordin-ary Wallieh returns to Egypt by the Austriaq Lloyd steamer leaving
                        Trieste on Friday.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
