<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-11-16">November 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-13">13 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="issue">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</head>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE PANAMA CANAL.</head>
                    <p>I am afraid that President Roosevelt’s domestic worry, as you term it in your
                        number of the 10th inst., will not cease for many summers to come. Having
                        resided on the Isthmus of Panama for seven years and contributed a series of
                        articles to the “Times,” “Saturday Review,” “Scotsman,” “Chambers’ Journal,”
                        and “New York Herald,” I can speak as an authority with “connaissance de
                        cause.” First and foremost, without entering immediately into technical and
                        financial matter, such as the Chagres River, Culebra mountain, the ports of
                        Colon and Panama, the expense and difficulty in finding labour, let me refer
                        to the climate and the sanitary conditions of the Isthmus. Yellow fever
                        resides permanently, whether in an endemic or epidemic form, and until this
                        scourge is eradicated the canal will cost millions sterling, take years to
                        build, and thousands of lives will be its holocaust. Has there been any
                        specific discovered to save a patient once attacked with this disease, and
                        what percentage die and how many recover? There are only special beings,
                        “lucky dogs,” who seem exempt from this fatal disease. A muscular, lean man
                        acclimatised in a torrid zone between the ages of 40 and 60 appears to
                        escape its virus, providing he is abstemious and refuses to drink Panama
                        water in any shape or form. Youth and middle age are more subject,
                        especially those who have not lived in or frequented a warm climate.
                        Sanguine, lymphatic, and corpulent natures are tempting preys to the
                        disease. To be acclimatised is to be in a constant state of anaemia, a state
                        which the microbe despises. Children seem to be exempt. I am not alluding to
                        the indigenous population, for it would be very unfortunate if they could
                        not live in their own country, although some, very few, do die from yellow
                        fever through contagion or intemperate habits. The native population are as
                        yellow as quinces, and in a perfect state of chronic anaemia. The yellow
                        fever microbe is seldom the tenant of a black man ; he has enough to do with
                        other bacilli. </p>
                    <p>During my sojourn on the Isthmus, with a change of air every two years, I
                        knew but very few Europeans who recovered from an attack, and these attacks
                        were slight. None ever weathered a virulent case. We have amongst us to-day
                        a worthy and excellent Sister of Charity of the Order of St Vincent of Paul,
                        who for several years was the Angel of Mount Ancon hospital, where she
                        unremittingly tendered her care and services to the last moments of many a
                        patient </p>
                    <p>To construct a canal through these Nicropolai you must commence by purifying
                        the whole Isthmus, and changing the sanitary conditions, then you may
                        succeed in improving the climate, but otherwise you can bury your dead and
                        spend your millions, as the French company did from 1881 to 1885. It was not
                        a “French folly,” but a French misfortune. They went boldly and gaily to
                        work, but M. de Lesseps never dreamt of such a climate nor contemplated such
                        a task. He preferred the Panama route on account of its being shorter than
                        others proposed, but had he selected any other, the Atrato, Darien, or
                        Nicaragua, even Tehuantepec, he would have succeeded. His genius and
                        popularity would have moved mountains, but he could not battle against the
                        hidden monster of disease which rendered his staff and workmen fearful,
                        nervous, and careless. Engineers-in-chief died, like MM. Blanchet and Boyer,
                        men of vast experience and capacity. In a few months the wife, son, and
                        daughter of Mr. Dingler, the director general, were victims of yellow fever.
                        All collapsed; it was a forlorn hope with a “sauve qui peut’’ which ushered
                        on the scene in many cases the fiend of dishonesty. “Apres moi le deluge”
                        was the password. </p>
                    <p>The luxuriant vegetation and the dense foliage on each side of the proposed
                        line of the Canal prevent the rays of the sun from penetrating the
                        accumulated heaps of dead and decayed vegetable matter from which emanate a
                        mephitic vapour charged with the germs of disease and pestilence. What part
                        of the Isthmus can be pointed out as free from these seeds of malignant
                        fever ? Is it in the swamps of Rio Grande, on the heights of Emperador,
                        Culebra, or Obispo ? On the plains of Mamei, Matachin, or Bohio-Soldado ?
                        Surely not at Gatun nor Colon ! The fever lurks in the dry season from
                        December to March and is ready to sally forth as soon as the change is
                        taking place from April to June and from September to November. Seasons are
                        only two, the rainy and the dry, which fairly divide the year. The former is
                        torrential; the storm gathers in the hours of the antemeridian and bursts
                        with violence, accompanied often with tremendous flashes of fork lightning.
                        I have, on several occasions, seen objects struck with unusual force,
                        displacing blocks of masonry, reducing planks into splinters, melting leaden
                        gutters on the tops and sides of houses. These phenomena are independent of
                        a few good shakes by earthquakes and a few revolutions now and again as a
                        pastime. These are the Isthmian games of this chosen spot. After a rain
                        storm you have rivers and rivulets. The Chagres rises with an extraordinary
                        rapidity. It rose 30 feet in one night in 1882 in one of these charming
                        freshets mandwashed away <cb/> the rails, sleepers, and embankments of the
                        railway between two sections near Barbacoas. </p>
                    <p>Trees grow without culture, (no need of arable land), on the tops of houses,
                        and your boots and shoes in one night in the wet season are coated with a
                        lovely soft mildew like lambswool. As for perspiration, you are in a
                        constant state of liquefaction, from the damp heat before the storm burts,
                        when you are partly relieved. Then comes the dry season, when the land is
                        absolutely arid—better the Sahara, even with Jacques Ier. as Emperor. It is
                        difficult to obtain water and one is obliged to go several miles to bring a
                        pailful or purchase one from the trickling Matasnillo and its stagnant
                        pools. And then it is not as if your journey could be rewarded or your
                        purchase satisfied with a meagre quantity of good water, but you are
                        confronted with a pail of dancing animal culae. The house trees fade and die
                        and are whirled away from the slender roots with the breath of Aquilon; but
                        do not weep ! The tiles will bring forth others next season. The streets and
                        roads are watered with clouds of fine dust and the Savanna is a parched
                        plain. “0 fortnatos nimium, sua si bona norint Panamania!” </p>
                    <p>This is only climatic, what about the technical side? Will the Culebra be
                        ever mastered, will it be prevented from closing its wound when it is cut ?
                        This is the phenomenon of the moving mountain. What about the Chagres ? is
                        that to be muzzled, how and when ? By a deviation to the east of Colon or by
                        a dam which in my time was to retain 2,000,000,000 cubic metres of water.
                        Well! if it comes to grief on a freshet like 1882 it will remind us of the
                        flood without the ark which will not be ready to receive the Isthmians of
                        Panama. This sovereign miniature State was wrenched from the territory of
                        Columbia. A second Andorra with a Bishop as President instead of an
                        engineer. The former will be more useful in this case as there will be only
                        souls left. What about the ports of Panama and Colon and the three-mile
                        dredging in open roadstead to Flamenco ? MM. Barratoux, Latellier &amp; Co.
                        worked like Spartans at this channel but they found out to their
                        astonishment that as fast as they dredged in front it filled up behind, and
                        for a surplus of misery they lost their director, Mr. Lilas, and part of
                        their staff from yellow fever. Mr. Latellier thought it wiser to abandon his
                        hourglass and take up journalism. </p>
                    <p>Is it a level or a lock canal ? Ask Mr. Eiffel if he knows about the lock
                        system. I know he is a “tower” of strength, but when he found that the
                        Atlantic rose only six inches and the Pacific 20 feet he thought that,
                        considering yellow fever was to be calculated with this rise and fall, it
                        would be prudent to leave that problem for later on and construct a more
                        profitable enterprise in the shape of “la tour d’Eiffel.” </p>
                    <p>I never doubt American enterprise with money and science, but they have not
                        yet discovered the antidote for yellow fever, nor the remedy to prevent
                        staff and workmen deserting. Moreover, will they be able to induce West
                        Indians to come to the Isthmus, only to return invalided and increase the
                        poor rates ? And if they do, will the governors allow the depopulation of
                        their dependencies ? If they want to get rid of the coloured population of
                        America the best thing would be to make them a present of the infant
                        Republic, and allow them to govern themselves and dig the Canal. The
                        coloured American race would be extinct in a very few years. They might save
                        a couple to please Bostock. </p>
                    <p>If they could invent automatic excavators, diamond drills, self-working
                        dredgers, etc., I could believe that the Panama Canal was approaching its
                        construction, but as long as “Yellow Jack” holds its sway I must wait until
                        the spread Eagle has conquered him. </p>
                    <p>Panama is more American now than Colombia, and had not America supported the
                        Franco-Panamanian visionaries with Mr. Bunau-Varilla as High Commissioner
                        and Envoy-extraordinary and Plenipotentiary per interim, the Canal would be
                        the same to day as it was 25 years ago, but with £15,000,000 more in the
                        American Treasury. There is a notice out, I see, that stray and ownerless
                        dogs found in the San Stefano quarter during the night of Friday and
                        Saturday at daylight will be poisoned by the police. I am off— Vale.</p>
                    <byline>STRAY DOG.</byline>

                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>HEAT AND CHOLERA.</head>
                    <head type="sub">A DANGER TO EUROPE.</head>
                    <p>Professor Chantemesse, an eminent French doctor, and Director-General of the
                        Paris Hygienic Bureau, says, according to the “Daily Mail” correspondent,
                        that Europe is seriously threatened with a cholera epidemic this year.
                        During the last four years, he states, cholera has been advancing rapidly
                        westwards, and it now threatens to invade Europe by four different routes:
                        (1) Through Moscow, St Petersburg, and the Volga river ; (2) through the
                        Black Sea, Odessa, and Central Europe ; (3) through the Danube and the
                        Balkan principalities ; (4) through Constantinople, the Adriatic, and Italy.
                        All that is wanting now for the advent of cholera in Europe, says the
                        Professor, is a long spell of hot weather. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>ROYAL BIRTHDAY.</head>
                    <head type="sub">THE PIGMIES AT BUCKINGHAM PALACE.</head>
                    <dateline>London, July 7.</dateline>
                    <p>Princess Victoria, whose thirty-seventh birth, day it was, yesterday received
                        many presents and congratulation. Her Royal Highness, who takes the keenest
                        interest in, and displays the warmest affection for, her younger relations,
                        is understood to have selected for the celebration of her birthday a garden
                        party, to which her nieces and nephews and some fifty juvenile guests were
                        invited. </p>
                    <p>In the grounds of Buckingham Palace Queen Alexandra arranged an entertainment
                        for the young folk, and arranged for the presence of the forest pigmies,
                        Jumbo junior, the baby elephant, two performing ponies, and a
                        prestidigitateur of marvellous powers.</p>
                    <p>The Duchess of Sparta and her children, with Prince and Princess Frederick
                        Charles of Hesse, and their little ones, came up from Seaford for the
                        occasion, and joined the Crown Prince of Greece, whom they accompanied to
                        England on Monday last, and who has since been staying at the Palace as the
                        guest of the King and Queen. All her Majesty’s grand-children also came up
                        for the day. </p>
                    <p>The guests were received at the grand entrance, and conducted to one of the
                        spacious drawing-rooms, where tea was provided for them, accompanied by
                        vocal mnsic. </p>
                    <p>Of the attractions in the grounds the keenest centred, at least for a time,
                        in the pigmies, who were armed with their tiny bows and arrows. Grave and
                        solemn, seated beneath a tree in a shaded part of the grounds, the pigmies
                        awaited the arrival of her Majesty, the Princes and Princesses, and guests,
                        and submitted, without any apparent shyness or unwillingness, to the
                        interested scrutiny to which they were subject. When attention was diverted
                        in turn to the performing animals and the mystifications of the conjurer,
                        the pigmies appeared as interested in the performances as the general body
                        of guests. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE CONSTANTINIDI CASE.</head>
                    <head type="sub">HUSBAND AND DIVORCED WIFE</head>
                    <p>The hearing of the case of “Constantinidi v. Constantinidi and Lance” was
                        resumed in the Court of Appeal last Thursday, before Lords Justices Vaughan
                        Williams, Stirling, and Cozens Hardy. It was an appeal by Mrs. Julia Lance
                        from a judgment of Sir Franois Jeune given on December 5, 1904, directing
                        that an order of the Registrar as to the alteration of settlements made on
                        her marriage with Mr. Demetrius Sophocles Constantinidi should be varied.
                        Lord Justice Vaughan Williams said that the judgment appealed against had
                        been given by the late President in exercise of the discretion conferred on
                        him by section 31 of the Matrimonial Causes Act, 1857, with reference to the
                        variation of a marriage settlement after the decree for divorce had been
                        made absolute, and was in the petitioner’s favor. His Lordship read the
                        facts as stated by the late President, under which the proceedings for
                        divorce were instituted by the husband. The President had pointed out that
                        the authorities were in favor of the principle that where a wife had by her
                        misconduct broken up the home it was justifiable to give her husband a
                        portion of her income to restore him to the position he would have ocoupied,
                        and also on the broad principle that a co-respondent should not be allowed
                        to profit by his own iniquity. The President had found that the petitioner
                        had not himself been guilty of misconduot before the date of the
                        respondent’s going to South Dakota with the obvious intention of procuring a
                        so-called divorce and contracting a bigamous marriage. No doubt, continued
                        Sir Franois Jeune, after she had gone the petitioner himself was guilty of
                        shameless misconduct, but the President was unable to say that she had not
                        conduced to her husband’s misconduct. Having granted a divorce to the
                        petitioner in this case—a decision which had not been challenged—he could
                        not hold that the petitioner’s misconduct should debar him from the relief
                        he sought. He did not propose to take the £25,000 damages awarded by the
                        jury or the unpaid costs into account, but he had to consider what the
                        respective settled incomes of the parties were. The petitioner’s . was £710
                        and the respondent's £2,200, the latter derived from a capital sum of
                        £51,000. The President, taking those figures and facts into account, varied
                        the order of the Registrar, who had reported as follows : “Having regard to
                        the verdict of the jury against the petitioner, to their being no issue of
                        the marriage, and to no neccessity being shown for providing for the
                        petitioner out of the wife’s trust funds, it is submitted that no order
                        should be made in variation of the respondent’s settlement of October 23,
                        1889.” In his (Lord Justice Vaughan Williams’) opinion that order of the
                        Registrar was the right order. But the late President had varied that order
                        and had directed that the trustees should pay to the petitioner two sums
                        yearly of, roughly, £1,000 each, one to be paid immediately, and one after
                        the death of the respondent’s mother. The order of the late President must
                        be set aside, and an order made in the sense of the Registrar’s report </p>
                    <p>Lord Justice Stirling and Lord Justice Cozens-Hardy concurred. </p>
                    <p>It was decided that the costs of the appeal should be paid by the
                        petitioner.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA. The best halfway home between Egypt and
                        England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA. Main line expresses stop. Fine woods,
                        Sands, Sea bathing mild climate, English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home
                        comfort. Electric light. Modern sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and
                        gardens. 1-48-31 Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAVY.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>London, July 4.</dateline>
                    <p>The new force of cavalry which is about to be raised in Egypt will no doubt
                        attract many officers to that servioe, for the land of the Pharaohs is a
                        popular place to soldier in. At the same time our cavalry regiments cannot
                        afford to part with many officers, the commissioned ranks being depleted as
                        it is. </p>
                    <p>The S.S. Dunera is due to leave Southampton on the 27th of September with
                        drafts on board for Gibraltar, Malta, and Egypt. The same liner will take
                        out drafts to Egypt in November. </p>
                    <p>Colonel E. K. G. Aylmer, C.B., an officer well-known in Egypt, will retire on
                        half-pay from the command of the 19th Hussars at the Curragh on the 17th
                        inst. under the four-years’ rule. He will be succeeded by Brevet Lieut.-
                        Colonel H. G. De Pledge, the second in command. </p>
                    <p>The administration of the King’s African Rifles, of which there are five
                        battalions, has been transferred from the Foreign Office to the Colonial
                        Office. Brigadier-General Sir William Manning, Inspector-General of the
                        force, retains that appointment under the transfer of administration. </p>
                    <p>All the British cavalry regiments in India have been re-armed with the short
                        rifle. The mode of carrying it has not yet been decided upon. </p>
                    <p>The War Office has taken a strong step towards reducing the expense of living
                        in the cavalry regiments of the line, and the King’s Regulations will be
                        amended accordingly. All extravagances, which heretofore have been the means
                        of keeping young men of moderate means out of the service, are to be put
                        down, and commanding officers who fail to aid and assist the authorities in
                        keeping expenses well within bounds will be liable to be summarily dealt
                        with. The system of keeping two sets of accounts, one showing the legitimate
                        outlay, and the other expenses which hardly come under that heading, is to
                        be suppressed, and semi-private accounts will be tolerated under no
                        circumstances. The Army Council is of opinion that no difficulty would be
                        experienced in keeping up the supply of eligible candidates if the
                        expenditure were reduced. Regimental drags have been marked down for
                        abolition, as being a very expensive item. It must be remembered that many
                        deserving officers who won commissions in the late war had to resign these
                        hard earned commissions after the war closed owing to the expense in cavalry
                        regiments. This time the Army Council seems to be in earnest. </p>
                    <p>Germany’s campaign now in progress in South-West Africa has witnessed some
                        successful experiments in the use of camels for army transport. The camels
                        are brought from Fuertura Ventura, an island of the Canaries group, and have
                        proved specially useful for transport across the stretch of shifting sand,
                        about forty miles in extent, which separates the coast from the interior,
                        and which has proved fatal to ox and mule transport. The animals are able to
                        cross the sand without water and carry a load of 600lbs. each. They are fed
                        chiefly on alfalfa, chaff, and barley, and stand the change of climate well. </p>
                    <p>The youthful King of Spain is determined on having a Navy commensurate with
                        his dominions. The programme is a modest one, embracing four battleships of
                        16,000 tons displacement, five armoured cruisers of 10,000 tons
                        displacement, and a dozen smaller craft. The programme is to be spread over
                        a number of years. The last of the cruisers of the Orlando type building for
                        the Spanish Navy is in hand, and it is ironically said that at the present
                        rate of construction she will be ready for commission about the year 1910. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>VISITORS LIST.</head>
                    <head type="sub">WINDSOR HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>Dr and Mrs. K. Johnston, Mr. M. Maliolin, Mr. Goldie, Dr. Goldslich, Lt.
                        Robert Porgès, M. Jacques Anger, M. Paul d’Albert, M. and Mme Samarina, Mr.
                        Doulcardis and family, M. M. Ralli, M. Salomone, Mr. and Mrs. Peacock, Dr.
                        J. R. Marshall, Mr. Normandeau, Mr. Rollin, Mr. Rifflard, Mr. Chasse, Mr.
                        Levi, Mr. Wade, Mr. Purvis Bond, Mr. Panas, Mr. and Mrs. Turabian, Mr. W.
                        Scott, Mr. Vlandy, Mr. John Wright, Mr. A. Tederman, Bakri Bey, Mr.
                        Merulier, Mr. Spartman, Mr. Jacovides, Mr. Herbes, Mr. Stewart, Mr, Guiné,
                        Mr. Brown, Dr. Chidoudi, Mr. Gogonelli, Mr. Ganagé, Mr. Behich, Mr. Dosse,
                        Mr. G. Dahan, Mr. G. Ninci, Mr. Hanki, Mr. Tite, Mr. Henry Barthau, Mr.
                        Pagori, Mr. Macarius, Mr. Nicolas Thomas, Mr. and Mrs. Hague, Mr. Merloy,
                        Mr. Wolley, Mr. Jones, Mr. Strong, Mr. Long-Branch, Mr. Sevasly, Mr.
                        Chrisocoïdes.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>Cheap Prepaid Advertisements</head>
                    <p>Under this heading advertisements are inserted at the following rates :—</p>
                    <table rows="4" cols="4">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>ONCE</cell>
                            <cell>3 TIMES</cell>
                            <cell>6 TIMES</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>15 words . . .</cell>
                            <cell>P.T. 5</cell>
                            <cell>P.T. 10</cell>
                            <cell>P.T. 15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>30 words ...</cell>
                            <cell>„ 8</cell>
                            <cell>„ 16</cell>
                            <cell>„ 24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Every 10 words, beyond 30. . .</cell>
                            <cell>” 2</cell>
                            <cell>” 4</cell>
                            <cell>” 6</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The address is counted. The advertisement must appear on conseontive days for
                        above rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged for advertisements not
                        appearing consecutively. </p>
                    <p>All such advertisements must be prepaid, and to this rule no exception
                        whatever will be made. Letters in reply to advertisements will be posted to
                        any address if a few stamps are sent by the advertiser to cover postage. </p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Agard's international industries AND TRADE MARKS REGISTER. - A useful
                            business directory containing addresses of all important business firms
                            of Great Britain the Continent, and Egypt. Circulating all over Europe
                            and America. Price— One pound Sterling. Post Free. </p>
                        <p>AGARD'S INTERNATIONAL HOTEL GUIDE sent post free to all first class
                            Hotels throughout Europe, America, the Colonies and Egypt. The best
                            reference book for travellers. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>ADVERTISING AGENTS.—The best public Advertising sites in Alexandria
                            belong to G. Vestri &amp; Co., Advt. Agents, St. Catherine's Square.
                            Special rates for permanent clients. Moderate terms. Prompt despatch. </p>
                        <p>25642-31-12-905</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>APPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German, to the Berlitz Schools,
                            Alexandria (26, Rue de l’Eglise Copte) ; Cairo Sharia Kamel), Most rapid
                            method Trial lesson free. Evening classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per
                            month.</p>
                        <p>23069-30-9A-905</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>ARABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Shefik,
                            “Egyptian Gazette’ offioes. </p>
                        <p>25888- </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>AMERICAN MANUFACTURER'S Agency wishes to advise having received a fresh
                            consignment of Roll-top Desks, Morris Chairs, Sewing Maohines,
                            Refrigerators,Typewriters and various other American goods. No. 7 Rue de
                            l’Ancienne Bourse. </p>
                        <p>25878-2-5-906 </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <p>A LOUER Chambres meublés, avec ou sans pension, Rue Chérif Pacha,
                            vis-à-vis Bourse Khédiviale, 2e étage, Alexandrie. </p>
                        <p>261966A-5</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>BLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9, No. 7 £11. W.T. Emmens, 99 Rue Attarine,
                            Alexandria, Address, Post Offioe Box 35. </p>
                        <p>30-6-906A</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>CLERK, thorough knowledge English, French, also Arabic quick typist and
                            stenographer, seeks situation. Apply, No. 26,226, “Egyptian Jazette”
                            offices. </p>
                        <p>26226-6-3 </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>EXPERIENCED ACCOUNTANT WANTED with thorough knowledge of English; an
                            Englishman would be preferred. Salary according to qualifications.
                            Apply, giving full particulars, to No. 26,230 “Egyptian Gazette.”
                            offices. </p>
                        <p>26230-6-1</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>WANTED, by an Engineering Firm, a man capable ot doing Customs work and
                            well up in transport of heavy machinery. Must have a thorough knowledge
                            of Railway Tariffs and store work. Apply X.Y Z. 1001 “Egyptian Gazette”
                            offices. </p>
                        <p>26223-4-4 </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>WANTED, in Alexandria, banno lessons. Reply, stating terms, etc., to No.
                            26,227, ‘Egyptian Gazette ’ office, Alexandria. </p>
                        <p>26227-3-2</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>OKQlPASaH m OVALITY AND CONDITION, HALLS “BOAR’S BRAD” BRAID. Guinness’s T*B
                        LL * c? Bass’s Foreign ,ndia TRADE MARK. Extra .. mamsmam .Pale b°ars HEAD
                        Stout ALE *°STOUT. ^ LIGHT SPARKLING PALZ ALE. Sous Exrotnu t T. B. HALL
                        &amp; Co., Ltd. st” Sole Importer for Egypt and the Sudan: G. MARCUS &amp;
                        Co. ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO and TANTA.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="article">
                    <p>British Chamber of Commerce.—We would call the attention of persons
                        interested in Egyptian trade to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce
                        of Egypt, whose office in Alexandria gives information as to standings
                        trade, &amp;c., to its members, and whose monthly publication reviews our
                        commerce. The annual subscription is 11 and all British traders should
                        become members. Our London office, 36, New Broad- street E.C., acts as
                        London agency to the Chamber. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>MS BRYAN &amp; Co. Continental Hotel
                        Buildings CAIRO. St. David’s Buildings, 1LSXJLNDBU, and 35 - 37 Noble Street
                        LONDON, E.O. English Tailors, Drapers and Outfitters. TRAVELLING R
                        COMPRESSED CANE TRUNKS. SOLID LEATHER OVERLAND TRUNKS. GLADSTONE A KIT BAGS.
                        SUIT OASES, RUGS, Afl. ATHLETIC GOODS: A VARIED STOCK, INCLUDING Slazenger’s
                        Doherty “E.G.M.” Demon. AND Ayre’s Central Strung Racquets. TENNIS BALLS
                        FRESH SUPPLY WSEL*. BOOTS A SHOES. All the newest shapes in the beet English
                        makes:— BUCKSKIN TENNI8 BOOT AT £1 A SPECIALITY. Owing to the increased
                        business in this * Department a new Show* room has been Bitted up wherfc
                        better attention can be given to Gtistotners* CLOTHS: The largest 8tock in
                        Egjpt at Cloths of the best British Manu« facture : TROPICAL TWEEDS,
                        FLANNELS, DRILLS, &amp; c.f &amp; c ill garments cut by experienced English
                        cutters. Fit and style gua* ranteed. GENTS’ OUTFITTING: The newest Shades in
                        Crepe de Chene Ties. Cellular, Oxford, Zephyr Shirts and Pyjamas in great
                        variety. Soecial Attention paid to Shirts Made to Measure. HOSIERY AND
                        UNDERCLOTHING IN THH BEST MAZES. PANAMA, STRAW, A FELT SAtfl CORK &amp; PITH
                        HELMETS. CAPS. HOUSEHOLD LINEN AT SPECIALLY CHEAP PRIOES. TABLE CLOTHS,
                        NAPKINS,SHEETS, AND PILLOW CASES. FLANNELETTES, VIYELLA8 AND CEYLON
                        FLANNELS. SOAP, PERFUMERY, RUBBER SPONGES, BRUSHES, STUDS, MIRRORS (un A
                        BtfM) FOUNTAIN PENS, *«., A*. Davies Biyan &amp; Co., Cairo A
                        Alexasdria,</p>
                </div>

            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
