<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Amber Fling</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 29, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-20">November 20, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7,350] ALEXANDRIA, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 20, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS.</head>
                    <head>APPEAL TO SOLDIERY.</head>
                    <head>END OF STRIKE</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The workmen have addressed an appeal to the soldiers to strike, disobey
                        orders, and join the straggling people. ( Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 18.</p>
                    <p>M. Witte’s appeal has been received with universal derision.</p>
                    <p>The Ukase regarding the peasants is re- garded as yielding to threats, and
                        not a spontaneous concession. ( Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The general strike is localized here. It is over at Warsaw. (Havas)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 19.</p>
                    <p>It has been decided by the Council of Work- men to terminate the strike on
                        Monday. (R.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 19.</p>
                    <p>The delegates of the workmen’s council have decided to terminate the strike
                        on the 20th inst: (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUTINOUS RUSSIAN PRISONERS.</head>
                    <head>GUARDED BY JAP TORPEDO BOATS.</head>
                    <p>Nagasaki, November 19.</p>
                    <p>500 Russian prisoners returning to Vladi- vostok on board the transports
                        Vladimir and Varonej showed signs of mutiny. A hundred Japanese police
                        therefore boarded the vessels, which are now guarded by Japanese torpedo
                        boats. (Renter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KING.</head>
                    <head>GENERAL HEALTH EXCELLENT.</head>
                    <p>London, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The King's general health is excellent, and His Majesty is most cheerfal. He
                        has received numerous sympathetic messages, including one from the London
                        County Council. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>London, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The King visited the stables, accompanied by Sir Frederick Treves, walking
                        with the aid of a stick. His Majesty afterwards motored to Virginia Water
                        and joined a small shooting party. He will join Lord Farquhar’s shooting
                        party next week, driving from point to point. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PANAMA CANAL.</head>
                    <head>DECISION OF COMMISSION.</head>
                    <p>Washington, November 19.</p>
                    <p>The Panama Canal Commission has decided, by a large majority, in favor of the
                        sea level canal. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN TORPEDO BOAT SUNK.</head>
                    <head>32 MEN MISSING.</head>
                    <p>Kiel, November 18.</p>
                    <p>A German torpedo-boat collided with the cruiser Undine near here and sank. An
                        officer and 32 men are missing. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Kiel, November 18.</p>
                    <p>A torpedo-boat has sank in a collision with a cruiser; 33 sailors have
                        disappeared. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SINKING OF CHANNEL STEAMER.</head>
                    <head>123 PERSONS LOST.</head>
                    <p>London, November 19.</p>
                    <p>The Channel steamer Hilda, from South- ampton for St. Malo, sank this morning
                        near the French coast 123 persons were lost five only were saved.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Servan, November 19.</p>
                    <p>The English S.S. Hilda has sank. 123 per- sons were drowned and five saved.
                        (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FATAL FIRE IN GLASGOW.</head>
                    <head>39 PERSONS PERISH.</head>
                    <p>London, November 19.</p>
                    <p>39 persons have perished at a fire in a model odging-honse in Glasgow.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POWERS’ NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                    <head>DEPARTURE OF VESSELS.</head>
                    <p>Toulon, November 19.</p>
                    <p>The men-of-war Charlemagne and Kleber, with two torpedo boats, have left to
                        participate in the naval demonstration against Turkey at Mitelyne.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOOTBALL.</head>
                    <head>NEW ZEALANDERS’ SUCCESS.</head>
                    <p>London, November 18.</p>
                    <p>Football. The New Zealanders have never been beaten. They have scored 624
                        points to 22. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORWAY'S NEW KING.</head>
                    <head>ELECTED UNANIMOUSLY.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The Emperor has directed Prince Henry of Prussia, with the flagship, to
                        escort the Norwegian man-of-war conveying King Charles to Christiania. It is
                        probable that a British warship will also be sent. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Christiania, November 18.</p>
                    <p>The Storthing has formally elected Prince Charles King, unanimously, only one
                        member being absent. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Christiania, November 18.</p>
                    <p>Prince Charles has been unanimously elect- ed King. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KING ALFONSO IN PARIS.</head>
                    <p>Paris, November 19.</p>
                    <p>King Alfonso has arrived. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Helouan.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel des Bains, Helouan, opened its doors for the season to-day.</p>
                    <p>Khedive’s Accession Fetes.</p>
                    <p>The second list of subscriptions for tho cele- bration of the Khedive’s
                        Accession Day brings the total np to P.T. 253,950.</p>
                    <p>Hospital at Port Said.</p>
                    <p>Tho Constantinople newspapers state that an Ottoman military hospital is to
                        be built at Port Said. The site has already been acquired and the places and
                        estimates are now being made.</p>
                    <p>Port of Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Wm. Simons and Co., Limited, Ren frew, have received an order to
                        construct a 1,000 ton powerful bucket hopper dredger, two hopper barges, and
                        a steam tug for the port of Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>All Saints’ Charities.</p>
                    <p>The annual jumble sale in aid of the funds of All Saints’ Church charities
                        will be held on Thursday next, 23rd inst., at Sauti’s Res- taurant, Esbekieh
                        Gardens, Cairo. Sale to begin at 3 p.m., closing at 5.</p>
                    <p>Satvini at the Zizinia.</p>
                    <p>Salvini, the Italian tragedian, leaves Egypt, on the conclusion of his visit,
                        on Wednesday next for Italy. Tomorrow night he will give a farewell
                        performance at the Zizinia, when he will appear in Ron Cesarb di Bazan.</p>
                    <p>Walker &amp; Meimarachi, Ltd.</p>
                    <p>The new local board of Walker &amp; Meimara- ohi, Limited, is to be a very
                        strong one. Mr. W. A. Luning, one of the directors of the com- pany, has
                        arrived from London in order to attend the forthcoming meeting, when the
                        composition of the local board will be decided upon.</p>
                    <p>Bank of Athens.</p>
                    <p>M. Pan. G. Schisas, the able sub-manager of the Bank of Athens at Alexandria,
                        has been appointed manager of the bank's newly-opened branch at Cairo, and
                        will sign conjointly with M. Jean G. Sauliotis, the cashier. M. Jean
                        Joannides, tho manager at Alexandria, has assumed the general management of
                        the Bank’s agencies in Egypt, and will therefore have the right of signature
                        in Cairo as at Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>A "Converted" Jew.</p>
                    <p>Apropos of our leading article today, we may mention that a man described as
                        a "Hebrew Christian,” who was on his way to America to his daughter's home,
                        brought a letter (which we have seen) from the Jews' Society, Jerusalem, to
                        the Rudolph Home, asking that kindness might be shown to him on his passing
                        through Alexandria. Food was given to him, and shelter provided, but he
                        asked for money, which was refused. He left the home after three days' stay
                        and applied to the Chief Rabbi for assistance! It would be interesting to
                        learn the particulars of this man's "conversion," which, doubtless, have
                        been duly reported to London, and it is somewhat difficult to understand
                        what good purpose was effected by merely sending him on to Alexandria
                        instead of direct to America.</p>
                    <p>Probably the Jerusalem Society were anxious to get rid of him at the least
                        possible cost, and so passed on their “convert" as far as Egypt only.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BEKANNTMAOHUNG.</head>
                    <p>Auf Antrag des Kapitians Coltzan, Fuhrers des deutschen Dampfers “Theodor
                        Wille,” Heimatsbafen Kiel, Unterscheidungssignal L.B.J.R. ist Termin zur
                        Ablegung der Verk- larnng uber die Begebenhelten der Reise von Herrosand
                        (Schweden) uber Algier nach Alex- andrien auf Dienstag, den 21. November
                        1905, Vormittags 10 Uhr, im Kaiserlichen Konsulat anberaumt worden.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrien, deu 20. November 1905.</p>
                    <p>Der Kaiserliche Komsul.</p>
                    <p>Gez : von HUMBOLDT,</p>
                    <p>26742-1 Kaiserlicher Generalkonsu.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW RAILWAY BOARD.</head>
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL DECREE.</head>
                    <p>The following is a translation of the Khe- divial Decree constituting the new
                        Railway Board : —</p>
                    <p>We, Khedive of Egypt;</p>
                    <p>Upon the proposition of our Minister of Public Works, and with the
                        approbation of our Council of Ministers,</p>
                    <p>Decree :</p>
                    <p>1. Subject to the provisions of this law the State Railways and Telegraphs
                        shall continue to be attached to the Ministry of Public Works.</p>
                    <p>They shall be placed executively under a General Manager.</p>
                    <p>A Rail way Board shall be created, Which shall be responsible, in accordance
                        with the provi- sions of this law, but subject always to any general or
                        special directions to be given from time to time by the Council of
                        Ministers, for the general oversight and control of the management and
                        working of the State Rail- ways and Telegraphs.</p>
                    <p>2. The President of the Council of Ministers shall be ex-officio President of
                        the Railway Board, and the Financial Adviser and the Advisor to the Ministry
                        of Public Works shall be ex-officio members thereot.</p>
                    <p>The Council of Ministers shall from time to time appoint one or more
                        additional members of the Board ; it may also appoint from time to time one
                        or more extraordinary members of the Board, who shall be entitled to sit
                        thereon but shall not be entitled to vote. Provided that no ordinary
                        additional member or extra- ordinary member of the Board shall be appoint-
                        ed for any longer period than two years.</p>
                    <p>3. In the event of the temporary absence or incapacity of any officer who is
                        an ex officio member of the Board, when no other officer is appointed
                        generally to perform the duties of the officer so absent or incapacitated,
                        the Concil of Minsters may appoint some other officer to temporarily replace
                        the officer so absent or incapacitated, as a member of the Railway
                        Board.</p>
                    <p>4. The Board shall not transact any business unless three members at least
                        are present, of whom not less than two shall be ex-officio members or
                        persons appointed temporarily to replace ex-officio members.</p>
                    <p>5. Subject to any general or special direc- tions to be given from, time to
                        time by the Council of Ministers, the Railway Board shall from time to time
                        make and may from time to time alter or rescind, rules for the manage- ment
                        and working of the State Railways and Telegraphs.</p>
                    <p>The Bosidhall, in particulars</p>
                    <p>a. Define the matters which may be dealt with and disposed of by the General
                        Manager without reference to any superior authority, and the matters which
                        the General Manager shall not deal with or finally dispose of without
                        reference to the Minister of Public Works or without reference to the Board
                        as the case may be.</p>
                    <p>b. Define the relations between the Chief Officer of the Telegraph Department
                        and the General Manager.</p>
                    <p>c. Prescribe the manner in which the ac- counts of the Railways and
                        Telegraphs shall be kept.</p>
                    <p>d. Prescribe roles within the limits of the laws for the time being in force,
                        as to the appointment, promotion, discipline and dismissal of the employees
                        of the Railway and Telegraph Departments, and shall for that purpose be
                        entitled to exercise any powers vested by law in the Council of Ministers or
                        a Minister or in any committee or body inferier thereto, and to delegate any
                        of such powers to the Minister of Public Works or to the General
                        Manager.</p>
                    <p>e. P esc-ibe rules as to its own procedure.</p>
                    <p>f. Notwithstanding the generality of the provisions of the preceding article,
                        none of the matters hereinatter mentioned shall be finally disposed of
                        without the decision of the Board being taken thereon:</p>
                    <p>a. The preparation of the estimates for working and maintenance.</p>
                    <p>b. The approval of the final annual accounts.</p>
                    <p>c. Any general programme for extensions of the railway system, or for
                        improvements therein. </p>
                    <p>d. Any estimate for works, the estimated cost of which exceeds L.E. 20,000,
                        or the acceptance of any contract for an amount exceeding L.E. 20,000.</p>
                    <p>e. The appointment or dismissal of any officer at a salary exceeding L.E. 500
                        a year, or the promotion of any officer to a salary exceeding the like
                        sum.</p>
                    <p>f. The issue of any tariff or modification thereof.</p>
                    <p>g. Any matter which shall be referred to the Board for decision either by the
                        Minister of Public Works or by the General Ma- nager.</p>
                    <p>7. The General Manager shall be appointed by the Minister of Public Works
                        upon the nomination of the Bailway Board, and shall be removable in like
                        manner.</p>
                    <p>8. As from the coming into force of this law, the members of the existing
                        Railway Board shall cease to hold office.</p>
                    <p>Two sections remain repealing the Decree of February 5,1889, and putting the
                        present law into force.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>WANTED an Englishman as Manager to the British Recreation Club, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Applications, which must be received not later than the 30th inst., to be
                        addressed to the Chairman of the House Committee, stating qualifications and
                        whether married or single.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES’ LAWSUIT.</head>
                    <head>PRINCE HUSSEIN’S CLAIM WITHDRAWN.</head>
                    <p>We are informed that H.H. Prince Hussein Pasha Kamel has decided to abandon
                        the claim which he brought with the other princes, heirs of the late Ismail
                        Pasha, against the Government for the restitution of certain sums by the
                        Daira Sanieh. Company.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
                    <p>Among the decisions of the Council of Ministers which met at Abdeen on
                        Saturday under the presidency of H.H. the Khedive are the following:—</p>
                    <p>1. Recognition of the National Hotels and Residences Company.</p>
                    <p>2. Recognition of a joint stock company for protection against fire.</p>
                    <p>3. As to the modification of interest on (Fawaed el Iltazam) concession
                        taxes, which it is suggested are to be reduced by 5 percent per month, this
                        project to be handed over to the Legislative Council</p>
                    <p>4. The Behera provincial council to be convoked oh the 5th prox. and the
                        Ghizeh provincial council on the 14th prox. to consider irrigation projects
                        for 1906.</p>
                    <p>5. Construction of an irrigating canal 605 metres in length at Wahdiya’
                        Assiont.</p>
                    <p>6. Construction of cemeteries and expro- priation of lands for the same in
                        various localities in Kalioubieh, Dakahlieh, and Minieh provinces.</p>
                    <p>7. Approval of a credit of L.E. 15,000 for sanitary precautions to be taken
                        on the return of ,the pilgrims.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>After presiding over the Council of Ministers held on Saturday at 11. a.m. at
                        Abdeen Palace, H.H. the Khedive gave audiences to M. de la Bouliniere, Hon.
                        Mr. Iddings, the new Ameri- can Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General; Fakhry
                        Pasha, who presented Mr. Landon, Inspector to the 2nd Circle of Irrigation ;
                        Mr. P. W. Machell, on his departure for England; Ismail Pasha Sirbaok, the
                        Under Secretary of State for War; Count von Trauttenberg, Count G. de
                        Zogheb, and Sultan Effendi, professor at the Normal School, Nasrieh.</p>
                    <p>On Thursday H.H. the Khedive will attend the ceremony of the Leilat el Kadr
                        at the Citadel. On Friday he will give an "iftar" to the merchants of Cairo
                        and will attend the Mosque of ’Amr for prayer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FASHIONABLE MARRIAGE.</head>
                    <p>The marriage of Dr. Junius Chevalier de Puscarius, Austro-Hungarian Consul at
                        Alex- andria, to Miss von Tschudi, daughter of Mr Christoph de Tschudi, of
                        the firm of Planta and Co., of Alexandria, took place on Saturday afternoon.
                        A largely attended reception was given after the religious ceremony at the
                        house of the bride’s parents.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARRIVAL OF TRANSPORT,</head>
                    <p>The hired transport Assaye arrived at Alex- andria from Southampton and Malta
                        yesterday with details for the Army of Occupation. The details included
                        about 400 officers, N. C. O’s., and men of the 1st Battalion Royal Dublin
                        Fusiliers, who will complete the regiment stationed at Mastapha, which
                        replaced the Royal Berks, on their departure for Khartoum. The troops
                        disembarked this morning and marched to barracks.</p>
                    <p>The Assaye leaves for Port Said to-day to embark the 2nd Battalion. Rifle
                        Brigade for India.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN RAILWAYS.</head>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive has been most graciously pleased to approve of the following
                        promotions. To date 5-11-05:—</p>
                    <p>Local Kaimakam E. C. Milwinter Bey, D.S.O., Assistant Director of Sudan
                        Railways, to be Kaimakam.</p>
                    <p>El Bimbashi R. J. Done, Assistant Director of Works, to he local
                        Kaimakam,</p>
                    <p>El Bimbashi M. E. Sowerby, Sudan Railways, to be local Kaimakam.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TANTAH ELECTION.</head>
                    <head>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</head>
                    <p>Sir,—I learn that owing to the effect of the article you published a few days
                        ago concern- ing the Tanta Municipality, pointing out that the new election
                        was performed under pressure in favor of the new members; who are unfit for
                        the position, the Inspector of the Interior has requested you to support ,
                        your allegations by proof. My newspaper, "Al Horrieh,” Tanta, being the
                        first to criticise the election in a special supplement, indicating the
                        irregulari- ties which took place in the same election, I send you by post
                        “Al Horrieh” and its supplement.</p>
                    <p>Notwithstanding, simple and good proof can be given to the Inspector. He
                        should be re quested to ask the moudir, himself, whether the municipal
                        election was concluded according to the usual rules, and if the pressure of
                        some notables of influence had any effect on its results, or not. The moudir
                        cannot deny the fact that the new members are uneducated and unfit.—Yours,
                        etc., MAHMOUD FEHMI.</p>
                    <p>Tanta, November 19.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BARK OF ABYSSINIA. </head>
                    <head>GERMANY’S INTEREST.</head>
                    <p>It is rumoured in Cairo that the German Government is taking considerable
                        interest in the fortunes of the Abyssinian Bauk and is of opinion that at
                        least one-third of the shares should be in German hands. </p>
                    <p>How far this statement is true we have no means of knowing, but it is worth
                        noting that more than one German bank offered to subscribe the whole capital
                        required, and that £100,000 was actually subscribed. </p>
                    <p>Mr. McGillivray and the staff of the Bank of Abyssinia leave Cairo for
                        Abyssinia about the 1st December next '</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY. </head>
                    <p>The steadily increasing progress of Alex- andria is seen in the report of the
                        Administra- tor on the Budget Estimates of the Alexahdria Municipality for
                        the forthcoming year. The estimates amount to LE. 195,000 in receipts and
                        L.E. 191,570 in expenses, leaving a reserve of LE. 3,430. The estimate
                        receipts show a snrplnB of LE.- 11,850 over those for J905. This surplus is
                        made up for the most part of the following items: import and export dues,
                        L.E. 2,000; tax on vehicles and beasts, L.E. 1,200 ; house tax, L.E. 3,400;
                        2 % tax. L.E. 1,500 ; quarry working dues, L.E.1,000. But from this surplus
                        of nearly L.E., 12,000 a deduction must be made of the budgetary estimates
                        for 1905;. figuring in the extra- ordinary budget of the next year’s
                        working; in accordance with the regulation on June 12, 1905. If, therefore,
                        half of tho Free State Land sales, L.E. 4,000, and the sales of the Tanzim
                        surplus, L.E. 8x0, be deducted, the total net surplus will be L.E. 7,000. </p>
                    <p>A note on the extraordinary budget con- tains an interesting, statement of
                        the expen- diture of the Municipal Loan up to the end of last month. Of the
                        total loan of L.E. 499,980 .(£540,000) there only remains a balance in hand
                        of LE. 31,070, the Munici- pality having up to now expended L.E. 463,994 out
                        of the L.E. 495,070 allotted for the various credits. The following sums
                        have already been spent: Quay-Collector, L.E. 356,132 ; filters and
                        levelling land, L.E. 5,568 ; filters (forfait), L.E. 51,004 ; new drainage
                        works, L.E. 27,158 ; expropriations, L.E. 18,301; miscellaneous expenses,
                        LE. 5,831.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER AND GORDON.</head>
                    <p>Lord Edmond Fitzmaurice has sent the fol- lowing letter to the Editor of the
                        ‘‘Times” in , reply to Lord Cromer: - </p>
                    <p>Sir,—I do not think that the interesting communication from Lord Cromer,
                        which appears in your columns of today, with refe-renece to the instructions
                        to General Gordon in 1884, necessarily requires any comment on my part, as
                        the fuller and more detailed narrative of the facts given by him
                        substantially confirms my own shorter acccount. I may, however, take this
                        opportunity of saying that in that account, I was anxious to show that there
                        was no desire on my part to divest the home Government of responsibility at
                        the expense of Sir Evelyn Baring in regard to General Gordon’s instruc-
                        tions and what followed upon them.</p>
                    <p>In this I am glad to gather from Lord Cromer’s letter that I have not been
                        unsuccess- ful. How far the two sets of instructions, for both of which the
                        home Government must accept responsibility, were contributory causes, and in
                        what proportion, to the subsequent disaster, will probably always remain a
                        subject of legitimate difference of opinion. </p>
                    <p>In regard to the passage to which Lord Cromer alludes at the end of his
                        letter, there was no intention on my part to convey the impression that the
                        epigram attributed to him in 1882 by M. Alfred Ramband, in his recently
                        published “Life of M. Joles Ferry’’’ was uttered at a time when he and M. de
                        Reverseaux were respectively the representatives of Gveot-Britain and France
                        in Egypt; and I can only regret that my reproduction of M. Alfred Rambaud’s
                        story should have produced that impression.</p>
                    <p>Believing that it was possible that the career ofM. de" Reverseaux might not
                        be quite so fami-liar to English as to French readers, I merelywished to
                        indicate that he was the distinguished diplomatist who was afterwards
                        Consol-General in Egypt. But I admit my language should have been clearer. I
                        may, however, beallowed to point out that, if Lord Cromer willrefer to the
                        passage in M. Alfred Rimbaud’s work he Will see that the anecdote is told in
                        aperfectly complimentary sense, and is intended to emphasize the
                        inferiority, in other author’sown opinion, of French diplomacy during the
                        period in question, to the diplomacy in Egyptof Great Britain, in which Lord
                        Cromer hashad so eminent a part.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL</p>
                    <p>RESTURANT</p>
                    <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners</p>
                    <p>Served on the Terrace.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>ARIST0N AERATED WATERS</p>
                    <p>Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria: 7 Rue de la Posto.</p>
                    <p>Mario: Opposite the Trinwayz Co. Works</p>
                    <p>Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Anglo-Amerioan Nile Steamers</p>
                    <p>HOTEL COMPANY:</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Goods between Alexandria and Cario.</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a week</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co, LTO</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>quis and Marchienes de Marscot, and Dr. Rucker-Jenisch, were among the
                        passengers who arrived to-day by tho Austrian packet.</p>
                    <p>The Marquis Silvago Raggi and Count G. Marzoni returned from Europe yesterday
                        by the Florio-Rubattino Orione.</p>
                    <p>Mr. P.W. Machell left Port Said for England early this morning.</p>
                    <p>Herr von Verseri leaves will Tuesday; next to take up his post at Salonica
                        again after soting as Consul for three months at Cario.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Gumprecht, German Consul at Cairo, arrives on Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Mr and Mrs Maspero leave Cairo by their dahabieh on the 20th inst. for Upper
                        Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Mr. P. Oziol, first French Depute de la Nation in Cairo, is expected, to
                        return from Europe next Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Mr. A. J. Cotterill, of the Railways Adminis- tration, leaves Marscillas for
                        Port Said on the 24th inst. He has been engaged during, the past two months
                        on the mission of inspecting the construction of the Nile bridges that are
                        being made by the French firm of Messers. Dayde and Pille at Paris.</p>
                    <p>Major Ricarde Seaver, who, we are pleased to hear, is much better, is leaving
                        England for Egypt on an important business mission.</p>
                    <p>Among this morning’s arrivals by the S.S. Semiramis Irom Trieste are Mr.
                        Schoeller, agent at Alexandria of the North German Lloyd, and the Misses
                        Schoeller.</p>
                    <p>Mr.Edleman, the new agent of the Anglo America Nile Steamer and Hotel Co.at
                        Luxor, left Cairo on Saturday, together with Cook’s representative.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Gordon, veterinary inspector, in the Sanitary Dept., has been transferred
                        to the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Captain F. St. J. Blacker, 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade, left Port Said for
                        Malta today on the S.S. City of Agra.</p>
                    <p>Lieut. C.W. Hemy, 2nd Battalion R. Berks. Regiment, left Cario for Shellal on
                        Saturday in order to rejoin the headquarters of his battalion.</p>
                    <p>Referring to the notice in our issue of the 17th inst. of the annual meeting
                        of the Alex- andria Literary,Musical, and Dramatic Society Mrs. Grafton
                        writes that “finding her name amongst those of the newly elected committee
                        she regrets being unable to comply with this arrangement.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PAISSENGER LIST. </head>
                    <head type="sub">ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. Orione of the Florio Rubattino Co. arrived yesterday from Genos and
                        Messina: - </p>
                    <p>H.E. Marquis Salvago Raggi, Count G. Man- zoni, Mme Teresa Beucini, M. Lauw
                        Nasi Trombotto, M. Henry Abrs, Berlindi Bey, Cav. Burlati, Mme Marchettin,
                        M. and Mme Gabelli, M. Corniadis, M. Miami and fam., M. Giorgio Och, Mr.
                        Bishop, Mr. Morley, M. A, G. Motke, Mr. Fleetwood, M. Manzi Rava M.K.
                        Rickard, M.G.D. Suit, M.O. Vero- nil, M.J. Eucdums and fam., M. Furet, M. A.
                        Vifeli, M.K. Stiekel, M.H. Genes and fam., M.G. Mesina, M. Montepagani and
                        fam., M. Frontnier, M. De Gibbard, M.J. Sab- bag, M.M. Fittak, M.
                        Commariomoll and sam., M.A. Fassone and mother, M. Clott, M. Albert Mayor,
                        M. Tobler, M.C. Failli, Mr. St. Garrett and comp, Capt. C. Richard, M.D.
                        Martelli, M. Yanni and fam</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DEPARTURES.</head>
                        <p>Per S.S. Habsburg of the Austrian, Lloyd sailed Saturday for Brindisi and
                            Trisete :— M. Konig, M. Q Birk, Consul Seifert, Chev. Eugmann, M.J.
                            Levy, M. and Mme Calprurce, Col. Kremec, Col. Hoffman, M. Hupper, Mr. G.
                            Vimercati, M.H. Grohmann, M.A. Spitzer, M. Mikelicj, M. Alfred Leo, M.E.
                            Peck, M.E. Yolles, Dr. Schuster, M. Turlesky.</p>
                        <p>Per S.S. Dumb sailed Friday for Mar- seilles: -</p>
                        <p>M.E.A. Giles, Colonel Forster and family, Mr. Knupper, Mr. Barry, Mr.
                            Kittner, Rev. and Mrs. C.B. Johnson, Mr. and Mrs. Fea- theratone, Mrs.
                            Bixie, Mr. and Miss J. Nicholas, M. Pinole, Miss Shirley, Mr. and Mrs.
                            Begum Billecocq, Capt. Coste, Mrs. H. and H.Mah. mood, Miss Martelette,
                            M. Isaac M. Curel, Mr. Crowe,</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. Credo Rince left today for Manchester.</p>
                    <p>The Messegeries Maritimes S.S. Senegal, from Marseilles, passed the straits
                        of Messina on Saturday and is due tomorrow morning.</p>
                    <p>The Most liner Monks arrived yesterday morning from Luxerpcol via Gibraltar,
                        Algiers, and Malta, with passengers, majs and general cargo.</p>
                </div>

            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
