<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexander Caliendo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-20">October 20, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-12">April 12, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WAR. JAPANESE PREPARATIONS</head>
                    <p>Tokio, April 11. JAPAN is meeting the Russian plan for the reorganization of
                        Manchuria by extensive preparations, to the extent of doubling or even
                        trebling the present units. It is estimated that by the autumn the Japanese
                        organisation will exceeed 1,000,000 men,the actual fieldss force being,
                        roughly 700,000. The Japanese are confident of their ability to take and
                        hold Harbin, and, simultaneously, to operate against the Russians eastwards
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. ANCHORED NEAR ANAMBAS.</head>
                    <p>The Hague,April 11. The Russian fleet has anchored ten miles to the north
                        west of Anambas. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOROCCO. THE FRONTIER INCIDENT. </head>
                    <p>Tangier, April 11. A fight between the Sultan and the Pre- tender’s troops
                        has taken place at Usda. The former had been repulsed when a French frontier
                        force intervened, and defeated the Pretender. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FRENCH PLOT. CAPTAIN VOLPERT ARRESTED.</head>
                    <p>Paris, April 11. Captain Volpert has been arrested for parti- cipation in the
                        plot. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE "ENTENTE CORDIALE”. THE BRITISH FLEET AT BREST. </head>
                    <p>Brest, April 11. Extraordinary preparations are being made for the reception
                        of the British fleet. The Municipal Council has voted an unlimited credit
                        for the entertainments, and the popula- tion is organising independent
                        fetes. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GOVERNMENT MAJORITY. FALLS TO TWELVE.</head>
                    <p>London, April 11. House of Commons. — The Government majority fell to 12 on a
                        motion relating to education in Ireland. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CRETAN INSURRECTION. INSURGENTS MENACING.</head>
                    <p>Canea, April 10. H.M.S. “Juno,” with troops on board, re- turned here and
                        landed 12 prisoners. A huge crowd followed the prisoners to the police
                        station, and cheered them. The insurgents were so menacing that the Italian
                        detachment Was obliged to load their rifles. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive spent yesterday at Mariout. Today, his Highness is at Edfina. It
                        is expected that the Khedive will attend the Zizinia Theatre this evening.
                        Miralai Watson Bey, A.A.G.of the Egyptian Army, is to be appointed first
                        A.D.C. to H.H. the Khedive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the. G. P. 0., Alexandria, at
                            6.30 p.m. to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The San Stefano Casino will be opened for the summer season on Saturday
                            next, 15th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Congdon c. Houghton</head>
                        <p>The hearing of the civil action brought by Mr. Congdon, of Cairo, against
                            Mr. W. Houghton will be heard by the Supreme Consular Court, most
                            probably at the end of May.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Army of Occupation</head>
                        <p>Lieut-Col. A. M. Mantell, R. E., C. R E., Alexandria, has left Alexandria
                            for Cairo in order to take over the duties of C. R. K. in Egypt during
                            the absence on leave of Colonel L. B. Friend, R. E.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>23 vessels passed through the Canal on the 8th and 9th inst. 17 of these
                            were British, 1 French, 3 German, 1 Spanish, 1 Norwegian. The receipts
                            for the two days were frs. 574,752.96, making the total from the 1st
                            inst frs. 2,406,045.53.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Rabies</head>
                        <p>The day before yesterday, an Ar- menian lady, Mme Arian, was bitten by a
                            dog believed to be mad, in the Abdeen quarter of Cairo. Yesterday, a
                            cat, also believed to be suffering from rabies, attacked and bit five
                            Arabs in the Waili district, Abbassieh.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Al Azhar</head>
                        <p>The Sheikhs Bakri Sadafi and Mahmord El Geziri have been appointed
                            members of the council of administration of the Al Azhar University in
                            place of Sheikh Mohamed Abdou and Sheikh Abd al-Kerim Suleiman, who have
                            resigned. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Salt and Soda Co</head>
                        <p>The sales of salt during March realised L.E. 23,072.936 as against L.E.
                            23,376.268 for the corresponding month in 1904 ; the total amount
                            received from sales since January 1 being L.E. 66,787.038, while for the
                            same period last year it was L.E. 71,934.585.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Union Artistique Francaise willgive a dramatic performance at the
                            Eden Theatre, Alexandria, on Saturday next, the pieces to be represented
                            being, A la Chambree, Le coeur a ses raisons, and Uu client serieux.
                            Misses H. Felix and Sant’Andrea will kindly assist in the musical part
                            of the programme. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Adjudications</head>
                        <p>The contract for the con- struction of a school at Benha has been given
                            to M. C. Zouro; for the construction of an inspection building at
                            Kilometre 62, on the Nubarieh Canal, to M. S. Laonelli, and for certain
                            repairs between the twenty-second and forty-fifth kilomotres, on the
                            Mahmoudiah Canal, to M. S. Perullo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cleopatra Cigarette Co</head>
                        <p>We beg to draw our readers attention to the advertisement on page 1 of
                            to-day's issue, of the Cleopatra Ciga- rette Company, which was founded
                            a few months ago by George Nungovich Bey and Mr. Constantino Meimarachi,
                            and has already obtained one of the highest positions in public
                            estimation as a producer of excellent cigarettes. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Recovery of Stolen Property</head>
                        <p>A short time ago Mrs. Hazzan, a Syrian lady living in Mohamed Aly-square,
                            had jewellery to the value of £200 stolen by a servant. Teo man was
                            caugbt, but no trace of the booty could be found until two days ago,
                            when it was very cleverly discovered by some Alexandria de-
                            tectives.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Prince Colibri</head>
                        <p>This wonderful little man will hold his first reception in Alexandria
                            this afternoon, commencing at 5 p.m., in the Alhambra Theatre. A
                            committee of medical men in Cairo declared him to be a “most wondrous
                            mite of humanity,” and those of our readers who wish to gaze on the
                            eighth wonder of the world should not miss such an unique
                            opportunity.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Shooting Affray</head>
                        <p>Yesterday evening, at the 8.30 o’clock, two Italians began discharging
                            revolvers at one another in Sisters-street, Alexandria, owing to
                            jealousy about a woman. None of the shots took effect. The two men were
                            cleverly captured by a policeman. This man happened to be in plain
                            clothes at the time, and was travelling in a tramcar. When he heard the
                            report of firearms he jumped off the tram and arrested both of them.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Baby on the Bourse</head>
                        <p>An extraordinary "scene” was enacted this morning at the Alexandria
                            Bourse. While the exchange was crowded a pretty young woman, carrying a
                            baby in her arms, rushed in with the avowed object of consigning her
                            offspring to its father, a well- known remisier, who had it appears,
                            married and deserted her. The man in question, however, was not on the
                            Bourse at the time, and after publicly denouncing her faithless spouse
                            in unmeasured terms, the excited woman was politely escorted to the
                            door.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Bandmann Dallas Opera Company</head>
                        <p>The "Daily Malta Chronicle” of the 28th inst. gives an account of the
                            opening performance of the Bandmann Dallas opera company at the Manoel
                            Theatre there. "A Country Girl" was produced and was witnessed by a full
                            and appreciative house. Old favorites (says the "Chronicle”) were
                            greeted with rounds of applause, whilst the new members of the company
                            received no less warm a reception, as they gave unmistakable proofs of
                            artistic capabilities.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The White Slave Traffic.</head>
                        <p>—We Are glad to find on enquiry as to the progress made in this matter,
                            that the report that the Govern- ment has contributed L E. 100 to the
                            recently formed committee for the suppression of this vile traffic, is
                            quite correct. We have every reason to hope that now that this matter
                            has been taken in hand, and influential support of the movement is
                            ensured, that Egypt will soon come into line with other countries in
                            doing her best to prevent her ports being utilised for such
                            purposes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alexandria Archaeological Society.</head>
                        <p>— With the object of giving the members of the Archaeological Society an
                            opportunity of visiting the mosaics, discovered by Prince Omar Pasha
                            Toussoun and offered by his Highness to the society, an excursion to
                            Aboukir has been arranged for Monday next Prof. Breccia, Conservator of
                            the Museum, has agreed to give a short lecture concerning the find on
                            the spot. Those taking part in the excursion will leave Alexandria
                            station at 4 p.m. and Sidi Gaber at 4.10 p.m., arriving at Kharabah at
                            4.40 p.m The return journey will be commenced at 7.22 p.m., arriving at
                            Alexandria at 8 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM. Near Shepherds’s &amp; Continental Hotels. Turkish Baths,
                        Plain Baths XRAYS. Electric Light Baths Massage &amp; Electro-Hydropathic
                        Baths. Medical Directors, Dr. Professer Fernario &amp; Dr. M. Reef</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST AND INVESTMENT. COLOSSAL SUCCESS.</head>
                    <p>The list of the above company closed at noon yesterday, with a result that
                        tho Anglo- Egyptian Bank in Cairo have received applica- tions for the
                        enormous amount of 2,990.226 shares. In Alexandria the applications amount-
                        ed to over 6,750,000 shares; altogether a total of nearly 10,000,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE POLYTECHNIC SCHOOL.</head>
                    <p>The strike at the Polytechnic School, Cairo, continues. The pupils are said
                        to have forward- ed a petition to the Ministry of Public Instruc- tion
                        protesting against the tone of the letters addressed by the head master to
                        their respect- ive parents. We should have thought that the parents were the
                        best judges, but 'HysT; rfilv worfpuy paV ojulvan? «u%6|u#’ rival seems to
                        be the view generally taken, and not in this case only, by young Egypt. The
                        peti- tioners add that if the tone of the letter is not modified they will
                        not return to the college at all.</p>
                    <p>The situation is more absurd than ever ; we have the authorities saying in
                        effect, "As a punishment you shall not come back for a week, but if you
                        don’t come back then w expel you," to which the pupils retort, "We promised
                        to strike and have got a week’s holi day in consequence. If you don't ask us
                        to come back very politely we shall not come back at all.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to hear this morning that the recalcitrant pupils of the college
                        have decided to return on Saturday, while continuing their protest against
                        the tone of the letter forwarded to their parents by the head master. Great
                        satisfaction will be felt at the close of an un- fortunate series of
                        incidents.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DUKE OF THE ABRUZZI.</head>
                    <p>The Duke of the Abruzzi paid a visit yester- day morning to the Salisian
                        College. At midday his Royal Highness gave a luncheon at the Mohamed Aly
                        Club in honor of Sig. Monzani, acting Consul-General for Italy.</p>
                    <p>The Duke has given £20 to the benefit of the Alexandria foundlings. The
                        "Liguria" leaves for Spezzia at 6 a.m. tomorrow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesSuez">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <p>Suez, Tuesday. The French cruiser “Encernet,”which arrived at Suez last
                        Monday from Djibouti, will remain at this port for three weeks in order to
                        be overhauled, and to change her crew. The "Encernet" will subsequently
                        return to Dji- bouti. </p>
                    <p>The British cruiser "Diadem" anchored yesterday evening in the Suez roads at
                        8 o’clock. She will sail in a few days, after finishing coaling, bound to
                        China, and on her way she will call at Aden and Trincomalee. This morning
                        1,420 Egyptians pilgrims arrived at Suez from Tor by the Khedivial Mail Line
                        steamers: 700 by the S S. “Rah- manieh,” 520 by the S.S. “Missir," and 200
                        by the S.S. “Callioubieh." All of them will leave Suez to-morrow by special
                        trains for their res- pective villages. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A GRAND NATIVE WEDDING.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon and evening, receptions were held at Idris Bey Ragheb’s
                        fine house near Abdeen Palace, on the occasion of the marriage of his
                        daughter, Fitnat Hanem, to Mohamed Bey Suleiman, son of Mahmoud Pasha
                        Suleiman. The road leading to the house, the court, garden, and reception
                        hall were beautifully and tastefully decorated with flowers, lanterns, and
                        fairy lamps. Whoever was responsible for the floral decoration, deserves the
                        utmost credit for his taste. The first reception was held at 5 p.m., the
                        second at 9 p.m. An enormous member of guests were present, at one time
                        reaching the impos- ing total of 15,000. The buffet, which was largely
                        patronised, was under the care of Mr. Wild, the popular manager of the Savoy
                        Hotel, and we need not say that it did him credit. Music was supplied by the
                        Egyptian Army Infantry Band.</p>
                    <p>Among those present were Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, Boutros Pasha Ghali, Fouad
                        Pasha, Fakhry Pasha, Dr. RuckerJenish, Aziz Pasha Izzet, Thurneyssen Pasha,
                        Adly Pasha Yeghen, Riaz Pasha, Hilmy Pasha, Comanos Pasha, Mr. Machell,
                        Crookshank Pasha, Dr. Pietri Bey, Piot Bey, Mr. F. Suaree, Scander Pasha
                        Fehmy, Hassan Pasha Assem, Ibrahim Pasha Mahmoud, Prince Radziwill,
                        Fabricius Pasha, M. Rolo, M. Sciortino, M. Anders and many other well-known
                        members of native and European society, whose names we have not space to
                        quote.</p>
                    <p>A reception will be given to ladies this evening at Idris Pasha Ragheb’s
                        house, and to-morrow there will be a reception at the house of the fortunate
                        bridegroom. Our most hearty congratulations are duo to the young married
                        pair and to their distinguish- ed parents.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Menis” arrived at Malta on Monday morning, homeward bound. The S.S.
                        “Seti" arrived at Liverpool yesterday morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN CABLE RATES. IMPORTANT REDUCTION.</head>
                    <p>The recent negotiations between the Egyp- tian Government and the Eastern
                        Telegraph Company have led to a decision to reduce, in principle, the cable
                        rates to England from 1s. 5d. to 1s. per word. This decision is not
                        officially announced, and the date of the coming into force of the new rate
                        is not yet known. The last reduction was on July 1, 1904, when tho rate was
                        reduced from 1s. 7d. to 1s. 5d.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Mr. Maximoff, Russia Consul General and Diplomatic Agent, paid a visit to
                        H.E.the Governor this morning, previous to his ap- proaching departure for
                        Cettinge.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Maximoff leaves Alexandria on Friday next by the S.S. "Tsar" for
                        Constantinople.</p>
                    <p>His successor,-Mr. Smyrnoff, is expected to arrive here about the begining of
                        May.</p>
                    <p>The portrait of Lady (Eldon) Gorst has been painted by Professor von Herkomer
                        and will be exhibited at this year’s Royal Academy. The wife of the late
                        Financial Adviser to the Egyptian Government is represented in an evening
                        costume of some scarlet fabric.</p>
                    <p>Among the departures for Europe Turday by the S.E. “Schleswig” were Lady
                        Elwin Pal- mer, Lady Bisset, General Fred Lance, C.B., Major and Mrs.
                        L’Estrange Johnstone, Hon. Mrs. Ivor Guest, Mr. Freiherr and Baronin von
                        Adelaheim, Hon. Mr. W. Colthorpe, Baron von Lodoreit, etc. </p>
                    <p>We hear that Mr. C. H. Walker, of the Ministry of Public Instruction, will
                        shortly be appointed inspector under the Sudan Adminis- tration.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="legal"><head>CHRONIQUE JUDICIAIRE </head>
                    <div type="item"><head>TRIBUNAL DE COMMERCE D’ALEXANDRIE</head>
                    <p>Livraibon de Titres Nouveaux R. Rutimeyer coatre la Sooiete Generate de
                        Bressage et de Depots rqat-on on absoaoe d’un texto formal de loi appliquer
                        par analogic an cas de vol on de perto de titres an portenr lea rfegles
                        ddicts par.le oode en vue de la perto d’uue lettro do change </p>
                    <p>C’cst oe qne pretend le demandeur qni s’a- dresse A la justice pour reclamer
                        la dAlivrenoe d’un scoond titreou d’un duplicata. Lo tribunal mixtede
                        commerce d’Alexandria vient de ddbouter M. Rutimeyer de sa de- mando et de
                        lo oondamner aux fraia Voici dans lean grandes liguea lee motifs invoqutfs
                        par le juge.</p>
                    <p>Sans avoir A relever les differences qui pen- vent exister entro le caraotire
                        d’ono luttre do change et celui d’une action au portenr, il oat de principo
                        quo lbs societbs par actions dont les titres sout an porteur he doivent,
                        oommo oo titro l’indiquo, qu’un titre. Par consequent, on cas de portq ou de
                        vol d’une action, o’est au porteur dventuel qua la societb qui l’a bmise
                        doit la payer. Pour carter les droits du porteur eveutuel il faudrait
                        btablir sa mahvaise foi. Dans ces oonditions la tnbonal no pout passer outre
                        au principo, alore mfime qne la society intbreasAe so bomenit, oommo bn
                        l’espice la Societb do Pressage et de Dbpdts, A sen rapporter A la decision
                        de la juatioe. va sans dire, copcndant, qne la Societe pout, sous sa
                        responsabilite et extrajudicuurement, moyennant les garanties qu’elle jagera
                        neoos- saires, deiivrer on duplicata et payer memo les coupons echus.</p>
               </div> </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <dateline>(Auiourd hui a midi et demie)</dateline>
                    <p>En sympithie aveo Lindros, lo marche a on- vert on hausse et les prix ont iti
                        pouases, maia oe beau mouvomont n’a pas tarde A suooombor sous le poids doi
                        realisations. On oldture A dcs cours sensiblemont les mCmes qu’hier.
                        Cepcndant, on remarqae de la hansso snr TAgrioole A 13 3/8, snr la Dalra A
                        27 3/8 et sur l’Anglo-American Nile A-5 7/8. Par contro. il a baissede la
                        New Bgyptian ASS et de la Brasierie dee Pynunides A 128 1/2.</p>
                    <p>On achte la Nationale A 27 7/16, Invest- ment A 2 7/32, la Land Bank A 9 7/8,
                        les Eaux du Cairo A 1,975 et les Tramways d’Alexan- dria A 147, tandis qu’on
                        vend la Banqnb d’A- thonoi A 117, les Banx d’Alexandria A 16 7/16 et la
                        Delta Light A 14 3/16. Lo nombre des transactions a 616 conside- rable.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light. - LIFT - Moderate Charge</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR PHARMACY</head>
                    <p>Kaur-El-Nil Square, CAIRO. Best Chemical Products. English and foreign
                        prescriptions carefully prepared by certificated chemists. Always in stock
                        large assortment of English proprietary articles &amp; specialties</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management. 11.11.906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRIVATE THEATRICALS AT BULKELEY.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday evening, Mrs. Lang Anderson gave a most charming entertainment in
                        Alderson’s Garden to her numerous friends, who number- ed between three or
                        four hundred. The pro- gramme consisted of two farces, with an inter- lude
                        in the shape of a violin solo, Mariani's “Abandono” exquisitely rendered by
                        Miss Euna Anderson, whose skill kept the whole audience in an enraptured
                        silence, which at the close gave plane to tumultuous applause. The guests
                        were invited for 9 o'clock, and shortly after that hoar the theatre
                        presented a most brilliant aspect, the ladies most richly gowned, their
                        dresses blending with the large number of military uniforms. It is quite
                        impos- sible to mention who were present. Suffice it to say that the
                        gathering was representative of British society in Ramleh and Alexandria.
                        The host and hostess, assisted by the Misses Anderson were indefatigable in
                        attending to their guests, all of whom were unanimous in pronouncing the
                        entertainment an immense success. The first play given was “Petticoat
                        Perfidy,” in which Mrs. Borton and Mrs. Gedge undertook the parts of the
                        rival ladies, Mrs. Montresor and Mrs. Norwood Jones. They were simply
                        perfect in their acting. As for Miss Lang Anderson, in the role of Juliette,
                        the French soubrette, she fairly brought down the house by her espiegle
                        rendering of the part. Her impersonation of the false Russian Princess was
                        excellent and was acknowledged to be fully up to professional achievement.
                        The second face, “A Regular Fix,” was quite as amusing as "Petticoat
                        Perfidy” and kept the aydience in roars of laughter. The principal part fell
                        to Mr. J. R. Bassett, who filled the rele of Mr. Hugh de Bras te perfection.
                        The part was somewhat trying, and called for a good deal of histrionic
                        ability. But Mr. Basset never faltered from start to finish, and his
                        vivacity and the aplomb with which he met his difficulties kept the audience
                        spellbound with amusement Mr. E.T. Pool was also excellent as the old
                        solicitor, and his “make up” was per- fect. In fact the "make up’s” were all
                        ex- tremely good, and Miss V. Aldereon, as the old housekeeper, Mr. Douglas
                        Allen, as the bailiff, and Miss E. Allen as Matilda Jane, looked (as well as
                        acted) their parts to perfec- tion. Mrs. Gedge and Miss Lang Anderson kept
                        up the high standard of acting they had displayed in the previous farce, and
                        the scene in which the former went into hysterics was a very capable
                        piecoeof acting. Mr. P. J. Byrne and Mr. G. M. Sharpe were equally good in
                        their roles, and from the begining to the end not one of the actors or
                        actresses showed the slightest sign of faltering, and there was never any
                        need of a prompter. Both the pieces could not in fact have been better
                        acted, and immense pains had evidently been taken to ensure per- fection.
                        After the dramatic part of the enter- tainment, an adjournment was made to
                        the buffet, and the pleasant evening was brought to a close with a
                        dance.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="letters"><head>LETTER TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                        correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit-
                        within certain necessary limites- free discussion.</p>
                    <div type="item"><head>AN INSTITUTE FOR CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—I was glad to seoethis matter
                        brought forward so ably in your leading article, and so forcibly seconded by
                        the writer of "Under the Mosquito Net.” Perhaps I may be allowed to trespass
                        on your kindness to tell of the results of two years’ work for the
                        inauguration of such an establishment in this city. The idea was forced upon
                        me by overhearing a young man remark that there are but two amusement to be
                        had here,—getting drunk and the frequenta- tion of the places at which, on
                        the authority of Solomon, the dead are unseen guests. Here was the truth
                        bluntly stated, and I was obliged to think the matter over.</p>
                    <p>As I generally act after having lain a-think- ing, it was not long before I
                        was in communi- cation with England regarding funds for a Young Men’s
                        Association. For a time I thought the ship I had launoched was going on very
                        well, but suddenly she struck on a rock and foundered. That rock was the
                        question of nationalities. I maintained that the association should admit
                        all Europeans, the people who had the money said it should only admit
                        Englishmen, I refused to have anything to do with it on their lines, they
                        refused the funds on mine, and things came to a stand still, where they are
                        likely to remain until the end of the ages.</p>
                    <p>Yet I did not despair. There is in Cairo, not a hundred miles from the old
                        Alhambra, a very fine hall, and I decided to try to persuade the person who
                        presides over its destinies to do something to stem the tide of vice and
                        intemperance, and draw young men from the saloons by providing healthy
                        amusement for them elsewhere. The answer I got was as follows : "If these
                        men are not going to be converted, and to attend our meetings and Bible
                        classes, they are as well in the saloons as here." There was nothing further
                        to be said; it was a case of “Ayt sint quod sunt, aut non sint,”</p>
                    <p>Thus a splendid concert hall, which might, under proper management, be the
                        means of keeping many young man away from the bqttle and worse, is allowed
                        to waste its sweetness on the desert sir, because, in the opinion of its
                        diredtress, a concert, like all other amusements, is of the Devil.—I am,
                        etc.,</p>
                    <byline>Henry C. Sims.  </byline><dateline>Cairo, March 10.</dateline></div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-1x.7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHAMBRE DE COMMERCE INTERNATIONALE. RAPPORT DU COMITE</head>
                    <p>Messieurs, Nos premifcrea paroles seront poor adresse un dernier adien A oenx
                        da nos mem bras qo nt dooddds depuis notre dernire AsssmblA amort a frappd
                        impiteysiblejnent dans no mgs ot nous avons perdu 7 de nos oollbgiie epnis
                        an an. Nous prions lean famnu de toevoir aveo nos regrets personnels, les
                        sent iants de oondoldanoe de la Chambre tout entiere.</p>
                    <p>Messieurs, Nous aronSl’honneur de voua rendre compte des thkyaox quo notre
                        Comitf a aooomplis de- puia notrq Aaasmblta G4nfcale d’A nil dernier. Bien
                        quVbetto Ipoqne nous fusions aortis da la premire eiriance, il reitait
                        snoore bean- coup A fairo poor qua, notre Institution (tt dtiiuitivement
                        assise et nous avons on A com- puter notre organisation snr bien des points.
                        Nous avons £ait de trAs seasibles progrea et, si nous no pouvona pas
                        oons'ddrer 6ire an bout do nos poines, s'il mate encore d'dnergiquea effort
                        A fairs, au moins arons-nous la satis- faction de voir la favour irolssante
                        aveo la- quello les particuliers et las administrations dcoutODt ou demon
                        dent nos avis. </p>
                    <p>Toutd'abord, nous rappcllerona oe qne nous lee Elutions qn’ils ddsirent voir
                        A certainee difnculWa qni les concernent ou oonoernent leur profession ne
                        sontpas aplanies oommo ila le vondraient, les abqs ns aont pas encore ri- p
                        rim is, les riformas se font attendre. A eela il y a de multiples raisons,
                        maia las principalee sont.</p>
                    <p>1. qub souveot ila gardent lours souffranoes plus ou moins caohfes et n’en
                        saisissont pas la Chambre.</p>
                    <p>2. quo les niclamationa les mieux justifidaa n'abouUssent pas du jour
                        atlendemain et par le seal fait quo le dfair de voir oesser las abas a
                        manifest.</p>
                    <p>3. las riformas si nombrenses et si desirables A apportar en bien des points
                        ne dependant pas seulement des efforts qni sont fiuts poor las amener, maia
                        sont le pins sou vent trie longues A obtenir et pins longues enooro A
                        etablir d6- finitivoment.</p>
                    <p>Pendant l'annee eooniee, la Comits a an la satisfaction do voir qne les
                        qnsetiOns qu’il a estuaires et soigneusement débarrassées de tout ce qui
                        n’Atait pas l’intdret gdndral, ont troovd anpris des administrations
                        compdtentes l’ao- cuoil favorable on les j nates sola dons Mon dovit
                        Attendre.</p>
                    <p>C’est ainsi qno sar la question dn Concor- dat priventif oe sont lee dtudee,
                        lee trsvanx et les vm ox qne yotre Comite a prison- tea au Gouvemement, qui
                        ont servi de bases aux decisions de lA Conference judiciaire ; que, sur la
                        question des billets d’aller et j+ tour, l’Atbiinistration des Chemins de
                        for en a promis loVdtablissement progressifet proohain; que le Corps
                        consolaire sans abandonner au- cune do tee prerogatives a oonsenti A uns
                        oon- sultation. otficieuse de la Chambre sur les liatos des dlectoba pour
                        les juges assssseurs. — Le Gouvernement prond on tris ririeuso conside-
                        ration et exabine lo moyen de satisbire au voeu dmis par la Chambre
                        rolativement A nne legislation .gendmlo concqrnant l’nsage des Poids ot
                        Meeuros, et nona esperona qne life obeervatioiir qne nous avons prison toes
                        relati- vemont A l’oxddntion dn ddcret dn 7 Janvier sur le droit de
                        sdjoaranr les qtufia d’Alexan- drie amdneront nne amodiation dee mesnres
                        edietees pour les rendre vdritablement oonfor- mes aux usages ot aux in tort
                        ts da Commerce. Enfin, nous avons en le plaisir de roir des oom- mercants en
                        ddsaooord fairo appel A l’arbitroge de la Chambre ; o’est 1A l’henreux
                        avinement que nous derons signaler et enoonrager do tout notre pouvoir.</p>
                    <p>Notre comite qni a tenu de nombrenses sdanoes n’a pas bornd ses travaox anx
                        ques- tions ci-dessus ; il a en A examber et A fiurfl valoir anprta doa
                        Chemins de fer nne recla- mation dcs importateura de menblei et en outre, A
                        dtudier diverses antres questions uotammont cello des droits d’aocise snr
                        les ootons filds, le drawback dm taboos, Etc. En dehors do oee questions il
                        en mt nne qui con- tinue A nous prioocuper oonstamment et qui a touto notre
                        attention, car elle a use im- portance capitate, o’eat l’extonaion mtoo de
                        notre Chambre, extension qni, hooreoaement, crolt sans oesse.</p>
                    <p>Depuis Pan dernier nous avons aoanis 184 membree noaveaux, oe qni porto le
                        total actuel A .prts de 500 et nous voua signale- rona qne les seals membres
                        da Comito ont amene, en jnb 1904, par leur propaganda 1 pcrsonnelle,
                        quaranto adhesions noUvellis. Ioi J nous ouvrirons nne parenthfcae pour
                        .vous odresaer nno nonvelle exhortation A nous amener de noaveaux ooUAgnoe.
                        Plus nous serous uombroux, plus nous nemos forts ; anssl nous insistons .
                        tout Dartiontitosment sur lo devoir qu’a chaoun ao nous de ro- crutor parmi
                        ses oorreepondanta et see emit de noaveaux membres de notre institution.
                        Nous ne morions trop insister sur oe point ot nous esperona qne notre appbl
                        aereentondu. Notre Bulletin eet dAplos en pins en favour et les articles qni
                        y paraiaaent soot si bte- reasanta pour le Commerce Gdofnd, qne de grands
                        Jotunaox d’eoonomie politique ne dedaignent pas de las rrorodnire. Nona
                        faisons appel A tons lea Membres de la Chambre pour qu’ila veuillqnt bien de
                        temps A autre prendre nne part effective A la ridaction do ces articles. La
                        pnhlioation de notre Bulletin, toujour* en progria, ripand vos noms et vos
                        firme^ non seulement dans le pays, maia dans le monde entier et de oela
                        aussi vous ne ponvez manquer de retirer des a vantages directs on indireots.
                        Nous evens aotuollemant 140 correspondents dont 129 Chambrea de Commerce qni
                        nous envoient riguliiremout d’inWressants Bnlletina.</p>
                    <p>La Biblitheque de la Chambre reooiten outre 39 joumaux et revuea venant de
                        toutoa les partiea du Moadeat tails an ton to* league*. Tous oea doonmonta
                        constituent nne mba Prioieuee de reDaoifnements poor qui vent bien les
                        consulter; nous appelons votre attend.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
