<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10-10-16</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-07-01</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN • GAZETTE, SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905.</head>
<div type=“item”>

<head>RUSSIAN, DISORDERS.</head>

<head>MUTINY SPEEADING</head>

<head>“ODESSA BOMBARDED.</head>

<head>THE POTEMKIN SURRENDERS!</head>

<p>Sevastopol, June 30.)

Four battleships, one cruiser and several

torpedo boats left here yesterday evening under

the command of Admiral Kruger, with orders

to sink the “Potemkin” if she refuses to sur-

render, and then assist in restoring order in

town.	(Reuter.)<p/>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Odessa, June 30.

The "Potemkin” began to bombard the

town at 11.30 yesterday evening.

The transport "Vecha” has joined the muti-

neers.

The central railway station has been burnt.

The funeral of the sailor who was shot tor

presenting the petition for better food, was a

great popular demonstration. There was do

disorder. Neither police nor troops were on the

route.

The burnt ships include the “Satatow” of

the Volunteer Fleet.	(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Libau, June 30.

The seamen here have mutinied and wrecked

the barracks. 'The Cossacks and artillery have

been called out and fighting has ensued, but

there are no details.	(Reuter.)</p>

<p>ODESSA, June 30.

Nii e vessels have been burned, but it is

believed that none of them were British.

Machine guns were used to clear the streets.

Two more regiments have arrived. (Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>St. Petersburg, June 30.

It is reported that a mutiny has broken out

at Cronstadt, and that the sailors have stoned

a number of officers. The troops at Peterhof,

where the Tsar is, have been reinforced. (R.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Washington, June 30.

The American Consul at Odessa telegraphs

that the fleet arrived at noon, and that the

"Potemkin” surrendered without firing a shot.

(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Odessa, June 30.

Martial law has been proclaimed.

The funeral of the sailor, whose death was

the cause of the mutiny, took place yesterday.

The police did not make an appearance.

Owing to the arrest of the sailors, the

"Potemkin” bombarded the town. The sailors

were released.	(Harm.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>THE “PERES VIET” REFLOATED.

Port Arthur, June 30.

The battleship “Peresviet” has been refloat

ed here.	(Reuter)</p>

<head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head>

<head>EARLY SETTLEMENT EXPECTED.</head>

<p>Paris, June 30.

It is announced that M. Rouvier will hand

a note to Prince Radolin to-day accepting the

conference, regarding Morocco.	(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Paris, June 30.

It is expected that the Franco-German inci-

dent will be settled next week.	(Havas.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>EGYPT’S JUDICIAL REFORM.<head>

<p>Paris, June 30.

The Chamber of Deputies has agreed to the

prolongation of the judicial reform in Egypt.

(Havas.)</p>

<head>EAST FINSBURY ELECTION.</head>

<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>

<p>The Plague.-Yesterday’s bulletin records

a fatal case at Port Said and another at

Ashmoun.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>A Foundling..—A lining new-born child

was found yesterday in the Haret el Balkatria,

and was sent to the hospital.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Public Instruction.—Mr. Dunlop will select

25 gentlemen whilst he is in England to add

to the staff of Government school instructors.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Course the Nile.--A credit of L.E.

6,350 has been opened for an examination of

the course of the Nile near the Upper

Cataracts.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Crown Casino.—A variety company makes

its debut this evening at the new theatre

which has been built at the Crown Casino,

Ibrahimieb.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the

Esbekieh district of Cairo during the night of

Monday and at daylight on Tuesday will be

poisoned by the police.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>French Comedy.— The Gonnet Levy-French

comedy company arrived at Alexandria this

morning and opens this evening at the Eden

Theatre with the 3-act comedy Mme Mongodin.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Suez Canal.— 9 vessels passed through the

Canal on the 28th ulto., 4 of which were

British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Turkish. The

day’s receipts were fra. 207,947.32, making the

total from 1st June frs. 7,714,139.54.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>SPEECH BY LORD CROMER.</head>

<head>THE CONDITIONS OF EGYPT'S

PROGRESS.</head>

<head>(Special Cable to the Gazette.)</head>

<p>London, June 30.

The Earl of Cromer has received the honorary

freedom of the Skinners’ Company. His lord-

ship, in replying to. the toast of his health,

declared that the Anglo French Agreement

had been of unmixed benefit to all who had

to deal with the local affairs of Egypt and

wore now relieved from the constant friction

and annoyance that haul marked the past.

The story circulated in the Press to the effect

that representations had been made to H.H.

the Khedive as to the presence of British

troops in Egypt was purely mythical. Four

conditions were necessary to secure the uniform

progress of Egypt : first, no hurry; second,

that Egyptian affairs should be kept outside

the domain of British party politics ; third,

that the utmost care should be taken not to

force Western ideas and exotic institutions

upon the Egyptian people before the country

was ripe for their assimilation; fourth, that

Egypt should continue in the future as in the

past to be governed in the interests of the

Egyptians themselves.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>(Reuter’s Telegram)<head>

<p>London, June 30.

The Earl of Cromer, speaking at the banquet

of the Skinners’ Company, dwelt upon the

benefit to Egypt caused by the Anglo-French

entente, and the valuable co-operation of the

Egyptian Government. His relations with the

 Khedive were most satisfactory.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Fatal Accident. — An Italian named Gae-

tano Flatino, aged 65 years, was run down by

a cab in the Attarin quarter yesterday. His

skull was fractured and he expired within a

few minutes after being conveyed to the

French Hospital.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>“Under the Mosquito Net.”—The notes

under this title which we usually publish in

our Saturday’s issue will not appear during

the next few weeks. The concluding portion

of the article entitled "The Principles of

Heredity" is also similarly postponed.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>

<p>At- Thursday’s meeting of the Legislative

Council, Ibrahim Effendi Abd el Al, the new

Fayoum delegate, was presented to the mem-

bers, and the proposal for the formation of an

Armenian Catholic community discussed. It

was • finally decided to have these proposals

printed and distributed among the members

of the Council

The Coined meets again on August 1.</p>

<head>PUBLIC WORKS.</head>

<p>Coal Imports. — From 1st January to 29th

June, 458,233 tons of coal were imported into

Egypt Wales sent 260,729 tons, Newcastle

87,864, Scotland 65,132, Yorkshire 26,876 and

other places 17,632 tons.During the same period

of last year the imports amounted to 482,943

tons.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Shepheard’s Buildings.—A short while ago

we informed the public that the shops which

form part of the buildings of Shepheard’s

Hotel were to be pulled down and larger ones

erected in their place. The work of destruction

has already been commenced and four of the

shops are being rapidly demolished.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Sudan Mines.—Application has been made

to the committee of the London Stock Exchange

to appoint a special settling day in Sudan

Mines, Limited—Further issue of 400 shares

of £1 each, 2s 6d paid (Nos. 1 to 200 and 401

to 600); and 3,896 shares of £1 each, fully

paid (Nos. 7,605 to 11,500).</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>LIBERAL GAIN.</head>

<p>London, June 30.

Mr. Baker, Liberal, 2,320, Mr. Cohen, Con-

servative, 1,552; in succession to Mr. Richards,

deceased. This is a Liberal gain. (Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>HOME CRICKET<head>

<p>London, June 30.

Kent beat Yorkshire by six wickets.	(R.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</head>

<head>ALEXANDRIA.</head>

<head>Oz PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED</head>

<head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer</head>

<p>& .HOTEL COMPANY.</p>

<p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO</p>

<p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>

<p>Agents at Alexandria:—</p>

<p>ALEXANDRIA RCNIil WAREHOUSE CO. LB.</p>

<head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>

<p>The best hallway home between Egypt and England is

VIAREGGIO. near PISA</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Mainline expresses stop. Pina woods, Sands Sea, bathing;

mild climate, English Pension, villa Shellay. Eve: home comfort  </p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>PUBLIC WORKS</head>

<p>Among varions credits that have been

opened by the Ministry of Finance we note

the sum of LE. 11,000 for the necessary

repairs to the Tewfikieh School, LE. 4,750

I or the construction of new agricultural roads

in Ghizeh Province, LE. 1,500 for repairs to

the Alexandria Mixed Court of Appeal, LFL

950 for the improvement of the harbour lights

at the entrance to the port of Alexandria, and

smaller credits for the purchase of the necessary

material for the sinking of artesian wells in the

mining districts, for the purchase of pomps,and

for the purchase of dog muzzles rendered

necessary by the new law relating to rabies.<p>

<p>Alhambra Theatre.—The excellent Italian

operetta company which is holding the boards

of this playhouse continues to attract large

audiences. This evening, the company will

stage Suppe’s popular operetta Donna Juanita.

To-morrow afternoon La Gran Via will be

given with the first and second acts of I

Grandtieri.</p>

<p>Seizure of Hashish.—On Wednesday and

Thursday last the Coastguards made seizures

of no less than 500 and 200 okes of hashish on

the small islands oil Agamc. It had been de-

posited on the islands by the smugglers while

awaiting an opportunity to pass it to the

shore, which is so well guarded that it is

now a matter of extreme difficulty to land

hashish. Before the transfer of the above

large quantities coaid be managed the Coast-

guards got wind of its concealment and

seized it.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>The Kanaan Affair.— The Native Par-

quet of the Minet-el-Bassal Kism has presented

its report to the Gouvernorat on the Kanaan

affair. We are glad to hear that an enquiry

has been opened on the subject, and hope that

it will be possible to discover who was respon-

sible for the extraordinary mistake made by

some one in the Native Hospital who ordered

the burial of the corpse without a proper

inquest, and noted the discovery of the body of

a Sudanese 1 Why not a Japanese or an

Eskimo ?</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>“King’s English.”—A very interesting ar-

ticle appeared a short time ago, showing the

great differences in the language, add espe-

cially of pronunciation, in different parts of

England, and a witty allusion was also mud?

to. '“American English.” It admitted, however,

that many modem Americanisms were in use

in the time of Shakespeare, but the universal

opinion- is that there is only one English

worthy 'of the nine, which is “King’s

English,” and special care is taken to keep

only to the form throughout all the Berlitz

Schools, [b. 2vt] .</p>

<head>THE S.S. “ST. KILDA.”</head>

<head>CREW LANDING AT PORT SAID</head>

<head>INTERVIEW WITH CAPTAIN.</head>

<head>HOW THE VESSEL WWAS SUNK.</head>

<head>(From our owmn Correspondent.)</head>

	<p>Sfiez, Friday.

As I advised yon this morning by wire, I

proceeded on board the Russian cruiser

“Dnieper” (ex “St. Petersburg”) In order to

interview the crew of the sunken British

steamer “St. Kilda,” but the officer on duty

absolutely refused tO allow me to see any of

the British offCoers, saying that it was strictly

forbidden. He added at the same time that

they would probably oe landed at Fort Said,

I understand, however, that the S.S. “St.

Kilda” left Hongkong for Yokohama on the

4th June, with a cargo of rice, cotton, and

hemp, and when 40 miles out she met the

Russian Cruiser "Dnieper,” which signalled to

her to stop. A "prize crew was subsequently

put on board, and next- day, when the crew

had been removed, the cruiser sank the “St.

Kilda” after firing ten shots. All the personal

effects belonging to the crew were lost. 41 of

the Chinese crew belonging to the “St Kilda”

were transferred to the Dutch steamer “Flores”

and landed at Singapore, while the British

officers were retained and brought here.

It is remarkable that' the “Dnieper,’’ in spite

of the long voyage and the heavy seas she en-

countered, has the appearance of having been

recently drydocked. She is heavily armed with

large and small machine guns, and fitted with

wireless apparatus. She is also flying the naval

flag. J

At about 9.30 a.m. to-day the Russian com-

mander paid an official call on the commander

of the British battleship "Canopus,” which was

duly retamed. The same offcoial calls were

exchanged later on between the battleship

“Goliath,” which arrived at 10.30 a.m., and

the “Dnieper.”

The battleship “Goliath” was reported by

the “Canopus” as approaching Suez at 7 a.m.,

>eing in wireless communication with her.

Finally the battleship "Canopns” entered

the Canal at i 1.15 this morning. *

The "Goliath” left at 1.40 this afternoon,

and the “Dnieper” at 1.55 for Port Said, where,

!, understand, she will take in about 300 tons

of ooal, not having taken anything at this

port.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>(From our own Correspondent.) ,

Port Said, Saturday.

After considerable difficulties had been put

in my way I at last obtained an interview

with Captain Jones, of the S.S. “St. Kilda.”

Captain Jones states that' the “St. Kilda”

left Hongkong on Jane 2 last. The Europ%p

crew refused to proceed to Japan and were

lauded at Hongkong on Jane 3 and impri-

soned. A Chinese crew was shipped and

the "St. Kilda” sailed for Yokohama on the

same day.

'On Jane 4 theRassian cruiper “Dnieper”

stopped and.captured the “St. Kilda,” putting

a prize orew on board. The ships proceeded at

a speed of nine knots in oompany into deep

water and at 6 a.m. on the 5th Jane an un-

successful attempt was made to sink the

“St. Kilda” by means of dynamite, after

the crew had been taken off. The Russians

then opened fire with their quick-firers and

sank the captured vessel with 16 4.7 inch

projectiles at 10 a.m.

The “St. Kilda” was bound from Rangoon

to Yokohama with a cargo of rice, cotton, and

sugar. The “Dnieper” had been warned of

her departure by Russian agents at Hong-

Jcong. After the vessel had been sank the

Chinese crew were put on board the S.S.

“Flores,” bound for Singapore.

The prisoners, who were thirteen in number,

were well treated on the “Dnieper,” being each

allowed a cabin and having perfect freedom

of movement abont the decks.

The commander of the “Dnieper”' refused

to receive the visit of the captain of H.M.S.

•’Lancaster” this morning. The Russian cruiser

carries eight 4.7q.f. -guns and 27 pieces of

smaller calibre ; she is bound for Liban and

the prisoners have received orders to disembark

at Port Said to-night.	.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>DANGEROUS GAMINS.<head>

<p>We wish to call the attention of the autho-

rities to the dangerous use of catapults in the

streets by European and Arab boys. These

gapiins appear to be supplied with up-to-date

weapons, and samples of their ammunition

which we have seen look most formidable,

small bolt heads and chopped iron bars being

the pattern most in favour. Every evening

parties of boys may be seen in the quieter

streets, especially in the Moharrem Bay quarter,

shooting at the small birds whioh settle on the

tamarisks planted'by the road. We imagine'

that the use of catapults on the public roads is

forbidden, and there can be no doubt about the

i'legality of their nse when missiles are fired

into gardens with disastrous consequences to

windows and grave risk to the eyesight of

those who happen to be in the line of fire.

Even the Mohamed Aly-sqnare is rendered

unsafe : the windows of St Mark’s Church

have repeatedly been broken by stones and

lamps of iron. Mr. Casimatis, of the Anglo-

Egyptian Bank, whom is also in charge of part

of the business administration of the church,

has made an interesting collection of ammnni-

tion fired into the windows and has captured

two of the culprits, whom he handed over to

the police—without any obvious result. This

morning the bowab of the church^w^s struck

on the left side of the face by a stone from a

! catapult which infiioted a very nasty wonnd.

Had the missile struck the unfortunate man

an inch higher he would probably have lost

the sight o^one eye. We hope that the autho-

rities will take steps to render the repetition

1 ot the offence highly dangerous to the offenders.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>

<p>The following is the programme . of the

Wagner concert to be given to-morrow, com-

mencing at 10.30 a.m. :—

1 Huldigungs Marsch.

5	Ouverture do Rienzi,

3	Proludo Lohengrin.

4	Entire dos dieux dana le Walhall do “l’or du Rhin.”

6	Ouverture doe Maitre-Chantours.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

<p>The Moss liner "Raineses” sailed yesterday

afternoon for Liverpool, via Malta, with pas-

sengers, mails, and general cargo, including

4,247 bales cotton.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>

Obtainable from every respectable Firm

In Cairo, Alexandria & The Sudan.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>CAIRO TO PORT SAID.</head>

<head>MENZALEH CANAL AND

NAVIGATION CO.</head>

<p>This new company, founded last year, hopes

to inaugurate the Port Said to Matarieh

branch of its service across Lake Menzaleh

about the middle of October. The Matarieh

to Damietta section will also be completed

soon after, dredging operations being now

hastened for that purpose. The distance

between the former two places is some 28

kilometres, and the same distance separates;

Damietta from Matarieh, where the lake service

works in conneotion with the passenger trains

of the Compagnie des Chemins de for de la

Basse Egygte to Mansonrah and at the latter

town in coincidence with those of the Sta’e

Railways.	c

In October therefore there will be a through

service between Cairo and Port Said by rail-

way and passenger steamer. For the latter

traffic there are two stern-wheelers for passen

gers besides two togs and six lighters for

the freight traffic. All these were constructed

in England, brought oat in sections, and put

together at Karpati, near Port Sail, by the

Anglo-American Nile Steamer Co., who have

entered into a contract to work the lines of

the Menzaleh Canal and Navigation Company

for two years from the date of inauguration.

The steamers have good accommodation each

for a certain number of first and second class

passengers, besides 15^> of the third class.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>GERMANY AND TURKEY

VERSUS

ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST.

BY W. M.</head>

<p>THE DANGER

(Continued.)—^

-The great line that runs tike an artery

rom Constantinople to Konieh is to be carried

on across the Taurus to branch off eastward

to Bagdad and Koweit, southward to Aleppo

and the Syrian system, is a military line par

excellence. Its two branches will one day aid

the German Empire to strike Britain in Aria

and Afhoa. German diplomacy in Turkey has

never ceased to keep the question of Egypt

and Arabia alive and to suggest the possi-

bility that a new Turkish army may

day inflict on Britain the Btroke of Exoatibnr, \

from whioh there is no recovery, cleaving in 1

twain the Empire withont the slightest inter

ference on the part of the fleet on whioh

England’s hopes are centred.

The Turko-German Staff aima at nothing

less than an immediate advance on Egypt

by an overwhelming Ottoman army, should

war unhappily break out between Germany

and Great Britain after the comply., 0f

the Ottoman strategic tines. The snooessof

the invasion would involve the suppression of

the Mixed regime, the substitution of a dele-

gate of the Soltan for our enlightened Sovereign

and his British friends and advisers, while the

direoting power—which wonta not

its position too strongly -» would be the

German Empire. “ Delenda eat Carthago ”

and “ Unsere Zukonft liegt am Wasser"

have an identical meaning in Germany. Her

chief continental rival has been beaten down at

Mukden and Tsusima by her adversary’s ally,

and the Turkish. alliance. originally d—

against Russia or England may now be direoted

exclusively against the latter. Beware, England,

or the day of yonr overthrow will see this ful-

filment of the German dream and the wings of

the eagles overshadowing half the world !

Neither in the Suez Canal, which a few

merchantmen oould block to-morrow, nor in

the straits of the Dardanelles, impregnably for

tified by Von der Goltz and Brialmont against

all the navie&of the world, oan England

her future foe* Her influence in ^ypt^ her

share in the - Sudan, her domination in the

Aden Protectorate, Uganda, and East Africa

are doomed, and these lost, will not the decay

of British prestige lead to the loss of India

from internal causes, unless—

Yes, that will be the inevitable consequence

of Britain’s Egyptian and Arabian policy,

which has earned the frown of the Shadow of

Allah, unless l er people, bringing into play the

foresight and sagacity that , have made them

great, have reoonrse to the sole Remedies that

oan conjure the peril.

(To be continued).</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY CO.<head>

<p>A correspondent writes:—Apropos of acc

cidents on this railway, they are of almost

daily occurrence now. On Friday last the

Nesleh engine broke down as it was about

to leave for Fayoum ; another engine was

sent, bat never reached its destination, and

as no other was available passengers and

train had necessarily to wait until one of

the other branch trains arrived at Fayoum,

when -that engine was sent and succeeded

in returning home with its unfortunate com-

panions “hoars late.”

The Shawashna train on the same day

was never seen at Fayoum. A few days ago

a funeral party ordered a "special” for 3 p.m.

for Daire el Azab; they arrived and had to

sit in the train in the broiling afternoon

sun until 5.30 p.m., when the engine from

Lahoon took the train. No other was available.

Last year the traffic receipts were published

pretty regularly and always showed an increase.

It would interest many to know' why they

are now suppressed, as LE. 300 a month

will not cover the decrease of receipts, and

from what can be gathered it is likely to

be still more. It really is time the public

were better served and these directors were

stopped Splaying at railways,” for I am told

that the native who is “running the show” at

the moment, seising the moment'of chaos,

actually threatened to resign “playing at

puff puffs” unless he got more pay, and, in

the face of this large and continued decrease

of receipts, I hear he&4So have an increase

of P.T. 200, so that the fiuce may continue—

“Great Soot 1”</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

<head>SPORT AND

PLAY.</head>

<head>SALVAGE OF “FOYLE” PROBABLE.</head>

<head>( From oui Correspondent. )</head>

<p>Suez, Friday,

The S.S. “Foyle” is now slightly making

water in No. 2 hold, and about 70 tons of rice

las been thrown overboard.

Owing to the fine weather, disoharge is

continuing satisfactorily, and up to the 24th

inst., over 800 tons of dry rice, and 500 tons

of damaged rice, haul been discharged into

lighters and landed at Perim.

It is now expected that the “Foyle” will be

shortly refloated if the weather continues

favorable.

The divers report that tittle damage is visible

but fear it is considerable underneath the

forepeak.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>THE MISSING SUEZ TUG.</head>

<p>Suez, Friday.

The lighters laden with rioe belonging to the

German steamer “Helene Riokmers” have been

seen lying at anohor 20 miles south of Ras

Gharib^ lighthouses, but nothing has been heard

of the tog. Strong northerly winds prevail and

a heavy sea is running in the Sum Gulf, so

it is expected that the tng has taken shelter.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>“TROTTER EGYPTIEN.”</head>

<p>The following is the programme of the fourth

day’s racing at the Hippodrome, Round Point,

which takes place on the 22nd inst:—

Prix de Hadra.—P.T. 700 (400 200 100).

Pour chevaux ambleurs (Rahouan) atteles on

months. Eprenve nniqne—4 tours de piste

2364 metres—Entree P.T. 50.

Egyptian Maiden.—P.T. 6.000 (3.000-1.500-

1.000-500—Poor ohevaux arabes et indigenes

mf Jen (qni n’ont jamais gagne de premier

prix)—En denx dpreuvee 3 tonrs de piste 1784

metres. Entree P.T. 500—(Cette conrse am*

lien s’il y a an moins 6 engagements).

Prix de la Promenade.—P.T. 300 de Sweep-

stakes. Poor cbevanx de la m®me dearie

attelei en paire A des voitnres americaines A

qnatre rones caontchontdes. Pour ohevanx

de tons pays. Seront exolns lea trottenrs de

conrse. Le.ler reoevra an objet d’art et le

65% sur les entrdss. Le 2me le 35%—

Eprenve nniqne.—Distance 4 tours de piste

2364 mdtres.

Grand Handicap International. — P.T.

5.000 (3.000 1.000 700 300) En 2 eprenves—

Pour tons chcvaux de Ire, 2me, 3me, 4rre

classe avec rendementi de distanoe anivant

la vitesse opnstatde en Egypte. Les ohevanx

qni n’ont pas de vitesse constatde partiront

scratch. Distance 3 tours de piste 1.780 m.

minimum. Entree P.T. 300.

Conditions G£n£rales.—Les courses sont

sonmises aux rdglements da Trotter Egyptian.

Les inscriptions seront oloeee le 15 juillet

A 4h. p.m., et devront Stre adressdes avec le

montant des entries an Seordtaire du Trotter

Egyptian, Mr. O. della Marra, Rond-Point, ex

Vdlodrome, Alexandria</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>The Rev. F.'^B. N. Norman-Lee, S.O.F., and

Mn. Norman-Lee are leaving on the 4th inst

by the P. & 0. “Egypt” for England. Mr. and

Mn. Norman-Lee take tins opportunity of

thanking their numerous friends for their kind

enquiries and sympathy daring Mrs. Norman-

Lee’s severe illness. Mr. Norman-Lee will be

away for four months and daring that time his

duties at Alexandria will be performed by the

Rev. Arthur H. Manning, acting chaplain to

the Forces, who is staying at the Miramare

Hotel, Ramleh.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>A cable from London states that Baron de

Knsel Bey, manager of the Egyptian Tnut

and Investment, Limited, has left for Egypt

viA Brindisi, and iB dne at Alexandria on

Wednesday next</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Dr. Warpoek, medical superintendent of Ab-

bassieh Asylum, left Egypt yesterday for

England on three months’ leave of absence.<p>

<p>Mr. S. G. Violate left Alexandria to-day for

a short holiday in Greece,</p>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
	    <div type="page" n="7"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905.</head>
<head>OUR LONDON LETTER</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
<dateline>London, Jane 23.</dateline>
<p>At Ascot, yesterday, the leading event was the
Plate, which, in the early years of her marriage,
was named after the Queen Alexandra that is,
and it would seem, with the happiest results.
"Racing,” King Edward’s great-grand-uncle,
the Duke of Cumberland, is said to have re-
marked, "languishes for want of support from
the Crown and aristocracy.” So he went a-
racing, with "the best stock, the best blood,
and the most numerous stud in the kingdom.”
Later on, the Ascot he virtually made felt
the influence of the “added money” of the big
gate meetings. The Alexandra Plate was the
first instance, on classic ground, where £1,000
was added to the stakes. True, the race was
inaugurated by the victory of Count de La-
grange’s Fille de l’Air, so named after a fairy-
tale by Cogniard Freres, which was drawing
all Paris to the old "Fol. Dram.” “But since,”
remark the Earl of Suffolk and Berkshire and
Mr. W.G. Craven, "the wealth and liberality of
the Royal Meeting have increased pari passu."
Twenty years ago, these authorities could
aver, "all that is most excellent in horseflesh,
and most ambitious in ownership, is annually
attracted to this favoured spot.” The favored
spot has lost none of its attractions since 1886,
and the brillianny of the era which the writers
dated from the founding of the Alexandra
Plate has, assuredly, suffered no eclipse.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>The most effective and artistic incident of
the Royal trip down the Thames on Saturday,
when the Prince of Wales inaugurated the
London County Council steamboat service, was
the skillful display of the Prince of Wales’s
feathers in water by the Metropolitan Fire
Brigade on their fire float. The pretty device
was exceedingly well’ reproduced. An unsa-
tisfactory circumstance of the trip was that the
Prince allowed himself to be so closely surround-
ed by his friends on the “King Alfred,” that the
crowds on the Embankment and on the bridges
had the utmost difficulty in distinguishing His
Royal Highness.</p>
<p>The principle on which Civil Lis; pensions
are granted is sometimes hard to understand.
There is, happily, no difficulty in approving
Shat just published. The names which have
called forth official bounty are either great
names or names associated with solid, benefi-
cial, But alas ! unremunerative work. J. G.
Frazer, le Neve Foster, Yorjf Powell, and
Freeman : under these cognomens the educa-
tion and well-being of mankind have been
furthered. So in a smaller degree with the
others mentioned in the list. But, though
satisfactory, it is a sad record. To many of the
pensions the phrase “straitened circumstances”
is added as a reason for the giving. Astronomers
and physicists, men who have given -their lives
to history and research, die without monetary
reward for their services, leaving their families
in such a condition that a hundred pounds
from the Civil List comes as a real blessing.
Supposing, for instance, that Professor York
Powell had devoted his great gifts to commerce
or finance, he would perhaps have died a
millionaire ; certainly his daughter would no£.
have struggled with “inadequate means of
support." It is to such cases that Civil List
pensions are properly applied.</p>

<p>The great Indian controversy is over, and
Lord Kitchener has scored a great victory.
The anomalous position of the Commander-in-
Chief, which brought about the regrettable
possibility of his resignation, is a thing of the
past, and Mr. Brodrick was able yesterday to
make the important and welcome announce-
ment that Lord Kitchener will in future have
a free hand in the management of all the mili-
tary combatant services. It would have been a
serious calamity for India had the outcome
been any other. Glad as we should and shall
be one day to have the benefit of that master-
mind in the organisation of our own military
affairs, it is a matter of greater urgency that
the work so well begun in India should first be
accomplished. The details of his reorganisation
scheme Mr. Brodrick also laid before the
House of Commons. It entails a considerable
expenditure, but the consideration that it will
not only increase and improve the Indian
Army, but render it independent df home
probably disincline him to attempt any settle-
ment of the Norwegian difficulty.
If Swedish Princes can recover them the
affront to their dynasty, and on of them
should be asked to accept the Norwegian
Crown, there are younger sons of the King
who might suit The Crown Princess of Den-
mark, a Swedish Princess by birth, also has a
son or two who could be spared for a situation
worthy of acceptance.</p>

<p>With a courtesy and a touch of sentiment so
characteristic of the Japanese, acknowledgment
of subscriptions to the Japanese Soldiers’ and
Sailors’ Widows and Families Fund is made in
very graceful fashion. A correspondent for
wards his receipt for my inspection. It includes
an acknowledgment from the Treasurer of the
Red Cross Society of Japan, a printed note in
Japanese, and a pretty little lacquered cup
wrapped in a silk handkerchief and forwarded
from Tokio in a sandalwood box tied with
green silk cord. The cup constitutes a charming
'souvenir of the gratitude of our Eastern allies.</p>

<p>Whether war correspondence is declining or
not as a permanent profession, it seems to be
the quickest way to prominence. The eldest
son of the late Sir Ellis Ashmead-Bartlett has
beer through a tolerable slice of the Japanese
war, and watched the siege of Port Arthur with
General Nogi. After the surrender he came
back through the States, and lectured to many
military and civilian audiences, one of his
marked successes being at West Point Academy,
for the benefit of us here at home he lectures
on Monday afternoon at the United Service
Institution, accompanying his remarks with
photographs of his own taking. And soldiers of
an older generation may not be disinclined to
earn something from this enterprising junior
of twenty-four.</p>
<p>The Prince of Wales, on his arrival at
Cardiff on Friday of next week, will drive
straight to the Castle, ,the Marquis of Bute’s
magnificent residence in the centre of the town,
where Lord Bute will entertain him at lun-
cheon. In the afternoon His Royal Highness
will lay the foundation-stone of the new Uni-
versity College in Cathays Park, and later will
attend the graduation ceremony. The Prince
will be the guest on Friday night of Lord and
Lady Windsor at fit. Fagan’s, their seat just
outside Cardiff, where a distinguished party
will be invited to meat him. The functions on
Saturday include the conferring on the Prince
of the freedom of the borough, followed by a
municipal banquet, and he will leave Cardiff
for’ London the same day.</p>
<p>The finding of the court-martial upon the
submarine disaster is satisfactory in so far 88
it acquits Lieutenant Candy and the other
survivors of all blame ; but unsatisfactory, and
necessarily so, because it was found impossible
exactly to determine what brought about
A 8’s loss of trim and inability to answer the
helm at the last. Only the dead helmsman,
probably, could have cleared up one doubt. It
is certain that the submarine somehow got out
of trim, owing to some shifting of weight,
either on the part of the crew or by the ad-
mission of water. But it cannot be known
whether the horizontal diving rudders really
were put hard up in good time to counter-
act the forward dip, as Lieutenant Candy
ordered. They were found hard up finally, but
may have been put so too late. A blunder may
have been made earlier and the rudders put
down instead of up, or they may have been in-
adequate to counteract the loss of trim. These
seem to be the alternatives, and both raise
questions as to the delicate stability of these
ships which call for farther expert investigation.</p>
<p>It is perhaps better for all parties that the
Norwegians declared their views openly before
the marriage of Prince Gustavua Adolphus.
The Royal bride and bridegroom, with relatives
on both sides, now know what not to expect,
and will* not be obliged to include Norway in
their tourist programme, or to waste civilities
on people who do not wish to see them.</p>
<p>The separate Crown of Norway would not
be worth the acceptance of any Prince of
standing, were it not that the existence of
a Republic in northern Europe might lead
to considerable awkwardness, and weaken the
monarchical principle neighbouring countries
It remains to be seen whether one of Berffa-
dotte’s Swedish or Danish descendants will be
able to adjust matters, less to benefit the self-
assertive Norwegians than to maintain the
prestige of the Royal caste.</p>
<p>Prince Charles of Sweden, third son of King
Oscar, is forty-four years of age, and is married
to his kinswoman, Princess Ingeborg of Den-
mark, who is twenty-seven. They are a cheer-
ful, sensible couple, and would make a good
King and Queen. Prince Eugene of Sweden,
King Oscar’s fourth son, is forty years of age
unmarried, and has artistic tastes which would

their last phrase. Except for this, and for the
men who go out at the end of each act and
won’t return in time for the beginning of the
next, there is nothing at all to complain of the
opera. Between acts there is, of course, a
regular babel of chatter, and some of it is so
funny, especially this week when the Londoner
points opt to the country cousin all the great
folk present, and the country cousin is quite
satisfied, never thinking that the people pointed
out are at Ascot and their boxes occupied
by friends. After all, the country cousin is
gratified, and no one is a pin’s point the worse.
One wonders what the real people would think
-could they see those pointed out for them!</p>

<p>The docking of a ship at Portsmouth is gene-
rally looked forward to by the dockyard
‘‘mateys” as an excellent opportunity of obtain-
ing some good fishing. About a foot of water is
always left in the dock for cleaning out, and
the fish can he easily seen swimming about un-
able to escape. Last Saturday at one of the
docks quite a number of bass were - discovered
by the dockers, and much amusement was
caused by the trantic efforts of the men en-
deavouring to comer the fish with spikes and
brooms. It takes an expert in this kind of fish-
ing to land a prize successfully, but on this oc-
casion about half-a-dozen large fish were caught
Quantities of oysters were also gathered by
some of the men from the bottom of the vessel
docked.</p>
<head>ARMY AND NAVY</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
<dateline>London, June 23.</dateline>
<p>My readers will regret to learn of the
death of Colonel E. H. Burney, C.B., who ,
retired a few months ago from the command
of the 2nd Battalion Royal Berkshire Regi-
ment, at Alexandria. Colonel Burney,. who
was in his 44th year, was visiting Paris
when he contracted his fatal illness. He saw
service with the Royal Berks in the Egyptian
War of 1882, and commanded the 2nd batta-
lion in the late South African War.</p>

<p>Lieutenant B. G. Bromhead, Royal Berks
Regiment, has been ordered to embark for
Egypt on the 14th prox. to join the 2nd Bat-
talion, on absorption. He recently returned
home from the Cape, where he did duty for
three years with the South African Consta-
bulary.	</p>
<p>Major H. B. Mainwaring, Lincolnshire Regi-
ment, has left the 1st Battalion at Se-
cunderabad, and taken his retired pay, after
a little over 27 years’ service. Major Main-
waring got his first commission in February,
1878, ways promoted captain in 1884, and
major in. 1896. He was in Kitchener’s expedi-
tion to Khartoum and was present at the
battles of Atbara and Omdurman (mentioned
in dispatches, 4th class Osmanieh, British
medal, and Khedive’s medal with two clasps).</p>

<p>The Rifle Depot at Winchester is to be
maintained at its present establishment
Curiously, whilst other regiments have a
difficulty in getting recruits the "Green-
jackets” have none.</p>

<p>It has been decided, says a contemporary,
to discontinue the carrying of the revolver in
civilised warfare. In the South African war
the drivers of the R.H.A., and the R.HA. dri-
vers of transport, staff sergeants, farriers, and
others were served out with Webley revolvers.
These were only carried for a short period,
when they were relegated to the kit bag.
Offioers who served in that campaign say that
however useful the six-shooter is in savage
warfare—and it is a very good weapon for rough
and tumble fighting—it is useless for oivilised
warfare where fighting is carried on at long
range. It. is now proposed to replace the
revolver by a light carbine. Farriers are still to
carry the Webley for shooting horses.</p>

<head>SOME ERRORS OF ARTISTS.</head>
<p>In an interesting article on “Artistic In-
congruities and Anachronisms, ”u» “Chambers’s
Journal,” reference is made to a picture,painted
about the eighteenth century, in which Abra-
ham appears ready to sacrifice Isaac with a
loaded blunderbuss. This antedated the use of
firearms by more than three thousand years.
Pictures are knoWn of the Israelites crossing
the Red Sea armed with muskets and other
weapons of offence of comparatively modern
date.</p>
<p>It is in the matter of costume that the early
painters found such a stumbling block. In the
Edinburgh National Gallery is a picture in
which Pharaoh's daughter and her ladies are
arrayed in the long-waisted bodices and hooped
skirts common to' Europe in the sixteenth
century. In another picture of the same date,
representing “Joseph and his Kindred in
Egypt,” which is hung in the National Collec-
tion in London, there is no trace of the
distinctive feature of Egyptian architecture
about the buildings ; they are all Italian in
type. Note, again, another picture by,Paolo
Veronese in the same gallery, "The Family of
Darius at the feet of Alexander after the
Battle of I88U8.” Again we have these pointed
waists and enormously distended skirts, which
are certainly incompatible with an event which
occurred- in the year 333 B.C. The artist was a
Venetian, and he drew the Venetian costumes
of his own period, 1528-88.</p>
<p>Raphael, like so many others, drew his
Madonnas, his saints, and his martyrs from
Italian models, and clothed them in contempo-
rary Italian costume, giving the figures as a
background the scenery with which he was so
familiar. It was only when travellers came to
visit the Holy Land, and saw the people there,
unchanged in sentiment, habit, and customs
for centuries, that a few came to realise that
the pictures were wrong.</p>

<head>A MODERN SACRIFICE TO ANCIENT
GODS.</head>
<p>It has been calculated, according to “Engi-
neering,” that a storage capacity of two mil-
liards of cubic metres^ or two thousand million
tons, is required to convert each million acres
of the land of Egypt from flood to perennial
irrigation. Hence the problem is, to supply
reservoirs capable of storing four milliards of
cubic metres of water. The Assouan reservoir
at its present level stores one milliard of
cubic metres, leaving three milliards yet to
fie retained, if it bad not been for the senti-
mental outcry of certain European archaeolo-
gists, to whom the preservation of a ruined
temple, which most of them had never seen,
was of more interest than the welfare of
millions of their fellow-oreatures, the Assouan
reservoir would now be of twice its capacity,
and another half-million acres rendered able
fa produce the long-stapled Egyptian cotton
which is so greatly in demand, As “Engineering”
expresses it, the fellaheen cried to the Govern-
ment for bread, and it has given them stones,
in deference to the withes of a few foreign
antiquaries. However, the fault is now com-
mitted; Egypt is poorer by 15,000,000, but
retains a useless pile of half-submerged ruins.</p>

<head>AGARD’S INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES</head>
<head>AND TRADE MASKS REGISTER. -</head>
<p>A useful business directory containing addresses
of all important business firms of Great Britain
the Continent, and Egypt. Circulating all over
Europe and America. Price—One pound Sterling.
Poe=st Free.</p>
<head>AGARDS INTERNATIONAL HOTEL
GUIDE</head>
<p>sent poet free to all first class Hotels
throughout Europe, America, the Colonies and
Egypt. The beet reference book for traveller.</p>

<p>ADVERTISING AGENTS.—The best public
a Advertising sites in Alexandria belong to
G. Vestri & Co., Advt Agents, St Catherine’s
Square. Special rates for permanent clients.
Moderate terms. Prompt despatch.
26642-81-12-906</p>
<p>ARABIC LESSONS given by an'Bgptian
H tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Snefik,
“Egyptian Gazette’^ offices.	25888-
25888-</p>
<p>APPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German,
ax. to the Berlitz Schools, Alexandria (26,
Rue de l'Eglise Copte  Cairo Sharia Kamel),
Most rapid method Trial lesson free. Evening
classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per month.
23069-30-9A-906</p>
<p>AMERICAN MANUFACTURER’S Agency
ax. wishes to advise having reoeived a fresh
consignment of Roll-top Desks, Morris Chairs,
Sewing Machines, Refrigerators, Typewriters and
various other American goods. No. 7 Rne de
l’Anoienne Bourse.	25878-2-5 906</p>
<p>BLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9, No. 7
A> £11. W.T. Emmons, 99 Rue Attarine,
Alexandria, Address, Post Offioe Box 35.
30-6-905A</p>
<p>CHIEF ACCOUNTANT first-rate Cairo firm
'-J wants occupation after office hours. Apply
to this paper, XV. 348.	26185-3-1</p> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
