<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-11-07</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-05-15</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>ALEXANDRIA. MONDAY, MAY 15, 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">BREMEN EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS
                    ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, and SUEZ,
                    NAPLES, MARSEILLES,
                    GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON, ANTWERP,
                    BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,
                    EASTERN ASIA, AUSTRALIA Etc.
                    <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.
                        Peninsular and Oriental S. N. Company. Summer Rates will be charged from 2 May to 31 October. 
                        For the convenience of families and others,a large portion of each ship’s accommodation has been 
                        reserved for Egypt, so that Berths can be definitely engaged at once, as if the voyage wore 
                        commencing at Port Said. Plans can be seen at the Offices of the Company s Agents. 
                        The through Steamers for Marseilles and London are intended to leave Port Said after the arrival 
                        of the 11 a.m. train from Cairo, every Monday until June, and then every Tuesday. A steam tender 
                        will meet the train to convey passengers to the ship. Caledonia	 8 May 1 Arabia 	 6 Jane 1 Egypt	 4 July Moldavia	 15	„	Himalaya	 13	„	Britannia	 11	„ Macedonia	 22	„	Persia 	20	„	Caledonia	 18	„ Victoria ...	29/30	„	|	India	27	„	|	Mongolia	25	„	British India S. N. Company, Limited.
                    </p></div>
                <div type="item">MAIL AND PASSENGER STEAM SHIPS.<p>SAILINGS FROM SUEZ, LONDON and CALCUTTA LINE. Calling at Aden, Colorado and Madras Outward, 
                    and Marseilles(Ganoa and Plymouth optional) Homeward. Fortnightly Service in connection with 
                    the Uo’s Indian Mail Lines and monthly with the East Mail Line between Aden, Mokgassa and Zaneiwran. 
                    OUTWARD -S.S. Mombasa ... May 27	- HOMEWARD - S.S. Goorkha ... May 24 Queensland Line of Steamers 
                    between London and Brisbane. Calling at Colombo. Batavia. Cooktown, Townsville, and Rockhamptom. 
                    The S.S	will sail from Suez on about 	 1 SSteu 8UIKSM ::: SSISSE: ::: uMJIGadSK From Port-BaldM loot Homeward, 
                    and «I more Omiard. Second Ulaes. two third of In Cleee Fare*. Agent* at PORT SAID, for the London, Calcutta and 
                    Penriau r. tlf Y-inea, Mean*. Worm* A Oo. Agent* at I’OBT BA1D, for tho London and Quooneiand LUrttHi^k. Will* A oo.. 
                    Limited. Moaara. Tho*.Cook A Son and tho Anglo-American Hotel A 8te*d.-r company, CAIRO A ALEXANDRIA. For furthur particulars. 
                    Freight and apply to O. BKYTS *e Co. Agent*, Bui.	31-12-004<p>
                    <p>The British Express Steamers leave Port Said directly tho Indian Mails arrive. Passengers can go on Board tho evening before. The Fare remains as usual. For all further information apply to the Company's Agents, Messrs. Tnos. Cook & Son (Egypt) Ltd	 CAIRO. George Boyle, Esq	 PORT-SAID. Messrs. Haselden a Co	 -	 ALEXANDRIA. P. G. DAVIDSON, Superintendent P. & 0. S. N. Company in Egypt SUEZ.	ANCHOR LINE, LIMITED. C HENDERSON BROTHERS,) LONDON, LIVERPOOL AND GLASGOW. Booking Passengers and Cargo through to Ports in India, hnrope & America. First class passengers steamers. Hailing fortnightly from Snex, ^LJYMUTOOL8 8.8-“Britannia-	Jan. a | For CALCUTTA 8A -Poral.-	May 11
                    Orient-Pacific Line of Royal Mail Steamers. REDUCED SUMMER FARE8 FROM MAY TO OCTOBER INCLUSIVE. OUTWARDS to AUSTRALIA.	E.loon Fare.: from Po^d lo Oibr^Ur £3; Mareeille. £9, Liverpool UU sea route) £15; London (all sea route) £ 12 London v» Ntraein*. £15.5,0.  emberbng at Sail £2 more, 10 o|o reduction for officer, of Army o Occupation ud Government emptojfa. Through tickets issued to Hew-Iork (rii Olxegow). Faroe on xpplioaUon	' Agent* in Cairo, Moaara. Tho*. Cook & Son. Fort-Slid, Honn Cory Brother* St Co., Ltd. For further particular* of Freight or Faeeage apply to O. BKYTS St Co.. Suo*.	31-12-905
                    RJLS. ••Ortona- will leave Sue. about May IS. K.M.S. "Orontca will loavo Suo* about Juno 8. HOMEWARDS to NAPLES. MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH,; LONDON, TILBURY. , Porvaald to Naploe	tat Claa*. £11 SndClasa. £ 7 3rd Class, £4* Ret are tltkete oo tag*? leeoad. boi paroeogtre paying fall fare lo one direction allowed abatement of Id fare back If retain voyage be made within 4 month* of arrival or abatement of >0 o,o If return voyage be made within e mont baof arrival. Agent*. Onto :-Tboa Cook A Son. Auunxu i—R. J. Moaa A Co.—For all Information apply Wm. STAPLEDON & Sons, Pout-Said A Pobt-Txwvik (Sue*) S1-I2-9U*	^	Deutsche Levante-Linie. _ a‘B“ *“-a hmu,er Bteemibip*. Ik*a.nr UuoB-weekly teevtoe from , viA A.STWRKP A Malta, to Alkxandria and vioo-veraa, admitting ■	good* Irani nil the principal German iiatlway Qlauone on direct Bill of Landing l\nrA3!£A	to Aluxakdbu and all the principal pone of Egypt, Byrian Coast, eto., at tho £*VOQr*ble through raioe of the IlKUTaoHC Virner (traffic). ^	EXTENTED AT ALEXANDRIA. ■ r,.8 Chios bow on the berth loading will sail on or about the 11 May tot Botterdam A Hamburg
                    BIBBY LINE MAIL STEAMERS. Special Reduced Rataa During Summer Season.	li	BB. Patmci 16 May from Antwerp bonnd for Beyrout. ^	B.a, Argot	17 „	„ Hamtmrg bound for Beyrout. 8 B. Pyrgos	8 June „	.,	„	„ For tariff and partienlara apply to ADOLPHE 8TR08S, Alexandria, Agent. — ll-B-BOl
                    OUTWARDS to COLOMBO. I'UTICORXN. otc., and RANGOON. Departure* from Suoa s.s. Staffordahlro «.ooi ton*, learn about May It. S.S. Woroeatorahlra 7.141 tone, leave* abont Janet. HOMEWARDS to MARSEILLES and LONDON. Departures from Port Bald.	NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL. ALEXANDRIA.
                    S.S. Lancashire t.ut too* leave* about June It. is».S8fvs!B&ss8&	s^BSSGSSSESGB^^^TSSiS&P us	tun miACi cs rsx avixce. - onnrci: qaicis. - ounin hut all ruixi asb ctuiuu.	h-i<p></div>
                
                
                <div type="item">KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE. FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS. GREECE . TURKEY LINE. Express steamers leave Alexandria every Wednesday at 4 p.m. for PIR2EUS, SMYRNA,	FORT SAID-SAVOY HOTEL. NEW FEET-CLASS HOTEL, OVERLOOKING THE HARBOUR OPPOSITE OUFTOM HOUSE Op«n Mil tha year Found. — Wall-appointed Bar. M-ODUBA TM OBAUaaS. BPMOIAL 'CBBUB BOB BBBIDBBTB 11902-5
                    Vienna, Paris, and London.	PALESTINE - SYRIA UNE. Fast steamers leave Alexandria every Saturday at 6 p.m., and Port Said every Sunday at 6 p.m., for JAFFA (for Jerusalem), CAIFFA (for Nazareth), BEYROUT (for Damascus), TRIPOLI, ALEXANDRETTA, MESSINA, continuing in alternate weeks to LARNACA and LIMASSOL (Cypres).	red sea UNE. Steamers leave Suez fortnightly on Wednesday at 6 p.m. for JEDDAH, 8UAKIN, MASSO-	HOTEL BRISTOL. CAIRO. Full Booth, Hsotrio Light, oppotitv YiaWrvJ, Gardcas, Large Verandahs, Moderate Charges, iiHAH, HAT’ .B. Proprietor, This Hotel is beautifully fitted op and is in he mod central part of Cairo. Terms for pension tare at the rate of tan shillings a day. Special terms for officers of Army of Ooonpation.	24,882-81-10-5
                    SUAKIM direct Calls will be made at TOR (for Mount Sinai) as required. N.B.—Deck chairs provided for the use of passengers, excellent cuisine and table wine free. Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at the Company’s Agencies at Alexandria, Cairo, Port Said, and Suez, or at Thob. Cook & Son or other Tourist Agency.	31-12-904	GUARDIAN ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED, OF LONDON. Established 1821.
                    The Moss S.S. Company, Ltd. For LIVERPOOL calllng at MALTA (Messrs. JAMES M088 A,Co., 81, James St, Liverpool, Managers.) •Amael*	Ton*.4.COO | •Mooria	 Ton*7.S00 I'Phlle*...-	Ton*6,900 i Tabor	Ton* 3,700 •ssr • : 88 1 Si::::::: :: IS* 1 Sm—~ ; ®l fta=S3SSS	Annual Income .......	£886,000. Total Funds	£6,200,000. Agents for Egypt and the Sudan - HEW AT & Co., Alexandria^
                    *8 Btngleg*14. Retara.—To kali, let, 04 Single, *8 furore, tnd. *1 Single. *4 Recare.—Relare ticket* available for eix S£^Mobr£ » SSt}.SJL Kw.m.cbuJnot on eppltaUoo. IMgo tetao by special agreement ouly. ^	^	LONDON ASSURANCE CORPORATION. 079	Establishment 1720. - Aeent,.- BANK OF EGYPT. Limited.
                    R. J. MOSS A Ca, Alexandria, Agencies.	N44M	ain a InaaranoH uMina
                    MARINE INSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED. ■ftabliifaoa 1811. Oofltol Jl,000,000, Bo*ova Find 48*1,000.	8MI-B04	LONDON.—Founded 1710. -Total sum Insured in 1803 £487,600,000. Agssti: EBON HtELLHR. Gslro. and BEHBKND Jk Co.. Alexandria. 16.1 .tit 1
                    1, wa Bresi Btm), IiOHDOF.-fctebU.h»a ll08.-ToW Jteml. we**a 4)0,000,000. 11.18.801	FoHsfo Imti el DOBS by Q. BKYTS & Go., AgocM,	NORTHERN FIRE AND LIFE ASSURANCE Coy. The onilsrsigned agents ore authorised to issue policies on behalf of the above Company.</div>
                
                <div type="item">CAIRO-KHARTOUM SUMMER MAIL SERVICE.
                    <p>Wednesday and Saturday p.m. depart Cairo	arrive 
                        "kondey and -Friday 7.M a-m. Rsvaisa::rts -Saodev 
                        and Wednesday	l.M pan. arrive Khartoum depart Thursday 
                        and -Monday	11 noon Hall delivered Khartoum. Sun. and 
                        Wednesday evening, and Cairo, Hon. and Friday evening. 
                        -Dining and Bleeping Can.</p>	</div>
                <div type="item">ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.
                    <p>IkooaroursD A. D. 1720. Chief Office: ROYAL IZOHANOl, LONDON, X.O FUNDS IN HAND EXCEED 	 
                        £4,500,000	CLAIMS PAH) 	 £40,000,000 FIBE	MARINE
                        P. HENDERSON & CO’s UNE.	Auuniu	 ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.	Aasxaxbua	 
                        Mr. J. B. OAFFABI. Oaiae	 Mr. J. B. OAFFABI.	Bsax	 Mr. OEO. MEINSOKE. 128M1M0I
                        (Electric Light.)	SALOON (Amidihipi) FARE £12.	(Latest improvements.) 
                        S.S. Mandalay 6000 Tons will leave PORT-SAID about May 11 for Liverpool. 
                        Peoc	5800	„	„	„	„	„ June 3 „ Devonport „ Irrawaddy 7300 to follow. 
                        Due in LONDON or LIVERPOOL 12 days thereafter. Apply WORMS & Co., Port Said and Suez. 
                        COOK & SON, (Egypt) Ld., Cairo G. J. GRACE & CO., Alexandria.	National Bank of Egypt. 
                        CAPITAL L. 2,600,000 - KESERVE (environ) : L. 862,000. Gouvemeor : 
                        But EL WIN PALUEB, K.C B„ K.O.M.G. Biige Social au Caere, Buccurtale d Alexandrie, 
                        Agenee d Auiut, Auouan, Benha, Beni-Buef, Ohibin el Korn, Damanhour, Payoum, Khartoum, 
                        Keneh, hlamourah, Mmieh, Port Said, Buahim Bohag, Tantah, Zagasig, Mulin (Coirs) et Umires 
                        (4 * 6, King William Street) </p></div>
                <div type="item">LA NATIONAL BANK OF EGYPT 
                    <p>refoit da puts h terme. fixat, fait das
                        Thos. Cook & Son,	aranee* et ouvre de eomptsa oonrante nr tin, valours el merchandise. 
                        Elle •‘ooeupe de 1'aehat. et de la venM d'effets nr I'Klrmngvr, de i'eseompte, ninsi qua de
                        lout** opuntions d* Banqo*. 51-12-904 (Bstpi), Lixmo.</p></div>
                <div type="item">HEAD OFFICE—LUDGATE CIEOU8—LONDON. 
                    <p>CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE - CAIBO, near SHEPHEARD'B HOTEL. Alexandria, 
                        Fort-Said, Suez, Luxor, Assuan, Haifa, & Khartum. GENERAL RAILWAY AND STEAMSHIP ACENTS. 
                        RANKERS. BAGGAGE AND FORWARDING AGENTS. Officially appointed & Sole Agents in Cairo to the 
                        P.&O. S, N. Co.	IMPERIALitOTTO^NI bank. Hud Orrio* re CONSTANTINOPLE. Ohi.f Aomoim: LONDON A 
                        PABI8. BRANCHES IN ALL THE PBINOIPAL TOWNS IN TUBKHT. Aa-ancles in Emt: ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO. PORT SAID</p>
                    <p>RESIDENTS IN EGYPT proceeding to Europe for the summer are requested to apply to ou*1 offices 
                        for information respecting their Passages, where steamer plans may be consulted and Bevths 
                        secured by all I*ines of Steamers to a 1 parts of the Globe; arrangement- can a so be made 
                        for the collection and forwarding of their	BANK OF ATHENS, LIMITED. BEU'S ASIA STEAMSHIP CO. 
                        and, Cairo, l omunuac^lo,.Smyrna. At Caodla and through.	WMkIr , UMmer	^ p^p,, OTTh*rBSk 
                        uml«t«ke.»U banking buelnea. la Igypi. Oreece. nudailo mrrymg Hall* from Auumu Is Ovrsss an* sic. 
                        InienaUon —* depomiei »5i« par ann. at sight i 4* 0,« tbs B, m Com aod vtoo-versa. 5£ r •	of f^*Lk 
                    </p> 
                    <p>Large and splendidly appointed steamers belonging to the Co. leave Cairo thrice weekly 
                        between November and March, for Luxor, Assouan and Wady-Halt* in oonneotion with trains 
                        de luxe to Khartoum. Moderate fares. PREIGHT SKRVICB. 8te*mers leave Cairo every Saturday 
                        and Tuesday for Aasonan and Haifa.	</p>
                    <p>Large and splendidly appointed steamers belonging to the Co. leave Cairo thrice weekly 
                        between November and March, for Luxor, Assouan and Wady-Halt* in oonneotion with trains 
                        de luxe to Khartoum. Moderate fares. FREIGHT SERVICE. 8te*mers leave Cairo every Saturday 
                        and Tuesday for Aasonan and Haifa.	</p></div>
                <div type="item">SUDAN DEVELOPMENT & EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED KHARTOUM Caibo Orrics, Bhajua Kabs-bl-Bh..
                    <p>Beautiful arrangement for tons in PALESTINE, SYRIA and the DESERT, lowost Rates arrangement.	
                        ^ ^ ^nipB(at u ^ ^	10-lMW	</p>
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer & Hotel.Coy.
                        Weekly departure during Winter Season by the
                        Luxurious First Class Tourist Steamers VICTORIA, PURITAN 4 MAYFLOWER,
                        Regular weekly Departure! to the SECOND CATARACT by the S.S. INDIANA.
                        THROUGH BOOKINGS TO KHARTOUM, GONDOKORO AND THKIWHITB NIlT.
                        Sturner, ud Dahabeahi for print* charter. Steam Tup snd Steam lannet-^ for
                        fBElOHT 1EBVICE ,T STEAM BARGES BETWEEN CAIRO ANO ALEXANDRIA.
                        Working in conjunction and under special arrangement with the
                        "Upper Bgypt Hotels Company."
                        For details and lUnatratod programmes apply to “THE ANGLO-AMERICAN NINE and
                        HOTEL COMPANY.”</p></div>
                <div type="item">OFFICES IN CAIRO: Sharia Boulac, "Grand Continental Hotel Building!."
                    NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD.
                    <p>Regular B.rrte.	and rraUht)
                        Bohleswig leavsi Ausamu 5 p.m. May 24.
                        Hohenxollern „	„	„ May IT, A U, Jane u, Jnly 8, k 18 etc,
                        Tha following ■ tenure sts Intended to leeve PORT SAID :
                        Hombwabd i for 3 re Si
                        isST”-'
                        la Nanas, Bssoa, (BnsaLTa s\ Bodthiswoi, lmnn
                        ! SI SKmnaa	“’r ::: “ r Js
                        I _ ! BaTSBN	SOM “ Z Z Z 1 I -
                        Odtwabd i for Oklae and dopes ->ta Buss, |	For Asetrelle
                        Anew Cozninto. Praam, BnroAmu. |	via Buss, Aon, Colombo.
                        SSSS."	Si	Tr r r r £ I S.t^w	22 ~--------JS
                        B0HAHHH0B8T	1111 _______ H	Jm. I DABHBTAPT	Mil J	Z Z Z Z I tSS
                        fob rcnraoM ruriiruu i»ir h hi huh at m
                        NOMDDEUTSOHER LLOYD •» Cairo, Els*aedtla, Mil Bald and Sosa.
                        OTTO STK3ZIN3, Asm is Cairo, Otoba Squabs.
                        O. H, ftCHOXLLEN, Aoxsr is Alszabdua, CJlaopatn lau,
                        Mn. TBOS. COOK A BOM (Bn* Us. ^^ECUUUB^aMSUXA Idea«, NMX«« t. Ml tejJMS
                        Austrian Lloyd’s Stsam Navlqstlen.
                        r
                        w^Jfcy'
                        i. 18	•• Cleopatra „ iTsllieh. | Jnnr 8	„ Oletfatra „ IhH.
                        Fortnightly SerVioe: Alexandria-Brindiai-Trieat«.
                        Steamer Uavee Alexandria on n ihosi 10th and Mth May.
                        Far Bast Line.
                        East African Line.
                        To AiM, McmbsHBi fcnittu, Stbt, Defcfos Bay, Derbaa iktu 4th May.
                        Syrian -Oyprns-Oaramanian line.
                        Btwmn lam Alexandria aa n ikeai 8th and 22th May.
                        Errs air .*virsR£sT*Sb3r.«;
                        of tha^Armr of*Oc *neaUon^and'tbat° faStUaf 0oT,rttM,a* offl.“U, Mutton,</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman Lines, Limited.
                        < Including Watoott A Lsarsnoi Lins,)
                        (tegular tailings from LIvtrpoelQlaifoirAntwsrj sod London to Alexandria. Fnqsasl Mdllafl boa Alas-
                        •rrtrlo to LfworpoM *"•* T«ni?or 'rbreuph fr»lgfct ••■t.. t0 Inland town. In Groat Britain alto to tha 0JJ.A
                        Ellerman B.8. Athenian expected from Liverpool. Swansea A Malta If dna on or about May 18
                        Westoott , Ore.-lee	,	„ Antweip. Lot don k Malta „	„	„	„	10
                        Elerm-n 8.8. Brsfamua now on’be berth for Livirpool will eail fir that port on or about 17lhinrt.
                        Fare first cam £l». accommodation amidebip.
                        . B. TAMWeCO AUrandrU £#*■• aatva.an.a.p
                        lines, limited.</p></div>
                <div type="item">CITY LINE.	CITY  LINES.
                    <p>MALTA, LONDON, COLOMBO A CALCUTTA.	' MAB8BILLE8, LIySpOOiTbOMBAT A KARACHI.
                        The undermentioned Km Clue Passenger Seamen wiU'ba diepatebed from Fort Bald 
                        on or ebont the following data, for r—
                        assetsas*. B.8. Cm or Coaiimi	May 13 I BSSSITtSsn-M.
                        SALOON FAMES1—Port Bald lo Malta *4.10.0. Marseilles, **.0.0. 
                        London or I.lrerpooL dlAlAO. Colombo, CairoUa.
                        Bombay or Karachi. *34.0.0. Special sate, for .teamen not carrying Doctor 
                        orStewudtaa For farther panlonlan apply H
                        CORY BROS. & Co., Ltd., Agents for Crry Line, Port Said ; W. 8TAPLKD0N & Bov, Agent*
                        for Hall Line, Port Said ; or COOK & Son (Egypt), Ltd., Cairo.	23783-28-8-905
                        Navigation Generate Italienne.</p></div>
                <div type="item">Societes Bennies Florio-Rubattino. - Services Postaux. - Departs de Mai.
                    <p>Los Jeudib 4, 11, 18 et 25 ft 3 h. p.m. direct ponr Mesaino, Naples, Livourne et QAnei.
                        Les Lundi 1 et 15 A 3 h. p.m. direct poor Brindisi, Bari, Anofine et Venise.
                        Le Mrbcbkdi 17 A 10 h. a.m. ponr lea escalea de la Syrie et Larnaqne.
                        Les Lundi 1 ot 29 A 4 h. p.m. ponr Port-Said, Snex et Massawah.
                        Les Dimanohb 7 et Lundi 22 A 5 h. p.m. ponr Port-Said.
                        Telephone Company of Egypt, Limited.
                        ('amo-AtiTureau T*aAraoaw.—Rato* a* follow, P.T. 6 for each 3 minolee, or fraction of 3 minutcai P.T. lo for
                        Alexandria, Si aiark'e Solid Inge,</p></div>
                <div type="item"> ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE COMPANY, LTD.
                <p>(8oci£rfi dks Entrepots d'Alexandrie)
                Bonded Warehouses
                IN ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, PORT SAID, AND SU£Z.
                Special rwwlcKil, foe clearing an.l fbewgrtlng and for a luggage an.1 paroel Kipreae Barrie.
                Goode delivered agalnei ovsh for account of ehlppera.	31111-1.8*03
                Messrs.</p>
               <p>HENRY J. MONSON & Co’s
                 NITRATE AND PHOSPHATE QUARRIES.
                 BILVXR MKDAL AORICTOLTinUl EXHIBITION, CAIRO, UN,
                 Worica «* t Kif t.Maaia, ■•bciaix and Luaor.
                 Head Office, Cairo. London Office 1®, Frachureh 8t. B.C,
                 Chemical manure, Lime, Cement, Plaster of Paris, Tile Paving and Fire Brick, Paints, eto. immm</p>
               <p>NILE COLD STORAGE
                  COMPANY. LIMITED._
                  PURVEYORS OF THE FINEST COLONIAL
                  MEAT, GAME, POULTRY, BUTTER, FISH, •*©., •iCs
                  The Company have opened a shop in the New Market,
                  CAIRO, Non. 39 & 40, where the goods imported by them can
                  be inspected and purchased.
                  IMMfteas. MS. r.MS,	</p></div>
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

