<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-01">December 1, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-05">September 5, 2016</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7285] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 5, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE TUESDAY SEPTEMBER 5, 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PEACE TREATY SIGNED. TSAR’S TELEGRAM TO LINIEVITCH. JAPAN CEDED ALL POINTS.</head>
                    <p>Portsmouth (N.H.), September 4. The treaty will be signed at five o’clock
                        this afternoon. It is ratifiable after fifty days. The Japanese expect to
                        leave tomorrow, the Russians on Wednesday.</p>
                    <p>(Later). 'The treaty of peace was signed this afternoon. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 4. The Tsar’s telegram to General Linievitch says
                        that Japan yielded to Russia's demands upon all the conditions. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Portsmouth (U.S.A.), September 4. The peace treaty will be signed tomorrow.
                        (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SHAH IN RUSSIA. BANQUET AT PETERHOF.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 4. Yesterday, at a banquet at Peterhof in honor of
                        the Shah, the Tear's toast expressed his desire to demonstrate personally
                        his pleasure in renewing his assurance of friend-ship and his best wishes
                        for the prosperity of Persia. The Shah replied, profoundly thanking he Tsar
                        for his cordial reception. He drank to iis prosperity and greatness.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO. ULTIMATUM EXPIRES TODAY.</head>
                    <p>Paris. September 4. The French ultimatum to Morocco expires tomorrow. (
                        Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TURKEY AND GREECE. RAPPROCHEMENT ANTICIPATED.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, September 4. Prince and Princess Nicholas of Greece have been
                        staying here. The Sultan showed them narked attention. This is regarded as
                        indicat-ing a rapprochement of Turkey and Greece regarding Macedonia.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EAST AFRICAN RISING. EUROPEANS MURDERED.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, September 4. Official despatches received here show that the
                        rebellion in East Africa is becoming formidable, and is spreading to
                        districts hitherto regarded as being loyal. The caravans en route for the
                        Great Lakes have been attacked. The Europeans in the region of the Ruaha
                        River have been murdered. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHOLERA IN EUROPE. CASES INCREASING RAPIDLY.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, September 4. Until now there have been in Prussia 66 cases of
                        cholera, of which 23 were fatal. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Berlin, September 4. Seventy cases of cholera have been notified in Prussia
                        and twenty-three deaths. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BARCELONA BOMB EXPLOSION.</head>
                    <p>Barcelona, September 4. Four persons were killed and about sixty injured by
                        the bomb explosion of the day before yesterday. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Vienna, September 4. H.H. the Khedive has arrived. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Commandant Lemaire, of the Congo Free State service, will probably return to
                        Cairo next January, and will, it is hoped, give a lecture before the
                        Khedivial Geographical Society on the regions which he has explored.</p>
                    <p>Mr. T. H. Marsden, cab-manager of the Alexandria branch of the Anglo-Egyptian
                        Bank, has arrived from England.</p>
                    <p>M. Girard, chief accountant of the Societe des Sucreries et de la Raffinerie
                        d’Egypte is expected to arrive by the French boat to day.</p>
                    <p>Mr. J. C. Maclaren arrived by the Austrian Lloyd boat yesterday.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death, which occurred last night at Mammern,
                        Switzerland of M. Aziz Georges Mabardi, a partner in the well-known firm of
                        Messra. Steinemann, Mabardi and Company, of Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>A native boy was found dead in a house in the Bab Sidra Barrani on
                            Sunday. This is only case of plague reported in yesterday’s
                            bulletin.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Boulac quarter of Cairo daring to morrow night and at dawn
                            of the 7th inst. will bo poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Editor in Trouble</head>
                        <p>The editor of "Al Khilas,” a native satirical journal was condemned
                            yesterday by the Saida Zeinab Summary Court to nine months imprisonments
                            with hard labour for diffamation of character.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Train derailed</head>
                        <p>A goods train ran off the lino hear the Matarieh Station on Sunday night
                            owing it is said to the driver having taken a curve at excessive speed.
                            Traffic was delayed till a late hour on Monday morning by the
                            accident.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"Reunion Des Familles" Society</head>
                        <p>On the occasion of the ninth anniversary of this society a grand “soirre
                            de gala” will be held at the Mex Casino on Saturday next, commencing at
                            9.30 p.m. The casino will be illuminated, there will be a display of
                            fireworks, and it will also be made the occasion of the last ball of the
                            season.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Lambs and Doves</head>
                        <p>One of our native contemporaries recently published an extraordinary tale
                            according to which Mansfield Pasha was hastening from England to
                            remonstrate with Mr. Moberly who had sold two lambs and some pigeons
                            belonging to the Chief of the Cairo Police. Though it referred to lambs
                            and doves the tale proved to merit the title of "a cock-and-bull
                            story.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Charitable Act</head>
                        <p>A slight outbreak of fire occur at 16, Rue Abou Dardar, Alexandria, the
                            other day bat was quickly extinguished. The damages could not be
                            recovered from the insurers, "La Polar” Sociere Anonyme d’Assurances,
                            Bilbas, but M G. Kaul. agent of the insurance company, very generously
                            subscribed the whole amount The house in which the fire broke oat is a
                            ladies’ pension which is managed by the Religious Sisters of Notre Dame
                            de Delivrande.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Firework Bxplosion</head>
                        <p>It appears that the name of the employe killed by the explosion of the
                            first firework at Ras el Tin on September 1 was Ali Awad and not Adb el
                            Meguid Effendi Hamdi, as we were first informed by the gouvernorat. The
                            deceased, an employe of the Army Stores Department, was sent to
                            Alexandria to light the fuses of the mortars from which the rockets were
                            discharged. He was literally blown to pieces by the banting of the first
                            mortar fired, which appears to have been overcharged at Cairo. Gellab
                            Wahba, who was also wounded, expired two hours after reaching the
                            Government hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"L'Union Artistique Francais"</head>
                        <p>The sixth performance of the "Union Artistique Francaise” will be given
                            at the Eden Theatre to-morrow evening, commencing at 9 p m. The first
                            part of the programme will consist of an orchestral piece, the waltz
                            “Eternelle Folie," and a pianoforte solo, “Trot da Cavalier,” played by
                            Mme Barabino, and this will be followed by the one act comedy entitled
                            Les Deux Timides. The second part will commence with the waltz, “Belle
                            capriciense” played by the orchestra, after which M. H. Tirinanzi will
                            give a flute solo, accompanied on the piano by M. Corbo, and Mme
                            Barbarino and her daughter of six yean of age will then play a
                            pianoforte duet. The one-act comic opera, A Clichy, will be played in
                            this part. The third part of the programme will consist of a violin solo
                            by M. Corbo, a pianoforte solo by Mme Barbarino, and the oomedy entitled
                            La Grammaire.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Pyramids</head>
                        <p>There are not very many spots in Egypt which have such an historical past
                            as the Ghizeh Pyramids, but hitherto residents and others desirous of
                            visiting the Pyramids have found it rather inconvenient in the way of
                            obtaining refreshments. It is therefore with very great pleasure that we
                            note the enterprise that has filled a long-felt want by the
                            establishment of a bar and restaurant there. Excellent arrangements have
                            been made for catering of every description at the “Pyramids” bar and
                            restaurant situated opposite Mena House Hotel,at the foot of the
                            Pyramids. One can obtain everything one requires to satisfy the inner
                            man here, at very reasonable, rates. A sure guarantee that all the
                            mineral waters, wines, spirits, beers etc. retailed at this bar and
                            restaurant are of the best quality, is the fact that they are supplied
                            by Mr. N. Spatis, the well-known merchant and mineral water
                            manufacturer.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of
                            the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with
                            the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services
                            of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring
                            information on trade matters generally, including the question of
                            appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is
                            obviously in the interests of all British traders hero to become
                            members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription
                            is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy
                            of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain
                            farther particulars from our London office, 86 New Broad-street, which
                            acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES AFFAIR. PROPOSED GENERAL MEETING.</head>
                    <byline>(From our London Correspondent).(By Telegraph)</byline>
                    <dateline>London, Monday.</dateline><p> Sir Ernest Cassel has met the managers of the
                        Sucreries et Raffineries d’Egypte in consultation at Paris, and Maltre
                        Carton de Wiart was also present The question which the meeting was called
                        together to decide was the possibility of convening a meeting of
                        shareholders, but the matter was left in abeyance, as it is uncertain
                        whether Egyptian law permits the summoning of a shareholder’s meeting in
                        such a manner. It is possible that the sole right of calling together such a
                        meeting rests with the liquidator appointed by the Cairo courts. The
                        conference was adjourned until to-day.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASSOUAN AND LUXOR. HOTEL NOTES.</head>
                    <byline>(From our correspondent.)</byline>
                    <dateline>Assouan, Sunday.</dateline>
                    <p>The new hotel at Luxor now being erected by the Upper Egypt Hotels Co., is
                        situated on the river bar k just before Mr. Irsingers’ house, known to most
                        tourists as the "Dutchman's castle.” The hotel is being built on a site
                        covering eighteen teddans. There will be about 50 rooms, 24 of which will
                        have a bathroom attached. There is also a magnificent ball, and two large
                        covered verandahs, one of which faces the river. Tourists will also find a
                        large billiard room 'and some fine tennis courts. The water supply has also
                        received special attention, an artesian well having been bored for the
                        exclusive use of the hotel. This fine hotel will be opened in the season of
                        1907, and the present Luxor Hotel will bo used as an auxiliary to it</p>
                    <p>The well known Cataract Hotel at Assouan is to be enlarged for the coming
                        season. One new wing is being added on the west side comprising several
                        private suites, and another 40 bedrooms. Mr. Pagnon has also decided to
                        enlarge the present hall, which has always been so much in favor with
                        tourists.</p>
                    <p>The splendid hotel can now accomodate 300 people and it is said that orders
                        are already flowing in for rooms to be reserved. The hotel will open as
                        usual the first week in November.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CLIMATE OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>There is a generally expressed opinion among most old residents, including
                        Dr. Abbate Pasha, president of the Khedivial Geographical Society, who has
                        resided over 50 years in this country, that the climate of Egypt is
                        undergoing a gradual change and the reason assigned is that, owing to the
                        Assouan Reservoir and the various irrigation works recently established, the
                        area of cultivated land has enormously increased of late, and in oonsequence
                        the amount of water evaporation is greater. The Suez Canal is also supposed
                        by some to have contributed in bringing about the change.</p>
                    <p>A report was spread some time ago that the Sphinx at Ghizeh disclosed signs
                        of crumbling, owing to those altered meteorological conditions, but careful
                        inquiries showed that the rumours were untrue and Captain Lyons,
                        director-general of the Survey Department, who is an acknowledged authority
                        on such matters, has recently stated that none of the observations made
                        daring late years indicate any gradual or permanent change in the climate.
                        Judging by the experiences of the summer now drawing to a close it certainly
                        does not give residents, especially of Cairo, any reason for thinking that
                        the heat is growing less, for this has been one of the most trying of hot
                        seasons.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FRENCH SQUADRON.</head>
                    <p>Our Suez correspondent writes under yesterday’s date as follows: —</p>
                    <p>The seven French destroyers, end torpedo-boats came out of the Canal
                        yesterday at 4.30 p.m., after a very quick run through, and moored in the
                        Port Ibrahim basin, waiting for the cruiser Foudre, which arrived here in
                        the forenoon to-day and anchored in the roads.</p>
                    <p>The squadron will sail to-morrow at noon for Djibouti</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CLOSE OF AN INCIDENT.</head>
                    <p>We are informed that the incident, which toot place on the quays on Tuesday
                        the 29 th ult, the importance of which has been much exaggerated, has been
                        closed to the satisfaction of all parties.</p>
                    <p>The lady therein concerned, wishing to avoid all unfriendly comment on the
                        energetic movement that escaped her in a moment of over excitement, has, of
                        her own accord, withdrawn the complaint she made against the Custom House
                        employes, while the latter, deferring to the wishes of the acting
                        director-general of the Customs Administration, with-drew their action
                        against the lady in question. The tact and courtesy that have led to this
                        happy solution deserve a generous recognition.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesConstantinople"><head>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.</head>
                    <head>The Hashish Trade.</head>
                    <p>( From our Correspondent. )</p>
                    <p>Constantinople, September 1.</p>
                    <p>I hear from Athens that M. Rallys, President of the Council of Ministers,
                        replying at a meeting held at Volo to the deputies of that district, who
                        demanded State aid for the purpose of increasing the tobacco export of Volo,
                        stated that the final negotiations for a new commercial treaty between Egypt
                        and Greece were to be opened in the near future, and that the Hellenic
                        Government’s first care would be the safeguarding of the interests of the
                        Thessalian tobacco-growers. M. Rallys added that he hoped that all
                        divergencies of opinion between the Governments referring to the cultivation
                        of hashish in Greece and to the closing of Greek gambling houses in Egypt,
                        would soon be settled to the satisfaction of all concerned. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONSULAR AND DIPLOMATIC.</head>
                    <p>Last week M. Anders, Dragoman of the German Consulate General at Cairo,
                        arrived here on leave. M. Eugene von Kuczynski, formerly Austro-Hungarian
                        Consul General at Alexandria, and actually Minister at Rio-de-Janeiro, has
                        been transferred, so say the Vienna papers, to Pekin. M. Guy the dragoman of
                        the French Embassy here, is to be transferred, as you doubtless know, to
                        Cairo end his place will be taken by M. Bougani, recently attached to the
                        Consulate-General et Muscat.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesCyprus">
                    <head>NOTES FROM CYPRUS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE HIGH COMMISSIONER.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <dateline>Nicosia, August 24.</dateline>
                        <p>His Excellency the High Commissioner who is accompanied by his wife and
                            family, is now making a stay of two or three days at the Monastery of
                            Kykkou, which is situated in a romantic and picturesque spot in the
                            Southern range.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AGRICULTURAL NOTES.</head>
                        <p>The post of Director of Agriculture, which has been vacant for eight
                            months, since the resignation of Mr. Gennadius in December last, has
                            been given to Mr. Diomedes Saracomenos. This gentleman was for many
                            years Professor of Natural Science in the Gymnasia of Athens, and also a
                            sub-director of the School of Agriculture of that city, and was for
                            seven years Director of the Agricultural Stations at Misso-longhi and
                            Corfu. He holds the diplomas of the Institut Agronomique de Peris and of
                            the Academie des Sciences (Sorbonne) Peris. He has now taken up his
                            duties. Many matters will call for his early attention, and it is likely
                            that an impetus will now be given to the experimental cultivation of
                            cotton, cereals, and other seeds and plants. It is known that Professor
                            Wyndham Dunstan, F. R. S., the Secretary to the Imperial Institute, was
                            out here last spring for the express purpose of examining into and
                            reporting upon the possibilities of developing the agricultural
                            resources of the Island, and some practical results of his
                            investigations and recom mendations may now, perhaps, be looked for. The
                            agricultural prosperity of Cyprus may by truly raid to depend, in large
                            measure, upon its water supply, and, of late years, efforts have not
                            been wanting to improve end aug-ment the facilities for irrigation. The
                            formation of large reservoirs in the Messaoria at a considerable expense
                            have not, as yet, fulfilled the hopes that were entertained respecting
                            them, and although, no doubt, that undertaking need not be regarded as
                            valueless, further outlay will, undoubtedly, be needed before these
                            reservoirs can be put to thorough utility. At present they ere mainly
                            dependent upon the river water for their supply, but as this comes down
                            in flood only during a few days in the year, and is then largely tapped
                            by riparian villagers, but a small quantity reaches the reservoirs. If
                            this thorny question could be satisfactorily solved, we should probably
                            see a greet deal of land, now idle, put. into regular cultivation. The
                            attempts at Artesian boring now being carried out at Nicosia are
                            therefore, of intense general interest We understand that the boring has
                            now reached a depth of nearly 350 feet.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WEATHER.</head>
                        <p>The weather, which was fairly hot last week, averaging, at Nicosia, from
                            99° to 102° Fahrenheit has now been become cooler, and indeed there is
                            little to complain of as regards the temperature here. At Troodoe, we
                            hear, it has been quite fresh, particularly at nights, and those living
                            in tents have needed additional coverings.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>POLICE UNIFORMS.</head>
                        <p>By order of the new Chief Commandant of Police, the zaptiehs now wear
                            white cloths over their fezes, which fall over their necks, and, besides
                            being picturesque they should afford a grateful protection from the
                            sun’s rays.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BEYROUT-DAMASCUS-HAURAN LIGHT RAILWAY. TURKISH RAILWAY ENTERPRISE.</head>
                    <p>( From our Correspondent. )</p>
                    <p>Beyront, September 1.</p>
                    <p>Railway enterprises in Turkey without kilo-metric guarantee are apt to prove
                        financial failures in their incipient stage, things progress so slowly in
                        that Empire. The Beyront-Damsscus narrow gauge line has had particularly
                        disastrous results owing to multifarious reasons. British influence
                        which—thanks to the vigilance and diplomatic skill of its representative has
                        since taken the ascendency - had, at the period of the construction of the
                        line, not quite supplanted French political preponderance in the Lebanon,
                        and France considered herself the chief protector of the semi-independent
                        province, and it is thought that the line was made to wind over such awkward
                        heights of the Mountain chiefly to please the Lebanese and form a sort of
                        iron link to farther knit the friendship, and strengthen the bond between
                        France and its protege. It is not an uncommon thing for the chivalrous
                        French to allow their feelings to get the better of their practical sense.
                        Political and personal reasons caused the railroad to he constructed through
                        a most awkward country, the gradients at some acclivities of the Lebanon
                        being at as much as seven metres per kilometre. Then the extravagances and
                        robberies in the contract department are said to have been so general, that
                        it is estimated the cost of building the line was more than twice as much as
                        it would have been, were the expenditure judicious and the contracts works
                        works entrusted to honest hands, and subjected to proper control.</p>
                    <p>Even then had it not been for the extension to Homs-Hama the concern would
                        still be a losing one. The consumption of coal involved in the crossing of
                        those steep gradients of the Lebanon is enormous, while the capacity of the
                        locomotives is thereby considerably limited. These disabilities have further
                        been accentuated by inadequate management of which there have been, and are
                        still, glaring instances. The catastrophe of the year before last is too
                        notorious to require anything beyond mere mention, while the various minor
                        accidents that occured daring last summer owing to the insufficiency of old
                        locomotives and the large influx of passengers, all point to far from
                        vigilant control and intelligent management The local directors here throw
                        the blame on the central administration, which limits their field of action,
                        and does not encourage any spirit of initiative on their part This is the
                        evil of centralisation, which found its apotheosis in the Russian
                        bureaucracy.</p>
                    <p>The passenger service daring the summer months yields important receipts, but
                        there is nothing done to improve it Indeed the pas-, sengers’ comfort would
                        not have been more lightly thought of had all those respectable folks been
                        so many dumb cattle. The first-class carriages are fitted up more wretchedly
                        than third-class carriages in other civilized countries, while the
                        second-class carriages do not differ from cattle trains, except in being
                        fitted up with straight and uncomfortable wooden benches. But this is not
                        all. The windows of the first-class compartments have no blinds, and as the
                        suburban train starts from Beyront at about 5 p.m. the passengers are
                        subjected to a semi-tropical sun for about two hours, while after sunset the
                        primitive looking oil lamps fixed to the ceiling do not sometimes give any
                        light, owing presumably to the bad quality of the oil, or more likely to
                        utter neglect. I had to use up almost a whole match-box' to find my stick on
                        arrival the other day at Aley in the dark.</p>
                    <p>And over and above all this the company imposes such onerous conditions on
                        the passengers, and especially the subscribers among them, and ignores so
                        totally the elementary principles of reciprocity of rights that one is
                        forced to the belief that the company considers the service it performs as a
                        gratuitous one, and one, therefore that should be accepted by the country as
                        a boon.</p>
                    <p>But reform has been known to follow often eat after great abases, and some
                        seem to see signs of awakening on the part of the company, and they put
                        their trust in the change of management. Indeed I have known the present
                        director, while he was yet acting-director, to take such an active and
                        sincere interest in the question of the satisfaction of the passengers that
                        he would in person go at early hoars to the station to see things for
                        himself. The chief cause of complaint was lately the insufficiency of
                        carriages. and it has been decided by the present director that whenever a
                        train was filled a supplementary one should be added, to start soon after
                        the first train, and carry the passengers that had been left behind, thus
                        avoiding en-cumbrance and the danger of straining the locomotive through
                        overloading. A farther grievance is the foot that passengers provided with
                        first-class tickets have sometimes for want of room to go into second-class
                        compartments and vice-versa. Surely the company can know the number of
                        places available and can therefore instruct the ticket clerk not to issue
                        any tickets in excess of the number of places allotted. But let us hope with
                        the optimists that under the new management a new era of reform will be
                        inaugurated. “This is a consummation devoutly to be wished."</p>
                    <p>It is to be hoped, however, that reform in other directions will be effect-ed
                        as well. A most injudicious economy i. still being displayed in the
                        remuneration of the staff employes. Ex-chauffeurs with inferior salaries
                        have taken the place of certificated engineer, engaged in France on the
                        initiation of the work of exploitation, regardless of the risk to life and
                        property that this might involve. It is true that the appointments of the
                        French Heads of Depart-ments have also been sensibly reduced, but still a
                        great disproportion exists between the renumeration of the superior and
                        subordinate employes. The latter, upon whom the largest and hardest share of
                        the work devolves, such as station masters, eta, are paid pitiful salaries,
                        and out of all proportion with the output of work performed. Their only
                        fault perhaps is the fact of being natives, for since the company has been
                        able to pay', liberal bonuses to its directors it could have meted out the
                        same treatment to its other servants, who have not contributed lees actively
                        to the development of its business because they are leas conspicuous. The
                        company must realise that insufficiently paid labour must necessarily end by
                        being inefficient, and in their own interest, and in mere consideration of
                        the principles of justice and humanity, it is to be hoped that due attention
                        will he paid to this question of the remuneration of the secondary
                        employes.</p>
                    <p>The extension from Rayak to Homs and Hama is a broad gauge line, and although
                        the passengers on that line are mostly filthy peasants, and men of rather
                        primitive habits, yet the carriages are fitted up in a comparatively
                        luxuriant style.</p>
                    <p>The Homs-Hama extension served to develop, considerably the traffic of the
                        company, and, as a natural corollary, widened the scope of. the commercial
                        activities of Beyrout, while it reduced the port of Tripoli to a nullity.
                        All the exports of wool and grain that used to find outlet at Tripoli have
                        been diverted to Beyront, thanks to the railway. The advantages of rail
                        carriage are manifestly superior to transport by the primitive means of
                        camel and mules. Besides the economy of time and punctual delivery, more or
                        lees, there is the fact of greater security, which is an important
                        consideration tor the insurance. But the narrow line of Beyrout seems to
                        fail to answer the requirements of the traffic, and fulfil all these
                        advantages. The grain crops of the Homs and Hama districts being
                        exceptionally abundant this year, it is estimated that no less than 40,000
                        tons of barley, beans, etc. but chiefly cf the first-named article, will be
                        destined for exportation. But I have heard it said that the railway company
                        frankly avowed its inability to carry more than half of this quantity, and
                        the remainder will have to lie over till next year or be transported on
                        camel back to Tripoli As our grain exports are chiefly destined for the
                        United Kingdom, the matter necessarily affects British maritime interests,
                        for loading in a sheltered harbour is infinitely more expeditions than in an
                        open roadstead, and quick despatch is a matter of vital importance to
                        shipping. The present director is doing his best to cope with this increased
                        demand of commerce, and they say that in addition to the six trains that
                        have heretofore been running each way daily between Rayak and Beyrout,
                        another eight trains are to be farther put in use. But the evil is inherent
                        and lies in the defectiveness of the line both to respect of its narrowness
                        and steepness. The tonnage capacity of the trains is by far too
                        restricted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesSuakin">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
                    <head>RAINS CAUSE GREAT DAMAGE</head>
                    <dateline>Suakin, August 30.</dateline>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent) </byline>
                    <p>Heavy rains keep coming down on the railway lines and washing them away in
                        several places, and it is only with the greatest difficulty that the lines
                        can be kept in position. Many trains from here had to be suspended owing to
                        the line being broken in several places. Bimbashi Sowerby, Bimbashi Lord.
                        and Mr. Hickley, with all their gangs of thousands, are working day and
                        night the heavy torrents of rein to repair the broken parts.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CONDENSOR EXPLOSION.</head>
                    <p>I have much pleasure in informing yon that Mr. Warn and Mr. Archer, who were
                        lately scalded by an explosion of a steam pipe in the condensor, have now
                        completely recovered, and both have resumed their duties. All the damaged
                        parts in the condensor have been replaced and a new lime-catcher supplied ;
                        the unlucky Suakin railway condensor is now at work once more end turning
                        out very pure water.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>
                        <head>Regatta.</head>
                        <p>The following is to-morrow’s handicap when two handsome cups given by the
                            Commodore will be raced for : —</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="page" n="4"/>
                <div type="page" n="5"/>
                <div type="page" n="6">
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
