<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brayan Barbosa</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-12-07</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-07-26</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="section">
                    <head>ISAM AND KAISER.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MOTIVES FOR MEETING.</head>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 25. There are endless theories as to
                            the motives of the Imperial meeting, from the, natural desire of the
                            Sovereigns to discuss the political problems confronting Europe, to the
                            design of the German Emperor to combine Germany, Russia and France
                            against Japan in view of the peace negotiations. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p><placeName>ST. PETERSBURG,</placeName> July 25. The Tsar has returned to
                            Peterhof. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BALFOUR MINISTRY OPPOSITION FIGHT.</head>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 25. The Unionist organs approve of
                            Mr. Balfour's decision to remain in office, deeming it right that his
                            personal feelings should give way before national considerations. The
                            Radicals denounce the Government for clinging to office. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 25. HOUSE OF COMMONS.—In accordance
                            with yesterday's threats, the Opposition is obstruct- ing business at
                            every turn. The Unemployed Bill was abandoned. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIA. BOULIGUINE PROJECT SHELVED.</head>
                        <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> July 25. The promulgation of the
                            Bouliguine consti- tution project has been indefinitely postponed.
                            (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>M. ROUVIER AND M. WITTE.</head>
                        <p><placeName>Paris,</placeName> July 25. M. Rouvier and M. Witte again
                            conferred at length to-day. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RED SEA PIRACY. ITALIAN NOTE TO THE PORTE.</head>
                        <p><placeName>Constantinople,</placeName> July 25. Italy has handed the
                            Porte a threatening note on the subject of acts of piracy in the Red
                            Sea. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET. FOURTH TEST MATCH.</head>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 25. England v. Australia. England 362
                            runs for 6 wickets. Hayward, 82. Jackson unfinished 103. {Reuter.)</p>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 25. The weather was fine, and there
                            were 20,000 people present. There had been rain over-night and the
                            wicket was dead. England 446 first innings. Jackson 113. Australia 197.
                            Darling 73, followed by 118 runs for 1 wicket Duff, unfinished, 58.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <p>Yacoub Pasha Artin, Under Secretary of State for Public Instruction, is
                            among the passengers leaving for Europe to-day by the S.S.
                            Schleswig.</p>
                        <p>Miralai Schalch Bey, Commandant of the Suez Canal Police, has been
                            granted 2 1/2 months’ leave of absence, dating from July 19. Three
                            months’ leave of absence has been granted to Capt. the Hon. C. James
                            assistant director of Personnel and Accounts Department from July
                            29.</p>
                        <p>Mustapha Bey Maher, Moudir of Assouan, has returned to Cairo from
                            England. Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we
                            notice : Mr. Lsaze de Meux, Frl. Koch, Mr. W. Collet Major Turner, Mrs.
                            Ludlow, Capt. Young, Capt. and Mrs. Blakeney, child and nurse, Rev. R
                            Maclnnes, M. Vassilieff, Mr. Dolrishmann.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ANGLO-AMERICAN NILE STEAMER.</head>
                        <p>de HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                        <p>River transport of goods between Alexandria Gairo</p>
                        <p>Three Sellings a-Week.</p>
                        <p>Agents at Alexandria:-</p>
                        <p>ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LD.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CARLTON HOTEL,</head>
                        <p>BULKELEY (near Alexandria.)</p>
                        <p>BAMLER’S FASHIONABLE HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>PATRONISED BY THB ELITE.</p>
                        <p>Full Pension from P.T. 40 a day. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber
                            station.</p>
                        <p> C. AQUILINA. Proprietor</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>THE LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL will meet on Tuesday next</p>
                    <p>THE BRINDISI MAIL will be distributed at I the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 9 30
                        p.m. to-day.</p>
                    <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the c Mousky district of Cairo during the
                        night of Thursday and at daybreak on Friday will be poisoned by the
                        police.</p>
                    <p>NEW WAY OF PAYING OLD DEBTS - A Roumanian woman who owed a sum of money to a
                        man who pressed her for payment, attempted to commit suicide yesterday by
                        taking poison. Her life was, however, saved.</p>
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL.—22 vessels passed through the Canal on the 22nd and 23rd inst, 13
                        of which were British, 5 German, 1 French, 1 Dutch, 1 Austrian, 1 Egyptian.
                        The receipts for the two days were frs. 664,677.92, making the total from
                        the 1st inst. fr. 6,511,506.14.</p>
                    <p>THE PLAGUE. —Yesterday’s bulletin records two cases (one fatal) and two
                        recoveries at Alexandria. The patient admitted to hospital is an Italian
                        joiner living in Anastassi-street, while the fatal case was that of a native
                        servant, who was a relative of the man found dead on the 23rd inst.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO TRAMWAYS.—It is stated that an agreement has been com0 to between the
                        Public Works Department and the Cairo Tram- way Company for an extension of
                        the life of the latter by five years, so that all the com- pany’s material,
                        as well as the lands bought and buildings constructed, will not become the
                        property of the Government till the year 1951.</p>
                    <p>MR. LYNN’S CASE.— The General Orders issued by the Ministry of the Interior
                        an- nounce that Saghcolaghasi J. Lynn, moawin of police, Alexandria City,
                        has resigned his ap- pointment, and has been struck off the strength of the
                        police, with effect from yesterday’s date. We understand that the Alexandria
                        Muni- cipality will in all probability take into account the excellent
                        services which Captain Lynn has rendered to the city, and in likewise
                        accepting his resignation will grant him a gratuity.</p>
                    <p>ROYAL BERKS.—The warrant officers, staff sergeants, and sergeants of the 2nd
                        Battalion Royal Berkshire Regiment gave a quadrille party in their mess-room
                        at Mustapha Pasha yesterday evening, to commemorate the anni- versary of the
                        Battle of Maiwand, in which that regiment took a conspicuous part. The floor
                        of the mess-room, gaily decorated for the occasion, was in excellent
                        condition, and to the strains of the string band of the regiment dancing was
                        indulged in with the greatest zest until an advanced hour this morning.
                        There were a large number of guests, including several officers of the
                        regiment, and the general hosts were indefatigable in their attentions to
                        all. A well-stocked buffet was provided and done ample justice to.</p>
                    <p>ST. ANDREW’S GIRLS’ UPPER SCHOOL.—The exhibition and prize-giving took place
                        in this school yesterday in the presence of a large gathering of parents and
                        friends. Mr. Vice- Consul Freeman occupied the chair. An Eng- lish cantata,
                        "Festival of the Flowers,” in which each pupil represented a different
                        flower, was much appreciated. The choral singing, duets, and solos were
                        beautifully rendered, and the various "flowers" acted their parts to
                        perfection. The French pieces, La Sonambula and Froufrou, were also of an
                        excellent order, and reflect the highest credit on M. Coupson, French
                        master. Other items on the programme were an Arabic recitation and an
                        English piece by the junior pupils. The duties of accompanist were
                        excellently performed by Miss M. Gatt. Towards the end of the programme the
                        prizes were presented to successful pupils by Mrs. Freeman, whose first
                        public appearance it was. Among the prize-winners we especially noticed Miss
                        E. Samama, who, besides several other prizes, gained a handsome medal for
                        Scripture, presented by Major Allan of Glasgow. Next in order of merit came
                        Misses Jacobson and Youameidis. Thereafter Mr. Freeman, in a few well-chosen
                        remarks, congratulated Miss Hannah, M.A., head mistress, her efficient
                        staff, and the pupils themselves, on the suc cessful work done daring the
                        session, and invited the audience to inspect the needlework, drawing,
                        painting, and kindergarten in the adjoining room. This exhibition also
                        showed wonderful efficiency in these branches of school work. At the
                        conclusion of the entertainment Rev. H. P. Reid proposed a hearty vote of
                        thanks to Mr. and Mrs. Freeman for their presence on this occasion, which
                        was cordially responded to.</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BECK CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
                        <p>BREMEN.</p>
                        <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm</p>
                        <p>In Caire, Alexandria the Sudan</p>
                        <p>Otherwise apply is E.J. FLEURENT, F. MICALLEF Sole Agent</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>
                        <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons Dinners</p>
                        <p>Served on the Terrace.</p>
                        <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11:30 P.M</p>
                        <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION SEA BREMEN</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>FIGHTING THE COTON WORM</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUCCESS OF MEASURES.</head>
                        <p>The energetic measures which have been taken by the Ministry of the
                            Interior to combat the cotton worm and to check as far as possible the
                            damage which it causes to the cotton crops, are proving very successful,
                            as the considerable decrease in the area attacked during last week amply
                            demonstrates. The first brood which appeared in June has been dealt
                            with, that of July is at present being actively dealt with and has to a
                            large extent been destroyed, and the workers are now busily seeking for
                            the eggs of the third or August brood, which in previous years has
                            always proved to be the largest and has caused most damage. We
                            understand, however, that the work of the last two months has been so
                            effective that the third brood will, in all probability, be very slight,
                            and that there is very little fear of the worms appearing in large
                            numbers.</p>
                        <p>In connection with this work, we might mention that Mr. Machell has not
                            yet fixed the date when he will go on leave, but is waiting until be can
                            be certain that there will be no re-appearance of the worm this season,
                            when the work will be practically completed. Mr. Machell has shown
                            himself indefatig- able in the way he has organised and super- intended
                            the work for the destruction of the worm, and in his personal inspection
                            of the work done in those cultivations which have suffered more severely
                            than others.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>QUARANTINE IN GREECE.</head>
                        <p>The following telegram has been received from Athens by the Hellenic
                            sanitary delegate on the Quarantine Board :—</p>
                        <p>"Arrivals from Alexandria and Adalia sub- jected 48 hours’ quarantine,
                            also medical inspection from the littorals Syria and Asia Minor, Port
                            Ptolemais as far as Adalia, excepting Adalia, thence as far as Smyrna,
                            excepting Smyrna.”</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA BRIDGES.</head>
                        <p>We hear that the special committee, con- sisting of Mr. Chataway,
                            representing the Mu- nicipality, Mr. Williams and Mr. Acres, repre-
                            senting the Irrigation Department and the Railway Administration
                            respectively, Mr. S..H. Carver, representing the Alexandria General
                            Produce Association, and Mr. L. Stagni, repre- senting the importers,
                            have drawn up a report on the increase of the number of bridges on the
                            Mahmondieh Canal.</p>
                        <p>The committee consider it impossible to enlarge the existing bridges and
                            recommend the construction of a new bridge linking the Sharia Shoanah el
                            Tainat with the rue du Canal Mahmondieh, east of the Fire Station. They
                            have also decided to consider the con- struction of a new bridge nearly
                            opposite the rue Tewfikieh, and to replace the Ibrahim Bridge by a new
                            bridge of greater width, the details of which will be settled as soon as
                            the new bridge is completed. In view of the con- fusion prevalent with
                            regard to the name of the bridge below the Ibrahim Bridge it was de-
                            cided to rename it the Daira Sanieh Bridge. The new bridge will be
                            called the Abbas Bridge.</p>
                        <p>The Municipality has expressed its agree- ment in principle with the
                            conclusions of the committee and has decided to submit them to the
                            Government</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN MINING.</head>
                        <p>In its Mining article, the "Financier" of the 17th inst says Elsewhere,
                            however, more bullish views were held, significance being attached to
                            the strong buying of Egyp- tians which took place last week. It is
                            thought, in fact, that another effort is on the tapis for bringing
                            Egyptian mining enterprises into public favor. The last move in this
                            direc- tion, it may perhaps be remembered, was hopelessly baulked by the
                            turbulent condition of politics, and since then, in company with
                            Kaffirs, prices have gradually dwindled down to what can now only be
                            described as bed- rock level. Now, with the political outlook
                            comparatively dear, and the speculating public sorely in need of a new
                            area wherein, so to speak, they can have a good run for their money, it
                            is thought the attractions of Egyp- tians are bound to claim attention.
                            It is on this assumption, at any rate, that astute and influential
                            people have been quietly acquiring lines of the leading Egyptian
                            stocks—witness the sharp advance which occurred the other day in
                            Egyptian Mines—and equally good, too, was the buying of such shares as
                            Nile Valley, Um Rus, Central Egypts and Egyptian Options, as well as
                            several of the Trust com- panies. An indication of how mining develop-
                            ments are proceeding space is contained in the circular to hand from the
                            Mysore Reefs Company, which in the autumn is forming two exploratory
                            parties for the purpose of prospecting ancient mining sites in Egypt and
                            the Sudan. This company and the Egyptian Mines, it might be mentioned,
                            are big holders in the prosperous Um Rus. Generally speak- ing, the
                            outlook for Egyptians is regarded as distinctly favorable, and the
                            opinion is strongly held that the next wave of specula- tion in mines
                            will turn in this direction.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                        <p>The second vocal concert at the Casino will take place to-morrow, at 6
                            p.m., when the Bra- cale orchestra will accompany the singers as before.
                            The following is the programme :</p>
                        <p>1 Prologue de Paillasse—Bariton—Mr. S. Greggio.</p>
                        <p>2 scene et air d'Aids-Soprano-Mlle Cantoni.</p>
                        <p>3 Romance des fleurs de Carmen-Tenor-Mr. G. Giovanelli.</p>
                        <p>4 Duo de Cavalleria. Rusticans— {Mlle Cantoni. Mr. Giovanelli.</p>
                        <p>On Sunday next a grand Verdi oonoerconcert (vocal and instrumental) will
                            take place.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SIR H. PINCHING’S DEPARTURE.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                        <p><placeName>Port Said,</placeName> Tuesday. Sir Horace Pinching, K.C.M.G.,
                            Director- General of the Sanitary Department, left here by the
                            Messegeries SS. Ville de la Ciotat after a short stay at the Eastern
                            Exchange. He goes to Marseilles and thence to England.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BAD WEATHER REPORTED.</head>
                        <p>The Ville de la Ciotat, during her passage through the Arabian Sea,
                            experienced some very bad weather and has lost her foremast and a
                            quantity of deck furniture.</p>
                        <p>The B. I. Mombassa, which arrived here from the Canal this morning,
                            reports an exceedingly heavy monsoon. To the north- ward of Socotra she
                            experienced but little sea, but for some hours was in the thick of a
                            lull gale of wind which did some damage about the decks.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EASTERN COASTING TRADE.</head>
                        <p>The Eastern coasts trade seems to be on the increase of late. Counting
                            the two vessels which have arrived from Hamburg and Liver- pool
                            respectively to-day, one of the Admiral class of the Hamburg-Amerika
                            line and the Kohinur, of the Asiatic (Turner Morrison) Line, no less
                            than nine ships have passed through on their maiden voyages for the
                            coast trades of China and India this month. These vessels, — as does the
                            Qaeda, the leviathan 12,000-ton ship which I referred to last week, —
                            will most likely never return to the "land of their birth” but will
                            remain per- manently on the coasts for which they are destined. The
                            Hamburg-Amerika Line has a somewhat large fleet on the China coast
                            running in opposition to the China merchants and two large British-owned
                            lines sailing from Shanghai.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EASTERN EXCHANGE</head>
                        <p>Considerable improvements are now taking place in and around the Eastern
                            Exchange. Some time back, I understand, the proprietors purchased a
                            large piece of the adjacent land, which, if built on, would have much
                            affected the value of the building. The greater part of this piece of
                            ground is now being cleared and a small garden is to be there planted
                            and arranged, and I hear, later on, is to be greatly enlarged.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SINKING OF THE CONGAL</head>
                        <p>Two engineer surveyors have been out here during the last few days on
                            behalf of the underwriters of the Congal and the owners of the
                            Craftsman. These gentlemen have just completed-their surveys and the
                            result will probably, determine the value of the work of her salving due
                            to the Canal Company. It is said the award will probably only be the
                            payment of out-of- pocket expenses.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRIMARY CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION.</head>
                        <p>Monday's "Official Journal” contains a long list of the successful
                            candidates in the Primary Certificate examination. Out of 3,333 can-
                            didates 1,173 passed the examination with success.Of the total of the
                            successful candidates 1,111 had taken the English and 62 the French
                            course.</p>
                        <p>The successful candidates have been grouped in two divisions. The first
                            division includes all who obtained 75 % or more of the maximum number of
                            marks obtainable, who number 180. The first name on this list is that of
                            Nessim Abd-el Sayed, of the Bab el Charieh Sobool, who obtained 140 1/4
                            marks out of 160, his average being high all through. Hamid Ahmed, of
                            the El-Tahdirieh School, is second on the list with 136 3/4, and eleven
                            other candidates have obtained over 180 marks. We notice that the 12
                            candidates on the French side who obtained marks justifying their
                            inclusion in the first division show a higher average in their marks for
                            French than the pupils who took the English coarse obtained for English.
                            Twenty girls entered for the examination, of whom 10 passed. The
                            Government schools sent up 556 boys who took the English course and 9
                            girls, one only boy taking the French course. From the free schools 497
                            boys and 1 girl entered on the English side, and 53 boys on the French.
                            48 private pupils took up Eng- lish and 8 French—all boys.</p>
                        <p>We wonder would it be possible for the Ministry of Public Instruction to
                            publish, with the lists, the religion and origin of the pupils entering
                            for the examination. Statistics showing tbh proportion of Syrian, Copt,
                            and Israelite candidates would be of considerable interest to the
                            public.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JUDICIAL NEWS.</head>
                        <p>It is reported that there is a distinct pos- sibility that the finding of
                            the Court of Appeal in the Riffahi ease may not be maintained by the
                            Court of Cassation, on the ground that three days’ evidence was not
                            given to the accused, and that a new trial may be neces- sary. The Court
                            of Cassation will hear the case on August 1.</p>
                        <p>Another interesting case, that of Androus Meloka, will come before the
                            Cairo Assize Court on August 12.</p>
                        <p>The Léon Fehmy case will be heard at the same session of the Court</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DRURY BEY’S TRANSFER.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)</p>
                        <p><placeName>Suakin,</placeName> July 19. In my last notes I made mention
                            of the transfer of Kaimakam Drury Bey, R.N., Con- troller of Sudan
                            Ports, to the Bahr el Ghazal, but this move has now been cancelled owing
                            to the death of Kaimakam Fell Bey, R.N., who was to have relieved Drury
                            Bey.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WEATHER.</head>
                        <p>The weather is still very hot and khamseen winds continue to prevail. The
                            thermometer in the shade is sometimes as high as 110* F.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SPORT AT SUAKIN.</head>
                        <p>The members of the British Railway Em- ployés’ Mess held a pigeon match
                            on the sea front at Quarantine Camp on Friday, the 14th inst. There was
                            a very strong wind blowing from the north, which rather upset some of
                            the guns, and got worse towards the close of the day. Mr. Claude S.
                            Archer made very good scoring, taking 10 birds out of a possible 11, and
                            thus securing the two most important events of the day. Mr. Archer was
                            hard pressed, however, by Mr. Gaiger, who was one bird only to the bad,
                            Lost by an unlucky bird falling a few feet outside the line. Mr. Hodges,
                            under very trying circumstances, won the 3rd event. There was a very
                            large attendance and a very enjoyable afternoon was spent.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TRAFFIC DEPARTMENT.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Albert Cree, of Alexandria, Inspector of Traffic, Suakin-Atbara
                            Railways, has resigned his appointment after two months' service, Mr.
                            Cree is the third English inspector of traffic ; the two before him also
                            resigned with less than three months’ service. Mr. Cree leaves Suakin to
                            day for Suez and Alexandria by the Khédi- vial mail steamer
                            Dakahlieh.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FEVER.</head>
                        <p>Very few cases of fever exist now. Mr. W. H. Bailey, Inspector of
                            Bridges, who was laid up in hospital with it, has now completely
                            recovered and resumed his duties. Kaimakam Mohamed Bey Ahmed,
                            Commandant, Suakin Police, has also recovered from his late illness and
                            resumed his’ duties.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUAKIN MOUDIRIEH</head>
                        <p>The acting Moudir, Mr. Kerr, and the whole mondirieh staff have gone to
                            Erkoweit for the summer months.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SPORT AND PLAY. CRICKET.</head>
                        <p>E. T. C. SENIORS v. JUNIORS.</p>
                        <p>This match was played yesterday (Tuesday) and ended in a win for the
                            Juniors by 5 wickets. For the Seniors, Messrs. R. MoLean and Stacey
                            scored well, and for the Juniors Messrs. Harrison, Henley, and Byrne did
                            best Scores :-</p>
                        <p>Seniors.</p>
                        <p>Mr. C. D. Stacey c. Gheesman b. Byrne 31</p>
                        <p>„ A. B. Collier, hit wicket b. Thurston 0</p>
                        <p>„ B. McLean, c. Blythman b. Byrne 14</p>
                        <p>„ R. B. McLean, b. Byrne ........ 44</p>
                        <p>„ C. P. Steele, run out .......... 17</p>
                        <p>„ H. Hanley, b. Thurston .........16</p>
                        <p>„ W. T. B. Carlisle, b. Blythman .. 1</p>
                        <p>„ S. MunGavio, b. Thurston......... 2</p>
                        <p>„ H. Sedgwick not out.............. 0</p>
                        <p>„ J. H. MunGavin, b. Thurston..... 0</p>
                        <p>„ G. W. Hird c. Harrison b. Thurston 1</p>
                        <p>Extras............................ 10</p>
                        <p>186</p>
                        <p>Juniors.</p>
                        <p>Mr. G. N. Cheesman b. R. McLean... 18</p>
                        <p>„ P. J. Byrne c. and b. Stacey.... 26</p>
                        <p>„ M. Blythman b. R. McLean.......... 6</p>
                        <p>,, B. G. Henley b. R McLean....... 28</p>
                        <p>„ P. E. Harrison c. Stacey b. Collier 50</p>
                        <p>„ J. B. Harvey not out ............. 3</p>
                        <p>„ H. F. Thurston not out .......... 13</p>
                        <p>„ J. R. Lees </p>
                        <p>„ C. S. Scarth </p>
                        <p>„ C. R. Dowson Did not bat</p>
                        <p>„ A. C. Lester</p>
                        <p>Extras..... 9</p>
                        <p>for 5 wkts 153</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>We are asked by the Golf Steward to state that the results of the recent
                            competitions were as follows:—</p>
                        <p>Alexandria Sporting Club Challenge Cup and Gold Medal.—Judge Percival</p>
                        <p>Handicap Match Play.—Mr. Kerr.</p>
                        <p>Handicap Foursomes.—Mr. Logan and Cap tain Riach.</p>
                        <p>Driving Competition. - Mr. Logan.</p>
                        <p>Handicap Stroke Competition. — Major Ludlow.</p>
                        <p>All the matches in the different events were very closely contested,
                            which speaks well for the handicap. The match in the final round in the
                            challenge cup was a most excellent contest, Mr. Logan, who was conceding
                            14 strokes, only being defeated on the last green.</p>
                        <p>Saturday’s Gymkhana will commence at 3.30 p.m., and not at 4 p.m.</p>
                        <p>The following is the programme of music to be played at the Gymkhana on
                            Saturday next :—</p>
                        <p>1 March… To the Assault .. Old Hume.</p>
                        <p>2 Overture… Raymod… Thomas.</p>
                        <p>3 Russian Peasant Dance… Kukuska… Lehar.</p>
                        <p>4 Selection… Romeo e Giuletta… Gounod.</p>
                        <p>5 Valse… Monte Christo… Kotlar.</p>
                        <p>6 Nocturne… L’Esperance… Ascher.</p>
                        <p>7 Selection… The Mikado… Sullivan.</p>
                        <p>8 Minuet…-… Paderewski.</p>
                        <p>9 Serenade… Venetian… Heeley.</p>
                        <p>10 Gavotte… Plasscato… Watson</p>
                        <p>Khedive Anthem- God Save the King.</p>
                        <p>S. Doss, Bandmaster, 2nd R. Berks</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>DELEGATION MUNICIPALE</head>
                    <p>(Communication Officielle)</p>
                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s’est réunie le 95 juillet à 5 b. p m. sous la
                        prétidence da M. Amb. A. Ralli.</p>
                    <p>Présente : Mrs. Ahmed Bey Eyoub, Mansour Bey Youssef, Schiess Bey. S.
                        Valensin.G. Zervu- dachi, membres, A. Wilnes secrétaira p. i.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation adopte l’avis du Conseil du Tanzim, les notes pré tentées par
                        l’Ingénieur en Chef ainsi que par l’lnspecteur Sanitaire an sujet des
                        projets d'affectation des terrains situés an Mex, à des entrepôts de
                        bois.</p>
                    <p>Elle décide de communiquer ces documents au Ministère en vue d'une demande de
                        com- pensations équivalentes aux pertes que ce projet fera subir à la
                        Municipalité.</p>
                    <p>Elle adjuge à M. Lagoudakis, plus bas offrant, la fourniture des registres et
                        imprimés pour les années 1906, 1907 et 1908.</p>
                    <p>Les travaux de dallage de la rue longeant le quai de Mahmoudieh depuis le
                        dallage actuel jusqu'à la rue Ragheb Pacha, sont ad- jugés à M. Calvario
                        Nicolas, plus bas offrant, au prix de L.E. 238 et 1/2.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation prend note de l'acceptation donnée, par lettre du 19 juillet,
                        par la Com- pagnie de Ramleh au projet d’abaissement de ses lignes entre le
                        Victoria College et la tran- chée de l’Ibrahimieh.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide l’impression d’un cer- tain nombre d’exemplaires de
                        l’arré'é portant tarif des voitures publiques,en livret de poche, pour être
                        distribués au public.</p>
                    <p>Elle demanders à la Commission l'ouverture d’un crédit de 25 L.E. environ,
                        représentant le 10% de crédit ouvert par la Commission pour participations
                        aux agents de la Police poor servions rendus à l’occasion de la vente des
                        plaques aux cochers.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation fixe à P.T. 5 le prix de cha- que nouvelle médaille pour les
                        chiens, deman- dée par les particuliers en remplacement de celle qu’ils
                        auraient perdue.</p>
                    <p>Sur la demande du Servi de de Nettoiement, la Délégation proposera à la
                        Commission un virement de crédit de L.E. 100 pour hais divers et
                        déplacements et certaines réparations et achats de matériel de ce
                        service.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation prend connaissance d'un rap- port de M. Monfront, Chef du
                        service des plantations, an sujet des bassins de la place Mohamed Ali. M.
                        Montent est d’avis ou de les supprimer ou de les rendre à leur destina- tion
                        primitive en y installant des jets d'eau. De plus M. Monfront ajoute qu'il y
                        aurait liez de remplacer les kiosques servant à la musique, qui sont dans un
                        état pitoyable et font le plus mauvais effet.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation partageant la manière de voir de M. Monfront, décide de lui
                        demander de lui présenter un projet comportant les améliora- tions qu’il
                        compte apporter à la place Moha- med Aly.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation prend également connaissance d’une note de M. Monfront relative
                        aux obser- vations faites à la Commission Municipale au sujet de plantations
                        de tout petits arbustes le long de la promenade de Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Cette note sera soumise à la Commission.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide de mettre en adjudi- cation la reconstruction du mur de
                        soutène- ment de l'hôpital du Gouvernement en façade de la rue d’Allemagne,
                        conformément aux indi- cations qui seront données par M. Williams.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide la mise en adjudica- tion de l'empierrement en caillasse
                        de 3 routes transversales à l’Ibrahimieh, savoir, celles longeant les
                        propriétés Sannos, Massa et l'école Anglaise.</p>
                    <p>El'e décide également de mettre an adjudi- cation le macadamisage de la rue
                        Demetrino, au quartier Grec, moyennant la contribution offerte par le
                        propriétaire riverain.</p>
                    <p>Quant à l'empierrement d’antres rues de ce quartier proposé par les servions
                        la Délégation en ajourne l’examen à une époque ultérieure.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation charge l’ingénieur en chef de se mettre d’accord avec Mr.
                        Monfront au sujet de l’endroit cii devra être érigé le nouveau chalet de
                        nécessité-sur l’emplacement du square ouest de la place Mohamed Ali</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PASSENGER LISTS DEPARTURES.</head>
                        <p>Per N.D.L S.S. Schleswig, leaving Alexan- dria to-day for Marseilles :
                            —</p>
                        <p>Yacoub Artin Pasha, Mme. and Mile. Ya- coub Artin Pasha, Mr. C. Ambrogio,
                            Mr. T Arditi, Messieurs Abiad, Mrs. Abiad, Mr. A. Bareketti, Mme.
                            Bordarier, Mr. Charles Bopp, Mr. C. Cohen, Mila Chappins, Mr. Felix Ca-
                            racco, Mr. S. Francis, Mr. P. Glymenopoulos, Mr. Chini Glymenopoulos.
                            Mme-Glymenopou- los, Mr. and Mme. N. Goussio, Mr. Ghazaros- sian, Mr. K.
                            Gomushguerdan, Mr. Isidore Hornstein, Mr. and Mme. Heine, Mr. and Mme.
                            Th. Kindyneko, Mr. Selim J. Khouzam, Miss Leishanan, Mme. J.j Darcy
                            Montanier, Mr. M. Mano, Mr. M. Mardirossian, Mme. Reine Marcel, Miss C.
                            Newton, Captain Gius. Pereira, Mile. Mary Pereira. Mr. Bruno Pe- reira,
                            Miss Reeve. Mme C. D. Stacey, Mr. and Mme. Jean Sabb, Mme. Vve N.
                            Savidis, Mr. and Mme. Otto Sterzing, Mme. Santone, Mr. Ad. Utendoeffer,
                            Mr. Spiro Valeskaki, Mme G. Zervudachi, Mila Zervudachi, Mr. Zervu-
                            dachi</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The S.S. Indian Prince, with passengers and general cargo, left Malta
                            yesterday and is due at Alexandria on Saturday.</p>
                        <p>The Ellerman S.S. City of Oxford, from Liverpool, Gibraltar and Malta,
                            left the latter port on Tuesday and is due here on Friday with general
                            cargo and passengers.</p>
                        <p>The S.S. Falernian left Liverpool on Satur- day and is due here on the
                            6th proximo.</p>
                        <p>The Ellerman S.S. Britannia is expected to sail on Friday next for
                            Liverpool.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
