<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, MAY 19, 1905.</head>
<div type="item"><p>THE STATE RAILWAYS.
BY “TRAFFIC.”
(SECOND ARTICLE).
The work to be done by the Council and the
General Manager may be summed up as the
"Administrative” work, or work of control, and,
this having been provided for, there remains
the executive work or actual working of the
railway. This falls naturally under their heads
having reference to the object with which a
railway is established. This is, to provide for
the conveyance of goods and passengers from
place to place over the lines of the railway,
and there are three prime essentials that go to
the realization of this object; first, the provi-
sion of the “railway," the lines, stations, etc.;
secondly, that of vehicles to carry the goods
army ani> nayy
(Fbom our Correspondent).</p>
<p>London, May 11.
It has been officially announced that the
King’s birthday will be celebrated at all naval
and military stations abroad on the 9th of
November, his natal day. At home stations
it will be celebrated on the 30th of June.
The first class battleship 'Canopus” and
"Goliath" left Portsmouth yesterday for the
China Station to relieve, it is stated, the
battleships "Centurion” and "Ocean," the
commissions of which are about to expire. _lt
is generally well understood that England will
maintain a strong battleship squadron in the
Far East until the cessation of hostilities, in
accordance with an agreement to that effect
with JspaD.</p>
<p>Captain C.W. Barton, D.S.O., Northampton
J5QYPTIACA.
and passengers, and, thirdly, that of the motive ; Regiment, who for the past two years has
essentials under the conditions that affect the promoted a company commander in the
management of a modern railway involve a same'battalio. He earned the D.S.O. in the
number of minor departments, such as the South African campaign in addition to the
Signalling, Telegraph, Stores, etc., all of which medals with three clasps. He was wounded at
are interdependent.	the action of Rhenoster River.</p>
<p>Now that a railway may be worked economically
and efficiently nothing is of more Lieutenant-Colonel R. C. C. Cox, Royal
importance than that these different depart- Inniskilling Fusiliers, who from command of
that they may work together, each accomplish- “ gQOCe£ion to Lieutenant-Colonel G. M.
ing its own work m the best manner and each Mackenzie, transferred to the 1st Battalion,
contributing in the largest possible manner to MrT0d with the 1st Battalion in the Boer War
the efficiency of the others. This interdependence of 1900-02, and was mentioned in Lord
deuce of the different departments goes down Kitchener’s dispatches for meritorious work
to the minutest details in all branches of the (medal with three clasps and promoted brevet
work, and it is evident therefore that the« lieutenant-colonel.)
first essential of an effective executive service	"	. D ...
i. tiio prop* coordination ot it. v.riou, . Mm* Clraito Moon* Royal B.tlolorelU.
Kotiotu. How’tW. »n tatb. 
question upon which authorities are not agreed. for promotion to the rank of lieutenant-colonel.</p>
<p>Almost every railway has its own method, the Major Moore has also had the advantage of
great diversity that obtains in actual praotice practical as well as theoretical campaigning,
being however largely due to the varying having seen service in the Sudan operations
condition, .nd oiroum.Umoro nndor which th. of	■“““ft >•»	»r
.Intact Boro »ra wotlrai A. . gonorol], (nodJ «d Khod.y.^t,,).
applicable system, and one that very nearly
approaches that at present adopted by the Says a contemporary—Lord Cromer and the
State Railways, the following diagram gives a Sirdar, Sir Reginald Wingate, are anxious to
oic.ro, id- a- rau_be ob-inod . ro.ro ^*2?^ STudS*.
verbal explanation .	larger number of recruits to join the colours.
been promoted a company commander in tho
same battalion. He earned the D.S.O. in the
South African campaign in addition to the
medals with three clasps. He was wounded at
the action of Rhenoster River.</p>
<p>Lientenant-Colonel R. C. C. Cox, Royal
Inniskilling Fusiliers, who from oommand of
the lst-Battalion at Londonderry, goes to Cairo
to take up the command of the 2nd Battalion,
in succession to Lieutenant-Colonel G. M.
Mackenzie, transferred to the 1st Battalion,
served with the 1st Battalion in the Boer War
of 1900-02, and was mentioned in Lord
Kitchener’s despatches for meritorious work
medal with three clasps and promoted brevet
ieutenant-oolonel.)</p>
<p>Major Charles Moore, Royal Berkshire Re-
giment, Superintendent of Gymnasia at Col-
chester, has passed the qualifying examination
for promotion to the rauk of lieutenant-colonel.
Major Moore has also had the advantage of
Eractical as well as theoretical campaigning,
aving seen service in the Sudan operations
of 1885-S6, including the action of Ginniss
having seen service in the Sudan operation
of 1885-S6, including the action of Ginnia
(medal and Khedive’s star).
Says a contemporary—Lord Cromer and the
Sirdar, Sir Reginald Wingate, are anxious to
increase the efficiency of the Sudanese batta-
(1) General Manager
(7) Wav and Works
i) Carriage Pel t.
""rL</p>
<p>This diagram is defective in respect that it ,
Ices not sufficiently clearly show the close ,
relation existing between the Traffic and the |
Signaling Departments. Originally, when rail-
way signaling was of the most primitive kind, 1
it was always looked upon as part of the work
of the Permanent Way, or Way and Works,
hut with the use of the modem block systems !
of signaling this department absolutely 1
demands tho services of special experts, who 1
must be wholly guided in their work by the '
requirements of the traffic, and while there- 1
fore still bound to work in close co-operation '
with tho Way and Works it may justly be ;
looked upon as a sister branch of the whole
work of the lines rather than as a section of
the Way.</p>
<p>It will be seen that this table gives eleven
departments instead of the “four or five”
mentioned by the Commission. Of these, 3, 4,5
and 6 represent the work of which the traffic
manager is, or should be, the controlling chief,
5 and 6 may be and often are, as here in Egypt,
united in one department. No. 7, the Way and
Works, is the department that lays the lines
and keeps them in repair and so forth, and it
must therefore work in the most perfect har-
mony with the Traffic but with the utmost
independence as to its internal organization
and working.</p>
<p>The Stores Department having to provide
all the materials of every kind necessary for
tho working of the railway, should have as
branches of its work the printing and lighting
(by oil, etc.), at present, I believe, worked in-
dependently. The internal organization of this
/department is a matter of great importance.
To be efficient there should be one head or
central and controlling office, aided by a num-
ber of local stores in required centers, for the
distribution of material.</p>
<p>Finally, the Account Department should be
in a measure at once the obedient servant and
the absolute master of all the others. It should
be divided, not as the Commission suggest
into two, but into three sections, the accounts
proper, the registering of income and expendi-
ture, the cash, and the audit This latter
should be quite independent.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BIG COTTON WAREHOUSE
DESTROYED.
Loss to the extent of nearly £50,000 was
caused last week by a fire at a cotton ware-
hc uie of the Lancashire and Yorkshire Rail-
way, at Oldham. Over 4,0C0 hales of cotton
were involved, and the blaze was tremendous.
The warehouse, which was 60 yards square,
was specially built for cotton storage. For-
tunately, tho flames were kept from the ad
joining warehouses. The cause of the fire is
unknown. The brigades were workirg up to
nor-land cot fired the area of the fire to an
iron structure 60 yards square. The steel
piDys supporting the roof were twisted, and
the building at one tijnp bad the appearance
trfa fcrwee,
lions of the Egyptian Army, and to induce a -
larger number of recruits to join the colours, t
One most successful method was that adopted I
with the native Egyptians by the military
authorities years ago.</p>
<p>In the “good old days” of Egypt—modern j
Egypt, of course—the recruit never know how i
long he would have to serve ; enlistment was 1
next door to banishment; the comfort of the
private soldiers was not thought of; barracks i
were offensively foul. However, when Lord i
Dufferin took charge all this was changed. The i
men were properly fed, clothed, and housed ; <
their pay was regular ; they were looked after i
when ill. The soldier actually got leave, and i
wont home to his native village with money in |
his pocket. No better inducement could be i
placed before the fellaheen.</p>
<p>But apparently the Shilluks and Dinkas of '
the Sudan have neither forgotten the old con-
ditions nor properly understood the new, and
are shy of taking service. These black men of
the Sudan, however, unlike the Egyptians, do
not take kindly to drill. They can scarcely be
described as muscular, being tall, slight, nar-
row-shouldered men, liable to chest complaints,
but they are full of activity, and have a posi-
tive love of fighting. The Dinks is first cousin
to “Fuzzy-Wuzzy,” and only needs the lead of
a capable British officer to face any foe. They
fear nothing, and appear to have more in
common with white troops than with their
Egyptian contemporaries.</p>
<p>The dramatic climax in Sir Arthur Conan
Doyle’s “Waterloo,” in which the old Guards-
man falls back dead after recounting his fight-
ing days, is recalled in a striking manner, says
the “Chronicle,” by the death of a Crimean
veteran, named Friend, at Shoe buryness. After
being unconscious for three days, Friend
seemed to rally somewhat, and the watchers
by his bedside noticed that he appeared to be
attempting to describe something that was
passing through his mind, Presently he was
heard to mutter, “Hark! Music 1 the band of
the 44th I” The old man raised himself np in
bed, while a faint smile Bickered about his face,
and then fell back almost immediately. He was
dead. Friend enlisted in the old "Fighting
44th,” and was made a sergeant fox a deed of
heroism at the battle of Ain a. He stood beside
Captain Nolan when the “Charge” was ordered
' at Balaolava, and Nolan's body fell at his feet
when the dead rider’s horse stopped after the
charge.</p>
<p>Something like coma or suspended anima-
tion has fallen upon the much vexed subject of
Army reconstruction. We may still believe
that things are in a bad way, but apparently
we do not greatly care, and are content to
leave the new men to work their will without
protest or interference. One very serious ques-
tion, that of our reserves, is being more and
more neglected, and to a dangerous degree.
The new sobbed of the General Service Army
may have much to recommend it, but when
fully in working order the reserve naturally
must suffer. The system of prolonged service
with the colours must of course impoverish the
reserve, and, so far, no steps have been taken
to meet the depletion. The true remedy is in
the development of the other part of the
scheme, the creation of the home or short ser
vice army from which men will pass quiokly
and in considerable numbers into the reserve.
It is very reasonably feared that candidates
if they have their choice between engaging
for three or nine years will almost certainly
elect the former, and we shall once more find
edefidtio the foreign</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BY JOSEPH OFFORD.
In the "Bulletin de la Socfctd Framjaioe
Jo Fnui les Archcologiqnes,” 2nd fascicule,
M. de Riddtr ^ivea a summary of the last
campaign of excavation carried out by M.
Gayet at Antinode. In this, his ninth season
of research, M. Gayet again devoted his atten-
tion entirely to the „ necropolis, the tombs
forming which are excavated in the hill ^
sides, or in the defiles of the hills behind
tho site of the ancient city. The entrances
to the sepulchers had, however, been almost
entirely covered up by the accumulating
sands of centuries, rendering it difficult to
disci v.-r, and dangerous to excavate them
nnlers all the debris was removed in the most
thorough and consequently costly manner, s
beyond the possibility of the funds at the
explorer’s disposal.</p>
<p>Not with standing these difficulties, the results I
of the work have been as successful as upon \
auy previous occasion, and will almost oer- j
taiuly tempt the society to provide the j
means for further carrying on the researches.
Among the sepulchers excavated is one be-
longing to an actor in the Olympic games, ]
a charioteer, .and a gladiator. Also one of a
lady named Khelnies, the singer of Oseris- j
Antinon". Many of the mummies have the
faoe and busts protected by cartonage masks,
or breastplates painted and gilded, the oolours
still brilliant aud the excellent workmanship
of the painter well preserved. There are the
usual terra cottas and vases of all ages,
from the old Mykenaen style to tho Persian, s
and even Byzantine epoch. A quantity of I
late ivory carvings are among the smaller t
class of relios.</p>
<p>As in previous years the quantity of dress £
fabrios and tissues forms the chief produot of i
the excavations. They are of immense variety f
and many of the designs of most fantastio oha- c
racter. M. de Bidder thinks one tableau re- e
presents an episode in the legend of Dionysius, t
as preserved in the Alexandrian oomedy.Many e
of the worked figures have the characternames i
embroil icred beside them iu Greek letters. i
The fi eat specimens of M. Gayet’s earlior i
finds of vestments are now in the Brussels c
Museum, and it is to be hoped that the oollec- t
tion obtained last year may be retained in i
Franoe.</p>
<p>During the year 1904 the Musses Royanx c
at Brussels have secured numerous additions e
to’the Egyptian collection there, chiefly by ]
pnrehase from the Amelineau sale b Paris, (
and by presentation from the British "Egypt
Exploration Fund."</p>
<p>Among the various objects, several provide
new names of members of royal families, or
notabilities, and deserve recording because the
notice of them may lead to the identification
of other memorials of the same personages, or
to connecting them with monuments of their
relatives, and thus hasten the time when the
great history ol Egypt, its Pharaohs, officials, -
and people, from Menes to Alexander can be 1
written.</p>
<p>Some funerary statuettes from theElKharjeh
oasis give us a new ohief of that distriot, “the
prince of the southern oasis,Nehmehy.”A frag-
ment of a bas-relief from Abydos, of Ramses
III. records a new queen consort of his, Thyi-
mer-en ast A larger portion of tbs stele is now
stored iu the Cairo Museum. Very interesting
from the scientific post of view, as displaying
tho metallurgical knowledge of the ancient
Egyptians in very early times, is a oopper vase
which Professor Petrie asoribas to Papi I. of
the 6th dynasty, and as Mr. Quibell found
large bronze statues of that period atHieracon-
opolis, the bronze founders of that epoch
must have been experts.</p>
<p>Last year the Brussels Museum received a
large imitation of a feather plume, stuccoed
and gilded, which on close examination proved
to be of bronze; it therefore may be considered
to have fitted into the head dress of such a
brotize statue. Among the thousands of objects
found by M. LegTab last year at the
Karnak temple he enumerates “grandee plumes
ornant la coiffure d’Osiris en bronze borustd
et dob.” From the Amelineau sale came a
large vase ornamented with a figure of Osiris
incised upon the clay of the vase, and bearing
a long hieroglyphic inscription giving the
names of two priests. It dates from the 19th
dynasty or thereabouts, to judge from the
workmanship. Of the same period is a little
miniature sarcophagus of a scribe named Si
1 Isis, and a statuette of a certain Peduhor, son
1 of Pedubastit.</p>
<p>The antiquities received from the "Egypt
Exploration Fond” include objects inscribed
with names of the earliest dynasty monarchs,
such as Nar Mer, Hotel-Aharri, and Noteren,
also a princess Neit-Hotep, perhaps of the
first dynasty. These were completed by the
acquisition of a gTanite fragment bearing the
r name of King Den. Of the same epoch are
f two ivory figures of a dog and a lion; the
3 latter an exceedingly well-executed piece of
/ realistic work.</p>
<p>An interesting relic is the wooden "plan-
t Odette" of a scribe of the Roman epooh, valu-
h able as a specimen of Coptio calligraphy, for
i hoth sides of the object are covered with
i. Coptio writing giving the accounts of some
f church. A small collection of papyri is selected
a from the vast stores recovered by Messrs.
y Grenfell and Huntione contains the commence-
o ment of chant 19 of the Iliad, another the
e beginning of Euripides' Audromacho; whilst 18
n others are fiscal or. legal documents.
London, May 12.
IVORY.— The following quantities have
arrived for the quarterly sales, July 25 :—
Tons, owt qrs. lbs
East Indian............. 2	4	2	1
Egyptian................ 8	9	0	7
West Coast African....	-	1	0	8
Abyssinian.............. -	5	8	10
Lisbon.................. -	1	8	21
Total........ f
Deliveries, sboe -April auotic
GUM ARABIC.—Of 16 c
peas 77s.</p>
<p>Mr. Joseph Chamberlain presided at the
annual dinner of the London School of Tropical
Medicine, held at the Hotel Cecil, London, on
the 10th inst. The guests numbered nearly
500. In proposing the toast, “The London
School of Tropical Medicbe,” Mr. Chamberlain,
in the course of his speech, said : Just think
for a moment of one or two well-known instan-
oea. Compare the condition of Egypt as it was
a quarter of a century ago, when this rich coun-
try was apparently b the down stage, and it
seemed hardly possible that it could ever agab
rise from its ashes. Compare it as it was, almost
impotent owing to the extortions practiced b
it, with the Egypt of Lord Cromer—the Egypt
of to-day. Look at the case perhaps even more
extraordinary, of the Sudan—five years ago
devastated by the brutal tyranny of its rulers,
the people tortured and oppressed, the whole
country depopulated till there were not enough
souls in the land to till it and gab its riohes.
Now see it, a few years later, rising bto a
greater prosperity than ever before.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BECK & DO’S PILSENER BEEF
BHBMEN.
FEARS BO E0BB9T 00B1F11TI0H FOB QUAIITT.
N.B.— Inferior Banned now being offered to lfan
tgn ef certain good mkI*>.
Beware et rrflly 4D»cv»d acmtstiter* mutiny
hn Hb tuy (mini bin wBsia
This Series ofPens
An^ write as smoothly
/MB as a Lead Fencil.
Neither Scratch
nor Spurt, the points
being rounded by a special
Anti-Blotting Pens.
Assorted Sample Box for seven stamps from the
WORKS, BIRMINGHAM.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>LONDON COMMERCIAL REPORT.
...6	2	1	19
auctions 35 tons.
>f 16 cases 1 Bold, Trieste
EGYPT’S PROGRESS.
LIVERPOOL COTTON PENALTIES.
DAVIES
Cheap Prepaid Advertisements
Under this headbag advertisements are re-
sorted at the following rates :—
ONCE 3 TIKES 6 TIKES
15 words	. . .	p.T.	5	P.T.	10	P.T.	15
80 words	...	„	8	„	18	„	24
Every 10	words,	\	9	,	.
beyond SO. . .	/	2	"	4	..	»
The address is oounted. The advertisement
must appear on consecutive days for above
rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged
for advertisements not appearing consecutively.
ADVERTISING AGENTS.—The beet publio
Advertising sites b Alexandria belong to
U- Veetri Sc Co., Advt Agents, St Catherine’s
Square. Special rates for permanent clients.
Moderate terms. Prompt despatch.
______________ 25642-31-12-906
---------------------------:	& Co.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>Cheap Prepaid Advertisements	
Under this heading advertisements are b- Continental Hotel Buildings,
serted at the following ratee :—	CAIRO
id..*, . . . rT» ^ St. David's Buildings.
80 words ...	„ 8	„ 18	„ 24	ALEXANDRIA,
2	4 .. » and 35-37 Noble Street
The address is oounted. The advertisement	LONDON, E.O.
must appear on consecutive days for above	__
rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged
for advertisements not appearing consecutively. TN 1 " V. fll *1
ADVERTISING AGENTS.—The been public	
Advertising sites b Alexandria belong to
£ Vestri & Co., Advt. Agents, St Catbmne’s	TYfQ YV AT*C1
feteDrapers
________________ 95642-31-12-906	J
and Outfitters.
“Egyptian Gazette offices.	26888-	___
Bu“.	Beg respectfully to an-
Alexandria, Address, Poet Office Box 85.	I10U11C6 til at th-GV h&Y8
80-6-905A	.	, ,,	. J
“	.————-----------received their various
DORMAN & Co. have just received a new ,	-,	.	, -	,	.	,
D supply of Tennis Balia, Rackets, and StOGELS IU tlI6 lftbGBt
Cri”_______________________^	styles suitable for the
Preset Season.
and style guaranteed.	26981-6-3	___
EXPERIENCED NURSE would take charge	^
A-^ of infant for free passage to England	*
£»No-_
tor sale.—Cart itook,,. md H.™., A large assortment of
^ "te Blacks, Blues, Scotch,
------------------ Irish & flams Tweeds.
G'K.SS'tE All garments cut by ex-
luk’s, Mousky, Cairo._25959-12-5 experienced English Cut-
A RABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian
tutor to Europeans. Apply M7 Hhefik,
“Egyptian Gazette offices.	25888-
DLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9, No. 7
D £11. W.T. Kmmens, 99 Rue Attarine,
Alexandria, Address, Poet Offioe Box 85.
______________	80-6-905A
DORMAN & Co. have just received
AJ supply of Tennis Balls, Rackets
Cricket Bats.	25f
received anew
Rackets, and
25980-6-3
AA P.T. 250. Best English doth, latest fit
and style guaranteed.	25981-6-3
EXPERIENCED NURSE would take charge
Aj of infant for free passage to England
June, July. Apply, No. 25,949, "Egyptian
Gazette" Office.	26949-6-6
DOR SALK—Cart, Donkey, and Harness.
A- £25. .Apply, No. 26,952, “ Egyptian
Gazette Office.
f'OVERNESS CART, in good condition, I t©rSj fit find 8tyl0 glI8“
P.O.B. 686^°dairo*1	PP 7 *25977^8 ranted.
A Liverpool correspondent writee on the
11th inst:—The Liverpool Cotton Association,
Limited, after careful consideration, deoided
yesterday to take action in respect ot the four
associate members who have seriously broken
the brokerage rules of the Association. The
fines imposed a few weeks ago of £250 each
have not been paid, nor will they.it is officially
stated. The Association will now take steps to
deprive the four Association members from
previous privileges and rights. This is practi-
cally expulsion. The four cotton spining
companies they represent b Oldham will be
deprived of the benefit ot the quarter per oent.
commission charge. The member who was fined
£1,000 (Mr. 8. Clegg) has paid it The other
member (Mr. A. Huntingdon) committed sui-
cide yesterday.The Lancashire trade is scarcely
likely to take ap the matter at present.
Ill OUNTAIN CAMP, for boys during sum
ill mer holidays. Apply, Peroival Mayall,
B.A., Headmaster, English Sohool, Cyprus.
25921-48-11</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>Calendar of Coming Events
ALEXANDRIA.
May.
Fri. 19
Office.
TO LET, Summer mouths. Position
sea. Apply No. 25,983, "Gazette”
25988-6-2
T ANCASTER HOUSE, Sharia Wabour-el,
AJ Moyah, Cairo.’Comfortable apartments-
with or without board. Terms very reasonable.
25599-16-6-906A
ill mer holidays. Appl
B.A., Headmaster, Eng ha
A varied stock of
Ladies’ Blouses, Boas,
Skirts, Belts, &c.
Careful attention is
paid, to Ladies'outfits
YTURSE WANTED for two English children. -*
i-l £24. Apply, No. 25,972, " Egyptian •all J? /TV
ttMQtte” offices-___________________25792-6-4 SUltOOk JOT l OUVS UJ)
NICE FURNISHED ROOM to let to Engluh I -	-T<1
gentleman in private fiat, Greek quarter.! fJiJ> Nl.lP,
Apply No. 25,986, “Egyptian Gazette” offioes.1	^ *****
25986-3-1
SINGING LESSONS recommended by the
famous tenor Jkah ds Reszee given by
Herr B. Weohsler of Heidelberg University.
Voioe production systematic. Apply for trial
lesson, press extracts, Hen B. Weohsler, Post
Offioe, Cairo.	25929-12-10
Fri. 19 A 8. 0. grounds. Tennis match.
K. S. C. v. A. 8. C.
Alhambra. Italian operetta oom-
pany in AH Baba. 9 pjn.
Sat. 20 Race from Sidi Qaber to Alexandria
by pupils ot Scotch School. 6a.m.
A. C. C. grounds. Cricket. Gar-
rison XI v. A. C. C. 1.80 p.m.
Mustapha Rifle Range. Praotice
by B. R. C. 2.80 pjn.
San Stefano Casino. Opening Ball
of Season. 10 p.m.
Sun. 21 San Stefano Caebo. Concert 10 a m.
Gabbari. Pigeon Shooting. 2.80 p.m.
Toes. 23 Cricket B. T. C. v. Sergeants of
the Berks. Commence 2 p.m. on
AC. C.
Ban Stefano Casbo. A.LM. &
D. S. Conoert 9.15 p.m.
Thuis. 25 A. 8. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting. 3.80 p.m.
Conoert at Sailors' and Soldiers’
Institute. 8 p.m.
Sat 27 AS. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting. 8.30 p.m.
OAI RO.
Zoological Gardens. Performance by
Ghizeh Boys’ Band b afternoon.
Shepheard’s Hotel. Meeting of
K. G. S. 5 p.m.
Esbekieh Gardens. Performance
by British Militaiy Band. 9 to
11 p.m.
Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
British Military Band. 9 to 11
p.m.
Masonio Hall. Meeting Idris lodge.
9,80 p-B.
SiNGIRQ LB880NS recommended by the	f’
famous tenor Jkak de Reszee given by	IT IG I 1 I LY
Herr B. Weohsler of Heidelberg University	^ -LiA! -L KJ
bMon,Ppres8 extracts, Herr B. Weohsler, B OUTFITTING:
Thelatest novelties in Ties,
^ CoUarS) ghirt8) al0TeBj &&
Hosiery in all the newest
moderate. For particulars apply, Magariua makes, (Camel Hair brand
Viotoria, Alexandria.	25963-6-4 ■	. *»
A- Eleotrio light; bath. Independent en-
trance. English,roeto Reetante,Cairo. 26965-6-4
the summer, a large, airy, roomy, Fur
; a speciality).
A- family, Boulevard d’Allemagne, Rue Cdsar,
No. 1. Splendid position.	25991-3-1
1 House \ two flats; garden ; splendid situ a-1	.	.
tion. Apply, No. 25,854, "Egyptian Gazette” i We are also making a special display
°|Bcefl-_	_	25982-6-2 jn the Drapery Department, oon-
TO LET.—Nice furnished rooms in French nietine of Household Linen, Blan-
family, Boulevard d’AUemagne, Rue Cdsar,	®	,	«...
No. 1. Splendid position.	25991-3-1 kets, Calicoes, Eider-down guilts,
---------------------------------- Cushions,&o.,Ac., whioh are mark-
| HB HUTCHINSON NURSING HOME ed at Buch figare8 as to oommand
A in Sharia el Falaki, Cairo, is now com-	D
fleted and open for the reception of patients. attention.
urther particulars, terms, eta, can be obtain-	----
ed from the Resident Medioal Offioer.	«	. n r* i
__________________________muM'Roots & Shoes in the latest
May.
Prl 19
YTb^k”ariitt ^'shapes, Bags, Trunks & all
^TJZ^!tXmLT^t\Leather goods in great va-
metic, and served as Cashier, Aocountant, and eyjpfu
Interpreter respectively. Apply, No. 25,993, (
“Egyptian Gazette” owes.	25998-6-1
-------------------------1 AIbo a large assorted supply of the
TiSA*iLrD="1 HAT8, CAPS. UMBRELLAS,
Offioe, Cairo.	25966 4, WALKINQSTICKS, RUQS, 1
RANTED at Port Sudan, for Government' 5	TOPHI FR
VV Works, an estimating Draughtsman, . TOILET REQUISITES, AO.
salary L.E. 18 per mensum. Applications b j	-
writing to Aset. Director of Works, War M ■	|%	n «
ufa-_________________12211 Davios Bryan & Co.
11/ ANTED. — English Governess, knowbg ,
AgMoa^RwIfosstto!*11 Aw'>' siwh _ Cairo ft Maxandriv
117ANTED at Port Sudan, for Government.
*1 Works, a typewriting Bngliah Clerk,
salary L.K 16 per menus. Applications in I
writing to Asst Director of Works, War
Offioe, Cairo.	25966-4 >
WANTED at Port Sudan, for Government
Works, an estimating Draughtsman,
salary L.E. 18 per mensum. Applications b
writing to Aset Director of Works, War
Offioe, Cairo.	26967-4
11/ ANTED. — English Governess, knowbg
>' little Prenoh or Italian. Apply Mrs. Joseph
Aghion, 80 Rue Rosette.	86990 6 1</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

