<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hank Thompson</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-15">October 15, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-02">November 2, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 2, 1905</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>FIGHTING IN RUSSIA.</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DISTURBANCES CONTINUE.</head></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>MANY KILLED AND WOUNDED</head>
                        <dateline>Odessa, November 1.</dateline>
                            <p>The provocative tactics of the police precipitated several encounters yesterday, which culminated in desperate fighting. It is reported that 200 men were killed or injured. (Reuter)</p>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, November 1.</dateline>
                            <p>Eight men were killed and many injured in encounters between the troops and demonstrators yesterday evening.
                            </p><p>A number of mass meetings have resolved to demand full political amnesty, the removal of the troops from the streets, and the formation of a militia to maintain order. They also demand the removal of General Trepoff.
                            The Tsar has directed the abrogation of the dictatorship decrees in Finland, and is summoning a Diet.
                            M. Pobiedonostzeff, the Procurator of the Synod, has resigned.
                            Many persons were killed at Lodz and elsewhere yesterday. The troops fired volleys into peaceable processions.	(Reuter)</p>
                            </div><div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, November 1.</dateline>
                            <p>A great movement in Finland is firmly demanding a free constitution.
                            General Trepoff has placarded the city with warnings to the inhabitants to maintain order, as all disturbances will be suppressed in the most rigorous manner. The streets are again being patrolled by troops.
                            The troops have closed the University, which has hitherto been the rallying point of the revolutionary party.
                            The mutinies and assassination of Admiral Birilef and General Treyoff remain unconfirmed.	(Reuter)
                            </p></div><div type="item"><dateline>Odessa, November 1. </dateline>
                            <p>There were 37 killed and 81 seriously wounded and taken to hospital here yesterday. The fighting continues.
                            A mob of roughs has taken possession of the city, and is plundering the shops and shooting the inhabitants. The civil militia is powerless, and the authorities will not interfere.	(Reuter)
                            </p></div><div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, November 1.</dateline>
                            <p>The Cossacks dispersed the students who were holding a demonstration in front of the University.
                            Disorders continue in Warsaw and Odessa.(Havas)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>JAPANESE LOAN.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>NOTHING DECIDED YET.</head>
                            <dateline>London, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>The "Morning Post” announces that the Japanese loan will be issued in a day  or two. (Reuter)
                                </p></div><div type="item"><dateline>London, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>M. Takshashi states that Japan has not yet decided as to a new loan.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>DAMARALAND RISING.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>GERMAN LOSSES IN DAY’S FIGHT.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>Berlin, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>The Governor of German East Africa has asked for a reinforcement of 4,200 men in order to suppress the rising. The majority of these will be raised locally.	(Reuter)
                                </p></div><div type="item"><dateline>Cape Town, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>The Germans lost 13 killed, including 3 officers, and 36 wounded and missing, in a day’s fighting with 400 Hottentots in Damaraland.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        </div><div type="item"><head>THE SWEDISH CROWN.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>Christiania, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>The Storthing has granted authority to the Government to negotiate the acceptance of the Crown by Prince Charles of Denmark. (R.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>M. LOUBET RETURNS TO FRANCE.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>Paris, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>M. Loubet has returned.	(Havas)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>BRITISH SQUADRON FETED.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>Annapolis, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>The British Squadron has arrived. A great naval reception and the most elaborate fetes are being arranged.	( Reuter </p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>RACING.</head></div>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>London, November 1.</dateline>
                                <p>Cambridgeshire Stakes. 1. Velocity; 2. Santry; 3. Dean Swift.
                                18 ran. Won by a length. Three-quarters of a length, divided 2nd and 3rd. Betting.—7 to 2 against Velocity; 40 to 1 against Santry; 50 to
                                1 against Dean Swift,	(Reuter)</p></div><cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Ports and Lighthouses S.S. Aida left Alexandria this morning for the Red Sea.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Port Sudan.—The official opening of the new Sudan port has been fixed to take place on the 27th January.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Sudan Railways —The Cairo Khartoum winter time-table will not come into force before the 10th proxo.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Mahmal Escort, this year, will be composed of 2 0 troops in active service. Formerly, the escort consisted of discharged soldiers.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>An Egyptian Wanderer — A fine specimen of the Egyptian flamingo has been shot on the sand dunes near Graveline, a few miles from Calais.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Sanitary Department. — Messrs. John Smith Purdy, Antoine Agheretes, and Bedros Michael Ormanian have been authorized to practise as doctors in Egypt.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Ports and Lighthouses Administration.— The tender submitted by Mr. Ed. Almagia has been accepted for the construction of timber quays on the Gabbari coast.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Bank of Egypt, Ltd.—Mr. Umberto Albini has been authorised by the board of directors to sign for the sub-manager in conjunction with either the general manager or the sub-manager.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>New Hotel at Luxor.—The Upper Egypt Hotels Company will shortly, begin the construction of a new hotel at Luxor. A notice on the subject appears in our advertisement columns to-day.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>This Morning’s Execution. - Rohaiem Youssef, the murderer of a compatriot, suffered the last penalty of the law in the execution chamber at Hadra prison this morning at 9 o’clock. The execution was not marked by any untoward incident.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Central Egypt Exploration Co.—Application has been made to the Committee of the London Stock Exchange to appoint a special settling day in Central Egypt Exploration Company, Limited.—100,000 Vendors’ shares of £1 each fully paid (Nos. 8 to 100,007).</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Alhambra Theatre—The Gardet French comedy company arrived at Alexandria this morning from Cairo, where they made their final appearance at the Esbekieh Theatre last night in Le File Surnaturel. They will open with the same piece at the Alhambra Theatre this evening.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Egyptian Institute—The opening sitting of the Institute will take place on the 6th inst. On this occasion M. Maspero will deliver an oration on the late M. Oppert and M. Du ilh ; M. Arvanitakis will speak on astronomy, and M. Fourtan on fossils, while M. George Legrain will give his lecture on Karnak.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Delta Canals - The Ministry of Public Works has proposed that the undermentioned classes of boat authorised to use the navigable canals in the Delta should be of the following dimensions in metres, the figures respectively representing the maximum length and breadth: steam barges, 35, 6,25; oa;go boats 25, 5; tugs, 20, 4; country boats, 22, 6. The above measurements are only for the principal canals.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>English Tailoring in Egypt is rapidly developing, and among the fashionable West-end firms, who are pushing their connection are Messrs. Thomas and Sons, of 32, Brook-street, London, W., whose representative, Mr. Botham, is now staying at the Hotel Abbat, where he will be pleased to see any customers. A special feature in regard to this enterprise is that Mr. Botham will remain in Egypt throughout this season, so that a perfect fit may be relied upon.</p></div></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>BECK AND GO’S PILSNEEBBIEfi
                            PEABS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOB QUALITY
                            MB. — Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good dreles. Beware of mtty
                            SUPERIOR BRAND OF BEER.
                            CARLTON HOTEL,
                            MuraiY (near Alexandria.)
                            BAMLEH’S FASHIONABLE HOTEL rATBONiran bt thn run,
                            Fan y—*>■ trmm T.T. Nile. Flatten trmm OAtra »U«»t at MiMriw etatfaa.
                            C AOUlLINa.
                            Anglo-American Nile Steamers
                            HOTEL oompajsiy.
                            Birtr Tnammrt of Oooda between Alexandria and Cairo. THRtE SAILINGS A-WEEK.
                            Agents at Alexandria t
                            WAUHOUSC M., ITS,</p></div><cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>ALEXANDRIA’S NEW PARK.</head>
                        <head>THE  RESTORATION OF NOUZHA.</head>
                        <p>Nouehs Gardens, situated on the bank of the Mahmoudieh Canal, near Ramleh, destined shortly to become one of the fashionable rendezvous of Alexandrians. For years past the grounds, at one time beautiful, have been allowed to go to wreck and ruin, being only used for an occasional picnic party.
                            A charge has now come over the place, however. The Municipality, at the beginning ol the present year, very wisely decided to take the property in hand, and restore it to its pristine beauty ; and judging by what we saw during a recent visit, a most excellent beginning has been made. If the necessary funds are forthcoming Alexandria will in a very short time be endowed with a park and grounds worthy of a big city, attractive not only to residents—who are sore to make it their favorite drive—but also to visitors.
                            The grounds now present a most charming and fascinating aspect. Avenues, alleys, and paths have been laid out, all the undergrowth has been removed, the grotto and pond have been completely relaid, hedges trimmed, and new beds and a lawn laid out. Great attention has been paid to the trees; of which some very rare specimens are to be found, and these have been brought Well into view. A special plot, shaded and cool, has been cleared out for the use of children,
                            We particularly noticed a plot laid out with chrysanthemums. There are a thousand of these plants to be seen in full bloom, and they present a striking and most beautiful mass of colours, some blooms being particularly noticeable for their vivid colour and size. It is quite, a good show, and Augurs well for the future.
                            We hope that now this excellent beginning has been made the work will be kept up, and that by next year, with a band day and the necessary accommodation provided for afternoon tea, etc., Nousha will become the rendezvous of our local "smart set.”</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                            <p>The Khedive held an Iftar Abdeen Palace on Tuesday evening.
                                His Highness spent yesterday at Koubbeh
                                Palace.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</head>
                            <p>The directors of the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Limited, have decided to recommend to the shareholders at the general meeting to be held on November 21 the payment of a dividend of 7s. 6d. per share for the half-year to August 31, making with the interim dividend of 5s. per share paid June 1,12 1/2 per cent, for the year. They place £30000 to a pension reserve fund and carry forward £36,000.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE CRONIER DEBACLE.</head>
                            <p>In a letter to the London "Standard,” on speculation in sugar, Mr. Geo. Mathieson, managing director of Messrs. Clarke, Nickolls, and Coombs, Ltd., says :— The French expert at the Brussels Convention, the late M. Cromer, although in the end he overreached himself; quite correctly recognised in that international compact the finest Instrument for speculation that had been forged for many a day. Its restrictions in preventing the free circulation of sugar delivered consumers for a time into the cornerers’ hands. It was largely owing to the small surpluses of Russia, etc., that Mr. Martineau despises, finding their way round, and setting free for export sugar otherwise required in non-prohibited countries, that the corner was ultimately broken up. Although M. Cronier, by attempting to grasp to much, came to disaster, other more fortunate speculators succeeded in fleeting sugar consumers in this country alone to the tune of at least £6,000,000 during the last twelve months, as can be seen by the Board of Trade figures. It is no mean achievement, and while the convention is in operation, other speculators, when chance offers, will work it to the same end more effectively, and, perhaps, guided by the Cronier disaster, more wisely for themselves. But we are hopeful our lesson has been learnt, and that no British Government will be mad enough to renew the contention, or ever again enter into a similar compact, In an article on the financial situation and the position of the Basque de Ftaooe, the "Monitear des InWrtts Maferiels” remarks:--
                                " Il est certain que si les traites Cronier avaient été présentées à la Banque de France, elles auraient été presentées. Le tireur était depuis longtemps assez suspect an point de vue do-crédit dans le monde 'financier. Voici an moins deux ans, dit-én aojonrd’hni, qne le président des Raffinerie et Sucreries Say était au-dessous de ses affaires. On ne oonçoit pas qne dés banques et banqnieirs de premier ordre aient pu lai faire orédit, et rien qne le taux de 8 f/0, qne M. Cronier consentait à payer à ses fscomptenrs alors qne le bon papier trouvait à se placer à 1 1/2 et 2%, devait mettre les banquiers en méfiance ”</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                            <p>The Ellerman S.S. Assiout sailed last night for Liverpool direct with a full cargo, including 4,667 bales cotton.
                                The Moss liner Seti sailed from Malta yesterday noon and is expected here on Saturday afternoon next, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p></div></div>
                <cb n="3"/><div type="item"><div type="item"><head>THE MECCA PILGRIMAGE</head>
                        <head>GOVERNMENT CIRCULAR</head>
                        <p>The Egyptian Government has issued a circular relative to those who wish  accompany the Mahmal caravan to the Hadjas, in which it points out the advantages which are gained by making the pilgrimage under such conditions.
                            This year, as in former years, the Government has decided to allow those who are desirous of so doing, and who undertake to submit to the prescribed conditions, to accompany the" Mahmal caravan.
                            Those who take Advantage of this offer of the Government will he placed under the protection of the Emir el Hag and the military escort of the Malmat, and in case of need they will receive immediate medial care and ebemists, who are at the disposal of the accompanying pilgrimage are also attached to the Caravan. The journey will also be accomplished by the shortest possible and least laborious route, and under special conditions as regards comfort safety, and prestige. The cost of the expedition will be lessened by joining the caravan, as pilgrims will profit by the advantageous arrangements which the Emir el Hag is able to make regarding camels.
                            In So far as the expenses of the journey  concerned, experience has shown that the sums deposited in former years have been insufficient, and for the present year it has been decided that those accompanying the Mahmal must make the following deposits, according to the degree of comfort they desire to travel in: L.E. 25.500mm. for each first class passenger; including charge for one camel (an extra charge of L.E. 13.500 mm, is made for every additional camel); L.E 23 for the second class passenger with [    ] camel ; L.E. 20.500mm. for the third class passenger with one camel; LE. 14 whenever camel is shared by two pilgrims ; L.E. 10.500m. for every child from 4 to 10 years of age who shares a camel  another child or with a parent.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>NO QUARANTINE IN TURKEY.</head>
                            <p>A telegram from Constantinople states that the quarantine measures applied to arrivals from Alexandria have been suppressed.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>WESTERN EGYPT RAILWAY.</head>
                            <p>The Board of the Corporation of Western Egypt, Ltd. have decided that the railway now in the course of construction from the Egyptian State Railway at Abou Ticht, in the Nile Valley, to Khargey in the Oasis of Khargeb, shall be known as the Western Egypt Railway</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND ALLOTMENT.</head>
                            <p>The statement to which publicity has been given, to the effect that Lord Cromer had expressed his Sympathy With the objects of the Anglo-Egyptian Lind Allotment Co., is without foundation.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>JUDICIAL APPOINTMENTS.</head>
                            <p>Commendatore G. Moriondo, Vice-President of the Mixed Court of Appeal, Alexandria, has been appointed Procureur-General of the Court of appeal at Cagiliari.
                                M.P. Prampolini, judge in the Cairo Mixed Tribunal, has also been appointed Procureur-General of the court of appeal at Casale.
                                These two magistrates have been placed at the disposal of the Egyptian Government in order to continue their present functions.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>NILE SEASON BEGINS.</head>
                            <p>A special sleeping-car will be attached to the train leaving for Luxor to-morrow night for those tourists who have come to Egypt by the Vectis and who wish to pay a short visit to Luxor and its surrounding. For the return journey the car will be ached to the train leaving Luxor on Monday evening.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                            <div type="item"><p>It is expected that the Kind and Queen may attend the marriage of Mr. Peroy Machell with Countess Victoria Gleichen, which is to take place in the chapel Royal, St. Jame's Palace, some time in December.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>The Sirdat is leaving for Khartoum this evening.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>The name of the Governor of the Suez Canal, H. E. Mustapha Ibadi Pasha, was inadvertently omitted from the list of those present at the reception by H.R.H. the Prince of Wales on the arrival of H.M.S. Renown, ad also from the list of those who attended the reception and dinner given by Admiral Sir Wilmott Fawkes on board H.M.S Powerful, mentioned in our issue of 28th October.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>M. de la Bouliniere, French Diplomatic Agent and Consul General, is arriving from Europe on Tuesday next.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Moberly Bery, Assitant Commandant of Cairo City Police, went to Port Said yesterday to meet Mansfield Pashs, the Commandant.</p></div></div></div>
                <cb n="4"/><div type="item"><div type="item"><head>A SUDAN HERO.</head>
                        <head>THE LATE SIR CHARLES WILSON</head>
                        <p>The "Times" gives the following appreciation of he Sudan career of the late Sir Charles Wilson:--- When troubles with Egypt were brewing in1882, Sir Charles Wilson volunteered for special service in that country, and after the
                            [Next few lines of text are illegible]
                            Lord Dufferin’s mission until the end of 1883. For the Egyptian campaign he received a medal and the Khedive a Star and promotion by brevet to the rank of colonel in the Army. He also received the honorary degree of D.C.L. from Oxford in 1883. Up to that time honors had been gained in peaceful fields either by scientific ____________ or by ___matic successes. As a natural consequence of _______________________ his military advancement had been relatively slow. The chance for him to earn distinction in the leadership of mend did not come until he had lost the habit of thinking and acting as a soldire. All Sir Charles Wilson's Oriental experience and familiarity with Ara________ marked him as an _____________ to direct the intelligence branch of a force operating against native tribes in the Sudan. For these duties therefore, he was appointed Deputy-Adjutant and Quartermaster-General on the Headquarters staff with Lord Wolseley's expedition for ____ relief of General Gordon in September, 1884. One of his subordinates then was Captain Horatio Herbert Ki_____, who, holding temporary rank as a major in the Egyptian Army, had been sent up the Nile by Sir Evelyn Wood earlier that year to prepare the way for an advance by enlisting the services of Sheikhs who had no thrown in their lot with the Dervishes. Much of the organisation on which Sir Charles Wilson relied afterwards for news of the Mahdi's movements was thus rady at hand. Nevertheless he had to exercise great discretion and keen judgement in sifting the evidence of agents whose stories were more often than not untrustworthy. That he performed these duties to Lord Wolseley's entire satisfaction is proved by frequent -mention in despatches, though events several thinks discounted the value of his conclusions. He did however, succeed in establishing communications with the beleagureed her in _______________________ were kept up to the last by ___________________ fidelity to the cause they served _____________ in question simply because _____________ taken did not give them a _____________ any important secrets. When Sir Herbert Stewart's little force set out from Korti on January 6, 1885, for a hazardous but glorious march across the Bayuda desert, Sir Charles Wilson accompanied it. To him Lord Wolseley had entrusted a letter for General Gordon, with orders that he should deliver it into the hands of the defender of Khartoum. There was no thought at that time of the possibility of his having to command the desert column if Sir Herbert Stewart should be killed or wounded seriously. Lord Wolseley had made arrangements, which were shattered when in Colonel Fred Burnaby fell fighting at Abou Klea.
                            After Sir Herbert Stewart was wounded fatally in the second battle at Gubat the command devolved on Sir Charles Wilson in cirute of his seniority. Being thrust suddenly into the position of military leader for which previous training had not qualified him he did his best to cary out Sir Herberts Stewart's plans. Whether he delayed too long after Gordon's steamers had joined him or simply took the common-sense precaution which circumstances demanded, is a question about which differences of opinion will alas exist. There was certainly nothing to justify the bitter attack made upon him because of his failure to reach Khartoum before it fell. A scapegoat was wanted to draw off attention from the blunder of others in higher authority, and he suffered accordingly. The attack delivered by SIr. Charles Wilson at Metemmeh on January 21 did not though unsuccessful, involve waste of time, because the four steamers from Khartoum only reached him while his troops were being withdrawn from that attempt. The next day, a hostile force having been reported near Shendy, Sir Charles Wilson thought it necessary to make a reconnaissance down the river in that direction. Then it was discovered that the frail boat needed repairs to their machinery. These were not completed until late January 23. The following morning Sir Charles Wilson,having with him a few British soldiers in red coats and less than 200 Sudanese, started Khartoum. When after encountering many difficulties and fighting their way past Derviah batteries, the steamer were not within sight of Khartoum, they were too late. The place had fallen two days earlier, and General Gordon was dead. The belief that this catastrophe might have been averted but for the delay at Metemmeh and in the connoitring towards Shendy rests on no trustworthy evidence. </p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ISLAM IN THE SUDAN.</head>
                            <p>Shortly after the appearance in the Press of Slatin Pasha’s statement, that no Moslem preachers were to be seen in the southern portion of the Sudan. "Al Moayad" gave publicity to a scheme for preaching the Koran in those parts of the country where Christian missionaries have been allowed to preach the Gospel. Many moelena notables are said to be very anxious to prop___ Islam among the heathens of the Southern Sudan, and are generously supporting the scheme. According to "Al Moayad" a sheikh ___ stated that if a sum of about L.E. 400 were allowed him he would leave for the Sudan and would under take to _______ a _______________ and preach the Koran there. </p></div></div>
                <cb n="5"/><div type="item"><div type="item"><head>LE KRACH DES SUCRERIES</head>
                        <head>COMMENTSAUVER LA SITUATION</head>
                        <p>M. le Directaur del' "Egyptia Gazette" Une partig [                             ]de Sir Wiliam Willcock est cella qui traita des anciennes Usines de la D >ï- Saniefa.
                            Il fst aujourd'hui oftnaUttneot i>Metaté>aeé lee 9 usines % Usba/sh,
                            ï:^i	:
                            ateliers de Minieh, vatantLE. l.gÿfjMfc
                            La rapport annonoe que les Saentâeed’B-gypté ont dépensédepuis Tachâtde Cas aAf j ngqa’àl* oWture dadmisrbilto LJL SOCMWO poor modifier les dites usines qai repré eotaftfct donc une valdur indastrféUe A*~tL9»Mle lors dé rschat te 1908 ïoitT fie. itfOOtfOOO én ohiffresYtads.
                            Or oes usines ont été achetées pourri*'d* fra. ..50.000.000- par les Suereriée .dlgypte, payables en 20 ans par *meti*iaHtés de I* 64.600, areo la olahae dtabonfoeeu §u contrat que si:nne école des’ sèmes trielités restait impayée la totalité deé mines aRlsur» àmélioratiohs éetoqrnereieat eux vendeurs : la Daira SaniekSjagar Corporation.
                            |^s actionnaires dae.Sacreriaa oiit donc été
                            refiûts défis.' 26.000.000i offerte mentf formels odholus par le Cbnséü d'Admi-
                            .......
                            Comment expliquer. ■fn/jhynr dfls intéiffts oontïeires l'insistance |as oéiûmisaé^esAreÉda-Amnder aa . jhgnjoommist h psfnc^nt il’sm nouvelle semestriattté échéant le maaseoaiaht àlon que (grâoe> oettè cl* uwU. contrat 1401 ae . rfttorfina »utre tas jftnd4nr«)rW Wp. payement, libérerait nitihiwml !■
                            Sucreries d'Egypte des pstepaiAi ëliriiiniin si la dApraeeerab: d'usines /dont allé; RAbata que tairez et ‘qui «nttare*^knJéz|(oit^Mm par suite du JUhflaa dammàam	^
                            en lui RnomisanVitadQottoimtfcdés annuités déjh payées, prèsde Pi». 4OOO.O09;...
                            Du moment «qu'ilert probvd. perde rapport daSir William, que, Jm Administrateurs des Sucreries n’otRpas'oûvmt W'ÿëûz de leurs actionnaires'bd* ‘la tÜêur ÛMiôfé^da oes
                            «Wl Mfctfitade résiR Rengagements y relatif* pourquoi ne paeenpœfitprî, .	. gM^r.
                            Las 60.000.000 mentionnés qq^ dnâient gndaaUqMoIttro W*.
                            •““î “*•'** ««W«nt 4>M>K«(4wJ*
                            u D*“* *» 1890 par, jn. h nation	qqtte
                            8odS:é fcb
                            moyennant payement comptant de oes neuf
                            fe eeR^^jftsja re^pe deoontanuec àpayreetçRa*. *J8F
                            m^üraSameh anÇaptal Rte WW
                            avw l’o^ ^’içqu^jpajL ypfiî
                            totalité de 1 actif et dn pfitiif ïïwi
                            rJ$|i
                            •* fflWKWfÇfc RgRSoeiété et notamerent
                            ii on • explique maintenant lgwinpit tau lOOOO.parts fondateurs t4i.y^#
                            ws w,m9m- famè 1 «ww	TsJwujfctata RR
                            10.^0 SW* R 2^.000, sentaann^: çntltata énoais-é il y aqoelqués jMPtaPlÉU divûlendeRR 780.0:0,4»t Pru WflMOP et valan^ sn, Bogm lOO-v- ex-diredende 0 a.4,^ yen* pyRbbiuoant Rehsr sneuuuil* l.OOO.OOQ.foit F*, 26^)ÇaOOO. L’* a^*iiqqf aussi xUte apportas à la liquid***. w* P’èteR oa^e (§oo»4té pour. qoi to*#opt4ta' tribaé avant l’effondrement de la Société des Saoreries.	.,	^ v '.
                            Il^nfeAyoqer qu'jljjst jixta|é*,*nMp. trer unq Limited Liabiÿty Cûtapwty au CN>îtal nominni de R 69Q.PQP qui uhR taPtune d’exarm^m» ®«FBta ,uniye àdistribqi^*i oomptant Lst 1.800.000 soit 1rs. 45.00a000 h ses parts * fondatenre.
                            Oe qui eet Wnmâ âmï cetïira de Gon-' oordat t'ektl» Iprééedoi fàui VidAs Sa Sage commis d'un bénéficiaire de oes parta de fondateurs.	. - c
                            Le|en de . ceuq qui m «mt fut^d^ngyr oonine B^v’eoredesSbWnes et tfpBysEe se làinb ndmmbr ccttnmisàjres ik VâéStA Si» toute interVenWn des aotionniures tauâ îux yeux; leais fntPrïfè sont oeax 'àe|a Sanieh Sqg»£ Corporation ô.s^L ahtalùlÉrt oppotta a |oeûx des acjacmnaires qui àppa*reirîoent oonrebt ttufiSiiafit oèé risques d’ètr^ sL'goés à blsnp.
                            Le aSiobsAe^la^ Bo^éRlitaR ries est de Ers, 39,600,1)00 et Ai (mij^u des obligatibni qâ'ellé â âcàlikta s’élèrra ‘A ns. 50,00^,000 ; les reVèuVi ' bets BiK^SÜI à obtenir 1 rbvîèfir, tioec R/iâJta jlfisCttfe indiqués au rapport de Sir Inniuft wmtous
                            il*, iiw^lk' ÆSISfr
                            viAi
                            Illegible Block of Text</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ADVERTISEMENT</head></div></div>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
