<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN EGYPTIAN,’ SATURDAY, MAY 29, 199S.</head>
<div type="item"><p>T. A. SPARTALI & CO.
Large Assortment of Old and New Carpets,
ALL MADE BY HAND.
Purveyors to all large CARPET IMPORTERS in Europe and America.
LOOMS and DYE WORKS in all centres of production in Asia, employing 10,000 workmen.
CARPETS made to order in all sizes and dyed with permanent vegetable colours.
im~ Great Choice of Rich Designs. “•I
MODERATE, FIXED PRICES.—Central Hovse : SMYRNA, Ebt. 1842. Branch in London
Cairo Show Rooms 3 Rond-Point Soliman Pacha, opposite Savoy Hotel.
25366—31-1-906</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>UNDER THE MOSQUITO NET
“At I tayc a-thinking."
Inguldsly. '
A few weeks ago it seemed to be a settled
thing that steps were to be taken forthwith '
to establish a Rescue Home for girls in con
nection with the movement ior the repression 
oi the “white slave traffic,” and it was an
nounced that the Jewish community had 1
placed a suitable house at the disposal of the j
recently formed committee.</p>
<p>But alas 1 counsels of another order seem to *
have prevailed, and the executive committee f
of the newly-formed body bas been informed *■
that the proposed arrangement will not be
carried out, and has been recommended to
arrange for the police to send to the Rudolph c
Home any cases of an urgent nature. One of t
these, a Mohamedan girl from Turkey, has, t
in fact, been sheltered there for the past c
fortnight.</p>
<p>Now the Rudolph is an institution
having a very different mission to fulfil, and
moreover is a building ill-adapted for the re- t
ception of these cases. But it is carried on by o
a man who is heart and soul devoted to this t
good woik, and is not to be easily turned t
aside from any course to which he resolves to t
devote his energies, while the excellent lady i
who is partner in his life’s work is an ideal 
matron a home of the kind.	n
Perhaps no better way out of the difficulty
could be found than to make each alterations (
in the Rudolph Home by means of additions,
would render it adaptable for the purpose
for which it is proposed to use it; for surely
the willingness of both Mr. and Mrs. Rudolph
to undertake these extra duties, relieving the
committee as it would of the necessity of
providing a paid matron for the proposed
home, would be a matter of gTeat importance, ii
And for this willingness I can vouch. « ii
In other respects, too, the idea seems to be l
one that is capable of being carried through. On 8
the side oi the home facing the sea is a piece t
of loud belonging to it which is not yet built on,
while the committee have in hand a sum ol
£350 which they intend to use for building v
purposes.</p>
<p>This however would not be sufficient, and c
would probably require to be supplemented by 
another XoOU or £400, a matter that sorely
should not present any difficulty, seeing that
the community that originally proposed to
provide the home is not as yet committed to 
any pecuniary liability in the matter.
The plan suggested by Mr. Rudolph would
be to remove some of the present temporary 1
outbuildings, and erect in their place, and on >
the ground at present uncovered, a commo-
dious dining-room and a dormitory, while 1
above these could be built three, our, or five <
rooms, as required, for the purposes of a Girls’ «
Home, the entrance to which would be quite 1
separate from that used by the frequenters of
the Home.</p>
<p>I think that a proposal such as this deserves
careful consideration. While it is quite obvious
Xthat no fiat could be hired for the purpose, on
the other hand a large house would be quite
unsuitable, as no one expects that there will be .
many inmates at one time. Everyone too would .
be satisfied at the few it would be necessary ,
to shelter from time to time being under the t
care of one who has proved himself so disin-
terested a worker in the cause of humanity as
Mr. Rudolph.</p>
<p>Though the matter is perhaps one more for
private than public arrangement, and its deci-
sion one for the committees oonoerned, it is at
the same time one of great general interest,
considering ail that has been written and said
on the subject of late, and as snch I have felt
justified in introducing it into my notes this
week.</p>
<p>I have just been reading that very remark-
able little book written in prison by Oscar
Wilde, and most appropriately entitled “De
Profundis.” It is a truly wonderful production,
requiring much study in order to be fully
understood and appreciated.</p>
<p>As the reviewer says in the “Athenrenm"
of April 1, “all the old characteristics of the
writer’s style are here, with a new one super-
added." And it is just this new one that is so
remarkable and so difficult to deal with.
I do not propose just now to go into an
exhaustive analysis of Wilde’s book, containing
as it does so many gems of the purest water,
while it also embodies much that at first sight
appears objectionable and grates on the feol-
ings, although the more it is studied the
more apparent does it become that a deeper
moaning is intended than that which appears
on the surface.</p>
<p>But perhaps few tilings in the book are
more suggestive to the truth-seeker than the
following extracts, and they enforce a lesson of
"At Christmas I managed to get hold of a
Greek Testament, and every morning, after 1
had cleaned my cell and polished my tins, I
read a little of the Gospels, a dozen verses
taken by chance anywhere.............. Endless
repetition, in and out of season, has spoiled
for us the freshness, the naïveté, the simple
romantic charm of the Gospels. We hear them
read far too often and far too badly, and all
repetition iB anti-spiritual. When one returns
to the Greek, it is like going into a garden of
lilies out of some dark and narrow house.
And to me the pleasure is doubled by the
reflection that it is extremely probable that we
have the actual terms, the ipsissima verba, used
by Christ”</p>
<p>I have never liked the idea that we knew
of Christ’s own words only through a transla-
tion of a translation. It is a delight to me to
think that as far as his conversation was con-
cerned, Cbarmides might have listened to
him, and Socrates reasoned with him, and
Plato understood him."</p>
<p>How a translation of a translation may alter
the text,'and how greatly the meaning of the
original may be changed, is clearly shown in
the following illustration, which appeared in
the "Combill Magazine” for June 1899.It is all
the more remarkable in that re-translations
into the original English were made in each
instance, so that in no case was a translation
made from one foreign language to another.
The following lines were first translated into
Greek :—
“ I heard that S. would write my life
When I gave np my breath ;
I felt indeed that this would add
A new delight to death.”
The Greek version' was then re translated
into English by a second expert, whose render-
ing was then turned into Latin by another,
and after re-translation was successively trans-
lated into French, German and Persian, the
same method of procedure being followed
throughout.</p>
<p>The final re-translation gave the following
version of the original text:—
He. Dear, in my song you still shall live
Though under earth yon lio ;
She. Ah ! had you now that grace to give
I should not need to die.</p>
<p>"De Profundis” would be a valuable book,
if only for the reminder it gives us that the
utmost care is necessary in accepting transla-
tions of so called infallible writings of old.
Translators are by no means infallible, and
revision is from time to time deemed to be
necessary, but be the body of revisors ever so
learned, the very revision itself shows that
the new light which is continually being thrown
on things of old renders adaptation to modem
and more advanced thought to be imperatively
necessary.</p>
<p>The more familiar an impartial observer
may be. with the social usages and habits of
Great Britain and of the Continent of Europe,
the less en photic, says Mr. Brander Matthews
in the "New York Tribune,” will be his feeling
that the foreign standard is really superior to
American ; and the more inclined he will be to
explain away certain apparent disadvantages
of onr attitude as the price we pay for what
we hold in high esteem—equality and demo-
cracy, manliness and self-respect
The American theory of manners, if one may
attempt to formulate its basis, is founded cot
on any artificial distinctions of social position,
but on the simple relation of man to man. In
Europe bad manners, whether of the upper or
the lower classes generally spring from a lack
of sympathy. Iu America, bad manners are
caused by want of thought rather than by lack
of feeling. They are the result of carelessness
more than of wilfulness. The American is so
busy minding his own business that he has no
time to be as regardful oi the rights of others
as he knows he ought to be. He does not
mean to be rude, and if his attention is called
to it he mends his manners, if only for the
moment.</p>
<p>The American is profoundly good-natured—
and good nature is an integral element of good
manners. The carnival gaiety of an election-
night crowd in any American city, no matter
how bitter may have been the preceding can-
vass, finds no parallel in any other country in
the world ; it is an expression of that good-
hnmoured toleration which is a chief charac-
teristic of the American people, and which
every intelligent foreigner notes almost imme-
diately upon his arrival.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ORIGIN OF RIGHTHANDEDNESS.
the outer hand a large house would be quite The question why the majority of persons
unsuitable, as no one expects that there will be UB0 ^ rjght hand with greater skill than
many inmates at one time. Everyone too would ^ jeft has never been solved definitely. Dr.
be satisfied at the few it would be necessary Ueorg0 M Goald) of Philadelphia, has been
to shelter from time to time being under studying the problem, and, writing
care of one who has proved himself so disinterested in the "Popular Science Monthly," ho says he
terested a worker in the cause of humanity as believes that right handedness is so thoroughly
Mr. Rudolph.	^	ingratiated in human nature that it must have
been partially developed in the savage and
Though the matter is perhaps one more for creators of the race. Primitive man, in his
private than public arrangement, and its deci- opinion, must have felt a definite need for the
siou one for the committees concerned, it is at exercise of his right hand in preference to his
the same time one of great general interest, left; and that necessity must have been re-
considering all that has been written and said cognized and obeyed for a long period 
on the subject of late, and as such 1 have felt continuously. The impulse could not well have
justified iu introducing it into my notes this dictated his habits in eating, for knives and
week.	forks are of recent origin, the modern gnn had
not been invented, and writing was practically
I have just been reading that very remark- unkn0Wn. Moreover, in such operations as
able little book written in prison by Oscar chippiug arr0W8> weaving baskets, and wield-
Wilds, and mail entitlted “De ing dubi, bo». and «rrow«, it could not bare
Profundis. It is a truly wonderful progenitor, BtamJ „„oh ,bict har,d „„ en,ploJ„x|
rerpnrron miioh ntndy in order to be folly ..............w„|,„ M boon named to snoh a
riurlenrtorid and appreciated.	,tag0 ,jf .rfvarroeinarit j* to involve the use of
As the reviewer eay.'io the "Atkenteetn" t.WOl.wr. *■» »b|f‘ *“ tffjJ
of April 1, "all tire old cli.ractrrri.tio of the b«ld ™ *be loft ..de m order to protoot the
writer", style are here,■with a new one super. h.e”?" fhm. » a »*t»r of mnvenrenc, the
added." And it is just this new ooe that is so	St* li» more aet.va
remarkable and » difarlt to deal with.	fenet»nf f Sghtrng „th spear and and, and
.	with habitual exercise came special skill. An
I do not propose just* now to go into an attendant phenomenon wsa a Oner organisation
ojlraustive analysis of Wilde's book, containing of that paiUenlrrr oeatre m the brsmwhich
a, it doe. so many gems of the purest water, oontrolled these »»»™r»ia. and which was
while it also embodies moeh that St first sight	m lb.“1,(t h*“ of »'e“-
app»r. objectionable and grata, on the fool- *'* “	™
iogT although the mere it is studied the »>■ 0»«la 14!dI“' *h™ .“",l l™> *»»
mS™ apparent d.«a it become that a deeper greater demande open th. right eye, became
meaning is intended than that which appear, vision must precede the order lo stain, or to
, ai,„	give peaceful sign-ls. In this way there ui.-.y
n 1	•	have been developed a keenor power of vision</p>
<p>But perhaps few tilings in the book are in the right eye than in the left. Dr. Gould
more suggestive to the troth-seeker than the assumes that there was, and declares that
following extracts, and they enforce a lesson of "righthanded people are right-eyed," and that
which 1 am able to furnish a very striking in their brains the centre of vision is on the
illustration.	j left side, in close proximity to that governing
the right arm.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EUROPEAN v. AMERICAN MANNERS
34 YEARS OF RHEUMATISM.
PATIENT LAID UP IN BED
FOR 10 MONTHS AT A TIME DISABLED
AND HELPLESS.
4, York Street,	ans
Bilston, Staffs., England.
Gentlemen :—I will always do what I can m01
towards making your Doan’s Backache Kidney 0f c
Pills better known, because they have proved ;n ,
snch a blessing to me, and I believe in them. cr0i
I have been a martyr to rheumatism ever since n00
I was 20 j ears of age, and now I am 54. 0ve
When quite a young man I had to walk with |m|
cratches or sticks. This went on for over 0[a|
three years, and since that time I have never jjne
been properly free from the rheumatism, and den
never so franc as I am at the present time, since upc
using Doan’s Pills.</p>
<p>During those 34 years I had several severe ju ,
attacks of this terrible rheumatism. The one -j
in October of 1897, when I was living in
Wednesday, was, I think, the severest attack ^
I ever had; it kept me in my bed for 10 months,
and I became as helpless as a new-born babe. oaf
I was attended by one of the best doctors, bnt ^
he seemed unable to do me much good,
although ho told me more than once that if I
had been a millionaire he could not have tried ^
harder—and I believe him.</p>
<p>In March of 1899 I was kept from business .
for 17 mouths again with rheumatism and ,
kidney trouble. There were severe pains in .
my back and sides (especially the left side); ,10
my appetite became poor, and I didn’t relish
the food I was able to eat There was a nasty 0 .
taste in my month, no matter what I ate or
drank, and I couldn’t keep my food down. 1 1
Even a pipe of tobacco seemed to go against W£
me, and I became despondent and miserable, mc
feeling that life was not worth living.
But there was worse to follow : not long 061
after. I began to bo troubled with the kidney
secretions, the pain in passing being almost ‘D(.C
unbearable at times. There was also a sedi- .
ment from the urine. These distressing com-
plaints kept getting worse and worse as “
months went by, until one day I couldn’t pass .
the urine at all; I was in suoh a terrible “l
condition at the time that I thought my race 061
was nearly run.</p>
<p>It was then that I heard about Doan’s .
Backache Kidney Pills, and they were spoken !“'
so highly of that I determined to try them. J*
After I had taken a few boxes I felt easier, and
now that I have taken ten boxes I feel quite :y
free from any sign of rheumatism or kidney ,n’
trouble. I am a new man to what I was,
th:
Tt
H
St!
all
or
dii
Fi</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE STATE RAILWAYS.
BY "TRAFFIC.”
(THIRD ARTICLE).
The great problem that the Administration
of the Egyptian State Railways has to solve is
that of the growth of traffic, and it is one that
divides itself into many subordinate problems,
each requiring elaborate study, special know-
ledge, and far-seeing judgment. As it is on the
increase of the traffic that the success of a
railway system depends for its financial and
general reccess, it is obviously the first duty of
the administration to see that everything that
can be done is done to promote it. For this
duty the Commission has made no adequate
provisions, apparently ignoring the fact that
it is one that demands, on the part of the
official to whom it is entrusted, very special
ability as well as an intimate knowledge of
the country, its trade and commerce, its
people, their habits and customs, and many
other factors. Under the system of administra-
tion that I have sketched this would be the
work of the General Manager, whose opinions
and decisions, having been revised or approved
by the Council, would be carried out by the
various departments concerned. Thus it would
rest with the Traffic Manager to propose and
carry out necessary modifications of the
existing traffic arrangements, suggest addi-
tional trains, or other methods of meeting
the demands for increased accommodation,
and in doing this he might have to consult
with the Way Department and Locomotive
Departments.</p>
<p>To the outsider the providing of extra train
accommodation seems a simple thing, but it is
in reality very far from being so. We are
constantly hearing complaints of the over-
crowding of the trains, and these are com-
monly accompanied by the question, “Why
do they not ran more trains 1” and “Why do
they not pat on more carriages i" Well, to
answer the latter question first, to put on
more carriages is not necessarily so simple a
matter as the public assume. More carriages
mean more powerful engines, increased stock
of carriages, and possibly important alterations
in the arrangement oi stations, etc. To in-
crease the number of trains may not only
need some or all of these things, but may
even necessitate the opening of stations, or
halts, the provision of new sidings and other
elaborate and expensive modifications of the
line. The employment of larger engines may
demand the relaying of the whole of the line
upon which they am to run, and this might
also be required by any considerable increase
in the speed of trains.</p>
<p>These are but a lew indications of the
complicated nature of the problems involved,
but they are enough to show that these prob-
lems can only be effectively solved by very
careful study on the part of thoroughly prac-
tical men, and that without the necessary study
of all the factors, the ablest experts can at best
give nothing more than a mere guess as to
what would be the most advisable method of
dealing with them.</p>
<p>It is important, too, that the fact should not
be overlooked that the initial cost of altera-
tions and work intended to facilitate traffic is
but a very small item compared with the value
of the results to be attained, even though that
initial expenditure may run into tens of
thousands of pounds. If, for example, A and B
are two available methods of providing for
increased traffic, and we find that A' pounds
spent upon A will give an increase of one per
cent on the present revenue, and that 6 X
pounds spent upon B will yield a five per cent,
increase ; if other conditions do not materially
affect this result, it is not difficult to see that
the expenditure of the 6 X amount will in the
end be by far the most economical. Had Lord
Farrer’s Commission kept this simple fact in
mind, it would not, in all probability, have
been so hasty to condemn the Electro-Pneu-
matic Signalling installation at Cairo, for if
this be effectively carried out it should, by the
inoreased security it will give and the facility
it will provide for the rapid and effective
handling of a largely increased traffic, ultimate-
ly prove one of the wisest and most economical
investments the Administration has made.
There are many other points that one might</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CATARRH DESTROYS THE KIDNEYS.
MR. QEOBQB KINO, Deputy 8h :rlft
of Itensellaor Co., N. Y., for years
was a well known merchant of Troy.
In a letter from No. IS King St, Troy,
N. Y., he writea i
"Peruna cured me from what the
doctors were afraid would turn Into
Brlght'a Disease, alter I had suffered
with catarrh of the bladder and kidney
trouble.</p>
<p>Pernna Is a blessing to a sick man.
Eight bottles made me a well man and
were worth more than a thousand dol-
lars to me. I cannot speak too highly
of It. It Is now four years since I was
troubled, and I have enjoyed perfect
health since.”—George King.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>MR. QEOBQB KINO, Deputy 8h :rlff 1 «I contracted a severe cold seref^
of Rensellaer Co., N. Y., for years years ago, which from neglect develop**
was a woll known merchant of Troy. Into urinary trouble, and threataM*
In a letter from No. tS King SL,Troy, Drlght’s disease. I nsed Pernna hift.
N. Y., he writes:	folly for three and ona-half MaQA
"Peruna cured me from wbat the when my health was perfect eaea Mm.
doctors were afraid would turn Into I hare nersr had any trouble ilnoa."—
Brlght'a Disease, after I had suffered o. Fred Llndstrom.
with catarrh of the bladder and kidney Catarrhal Inflammation of the muooua
trouble.	lining of the kidneys, also calM
"Pernna Is a blessing to a sick man. Bright’s disease,” may be either aenta
Eight bottles madei me a well man and or chronle. The acute form prodnow
™	T".	‘	d"‘‘ symplnm. of reel. Preal.«ro. ISM Ifr.
lars to me. I cannot speak too highly serlons nature of the disease la at snna
ofit. Uisnow four years slnco I was .inspected, bnt the chronle variety may
troubled and I have enjoyed perfect com# on Anally and insidiously
health since. George King.	t^at Its preaenco Is not suspected nntQ
ft Prominent Member of I. 0. 0. f. ‘,ter “ h“ ,“‘*ned ,tM“ u’oroD«u»
Threatened With Bright’s Disease.- npon ,u TlcUm-
Pe-ru-na Restored Him to Health. At appearance of the flat symp-
tom Peruna should betaken. This rera-
O. Fred Llndstrom, Past Grand Master strikes at once at the very root ot
Independent Order of Odd Fellows, the dissase.
writes from 1923 University Ave., St. A book on catarrh sent free by T%*
Paul, Minn.:	Pernna Medicine Co., Colnmbus, O.
For special directions everyone should read "The His of life," a copy of whieh
surrounds each bottle. Pernna is for sale by all chemists and druggists at five shil-
lings per bottle or six bottles for twenty-five shillings.
Those wishing direct correspondence with Dr. Hartman and oan wail the oeeer
earv delay in receiving a reply should address Dr. B. B. Hartman, Oolnmbni, Ohio,
D.B.A.
The following wholesale druggist will supply the retail drug trade in Alexandria
Egypt.
MAX FISHER,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>Cairo and Alexandria,
ft Prominent Member of I. 0. 0. F.
Threatened With Bright’s Disease.—
Pe-ru-na Restored Him to Health.
0. Fred Lindstrom, Past Grand Master
Independent Order of Odd Fellows,
writes from 1923 University Ave., St.
Paul, Minn.:
Societe Internationale des Employes
D’ALEXANDRIE
SiiiOB Social : Roe Mosqo£e Attabine No. 21</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BUREAU DE PLACEMENT
Ofpres u’emplois
BONNE MAIS0N d’Alexandrie demande :
1.	an employd connaissant bien la Mercerie.
2.	an jeane hotnme aide-vendear.
Demandes
Compt^bla pr. Le Cairo saohaoit bien la Comp-
tabihte et connaissant l’Anglais.
Comptable pr. Le Cairo avec connaiasances en
langues.
Comptable pr. Port-Said avec connaiasances en
langnes.
Comptable pr. Alexandrie, commo employd gd-
ndral.
N.B.—Pour tons renseignements s’adresser
aoit directement, soit par lettre au Siège Social
de la Socidtd, Rne Mosqnde Attarine No.21.
Le Seordtariat ee ton vert les Lundi, Mercredi
*t Vendredi de 7 fa. 1/3 k 8 h. 1/2 dn soir.
Los insertions ci-desaus sont faites gratnite-
ment par les soins de la Sooidtd et seals, les
looidtaires pen vent en bdndfioier.
25785-7-4 906</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BUTTER-SCOTCH
(The Celebrated Sweot for Children).
Manufactory : London. England.
promenades and mountain excursions.
tensive palatial addition with ev*ry modern
comfort</p>
<p>Fireproof System Hdnndbiqne. Illustrated
pamphlet on Innsbrnok/rM from proprietor ■
CARL LANDSEE.
■ i ■	’ . •	■!—:ft---—---
MALLS
Sanit&ry
Washable

SOAP ■
CREAM ■ For Itching, Faoe Spots Eosema. and all Skin Irritation.
POWDER -
ees, noughue
I Cream Tint
Hold Hverywhere.</p>
<div type="item"><p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER t.
rapidly superseding wall papers in all tastefully furnished homes.
It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only requires the addition of
water to make it ready use. It is quickly and easily applied with
a whitewash brush, wth half the labour and al one third the cos! of
paint. HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing
to the eye. It appeals alike lo artistic and practical house decoration.
HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special value in hot climates.</p>
<p>Owing lo its cool, pleasing colours, great weather-resisting and
germ-destroying properties, it lends itself to every kind of wall, wood,
brick or stone coating, possessing all the advantages of paint, colour-
wash, and disinfectant at one third the cost of oil paint. It never
blitters in the hottest sun, and the fact that it can be washed adds
greatly lo its sanitary advantages.</p>
<p>Supplied in Tinn end Iron Kegs.
SoU Manufacturers
SISSONS BROTHERS «!, Co., Ltd., HULL.
tooka ar. hold In Cairo by SHANK RATCLITT*. Sanitary Contractor
and Knalnoor, Sharia Baptleh.
In Alexandria by RAMADAN YOCBSKT, Sanitary Contractor,
Ooaorol At on to ■ OBOBOB MOBBIS ft 0*. Alexandria ft Cairo,</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

