<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-07"> February 7, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head> </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
<div type="item">
    <head><placeName>ENGLAND</placeName> AND <placeName>GERMANY</placeName></head>
<head>MR. LEES BELLICOSE SPEECH</head>
<head>SENSATION IN GERMANY</head>
    <p><placeName>London</placeName>, February G.
        <persName>Mr. Lees</persName> speech, mentioned in yesterdays
telegram, has caused a sensation in Germany.
The papers are angrily demanding an explanation.
Some of them declare that Germany will
now Work with redoubled energy in order to
increase her sea power.</p>
    <p><persName>Mr. Lees</persName> now writes that he was incorrectly
reported, and that what he said was that we
must assume all naval powers to be possible
enemies. Owing to the growth of. such naval
powers, our possible enemies are more numerous
than hitherto, and, consequently, we have
to keep an anxious eye not only on the Medi-
terranean but also on the North Sea.
The "Standard" learns from Berlin that,
unless <persName>Lord Lansdowne</persName> promptly repudiates
the speech, Germany will ask for an explanation</p>
</div>

<div type="item">
    <head>SITUATION IN <placeName>RUSSIA</placeName>.</head>
    <p><placeName>Lodz</placeName>, February 0.
Two persons were killed aud 15 wounded at
the cemetery here yesterday in a conflict with
the troops during the funeral of some of the
previous victims.	(Reuter).</p>
    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg</placeName>, February 6.
The address of the nobles asks the Tsar to
allow the elected of the nation to participate
in the discussion of the measures taken by the
Government	(Havas).</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GEN. GRIPENBERG'S RESIGNATION.</head>
    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg</placeName>, February 6.
General Kuropatsnik reports some skirmishes.</p>
    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg</placeName>, February 6.
With referonce to the rumours relating to
certain that the question was considered some
days ago but may that it was then solved by the
acceptance of <persName ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q2995312"> General Gripenberg's</persName> resignation</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>NORTH SEA COMMISSION.</head>
<head>A COMMISSIONER'S VIEWS</head>
    <p>One of the foreign admirals on the commision
    of Enquiry, in an intervie with the correspondent
    said that, while the commisioners
    are at present convinced of the Russians
    good faith with reference to the presence of the
    torpedo boats, the commisioners are
    unable to believe there were any such boats.
    The admiral expected that the decision would 
    be such as to enable the russians to walk out
    with their heads erect.   (Reuter.)</p>
</div>
   <div type="item">
       <head><placeName>RUSSIAN</placeName> LOAN IN <placeName>FRANCE</placeName></head>
       <p><placeName>Paris</placeName>, February 6.
       Negotiations have been completed for the
       issue of a 5% Russian loan here.  Nearly a
       millitard of france has been entrusted to the 
       same firms which negotiated the previous 
       Russian loans in france.  It is understood the
       whole loan has been placed. The rate of issue
       is not stated.   (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
   <div type="item">
       <head>OUTRAGE IN <placeName>FINLAND</placeName></head>
       <p><placeName>Helsingfors</placeName>, February 6.
       A man disguised as an officer, has assasinated
           <persName>Mr. Johnson</persName>, Procurator of the senate,
       and wounded his son.  Mr. Johnson, was a 
       Finn, but intensely unpopular as a pronounced pro-russian.
       His assailant has been arrested.   (Reuter.)</p>
   </div>
    <div type="item">
        <head><placeName>GERMANY</placeName> AND <placeName>BULGARIA</placeName>.</head>
        <p><placeName>Sofia</placeName>, February 6.
            <persName>Prince Ferdinand</persName> is to officially visit the
            <persName>Emperor William</persName>.	(Havas).</p>
    </div>
    <div type="item">
        <head>COLLIERS STRIKE IN BELGIUM.</head>
        <p><placeName>Brussels</placeName>, February 6.
            A general strike of the colliers, in sympathy
            with the German workmen, began in Belgium
            today. Ouly 12 pits are now working. (R.)</p>
        <p><placeName>Charleria</placeName>, February 6.
            A strike has broken out in the mining basin. (Havas.)</p>
    </div>
    <div type="item">
        <head>FRENCH MILITARY SERVICE</head>
        <p><placeName>Paris</placeName>, February 6.
        The senate has passed the clause fixing the 
        period of military service at two years.  (H.)</p>
    </div>
        <div type="item">
            <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
            <p>A Foundling.—An infant was found by the
                police yesterday in a street in the Kom-el-
                Shougats quarter.
                The Pilgrimage.—A telegram from Jeddah,
                dated last Saturday, states that the number
                of pilgrims who have landed there to date
                amounts to 46,000.
                Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
                Ramleh and Moharrem Bey districts on the
                night of Saturday will be poisoned by the
                police.</p>
            <p>Gruesome Discovery.—The body of a native
                woman, with the head, hauds, and legs cut out,
                was found yesterday on the banks of the Mah-
                moudieh Canal, near Ramleh, and removed to
                the Government Hospital.</p>
            <p>Bank of Egypt.—In regard to the recently
                declared 10% dividend of the Bank of Egypt,
                we may mention that this and a bonus of 15s.
                per share is equal to a net distribution to the
                shareholders of 16% of the bank's capital for
                one year.</p>
            <p>The Mahmal Theft.—It is suggested that,
                in future, to avoid theft of bullion and valu-
                able, such as occurred in the recent case of the
                mahmal, the Railway Administration should
                construct special cars fitted up as strong-rooms
                for the transport of treasure.</p>
            <p>Ploughing Competition. — the Khedivia.
                Agricultural Society has decided to hold some
                official trials of a number of steam-ploughiug
                machines at shoubra on tue 24th inst. About
                six different machines have already been
                entered for the Competition.</p>
            <p>Suez Canal.—34 vessels passed through the
                Canal on the 2nd and 3rd inst. 23 of which
                were british, 2 Norwegian, 4 French, 2 Aus-
                trian, 1 Turkish, 1 Swedish, 1 Dutch, 1 Ger-
                man, the receipts for the two days being
                irs. 884.684.06. The total for the 3 days in
                February amounted to frs. 1,129,100.51.</p>
            <p>Delta Light Railway Co.—The Committee
                of the London Stock Exchange has ordered the
                following securiiy to be quoted in the official
                List: Egyptian Delta Light Railways, further
                issue of 11,113 5g per cent.  Cumulative pre-
                reference Shares of 10 each, fully paid, Nos.
                63,325 to 74,437 (registerd shares and share
                warrants to bearer).</p>
            <p>Menahouse Gymkhana— the total number
                of visitors on Friday who passed through the
                gates at the Menahouse Gymkhana was 800,
                which is a record “gain.". No less than 53o
                luncheons were served on that day in the big
                dining-hall at Mena House Hotel, The
                arrangements were througuout excellent.</p>
        </div>
        <div type="item">
            <head> THE KHEDIVE </head>
            <p> The <persName>Khedive</persName> has returned to <placeName>Koubbeh</placeName>.  His 
                highness will come to Alexandria on Thursday
            next</p></div>
            <div type="item">
            <head> PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT</head>
            <p> The public works department has fixed
                the following salaries for the under-mentioned
            officials.  The figures given represent pounds egyptian:-
            Technical Service :— C. Crawley, 700; J.
            Lamella Bey, 450.
            Towns and State Buildings.—Clifton, 1,000 ;
            Hewat, 1,000; Rebeot, 700 ; Chapman, 600;
            Pastour, 600 ; Ehrlich, 600; Euser, 400 ; Wat-
            son, 400 ; Zoucas, 831 ; H. Passe, 360 ; Srnir-
            giassi, 300 ; Bertrand, 276; M. H. FitzPatriok,
            276.
            Irrigation Service.—H. G. Piulaison 800 ;
            Mahmoud Bey Sidky, 900; Mofeaworth, 700 ;
            Adamson, 600 ; B xwell, 600 ; Lamb ton, 430 ;
            C-raper, 480 ; Sullivan, 300.
            Survey Department—Captain Lyons, 1,400,
            H. Hmuplireys, 720 ; Robert Bey 540 ; L.
            Craig, 076 ; A. Lucas, 540, G. Fraser, B.
            Wade and Dowson, 480 ; H. Skill, 360 ; B.
            Weldon, 300; E Binosi, 240 ; Bertrano,
            276 ; Elias Bey Sabbagh, 420.
            Antiquity Service.—E Brugsch Bey, 800 ;
            J. Quibeli and H. Carter, 600 ; G. Daressy,
            500G. Leg rain, 480.</p>
        </div>
            <div type="item">
                <head> BECK AND CO'S PILSENER BEER</head>
                <p> Fears no honest competition for quality.</p>
            </div>
    <div type="item">
        <head>LORD CROMER’S TRIP.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent.)
Medinet el-Fayoum, Sunday.
    <persName>Lord Cromer's</persName> speech here yesterday has
made a very good impression, and his strongly-
worded criticism on the growth of drinking
habits has been taken to heart. Many of the
omdehs who were among Lord Cromer’s au-
dience, were so impressed that they have told
me that they intend to petition the Govern-
ment against the manner in which liquor shops
are being opened everywhere in the villages
without let or hindance. I intend to found a
local society hero to combat the alcohofic habit
among the natives.
Lord and Lady Cromer and <persName>Lady Betrice
Thynne</persName> paid a visit to one of the native
kuttabs hero which is under the care of the
Ministry of Public Instruction
They also visited the native <persName>Sefa Coulop</persName>
rohoof. Della Bey, French consular agent here,
and the members of the schoof committee
recieved his lordship there.
the party took tea at the Moudir’s residence
and left at 3.15 pm for Wests.</p>
 <p>Lord and lady Cromer are expected to
 arrive at <placename>Beni Hasan</placename> this evening.
 We hear that Lord Cromer Is busily engaged
 on his annual report,</p> </div>
<div type="item">
    <head>THE PLAGUE</head>
    <p> During the week ending saturday only two
    cases of plague were reported throughout 
        <placeName>Egypt</placeName>, one at <placeName>suez</placeName> and the other in the <placeName>Toukh district</placeName>.</p>
</div>
            <div type="item">
                <head>BOVINE TYPHUS</head>
                <p> During last week, 11 deaths from bovine
                    typus were reported throughout Egypt, as
                against 6,164 deaths during the corresponding
                week last year.  The total number of deaths
                to date amounts to 146,803</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <head>A CASE FOR ENQUIRY.</head>
                <p>A cairo correspondent writes:- to the west 
                    of Abdeen-square is a nasty quarter where few
                    sanitary and moral laws are enforced and 
                    where the grossest criminality prevails.  While
                    in that locality today I learned that
                    in a quarrel between an armenian and three 
                    natives the armenian was so badly beaten that
                    he, after a week or more, died, and nothing
                    has been done to assailate or murderers. 
                    In fact, the principal was pointed out to me,
                    and i was informed that a seargant of police
                    was bribed to strike this mans name off the book
                    for they all were arrested at the time of the 
                    quarrel.  I wish this matter to be inquired
                    into, for it is a most gross outrage if it is true
                    as i am led to believe it is.</p>
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PROF FELIX'S RECITAL</head>
                    <p><persName>Professor Felix's</persName> concert took place at the 
                        Khedivial Hotel on Saturday night as an-
                        nounced, and considering the wet and tem-
                        pestous weather, was well attended. We must
                        congratulate the professor on his courage in
                        fixing a more modest price for the tickets than
                        is customary here for local artists, who ex-
                        pect their kind friends to pay the same price 
                        for the pleasure of bearing them perform as 
                        they would do for distinguished artistes from
                        Europe who can command audiences without 
                        the disagreeable touting system in vogue in
                        this country. Mr. Felix's selection of piece
                        was as it ought to have been, a happy one, as
                        his silvery touch was shown off to perfection
                        in most of them. If there was one piece
                        more than another that elicited enthusiastic
                        applause we might pick out an exquisite
                        Nocturne of Chopin's (Opus 15 No. 2), in
                        which an oft-recurring melody framed in flow
                        mg cadenzas brought ont the pianist's remark
                        able agility of finger. Wagner’s "Choeur des
                        Fileuses” from his "Vaissean Fantome”
                        arranged by Lizt, was also much appreciated.
                        Mr. Felix's wonderfully delicate touch is not
                        so well suited to the heavier German music,
                        which requires greater breadth of tone and a
                        deeper sentiment. To our mind his conception
                        of Mendelssohn’s "Fruhlings Lied” was quite
                        incorrect and far removed from the traditional
                        one as taught in German Conaervatories,but on
                        the other hand, the Duo by the same com-
                        poser was faultlessly played.
                        Professor Felix was ably supported by Mrs.
                        Frederick Cree, who sang, first, a romance by
                        Giordano from Andrea Chenier with great
                        refinement, and in the socond part Beetho-
                        ven's famous “Per Pieta.” Her passionate
                        rendering of the presto, “Ah crudel I” quite
                        carried away her audience, and on being encored
                        she repeated it with even more verve than
                        the first time. We must not omit the lovely
                        little duet by Missa, “Les Roseaux Chanteurs,"
                        charmingly suug by Mrs. Cree and Mme.
                        Felix, nor the instrumental trio performed
                        very ably by Mr. H. and Mr. L. Suzan accom
                        panied by Mr. Felix. Altogether a very plea-
                        sant concert, but we must suggest that another
                        time the pauses between the items should be
                        curtailed, and that a performer does not ussually
                        retire from the platform between two pieces
                        bracketed a and b. All praise to <persName>Mr. Lifonti</persName>
                        for the splendid Pleyel pianoforte lent for the
                        oocasion.</p>
                </div>
    <div type="item"> 
        <p> BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE- we would
            call the attention of persons interested in
            Egyptian trade to the work of the british
            chamber of commerce of egypt, whose office
            in alexandria gives information as to standings,
            trade, and to its members , and whose monthly 
            publication reviews our commerce
            The annual subscription is $1 and all british 
            traders should become members.  Our London
            office, 86, New Broad street E.C. acts as
            Londond agency to the Chamber</p>
    </div>
    <div type="item">
        <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN</head>
        <head>H. M. S. Sealark Damaged.</head>
        <p>(From our Correspondent).
            <placeName>Suakin</placeName>, January 28.
            H. M. S. '‘Sealark’’ arrived here from Sheikh
            Barghont on the 14th inst in a damaged ion-
            dition, having struck a rock about 4 miles off
            Sheikh Barghout whilst surveying. She had to
            come into Suakin for the necessery repairs,
            which have now been carried, out with the aid
            of divers and material obtained from the
            Sudan Government Railways
            The "Sealark" after surveying here and
            at Sheikh Barghout, will probably go into dock
            and then continue her survey as far as
            Australia, which is her final destination.
            The British S.S. "Dart” arrived from Eng-
            land on the 14th inst. with a very largo con-
            signment of rails and fishplates for the Suakin-
            Atbara Railways
            The British S.S. "Thornley” arrived from
            England on the 16th inst, with a large consign-
            ment of iron sleepers for the railway.</p>
    </div>
        <div type="item">
        <head>THE POWELL COTTON EXPEDITION</head>
            <p>According to intelligence just to hand, <persName>major 
            Powell-Cotton</persName>, who left Khartoum on an expedition
            from the Nile to the Zambesi, was at
            Lado at the end of December.  The expedition 
            was making good progress and was meeting
            with every assistance from the officials.  The
            explorer was in good health.</p>
    </div>
        <div type="item">
            <head>EGYPTIAN INVESTMENT AND
                AGENCY.</head>
            <p>Some foolish complaints have appeared in
                some of the Cairo newspapers in regard to the
                allotment of the shares of the Egyptian Investment
                 Agency, Limited. This outcry is
                absolute nonsense, for the company has no
                concession nor patents, and any one of the
                persons who consider themselves aggrieved in
                not having been allotted shares, can start as
                many companies for general financial business
                as they like on exactly similar conditions</p>
        </div> 
            <div type="item">
            <head> PASSENGERS' LISTS.</head>
                <p>ARRIVALS.  Le paquebet "Tebe”, de la Cie PlOrio Ruljat- B
                    tino arrivd avant-hicr de Ulnae avail k berd:	c]
                    MM. Seb. Uualtieri, Arrigo Ro»si, ig. „
                    Autouello d'Uulx, Comte Carlo, cheY. Tummjwo- e
                    Saudri, Bug. Ultouo, sa Game et 2 tillea, Coijite a
                    Giac. Suardo, Com. Em. Maraini et sa dame,
                    tiius. Muller, 0. J. Bucblcy, M. etMmoBrown, g
                    3 demoiselles, Gtov. de Martino, Kiciotii Gin- p
                    baldi, A. Voyl, B. Schiavons, Palioiti, Matijde *
                    beccacia, Diana Duly, bentiiglio, Maria Frito a
                    25 paasagers de 3mo clause.	0
                    Lo paquebet ‘ Semiramis” du Lloyd Autri- (i
                    ebieA arrivi htae de Tn^te avail k heed:	J
                    M.et51meStooit,MmoKrumviede,M.Buihb, J
                    Spiegelberg, Poridis, Consul Nordenbelz eb’s* «
                    dame, M. et Mmo Klenivoska, M. et Mjne t
                    de Wale lie, M. et Mme E. Gilbertson, M. et \
                    Mme Hostoup Schulz, Lumbart et 4 comp., 
                    Mayer, Coheu, Ernest Grill, Eugei Grew et deux u
                    de lam^ Lehlug, avocat Lorenzo Rmsi, M. et i
                    Mme Betokto, Scarpa, M. Mmeet MlleNabgcl,
                    Werdort Kuh.my, Flengffi, beuche, M. et
                    Mme Gritoer, Breitncr, Mme Frankel, Lum-
                    berger, M. et Mme Gooke, Margradi, Dapli, a
                    Hunter, Aspis, Hicbaum, M. et Mme Ot}t>, '
                    Strauss, Eugei, M. et Mme Ulrici, Mme Jeitdee ‘
                    et 8 paasagers de 3uio ciaose.
                    Le paquebet ■,Sala*ie'’ des Messageries Ma
                    ritimes, arrivd do Marseilto oe matin, avait 1
                    a berd :
                    M. et Milo Cemeray, M. et Mmo Bacpe- I
                    mrd. Mile Mane Armiugaud, Mmo 1. M. Ha.
                    verua, M-, Mme. et Mile. W. Carr, Miles M.
                    et C. Simpson, Mile Blanche Power, MlleCblo-
                    lotuj Young, M. K- S. Hiuckes, M. Salama,
                    M. Julio Herrera, Dr. Johuaton, M. E. W.
                    Huated, M. ot Milo de Roqueteuillo, M. et
                    Mine Baillitre, Mmo Gaudm, M. et Mine
                    Gruot, M. Soymour de Rioci, M. Robert Ca-
                    moD, M. et Mile Van Doormmck, Milo Van
                    deu beroh, Mme et MUe Cavanagh, M. et Mine
                    Lesbes, M- ot Mme Brtaaon, M. Rouanir,
                    M. et Mmo hastert, M. Knupple, Mme flo
                    t’Aigle, M. Herbert S. Job, M. W. J. Stonlake,
                    M. H. Ordeu, Mme Roussefet, M. E. Buruel,
                    M. G. Zmtrus, M. Beylier, Mme G. Begay, M-
                    M. Briguon, Mmo et Mile Barrozzi, M. et Mme
                    ganval, M. Bug. AUatn, M. Kahn, M. R. I.
                    Floreutz, M. K. W. Gaskin, M. T. Lesto, Mile
                    I.laarl, M- Urauoux,M.Malin,MllaMellerag*s,
                    Mine ot MUe Oelzmann et 19pae«agera de 3me
                    et 4the classes.</p>
                <p>DEPARTURES. Le paquebet “Habsberg'' du Lloyd Autri-
                    chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait k berd :
                    MM. lo Comte Dandidi de Sylva, 8.E. le
                    lieutenant-manichal Siedler et sa dame, Victor
                    vou Kbver. Consul gu‘ni!ral Orzedechi, M. et
                    Mme Rofleston, M. et Mme H. L, Koopfer,
                    tram. Path Palintfe, Mile Palmde, MUe voti I^il-
                    mader, Hon. A. Murray, M. P. de Portheim,
                    A. von de Hazay, Mme Jeanne de Lavigene,
                    Mme Hlltue Rumbeld, M. et Mme Mooettig.
                    H. Kit tor von Waguer etsadamo, E. M. SeUtjn,
                    . Luhmanu, C. Sohinalz, cap. de Kodofisoob,
                    i Comte Huraco do Choiseul, M. et Mme Gofd-
                    i schmid, P. lasoofa, Johann Haekl, Pranza
                    Wirtschafter, Dr. RafaeUe Castellano et famille,
                    Hugo Rosenbaum, Meyer, Zueke'rbaoker, Revd.
                    Ladislas, L Wof/dorf, Mme M. Winberger, Dr
                    . B. Friedmann, Napofeono Candiani, M. et Mme
                    j Carmelo Giovanni, et 4 paasagers de 8me
                    , ofasse.
                    Cofonel Sir Adofphus PRxfifeorg*, m Wd
                    son of U>e late Dulta of C*mWWi, V ytom
                    private secretary and equerry he way'for many
                    yeah, has arrived in B|jypt from Marseille*.
                    Sir John and.Ijady Evans will leave for
                    Khartoum next week.
                    ^MiraUiC. EWi^^^bwaigpomted^
                    LteutsoanVCofo^el Kenne, Y. C, D. S. 0,
                    who was such a popularfignre in (Wfo eooety
                    when the 21st Lancera werp here, is to be
                    married in London early pisxtfeioiijzife Azfoela
                    Maty, youngest daughter of the late finbert
                    Hibcert and Mrs. Hubert Hibbert, of 2, </p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"> 
                <head>NOTICE</head>
                <p> The chambers of <persName>Mr. J Nortin 
                    Kushe</persName>, Barrister at law, are situated at
                    Maison Spiro, first floor, opposite the savoy
                    hotel, Kaar-el-nil, Cairo.</p>
            </div>
                    <div type="item">        
    <head>KHEDIVIAL OPERA HOUSE</head>
<p>The Khedlvial Opera House reasserted
itself in La Totea. The performance was in
every way excellent. <persName>Signora Pandolfini</persName> obtain-
ed and justified the welcome due to an old
Cairo favorite both by her singing and by her
acting. <persName>Signor Girand</persName> was pleasing and artistic,
and Signor Polese was conspicuous for the
excellence of his acting; we could wish: that
all opera singers would give as much attention
to details. "II Sagrestano" was amusing ;
and we should like to hear more of Sig-
nor Sala, the “timbre" of whose voice
has some charm. Staging and choris were
alike all that could be desired. We trust
that other performances will maintain this
level, and do away with the undoubtedly
bad impression caused by Rigoletto (amongst
Other pieces given). We would say one word
as to the orchestra. Though, it is certainly
composed of good musicians and directed by an 
efficient oonductor, there is often apparent a
certain want of judgment, which might well be
remedied, a lack of complete harmony with
the singers, This, in light opera, where the
melodies for the chief performers are the most
prominent part, may not be so harmful in
effect: but it is fatal in any such opera as
Tristan, or indeed in any piece where the
composer has devoted his attention to the
music and not only to these who execute it In
a word, we would wish to find (and we-have
a right to expect) that sense of ensemble
which it is the duty, as it should be the
pleasure, of the Khedlvial Opera Honse to</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE</head>
<head>LUCIA DI LAMMERMOOR</head>
    <p><persName>Signora Isabella Sricher</persName>, the celebrated
operatic artiste, who created such a furore at
the Verdi Theatre in Cairo, and whose advent
bad been anxiously awaited by a large section
of the music-loving public, made her debut at
the Abbas helmy Theatre on Satdrday Even-
ing in Lucia di Lammermoor, and her magni-
ficent performance reached to the full the
highest expectations which had been formed
regarding her. To say that Signora Svicher
was admirable or excellent, would be but to
very mildly express the quality of her per
formapoe, from every point of view. Indeed,
we venture to say that never has Egypt before
been honored by the presence of two such
magnificent artistes as Signs. Gemma Bellin-
cioni and Sigus. Isabella Sricher, and from the
rapturous applause so lavishly bestowed by
enthusiastic and delighted audiences on each
of these accomplished ladies, it is oertain that
the season will be a successful one. Signa.
Svicher's Lucia, on Saturday, was an inter-
pretation such as is seldom seen. Her singing
was certainly a revelation to many present,
and herr acting was of a high order and showed
careful study of this mobt difficult rfllo. The
tenor, Signor Tomiaaui being unwell, the
role of Sir Edgard was sustained by Signor
Pagani, who scored a distinct success. In fact,
we think we have never heard Signor Pagani to
better advantage. Signor Baldelli, in the
small part of Raimondo, was excellent. The
other minor parts were in good hands and the
orchestra and chorus were fully up to their
 usual standard.</p>
</div>
            <div type="item">
                <head>ANDREA CHENIER.</head>
                <p>An admirable performance of Giordano’s
                    Andrea Chenier was given on Sunday night.
                    <persName>Signor Pagani</persName> was in splendid voice and gave
                    an excellent interpretation of the exceedingly
                    trying title role. He was the success of the
                    evening. <persName>Signora D. Bassich</persName>, who made her
                    debut on this oocasion, gave a fairly good
                    rendering of the part of Maddalens di.'Coigny,
                    but her voice is not robust enough to stand
                    her in good steed in an opera like Andrea
                    Chenier. As Carlo Gerard, the baritone Badini,
                    who possesses a voice of delightful freshness,
                    was eminently successful. <persName>Sig. Montanari</persName> also
                    scored a distinct success.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <head>RIGOLETTO</head>
                <p>Last night, a very excellent performance
                    of Rigoletto was given at the Abhas Theatre.
                    Excellent, we say, because in every respect
                    the “ensemble” was a matter for admiration
                    and, at times, even for Surprise. In Rigoletto
                    Verdi began to realise in a way which he
                    hitherto had not surmised, the important and
                    extensive powers of his mind Up to this
                    point he had written many tunes which had
                    been hummed and sung throughout the whole
                    world, but here he seemed to forego the 
                    enormous spirit of tune that was within
                    him, and to give himself up entirely to the
                    dramatic matter in hand. Last night's per
                    formance of the opera was eminently successful.
                    Signora Svicher, in the part of Gilda, was
                    from every point of view a very great success ;
                    her voice, which possesses some of the most
                    exquisite qualities of modern vocalisation, was
                    proved on this oocasion to possess an exquisite
                    and, if one may use the adjective in connection
                    with singing, a shining quality that impressed
                    one enormously, by reason of the absolute purity
                    of its evocation. Her range is enormous; she
                    never misses her effects, and, to sum up, we
                    regard her in no other light than that she
                    is dazzlingly brilliant She was frantically
                    applauded, especially after her delightful
                    rendering of “Caro noms,” which she was
                    obliged to repeat Sig. Tomisani took the part
                    of the Duke and enchanted everybody by the
                    magnificence of his singing. He is a tenor of
                    great power, and was in good form last
                    night, enthusiasm on the part of the
                    audience following everything he did. It stands
                    to reason therefore that his rendering of "La
                    Donna e mobile” waa triumphantly successful.
                    In the part of Rigoletto Signor Badini sang
                    excellently, though he did not impress us very
                    much with his acting. The other parts were in
                    good hands. The chorus was at times disappointing,
                    but on the whole good, while the orchestra 
                    deserves credit.
                    Tomorrow night, Signore Ballincioni will
                    appear in Fedora</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                <p>The "Sehleswig" arrived at Alexandria
                at 4 o'clock yesterday afternoon and most 
                of the passengers, 92 first class and 52
                second class, left by a special train for 
                Cairo.  <persName>Prince Lichtenstein</persName>, <persName>Count and countess von
                    Arnim</persName>, <persName>Baron and Baroness de Serclaes</persName>, <persName>Count
                        von Trautmansdorff</persName>, <persName>Count d'Ursel</persName>, and a
                number of other distinguished tourists arrived
                by this steamer.  The complete list of passengers 
                will be publsihed tomorrow.  The "Schleswig" leaves
                Alexandria on wednesday afternoon at 5 o'clock
                as usual.  A number of passengers have 
                already been booked.</p>
                <p><persName>Conolel Sir Adolphus FitsGeorge</persName>, the third
                son of the late Duke of Cambridge, whose private secretary 
                and equerry he was for many years, has arrived in Egypt
                from Marseilles</p>
                <p> <persName>Sir John</persName> and <persName>lady Evans</persName> will leave for Khartoum next week</p>
                <p><persName>Miralai C.E. Wilson Bey</persName> has been appointed Commanant
                of Senasr military district</p>
                <p> <persName>Liutenant-colonel Kenns</persName>, V.C., D.S.O.
                who was such a popular figure in Cairo society
                when the 21st Lancers were here, is to be married in London
                early next month to Angela Mary, youngest daughter
                of the late Hubers Hibbert and Mrs. Hubert Hibbert, 
                of 2, beaufort-gardens.</p>
                <p>The 2nd class of the order of the medjidieh has been conferred 
                by the Khedive on Mr. Law, Judge of the mixed trubunals at Cairo, 
                on the occasion of his retirement.  His Highness will give
                audience to Judge Law on the 13th isnt.</p>
                <p>Mr. A.H. Perry has gone to Port Said, and will 
                return to Cairo on Wednesday</p>
                <p>The great italian actor, <persName>Sig. Novelli</persName>, will 
                arrive at alexandria from italy early next month</p>
                <p>We regret to announce the death of well
                    known Egyptian resident at Stamboul in the
                    person of Mehmed Bey, member of the finan-
                    cial section of the Council of State, who died on
                    the morning of the 24th ulto. at his residence
                    at Beshiktash. The funeral took place in the
                    afterooon at the expense of the Privy Purse.
                    The late Bey was the son of Ibrahim Pasha,
                    and grand-nephew of Mohamed Aly Pasha.</p>
                <p>Among others to be seen dining in Shepheard's
                Restaurant, yesterday evening, we noticed
                Prince Lichtenstein, Baron von Drasch and a
                party, including Mr. and Mrs. Beckham, Mr.
                Baines and a party of 8, Marquis de Corea,
                Barou de Walzdorf and friends, Mr. and Mrs.
                Lewis Nixon and a party of 10, including Mrs.
                Mather, Mr. Morton, Mr. and Mrs. John dupec;
                Baron de Wecker, M. Ernpaiu and some Friends,
                Vicomte and Vicomtease de Fontarce, Vicomte
                de Sapucahy, Mr. and Mrs. O'Donnell Hiller,
                Liuut. and Mrs. von Meyer and a few friends,
                Mr, Mrs., and the Mieees Runerty, Mr. E. de
                Szeut-Ivauy and.friends Mr. P. de la Bella
                Casa and a party, etc.</p>
                <p> The small dance at Shepheard's last night, 
                it is needless to say, was a great success.  Among
                the dancers we remarked.  Mrs and miss carhardt, the misses
                bufferty, miss wildbur, miss H. Porter, the Misses budhead, Mrs. and the
                Misses haisen, the misses de gelshemen, 
                the misses hillen, baron and baroness de vassilko, baron M. Oppenheim,
                baron Dobrenski, Chebalier de rappard, Herr von pohl, Mr. and Mrs Calame, Etc.</p>
                <p> Mr. Givson Bowles, M.P., and Sir Curson and lady Wyllie are among 
                the latest arrivals at the cataract hotel, assouan.</p>
                <p>Other arrivals at the popular up river hotel
                include: mr and mrs e willis swan, mr and mrs r lenk, 
                mrs h meyer, mr. j. lamont, mr c mohr, mr r l and miss gardiner
                messrs. Jungfleish, messrs cohen, mr. j. tremaune, mr john l low, mr
                c s friedrichs, mr and mrs e r ackerman, mr mrs sud the misses pinkerton, 
                mr max heuraux, mr and miss l braithwaite, mr fuller maitland, miss maitland, mrs
                webster, missee atrindale, mrs saunders, capt jackson, misses miles, miss waterhouse
                col watson, mr jules aghion, mr. g chaix dest ange, count b, tyazkiewics, mrs standish
                , mr and mrs hugh cooper, mr otway tolar, mr ch. r. mcvicar, mrs and miss henry lee.</p>
            </div>
<div type="item">
<head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR,</head>
<p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its
position on Nile bank. Under Garmon Manage
ment. Moderate charges. Patronised by officer
of Army of Occupation. Concerts twice daily.</p>
</div>
            <div type="item"> 
<head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
<p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable hotel in alexandria, facing
    the sea central position.  Under english management</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer and hotel company</head>
<p> River transport of coods between alexandria and cairo.  Three sailings a week.
Agents of alexandria: alexandria bonded warehouse co.</p>
</div>
</div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body> 
    </text>
</TEI>
