<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-10-22">October 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-10">10 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, JULY 10, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="international" source="wire">
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>JAPANESE LAND ON SAGHALIEN ISLAND. RUSSIAN RETREAT. GUNS BLOWN
                            UP.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>St. Petersburg, July 8.</dateline>
                            <p>-General Liapunoff, commandant in Saghalien, telegraphs that a
                                Japanese squadron appeared to the south-east of Korsakovsk on the 7
                                th inst. and began landing troops from 15 ships, under cover of the
                                fire of the torpedo-boats. An hour later 15 torpedo-boats opened
                                fire on Korsakovsk, and killed five men. They were driven back by
                                the Russian guns. After all possible resistance General Liapunoff
                                blew up his guns, burned the Government buildings, and withdrew
                                northwards. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 9.</dateline>
                            <p>The squadron at Saghalien consisted of 2 battleships, 7 cruisers, 3
                                gun-boats, 36 torpedo-boats, and a number of transports which landed
                                a brigade. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>London, July 8.</dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese report occasional skirmishes on both sides of the
                                railway. The Russians have been driven northwards. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>THE PEACE COMMISSION. DEPARTURE OF JAP DELEGATES.</head>
                        <dateline>Yokohama, July 8.</dateline>
                        <p>Baron Komura and suite sailed this afternoon, receiving the most
                            enthusiastic send-off at Tokio by the eldest statesmen, the Cabinet
                            Ministers, Admirals, and Generals. They were seen off by immense crowds.
                            (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>THE MOROCCAN QUESTION. FRANCO-GERMAN AGREEMENT.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Paris, July 9.</dateline>
                            <p>An agreement has been reached between France and Germany regarding
                                Morocco. It is stated here that Germany acknowledges the exceptional
                                position of France, on account of the Algerian frontier, and the
                                possible effect of an agitation in Morocco on the natives of Algeria
                                and Tunis. The sovereignty of the Sultan is recognised, and the
                                integrity of Morocco proclaimed. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Paris, July 8.</dateline>
                            <p>M. Rouvier and Prince Radolin have come to an agreement concerning
                                the Franco-German Note. France adheres to the Conference; Germany
                                recognises the very special situation of France ; the sovereignty of
                                the Sultan is guaranteed, as well as the integrity of Morocco and
                                the “open door.” (Havas.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>CANADIAN NAVY. ARRESTS FOR INSUBORDINATION</head>
                        <dateline>Halifax, July 8.</dateline>
                        <p>Five of the crew of the Canadian cruiser “Canada” have been arrested for
                            insubordination. The crew refused to go to sea, complaining of
                            ill-treatment. (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>NO CHOLERA AT MARSEILLES.</head>
                        <dateline>Marseilles, July 8.</dateline>
                        <p>The reports of cholera at Marseilles are formally contradicted.
                            (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                        <dateline>London, July 8.</dateline>
                        <p>Cambridge beat Oxford by 40 runs. Notts beat Derbyshire by 8 wickets.
                            Surrey beat Lancashire by 11 wickets. Australians beat Hampshire by an
                            innings and 112 runs. Warwickshire v. Sussex has been drawn.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. Table d'Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the
                        Terrace. ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M DELIGHTFUL SITUATION • SEA ENGLISH
                        PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA. The best halfway house between Egypt and England
                        is VIAREGGIO. near PISA. Main line expresses atop. Pine woods, Sands, Sea
                        bathing a mild dim ate, English Pension, Villa Shelley. Ever home comfort.
                        Electric light. Modern sanitation, Benny aspect, close to sea and gardens.
                        i.tt’-n rtv.tiM. MWQnam zjtmwe. ARISTON AERATED WATERS Guaranteed Distilled.
                        Alexandria: 7, Rue de la Poste. Cairo: opposite the Tramways Co. Works,
                        Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Execution</head>
                        <p>El Said All Selim and Ramadan Mursi, who murdered an old woman who sold
                            eggs in the Sonk el-Bersim, were executed at Hadra prison this
                            morning.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The King and the Pigmies.</head>
                        <p>The King commanded the pigmies from the Ituri forest, now being exhibited
                            at the Hippodrome, London, to appear at Buckingham Palace last
                            Thursday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Assize Courts.</head>
                        <p>We hear that on its return to Cairo, the Ministry of Justice will
                            consider the early formation of Assize Courts in all the Egyptian towns
                            where a Court of First Instance sits.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Found Drowned.</head>
                        <p>An Arab named El Hag Mohamed el Maghraby, aged 24 years, has been drowned
                            while bathing in the Mahmoudieh Canal. His body was recovered and
                            removed to the Government Hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>12 vessels passed through the Canal on the 6th inst., 9 of which were
                            British, 1 Austrian, 1 French, 1 Turkish. The day s receipts were frs.
                            320,535.32, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 1,832,595.78.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Ein Chams district of Cairo during the night of Tuesday and
                            at daylight on Wednesday, and in the Esbekieh during the night of
                            Wednesday and at daylight on Thursday, will be poisoned by the
                            police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Union Artistique Francaise</head>
                        <p>are giving a performance (hors abonnement) at the San Stefano Casino on
                            Thursday, 20th inst., at 9,30 p.m. The programme comprises a
                            “bouffonnerie judiciaire” entitled Un Client Serieux, a one-act comedy,
                            LEnvers d’un Ruban, and a vaudeville, Les Deux Timides.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Batons for Bayonets.</head>
                        <p>—The Ministry of the Interior has decided, so we hear, to furnish the N.
                            C. O.’s and constables of the police with batons, which will replace the
                            decidedly unhandy short swords now worn. The “shawish,” when armed with
                            the baton, may look a little less military, but there is no reason to
                            suppose that his efficiency will be impaired.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Banking Houses.</head>
                        <p>—Mr. E. Forti, who has spent 15 years in the service of the Imperial
                            Ottoman Bank and is at present controleur of the Cairo branch of that
                            bank, has been appointed manager of the Alexandria branch of the Bank of
                            Salonica, which will shortly be opened. Mr. Singer, chief of the Stock
                            Dept., Credit Lyonnais, has been appointed to a similar position in the
                            same bank in Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Buried Alive.</head>
                        <p>—On Saturday afternoon a j roof collapsed on a party of workmen who were
                            palling down an old stable belonging to the Tewfik Coptic Benevolent
                            Society in St. Catherine’s-square. The unfortunate men were suffocated
                            by the debris that buried them, and though the Fire Brigade arrived at
                            the scene of the disaster without losing a moment and effected the
                            extrication of the bodies, all attempts to restore life were
                            unsuccessful.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Collision at Sidi Gaber.</head>
                        <p>—At about 2.15 o’clock on Sunday afternoon a train from Aboukir, while
                            running into Sidi Gaber station, collided with a State goods train which
                            was coming up from Gabbari. A policeman, named Bassuni Mohamed Azzam,
                            and Hassan Aii, a flour-seller from Kafr Dawar, were injured. The
                            inquiry is said to have proved that the accident was the fault of the
                            pointsman at Sidi Gaber.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Molahiz Gaffirs.</head>
                        <p>—A number of posts of “molahiz gaffirs” are vacant in the Ministry of the
                            Interior. Officers “en pension” or “en disponibilite” wishing to apply
                            for the vacant posts must present themselves at the Ministry. The pay,
                            which is fixed at L.E. 3 to L.E. 5, does not deprive the officer of the
                            right to his pension or his salary of “disponibilite.” The duties of the
                            “molahiz gaffirs” are to make five inspections per week, to report to
                            the markaz, to examine the roads, bye-ways, canals, etc., of his
                            district, and to arrest persons caught in the act of committing
                            crime.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>An Unnatural Son.</head>
                        <p>—A notable of Minieh province, Sheikh Ali Saleh Namman, has for some time
                            been greatly troubled by the conduct of his son, who added idleness to
                            insolence, failed completely in his school career, and finally robbed
                            his father of £200, which he spent in riotous living. The remonstrances
                            of the justly indignant sheikh appear to have inspired the boy with the
                            idea of killing his father and sisters, and enjoying the family wealth
                            at his ease. He accordingly mixed powdered datura leaf with their food
                            and when asked to eat with them, refused. Within an hour of the meal,
                            the sheikh and his three daughters showed symptoms of datura poisoning.
                            The principal medical officer of the moudirieh was called in, and
                            recognising the symptoms, asked the son why he would not eat with his
                            family. His answers proving unsatisfactory, the boy was searched and the
                            poison found in his pockets. The sheikh and his daughters, who are still
                            dangerously ill, have been sent to the hospital at Minieh. The son has
                            been arrested,</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>THE GRAND MUFTI. CONDITION OF PATIENT IMPROVED.</head>
                        <p>The condition of Sheikh Mohamed Abdou still gives rise to grave
                            apprehensions. The venerable patient is very weak and has passed the
                            last 36 hours in a semi-comatose condition, which was unchanged to-day
                            at midday. On the other hand, the fact that his condition is no worse
                            than it was on Saturday gives some ground for hope that he may yet rally
                            and recover. </p>
                        <p>Numerous messages of sympathy and inquiries have been sent to the family
                            of the Grand Mufti,and Princes, Ministers,Diplomatic Agents, and a
                            multitude of European and native notables have called at his house at
                            Schutz during the last two days. We wish to express our most sincere
                            hope for Sheikh Mohamed Abdou’s recovery. Egypt cannot afford to lose
                            one of her greatest sons. </p>
                        <p>Commenting on the news of the very serious illness of the Grand Mafia,
                            Sheikh Ali Youssef’s organ, “Al Moayad,” writes “We give with the
                            deepest regret and most poignant grief the sad news that has reached us
                            of the Grand Mufti’s health. It has proved impossible to convey the
                            patient to Cairo owing to the increasing gravity of his illness. His
                            many friends and relations are making the most anxious enquiries
                            concerning him. We hope heaven will grant him recovery and a long
                            life.”</p>
                        <p>As we go to press we hear that the Grand Mufti’s condition shows signs of
                            improvement.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>THE RIFAHI AFFAIR.</head>
                        <p>We hear that Mohamed Bey Saleh, President of the Assiout Court of 1st
                            Instance, has submitted a memorial to the Acting Regent, to the Judicial
                            Adviser, and to the President of the Court of Appeal. In the memorial he
                            claims that his judicial dignity has been offended by the language used
                            by Aly Bey Abou el Fatouh, who represented the Procureur-General, and by
                            Morcos Effendi Fehmy, Bedawi Bey Riffahi’s counsel, ooncerning the
                            Assiout Tribunal’s judgment, during the recent trial before the Court of
                            Appeal. The memorial demands that Morcos Effendi Fahmy should be brought
                            before a council of discipline on the ground of the aspersions cast by
                            him on the character of the Assiout Court. Mohamed Bey Saleh is said to
                            have stated that he would far rather resign his position than be exposed
                            to such attacks on his dignity and that of his colleagues, and see the
                            independence of the judges made a mere name.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>MARSA MATROUH.</head>
                        <p>The Government has finally postponed the discussion of the details of the
                            new administration of Marsa Matrouh till after the vacation. It is not
                            expected that any decree regulating the administration of Egypt’s most
                            western port will be issued till the end of the current year.</p>
                        <p>We hear that the Bedouins of the district between Marsa Matrouh and Solum
                            have completely recovered from the excitement into which they were
                            temporarily thrown during the spring of the current year, by the raids
                            of Abd el Kader el Kuzza, the noted sheikh of the Derna Hinterland, and
                            by Turkish military movements.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>SUPPORTING THE “KUTTABS.”</head>
                        <p>Our Minet El Kamh Correspondent writes: — Mouheb Bey, our energetic
                            Moudir, has visited many of the notables of the various districts of our
                            moudirieh, and has urged them to give all the assistance they can to the
                            “kuttabs,” pointing out the great benefits derived by the people from
                            the education there received. The notables of our markaz of Minet El
                            Kamh responded most generously to the appeal, and the sum of £1,000 was
                            subscribed by eleven of our leading men, six of whom are members of the
                            committee of the Minet El Kamh Kuttab.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head>
                        <p>By kind permission of Lt..Col. C. J. Markham and officers, the band of
                            the 1st Batt. King’s /Royal Rifles will perform the following programme
                            of music at the Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Tuesday), commencing at 9
                            p.m.</p>
                        <list>
                            <item>1 Overture—“French Comedy”—Keler Bela.</item>
                            <item>2 Selection—“Pinafore”—Sullivan.</item>
                            <item>3 Air—“Cujus Animam” from “Stabat Mator”—Rossini.</item>
                            <item>4 Darkey’s Droam—Lansing.</item>
                            <item>5 Romance sans Paroles—“Simple Aveu”—Thome.</item>
                            <item>6 Selection—“La Mascotte”—Audran.</item>
                            <item>7 Valse—“Sobre las Olas”—Rosas.</item>
                            <item>8 Two-step—“Creole Belles”—Zampe.</item>
                            <item>Regimental March.</item>
                            <item>Khedivial Anthem.—God Save the King.</item>
                        </list>
                        <p>Thomas Brown,, Bandmaster.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. “Niger,” from Marseilles, passed the
                            Straits of Messina on Saturday afternoon and is due here tomorrow
                            morning.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER BREMEN. Obtainable from every Respectable Firm
                        In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the Sudan Otherwise apply to E. J Fluerent, Cairo
                        F. Micallef Sole Agent 11, rue Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY. PEAKE BEY’S RETIREMENT.</head>
                        <p>El Miralai Malcolm Peake Bey, C.M.G., is struck off the strength of the
                            Egyptian Army from 4th July, 1905.</p>
                        <p>In the latest Army Orders from Head Quarters,Khartoum,the Acting Sirdar
                            expresses his appreciation of the services rendered by this officer for
                            the last ten years. During this period he has taken part with the
                            Egyptian Army in the following campaigns and actions:— Expedition to
                            Dongola, 1896, actions of “Firket” and “Hafir;” Nile Expedition, 1897,
                            capture of “Abou Hamed ; ” Nile Expedition, 1898, battles of “Atbara”
                            and “Khartoum;” and the Nile Expedition of 1899. As Commandant of the
                            Artillery and Director of Ordnance, which appointments he held for the
                            last six and four years respectively, and when in command of the Sudd
                            Expedition, which in 1900 opened up the White Nile to navigation, the
                            excellence and thoroughness of his work was most conspicuous. The Sirdar
                            also expresses his great regret at El Miralai Peake Bey’s retirement
                            from the Egyptian Army, and in the name of the army wishes him every
                            success in his future career.</p>
                        <p>His Highness the Khedive has been most graciously pleased to confer upon
                            this officer the decoration of the 3rd class of the Medjidieh.</p>
                        <p>His Highness the Khedive has also been most graciously pleased to oonfer
                            the decoration of the 4th class Medjidieh upon El Bimbashi E. J. F.
                            Vaughan, Assistant Private Secretary and Deputy Assistant Adjutant
                            General to H. E. the Sirdar.</p>
                        <p>The Acting Sirdar has issued a Special Army Order announcing to the army
                            with the deepest regret the death of El Kaimakam H. L. H. Fell Bey,
                            Senior Inspector of the Bahr El Ghazal Province, which occurred at
                            Tembura, in the Bahr El Ghazal, on the 19th June. Fell Bey joined the
                            Egyptian Army on the 26th February, 1899, and took part in the following
                            campaigns with that Force:—Nile Expedition 1899; Sudan, 1900-02. —
                            Re-occupation of the Bahr El Ghazal Province ; Sudan, 1904-05.—
                            Operations in the Bahr El Ghazal Province. He was in possession of the
                            4th Class Osmanieh cnd 4th Class Medjidieh, conferred upon him by his
                            Highness the Khedive. The Acting Sirdar feels sure that the whole army
                            shares his sorrow in the loss to the army of this valuable officer,
                            whose services in the Bahr El Ghazal had been of conspicuous merit.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>SUMMER LEAVES.</head>
                        <p>Leave of absence has been granted the following Sudan Government
                            officials and Army officers until the undermentioned dates” ~ El Miralai
                            Persse Bey, officer commanding Cavalry, until 28th September ; El
                            Miralai Matthews Bey, Governor of the Upper Nile Province, until 22nd
                            October ; El Kaimakam Maclean Bey, officer commanding 16th Battalion,
                            until 13th September; El Bimbashi Rome, Cavalry, until 21st
                            September.</p>
                        <p>Extension of leave has been granted to :— El Kaimakam Palmer Bey,
                            Financial Secretary, until 20th August ; El Kaimakam Kennedy Bey,
                            D.S.O., Director of Works, until 16th July ; El Bimbashi O’Sullivan,
                            Junior Inspector, Upper Nile Province, until 3rd August.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
                        <p>The plague bulletin for the week ending 8th inst. reports 19 cases of
                            this disease, of which 13 occurred at Alexandria, 4 at Tant-el-Ghezireh,
                            1 at Damanhour, and 1 at Goreis. Eight of the cases at Alexandria have
                            ended fatally and there are still three Europeans and four natives under
                            treatment in this town. Two deaths have also been reported during the
                            week from Toukh. The number of recoveries amounts to four, namely, one
                            European at Alexandria, one native at Zifta, and two natives at
                            Damanhour. There are at present 25 cases under treatment, 4 being
                            Europeans and 21 being natives. The total number of cases notified since
                            the 1st January amounts to 146, as compared with 701 cases during the
                            corresponding period last year.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                        <p>Thirty deaths from cattle plague have been notified in Egypt during the
                            week ending 8th inst. These cases have occurred in the following
                            districts :— Belbeis, 1 ; Hehia, 3 ; Shibin-el-Kom, 20 ; Menouf, 1, and
                            Beni Souef, 1. The number of deaths daring the corresponding period last
                            year was 1,156. Since the commencement of the epidemic the total number
                            of deaths amounts to 147,321, distributed as follows :—Gouvernorats,
                            892, Lower Egypt, 54,193 ; Upper Egypt, 92,236.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="calendar">
                    <head>CALENDAR OF THE WEEK. (Coptic and Mohamedan.)</head>
                    <list>
                        <item>Sun. 9</item>
                        <item>Mon. 10 The blessed Nile begins to rise abundantly.</item>
                        <item>Tues. 11 Abundance of honey.</item>
                        <item>Wed. 12 Sow Syrian durah.</item>
                        <item>Thurs. 13 Period of regular north-west winds. </item>
                        <item>Fri. 14 H.H. the Khedive Abbas Hilmi born, 1874. Season of
                            grapes.</item>
                        <item>Sat 15 General purification of the air. Abundance of cactus
                            fruit.</item>
                    </list>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>WRECKED PASSENGERS AT PORT SAID. SAVED BY THE CRUISER “RION." THEIR
                            SOMALI HOSTS.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Sunday.</dateline>
                        <p>Yesterday afternoon, the Messageries S.S. “Polynesien” arrived from Aden,
                            at which port she had taken on board 250 of the survivors the Wreck of
                            the “Chadoc,” which was lost! on Cape Guardafui on 26th June. The S.S.
                            “Iraouaddy,” of the same company, has just arrived from the canal,
                            haying on board the remaining 360, all of whom were picked up by the
                            Russian Volunteer cruiser “Rion” (ex “Smolensk”) on the 1st inst, and
                            landed at Aden, at which port the “Rion” was obliged to coal, she having
                            burned all her woodwork and fittings to enable her to reach Aden. </p>
                        <p>In an interview which I had with two of the passengers of the “Chadoc,” I
                            learned that the vessel went ashore at 4 a.m. close under Guardafui on
                            the 26th ulto. and that most of the ship’s boats were broken up.</p>
                        <p>The Somalis, many of whom spoke French, having served in the “Haussas,”
                            took the whole number, including 80 children, off the vessel, only one
                            being lost in the rescue operations. The passengers in many cases were
                            able to save their personal effects, and the steward’s department to
                            disembark a quantity of provisions. The natives built them rude huts of
                            twigs and gorse and treated them all with considerable kindness, which
                            belies the general idea entertained that the men of that coast are utter
                            savages.</p>
                        <p>After four days spent in the village, they were able to attract the
                            attention of the “Rion” by means of a signal staff erected on a
                            sand-hill to the north of the Cape and were all embarked (save one, who
                            was lost two days before) on the Russian vessel, arriving at Aden all
                            well on the morning of the 4th July.</p>
                        <p>By the “Polynesien” there also arrived 190 Russian refugees, who were
                            transferred to the S.S. “Tchihatchoff,” which vessel sailed last night
                            direct for Odessa.</p>
                        <p>M. Coullant, principal agent of the Suez Canal Company, together with a
                            number of other residents, amongst whom was Mme Schmidt, wife of the
                            sub-agent, left for France in the “Polynesien,’ which is due to arrive
                            at Marseilles at daylight on Thursday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>A LOCAL SCANDAL.</head>
                        <p>Some two months ago, I noted the destruction of the “Bains Minerve” and
                            the refusal of the authorities to allow a syndicate to build a similar
                            place on account of the reputation which it had gained. Since then, land
                            has been let in large quantities for the erection of bath houses on the
                            beach, and now, instead of the gambling and so on being carried on in
                            one large building, there are at least 20 or 30 in which the wildest of
                            orgies take place nightly. Not content with that, the whole line of
                            beach is now filthy in the extreme and a grave menace to health—and the
                            police do not see that which is plain to every resident.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>NAVAL BAND CONCERT.</head>
                        <p>The concert given by the British naval band last night was attended by a
                            large number of residents and visitors. The programme included
                            selections from “La Traviata,” “Faust,” “The Geisha,” etc., and proved
                            very successful.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The Earl and Countess of Cromer were present at the reception held on the
                        30th ult. by Lady Londonderry at Londonderry House, in honor of the King’s
                        birthday. Lord and Lady Cromer left London on the 1st inst for Inverness,
                        Scotland.</p>
                    <p>Sir Eldon and Lady Gorst are at Ramsgate, staying at the Granville Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Sir Wm. Garstin is leaving for England to-morrow via Port Said.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Rucker-Jenisch, German Diplomatic Agent, arrived at San Stefano
                        yesterday.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Brunyate is expected to arrive in Egypt early in August on his return
                        from leave.</p>
                    <p>Major Le Breton is expected to return to Cairo early in October.</p>
                    <p>Graf von Wedel, first secretary to the German Diplomatic Agency and Consulate
                        General, returned from leave in Europe to-day.</p>
                    <p>The name of Colonel D. F. Lewis, C. B., A.D.C., late Cheshire Regiment, has
                        now been restored to the half-pay list in the monthly “Army List.” Colonel
                        Lewis was placed on half-pay on return from Egypt September 27, 1900, and
                        was removed by error on it being intimated that he had been selected for
                        service as a Military Attache with the Japanese Army in Manchuria.</p>
                    <p>Cavaliere Falqui Cao, judge of the Italian Consular Court, and his family
                        arrived here yesterday from Genoa by the Memphis.</p>
                    <p>M Georges Philippides, chief of the Suez Canal secret police, has been
                        granted 3 1/2 months leave of absence, from July 15.</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will shortly take place, between Miss Lena
                        Erbicella Dores and M, Mioeu Riccardo.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="sporting">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY</head>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>A. S. C.</head>
                        <p>JULY SKYE MEETING. The following are the entries for the July Skye
                            Meeting:</p>
                        <p>Novices’ Race.—Prinoe Omar PashaTous-soan’s“ShneinaD,” Omar Rey Sultan
                            and Ahmed Bey BakriV*5tot,* Ishact Bey' Hu serin’s *£•y-rout” and
                            rtMastour,*‘Mr. Karam’s “Tembel,” Mr. Albert J. Sursbck's ,rHotspnr.” </p>
                        <p>Newcomers’ Plate: ^Saleh Bey ' Ibrahimieh, Mr. R. L. McCollougli’u
                            “Flashlight,” I shack: Bey Hussein’s "Kainboul* II..’' Mr. E Kanun’s
                            "TembeL” Mr. AIb*rt J.Sur-sock’s “Hotspur,” Mr. Donaldson’s "Derry boy,”
                            Mr. J. Hoyami’s “Cri-Cri/’ Hassan Bey Kheir el Din’s “Tanta.”</p>
                        <p>Trial Plate. — Omar Bey Saltan and Ahmed Bey Bakri’s “Zut,” Messrs. N.
                            Soussa and Kamel Eff. 'Maher’s “Sooial Life,” Saleh Bey Yaghen’s
                            “Wasaal,* Ishack Bey Huasein’a El Tahawi,” Ishack Bey: Hussein and Bey
                            Kheir el Din's “Laheh” (late ' Rais,) Mr. Ed. Bustro’s “Malgr6 Tout,”
                            Moharrem Pasha r Chehim’s “Aeolus,” Mr. Albert J. Sarsook’s “Sans
                            Pared/’ Capfc. G. B. Byrne’s “Mahmoud,” Mr. C. W. Hemp’s “Grand
                            Slam.”</p>
                        <p>Pony Stakes.—Prinoe Omar Pasha Tous-un’s “Hadban,” Mr. S. N. Simond’s
                            *fThe Bard,” Ishack Bey Hussein's “Lahek,” 'Mr. E. Karam’s “Bayard,” Mr.
                            Ed. Bustro’s “Nimr,” Mr. Albert J. Sursook’s “Haros,” Moharrem Pasha
                            Chehim’s “Cupid,” Mr. J. Chaloni’s ,"Temsah.”</p>
                        <p>July Plate.—Messrs. N. Soussa and Kamel Eff. Maher’s “Social Life,” Saleh
                            Bey Yeghen’s 'London,” Ishack Bey Hoasein’s “Salad” and “El
                            Tahawi,”’Mr.- Ed. Bostros' “M*lgr4 Tout,” Moharrem Pasha Chehim’s
                            “Mittaud.” Tropical Plate. — Saleh Bey Yaghen’s “Nonri,” Ishack Bey.
                            Hussein's “Shahrour,” Ishack Bey Hussein and Bey -Kheir el Din’s
                            “Lahek,” Mr. Albert J. Sursook’s “Sans Pared,” Moharrem Pasha Chehim’s
                            “Agib,” Baron J. E. de Menasoe’s “Radium.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB (ALEX.)</head>
                        <p>A spoon competition will take place at Mustapha range on Saturday next at
                            3 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>CRICKET A. C. C. v. E. T. C.</head>
                        <p>This match was played on Saturday last and ended in a draw. For the club,
                            MacLaren played well for 80, and for the E. T. C., Messrs. R. B. McLean
                            and Stacey played fine innings at a critical moment, The fielding of the
                            E.T.C. was not up to its usual good standard, and, had it been better,
                            would no doubt have given them the victory.</p>
                        <p> Scores — A. C. C A. B. Carver, b. McLean... 17 K.Macauley, b. McLean...
                            21 P. Carver, c. Henley, b. Byrne ... 22 G. MacLaren, c. McLean, b.
                            Thurston 80 P. P. Graves, c. Collier. b. Byrne... 0 K. P. Birley, c.
                            Henley, b. Stacey. 33 S. J. Dawson, b. Stacey  11 E. N. Haseldon, b
                            Thurston   9 S. Wyatt, b. Thurston  8 A. A. Carver, b. Stacey  0 C. S.
                            Scarth, not out  0 Extras    9 Total  210 E. T. C. M. Blythman, c.
                            Dawson, b. McLaren 4 G.N. Cheesman, b. McLaren, b.Dawson 0 P. J.
                            Byrne,c. Macaulay, b. Dawson..* 10 E. G. Henley, b. H. B. Carver ..* ...
                            16 C. D. Stacey, not out  60 R B. McLean, c. H.P. Carver, b. Birley 65
                            C. Steele, c. H. B. Carver, b. Birley... 2 G. Millar, c. H. P. Carver,
                            b. Birley..* 0 A. B. Collier, not out..*  * ..* 1 G. B. Harvey H. E.
                            Thurston did not bat Extras...   22 Total for 7 wkts  180</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>WATER POLO. R. A. M. C. v. ALEX. SWIMMING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>This fixture was brought off on Saturday afternoon at Rs-el-Tin in lovely
                            weather and before a good turn-out of spectators, both on shore and in
                            boats surrounding the enclosure. The R. A. M. C. started the game with
                            the sun in their eyes and after some near passing Ames got through the
                            defence and opened the score by a high-placed goal, the ball just
                            clearing the cross-bar, in favor of his team. Halftime arrived with a
                            score of one goal to the R A M. C.</p>
                        <p>On resuming, the club team carried the ball down field and for a time the
                            game was confined to the homesters’ goal. Some neat and exciting passing
                            now took place and Ecclestone, clearing, put a well-placed goal in, thus
                            bringing the club’s team score to one. Fast play was now witnessed, the
                            R. A. M.C. . trying hard for the conqueror, but time was celled, the
                            score remaining one all.</p>
                        <p>The following were the teams R.A.M.C.: Steele, Cruise, White, Bright,
                            Ames, Benn, Adams being in goal. Alexandria Swimming Club: Wood,
                            Hewgill, Mace, Darton, Ecclestone, and Webb in goal. Referee: Q. M. S.
                            Sauders</p>
                        <p>Members are hereby notified that from Saturday next, the weekly meetings
                            will be held at the basin entered by Custom House Gate No. 28, adjacent
                            to Messrs. Worms &amp; Co.’s petroleum tanks.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>


        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
