<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-09"> February 9, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<div type="item">
<head>thb bqtptiak OAirm, rmniaDAT, February o, leot.</head>
<head>CONDITION OF RUSSIA.</head>
<head>At'AIM MIC! aSaUCLIY.</head>
<p>St. I’KTF.Hsmmci, February 8
General Trepofl Miimumied tho Curatoi
the Elucati-m Department lx f-ro him and
formed him iluit he wasdetermined input do
tho academic uuap liy. All student* tvfu»inj.
return to their Kiudit* in a tranquil man
will bo Miummrily e.\|icllc If tlio pro less
syiu|u>thi'U with the students, education in
Petersburg will cease.
A tlreli 0 of tlio T-ur Mp|HiiliU M. ^KoIioIk
Councillor of the Euipiio, as president of
intluenii.il cou.mUtco to revise tho censorsl
and the press laws.	(tteuu</p>
<p>St. Petersbuko, Fobruary 8
'Ilie Fitiance Minister has submitted to i
Tsar a report a-kiug for reforms in favor
the workmen.
Tho stiike is dying out in Poland. (Hart</p>
<p>St. 1'etebsuubo, February 8
The Tsar has approved, and referred to
Committee 61 Ministers lor immediate legt
lion, a series ol most lioeral pro|K»als. '1
Minister of Finance is dealing with the cot
tions of labour, lie recoguisos notably
workmen's right to strike, which has hithe
been a crime.	IJletU'</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>v LOCAL AND GENERAJ.</head>
<p>Rudolph Home.—Mr. Eugcno Nahman hi
sent £1 to tho Rudolph Home, Alexandria,
memory of Mrs. Bauer.
American Mission.—Tho English servi
at the American Mission in TanUh will I
omitted nest Sabbath, but will be held
, seal two weeks from that day.
Suez Canal.—U vessels passed throuf
tile Canal on the Gth iiist.. viz., 9 British.
Dutch, 2 Gorman. 2 Austrian. Tho receipts f
the ilay were frs. 309,3*5.60, making the tot
r of up to the Gth iust frs. 2,325,331.82.
iwn Tiie Band of the "Tourah Prison Neg
; t., boys'" will play in the llelouaiCJportiug Glut
Her .neiosure, adjoining the I'cwfik Palace Hot.
“•re tomorrow, from 3 to 5.30 p.m. The boys w
St. also give an exhibition ol drill. Mcinbei
visitois, mid residents are invited. Eutran</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>FATHER CAPON.</head>
<head>REFUGED IN SWITZERLAND.</head>
<p>St. 1'eieksbukq, February 8.
Father Gapou is kuuwu to bo iuSwiizerlaud.
{JCcaUf.j</p>
<p>St. Petersburo, February 8.
Pope Gapon has taken reluge in Switzer-
land.	(Uacat.)</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE RUSSIAN GENERALS.</head>
<head>PROMISED REVELATIONS.</head>
<p>Irkutsk, February 8.
General Gnpeiiboig and ms stall haveanived
current to die eiicct tlial General Gripeuberg
is going l« Sl Petersburg lor tbe puipose ol
accusing General Ivunqiatkiii ol leaving hmi
iu the luiob, and ol gclieial inertia. (</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>/. SAD DEATH OF JUDGE KEILLT</head>
<p>Wo regret to announce the 4*atb, undr
painful circumstances, of Judge Keilly, Iat
111 American judge in tho Mixed Court of Appea
who had resided in Egypt for-twenty yean
The accideiit by which he met his dooth, i
06 thus reported in the “New York Horald
(Paris) of January 29 :—A- well-dressed mai
*s ap|ioariug to bo about Sixty years of age, we
knocked down by a delivery van on the Plac
do la Concorde yesterday.' Ilo nas taken to th
?•' Beaujon Hospital, whore ho died in the ever
I ng. In his pocketbook was found a card wit
or tho address, “Judge Keily, 49, Dorerestcee
*1 Piccadilly, London."
Tho late judge was appointed to the Corn
• •f 1st Iustauoe at Cairo in- the Khediviato <
r0 Tewfik l’odia and was promoted to th* .Qoui
3 3 ol Appeal some years altcrwarda. BothTteJad
eh |1M wife had a Urge circle of friends iuijgnr
•h |ur thoy were most genial Aid hospital^
™. Ju.lgo Keilly loaves two aoua and a’ daughty
c*3 l'ho Utter is married to Captain Hall, of th
Irish Rides.</p>
<p>hip A Dementi.—Mr. Aquiline, manager of the
rr.y Tcwtik PoUce Hotel at Helouan, writes to us
on the subject ol the incorrect statement made
m a Cairo uioiuiug newspaper to the effect
th.- .hat be has been appointed manager of tbe
ol .National Hotel at Cairo, lio writes : “I shad
tool obliged it you will moke it public Unit
u. circuwsuuices causeu mo to ilochue the kind
oiler mode to mo to work the abovo hotel."
The Cretan AIukdek.—Tho enquiry into
llje the circumstances mtoudiug tbe murder ol a
Cretan lawyer, Zagaki, by the Cretau poet auu
,l,.e patriot, Meuegakis, negau ibis morning at tho
ileileuic consular Court at Alexandria. Tbe
,llu tiogeiiy look place bore a low months ago but
rl° mo nationality ol tbe assassin was unsettle■
uutii tbe last lew days. Mencgakis has made
a complete coulossiou of bis crime, which ap-
pears to have been of a purely political charac-
ter, the victim having, It is alleged, betrayed
the cause ol the isuvuduni to the Button iu the
.ate resurrection.</p>
<p>Tbe Khedive will hold the Konrban Beyram
reception at Abdeen Palace on Tuesday next,
11th mat. The order of the reception .will be
published in our issuo ol Saturday next.
His Highness has bestowed the following
distinctions on Uie umlenneulioned officials on
the occasion ol their retirement from the
service of the Egyptian Government:
HaJistaA: jUobamed hffendi Aly, Ute
“moaweu idara, ’ Moudirieh of Gbirgeh.
Uabta: TakU Etloudi Malta, late, of the
Railway Adnuiusualiou.</p>
<p>dledjidteJi Commander (3rd class): Dr.
jjymmcra, late pruleasor of pathology at the
BcUool of Medicine.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>thiiSU.NAL AND SUDlAL.</head>
<p>‘ Lieut-Geu. Sir T. Kolly-Kenny left Loudon
yesterday week fur Egypt.</p>
<p>j We regret to announce the doath of Mme.
Veuve Saian Bauer, wnicb occurred at Alex-
andria yesterday. The iuucral will take place
mis alleruoou Iruin deceased's residence at</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>MINISTRY OF JUSTICE.</head>
<p>Mr. Hervoy Wedgwuod Vaughan Williams,
Darrisler-ut-law, has been appointed “Subetitut
au Conteutieux.”
Mr. Michael Harvey Rafforty, barrister-at-
law and “liceucie eu Droit" of Paris, has been
appointed inspector on the Surveillance Com-
mittee.
Both those appointments are “a titre d'essai"
for one year.</p>
<p>Capt. W. G. liusluasou, A. S. C., and Lieut,
il. h. MucKwuitu, D.S.U., R.R., bave re-
ported tbeir ainval in Egypt aud been
taken on tbe slreugtb ul tbe cgypuau Arrnj,
„eeu posted to tbu Department ol Supplies aud
,ne latter to tbe Summ Gtivornmeuu</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ADMIRAL TOGO.</head>
<p>KuhK, February ?•
Aduiir.il Tgo arrived Here, and rmmcoiatei;
hoisted bis ling nil ibe "Mlhaiia. I •
URITISII STEAMER CAPTURED.</p>
<p>loEio, Fenruary b.
Tbe British steamer ' Ivastry,' laden will
Hokkaido Island.	i /i-uu.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GERMAN VICTORY IN STAMUOL'L.</head>
<head>TILE PKoJbCIED NEW LOAN.</head>
<p>Consta.n riNOPLK, February 8.
The remarkable stiugg.e betweeu tbo German
and French Embassies here, with the object ol
inducing tbe Porte to ux|>cnd a considerable
proportion of tlio projected uow loan ol
£5,000,1X10 from tbu Imperial Ottoman Bank
upon guns in ilieir ro-pective Countries, enden
iu a victory for Germany. Tbe Porte consented
to buy Krupp guns. M. Constant, French Am-
bassador here, therenp-.n m.tilied tbe Porto
that the Paris market wuuld be closed against
the now loan. The Ottoman Bank consequently
withdrew from -the whole transaction. The
Deutsch Bank is now oUcring to assist the
Treasury.	(Hotter.</p>
<p>ihefullowiug passengers have left Cairo by tbo
> 3. "Raineses 111. lor tue .Nile trip : Prince
a .t.-:uberg, Maiquls aud Alaiquise do la
lags.-slere, Mr. aud Mrs. A. M. Druwu, Messrs.
• 1.. u aud J. 11. Doxter, Airs. Ivaxter, Mr. aud
Air-, ’iveluis, Air. and Jirs. Dugart, Aliases tuiny
< w. and Anna n. Riounead, Air. 11. Ganns, Miss
i U. Cu>e, Air. nuil Alls. G. li. Cruukstoil, Miss
K. Drunimolid, llev. J. A. aud Mrs. Duuuar-
niuimar, Airs. K. At. tvaits, Air. .NaUl. ElsUup
t-anar, Alls. R. E. Foster, Jlr. and Mrs. R. b.
oregory, AllssCs £>>eauur aud Rutb Gicgory,
.lira, and Aliss Guiniau, Air. R. M. Ring, airs,
vou Klouneu, Alias fanny Gebr, Miss A. C.
lain, Dr. J. tJ. and Airs. Merreui, Mr., Mrs. aud
Alias L. AlcDoiiaid, Mr. li. G. Miber, Mrs.
I AicKmlay, Mr. aud Airs. G. Malcolm, Miss
llelolse Meyer, Mrs. McCollum, Mr. Jas Rowan,
.Misses Florence aud Alice Kowau, Countess do
iorionne, Miss E. Bmelne, Miss Auuie Bteveus,
Airs. Joseph Buckney, Miss Adebude Bpotfurd,
Mr. and Mrs. W. R. Btiritug, Misses Dorothy,
May and Jeou W. tuning, Miss Tboruburn,
Air. 1. Thompson, Miss V. Whyte, Mr. aud
.Mrs. J. T. Walton, Miss Florence Walton,
Mr. J. II. Williams.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GERMANY AND ENGLAND.</head>
<head>MR. LEES SPEECH.</head>
<p>London, February 8.
Mr. Lee, speaking again at Eastleigh, referred
to the extra rdiuary outcry which had been
raised over his last >q>eecli. ‘Hie latter wan a
plain recital of certain naval reforms, but a
meaning had been read into it that never
existed. Ho bad suggested no threat to whioh
any foreign Power could take exception. (/<•)'
Amongst the latest arrivals at the Savoy
Hotel, Port Said, we notice Sir Beujamin
Baker, Sir John Aird, Mr. Franz Bayer, Mr.
and Mrs. V. Heller, Lt. Col. Mortou Duckelt,
Mr. John Smith, Mr. G. F. aud Mina Binl, Mr.
and Mrs. N. P. Cairties, Mr. Beruheim aud
Ihtuily, Mrs. and Miss Clayton.</p>
<p>Tlio following passengers left Shellal today,
by the P. S. “ Memnon. ” Dr. Hugo and Mr.-.
Hinzc, Mr. and Mrs. H. LmcoIn Tangye, Lady
D-megal 1, Rev. B. Boughton I>eigh, Mr R
W. Boughton Lcigb, Mr. P. F. Casarotto, Mr.
Mr. II. 1’helps Stokes, Mr. H. Arrowsmith, Mr.
Ionising Uee, Mr. and Mrs. John W. Stewart,
Dr. Ludwig and Mrs. Kom, Mr. H. Gilde-
tneistor, Baron and Baroness Podesta.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ALDEHSON’S GARD N, BULK.LJ.</head>
<head>OR AND VANIFTY ENTIRTAWIIDn</head>
<head>HOYAL, TOOKBV FAMILY.</head>
<head>HMtice enartiw OaK*v</head>
<head>PLAGUE AT LIVERPOOL.</head>
<p>Liverpool, February 8.
A fatal case of plague lias occurred here ‘-n
board the dS. “Crewe Hall" from Rangoon.
l NOTES FUOM 8UEZ.
“ (FbOH .2CH P^tMPOroiXT).
J-	MARQUIS DI RUDINI’S VISIT.
».	8uex, Fobruary 8.
is The Marquis di Rudini, ex-Prime Minister of
l" Italy, arrived at 8uet this afternoon by the
n, 4 20 train from Cairo on route torMaaaowah.
is At the station be was met by Mr. Luigi Do-
jo perais, Italian Vice-Consul at 8uez, Mr. Aug.
ie Pacho, and other members of the Italian
n- o»mmunity. Shortly afterwards, the Plorio-
[L Rubattino steam-launch conveyod tho Marquis
it, on board the steamer “ Tobe, " which sailed in
the evening lor Masaowah.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>of % COLLISION INTHE CANAL</head>
<p>rt . The British steamer " Goorkha " collided in
[j the Canal last Sunday afternoon, near Shaluf
it, slnfiou, with tho S^. "Solo,” which was moored
f._ at the time. Both steamers sustained some
J damage over the water line.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<head>BANKING IN EGYPT.</head>
<p>Tbe Comptoir National d’Escompte de Paris
expocts to have its Alexandria branch opened
lor working by next June.
The Bank of Rome’s new branch at Alex-
andria will open here in about two months’
time.
Tbo Credito Itariauo is considering the
advisability ul o-Uaulubiug a branch bore, but
nas come to no dobuite decision on the matter
aa yet.
Tbe now Geruian-Greek-Orient Bank will
establish brauenes ib Egypt, but nut im-
mediately, as it will start operations Erst
at Athens mid Constantinople.</p>
<p>Our Constantinople Correspondent sends us
Uie luilowiug details on this new Levantine
uauk :—lu Greece Uie orauebes ot tbe NaUon-
al Uauk will be at too disposal ol the Orieut
Rank, so it will not be necessary to open new
uianches iu that country. But in pruporUou
with tne development ot business, Uie Orient
uauk win establish branches in various towns
ot Turkey, Egypt, aud other countries in the
East. Willi regard to Uie capital, the National
uauk lur Deutschland, ol uerlin, aud the Na-
tional Rouk of Greece haro taken all the
siiarcs, the value uf winch is 10 million francs.
I bey have reserved to themselves the right to
make a public issue within three years. M.
A nting, mauager ul tbe National Bank lur
Deutscbiaud aud one ot those interested in
the Orieut Bank, has stared, iu an interview,
mat the aim of tbe now tinaucial establish-
ment is to Lieu i tale the importation of Hellenic
products into Geruiauy. It will advauco uiouey
on bibs of lading. M. Wituiig also said that
the Orieut Rank would establish iu Ureece
storehouses lor wares which the proprietor
does uot wish' to export immediately and on
which the Orient Rank will also advance
money. The Bank will endeavour to oome to an
understanding with the Deutsche-Levan to
Lmio to iacihtate the export trade.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>WIRELESS TELEGRAPHY AT SUEZ.</head>
<p>It is expected that Lloyd's wireless telegraphy
station at Port Tewfik will be completed by the
end of March, when Suez will be in communica-
tion with steamers in the -Rad Sow h*n»0
wireless* Apparatus on board, as well u with
Port 8aid.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>‘ PILGRIM 8TEAMSK ASHORE</head>
<p>The Greek steamer “Kilikia," bound to
Jeddah with a large number of Turkish pilgrims
on board, grounded iu the Canal in the Small
Bitter Lako, aud was refloated yesterday with
the assistanne of a Canal Company’s tug. The
“ Kilikia." sustained no damage whatever, and
prooeeded on her journey.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THB LAST OP THB PILGRIM8.</head>
<p>Tho Khedivial Mail Line, with a view to
clearing ont tho remaining foreign pilgrims at
Suez, who haduotthe means to pruoeed on their
journey, senttheirS.8. “Menzalah" to Suez. The
vessel Bailed for Jeddah yesterday afternoon,
after taking on board 600 pilgrims at a very
low rate, and 300, who were not in a position
to pay, were carried absolutely free. These are
tho last pilgrims this year on their way to the
Holy City viASuez.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>“FEDOBA” AT THE ABBAS</head>
<head>SIGNA. BBLLINCIONI’8 SECOND
APPEARANCE.</head>
<p>The performance of Ftdora at the Abbas
Helmy Theatre yesterday evening, with Signa.
Bellincioni in the title rOle, was undoubtedly
an event in the local theatrioal world. A
more finished performance it would be im-
possible to imsgine on any stage, and the
result was a repetition of the great artiste’s
triumph of Saturday last Fedora is as exceed-
ing interesting opera, in that the orchestral
treatment is very distinct from that acoepted
in most works of the kind : it has a curious
reminisoonoe of Wagner, notably of Trittan,
in oertain parts. Tbe libretto, known to most
people through M. V. 8ardou, is certainly
calculated to furnish good dnmatio singing, and
no artiste is better fitted to bring ont to the
full the dramatio points with which it abounds
than Signora Bellincioni. Her performance
was one of tho most remarkable achievements
in the art of musio-drema that we have ever
witnessed. 8he knew bow to work towards a
climax, both in particular and in general,
when the first of all realised the imprisonment
of tie great depths of her passion, and wbon
she later realised the ripeness and fulness of
her ultimate despair. She was, in a word,
magnificent; and her every action betrayed
the consummate actress that she is. Tbe
womanly love and devotion to the husband
who is slain, her cunning in oompaasing her
terrible revenge, her passion for her lover,
are depioted with masterly skill and daring
fidelity. With what exqui«ite gentleness and
feeling she wins the affection of her lover;
with what overpowering force and majesty she
faces and vanquishes the murderer of her
husband! Tbe infinite pathos of the concluding
act, the pathetic picture of the desperate
woman who flies to poison as a relief from her
mental agony, with the face of a Madonna,
and the great, sad eyes full of a sorrow for
whioh thore can be no alleviation are, in truth,
things that no one who has witnessed them
will ever forget Fedora is a character that
exactly suits the tomperamont, the personality,
and the splendid taleqt of the great Italian
actress and singer. Sbo was well seoonded in
her trying rflle by Sig. Pagani aa Conte Loris,
as well as by the other performers. 8ig. Pagani
is a tenor with a future and shared in Signora
Bellincioni's great triumph. He sang with
taste aud no little dramatio power, although
at times he seemed rather nervous, which was
probably due to the prosenoe and personality
of Siguora Bellincioni. The orchestra did full
justioe to the beautiful music of the opera,
and tbo ohorus worked well. Tho staging ol
the opera left nothing to be desired, both the
scenery and costumes being exoelleat. Signora
Bollincioni's dresses were nothing less than
superb.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>DEVELOPMENT OF FARSHUT.</head>
<p>Our Farshut Correspondent states that the
Postmaster-General has decided to open a
branch of the postoffice savings bank at
Farshut in consequence of the petition ot the
inhabitants, whioh be voioed in our columns.
The inhabitants are delighted with Saba
Pasha’s promptness in hearkening to their
wishes.
The employes of tbe Corporation of Western
Egypt are still hoping that the Railway
Administration will grant their request and
stop the “train de luxe'"at Farshut station.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>HELOUAN RAILWAY.</head>
<p>Since the Dolta Light Railway Company has
taken over the Cairo-Helouan lino, great
satisfaction has boen evinced at tbo reforms
that tbe company has introduoed. We extract
the following passage from our vernacular
ouutemporary "Misr”:
Wo are requested by several peoplo inhabit-
ing Helouan to express their warmest thanks
for the many aud various reforms brought
about by tbe Delta Company on the lino which
before long they oxpect to become one of the
most orderly and the least dangerous of lines.
Tbo reason that some are conducting a virulent
campaign against the company, despite its
recent existence, is due to the mere bet that
they are uot willing to squander money in the
samo way as the former oompany with the
view to preventing hypocrites from exhibiting
their crying and manifold defeats. Tho object
of tbe now oompany is reforms in the full
sense of the word, and no babbling or nonsense
whatever on tbe part of ill-intentioned people
is to deter thorn from attaining this moat
commendable object.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES.</head>
<p>Tbe export of Egyptian cigarettes during
tbe past year has greatly increased. In 1903
tbe total export of cigarettes from this oouutry
amounted to 531,199 kilos, of the value of LE.
423,332. During 1904 the amount exported
was 620,476 kilos, ol the value of LB. 494,964,
au increase ou the previous year of 89,277 kilos
aud L.E.71,632. The export to Knglaud last
year amounted to LE. 79,478, as agaiust LB.
78,208 in 1903. The principal figures lor the
other countries were as follows: Germany, LB.
247,236, as agaiust LE. 195,010 iu 1903, Aus-
tria, LE.38,101, as against LE.26,875 in 1903
PranoeLB. 8,797, as against LE. 13,166 in
1903. China and tbe For East, LE. 18,221 aa
against LE. 12,555 in 1903, British Possessions
in the Far East, LK. 57,693 as against LE
65.558 in 1903, Swedeu.LB. 10,743 as against
Ck 11,107 in 1903, Switzerland, LE. 6,891 as
against 6,620 in 1903, Belgium, LE 9,182 as
against 8,115 in 1903.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL
CAIRO.</head>
<p>Open all the year round.</p>
<head>jUEOTRlO LIGHT,-LIFT.- ■ODERATE OHAROEI</head>
<head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
<p>Largest 1st olssa and most oomfortablr
Houl ID Alexandria. Fecbg the M*
l'.ntr») position. Under English management
I14L*04</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>TRADE WITH CYPRUS.	^</head>
<p>Statement or Cnrer Expobtb fbom Larnaca We<
to Boypt, December, 1904.	by
Wh»t kilee	I,,00 Eg*, - Ho. S.M8
Barley	- "	22,647 Iambs’	“f
Bran	-	okes	10,965	moat	-	„	665	en
Potatoes	-	„	49,345	Oxen	-	„	204	ron;
Onions	-	„	24,5:10	8heep	-	„	143	^
Linseed	•	„	19,336	Pigs	-	"	149
Blackseed-	„	430 Goats •	"	34
Almonds •	„	770 Turkeys-	"	339	J*i
Wine	•	„	2,199	Fowls	-	"	1,892
Raisins	-	„	1,014	Mules	-	"	71	t41®
Caroubs -kantars 40 Camels - "	18 ^
Lomons	No.	80,600 Horses .	"	1
Gypsum -	Tons	441} Donkeys-	"	18	A1®</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENT</head>
<p>Tbe EE “Perim," of the Westoott and
I au ranee Line, left Malta yesterday and is j
due here on Sunday with a general oargo from ^
London.
The Ellennan 8iJ. "Avon" sailed henoe yee- p.fc
terday afternoon direct for Liverpool, with
general cargo, including 2,635 bales of ootton. -
The Moss liner “Ramoses" sailed yesterday
morning from Malta and is due boro on 8etor- y r
day afternoon, with passengers, mails, and ^
general cargo.	•	„	.Mr
The 8.S. “Britannia,” of tho Papayanm M •
line, left Liverpool yesterday afternoon and is yr
oxpected to arrivo, with mails and passengers, yf
on or about the 26th inst,	. pol
cotptian lam sunr.</p>
<p>(From our Financial Corxwomddtt.)
London, February 8.
The present week has been characterised by
cheerfulness in oar Stock Markets, owing in a
great measure io the growing belief that Russia
cannot much longer continue the war, and
also to tho hope that the Tsar ia beginning to
Have hjs own way in reierenoe to the reforms.
Ibo Faria and Berlin financiers have been
making the moat of the amelioration- of the
trouble in 8t Petersburg and have hoisted up
the prioe of Russian Four* to over 20 again.
Ot stock* and share* then ia little to report
this week of interest, to your readen. Am far
as the mining section is oonoeroed, business in
South Africans nosms to be at a coesplete
standstill at promt, with a drooping tendency
in price*. Egyptian mining properties, unlike
the other Egyptian companies, are not yet
independent and are still under tbe wing of
the South African Market, and consequently
they suffer wiih Kaffirs when the Utter are
weak. Nile Valley, have dropped to 2.1/lti
at the present moment, a prioe whieb may
tempt speculative investors,, AM forgetting
that the oompany is to a Urge extent in the
hands of	‘^»--r ~r
ly acquired a large and
United Africans at 1.9/16 shoeid be worth
attention. It is evident that the market
anticipate an motive future; for a special book
of referenoe has just been published, “The
Egypt and Sudan Mining Handbook.” Other
Egyptian stocks are steady and hold their
prtoes well generally. Bonk shares are a strong
point, especially National Banks, whioh are in
tmmand at 26 in anticipation of th* dividend.
The market expects a distribution of 15s. per
share. Some aay under, but 15a. is the general
idea. Agricultural* are firm at 10 7/8, other
pnoee are steady with little or no change on
Uie week, except %yptian Markets, whioh
nave fallen bock to 1. All Paris stoeka hare
been wonderfully well supported, especially
Russians, which they manage to keep np to
the level of 90;it ie really wouderinl how little
of this stock oomes out at this prioe, for it
certainly should tempt holders. Japanese stocks
keep strong. Money is cheap and the investment
market is strong, though not an actire ope, and
Consols keep finn at 88}.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>MISS HOESLI’8 CONCERT.</head>
<p>Miss Hoesli’s conoert at the New Khedivial
Total last night was a great success. There
vas a large audience in spite of the bad
veather. The talonted Swiss lady was assisted
>y the distinguished amateurs, Messra. Fos-
jolo, Jaoot des Combes, Weedon, and Ehrlich,
rbe concert began with Handel's well-known
Largo in G Major, sung by Mias Hoesli, assist-
by Mr. Ehrlich at the piano and Mr. Weedon
arith the violin. Mias Hoeali's voioe was
beautifully modulated to suit this diffioult
piece. It was much applauded by a critical
sudieuoe. M. Fasoolo followed with a violin
duet by Sinving, in whioh be was assisted
by a friend, whose name was not on the
programme. This intricate pieoe was executed
with marvellous facility. Tbe sooompaniment
wss cleverly given by Mrs. Foeoolo. Three
romances were next sung by Miss Hoesli, An
Die Nsoht (Bohm), Chant Hindoo (Bembcrg),
and Liebesleier (Weingartner).. The last item
was especially appreciated and was given with
great depth of feeling and perfect harmony.
Beethoven’s Adagio was well given by Messrs.
Weedon, Des Combes, and Bhrlioh, followed
by two solos by Mr. Fusoolo. Sohubert's
L'Abeillo was exoellently played and had to
be given again to satisfy the demands for an
enoore. Mias Hoesli then sang Xavier Le-
ronx's Lo Nil, accompanied by M. Dee
Combes on tbo 'cello and Mr. Ehrlich on the
piano. Tho 'cello adapted itself very well to
Miss Hoesli’s powerful voioe. Tho oonoert,
which closed with three romances sung by Miss
Hoesli, again showed the variety of that lady’s
talents, and the bouquets and applause she
received showed bow muoh her splendid vocal
gifts are appreciated by tho connoisseurs of
Alexandria.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>CAIRO BRAND HAMMAM. £</head>
<p>NsarBbe»hsat*i*W^wtalSMa	^
■ivuev s riw»eai75iwe«TSie •*»£. gel
Xwnwwiw«.l>r.>mniisyis«*rt>*Mali.»s*t pQ</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>VISIT* HtS' LIS IS.</head>
<p>GRAND HOTEL ASSOUAN.
II. Bmil Ghika and fitmily, Roumania; Mrs. W£i
1 Miss Paxton, Mr. and Mrs. Goydon, Rev.
Arthur Jones, Mr. and Mrs. Adoook, Mrs.
,t and Mrs. Pool, Mr. and Mrs. Wood, Miss J
leman, Mr. Alfr. Hudd, Mr. Gerald Wain-
ight, Mr. Kirkpatrike, Mr. G. Graham, —
ss Bellman, Mrs. and Miss Swan, Mr. and DI
■s. Poxcroft and family, Mr. and Mrs.
□ldery and family, Mjs« Biworth, Mr. and
■a. Bond, Bngland; Mrs. and Miss Wild, Mr. g j
i Mrs. Clausen, Misses Harrell and Ross,
r. and Mrs. John Wood, U&A.; Mr. and Be
rs. Signoretti, Cavaliere Pose, Commeodatore
ma, Italy; Mme. Dumeillet, France ; Herr
n Winningen, Dr. Herr von Lang MQnchen, q
mt Hahrath MUuehen, Herr Poensgen and O;
nily, Herr Franz Kohn, Herr and Fran
hlesinger, Messrs. Alfr. and David KappeL ]
srr von Ueehtrit*. Herr Wehmann, Herr
othe, Geheimer Modicinalrath von Kiln- L,
lhaffsr, Mrs. von Klingelhkffer, Mr. aod Mrs. rf
jhhnano, Mr. tad IteWiMartW, Q*bmj, *</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>PASSENGERS' LISTS.
DRPARTURRS.</head>
<p>Per SB. “Schleswig,” sailed yesterday from
Alexandria for Naples and Marseilles:—
lady Grace lavison Gower, Mr. and Mrs.
Oppenheim, Mr. A. Le Bran, Mr. Frank de la
Lome, Mr. von dor Planitx, Mr. von Watadorf,
Mr. and Mrs. Calame, Mr. Hyde Kennard,
Mr. Max Trinkaoa, Mrs. GertrudeScheele, Mrs.
Yale, Miss Thompson, Mr. and Mrs. Dupee,
Mr. and Mrs. Beckham, Mrs. and Miss Col-
thorp, Mr. and Mrs. G. H. Umpeon, Mr. and
Mrs. Wheatley, Mrs. Goebel, Mr. Turner, Mr.
and Mrs. H. 8. Bond, Mrs. W. H. King, Mrs.
J. L Johnson, the Misses Baker, Air. EL Mack-
intoeh, Mr. Robertson, Mr. and Bin. and
Miss Heydebrand, Herr von Herder, Bln. and
Miss Hurst, Miss von Watzdorf; Frau Ober-
loutnant von Planitz, Mr. J. Birkenrutb, Mr.
Fierro Verazzi, Mr. Bigeler, Mr. H«ll| Hadid,
Earl and Lady Potter (tic), Mrs. Lemge, Mr.
Mr. Ht V. Hawknes, Rev. A. E Conolly, Rev.
Gray, Mr. H. 8. Saoeville, Mr. Rom.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>
<p>ALEXANDRIA.
February.
Thun. 9 Zizinia Theatre. French Comedy
Company in Let AJairtt toni let
Affaire*. 9 pjn.
Abbas Helmy Theatre. Italian
Opera Company in I Purilahi.
9.15 p.m.
Pri. 10 Aldorson’s Garden. Variety En-
tertainment 4 p.m.
Res-el-Tin groands-Foothall.School
r. Mr. 8trange’s XL 8.90 p.m.
Zizinia Theatre. Lt Monde on ton
t'ennuie, in rid of Orwael Woaka.
9 p.m.
CAIRO.
burs. 9 KheBMal Opera House. Italian
Opera Company in Fedora.9 p.m.
Verdi Theatre. Italian Operetta
Company. 9 pLm.
Theatre dee NonveauUs. Variety
Entertainment 9.30 p.m.
Trocadero. Variety Entertainment
9.80 p-m.
Ghezirob Palace Hotel. SmaU
Dance 10 p.m.
nglo-American Nila Steamer,
6c HOTRL COMPANY.
ER TRAKPORT Of 00 OM invill AUUIORU A CAIRO
Three Sailing* ■•Week.
UCMWaA MMO WAIP—IM. tM.
10 MM</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ECK and GO’S PILSENER BEER
BREMEN.</head>
<p>fun io HontT comrirnua wb cuautt.
B.—Inferior Brandi now bsfog Ofltrei to K»
sgwr of certain Rood eareUs.</p>
<head>AVOYHOTEL LUXOR</head>
<p>Best and most oocnfortable, unique for its
Mition on Nile bank. Under German Manage
ont Moderate charges. Patronised by officer
Amy of Oowpetion. Conoaris twice deQy,</p> </div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
