<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-03"></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-19"></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, MAY 19, 1905.</head>
<head>lOCAL AND GENERAL,</head>
NUNGOVICH IIOTEI'S CO.
THE ARABIAN TROUBLES.
THE SUEZ CANAL SHARES.
KHEDIVIAL AGRICULTURAL
SOCIETY.
The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O.,
Alexandria, at1A p.ui. on Sunday.
Quarantine restrictions as against plague
arc applied in Egyptian porta to arrivals from
Leith.
Stray and Ownerless Doos found in
llelounn during the night of Saturday and at.
dawn on Sunday will be poisoned by the
police.
Alhambra Theatre.—Ali Haba, or The
J'nrty THerts, is to be produced at the
Alhambra this evening by the Magnani Italian
operetta company.
The Slave Trade. — A Bedouin, of the
Alatdeh tribe, has been sentenced to five
years’ imprirenmont with bard labour for hav-
ing tried to kidnap a Sudanese girl at Deraw
and fell her into slavery.
,'ukz Canal.—12 vessels passed through
the Cunulonthe 16th inst,, of which 8 were
British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 1 French. The
receipts for the day were fre. 379,057.03,
making the total from the 1st inst. frs.
5,011,268.30.
Dante Aliouikri Soc.ety.—The Alexandria
branch of the Dante Alighieri Society will open
an exhibition of work executed during the past
year in the schools belonging to the society.
The exhibition will be held in the Italian
evening rehods and will be open until
Wednesday next.
Alexandria Stockbrokers’ Association.— j
The meeting of tho association, which was to
have been held yesterday afternoon, has been
postponed for want of a quorum until Monday
next, when the new committee will be
i lected and a decision arrived at as to tho
ndmifsicn of tbo Egyptian Estates Limited,
to the official list.
Hutchinson Nursinq Home.—As will be
seen by an advertisement in another part of
our issue of to-day, the Hutchinson Nursing
Homo in Cairo is now open and ready for
the reception of patients. If only Mrs. Hut-
chinson bad founded her beautiful institution
in Alexandria, it would have filled tho want
which seems to be felt for such an institution
in this city.
Sale ok Palace.—The fine old. palace of
Prince Mo In mod Aly, brother of H.H. the
Khedive, which is situated at the Rond Point,
Kasr-el-Nil, Cairo, has, we understand, been
purchased by the Egyptian Improvements
Corporation from a load syndicate, the first
purchasers of this estate. Ou-his return from
Europe Prince Mohamed Aly will reside at
tho splendid mansion which ho has recently
had built on Rodah Island.
Alexandria Banks.—An American tourist
in Egypt, writing to the ‘'Republican” of
Meadville, Pa, U.S.A. remarks anent his
Alexandria impressions : — In Alexandria the
banks and about all the stores close between
noon and 3 p.m.,then reopen and continue the
day's business. Tho banks are quite large, but
have very antiquated ways of doing business,
and are very slow. I think they would drop
dead to see a hank run on the plan of ours in
the United States.
<head>MEETING OF SHAREHOLDERS.</head>
An extraordinary general meeting of the
George Nungovich Hotels Company was
hold last evening in tho Grand Continental
Hotel, Cairo. The board of directors was given
power by a unanimous vote to create aud
issue new shares to the amount of £50,000,
guaranteed by a mortgngo to bo raised on the
Continental and Helonan Hotels. This sum is
to bo devoted to tho enlargement of tho Savoy
Hotel and alterations to tho Continental
Hotel, an account of which was given in our
i-sue of the 17th inst
The meeting ratified the authorisation given
to Nungovich Boy by the board to sit on the
board of the Uppor Egypt Hotels Company.
M. Bonligny contested the validity of the
vote, but it was carried.
A dividend of 10s. was agreed upon by the
meering, and the board of directors was re-
elected.
<head>EGYPTIAN HOTELS COMPANY</head>
Tho Egyptian 'Hotels' Company, Limited,
has gained a groat impetus owing to the
ohange in the ownership of the majority of
the shares, which, as our readers are aware,
passed last year from the hands of the Grand
Hotel Company to those of Mr. Charles
Baehler. The excellent result of this season’s
working will allow of a substantial dividend
being declared. The company have offers for
their ground at Ghezireh, which, if accepted,
will amply cover the entire debenture capital.
The remaining capital will therefore in an
average year yield dividends that very few
companies will be able to compare with.
The Ghezireh Palace estate has developed
so greatly that it is now the most fashionable
suburb in Cairo. The Ghezireh Palace Hotel
itself has made a record season, and has quite
outgrown its old reputation as a drag on Shop
heard’s Hotel, for with tho advance of fashion-
able Cairo towards tho west, this hotel will
soon be in the centre of a very fashionable
residential suburb, .and is therefore becoming
year by year more patronised.
We understand that at Shepheard’s Hotel
great improvements are to be made, especially
in regard to the immediate neighbourhood.
The shops, for example, iu Kamel-street, on
the property of the hotel, are all to be modern-
ised. The frontage o.‘ the Shephc-ird’s Hotel
property towards Halim Pasha-street is to be
built upon and a line of fashionable shojis is
to be constructed there. Another line of shops
is to be built in tho other frontage, facing the
new estate of the Socidtd Beige Egyptienne,
which is the direct road to and from the
station. By these additions the revenue from
the Shepheard's Hotel property will be tre-
bled. The prospects of tbe company are thns
bright in the extreme, and under the manage
ment of Mr. Baehler the investor may consider
that his capital will be safely and remunera-
tively employed.
<head>ANGLO-AMERICAN COMPANY.</head>
A meeting of the board of directors of the
Anglo-American Nile Steamer and Hotel Com-
pany, Limited, was held on Wednesday after-
noon at Cairo. It was practically decided to
declare a dividend of 8 per cent, on the year’s
working. Although the profits have been
very largo this season, and a considerably
bigger dividend could bavo been declared, and
a substantial bonus allotted to the share-
holders, the directors bavo very wisely decided
instead to place a large sum to tho reserve
fund of the company. Tho financial position
of the company is excellent, and tho prospects
for the coming year are very propitious.
<head>PUMAKKABLE ASSERTIONS.</head>'
Berlin, May 11.
The pr gr..-H of tho revolt in tho Yemen is
being followed with keen attention in Germany,
where the conviction is now publicly proclaim-
ed that Great Britain is spinning a vast web
of intrigue against the authority of the Sultan.
Professor Schumann, the friend and travel-
ling companion of tho Emperor, identifies him
self in tho “Kroux Zeitung" with the connection
put forward by Dr. Ular in the "Revues des
Ilevues,” that Groat Britain is endeavouring to
foment a movement having .for its object the
transfer-reo of the Kbalifate from the Snltan
to tho Khedive. He quotes with approval the
supgp.lin i th it Ben Said, as well as the Emir
of Kuweit, whose object is defined as the
establishment of on independent Empire in
Central Arabia, are puppets of Great Britain,
and adduces the authority of Mustapha
Kamel Pasha in support of the assertion that
Great Britain will never succeed in "realising
th? Napoleonic dream of laying hands on the
Khalifate,and thus acquiring a moral dominion
over the entire Mussulman world.”
According to MnstaphaKamel Pasha, who is
described as an Egyptian patriot, the removal
of tho supremo religious authority from Con-
stantino; le would inevitably lead to the de-
molition ol Islam, to which the Khedive would
in no cir: mmti' ces give his consent. All
Mussulmans are aware of this, and they are
becoming embittered even to the pitch of
fanaticism against the Arab rebels against the
Porte.	v-,
Profeser Schiomannrpenta to the magni-
tude of ihe efforts which Turkey is making to
recover her authority in the Yemen, and
wains E-gland that if she promotes an in-
surrectionary movement her action, taken in
conjunction with French policy in Morocco,
will provoke a Pan-Ldamitic rising against
European influence, which would gravely affect
the condition of Tunis, Egypt, and India.
The riot mil significance of Professor Schie-
manii’s curious admonitions, which wore pub-
lished yesterday, is reudered apparent to-day
by a j umber of Press articles, in which
expressi. n is givon to the fear that Great
Britain is oi couraging Arabian ambitions in
order that she may proclaim a protectorate
over Koweit and Baesorah, “the terminus of
the Bagdad Railway.” It is farther pointed out
that a Ci ntrol Arabian Empire would directly
menace that railway, which, by-the-way, has
not yet ' e p constructed.
The "National ZeitUDg,”in an elaborate lead-
ing artiolo,depicts the entire situation as being
governed by '‘the antagonism between Lord
Kitcbei er and Lord Curzon.” Lord Kitchener,
it says, is convinced that the centre of gravity
of Indian do'bnce is in Afghanistan, where the
Russian monaco is constantly prescut, whereas
Lord Cuizon’s view, which accords with the
view hold by the authorities in London, is
that it is urgently necessary to counter Russia
in Persia. Lord Curzon, concludes the "National
Zeitnng,” evidently regards the moment ns
opportune for effecting a grand coup in the
Persian Gulf, and "it is in this connection that
the real significance of British policy in the
Yemen must be sought. Lord Kitchener, on
the other band, fears that any action in the
Persian Gulf will induce a counter-move on
the part of Russia again the land frontiers of
India. Ho is not ignorant of the meaning of
tho concentration of Russian troops near
Afghanistan, and he probably knows better
than Lord Curzon the actual state of British
defences.”
In other words, the semi-official Pre»s of
Berlin deems it necessary to fabricate Russian
and Pan-Islamitic scarecrows in order to protect
the future interest of Germany in Central Asia
against imaginary British designs.
<head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
V ’• da not hoM oomlre* rmpouiblo for the opinion* oxpre*»«J
by onr corrc*poo Jenu, bat we wish, In a epirit of tail pUy
to nil, to permit — within corpus nccoujvry limit*— free
COTTAGE HOSPITAL OR NURSING
HOME.
To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir,—I read with pleasure your article on
the above question yesterday, and I hope it
may lead to good results. I am aware that this
subject was discussed at various meetings
about two years ago and that the suggestion
was finally dropped. Those, however, who were
in favor of the bchemo were not, I think, at
all convinced that their theory was wrong.
There can be no doubt that the want of a
nursing home or cottage hospital is felt by
many. At the present moment there are three
Englishmen at the Government Hospital, who
would undoubtedly have gone to a nursing
Lome, had it existed. I am sure that we all
recognise the excellent work done by the
(i.rman Hospital at Moharrem Bey, but the
fact remains, as you pointed out, that we like
to be nursed by English nurses, and this unfor-
tunately is against the rules of this excellent
institution. I think a nursing home would be
a better scheme than a cottage hospital, and
one rule I would suggest is that the patient
should be allowed whatever medical attendant
lie or she wished. The home could be started
on u email scale.—I am, etc.,
X.
Alexandria, May 19.
<head>THE MENZALEII COMPANY.</head>
The Menzaleh Company is proceeding
steadily with its development work, and half
the cnbie distance to be dredged between
Mat&rieh and Port Said has been finished. The
Anglo-American Nile Steamer and Hotel
Company is getting on rapidly with the work
of constructing the company’s fleet
<head>ANOTHER NEW COMPANY.</head>
Another new company is shortly to be
launched in London and Egypt. It is a very
big industrial concern and will have a capital
of one million sterling. It has been entirely
underwritten.
<head>DEATH OFMR.CHAULESCAMMELL.</head>
The sudden death, while cruising in the Me-
diterranean, has been reported of Mr. Charles
Cammell, late of Messrs. Charles Cammell
& Co., the well-known steel and armour-plate
manufactures, of Sheffield. As contractors
for stool rails to the Egyptian Government, Mr.
CammoH's name was known throughout Egypt.
His firm, which is now carried on under Hie
style of Cammell, Laird & Co., Limited, have
built and equipped several firstclasa battleships
for the British Navy. By his decease, a vacancy
has been created on the board of the Egyp-
tian Trust and Investment, Limited, of which
Mr. Cammell was a director. His loss is
deeply deplored by his late colleagues, both in
Egypt and London.
<head>EGYPT AT THE ORIENTAL CONGRESS.</head>
The International Congress of Orientalists,
which mot recently at Algiers, discussed many
matters of considerable interest to Egypt, and
the papers of Prof. Mahler, ‘Die Sothis and
Monddaten der alten Aegypter,’ Baron Carra
de Vaux, ‘Etymologic du mot Pyramide,’ Prof.
Wiedemann, ‘LeCulto desAnimanx en Egypt?,'
were very good. A number of tho papers in tho
Islamic section bore reference to the local fea-
tures of Mohamcdanism in Egypt, while others
dealt with tho Islamic system of education and
the system now applied in Egypt, tho classifica-
tion of tho Arabic sciences, etc. A wido interest
attaches to a proposal by Sheikh Mohamed
Asal to seek primarily in Arabic itself for
the mean3 of representing modern ideas. No
Jehad was preached, however, although an
attempt on the part of Dr. Vollers to demon-
strate tho presonco of vulgarisms in the Koran
met with lively protests.
The lecture of M. Ronanet on ^rabic mnsio
was a very finit-hed exposition, based upon the
lecturer’s own researches in tho literature and
tho living tradition. He instituted an elabor-
ate parallel between the development of the
musical art and that of the architecture and
general civilisation of the Islam io world. In
general ho ascribed to the Arabio music a
more mystic and less intellectual character
("mixophrygian”) than that of the Europeans.
NAVAL NOTES.
BECK & CD’S PILSENLR BEER
Obtainable from avarjr Raagastabla Firm
In Cax*o, / lixamjsu A tb* Bblax.
othc*t£it* l*
L J. HILClIT, f. MOUIF to).
'•	u,3n t' ni.iUMIZM*
<head>ALDERSON’S CARDEN, BULKELEY.BMPIHK DAY.</head>
Bj kind p«ncie*Ion of tho <-'olonol «M Officer, tho Roy»l
Berk* Bond will pl»y from «toSp.ni.
The British firstclass battleships "Canopus”
(Capt. F. W. Fisher) and "Goliath” (Cspt. H.
C. Kingsford) left Portsmouth together on the
11th inst. for tho China station, there to relieve
the "Centurion” (Capt. Pegen) and "Ocean”
(Capt. Greet), They are expected at Port Said
on the 94th inst, and are to stay there proba-
bly «couple of 4*y*i
MR. GREENWOOD’S REJOINDER.
Mr. P. Greenwood writes as follows to tho
editor of the "Times”
Sir,—I hope it is possible to be sorry for
having said a certain something in a recent
speech of mine at tho Trocadero Restaurant
and yet be nnablo to admit that it can be
charged with culpability. The speech was about
the purchase of tho Khedive's Suez Canal
shares in 1875, when Sir Edward Stanton was
Consul-General at Cairo ; and among other
things I said that Lord Derby, annoyed at the
want of information from the Consulate on
that matter, exclaimed, "Master Stanton shall
hear of this !” and then came the words, "and
Master Stanton did hoar of it. He was quietly
removed from his post, and went into retire-
ment, I believe, to some Consulship on the
Black Sea." Thereupon Sir Edward Stanton
wrote mo a letter of complaint and explanation
which I immediately communicated to the
"Times.” (His sou, Colonel Stanton, now tells
your readers that I "quoted part of the letter
but omitted to insert the whole of it.” Here-
with I enclose tho original, from which you will
see that I did soud to the "TimeB” every word
of explanation and complaint which the letter
contains.) At tho same time I had to confess
that “retirement” is not the right word for the
removal of a Government official from one post
to another, and that I spoke from uncertain
recolleotion—as the words “I believe" indicat-
ed—in saying that Sir Edward Stanton was
transferred to some post on the Black Sea.
Sir Edward Stanton’s statement of the case
was this :—
"I have, of course, no knowledge as to what
may have passed between Lord Derby and
yourself. But I beg leave to state that your
reference os to my removal, &e., is absolutely
untrue. The negotiations with the Khedive
for the purchase of the Canal shares were car-
ried out entirely by myself ; and I remained at
my post till 1876, when I gladly accepted the
promotion to tho post of Chargd d’Affaires in
Bavaria, having previously declined the offer
of the Legation of Chile, offered me by Lord
Derby."
In transcribing this statement for the “Times”
I made no objection to any part of it, nor did
I offer any remark upon it And I would
gladly say no more now, except that I am truly
sorry for having dropped a sentence which
a moment’s reflection would have told me must
give pain. Now, however, I am put in this
position by the publication in the "Times” of a
letter from Sir Edward Stanton’s son:—Either
I must teem to admit by silence that Sir
Edward’s statement contradicts me and that I
have been culpably wrong, or else 1 mast place
that statement under the light of certain facts
which Sir Edward himself asserts. There is no
other choice, and I cannot be blamed, 1 think,
for not choosing silence.
That Lord Derby had reason for dissatis-
faction is expressly admitted. For the rest,
Sir Edward’s own statement is that, whereas
the affair of tho Caual shares happened near
the close of 1875 (middle of November in
that year), he left Egypt in 1876, and that in
this year he was first offered the Legation of
Chile, which he declined, and then gladly
accepted the post of Charge d’Affaires in
Bavaria. But what then ! 1875...1876, Egypt,
Chile thirty years ago, and Munich after the
confederation of the German Empire. Would it
be unfair to say that, so far, there is more
confirmation than contradiction 1
Now, however, Colonel Stanton adds a
particular which Sir Edward did not mention.
He says that his father, “for purely private
reasons, and on tho score of health, asked for
a chaugo," and then was offered Chile. There
is no resisting that statement and there can
be no wish to do so. But without it, and
under any circumstances, I should' still regret
the heedlessness which, as I well understand,
must have troubled Sir Edward Stanton with-
out need.
<head>FAYOUM BRIGANDAGE CASE.</head>
Major Elgood is still conducting an enquiry
into the case of the attack on the house of
Suliman Said at Biabmo in theFayoum.
It will bo remembered that Furag, a
Sudanese, and others when arrested accused
Abbas el Zumr of being the ringleader of the
party, and of having made off with the spoil,
but we understand that the latest reports to
hand state that this man was not even in
Biabmo on the night when the attack took
place, so that although ho may have been an
instigator, he was not at any rate a participator
in the crime.
We hope to be able to publish a full account
on the completion of tho inquiry.
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
The Khedive proceeded to Rns-ol-Tiu Palace
this morning and attended Friday prayers at
the Moiqne of El Abbassy.
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
The Ellerman S 3. “Alexandria” arrived at
Liverpool on Thursday morning.
The Khedivial Mail S,S. "Prince Abhas’’wiU
leave Alexandria on Wednesday for Rhodes,
Pirmus, Smyrna, Mitylouo and Constantinople.
The S.8. "Carib Prince,” from Manchester,
left Malta on Thursday and is duo here on
Monday with passengers and general cargo.
The S.S. "Royal Princo" left Manchester on
Thursday with passengers and general cargo
for Malta and Alexandria
<head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
Large 1st cIsm and no«t comfortable
Hotel it	Feeing the tee
Central prsitlui. I ndtr English management
(From our Correspondent).
Damanhonr, Thursday.
The first provincial meeting of the K.A.S.
was held hero last Monday under the presi-
dency of the Moudir of the Behora The meeting
was largely attended. The Irrigation Inspector,
the Chief Engineer, the sanitary Inspector o
the Moudirieb, and many notables wenT
present.
Mohamed Bey El Wakil suggested that an
■‘Agricultural Review,” dealing with trees and
flowers, the method and periods of their cul-
tivation, etc., should bo published periodically
and distributed among agriculturists. He stat-
ed that the absence of such a review kept
gardening in a backward state in Egypt.
Ismail Boy Dabus suggested that the society
should distribute rewards among persons who
took pains in cleaning their cotton crop, so as
to encourage others to follow their example.
He also suggested that the Miuistry of the
Interior should issue a circular to the omdehs
informing them that a deputation of the
K.A.S. would go round the provinces to
examine the cotton plantations, and that in
satisfactory cases the board would instruct
the banks who purchase the cotton to sell to
the society the cotton s-icd from the cotton
purchased. Iu this way, ho stated, the society
would possess a store of cotton seed from
different provinces.
There were many other proposals of a minor
character.
<head>EXCAVATIONS AT THEBES.</head>
Professor Naville and Mr. H. R. Hall have
been excavating at the eleventh dynasty tem-
ple at Dfir-el-Bahari at Thebes this winter for
the Egyptian Exploration Fond and some im-
portant discoveries have resulted. The site of
their work was the space left untouched dur-
ing Prof. Naville’s excavation of the well-
known temple of Queen Hatshepsut. The ro-
sult of ;heir labours is tho discovery of the
funerary temple of tho eleventh dynasty king
Montnhotep III. (Noblnpet-Ra), containing
the graves of priestesses of the goddess Hathor,
a divinity specially worshipped at D6r el Bahari.
The existence of eleventh-dynasty buildings
here had long been suspected, but not hitherto
discovered. The temple was reached in the
course of the first season’s work, 1903 4, and
the great court and the northern colonnade
cleared, and some fine reliefs were discovered.
In the past season, 19L4-5, the temple was
approached from the south, and the central
pyramid and shrines of the priestesses of Ha-
thor were cleared. In the course of the digging
some fine portrait-statues of the twelfth-dy-
nasty king Usertsen III. were unearthed, as
well as many small objects, such as workmen’s
tools, left during tho repairs to the temple,
which seem to have been effeoted during the
reign of Siptah, of whom a relief was found on
the facing of the pyramid. The temple is of
importance as being the most perfect known
temple-building of this early period, and the
mo3t ancient building at Thebes. Architectur-
ally it is interesting, as it stands on an arti-
ficially squared platform of rock, approached
by a sloping ramp, flanked by colonnades
which led up to a granite doorway, beyond
which was a sort of ambulatory of proto-Doric
columns surrounding a square central erection
apparently the bare of a pyramid. At the back
of this are finely decorated shrines oft he priest-
esses of Hathor. What lies beyond remains
yet to be explored. About two-thirds of the
work is completed, and it is expected that tho
excavation of the remainder of the si*e will
reveal the existence of the king’s own shrine,
which, if well preserved 1, will be a most remark-
able relio of Egyptian antiquity.
<head>GERMAN MISSION IN CAIRO.</head>
Dr. Rucker Joni6ch, German Diplomatic
Agent and Consul-General in Cairo, gave &
banqnet on Wednesday evening in honor of
Dr. Rosen, head of the German mission to
Abyssinia. Marquis Salvago-Raggi, Italian
Diplomatic Agent, and seven members of the
mission were also among the guests.
Dr. Rosen leaves for Berlin in a day or two.
<head>CAIRO-ALEXANDRIA TELEPHONE.</head>
The Arabic-speaking population of Cairo and
Alexandria have not yet woke up to the ad-
vantages of telephone communication between
the two cities. This is obvious from the
statistics of the telegrams for last year. The
number of messages sent over the Egyptian
lines was, in round figures, 1,825 000, an in-
crease of 179,000 over 1903. Of this increase,
176.000	was in Arabio telegrams, and only
3.000	in European telegrams. The European
traffic was adversely affected by the com-
petition of the C riro-Alexandria telephone.
Thesame cause also led to a diminution of 13$
per cent, in the number of "urgent" (triple-
tax) telegrams sent over the line-1. The tele-
jihonio communication between Cairo and
Alexandria brought in to tho Government a
revenue of L.E. 8,423 in 1904, Of this sum,
I/.E. 1.P60 represents the rent paid by the
Telephone Company for the two circuits leased
to them, The balance of L.E 2,078 waR earned
by the two circuits worked by tho Telegraph
Department between the Bourses of Cairo and
Alexandria. This latter sum represents 41,460
calls of three minutes’ conversation.
<head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
Eulkeley, Bamleb.
-wto. Vldlcr* from Uklro il'jhl t! SUI 0*Ur Sullen.
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, President of the
Council of Ministers,and Fakhry Pasha arrived
at Sau Stefaoo yesterday ever.i.-g from Cairo.
Sir William Willcocks will leave for the
Continent on the 24th ol this month and will
return to Cairo early in October.
Lewa Hunter Pasha, Director-General of the
Coast Gnard Administration, and Mrs. Hunter
arrived at Alexandria from Cairo last night
and are proceeding shortly to Europe. Hunter
Pasha’s state of health leaves much to be
desired.
Adly Pasha Yeghen, Governor of Cairo, will
leave for Europe on June 15 and will return
to Cairo on September 14.
Mr. Mcllwraith, Judicial Adviser, leaves (or
England on leave on the 1st Juno.
Boghos Pasha Nnbar and Mr. G. P. Foaden
will leave Egypt to-morrow to represent Egypt
at the Agricultural Congress at Rome.
Abdul Hamid Bey Abaza has been appointed
to aot as secretary, of the Khedivial Agricul-
tural Society during Mr. Foaden’s absence in
Rome.
We are glad to be able to state that Mrs,
Norman-Lee, wife of the Senior Chaplain to
the Forces in Egypt, is progressing favorably
and is now oat of danger. Mrs. Norman-Lee
has already been a month at the Deaconesses’
Hospital at Alexandria, suffering from enterio
fever. She will be taken to England as soon as
she is fit to be moved.
Major G.B. Stanistreet, R.A.M.C., and Rev.
Sidney Smith, B.A., C.F., have been granted
leave of absence.
The marriage of Miss Myrrha Ismalun to
Mr. Albert Cattaoui will take place on Tues-
day next.
The marriage of Mile Celine Piha, daughter
of M. and Mme Elie A. Piha Bey, to Mr. Clande
J. Rolo will take place at the residence of Mr.
Jacques Rolo, 5, the de Corinthe, on Tuesday,
23rd inBt., at 5 p.m.
<head>SPORT AND PLAY</head>.
ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.
An error occurred in tho list of handicaps
for the Khedivial Club Cup which was publish-
ed in our issue of the 15th inst. Moharrem
Pasha Chehin’s Mabronk will carry 12.7 and
not 10.7, as announced.
ALEXANDRIA CRICKET CLUB.
Negotiations are proceeding with a view
to getting up a match between Alexandria
and a Cairo XL, on Friday next, the 26th
inst If the match comes off it will be held
at Alexandria and will come conveniently
between the two race days of the Secoud
Summer Meeting of the A. 8. C.
Members are informed that the squash
racquet courts will be ready for play on
Monday next, 22nd inst. The subscription for
this year has been fixed by the oommittoo.at
P.T. 60, that for next year at P.T. 75. Mem-
bers wishing to make use of the courts are
requested to rend in - their names to the
secretary, Mr. Macaulay, Rue Amin Pasha
Fikry, together with the above-mentioned
sum of P.T. 6 \ Any member not paying
this yearly subscription may play on the
courts, on payment of P.T. 5 per diem to
the ground man. Racquets at P.T. 45 each
and balls at P.T. 3 each are to be had from
the secretary.
<head>PASSENGER LISTS DEPARTURES.</head>
Per S.S. "Seti” sailed from Alexandria yes-
terday for Liverpool, viil Malta:—
Mr. J. Armstead, Miss Crankshaw, Mrs.
Bewley’s three children, Mr. C. E. Carter, Miss
D. R. Collins, Miss Coruwel}, Miss Densham,
Mr. A. Dimook. Mr. T. Eastwood, Mr. J. Firth,
Miss Firth, Mr. R. M. Qentilli, Mrs. Hopkin-
son, Mr. W. Littlowood’s two children, Miss
Magrath, Mr. J. Myring, Mr. J. Hioks Pauli,
Mrs. Pringle and child, Mr. G. Taploy Smith,
Miss H. Spence, Mr. J. Templeton, Mr. W.
Trapp, Mias Wynhall, Mr. Saunders and two
children, Mr. and Mrs. J. Redding and 5
ohildren, Mra,Willmore'e'2 maids, Mr. J. Arbib,
Rev. Sherry, Mrs. Bewley’s nurse, Mr. and
Mrs. T. LaidJaw, Mr. C. J. Bridgewater, Mr.
Tewma, and 15 deck passengers.
Le paqnebot “Tobe” de la Cie Florio
Rubattino parti hier pour Gflnea avait k bord:—
M. et Mmo d’Asprea, Cav. C. Pini, Cap. R.
De Vita, G. Tamvace, M. ot Mmo A. Sosehino,
Mmo de Rauiori ot fils, G. Calzotti, A. Ba-
glioni, A. De Belinsky, Cav. A. Gugliehno,
fam. Gcofroi, Mmo Querri, F. Qaerri, Dom.
Rossi, A. Nourrison Boy et fam., Frit* Eglin,
Mme Re, Mme C. Lanxone, Bigg, Delaquis et
fam., Umb. Bollo, E. Bajoccbi, Icon Querry,
L. Bonenfant, 8t Giglio, A. Rabolini, M. et
Mme Depuis, G. Belleli et fam., Butler et fiU,
Th, PepexUehi, Yowwf Bey Chiba, </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
