<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Cassandra Frederick</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-17">October 17, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-08">May 08, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7192] ALEXANDRIA, MONDAY, MAY 08, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WORLD-WIDE MANOEUVRES. CAUSE OF POSTPONEMENT.</head>
                    <p>Melbourne, May 6. World-wide manoeuvres have been postponed. The “Cadmus" has
                        been ordered to join the “Clio" on the China station. Both these cruisers
                        are generally attached to the Austra- lian squadron. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p> London, April 6. The countermanding of the naval manaoeuvres is evoking
                        speculation of every description, but it is generally understood that the
                        decision is due to the continuance of the war and the apprehension of
                        causing a delicate situation by grand manoeuvres while tire Russian and
                        Japa- nese fleets are at sea. Moreover it would be inconvenient to deplete
                        the China squadron at the present moment. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN LOSSES IN OFFICERS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 6. The Tsar, in addressing 1,150 cadets, who were
                        promoted officers at Tsarskoe-Selo, men- tioned that he promoted them four
                        months earlier than usual owing to heavy losses of officers in Manchuria.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 6. The Tsar has made 1,500 cadets officers before the
                        proper time, owing to losses in Manchuria. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>YEMEN INSURRECTION.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, May 7. Sixteen Redif battalions, belonging to the First Army
                        Corps, have been called to the colours for service in the Yemen.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCO-ITALIAN DEMONSTRATION</head>
                    <p>Rome, May 6. The unveiling of Victor Hugo’s statue was imposing, and ended in
                        a warm Franco Italian demonstration. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUEEN ALEXANDRA IN ATHENS.</head>
                    <p>Athens, May 7. Queen Alexandra was greatly cheered at the Pan Hellenic games,
                        at which 50,000 specta- tors were present (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BIG PRICE FOR RACEHORSE,</head>
                    <p>London, May 6. Roberts Bass, the owner of "Sceptre,” has bought the stallion
                        “Cyllene" for 30,000 guineas. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                    <p>London, May 6. Yorkshire beat Somerset by an innings and 224 runs. Snrrey
                        beat Essex by 135 runs. England v. Australians drawn. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>The Plague— A fresh case of plague is reported from Toukh today.</p>
                    <p>Asile Rudolph— Mr. Rudolph gratefully thanks the ladies of the Rudolph Asile
                        Guild on behalf of the poor who received clothing on Saturday, April 29.</p>
                    <p>“Mohamed. The Rise of Islam” by Pro- fessor D. S. Margoliouth will be one of
                        the new volumes in Messrs. Putnam’s “Heroes of the Nations!' series.</p>
                    <p>White Slave Traffic.-The first meeting of the Executive Bureau of the White
                        Slave Traffic Repression Committee will be held at the Alexandria
                        Gouvernment this afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Children's Ball — The annual children’s ball given by Prof. Conegliaco with
                        the assist- ance of his pupils will take place at the Alhambra next Saturday
                        afternoon at 3.30 o’clock.</p>
                    <p>Slavery Case.—A court martial will meet in the next few days to pronounce
                        judgment on Gameh Abou Said, an Ababdeh, who recently abducted a Sudanese
                        girl and tried to sell her at Om Rassin, Assonan Moudirieh.</p>
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Boulac quarter during tonight, and
                        tomorrow at dawn, and in the Saida Zeynab quarter during tomorrow night and
                        dawn on Wednesday, will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    <p>The Museum Catalogue.- The catalogue of the Cairo Museum will not be
                        completed before ten years. Eighteen volumes have already been published,
                        seven others are in the press, and eight more are under preparation.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—19 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th inst, 14 of which
                        were British, 1 French, 2 German, 1 Turkish, 1 Dutch. The day's receipts
                        were frs. 533,311.78 making the total from the 1st inst. frs-
                        1,479,251.79.</p>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <p>S. &S.F.A—-The annual meeting of the Soldiers and Sailors Families’
                        Association will take place at the General’s House, Moharrem Bey, at 4.30
                        p.m. ou Thursday, 18th inst. All who are interested in the above association
                        are invited to attend.</p>
                    <p>Fatal Collapse of House.—A house belonging to Sheikh Ahmed El Diwani in the
                        Haret el Geladine, Waili Kism, Cairo, collapsed on Friday. The sheikh's
                        daughter, Mme. Zohra, was killed by the falling ruins. Her body has been
                        recovered.</p>
                    <p>Splendid Hotels of Egypt.—The capital for the Splendid Hotels of Egypt
                        Company, Limited, was covered forty-six times over. The mathematically
                        equitable manner in which the shares have been allotted, as shown in the
                        notice we published in our issue of Friday last, has given general
                        satisfaction.</p>
                    <p>Italian School at Port Said.—The Mar- quis di Salvago-Raggi is expected to
                        return to Cairo to-day or to-morrow from Port Said. The Italian Minister has
                        been the guest of Count de Serionne and is said to be making arrangements
                        for the purchase of a site for an Italian school at Port Said.</p>
                    <p>St. Georoe's Day. O. S.—A service in honor of the nameday of H.M. King George
                        of Greece was celebrated at St. George's Church, Old Cairo, on Saturday
                        morning. M. Gennadis, with the staff of the Greek Agency and Consulate, and
                        many well-known Greek residents, were present at the ceremony.</p>
                    <p>Alhambra Theatre—The operatic compa- ny at the Alhambra Theatre is attracting
                        good audiences. Yesterday’s matinee was crowded on the occasion of a
                        repetition, of Primacera Scapigliata, when Signa Imbunbo came in for the
                        usual ovations which that talented actress always receives. In the evening
                        the Venditore di Uccelli was given. To-night In cerca di felicita will be
                        given.</p>
                    <p>LadyGorst’s Portrait. The portrait of the wife of the late Financial Adviser
                        by Professor Herkomer, now on exhibition at the Royal Academy, is described
                        as "a splendid exercise in robust painting, direct, forcible, and unhesita
                        ting, exuberant almost in its vitality and yet controlled by the surest
                        seuse of artistic pro- priety."</p>
                    <p>Vienna Choral Society.—The net receipts obtained by the Vienna Choral Society
                        during their recent tour in Egypt amount to P.T. 44,302. This sum has been
                        forwarded to the Austro Hungarian Diplomatic Agent, who has divided them
                        among various charities, as follows: Moslem charities, P.T. 6,552 ; Aus
                        trian charities, P.T. 6,256 ; Italian charities, P.T. 3,''276 ; French
                        charities, P.T. 1,276 ; French Orphanage, P.T. 2.000; Rudolph Home, P.T.
                        3,276 ; Anglo American Hospital, P.T. 7,600; Deaconesses' Hospital, P.T.
                        6,552; Austrian Rudolph Hospital, P.T. 7,212.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Press.—In regard to Yacoub Pa-ha Artin’s ecture on Egyptian
                        Press Sta- tistics up to 1904, which is to be given at this afternoon's
                        meeting of the Egyptian Ins- titute, it is worthy of note that, in 1840,
                        there were only two newspapers in Egypt. One of these was published in the
                        Turkish, and the other in the Arabic language. Both Were offi- cial. In
                        1868, a private French newspaper was, for the first time, published at
                        Alexandria There are now 30 daily papers, 67 weekly or fortnightly, and 52
                        monthly or bi-monthly periodicals, making in all a total of 149. Of those,
                        96 are published in Arabic, 22 in French, 15 in Greek, 7 in Italian, 5 in
                        English, 3 in Armenian, and 1 in Hebrew.</p>
                    <p>Merchant Seamen's Home. — A concert arranged by Mrs. Roberts was given on
                        Friday evening last. There was a large gathering of seaman present, and Rev.
                        H. P. Reid presided Miss MunGavin’s songs, “The River of Year” and “Faithful
                        unto Death," showed off her fine voice to perfection, and as an encore she
                        gave “Three fishes went sailing." Mrs. Baylis’s pretty song and the duet
                        with Mr, Johnson from “Veronique” were enthusiastic- ally encored. Mr.
                        Johnson also sang “The Yeomen of England” and “Gallop away” in an artistic
                        style, and his encore "Devotion’ was splendidly given. Mr. Plank’s musical
                        recitations, “The Lesson of the Water Mill” and “An Old Bachelor," were
                        quite a nice change in the programme, and “Domestics’ Asides" and "Otto and
                        the Auto" were very amusing. Mr. Heaton sang briskly “Anchored” and also
                        accompanied some songs, as did Mrs. Roberts, who also played two lively
                        pianoforte solos, "Autumn Pastime" and "Moore’s Irish Melodies," by A. F.
                        Smith. She did not sing owing to a cold. Several others who were to have
                        taken part were prevented through indis position. Among those present we
                        noticed Mrs. A. Ward, Miss Harbord, Grafton Bey, Capt Thomas, Milburn Bey,
                        Mrs. and Miss Milburn, and several others.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">TYROL -Weissenstein Castle 3410 ft First-class private hotel near
                    Windisch-Matrei; Station, Lienz (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                    mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September. Prospectuses
                    and Pho- tographs, "Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo. 25365 48* 40</div>
                <div type="item">ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA The best halfway house between
                    Egypt and England is VIRAGO, near PISA Main line express stop. Pine woods,
                    Sands, Sea bathing mild climate, English Pension, Villa Shelley. Every home
                    comfort. Electric light. Modern sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and
                    gardens</div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item"><head>BRIGANDAGE IN FAYOUM ARMED BAND ON THE PROWL. A REIGN OF
                        TERROR.</head> ( From our Correspondent. ) <p>Medinet-el-Fayoum, Saturday.
                        Something akin to a reign of terror prevails in this province just now. The
                        country is being overridden by a formidable band of brigands. These men, who
                        number about a hundred, have got clever leaders and are well organised. They
                        are armed with the best guns, and have made their head-quarters on the
                        cultivated spots round the desert and hills that separate the Fayoum from
                        the Beni Souef province. They have moreover got secret agents in the various
                        villages of the province. They generally commit their depradations on dark
                        nights, when they make organised descents on the residences of the wealthy
                        inhabitants.</p>
                    <p>The night before last, members of the gang formed a cordon round the village
                        of Bishoun, some of the men being stationed at each bridge and main
                        thoroughfare to prevent help being sought by the inhabitants from the neigh-
                        bouring villages. The omdeh of the village was besieged in his house by
                        twenty armed men. There were only four ghaffirs in the vicinity, the others
                        being out on duty with the molahiz of police, and these four men were
                        utterly powerless to cope with the armed marauders.</p>
                    <p>Another cordon was formed round the resi- dence of the omdeh’s cousin,
                        Soliman el Sayed, who is reputed to have considerable wealth at bis house.
                        More than a hundred shots were fired by the brigands, the ghaffir of the
                        house being killed and three servants wounded.</p>
                    <p>On their entering the house Soliman el Sayed was threatened with immediate
                        death unless he gave up the keys of his safe. This he promptly did, and the
                        robbers made a clean sweep of all the money and valuables they could lay
                        their hands on, including a quantity of jewellery belonging to the omdeh’s
                        wife and sister. They afterwards made good their escape, and are in safe
                        hiding.</p>
                    <p>On hearing of this extraordinary occurrence, I immediately proceeded to the
                        village of Bishoun on behalf of the "Gazette” and there found the Moudir,
                        the Chief of the Parquet, the Commandant of Police and tho district mamour
                        engaged in conducting an enquiry. It was a case, however, of “locking tho
                        stable after the horse is stolen," as the robbers had left the village a
                        long time before they arrived on the spot. I think it would have been better
                        if the Moudir had also sent a detachment of police and ghaffirs to cut off
                        the retreat of the band before they could get across the desert. It would
                        likewise have been advisable to send detectives to find out where the
                        members of the band come from, and to keep their eyes on the brigands, in
                        order to find out what they are going to do beforehand, and not what they
                        have already done.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">FAYOUM NOTES. <head>PUBLIC v. PRIVATE EXECUTION</head> (From our
                    Correspondent). <p>Medinet el Fayoum, May 2. Three shocking crimes have taken
                        place here lately, and it does not seem as if the new sys- tem of private
                        executions is working well. Few of the criminal classes read the newspapers,
                        and as a rule they hear nothing about the carrying out of capital sentences.
                        Fayoum people do not see the hoisting of the black flag at the prison in
                        Cairo, and those who read about the execution of a murderer are not the
                        criminals who would be, perhaps, deterred from crime if they witnessed a
                        public execution on the spot where a murder had been committed. This might
                        act as a deterrent, which should be the main object of punishment</p>
                    <head>ENGLISH LANGUAGE IN SCHOOLS</head>
                    <p>I visited the Government school the other day, and spoke with some of the
                        pupils, who are making very satisfactory progress in learn ing English. The
                        headmaster graduated in England, and is therefore proficient in the language
                        of that country. In addition to the Government school, there are three
                        others —one for boys and two for girls—where all the pupils learn English.
                        In a few years' time the language should become almost universal in Egypt,
                        enabling the natives to read good English books and learn the lessons in
                        moral ity, good behaviour, etc., that they cannot find in the Arabic books,
                        which are so hard to understand.</p>
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Scottish Prince” left Antwerp on Friday last with general cargo,
                        &e, for Malta and Alexandria. The Messageries Maritimes S.s "Senegal,” from
                        Marseilles, passed the Straits of Messins on Saturday and is due here
                        to-morrow. The Moss liner “Amasis” arrived at Liver- pool on Saturday
                        morning. The Moss liner "Nitocris” arrived yesterday morning from Glasgow,
                        via Gibraltar and Malta, with mail and general cargo. The Ellerman S.S
                        “Sardinia" sailed on Sa- turday for Manchester with passengers and a general
                        cargo including 4,844 bales cotton, and 10,951 bags onions.</p></div>
                <div type="item">ARISTON AERATED WATERS Guaranteed Distilled ALEXANDRIA: 7, Rue de
                    la Poste CAIRO:</div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUCCESSFUL BIG GAME HUNT. MR. McGILLIVRAY’S RETURN.</head>
                    <p>Mr. D. P. McGillivray, of the National Bank of Egypt, returned to Cairo on
                        Friday morning, via the White Nile and Khartoum, from his big game hunt in
                        Abyssinia. His bag consists of a concession granted by the Emperor Menelik
                        to the National Bank for the establishment of an International Bank of
                        Abyssinia, and about one hundred head of big game, amongst which are some
                        record heads. Mr. McGillivray suffored considerably towards the latter, part
                        of his journey from inflammation of the eyes, but we are happy to hear that
                        he is now pro- gressing towards speedy recovery. We beg to tender him our
                        hearty congratulations at such a successful issue of his expedition, which
                        is as largely due to his indomitable will as to his financial capacity and
                        Skill with the rifle.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                    <p>We understand that the report of the Emir el Hag dealing with the El Hamra
                        incident has been received at the Ministry of the Interior. Since certain
                        other versions of the affair have been received from pilgrims who were
                        present, it has been decided to forward their evidence with the Emir el
                        Hag’s report to the War Office, where a committee of enquiry will shortly be
                        convened</p>.</div>
                <div>
                    <head>TRIPOLI FRONTIER.</head>
                    <p>Lemloun Bey, who has returned from Ben- ghazi, reports that all is quiet on
                        the Tripoli frontier, and that sheep and cattle are being collected for
                        import Into Egyptian territory.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive is going to Wardan this after noon to inspect the progress of the
                        Mariout line.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.</head>
                    <p>A council of discipline will be held at the Ministry of Justice to try the
                        judge of the Mehkemeh Sharieh of Tahta Markaz on Wed- nesday next, under the
                        presidency of the Minister of Justice, assisted by the Grand Cadi and the
                        Grand Mufti of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>The following are the terms of the arreté, issued by the Minister of the
                        Interior, for the suspension of the Moudir of Ghirgeh, Hasaan Bey
                        Wassif:-</p>
                    <p>Le Ministre de l’Intérieur, vu le rapport adressé par le Procureur général au
                        Ministre de la justice, en date du 3 mai 1905, constatant la nécassité de
                        mettre on mouvement l'action publique contre Hassan Wassif bey, moudir de
                        Guirgueh, accusé avec d’autres dans une affaire de faux;</p>
                    <p>Considérant que dans ces conditions il y a lieu de suspendre le dit moudir de
                        ses fonctions...</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUPREME CONSULAR COURT.</head>
                    <p>The Congdon-Houghton libel action has been settled out of court, the
                        defendant having expressed regret that the article in question was
                        published. The case was therefore dis- missed.</p>
                    <p>Mr. O’Sullivan, of the Irrigation Depart- ment, brought a case against the
                        Delta Light Railway Company for damage done to two. horses. The action was
                        withdrawn from the Supreme Court and will be sent before the provincial
                        court.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE RAILWAY INSTITUTE.</head>
                    <p>The second annual excursion of the Egyptian State Railway Institute was held
                        on Friday under the presidency of Mr. George Walker chairman of the
                        institute, when some 60 mem- bers, with their wives, children, and friends
                        availed themselves of the opportunity to pay a visit to that most favorable
                        of all pic-nic places, the Barrage. A special train, provid- ed free by the
                        Railway Administration, left Cairo at 9 a.m., and arrived at the Barrage
                        shortly before a quarter to ten. Some seven hours of enjoyment were spent by
                        the party before the return at 5.35 p.m. The manage- ment and catering were
                        in the hands of Mr. Ben Defrece, manager of the institute and the greatest
                        compliment we can pay him is to say that everything went off without a
                        hitch, and that everyone agreed that a greater success could not be
                        attained. A excellent lunch and tea were provided and all the provisions,
                        which were brought from Cairo, were of the very best, and not even the
                        ice-chest was forgotten. Beverages of al- most every description were
                        provided and the bar was well patronised, for the day was some- what warm.
                        Members and guests alike vied with each other in their efforts to make the
                        outing a success, and it was unanimously agreed that should future
                        excursions be run on the lines of this one, failure would be impossible.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POSTAL NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>Persons residing in the suburbs of Cairo and Alexandria, such as Helouan,
                        Ramleh, etc., are advised to have their correspondence from abroad addressed
                        to the town as well as the suburb, e.g., Mr. X. Y. Z., Ramleh, Egypt
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Correspondence thus addressed proceeds di- rect to Cairo or Alexandria and
                        can be more quickly delivered than that addressed only to the suburb, which
                        has to be sorted at the port of entry.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID THE S.S. “CANDLESHOE."</head> (FROM OUR
                    CORRESPONDENT). <p>Port Said, Sunday. The whole of the damaged cargo is now out
                        of this vessel. The official estimate of the loss sustained as regards cargo
                        alone, and excluding the damage done to the ship herself which is
                        considerable is between £18,000 and £19,000. The necessary repairs to the
                        hull of the ship, inasmuch as they apparently do not affect her
                        seaworthiness, are to be carried out in England. She will sail in a
                        fortnight’s time.</p>
                    <head>NEW BRITISH TORPEDO DESTROYERS.</head>
                    <p>At dawn to-day the destroyers “Dee,” “Erne," and "Ettrick" arrived from
                        England on their way out to Colombo. These vessels, and three others which
                        are due to-morrow morning, the. "Arun," "Exe," and “Itchen,” are remarkable
                        in their way, as they mark quite a new epoch in naval construction. Included
                        in the 1903 Estimates, they are quite new, steam 25.6 knots, and having a
                        displacement of 540 tons, appear to be an improvement on the old type Up
                        till 1902 no destroyers afloat exceeded 280 tons; the behaviour therefore of
                        this new class will be watched with interest.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS. ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Singapore" de la Cie Florio Rubattino arrivé hier de Gènes,
                        avait à bord:</p>
                    <p>MM. Richmann, F. Errante, N. Perecchi, Av. A. Cacace, E. S. Bender, Baron van
                        der Berch, L. Caron, R. de Stefano, P. Agostnco, Meabe, Poppof, M. Corasson
                        Cassilliger, Dr Budde et comp., Giglie Oberti, Don Enrico et 10 passagers de
                        3e classe.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot “Cleopatra" du Lloyd Autri- trichien arrivé ce matin de Trieste
                        avait à bord.</p>
                    <p>MM. Cremona, Zuckerbacker, Hankins, Jehle, Arsfalg, C. F. Vogel, Nieroth et
                        sa soeur, Aristzid, Knasel, Cavalli et bébé, et 23 passa- gers de 3me
                        classe.</p>
                    <head>DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. "Sardinia" sailed for Manchester on Saturday : Mr. Fred Rigg, Mr. J.
                        B. Hum- phreys, Mr. Carlos Ronzevalle, Mr. C. W. Hatfield, Mr. C.
                        Broulchurst, Mrs. C. J. Esan, Miss Alice Ironomonger.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Portugal" parti vendredi pour Marseille avait à bord :—</p>
                    <p>M. Lazare Mires, Mme Satow, Mlle Aude et 2 enfants, M. Jean Multida, M.
                        Glenat, Mme M. Mardo, Mlle Murdo, Mmes Rolland, Re- vieh et S. Denis, M.
                        Pelissier, M. M. Kabbag, M. Schulle, M. Bancher, Capt. Hills, Capt.
                        Brockenriger, M. Anderut, Mme Koblet, M. Boudon, Mme Blum, famille Debonne,
                        famille Leroux, M. et Mme Croissant, Dr. Sayed, Mme Lafton, M. et Mme
                        Tisseau, M. Tullock, M. Assimacopulo, M. Crossley, M. Walker, M. et Mme
                        Hadjes, Mme et Mlle J. de Zogheb, M. I. Slemback, Mme Lorello, R. P. L.
                        Perroy. M. Rossano, Mme de Lestrie, M. Morand, Mme Vve Laugier, Mme Van de-
                        Hecht et deux enfants, Mme Vve Mahmoud Affify, M. Bouvier, M. Sambos, M.
                        Herbonnez, Mme Molmi Belned, Mme Belingon, M. A. Collingudge, M. Batin, M.
                        R. J. Luston, M. W. Sheldon, M. Tigueron, Mlle. Chossogniole, Mme Longworck,
                        M. Paul Spriet, M. Saba- dini, M. et Mme Billaud, Frères Alphonse et
                        Lambert, M. Debbas, M. Nabas, Mlle Ge- naoui, Mlle Hoss, M. S. Hoss, Mme
                        Oubrey Mme Vexler et enfant M. Aldan, Mlle. Trouiller, M. et Mme Muste, M.
                        Bronwig Mlle et Platt, 17 passagers de 3me classe et 29 de 4me classe.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Semiramis” da Lloyd Autri- chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait
                        à bord: M. et Mme U. Ammann et 3 enfants, M. Hugo Aucke, M. le Dr. L. Aucke,
                        Mme Bernhard Mme Bond et Compagne, M. et Mme C. Berla et enfant M. et Mme B.
                        Coret, Mme Dotti et fille, Mme Daendliker, M. H. et Mile El. Farnall, M.
                        Grandy et 2 soeurs, Mme Emilie Gibbons, Mme Mathilde Gallichi, Mr. R. Gol-
                        denberg, S.A. le Prince et la Princesse Mob. Aly Halim et 4 de famille, M.
                        et Mme Hafner M. Hunter Jones, Just et 2 de famille, M. et Mme H. J.
                        Lancashire, M. R. Lecomte, M. lAssak, M. Hubert Miller, Mme Mnrikch, M
                        Meditz, M. G. Meinecke, Lord Milner, M. Oberhofer, M. le Comte A. Pongracz,
                        M. Rossi J. Raff, Mme Aly Bey Saddick, Mme Staub Mr. E. Stangen, M. R. H. A.
                        Storrs, Mr. Em. Stross, M. le Comte Szickeny, S. E. et Mme Serfonlah Pasha
                        Yousry, Mlle Sibbald, Mme E. Staiger, M. B. Springer, M. Angelo Titi M. et
                        Mme R. A. Tilche, gouvernante et 2 enfants,M. le Baron H. de Trauttenberg,
                        M. et Mme J. J. Tschopp, M. Tolentino,M. Werner M. le Comte et la Comtesse
                        Wedel, M. Mohed- din Bey Yousry, M. Selim Zogheb, M. Naghib Zogheb, Famille
                        Arlich, M. Bayer, M. et Mme Cizovich et nièce, M. David Coen, Mme Du- mont,
                        Mr. A. Dahl, M. G. Ernesti, Mme Fleischmann, Mr. Frederick, M. M. Frank M.
                        et Mme Vve Portogaloglu, Mme Scanavi Mlle E. Seifert, Mr. W. Strimer, M. et
                        Mme P. Stoermer,M. et Mme Kueuokeil,Mlle Oxford 10 femmes de chambre, 3
                        valets et 52 passa- gers de 3e classe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel In Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management 1 1 904 GRAND HOTEL BONNARD
                        ALEXANDRIA PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Prince Mohamed Aly Pasha, who recently arrived in Paris from Constantinople,
                        accom- panied by Mansour Bey, his secretary, expects to remain in Paris for
                        some weeks.</p>
                    <p>Lord Milner, Sariallah Pasha Yusri and his wife, the Princess Shukar, left
                        Alexandria for Europe on Saturday by the Austrian Lloyd steamer.</p>
                    <p>A marriage has been arranged, and will take place in October between Major
                        Edward Sidney Herbert, the Black Watch (attached Egyptian Army), and
                        Gwendolen, youngest daughter of tho Right Hon. Sir John E. Gorst, M.P. </p>
                    <p>The following marriage notice appears in "The Times" of the 1st inst. "On the
                        26th April, at St Peterss, Cranley Gardens, S.W., by the Rev. J. G.
                        Gauntlett, assisted by the Rev. E. Bormer Shokell, Olivet Herring, second
                        son of the late Tomlin Campbell, Esq., of Jamaica, to Martha Marion, second
                        daughter ot James Watts Grimes, Esq., late of Tco- woombo, Queensland.”</p>
                    <p>Lieut-Col. G. M. Mackenzie, 2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, and Lieut. E.
                        A. H. James, R.E, have been granted leave of absence on private affairs.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Landon, Inspector of Irrigation in the Indian Irrigation Service, is
                        shortly to be appointed to the Irrigation Department for service in Lower
                        Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr.
                        C. E Macdonald, Mr. and Mrs. A. M. Hafner, Mr. E W. Buckley, Mr. L. A.
                        Cooper, Mr. G. B. Goyder, Mrs. S. Gallienne, Suleiman bin Nasser, Mr. A.
                        Eeman, Mr. F. Canevari, Mr. Ant. Dottori, Mr. J. Williams, Miss
                        Treseder.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR. PUMPS IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Dear Sir,—We notice in your issue of
                        the 3rd inst. a paragraph headed "Pumps in Egypt" referring to some
                        observations made in “The Times" concerning the alleged superiority of
                        Continental-made, and especially French, pumps, as compared with those of
                        British manufacture. A correspondent writes you disputing-the accuracy of
                        some of the statements made by “The Times” correspondent above, and has
                        repeated the same in the paper "African Commerce".</p>
                    <p>We have had a very large experience during the last forty years in the sale
                        of centrifugal pumps in this country. For some years we were the agents of
                        Messrs. J. and H. Gwynne, of Hammersmith, subsequently we took up the agency
                        of the late firm of Messrs. Gwynne and Co., Essex works, Strand, London, and
                        we have now for many years represented Messrs. Ruston Procter and Co.,
                        Limited, of Lincoln, in the same line.</p>
                    <p>It is a fact that until lately Continental pumps have been increasingly in
                        demand in Egypt, not on the score of price, for they are considerably dearer
                        than British, but upon that of superior mechanical efficiency. So constantly
                        was this brought to our notice that we induced Messrs. Boston Proctor and
                        Co., Limited, to purchase several French pumps by the best makers and carry
                        out a series of experiments with electric drives and measured tanks, &c.,
                        the results of which completely bore out the ver- dict of the poblic. The
                        efficiency of some of these pumps was very good, and much in advance of what
                        British makers are as a rule disposed to guarantee. Messrs. Ruston Proctor
                        and Co., Limited, decided to at once re-design their pumps, combining the
                        best points in both British and French makes, and brought out their new
                        pattern helical pump, with which when tested in a similar manner they
                        obtained as high an efficiency in some cases as 84%. We are prepared to
                        guarantee in all sizes about 80% mechanical efficiency with these pumps and
                        are glad to be able to report that all our customers who have tried them are
                        more than satisfied.</p>
                    <p>We feel sure you will consider the above facts of interest, as it is
                        constantly stated that British manufacturers will not move with the times,
                        and an instance such as the above shows that however true the reproach may
                        occasionally be it is not of universal application.—Yours obediently, for
                        Allen Alderson & Co., Limited, F. Allen, Director. Alexandria, May 6.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Auiourt hui a midi et demie) Londres etant venu en hausse, notre marche a
                        brillamment debute ce matin, mais il n’a pas tarde a reactionner sous le
                        poids des realisa- tions.</p>
                    <p>Cependant, la plupart des grosses valeurs eloturent notablement an-deesus des
                        cours de samedi.</p>
                    <p>Ainsi la National Bank monte de 27 5/8 a 27 15/16, !e Credit Foncier de 313 a
                        318 l’Agricole de 13 7/16 a 13 5/8 et la Daïra de 28 1/2 a 28 11/16.</p>
                    <p>Par contre, plusieurs valeurs de second ordre sont en baisse: les Markets
                        tombent a 22/3, la Salt & Soda a 34/3, la Khedivial Mail a 4 1/2 Somme toute
                        la tenue est ferme aveo tendance a la hausse.</p>
                    <p>Les plaidoieries du proces entre les Privili giees et lee Dividendes Tramways
                        d’Alexandrie ont ete renvoyees au 22 mai pour attendre l’arrivee
                        d’Angleterre d’un procès-verbal d’assemblee</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
