<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-10">November 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-07">July 7, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="masthead">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, JULY 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.
                    </head>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOCIALISM IN GERMANY. A FRENCH “UNDESIRABLE.”</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Berlin, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>The Government has forbidden the French Socialist Deputy M. Jaurès to
                            lecture jn Berlin upon the international duties of Socialists with
                            reference to war, on the 9th inst;, on the ground that the German Social
                            Democrats would utilise the occasion ( to advance their antinational
                            efforts. (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Paris, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>Prince Radolin has informed M. Rouvier that Germany declines to have M.
                            Jaurès at the Berlin Conference. (Havas.) </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOUNDERING OF French SUBMARINE.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Bizerta, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>A French submarine with 13 on board has foundered in the lake here.
                            (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Ferryville, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>The submarine “Farfadet” has sunk with 13 hands. Attempts at rescue are
                            being made. </p>
                        <p>(Havas.) </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNITED STATES. MR. HAY’S SUCCESSOR.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Washington, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>Mr. Root, formerly Secretary of War, succeeds Mr. Hay. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GORDON-BENNETT RACE. CUP TO BE RETURNED TO DÇNOR.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Paris, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>The cup will be returned to Mr. Gordon-Bennett, owing to the decision of
                            the 28th June of the Automobile Club of Franoe to no longer take part in
                            the contests. England is the only country besides France, whose three
                            competitors completed the course. ( Reuter.) = V"""</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HENLEY REGATTA.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Henley, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>Grand Challenge Cup. The Leander beat the Sport Nautique of Ghent by 2A
                            lengths. </p>
                        <p>Diamond Sculls. Kelley beat Blackstaffe easily. Time 8 minutes and 10
                            seconds, which is a record. (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RACING.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>London, July 6.</dateline>
                        <p>The Princess of Wales Stakes. 1, St. Denis ; , Exchequer ; 3, Lancashire.
                            (Reuter.) </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>N ATI VH PRESS OPINIONS. LORD CROMER’S SPEECH.</head>
                    <p>In discussing Lord Cromer’s speech, “A1 Moayad” remarks that the better the
                        relan tions between Abdeen and Buckingham Palace, the better for Egypt, and
                        that the attitude of the extremists, whose idea of patriotism is a
                        systematic opposition to all that has to do with the'l )ccupation, is
                        brainless and even opposed to the principles of the Koran. With Lord
                        Cromer’s four conditions the “Moayad” expresses its agreement subject to one
                        or two reservations. While admitting that a direct control of Egyptian
                        affairs by Parliament would injure Egypt, it remarks that Parliament must
                        never lose its control of what are, after all, its agents in Egypt, and must
                        be able to check any abuse of their powers. In this connection, it is
                        earnestly to be desired that some means existed of bringing the Egyptian
                        point of view before Parliament as clearly as Lord Cromer’s point of view is
                        set forth in the Blue-books. The caution in the introduction of Western
                        ideas must not be exaggerated, for Egypt has made great strides, and
                        finally, while there is no question of Lord Cromer’s sincere devotion to the
                        good of Egypt, many of his projects have been diverted from their end by
                        those charged to carry them out. </p>
                    <p>“A1 Lewa” expresses its disagreement with “A1 Moayad’s” views. Opposition to
                        the British Occupation is an absolute necessity, and it is strange that ‘ Al
                        Moayad,’’‘‘after 14 years in opposition, should abandon its policy and
                        support Lord Cromer’s views. The opponents of the Occupation are the only
                        veritable patriots. If Lord Cromer’s wishes for the welfare of the Egyptian
                        people are sincere, he should permit them to occupy many of the important
                        positions now reserved for Englishmen, and reduce the expenses caused by the
                        Occupation. The Egyptians were the first civilised race in the history of
                        the world and are to-day as capable of assimilating modern civilisation as
                        the Japanese or the English themselves. The future will show their capacity
                        beyond dispute. </p>
                    <p>A Cabinet Council.will be held to-morrow ât San Stefano under the presidency
                        of H. E. Fakhry Pasha, Acting Regent. </p>
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Mousky district of Cairo during
                        to-morrow night and at daylight on Sunday, will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                    <p>Ra$ el-Bar.—A temporary post office for all branches of the service,
                        specie-packets excepted, has been opened at Ras el-Bar, near Da-mietta, for
                        the bathing sèà«Qn. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL,</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Double Execution at Alexandria.</head>
                        <p>—El Sayed Ali Selim and Ramadan Mnrsi, who murdered a female egg-seller
                            at Souk ElBprsim, will be executed at Hadra priaon on Moniky, 10th inst.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>—Yesterday’s bulletin records two cases, one of which was /atad, at
                            Alexandria. \ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>—8 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th inst., of which 3 were
                            British, 2 German, 1 Ottoman, 1 French, 1 Dutch. The day’s receipts were
                            fra. 226,420.69, making the total from the 1st inst. frsl 1,267,505.15.
                            * </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Plague Precautions.</head>
                        <p>—The medical officer in charge of the Labbane quarter has ordered a
                            cordon to be drawn round two houses where deaths have occurred which are
                            believed to be directly due to bubonic plagnè. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hashish Smuggling.</head>
                        <p>— A Greek subject, named Nicolas Aasimacopoulos, was arrested this
                            morning while attempting to smuggle four torbas of hashish, which were
                            wrapped round his legs, through the gates- of the Custom house. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>‘Quis Custodies Ipsos Custodes V</head>
                        <p>—The secret police arrested Constable Alexandrello, of the City Police,
                            at 6 a.m. to-day on disembarking from the S.S. “Athens.” This man was
                            implicated in the recent shooting affray in Sisters-street. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                        <p>—El Kaimakam Herbert Bey, Assistant Adjutant General, Recruiting
                            Department, will take over command of the Cairo District from El Miralai
                            Matchett Bey, who proceeded to Khartoum on temporary duty yesterday.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Dramatic Performance.</head>
                        <p>^- The Ernesto" Rossi dramatic clnb will give a performance at the
                            Pyramids Theatre on the 12th inst. of an Italian version of Bisson’s
                            comedy Les Surprises du Divorcé. The caste is a strong one and the
                            performance should meet with thé usual, success. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ramleii Railway Crossings.</head>
                        <p>—It appear? that automobiles and carriag^R are frequently driven at great
                            speed over tnlf level crossinj on the Ramleh Railway, especially at
                            Bulkeley, which renders the precautions taken by the company valueless,
                            notwithstanding the special watchmen placed on duty at these crossings.
                            The dangers to which automobilists and carriage drivers expose
                            themselves are most serious, as with this exaggerated speed it is
                            certain that more often than not the watchmen have hardly time to signal
                            to them before they are on the line. Consequently, we are asked by the
                            company to appeal to the public, when driving over these crossings, to
                            slacken speed in order to avoid any chance of accident. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>«RAID HOTEL ISKHARi, ÀLSXAKDBI4. ••* MU BAY, WINE INCLUDED’ }» f ARISTON
                        AERATED WATERS Guaranteed Distilled. ALEXANDRIA : I mrtlrItfAL!?.?.!,. » ■
                        7. Em 4.1. Pert* I "Su," Kiulï.’ÏÇ’,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Dr. Rucker-Jenisoh, German Diplomatic Agent, will leave Cairo for San Stefano
                        on Sunday. </p>
                    <p>Judge Bond, vice-president of the Native Court of Appeal, has left for
                        Zurich. </p>
                    <p>Mr. II. Boyle, Oriental Secretary to Lord Cromer, left yesterday by the
                        Rubattino boat for Europe. </p>
                    <p>Count von Wedel, First Secretary at the German Diplomatic Agency, is expected
                        hack in Cairo on Monday or Tuesday next. </p>
                    <p>Abdallah Bey Sfqr leaves for Italy to-day. At Rome he will meet the Maronite
                        Patriarch, whose yisit to Europe has given rise to a variety of conjectures. </p>
                    <p>Major B. W. Longhurst, R.A.M.C., has been granted an extension of leave from
                        July 14 to January*18,1906. </p>
                    <p>M. Skinder has been appointed architect the Egyptian Land and Q^ral Trust.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>SYRIAN PROTESTANT COLLEGE. 36th ANNUAL COMMENCEMENT EXERCISES.</head>
                    <byline> ( ,Fbom a Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <dateline>Beyrout, July 2.</dateline>
                    <p>-For over three decades the Syrian Protestant College stood, as it were, on
                        an eminence as a beacoYof knowledge shedding a growing light on Syria, and
                        in its later phases of development it has' plainly become one of the most
                        potent educational factors in the Near East. One has but to glance at the
                        latest edition of its prospectuses, of Which à judicious distribution is
                        annual’y made, to realise the magnitude of its infiuen o and the scope of
                        its field of action. This magnifioent institution recruits its army.of about
                        * 700 stadents from various countries. Its radius of power extends from
                        Armenia in the East to Greece and the Ionian Isles in the West, and from
                        Asia Minor in the down to Egypt in the South. But ils influence has been
                        mostly felt in Egypt, directly through the preponderant number 6Î seekers
                        for knowledge that the Land of ’ the haraohs has always supplied, and
                        indirectly but no less mightily through the Syrian settlers who constitute a
                        strong intellectual element in Egyptian life, and who, under the strong,
                        capable, and judioious guidance of British rulers, are contributing largely
                        to the progress of the country. Therefore any event of public character in
                        this birthplace of learning should not fail to appeal to the interest of the
                        readers of the “Gazette.” </p>
                    <p>The commencement exercises this year began on Saturday, 24th June, ten days
                        earlier than the usual and traditional time. This has been determined by the
                        early arrival of the Imperial Medical Commission from Constantinople.
                        Although the exercises commenced on Saturday yet they may be considered to
                        have been publicly inaugurated by the Baccalaureate service on Sunday, when
                        President Howard Bliss delivered his annual valedictory and exhortatory
                        address to the medical and pharmaceutical graduates. The scene was, as it
                        may easily be imagined, one calculated to call forth deep aud stirring
                        emotions and inspire thoughts of the noblest kind, and the young President’s
                        fiery eloquence rose splendidly to the occasion. The meeting was well
                        attended by students and many of the public. The blessing was fitly given by
                        the old President Emeritus, whose appearance in public functions at the
                        college is still inspiring and recalls to the hearts of older students happy
                        memories of the godd old days. </p>
                    <p>The exercises closed on Wednesday with the ceremony of thé distribution of
                        prizes And diplomas. The principal and striking féature of that day was the
                        processional march. At Ada Dodge Hall the procession, consisting of the old
                        graduates, the faculty, and the staff of teachers, formed* and proceeded to
                        the Memorial Hall at 3.30 p m. preceded by the American Consul and the
                        Imperial Medical Commission. The President and members of the Faculty wore
                        their "academic gowns, and as it marched forth with measured step and took
                        ito-feeats on the platform in the Memorial Hall* the procession presented a
                        sight of unusual solemnity. </p>
                    <p>The closing event was a delightful entertainment on Wednesday evening at the
                        President’s, Marquand House, wound up by a series of hilarious and comic
                        songs, lustily sung by a part of the American staff of teachers. The
                        entertainment is given principally in honor of the Imperial Medical
                        Commission, composed this year of General Mahmoud Hakki Pasha, a
                        distinguished officer, Colonel Ahmed rehmi Bey, and Major Escret Roushen
                        Bey. The reception wa3 held in the president’s class-room, a hall of
                        spacious dimensions, but which, owing to the large crowd, could afford only
                        standing room. This, coupled with the orrid heat of June, made it
                        particularly ncomfortable to the invités, and called forth uggestioiis from
                        some of them for an enlargement of the hall, which would not be inadvisable
                        considering the growing importance of the' college. Bat the welcome was so
                        hearty, and there was such a general air of conviviality, that the heat and
                        other little, discomforts were forgotten. Besides, to those blessed with a
                        sense of hnmonr and that rare power of selfdetachment, there wag afforded a
                        rich fund of /amusement by the presentation of the ijhtés to the Imperial
                        Commission. This distinguished body was victimised by a presentation of
                        almost all the large crowd of Quests, and for about half an hour there was
                        something like a pantomimic show of a fFe of ladies and gedtlemen coming
                        forward with lifferent degrees of grace and awkwardness to hake hands with*
                        the three commissioners, who cut curious figures, repeating with lutomatic
                        sameness the stiff, jerky, and deep German bow in reply to each
                        introduction. After the ordeal they withdrew to the cooler recesses of the
                        garden on which the hall opens, to indulge in timely refreshments and the
                        necessary accompaniment of the fragrant weed. </p>
                    <p>These entertainments form a cheerful ending for the graduates of a year of
                        hard study, wakeful anxieties, and stirring emotions, and no doubt
                        they-procure the hospitable President and his charming wife many a farewell
                        word of blessing from the grateful pupils who are to face the hard realities
                        of life. </p>
                    <p>I had almost forgotten to add that 28 medical students were presented to the
                        Commission for the final examination. Of these one did not complete his
                        examination, one failed to pass, 36 took the oath of office before the
                        commission and received their oollege diplomas. Their Turkish diplomas will
                        he sent to them later. </p>
                    <p>Nine pharmacy students were presented to the commissioners for final
                        examination. Of these all passed pud took the oath and reomy-eft diplomas.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAS-EL-BAR. THE EGYPTIAN MARGATE.</head>
                    <byline>(From a Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <p>Now that the summer has begun in earnest, many dwellers in inland towns will
                        be thinking of making a move soon to some favored spot by the seaside where
                        the invigorating ocean breezes will once more brace the jaded residents of
                        the interior. For those who have the means San Stefano is incomparably the
                        Queen of Egyptian summer resorts,but-to those to whom money is a primary
                        consideration, and others who prefer a free-and-easy and happy-go-lucky
                        existence, I know of ho better place close at hand than Ras-el-Bar, not far
                        from bamietta. </p>
                    <p>I very much doubt whether the frequenters of this little place, which springs
                        into life with the advent of the great beat, would seek to qualify its
                        attractions by comparison with those offered elsewhere, say at Ramleh or
                        Port Said, but I do not hesitate to say that it possesses a charm of its
                        own, and I am not surprised when I discern the same familiar faces there
                        £®ar after year. ' </p>
                    <p>» The season proper at this Egyptian Margate, if I may term it so, does not
                        commence in earnest until the middle of July, and is in full 8 wing until
                        about the end of September, iothat the hotel-keepers and others who minister
                        to the wants ot the strangers have, in a sense, to make hay while the sun
                        shines, although, considering the shortness of the season, no one can say
                        that the prices charged are exorbitant. The majority of the visitors are
                        Levantines and Egyptians, leavened by a fair number of Europeans of all the
                        nationalities that inhabit this country. </p>
                    <p>The hotels, if one can honor them with this name, and dwellings ajfe mainly
                        if not entirely constructed of the native rush mat fastened to wooden
                        uprights and are slighly raised from the land or ground in the same manner
                        as bungalows in India. Naturally, in a country like Egypt, where rain is
                        unknown for nine months at least of the year, snch habitations are possible,
                        but one could not calmly contemplate what would happen to the whole place
                        were it visited by a good monsoon 'rain of an hour’s duration. </p>
                    <p>Of course, of amusements of the fashionable kind there are none to hegnile
                        the time, but for those who love sea-bathing, fishing, and an bnt-of-door
                        life, Ras-el-Bar is a small paradise. The bathing ui the best in Egypt, and
                        eaoh hotel has a hnt wherein batherrssan undress and dress. There are a few
                        shops, sujch as the inevitable bacals, a good barber, ^chemist, and last,
                        hut not least, a branch post-office. There is also from June, to October a
                        small body of police under the orders of a native officer. </p>
                    <p>» I should not omit to mention, for the information of would-be new-comers,
                        who may like to give the place a trial, that there is a regular steam boat
                        service that carries the mail between Damietta and Ras-el-Bar, the trip
                        occupying about an hour and running in coincidence with the arrival of the
                        passenger trains from Mansourah. Daring the busy season the Egyptian Railway
                        Administration runs an express train weekly each way whioh starts from Cairb
                        every Thursday. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAIRO HOTELS.</head>
                    <p>In reference to the recent rise in the shares of the two leading hotel
                        companies of Egypt, it is worth noticing that the principal reason of the
                        rapid appreciation within the past few months of this class of securities is
                        the enormous increase since two years or so in the value of the land on
                        which the Grand Continental and the Savoy Hotels are built in the case of
                        the Nungovich Hotels Company, and in the case of the Egyptian Hotels
                        Company, of the land at Ghezireh, which has been and is being 3old at
                        rapidly increasing prices, </p>
                    <p>The former company bought $he New Hotel, now the Grand Continental, àboùt six
                        years ago, including the land it stands on and the furniture it contained,
                        for £105,000, which, at the time, was considered the lull value. The
                        presentvalue of the land alone, which measures 11,000 squarè metres, at the
                        modest price of £20 per square metre, represents an increase of no less than
                        £4 per share on the entire share capital of the company, not reckoning the
                        building, furniture and good-will of a concern that pays yearly dividends of
                        ten per cent. </p>
                    <p>The Savoy Hotel, as it is, was bought about a year later than the other from
                        Prince J)jemil Pasha Toussoum,we believe for £55,000. The land is 5,000
                        square metres in extent, but owing to the' extraordinary increase in the
                        price of land in the best part of the Ismailia quarter the site alone to-day
                        is worth the fifty five thousand pounds, without counting the palatial
                        buildings erected on it. This* repre-^ sente an increase in value of at
                        least £2 per share on the whole of the share capital. With these figures
                        before us can one wonder that the £4 shares of the Nungovioh Hotels are now
                        worth £10 or thereabouts, and those of the Egyptian Hotels at an equally
                        high premium ? . </p>
                    <p>As we mentioned a few weeks back, the former company have pnrobased by
                        preemption a portion of the estate of the late Sabet Pasha, adjoining the
                        Savoy Hotel, and on the ground so acquired they are to ereot additional
                        buildings to accommodate the large and ever-increasing clientèle that
                        patrorises this hotel during the winter season, besides enlarging the
                        restaurant and making other mnoh-needed improvements. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>BECK GO’S PILSENEj) BEER BREMEN. ' T1AB8 SO HOHMT COKFRITIOB MB QUALITY.
                        R.B,—Inferior Salads now Mag oftnd to lfa H" aMCtolo fOOâ MÜM. Beware of
                        otDly OfOMt «feMjjton matof foWAhl**» liiAlto Ini »</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID-.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SUBMERGED DREDGER,</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Thursday.</dateline>
                        <p>Work on the submerged dredger “Pharaonrp’ II.” is now being rabidly
                            pushed towards com- ‘ pletion. t learn that the vessel is to be raised
                            by qaite a novel method,' which' should prove most interesting. As I
                            noted some time back, she lies bn her side, and a kind of bed is being
                            .dredged ont along her side, at the bottom'of whioh is to be placed a
                            patent slip cradle. A cutting is to be made in the hank into which the
                            dredger lying on the cradle is to be towed. The entrance to the basin
                            will be closed, and it is then to be pumped out and the vessel attended
                            to as if she lay in a dry-dock. Hopes are expressed that the “Pharaon
                            II.” will be hanled into the basjn in two weeks’ time. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHARITY CONCERT.</head>
                        <p>The massed bands of H.M.S. “Suffolk” and ’Lancaster,” by permission of
                            the captains and offioers of the vessels, are giving a concert on
                            Saturday evening in aid of the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to
                            Animals. The concert is to he held in the garden of the Eastern
                            Exchange, which is being very prettily arranged. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FOURTH OF JULY AT MANSOURAH. </head>
                    <byline>(From a Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline> Mansourah, July 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Mr. W. L. Lawton, of the Jewell Export Filter Co., having just completed the
                        installation of a plant of these filters at the new waterworks in this town,
                        entertained his numerous friends on the dahabieh “Ariadne,” kindly lent for
                        the occasion by Mr. Dale, yesterday. Anchored in mid-stream, the rigging
                        dressed with the flags of all hâtions, that of the star-spangled banner
                        predominating, with a tapestried awning overhead, and palm-branches arched
                        over the columns around the sides, file dahabieh made a gay show by day. At
                        night, the numberless coloured lights, strung on high amongst the rigging
                        and all around, with their reflection on the waters, had quite a fairy-like
                        appearance. On the island in mid-stream two cannon had been plaoed, the
                        thunders of which were interrupted by the authorities, it being against the
                        Government regulations to fire artillery within 250 metres of the town, but
                        our oourteous Moudir : kindly the fireworks, rockets, Roman candles, etc.,
                        on this special occasion, the first time, in the annals of Mansourah, that
                        this American fête has been celebrated in such a public maimer.
                        Unfortunately the members of the American Mission were absent, having been
                        called away the previous day to attend a meeting at Alexandria, so that Mr.
                        Lawton was^ the only oitizen present, but he war a host in himself, and
                        reoéîved his guests for afternoon tfh at 5 o’clock on the deck of the
                        dahabieh. This fonction over the company crossed over to the island
                        amid-stream, where the gentlemen entertained the ladies by engaging in
                        athletic sports. On their return to the boat, they found a sumptuous dinner
                        spread out on a table which had been prettily decorated with flowers and
                        plants by Mrs. Dale. Toasts, songs, and musio followed to a late hour of the
                        night. </p>
                    <p>Mr. Lawton was ably assisted in the efforts to celebrate his national
                        fête-day by Messrs, McCrae, Anderson, and Holeman, whose hearty co-operation
                        went far to make the affair the success that it was. During the evening,
                        muoh was said in praise of our most energetic Moudir, Mustapha Pashà Maher,
                        for the many improvements he has introduced into the town, amongst them the
                        paving of the main streets, their present cleanliness and order, and the
                        construction of a, carriage drive and promenade along the hanks of the
                        river, south of the town into the open oountry. This drive is to be planted
                        with trees, which will form a shady avenue*, A new street has already been
                        commenced, orossing the town, and opening up a route from the river to the
                        open fields by the cemeteries. Not only has the Moudir had “Beni Adam” at
                        heart in his endeavours to benefit the town, but his establishment of a
                        branch of the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals has been so
                        successful, with the active and able support of his officers, the police,
                        and our veterinary surgeon Dr. Trydel, that it is an exception now-a-daysto
                        fin da siok animal about the streets, and whereas the S.P.C.A’s hospital was
                        formerly crowded with siok beasts, many having to be shot, all the stalls
                        are now often empty. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.</head>
                    <p>The lengthy text of the judgment of the Court of Appeal in the Rifehi case
                        has been given to th* Press. It leaves no manner of doubt as to the guilt of
                        the acoused, while it, admits the presenoe of extenuating circumstances. « </p>
                    <p>We hear that Hassan Bey Wassif has been sent to the infirmary at Menshieh
                        prison owing to a slight indisposition. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S/^Persian Prince,” from Antwerp, left London yesterday with general
                        oargo for Malta and Alexandria. </p>
                    <p>The 8J3. “Tuscan Prince,” from Manchester, left Malta yesterday and is doe
                        here on Monday morning next, with passengers and general oargo. </p>
                    <p>The Khédivial Mail S.S. “Irauilia"’ will leave Alexandria on Wednesday fo*
                        Pima* Smyrna, Mitylone andOoMtontmopk </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesCyprus">

                    <head>NOTES FROM CYPRUS</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DESTRUCTIVE RAIN STORM,</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>J * Nicosia, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>As mentioned in my last week’p notes, a good deal of inponvenjeLoe upst
                            threatened to travellers on the NioosiarTjroodos road in consequence of
                            t£e. dw»g9.c«iued by tbeheavy rain storm in the ftfados jange. At 0al*fc
                            the mountain, stream, whiph had . beoome greatly swollen, washed away
                            portion of the road which, winds in and; out at that point, and, many
                            tons of debris, were deposited. The Public Works Depart. ce£p promptly
                            to the rescue, and of men </p>
                        <p>Knd women were very qmclfo pnt to worjf to repair, the damage. little
                            delay or inconvenience was canari, tot the officiala wbo were then on
                            their way to their Troodoa encampments, and the road was opened to trafo
                            after an interval of some 24 hours or so. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW RAILWAY LINE.</head>
                        <p>The railway is now laid to within four miles of Nicosia, and the whole
                            line, from Nioosia to Famagusta is expected to be completed by about the
                            1st August, I hear that the Government is already using the completed
                            portion for the movement of grain from the threshing floors to the grain
                            stores, whioh have beén established at one or two along the line. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SALE OF GRAIN.</head>
                        <p>The Government has advertised for sala the following grain of this year’s
                            harvest, which represents tithe and recoveries from the seed corn
                            advances : </p>
                        <p>Wheat 316,500 kilns (English bushels) Barley 411,000 „ </p>
                        <p>Vetches 42i«50 „ </p>
                        <p>Oate 50,600 „ „ „ </p>
                        <p>all of whioh quantities, with the exception of vetches, which ère tery
                            slightly in exceM, aie less than those advertised for sale last year. I
                            understand that practically the whole of this has been sold, and at
                            higher priées than in 1904. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INVESTIGATION OF FLORA.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Jens Holmboe, a Norwegian expert botanist, is now in. Cyprus fpr the
                            purpose of investigating the flora of the Island on behalf of the
                            Botanioal University of Christiania. He has already spent Borne months
                            in Cyprus and contemplates remaining some little time yet. . ~ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOOD AND DRUGS ACT.</head>
                        <p>The Food and Drugs Act passed hist session by the Legislative Council
                            provides, among other things, that any purchaser of any ai* tide of food
                            or of a drug or medicine shaU be entitled, on payment to an analyst of
                            the sum of five shillings, to have snch article or drag or medicine
                            analysed by him, and to receive from th$ analyst a certificate of the
                            ijesult of his analysis. It also defines what is tP be regarded as
                            adultemtioit under the Act, and hew toffenoes are punishable. Duly
                            authorised persons are empowenMi to purchase any such artides jor tfiè
                            rntprm purpose of analysis, and power is given to the. Court to destroy
                            the subject matter of any charge. It is hoped that the 'enforcement of
                            this la* may have a salutary effect.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JEWISH COLONISATION; -</head>
                        <p>A small ohiftlik near Lamaoa has lately been acquired by the Jewish
                            Colonisation Society, and it is intended In course of time to import a
                            limited number of Jewish people as settlers, who will be taught to carry
                            on certain agricultural and industrial undertakings there. It is toe
                            soon to predict ho* "this will answer, hut, if wisely managed and a
                            capable, industrious, and intelligent colony is formed, with a fair
                            amount çf oapfcl at its disposal, it may not be uhrçasonabk to
                            anticipate good results both to the oblony; and, as on object lesson and
                            a means of extending the trade of the'Island, to Cypriw’ ih general. \
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURE8.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot “Tebe” de la Cie Florin Ru-battino parti hier pour Gènes avait £
                        bord î </p>
                    <p>M. et Mme V. Olîva, M. et Mîne Fiandro, Cav. Giordano, Filippo Grassb,
                        Lombardi Boccia et famille, F.-V. Piat* I. Tawü» ?. Petroni, J. Suares, M.
                        Magrin, C. Garbua, Av. Sooolis, Leonida Crespi, * A. £*ri, Dom. V. Pinto, M.
                        Blattner, Carlo Nàggiar/Callari Mussp, Mme M. Mieli, Anharnlnaall famille,
                        M. et Mme E. Nahman, Mme Vve Anastasia et fille, Mme Beneduoci, Ludwig et
                        fils, ^ahby Ibrah. Bey, V. Spozio,^ JirmoJ| Bey et famille, Padre Carlo, Mme
                        À. Alioe, Mme Booeja, Mme Collingwood, Mlle L. Qain, îfrosso Bey et famille,
                        É Berty et faniülë, "Br. tT. Musso, B. Métier et*atoïUe^MS Unài, f Mme
                        Serveuse, Arir Nadèr et sceut, G. Muller, H. Boyle, Av. I. Mosoa et famille,
                        Prof. K VanDiok et fille, M. et Mme A. SaU-nas, G. Bennici et femüte, D.
                        Simha, Aura Sassoli, Mob. Bey Tewfiqk, </p>
                    <p>Baron V. Morana, M. et Mme M*f*°*P° Granato. R J. Naggar, M.. et Mme Wispo et
                        Secrétaire, M** PuoomeefiHjM Mme A. Cangiaai, A. </p>
                    <p>Brandaui, G. Diaoono^^ “ </p>
                    <p>Lamberto B. ^ </p>
                    <p>70 pyefvs de 6me cUssti</p>
                </div>

            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
