<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
				<title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
				<editor><!-- Hank Thompson --></editor>
				<principal>Will Hanley</principal>
			</titleStmt>
			<editionStmt>
				<edition>
					<date when="2016-10-15"><!-- October 15, 2016 --></date>
				</edition>
			</editionStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
				<pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
					<date when="1905-10-30"><!-- October 30, 1905 --></date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div type="page" n="1">
				<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
				<!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
				<head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
				<div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="2"> </div>
			<div type="page" n="3">
				<div type="item"><head>﻿THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, OCTOBER 30-1905</head></div>
					<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>RUSSIAN REVOLUTION.</head></div>
						<div type="item"><head>SITUATION WORSE.</head></div>
						<div type="item"><head>LIFE AT A STANDSTILL.</head></div>
						<div type="item"><head>THE TSAR'S FEARS.</head></div>
						<div type="item"><head>London, October 28.</head>
							<p>It is said that on account of the gravity of the situation the Tsar's yacht is kept under pressure to convey the Imperial family to Denmark in case of necessity.(Reuter)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 28.</dateline>
								<p>The corporation of workmen decided yester-day evening to continue the strike to the bitter end, bat to give no occasion for violence.
								(Reuter)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>London, October 28.</dateline>
								<p>The situation in Russia is monopolising attention and depressing the bourses. It is j believed that it will be necessary to postpone the Russian loan.	(Reuter)
								Moscow, October 28.
								The political parties have decided to form a government of their own, which will act independently of the Imperial Government. Owing to the strike of the hands in the gas and electric works, many quarters here and at St. Petersburg were in Darkness last night. Only candles and lamps were available. (Reuter)
								St. Petersburg, October 28.
								The situation throughout Russia is getting worse. Telegrams from all parts show that the Government is paralysed by the wholesale strikes which spread to every trade and profession. There is practically no railway communication  and there are no newspapers. Ordinary life is at a standstill, and all schools, colleges, and universities are closed. Moscow is absolutely cut off owing to the strike of the telegraphists. Odessa is also practically isolated. The town council is establishing a militia for the defence of the citizens. Reval is plunged in darkness and the theatre has been burned.
								The Minister of Finance has informed the bankers that the negotiations for the loan are postponed pending an improvement in the situation.	(Reuter )
								Warsaw, October 28.
								30,000 infantry, 5,000 cavalry, and 100 guns are held in readiness to repress any disturbances. There have been crowded meetings in all cities in favor of the strike movement, bat the collisions between the troops and the populace have not, so far, been serious.
								(Reuter)
								St. Petersburg, October 29.
								M. Witte was received by the Tsar on Friday and Saturday. The proclamation of a Constitution is expected on the 3rd of November.
								A curious feature of the Russian revolutionary movement is the formation of citizen militia in different towns.	(Reuter)
								Odessa, October 29.
								The workmen, under the leadership of students, whilst erecting barricades in the streets, had a sharp encounter with the Cossacks. Five strikers were killed and 18 wounded.
								Two officers and four soldiers attended a meeting last night and asked the strikers not to fire on the troops, promising in return to fire in the air when summoned to quell disorders. (Reuter)
								St. Petersburg, October 28.
								The revolutionary movement is extending. It is rumoured that a yacht is in readiness to take the Tsar to Denmark.	(Havas)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>DEATH OF RUSSIAN GENERAL.</dateline>
							<p>St. Petersburg, October 28. General Dragomiroft is dead. (Reuter)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><head>FRANCE AND PORTUGAL</head>
							<head>M. LOUBET LEAVES LISBON.</head>
							<dateline>Lisbon, October 28.</dateline>
								<p>At the banquet the King and M. Loubet drank to the prosperity of the two nations.
								(Havas)</p>
							</div><div type="item"><dateline>Lisbon, October 29.</dateline>
								<p>President Loubet has left.	(Reuter)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>Paris, October 29.</dateline>
								<p>M. Loubet has embarked on his return to Marseilles.	(Havas)</p></div></div>
					<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>SPANISH CRUISER SUNK.</head>
						<dateline>Ferrol, October 29.</dateline>
							<p>The Spanish cruiser Cardenal Cisneros struck a rock and foundered. The crew were saved.	(Reuter)</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>Le Ferrol, October 28.</dateline>
							<p>The cruiser Cardenal Cisneros has sunk The crew were saved.	(Havas)
						The cruiser Cardinal Cisneros was built at Ferrol and took some twelve years to construct. She carried two 9.4 in. guns, eight 5.6 in. and a number of smaller pieces, was protected by an armour belt and was capable of a speed of 20 knots. She wav more or less a sister of the Vizsaya, Maria Teress, and Oguendo, which perished at Santiago, and, like them, was hardly fitted to meet the requirements of modern naval war.</p></div></div>
				<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>COERCING THE TURK.</head></div>
					<div type="item"><head>NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
						<dateline>Vienna, October 29.</dateline>
							<p>It is announced that all the Powers are in principle in favor of a naval demonstration to overcome the resistance of the Porte to the Macedonian scheme. It is doubtful whether the Porte will give way without a display of force. 	(Reuter
							Rome, October 30.
							Italy is averse to a naval demonstration against Turkey, but she will act if necessary.
							(Reuter)</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>EVACUATION OF PETCHILI.</head>
						<head>THE KAISER’S PROPOSAL.</head>
						<head>Peking, October 29.</head>
							<p>The German Minister, in an audience with the Dowager Empress, informed her that the Emperor William will forthwith propose to the Powers to withdraw from Petchili. (Reuter)</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE IN HUNGARY.</head>
						<dateline>Budapest, October 29.</dateline>
							<p>M. Fejerwary is submitting to the Diet a popular programme for universal suffrage, granting facilities for restoring the land to the peasants, and the use of the Hungarian language by officers in Hungarian regiments. If the Diet does not accept, an appeal will be made to the country. (Reuter)	</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>JAPANESE RICE CROP.</head>
						<dateline>London, October 29.</dateline>
							<p>The "Times” learns from Tokio that the rice crop in Japan is much below the estimates. Three prefectures are threatened with famine.	(Reuter)</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>ITALIAN KING VISITS BRITISH FLEET.</head>
						<dateline>Genoa. October 29.</dateline>
							<p>The King has visited the British Squadron.
							(Reuter)</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>ORDERED TO SOMALI COAST.</head>
						<dateline>London, October 28.</dateline>
							<p>The Fox and Pro(s)pine, which were at Suez, have received orders to proceed to the Somali coast.	(Reuter)</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
						<p>The Cairo Tramway Company have issued their winter time-table, which comes into force on November 1.</p>
						<p>The Pilgrimage.—A large number of Moorish pilgrims from Tangiers arrived at Alexandria yesterday by the Ellerman S.S. Sardinia.</p>
						<p>Boy Drowned —A boy named Seyid Ahmed Ibrahim. 11 years of age, fell into the sea from a small boat yesterday and was drowned. His body has been recovered.</p>
						<p>Stray Dogs.—Stray and ownerless dogs found in the Gamalieh district of Cairo during tonight, and in the Waily district during tomorrow night, will be poisoned by the police.</p>
						<p>The Cairo Chrysanthemum Show will be held in the exhibition hall at Ghezireh on Saturday and Sunday, November 4 and 5. The opening of the exhibition will take place at 3.30 p.m.</p>
						<p>Egyptian Army Examination. - Fourteen candidates out of a total of twenty-one who presented themselves for examination for promotion to the rank of Buluk Amin,at Abbasieb on the 18th inst, have been successful</p>
						<p>Butchers’ Strike.—Our Cairo contemporaries threaten us with a butcher's strike,caused, it is stated, by corrupt conduct on the part of an inspector of the abattoir. We hope that the Ministry of the Interior will take the necessary steps to save Cairo from such an unpleasant experience, at the opening of the season, too, of all times !</p>
						<p>A Ramadan Poem. Our native contemporary "Al Zahir” contains an Arabic poem, composed by Moh. Bey Abou Shadi, the proprietor of the journal, and dedicated to H.M. the Sultan on the occasion of the commencement of Ramadan, which commemorates the glorious recapture of Sanfi and describes the Yemenites as lacking knowledge, religion, and good manners. Perhaps they will atone for their past rudeness by giving Ahmed Faizi Pasha a warm reception at Sada, where their leaders have retired.</p></div>
					<div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
						<p>The Moss Iiner Tabor sailed from Liverpool on Saturday afternoon and is due here on the 1 th prox. with passengers, mails and general cargo.
						The M.M. steamer Niger, from Marseilles, passed the Straits of Messina Saturday and is due here tomorrow morning.</p></div></div>
				<div type="item"><head>THE ROYAL TOUR.</head></div>
					<div type="item"><head>RENOWN'S PORT SAID STAY.</head>
						<head>(From our Correspondent.)</head>
						<head>Port Said, Saturday.</head>
							<p>Now that the Royal party have left us on the continuation of their Tour, it may be interesting to review the progress of the trip up to the time of their departure.
							H.M’s. battleship Renown left Portsmouth on Sunday, 15th inst, for Genoa, where the Prince and Princess of Wales embarked. From Genoa to the Straits of Messina the Renown was accompanied by H.M.S. Lancaster, Suffolk, Terrible, and Cambrian, with Lord Chas. Beresford on board. Just as the Royal party were leaving Genoa the Italian Fleet rounded the point The fleet consisted of Sicilia, Marco Polo, Delfino, and other vessels.
							When the Renown and her escorts arrived in the Straits of Messina, they were met by the whole of the Mediterranean Fleet, consisting of H.M.S. Bulwark, Queen, Formidable, Implacable, Venerable, Irresistible, Sentinel, Prince of Wales, Goliath, Venus, 14 destroyers, and others. The actual place of meeting was off Cape Pellaro. The usual Royal salute was fired, after which manoeuvres began and lasted till sunset. Later in the evening there was a grand display of illuminations  and fireworks. The fleet returned to Malta as soon as Reggio was passed, and the Terrible proceeded to Port Said at full speed, in order to have time to coal at Suez before the arrival of the Prince.
							It was expected that the Renown would arrive here at 8 a.m. on Friday, and as a matter of fact no one expected her on Thursday,until about 11 a.m., when Capt. Tottenham informed the British Consul that he had received a wireless telegraphic message from H.M.S. Suffolk saying they would arrive at 3 p in.
							The Renown, on her arrival, moored opposite the Canal Company’s office. The band of the Lancaster played "God bless the Prince of Wales" while the Renown was mooring, and immediately after the Renown's band struck up "God save the King."
							The Princess, who was on the bridge with the Prince, looked charming in a black skirt with a white bodice and yachting cap. Their Royal Highnesses remained on the bridge until the ship was moored and the boats returned. They then retired to their private rooms, and afterwards received some official visits.
							After the visitors had left the Renown, the Prince of Wales was to be seen strolling on deck conversing with the Captain Soon after 7 o’clock his Royal Highness retired, and most of the people who had been waiting on the shore, in the hope of seeing the Royal party land, left.
							Early on Friday morning the Prince and Princess, accompanied by some members of their suite, left the Renown and boarded the Surprise, where they took lunch. Afterwards, the Prince inspected the yacht and shortly after 3 p.m. he and the Princess proceeded to the Lancaster. Here the Prince inspected the ship and, as already reported, rang the silver bell which was presented to the vessel by the ladies of Lancaster. Subsequently the Royal party went on board the Suffolk. Tea was the chief item on the programme on the Suffolk. The stern of the ship was very prettily decorated with flags, etc. The Prince, on leaving, shook hands with all the officers, and the sailors gave three cheers for the Prince and Princess, and another three for the King, as the Royal Standard was Hauled down.
							From H. M. S. Suffolk the Prince and party went to the Powerful, where they were met by the captains of all four ships. Dinner was served later in the evening, after which a ball was held, and the Prince and Princess returned to the Renown soon after mid-night
							The Renown finished coaling about 2 p.m. yesterday and by 6 p.m. everything was as clean and white as possible.
							Over 700 "Jac=ks” came ashore last night and the streets were full until the early hours of the morning.
							At 6 a.m. to-day the boats of the Renown were lowered and manned and by 6.15 the Renown was under way. Twenty-one guns were fired as a salute from the shore battery, and a little cheer went up from the few people gathered on shore as the Renown moved off. The Prince appeared on deck just as the bridge bell rang "Slow ahead.” An hour later H. M. S. Powerful left her moorings and entered the Canal, and at 9.45 H. M. S. Lancaster left for Malta.</p></div>
					<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>DEPARTURE FROM SUEZ.</head>
						<head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
							<dateline>Suez, Saturday.</dateline>
							<p>H. M. S. Proserpine sailed from Suez for the Red Sea last night at midnight, and was followed at daybreak by the Pox. These two ornisers were originally intended to escort the Renown.
							The battleship Renown, with the Prince and Princess of Wales on board, came out of the Canal this evening at 7.30 and anchored ft) the Bay, alongside the Terrible. The Renown presented a rare aspect in the Canal, as she was brilliantly illuminated and was using three electric light projectors to find her way between the buoys.
							9 35 the cruiser Powerful came out of the Canal and also anchored in the bay. She is going to take 2,500 tons of coal, and then sail for Australia.</p></div>
						<div type="item"><dateline>Suez, Sunday.</dateline>
							<p>At 8 o’clock  this morning the Royal Standard was hoisted on the Renown, which was saluted with 21 guns by H. M. S. Terrible. Both ships are painted white with yellow funnels. The Renown is taking no coal here, and is expected to sail at noon to-day escorted by the Terrible.
							</p></div><div type="item"><dateline>Suez Monday.</dateline>
							<p>H. M. S. Renown, escorted by H. M. S. Terrible, sailed yesterday at noon.</p></div></div>
			<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>ARRIVAL OF THE VECTIS.</head>
				<head>DETAILS OF COLLISION.</head>
				<head>(From our Correspondent.)</head>
					<head>Port Said, Monday.</head>
					<p>The S.S. Vectis (6,000 tons), of the P. and O. Co.,*arrived at Port Said to-day from Beyrout with a number of tourists on board.
					I learn that the collision which the Vectis had near Constantinople was with the Italian cargo steamer Esther. Although the damage done to the Vectis was slight, the Esther had a rent from rail to keel which was 20 feet wide. She only just managed to reach shallow water in a sinking condition.
					The passengers on board the Vectis praise Captain Johnson's prompt action, as the passengers were all assembled without any panic and the boats manned in a few minutes. Happily these precautions were unnecessary.
					The Vectis Will reach Alexandria the end of this week.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>SIR WILLIAM GARSTIN.</head>
					<head>GIFT OF £15,000.</head>
					<p>The Egyptian Government has Informed the Press that it has decided to grant the sum of £15,000 to sir William Garstin, C.M.G., in recognition of his valuable services to the country. We are glad to hear that Sir William Garstin is making as favorable progress as can be expected after his recent operation, and will resume his functions as Adviser to the Ministry of Public Works early in January.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
					<p>H.H. the Khedive received the Earl of Cromer in audience at Abdeen Palace yesterday morning. In the afternoon his Highness received  H.B. Mgr. Photios, Patriarch of the Greek Orthodox Church, Seifullah Yonssi Pasha, and the Vicar of the Armenian Orthodox community.
					At 3.30 p.m., his Highness presided at the sitting of the Council of Ministers, and in the evening he gave an "iftar” to the ulema, after which his Highness held a general reception in honor of his return to the Capital and of the commencement of Ramadan.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
					<p>The extraordinary general meeting of the shareholders of the Sucreries, which was to have been held at 4 p.m. on Saturday, has been postponed till the 25th prox. owing to a sufficient number of shares not being represented.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>A QUESTION OF PROPRIETORSHIP.</head>
					<p>Our readers will remember that some months ago the property of Aly Pasha Cherif on Rhoda Island was put up for sale by the Wakfs Administration, and was knocked down to Messrs. Zervadachi AND Co. at the price of £1,360 the feddan. This price was thought by the Wakfs Administration to be insufficient, and consequently it was decided to have a new adjudication. We hear that few companies were prepared to compete owing to certain drawbacks connected with this property, such, for instance, as the fact that all the river frontage, amounting to 14 feddans, had been sold by the heirs as private property to various persons, and consequently would not enter into the general sale. Another drawback was the fact that a portion of the property was understood to be leased for a period of seven and a half years and that under no circumstances would the lessee give it up to a purchaser until the expiration of his term.
					We now hear that the lessee has officially notified the Wakfs Administration of bis intention to hold his land for the entire period of his lease, although the administration only recognises his right to a part of it A good deal of discussion took place about this at the time of the first adjudication, as several important persons are said to be in interested in the matter, and the point is one that has an important bearing on the renewed sale of the lands, which has been fixed for the first of next month.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
					<p>Mr. Dupuis, Inspector General of Irrigation in the Sudan, will  probably return from his special mission to Canada and the U.S.A. on December 4.
					M. Barois is expected to return from leave on the 2nd prox, when be will resume his duties in the Railway Administration.
					Major P.G. Elgood, inspector in the Ministry of the Interior, has returned from leave and resumed his duties.
					Mr. M. Melville, inspector in the Ministry of the Interior, has been granted an extension of leave until the 16th proximo.
					Major W.F. Ilosiey, 2nd Battalion Royal Ioniskilling Fusiliers, hss been granted extension of leave until December 13.
					Mr. M. H. Goldie has been appointed manager of the Harrar branch of the National Bank Of Abyssinia.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM PORTSAID.</head>
					<head>BAD WEATHER IN THE HARBOUR</head>
					<head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
						<head>Port Said, Sunday. </head>
							<p>The last few days have seen a long of more or less serious accidents in the harbour of Port Said largely owing to the somewhat protracted spell of bad weather which we have experienced here.
						The night before the arrival of the Royal party in the Renown it blew hard from the east, and in a short space of time a sea got up which did considerable damage to the new East breakwater. Towards morning some 30 yards of newly placed block of concrete had disappeared and a large hole had been breached by the sea in the small jetty.
						Some forty native craft, wind bound, laden with coal, took refuge under the lee of the jettes and one was sunk
						The Messageries Senegal hooked some  mooring chains with her anchor and, drifting round, smashed he windlass, and divers lifting material were sent at daylight on Saturday to assist her.
						During the early hours of Saturday, a collier, the Appledore, to avoid a collision with some of the native vessels which at all times are to be seen crossing and tacking in the sea channels, let go both anchors and did so much damage to herself that she was obliged to slip both chains ; which chains and anchors it took over a day to recover and replace on board.
						The record was completed last night, when Bell’s Asia Minor steamer, the  Bear, coming into port, in the main channel, ran into and sank a very large Arab dhow laden with some 100 tons of coal and carrying no lights — which, by the way, is after all not at all an uncommon state of affairs in the harbor and on the coast line of Port Said. The sound of the crash of torn and rending timber, accompanied, as it was, by the noise of falling spars and the howls and screams of the vessel’s crew and of those of many other similar vessels at anchor in the vicinity, was awe-inspiring and terrifying in the extreme. The Bear apparently went astern on the engines, for her rudder could clearly be seen from the breakwater in a mass of foam and spray, and a circle of some yards of churned-up water was remarked, by many among the witnesses of the collision, Which occurred at 8 p.m.
						The Canal Company's launches were in the Vicinity and very quickly had lines on to the sunken vessel endeavouring to tow her out of the channel, with little chances of success, for the dhow bad completely sank in a minute after the shock, which most have cut her nearly in two. I have heard that no lives were lost and that her entire crew of 16 were picked op almost immediately. The Bear, after examination, slowly proceeded to her berth, having suffered no apparent damage, and to-day shear-legs and divers are at work getting the sunken ship dear of the channel, which, however, remained dear on its western side.</p></div>
				</div><div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM FAYOUM.</head>
					<head>FIRST WINTER RACES.</head>
					<head>(From our Correspondent.)</head>
						<head>Fayoum, October 26.</head>
						<p>The first winter races take place here to-morrow, and very great interst is being manifested in the meeting. Hamad Bey Basili is making preparation on a great scale and hopes that our races will eventually rival those of Alexandria or Cairo. However that may be, we shall have visitors from Cairo to-morrow in the dessert of Azab, close to the Nazleh waterfal and the old Coptic convent and only a matter of a few minutes' drive from Medinet el Fayoum</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>CASES OF LEPROSY</head>
					<p>A leper came to my office yesterday and I made enquiries as to how he caught this terrible disease. He informed me that he used to sleep in the same room with his brother and brother in-law, the last of whom was a leper and communicated the malady to the other two men. These three men are the only cases i have noticed in Abousir illage, Fayoum, and it seems to me that the disease must have been conveyed by fleas or other parasitic insects. Would it not be possible for the Government to build a small leper hospital to enable these cases to be segregated?</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
					<head>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB.</head>
						<p>Owners are reminded that first entries for the Maiden Pony Plate, value LE 100. and Cairo Derby, value L.E. 100, to be run at the Pint Winter Meeting in December, close on November 1. Also, nominations for the Jubilee Stakes, value LE 500, and Eclipse Stakes, value LE. 500, must be made on November 1 Subscriptions for the Paddock Handicap, value LE. 200, and Visitors Handicap, value LE. 200, to be run at the Third Winter Meeting, must be taken by November 1.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><p>Anglo-American Nile Steamers
					An
					rHTOTBJI, CQIwEIPAig-Y'.
					Blur Tnmwort of Goods botwosn Altsaadrfa sad Cairo. THftCC 6AU.INM A-WfcKK.
					. Agent* mt	*
					uumnu mem umaem ca, m,</p></div>
				<div type="item"><head>THE P18XNI CASK</head>
					<head>FURTHER HEARING OF WITNESSES</head>
						<p>Pisani, teh Malteese, was again brought before teh British Consular Court both on Friday and Saturday, on the charge of having attempted to murder Victoria Dehan, and Austrian subject, at the Pension Krauss, on the 13th inst Mr. A. D. Alban presided, Mr. Favargi acted as registrar, and Maltre Sciortino appeared for accused.
						In giving evidence on Friday, Captain Arthur Quartier, inspector of the secret police, deposed that he was called to the Pension Krauss in the Old Zaptieh=street on the 18th inst. and that on entering he found there a man who was connected with [    ] "Imperiale," an employe of the Telephone company, and the landlady. He was handed a revolver which he selt in order to convince himself that it had been fired recently and which he then put in his pocket. The mirror was broken and the carpet and two chairs were blood-stained. He found Victoria Dehan in the next room standing up and holding her right side from which blood was flowing. There was also a man in the room who proved to be Giorgio Mascarelli, the woman's lover. He took her to the Gards Medicale, where she was attended by a doctor. Shortly afterwards the Commandant of Police and the chief of the secret police arrived, and in their presence he unloaded the revolver, which contained two loaded and three empty cartridges. Accused came to the pension in te custody of the mamour of Mousky ceracol and witness examined his hands. He found the top right hand between the thumb and fore-finger discoloured, and there was a slight bruise on the fore-finger, the left hand was much discoloured and both smelt of gunpowder. Victoria Dehan, who had returned to the pension, was confronted with accused, who she identified as her assailant.
						VIncenza Zuixef, mother of the injured woman, was next called and said that she cae to Cairo to take her daughter back to Port Said, where her husband lived. She next accused at the railway station and afterwards went to the pension, having first visited the Hotel de la Poete. At the pension witnesses, Victoria Dehan, Pisani, and the landlady went into a parlour. Accused told Victoria that he had sent for her mother to take her back to Port Said. Victoria said she could not ge at present, and told accused to leave the room as she wished to speak to her mother. The landlady then told witne that she could not allow her daughter to leave as she had been recommended to her by someone. Accused asked Victoria why she would go with [her] mother, and the woman replied she did not wish to, whereupon Pisani drew a revolver from his coat pocket and fired at Victoria. The landlady rushed out of the room and locked herself into the opposite one, while witness ran out calling for help and as she was going downstairs heard another shot. Witness did not go back to the house but took the next train to Port Said.
						Emin Wasfi, mamour of the Mousky ranebl, was the next witness heard on Friday. His evidence differed in no essential detail from that of Captain Quartier, and Said Mustaqha was next called and deposed to having arrested accused.
						The first witness examined on Saturday morning was the medical adviser to the Austrian Consulate. The woman Victoria deposed witness, had two wounds which had evidently been inflicted by one bullet. The first wound was on the under surface of the right arm, oblique in direction, and superficial, it being caused by the Bullet grazing the arm, which the woman held up to protect herself. The second wound was serious. It was on the anterior right side of the thorax and had penetrated into the thoracic cavity, lacerating a portion of the rights lung. He had sent her to hospital and thought she would not be able to appear for at least ten days
						Giorgio Mascarelli, who lived with Vitoria Dehan, next gave evidence. The woman, he said, was married and her husband lived at Port Said, in which town he had made her acquaintance. He came into the pension where he and Victoria were living, just after the shots had been fired. A revolver was produced in court, and witness said it was similar to the one which he had seen lying on the floor of the room when he entered. He was aware that accused had had relation with VIctoria Dehan; accused and witness had not quarrelled about her. Dr. Ismail Hamadi, attached to the Cairo city police deposed to having examined the accused. He said that he found a wound on the left side of the neck at the junction of the head and neck and behind. THere was an irregular opening with a diameter of about half a centimeter. The hair in the neighbour-hood of the wound was signed; the wound might have been self-inflicted by the left hand. There was also a burn and wound on the right cheek, which might possibly have been caused by a piece of glass. There were black marks on both hands, especially the left, and also and abrasion on the right hand.
						Dr. Battista Mazzoli was the last witness called and deposed to having examined Victoria Dehan at the Garde Medicale. His evidence was similar in every respect to that of Dr. Basker the first medical witness called the case was then adjourned until the 7th pox. when it is hoped that the wounded woman may be able to give evidence.</p></div>
				<div type="item"><p>=-= M ’.w gttBagggggggssssgsgMg
					Beck AND Cb’s PilsehSr Bfer.
					BREMEN*
					ObtelneMe from every ReepeeWble nroi
					IN CAIRO, ALEXAMPRU iXD m «Ut)4V.
					LiinranT, asgfisg-</p></div></div>
				<cb n="1"/>
				<cb n="2"/>
				<cb n="3"/>
				<cb n="4"/>
				<cb n="5"/>
				<cb n="6"/>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="4">
				<cb n="1"/>
				<cb n="2"/>
				<cb n="3"/>
				<cb n="4"/>
				<cb n="5"/>
				<cb n="6"/>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="5">
				<cb n="1"/>
				<cb n="2"/>
				<cb n="3"/>
				<cb n="4"/>
				<cb n="5"/>
				<cb n="6"/>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="6">
				<cb n="1"/>
				<cb n="2"/>
				<cb n="3"/>
				<cb n="4"/>
				<cb n="5"/>
				<cb n="6"/>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
