<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-11-08</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-05-20</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, MAY 20, 1905.</head>
<div type="item"><p>Royal Insurance Coy.
FIRE AND LIFE.
Largest Fire Office in the World.
IIASELDEN & CO., Agents, Alexandria.
R. VITERBO & CO., Agents, Cairo.
HICENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.
(ESTABLISHED 1782) ;
IIASELDEN & CO., Agents, Alexandria.
FRED. OTT & CO., Sub-Agents, Cairo.
Soda Water Lemonade, Ginger ale, Ginger Beer, Toaio Water
Pomegranade, Orangeade, Pineapple, Champagne, Cider, etc., etc.
Water guarantee l t.y Chamberlain's Filter (Pasteur’s System). -
Inventor of WHISKY it SODA and BRANDY & S01)A, bottled ready for use.
Sole Agent in Egypt and Sudan for
Our Winter Season’s Stocks</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>COMPRISING AN
Exquisite and Extensive Selection of Solid Silver & Piated articles
CUTLERY, LEATHER & ATHLETIC GOODS & GAMES.
TEA AND LUNCHEON BASKETS.
OHOIG-E HAVANA AND INDIAN CIGARS.
VINTAGE WINES.
PROVISO S, CONNECTION RY AND TIBI DELICACIES,
Are now being displayed for Sale at exceedingly
moderate prices.
The Egyptian Supply Stores, (Branch Walkhb&Co., Cairo).
WALKER & MEIRACHI, Limited.
J. CALVET&Oo........
LOUIS ROKDERER ......
AUGUST ENGEL .......
MACKIE & Co. .......
DUNVILLE St Co , Ltd.
Wm. LANAH aN & SON..
THE COOK &BERNHEIMER Co.
STONE & SON.........
FREUNDBALLOR&Co.....
PIERRE BISSET.......
TERRaBONATEA Company, Ld.
J. CALVET Si Co ... ...................Bordeaux	Wine & Cognics.
LOUIS ROEDERER ........................ Rhk'ims	Champagnes.
AUGUST ENGEL ..........................Wiesbaden Rhine and Mosel.u Wines.
MACKIE & Co.	...	...	...	... Glasgow L.gavaliD, White Horse
Cellar & other Whiskies.
DUNVILLE & Co , Ltd....................Belfast Old Irish Whiskies.
Wm. LANAH \N & SON....................BALTiMORsMonongshtlaXXXX Whiskey.
THE COOK & BERNHEIMER Co...............New York	01J Valley Whisk* y
and Gold Lion CooktaiD.
STONE & SON...................... London Guinness’ Stoat &Ba8s' Pale Ale.
FREUND BALLOR&Co....................... Torino	Vermouth.
PIERRE BISSET..........................Cette Vermouth <fc Aperitives.
TERRaBONATEA Company,Ld................ Teas.
Depot for Prince Metternioh’s "Riohardsqaelle," the best mineral table waterin the world.
Great assortment of Wines, Spirits, Liqueurs, of the finest Brands, etc
GWYNNES, Limited,
(J. & H. GWYNNE, LTD., 4 GWYNNE 4 Co., UNITED.)
aWTiurs, LONDON.
ABO, Mb and Sib Editions, AL
HORSING a NRAI/8.
Trade Hark - “HVVEVCIBLE.”
manufacturers or the largest aid 
Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
In this world, suitable for all purposes, Inducting
RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE, IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAYING
4 FLOATING DOCKS, MUIRS, 4 ALL MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.
bass Pomps ean be driven by Bteam, Ghu, Oil, Water, Heetrldly, or other power, for Lifts ol
from 1 ft. to 1OOft., and from 6 to 600,000 Gallons a Minute. Makers of the Max Pumps.
Result* Guaranteed.	Over 50 Yaara' Praatloal Esparlansa.
All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially
designed to meet Egyptian requirements.
London Offices-	Works-
81, Cannon Street, London, Z.O.	Hammersmith, London, W
The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd:
Rue de la Care du Cairo, Alexandria.	issu-ll-U-sce</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL. PORT SAID. First Class Hotel. Modern, in all respects. Fire-proof, Drained to the Sea, Lifts, Electric Light, En glish and French Billiards. Fresh and Salt Water Baths.	l Re CmU Saucer tedesce is Bgjpt Bpaoial Urmi to Cairo Bondenta and Ibair fttmiliaa dacirou* of enjoying the ooo air and sea bathing daring the lummei months. DXAOOXAXS IS UOT»L DSDrOSM Milt ,
	tMU35«l
HOtel Beau-Rivag 15 Mlnotea by Garriaga or -*Palaia" tram from Bidl Gabor Station. 	 Fuat Gua Valour Horn wit* Btibt Unique Situation on the Loral* Cardan. - Lawn Tonni*. - Largo Tarrao*. - Xlaotrfo Light. - Baa Bath Stabloa Cor hone* and carri. Mod ara to Ohargo*. — Spadal ter-oa Cor aownmul Official* aea.n.i.006	PA <fe Remleh-Alexandrle. ’Ti. —< .jar—I1./ S^M.	fa Bftpt.	1 Moan* Ooaron. Beaoh. a. - Own apriaga. - Perfect eanitery arrangement*. *g«*. and Offloera at tha Army oC Oooapation. G. BUNOKEWITZ, Manager.
IMPORTANT NOTICE.
MARTELL COGNAC.
Tho principal importers of this weU-ki
■ 36/- per cnee or r.r. 170.5. I Vt
S-N.Vo
All ■oollnl MARTELL Cognac
SI:”'™
CIGARES
delaHAVANE
da provenance directe et
de toutes les meilleures marques
Nicolas G Sabbag</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ISIPOUTATEUR GliNEUAU .
FOoRh SStUB DE S» Lt KHEDiVc
et de tons lee grinds Olubi et Hdtels d’Egypte.
2—Hue de la Gave du Caire—2
A LEX A NDltlE
Adrea‘0 TAligrapb quo : dAliBAU ALKX.tXDlllC
To.ophone No £60.
248081-26.0C4
Bole Agent* to Egypt * Sadat;
G. G. DROSSOS & CO.
LATE PRAZZICA& DR0880S.
ALK1AHDBIA, CAJSO, TOUT SACS ARP
Ulf	tBiXUCTK	tl-6tCS</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE
PAVINC COMPANY, LIMITED.
Hamilton House, Blahopgat* St. Without, LOHDOH, 1.0.
CONTRACTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE
PruuovT-SBTmiL, Suru (Fiance) Raoca* (8icUy),
Onnu, (Veneauela), Mm Ow.ua,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EGYPTIAN BRANCH - FIRST ASPHALT FACTORY
ESTABLISHED IH EGYPT.
MohuTom-Boj Factory, 171, Mahmoodleh Germ), Aloxandria."
Offloo in Cairo: Haret-ol-Maahadi (laraaiUab Quarter).
For 8*1.0 of Maatlo Aaphalle Block*, Trinidad HotUod Bitnmon,
Brick* in Compreaaed A*ph*lto for luring, Compreaaed A.-
phalte Roadway*. — Contractor* for orory description of
Aaphalte Work* in th* whole of Egypt.	35-65.16-7-00-
phsllo Road won. — Contractors ti
___Wa.6. In whole nf Re</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>A BROKEN-DOWN SYSTEM.
Tbii i. » condition (or dikeaie) to which doctor,
giro many um but which few of them roll,
undent*nd. It i, limply weakne—abreak-down,
re. of iho vital lore** that tuataln tho ayuem.
No matter wh*t may bo itt cum (for they ara *1.
moatnamberlMil.it, fy-mptem, are much the tame:
the more prominent being aleepleatneaa, *eo»e of
BTOrtratfon or wearine... deprewion of Iplritl and
want of energy for all tb. ordinary affair, of life.
Now, what alone itabaolutelyefaeetial In all nch
cate,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>VITAL STRENGTH A ENERGY
to throw ofl tbeae morbid feeling., and dptrienc*
prove, that a. night aueceeda the day thi. may bn
more certainly ircurcd by a court* of the cele-
brated Ufe-riming tonic
ipRAP!pN,N03
a. it fa taken in accordance with the printed
direction, accompanying it, will the .haltered
health be rctored,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE EXPIRING LAMP OF LIFE
LIGHTED UP AFRESH,
and a new existence imparted In place of what
had so lately teemed worn-out, " u»ed op," and
valueless, The wonderful medicament i. purely
vegetable and Jnnocuool. j. agreeable to the taste
—suitable for all eonrtilntion. and conditions, in
either iex; and it Is difficult to imagine a case of
disease or derangement, whose main feature, are
those of debility, that will not be speedily and
permanently benefited by this never failing men.
perative ettenee, which i. destined to cast into
everything that had preceded it for thi.
KWteE!PK££3
3V and 4/u Purchaser, should see that the word
•THE.artow; anpesr. „„ Bririlh Government
Stamp (In white letter- on a red rrnnndl affiled</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BOEHME & ANDERER. *
NEXT DOOR TO TUIIF CLUB,
CAIRO.
GREAT STOCK GF ACCOUNT BOOKS.
Speciality i
Account Books made to order.
ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS & MAGAZINES.
Rodcara Outlory.
® The Tosh
Whisky
Established 1736.
MACKINTOSH &C-
INVERNESS.
AGENTS:
M.ELEFTHERION&C*.
CAIRO & ALEXANDRIA.
Retailors.
E. J. FLET7RENT,
Square Halim Pacha, CAIRO.
“AU DE ROUGE.’
GENERAL DRAPERY ESTABLISHMENT.
(Central Tramway Station).</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CAIRO.
P. PL UNKETT
PROPRIETOR.
DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH
TEXTILE MANUFACTURES
On Sale.- Summer supply of Ladies’
and Gent#' pocket Handkerchiefs, made
in Ireland, from Irish flax, acknow-
ledged to be the best the world can
prodnoe.</p>
<p>All who know and are able to ap-
preciate the auperiorlty of the Irish
Linen, will tut nothing else as a
»nb»tjtut4.	«*’*• ">►.
ol Uii R.iplriiory Orpnt, thtblgtttivt Oryinj,
ftm.lt Orfint, Urlniry Syittm
irtd Rhtumailim, Gout, Aithmi.
Drlnklnf- gnd Baihtcurt.
Inhalations, Pntunutlc chimbtri gt(>
Protpetiui through the Kurkommlnlon.
Alutralwiicr (Kra.nchcnbrunntnl. Sail from iht Sprlngl,
Emt Pa.tillci to bo had tvtrywbtra</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>BON-ACCORD
Centrifugal Pumps,
DRIVEN BY
steam, electricity, gas. oil or belt,
FOR
IRRIGATION, DRAINAGE, DOCKS, etc.
Apply in Egypt, Cairo, and Alexandria,
A. ABOAF & C°, (where a slock is kept.)
DRYSDALE & Co.
Manufacturers
Bon-Accord Engine Works, Glasgow.
Telegrams \
"BON-ACCORD, GLASGOW,"
34386-7-1
Telephone :
A B C A LIBBER'S 2505 NATIONAL
CODE8. Y27B CORPORATION,
I/£2k and
Perrins’
Sauce.
By Royal Warrant
to
His Majesty the King.</p>
<div type="item"><p>THE ORIGINAL AND GENUINE WORCESTERSHIRE.
MOUNT LXBANON.
HOTEL VICTORIA.
Splendid climate. Grand Sienery. First class
accommodation. Moderate Terras. Highest
Sunlight
A great economiser and saver
of time, health, and strength.
Laundry worries went out of
woman's life when
Sunlight Soap
came into it.
It is the purest Soap going.
AXLY WEATfllSii
go changn in tha weather. Barometer .toady.
THX "KOVFTIAN OAZXTTX- IB PRINTKD ON
PAFXB MANUTACTIjaXD AND SUPPLIED
BY THE LONDON PAP EH MILLS Co, LIMITED
(BALES OFFICE : Zl. CANNON STREET, XO.)
The Egyptian Gazette
Aa Iagll.li Dally S.wip.per, EitahlUhad la 1880.
Editor & Manager: R. 8NXLLiHa.
Prloo ■ One Piastre Tariff.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SATURDAY, MAY 20. 1905.
SOME POLITICAL EFFECTS
OF THE WAR.
Whether the Czar continue the war to the
point of exhaustion, or, to use Moltke’a
tremendous phrase, till Russia is "blanched
or whether, making peace or a long truce, he
betakes himself to the reorganization of Russia,
for which he has scarcely the mental power,
the weight of Russia in international politics
must for twenty years be grievously diminished.
Her real policy for the last half century has
been to lay trains for future expansion, and
that policy, if her present Government survives,
must for a generation at least be suspended.
Revolution, it is true, might pour new blood
through her exhausted veins, and make her
once more a formidable fighting power; bat
failing revolution, her Government must devote
itself to the reorganisation of the Army, the
settlement of the terrible agrarian question,
the concession of personal liberty, and the
restoration of the national fortune. On every
side the mast be passive, as France was after
Sedan, and during that passive period there
will be changed of attitude in every one of tho
many States which she threatens, or upon
which she impinges. Her word, for example,
will no longer be final at Pekin. Whether the
vast Empire of China passes under Japanese
leadership, or accepts Anglo-Saxon guidance,
or is ruled by the great Vioeroys of the Sonth,
the dominance of Russia, which has been in
the way of every "improvement," from the
reorganisation of the Army to the construction
of arterial railways and the exploitation of
mineral wealth, will be for a period at an end.
The half-dozen men who in Pekin continuously
guide the Throne have been possessed with
the fear that, if Russia wore defied, she
would exert her military force, and termin
ate at once the traditions and the profits
ol the Manohu dynasty. Relieved of that
preoccupation, they must commence some new
course, be it reform as Europe understands
reform, or a stronger centralisation, or sub
mission to some Power or combination of
Powers not animated by the Russian spirit
or seeking Russian objects, which would
involve radical change in all Chinese political
methods. The straggle for the greatest market
left in the world is certain to contiijuo, hut
it will continue without the interference of
the Power which has hitherto secretly settled
all the conditions of the race.
This of itself is a great change, and it is
only one amongst many. There are many
indications at Constantinople that Turkey,
relieved for the moment from the pressure
of her secular foe, is tempted to trust once
more to the old policy of violence, which at
heart Pashas believe to be the only one
worthy of the children of the faith. The
Divan may cease to diplomatist, and may
strike at Bulgaria, at Greece, at its own rebels
in Macedonia and Albania, with armies, and
if it strikes with effect, will strike to
slaughter and to enslave. That would in the
end bring down on Turkey the forces of
civilization, and as those forces must have an
agent, the actual work of expelling her from
Europe must fall to Austria, who hopes always
for Salonicaaud a new trade, aided perhaps
by Italy. Russia will rage at the thought of
losing her predominance in the Balkans; but
if Russia is paralyzed, only Germany can
interfere, and Germany is much more likely to
bargain for her there of the spoil. No doubt
also the vigour of Germany will be increased
by a farther debacle, for she will be
relieved from that fear of invasion from two
sides which ever since 1875 has been the
controlling factor of her policy and her legisla-
tion. Her Government mast, for example,
attend more sincerely to the protests of her
people against heavier taxation ; she may find
in her savings on the Army the means of
perfecting her Fleet; and she will find the
desire of her people for greater freedom and
lighter discipline increased by the temporary
extinction of that dread which has made her
organization as a barrack seem even to her
intellectuals a necessary misfortune. As for
France, her only course is to exchange her
alliance with Russia for an alliance with Great
Britain, and try to become the motive-power
of a combination of herself, Great Britain, and
America, which should steadily seek to secure
the liberty of the nations and the general
peace of the world. Even our own country,
apart from this alliance, which grows naturally
out of the entente cordiale, will b£ greatly
affected by the suspension of ambition in
Russia. She will be comparatively free from
the fear of a European coalition, and will be
released from that preoccupation—the danger
of an invasion of India from the North—which
has lain at the root of many of her difficulties
in the reorganization of national detente. Her
only dangerous land frontier—for America
does not wish to obtain Canada by conqueet—
is that of India, and it will be for many years,
as it wore, protected instead of assailed by the
huge but necessarily motionless mass in the
North.</p>
<p>Many of these conseqnenoes may be slow in
developing themselves, bat they must, we think,
follow if Russia is seriously beaten without
being completely revolution. If, on the other
hand, she is revolutionized, as so many expect,
the result of defeat may be very different,
though at least as important to the world. A
free Russia, whether under a new dynasty or
the old one chastened by a terrible experience,
will still contain one hundred and fifty millions
of white men, all full of belief in the destiny of
the Slav race, and still debarred from free or
easy access to the waters of the World. Russia,
rilled in accordance with her popular instincts,
may—indeed, must—abandon the dream of
dominating the Pacific; bat it would be to
throw herself more earnestly, and therefore
successfully, into plans for forcing an entrance
into the Mediterranean, her natural outlet, tho
economic strength of Russia lying in her
Southern provinces, and obtaining, perhaps by
purobase.au ioe-frte entrance into tho Atlantic.
There is a possibility of half-a dozen wars in
those two projects ; yet it is certain that if
Russians were Englishmen, or Prenohmen, or
Germans, those are the two which would in-
fluence every popular agitator. They would
never consent to sit down imprisoned ; and wo
cannot conceive why the enormous and stead-
ily multiplying Slav race, when once it has
released itself from internal oppression, should
be expected to sit down either. Those however,
are the questions and dangers of tho future.
Por the moment tho paralysis of Russia must
release China, Turkey, Germany, and Gioat
Britain from enormous pressure, must solidify
the entente cordiale with France, and ought,
therefore, to give humanity a respite from its
person banned truce. It may not, for there is
a black cloud gathering in European Turkey -
perhaps too in Moroco—but if diplomacy lies
any executive power—has, that is, the power
of making dynasties and peoples act reason*
ably towards each other—it ought.</p></div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

