<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kedric Heyward</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-24">November 24, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-20">June 20, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7219] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, JUNE 20, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JAPANESE ADVANCE. RUSSIANS FALLING BACK. LINIEVITCH’S REPORT.</head>
                    <p>London, June 19. The ‘'Daily Telegraph” learns from Tokio that the Russians
                        are bringing up reserves to reinforce their forward lines, which are only 70
                        miles distant from General Kuroki’s outposts. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, June 19 The advance of the Japanese in Manchuria is general. The
                        Russians are retiring. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 19. General Linievitch reports that the Japanese force
                        which occupied Liaoyang-Woping consisted of a division of infantry, 30
                        squadrons of cavalry, and 4 batteries of artillery. The attack began at 2
                        and ended at 8 a.m., when the Russians were outflanked. He makes no
                        reference to losses, but adds that reports from Korea show that the Japanese
                        have advanced from Kongchan to Munsan. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DISEASE RAMPANT AT KHARBIN.</head>
                    <p>London, June 19. It is reported that cholera and dysentery are still raging
                        at Kharbin, where the death rate is 100 per diem. There are now 56,000 sick
                        and wounded in the hospitals there. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZEMSTVOS DEPUTIES. RECEIVED BY THE TSAR. NATIONAL ASSEMBLY TO BE CONVOKED.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 19. The Tsar received the members of the Zemstvos
                        to-day. There are no details.</p>
                    <p>(Later). The Tsar informed the deputation of Zemstvos that he is unalterably
                        resolved to convoke a National Assembly.</p>
                    <p>The deputation was fully official and included three deputies from St
                        Petersburg, Prince Troubetzkois addressed the Tsar for half-an-hour dwelling
                        on the melancholy state of Russia. The Tsar, deeply moved, said that he
                        regrets the enormous sacrifices caused by the war, particularly the defeat
                        of Toushima, and that the convocation of a National Assembly will be his
                        daily care. He hopes that the Zemstvos will from, to-day assist in the work
                        which will re unite Russia to the Tsar-dom. The delegates were pleased with
                        the reception they received. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 19. The Tsar has received the deputation of the Zemstvos
                        Congress. Prince Troubetzkoi explained the situation to him. The Tsar
                        expressed bis regret for the enormous sacrifices caused by the war and added
                        that his unshaken wish was to summon a National Assembly. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WARSAW JEWS DISTURBED. INDIGNATION MEETINGS.</head>
                    <p>Warsaw, June 19. The Jews here are extremely disturbed on account of the
                        report that the scheme for popular representation excludes them from the
                        right of franchise. Numerous indignation meetings have been held, which have
                        been dispersed bv the police and troops. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records four oases (two fatal) and a death in
                            hospital at Damanhour, one case at Toukh, and another at Ashmoun. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hashish Seizure</head>
                        <p>At the Custom-house yesterday twelve boxes filled with hashish were
                            discovered among the cargo from the S.S. “Spartan Prince"</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Monsky quarter of Cairo during tomorrow night and at
                            daylight on Thursday will he poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Execution of Mohamed Ali Naggar</head>
                        <p>condemned to death for the murder of Ali Ismail Abod Shati, will take
                            place at the prison of the Cairo Native Court of Appeal tomorrow. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Drowinng Accident</head>
                        <p>The body of the carpenter of the S.S. “Clio,” who fell overboard in
                            Alexandria harbour a few days ago, was recovered yesterday and sent to
                            hospital for the usual coroner’s inquest.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alexandria Police</head>
                        <p>Local Kaimakams G. Cobbe Bey and M. Moberly Bey, Assistant Commandant of
                            Police in Alexandria and Cairo, respectively, have been granted the
                            commission of Kaimakam.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>12 vessels passed through the Canal on the 16th inst., 8 of which were
                            British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Turkish. The day’s receipts were frs.
                            316,290:63, making the total from 1st inst. frs. 4,457,664.75.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Unknown Forces</head>
                        <p>We may remind our readers of the fact that on Thursday next, Prof, de
                            Lafontaine, the hypnotist, will give his first seance at the Eden
                            Theatre, assisted by his Creole mediums from Mauritius.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Killed by a Fish</head>
                        <p>A fisherman, while fishing near Shebin el Com, caught a fish and held it
                            in his teeth. The man, being engaged in collecting his fish from the
                            net, relaxed his jaws and the fish darted down his throat, suffocating
                            him almost immediately.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Execution of a Parricide</head>
                        <p>Mahmoud Ibrahim Eid El Gazar, of Ballabish, Baliana district, suffered
                            the last penalty of the law this morning at the prison of the Native
                            Court of Appeal, Cairo. It will be remembered that the man was found
                            guilty of the murder of his father near Deyrout in September, 1904.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Measles in Upper Egypt</head>
                        <p>An outbreak of measles is reported from villages in the Esna district.
                            Orders have been issued by the Ministry of the Interior that all cases
                            are to be notified under penalty of fine and that owners of esheshes or
                            huts where cases occur are to limewash their dwellings and provide them
                            with such openings as the district inspector may deem necessary.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Attempted Murder</head>
                        <p>At 9 p.m. yesterday an Armenian local subject in company with a Greek
                            attacked a Greek barber in the Eastern Telegraph-street, striking him
                            across the face with a stick and attempting to stab him. The barber made
                            a successful resistance and overpowered his would-be murderer, who was
                            arrested, together with his confederate. It appears that the Armenian
                            had previously threatened to murder the barber.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT. ANDRAOUS’S ANTECEDENTS.</head>
                    <p>Let us hope that Andraous Meloka has no rivals in his art. A thief, who can
                        board a moving train and drop off with his booty unobserved and uninjured,
                        is a redoubtable opponent of society in general and the Railway
                        Administration in particular. We are now assured that Andraous was never
                        employed by the railway authorities. He certainly appears to have given them
                        a good deal of employment, for was not he condemned to six years
                        imprisonment in 1895 for a series of daring and ingenious train robberies ?
                        Now we are assured that he was employed by the police, no doubt on the
                        principle of set a thief to catch a thief but the report is unfounded.
                        Andraous’ time has been too much taken up of late years. Condemned for
                        burglary in 1888 by the Native Court of Appeal, he took to train robbery on
                        his release from prison until 1895. After being employed for some years in
                        the buildings of the Prisons Department he returned to the world and stole
                        jewels at Shoubra. Six months and life at Assiout under the observation of
                        the authorities were the result, and now, Andraous has performed his boldest
                        and his last exploit.</p>
                    <p>He denied any participation in the crime before the Parquet, but that was
                        only to be expected. His confederates also denied it, which was rather
                        remarkable, for the honor that is said to exist among thieves seldom
                        prevents at least one member of a gang from giving the authorities full
                        information of his comrades misdeeds when he has been laid by the beels.</p>
                    <p>"Cherchez la femme” was the motto of the Parquet, and on Sunday Andraous’
                        wife appeared for examination. Her statement was clear, enough. Four months
                        ago her husband came home with Makarius and Ibrahim Ashour, told his wife
                        not to disturb them, and shut himself up with his friends. With the
                        curiosity of her sex the Sitt Meloka listened and heard the clinking of
                        coin. The trio were obviously dividing the "swag.”</p>
                    <p>Andraous had made a capital error in not sending his wife out of the house or
                        looking her in her room. He was soon to make another. After seeing his
                        friends off the premises he presented his spouse with a handkerchief full of
                        sovereigns and bade her guard them. A few days later he made a hole in the
                        wall and there hid a tin box containing the coins; sis wife wondered where
                        they came from, and Andraous weakly told the story and sealed his fate.</p>
                    <p>Mansfield Pasha and Goubran Bay Moskat have supplied Mr. Machell with the
                        results of the inquiry up to date. The decision of the Ministry of War, with
                        regard to the members of the military escort which was of such little use in
                        guarding the treasure, may be deferred till the enquiry has brought to light
                        all the circumstances of the robbery.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMLEH BOULEVARD BURGLARY.</head>
                    <p>It is evident from the way in which the safe at Mr. Caffari’s office has been
                        prised open that it was a job which occupied five hours.</p>
                    <p>A gentleman, who passed by at about 1 p.m., states that he saw a light in the
                        office through the Windows. The ghaffir invariably knocks at the door, when
                        owing to press of work the office has been occupied and lighted up to 10
                        p.m. It is curious that on the night in question he did not notice anything,
                        and his conduct is suspicions.</p>
                    <p>The wholesale value of the silver stolen from the plate stores is L.E.
                        54.</p>
                    <p>Two men, a Greek and a native, have been arrested on suspicion of being the
                        thieves.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RED SEA WRECKS. BRITISH CRUISER RENDERING AID</head>
                    <p>From our Correspondent). Suez, Mondav. The Anchor Line steamer "Massilia,”
                        which arrived at Suez this morning from Bombay, reported that the British
                        steamer "Foyle,” from Rangoon, was badly ashore in the Red Sea south of
                        Hanish island, near Gebel Zuhur. As I stated in my telegram this morning, I
                        understand that this steamer has a full cargo of rice for Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The "Foyle” is apparently in a very bad position, and several native dhows
                        were sighted in the vicinity ; they are supposed to be pirates. A British
                        cruiser was proceeding at the time towards the wreck to render
                        assistance.</p>
                    <p>The other rice steamer "Helen Rickmers,” is still fast near Ras Garib, viz.,
                        14 miles south of the lighthouse, and has a heavy list The Khedivial Mail
                        liner "Rahmanieh,” which left Suez last Saturday night with lighters and
                        labourers, is now rendering assistance and receiving cargo discharged from
                        the wreck. The weather is continuing good, and salvage operations are
                        progressing favorably.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BROTHERS ISLAND LIGHTHOUSE. TO BE PULLED DOWN.</head>
                    <p>The present lighthouse on the Brothers Island (in the Red Sea) is about to be
                        palled down, and a larger one erected in its place, with a more powerful
                        light.</p>
                    <p>The work will be commenced on, or shortly after, October 1 next, when the
                        present light will be discontinued, and in its place two lamps, each showing
                        a fixed white light, will be placed one at either end of the island.</p>
                    <p>These lights will each be about 1,000 candle power and hung on poles about 30
                        feet high.</p>
                    <p>The new light will be white, flashing.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THEWFIKIEH NILE COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>The affairs of the above company seem again to be causing quite a ferment in
                        some native circles in Cairo in consequence of the non-fulfilment of their
                        duties by the two liquidators appointed last October as well as the action
                        taken lately by some former shareholders in instituting proceedings before
                        the Mixed Tribunals for the recovery of the money paid for shares, on the
                        ground that the shares were sold through wilful misrepresentation on the
                        part of the former board of directors. Besides the shareholders there are
                        innumerable creditor clamouring for settlement of their accounts who for
                        some time after the company stopped payment were kept quiet with the promise
                        that the late Menshawi Pasha would liquidate all outstanding debts and take
                        over the whole concern to work himself. These promises not being fulfilled,
                        and the liquidators having neglected to carry out their mandate, matters
                        have again assumed an acute stage.</p>
                    <p>The civil action of' the shareholders was before the Courts last Saturday and
                        has been set down for hearing after the vacation. At the same time criminal
                        proceedings, as we have already announced, will be begun against the members
                        of the former board, when some very sensational disclosures regarding the
                        financing of the late Thewfikieh Nile Navigation Company are expected to be
                        made public.</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUPPLY FROM ARTESIAN WELLS.</head>
                    <p>The Cairo Water Company is now supplying water to the principal districts
                        from seven artesian wells, fire of which are worked from engines at
                        Rod-el-Farag and two from the Bonlae engines. The districts so supplied are
                        Shoubra, Boulac, Fagallah, Esbekieh, Ismailia, and Kasr-el-Aiui, whilst the
                        Abbassieh, Gamalieh, Darb-el-Abmar, Khalifa, and Saida Zenab districts still
                        receive their water supply through the Abbassieh filters.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Bitter is occupied in making an analysis of the water which comes from
                        the artesian wells, so that at present we cannot give any information as to
                        the quality of the water and its purity, but we will publish the results of
                        Dr. Bitter’s investigation as soon as they are completed. As regards the
                        quantity of the water, 65,000 cubic metres are being daily pumped through
                        the Cairo mains, of which 25,000 cubic metres come from the seven artesian
                        wells in use and 40,000 cubic metres pass through the Abbassieh filters. Two
                        more wells at Rod-el-Farag are being prepared, and it is anticipated that
                        these will be completed in four months’ time; and should the system prove to
                        be thoroughly satisfactory after two years’ trial the number of wells will
                        be increased to sixteen.</p>
                    <p>The supply of water to Zeitoun cpmes from a special well in that locality,
                        but unfortunately it has proved very deficient as regards quantity, and the
                        Water Company has no hopes of improving the conditions for another two
                        months, by which time they will have another engine working and so double
                        the present supply. In laying the plant for the Zeitoun supply the company
                        estimated that it would not be necessary to exceed the amount supplied to
                        Assiout (2,500 cubio metres per day) and they accordingly constructed an
                        engine capable of pumping 3,000 cubic metres per day, and Zeitoun is now
                        receiving that quantify, the engine being kept working throughout the 24
                        hours. Meanwhile the remedy lies in the hands of the residents, and if they
                        refrain from using the large quantities which are at present being used for
                        watering the gardens, they will find that the supply is ample for domestic
                        purposes. It must be remembered that the sandy soil of Zeitonn will absorb
                        almost any quantity of water and it is evident that the amount so wasted is
                        considerable.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO WATER SUPPLY. KHEDIVIAL LAW SCHOOL.</head>
                    <p>The following advertisement has been despatched to the London newspapers :—
                        The Egyptian Ministry of Public Instruction invites applications for two
                        posts of lecturers In the English section of the above-mentioned School.
                        Salary £615, rising to £830. Candidates must be University Men, having
                        either a Law Degree or other legal qualification, and must have a moderate
                        know ledge of French. They will be required in the first instance to Lecture
                        (in English) on Jurisprudence, Roman Law, or Political
                        Economy.—applications, stating ago and qualifications, accompanied by copies
                        only of Testimonials, should be made by letter to M. Sheldon An os, Esq. If
                        posted In London not later than June 17, 1901, they should be addressed to
                        the Native Court of First Instance, Cairo. Later applications should be
                        addressed to St. Ermin’s Hotel, Westminster. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>T. H. the Princess Said Halim and Hussein Kamel, with many notables, have
                        called upon the Grand Mufti at his residence in Ramleh. </p>
                    <p>Lord Dormer, who arrived in Egypt on the 31st May in connection with a new
                        land company that is being formed, is returning to England to-day, by way of
                        Marseilles, by the P.O. steamer "Persia.”</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>RAISING THE CONGAL.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Port Said, Monday.</dateline><p> The caisson round the sunken
                        S.S. "Congal” was completed by Sunday morning. It is composed of 2-inch deal
                        and pine planks and is shored from side to side and to the deck with balks
                        of heavy timber jointed at the bleak edges and well caulked. At 10 a.m.
                        yesterday the pumping was started, divers being in attendance. Several
                        times, however, work had to be stopped to allow of alterations being made.
                        All night pumping continued, and this morning a large centrifugal pump was
                        got to work under the ship to wash away the mud which had formed along her
                        side. At about 11 a.m. the vessel suddenly lifted aft about a foot and
                        steadily from then on she lifted. She now is (8 p.m.) well up aft, but the
                        bow still remains touching the bottom. The dry-dock is ready to receive her
                        the moment her draft of water will allow, and it is expected that by evening
                        she will be ready to be put in the dock. The cost of raising the vessel will
                        amount to £1,400.</p>
                    <p>MORE RUSSIAN REFUGEES I learn from an official source that 33,000 more
                        Russian refugees am to return from Port Arthuron parole. Four
                        Hamburg-American vessels are chartered already. One of them, the "Trave,” is
                        now in Port Said and leaves for the East today.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAPTURE OF HASHISH.</head>
                    <p>Three or four days ago, a large haul of hashish was made by the coastguards
                        here. The smugglers were traced by their footprints in the sand some
                        considerable distance from the canal bank a little north of Ismailia and the
                        hashish, from 650 to 700 kilos, was discovered by the coastguards bidden in
                        a field. The smugglers have not been caught so far.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB (ALEX.).</head>
                        <p>The 3rd spoon competition of the season was shot off on Saturday last The
                            wind was strong and at times changeable. The following are some of the
                            qualifying scores:</p>
                        <p>1st Class 200 500 600 yds. yds. yds. TotaL Lucas, W. 29 33 29 91 Winner
                            Dickson, H.F. 31 27 29 87</p>
                        <p>3rd Class. 200 500 600 yds. yds. yds. Total Millar, F.G. 30 24 16 70
                            Winner Lovell, G.D. 22 23 15 60 Radcliffe, LE. 23 22 12 57</p>
                        <p>In the 2nd class no one turned up to shoot Members are reminded that
                            there will be practice as usual on Saturday next, commencing at 3
                            o’clock.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB</head>
                        <p>REGATTA The times of starting and handicap for tomorrow are the same as
                            last week. Class I. will be Coarse F and Class II. Course Q.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">

                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
