<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-11-07</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-05-15</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, MAY 15, 1935.</head>
<div type="item"><p>THE TYPEWRITER FOR BEAUTIFUL WORK.
Hat no Ribbon.
Swift, Quiet and Convenient
Illustrated Booklet post free.
Typo itr Hurt paper at in ordinary printing.
Made of Best Materials only.
The Yost Typewriter Co., Ltd.,
50, Holbom Viaduct, London, E.C.</p>
<div type="item"><p>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY.
CELEBRATIONS IN CAIRO.
From an early hour on Saturday morning
until the small hours of Sunday the streets
of Cairo were thronged by a crowd of holiday
makers celebrating the centenary of the foun-
dation of the Mohamed Aly dynasty, and as
the day wore on and evening approached the
crowds grew thicker and thicker, until, when
the hour of illumination had arrived, it ap-
peared as if every inhabitant of this great
city had turned out to take part in the
rejoicings, so great was the crush. The day
was intensely hot and a khamseen wind was
blowing from the south. The night was but
little cooler than the day, but the heat
seemed to have little effect on the huge
crowds.</p>
<p>All the main streets and buildings were
gorgeously decorated, and wherever one went
a fine display of bunting met the eye. The
streets appeared to be one mass of Venetian
masts wound round by fronds of the palm
tree and surmounted by the Ottoman flag,
and from mast to mast were bound festoons
of green leaves hung with numerous Chinese
lanterns. The triumphal arches at either end
of Abdeen-street were outlined by electric
bulbs of varied colours and the star and cres-
cent stood out prominently on either side
of each arch. The Ibrahim Pasha statue, in
Opera-square, was surrounded by vast white
columns from the top of which the Ottoman
flag proudly waved,and were heavily festooned
in the same manner As the masts. In the
main street Shepheard's and the Continental
Hotels were notable for the profuseness ot
their decorations, and the number of flags,
representing almost every nation, which hung
from their windows; while the offices of the
Gas Company were most effectively and bril-
liantly illuminated and attracted a great deal
of attention and admiration.</p>
<p>It was not, however, until we reached the
Nile bridge that we saw the finest effects, for
the scenery of this vicinity especially lends
itself tb decoration and illumination. No finer
sight than the one which met our eye when
wo arrived hero on our way to the greit fete
at Ghezireh could be imagined. The bridge was
decorated in the same manner as the streets,
that is, with Venetian masts at close intervals,
and from the masts of one side to those of the
other side hong a perfect plethora of Chinese
lanterns. Below lay the historic Nile, and glid-
ing to and fro on its bosom were a number of
dahabiehs brilliantly illuminated in variegated
colours, whilst in front stretched the promenade
with its dark background lit by gorgeous
lights. It was indeed a grandiose spectacle.
At 7.30 p.m. a procession of school boys was
formed at the Citadel and proceeded to Ghezi-
reh via Mohamed-Aly street, Opera-square,
Abdeen-street, Abdeen-sq^e, Sharieh Abdel
Aziz and the Nile Bridge. The boys, who were
divided into detachments according to their
schools, carried coloured lanterns and Ottoman
flags, and were preceded by torch-bearers,
marched along to the accompaniment of a
schoolboy’s band, and helped to make the pro-
cession a merry one by frequent bursts into
song. As the procession continued they became
closer and closer hemmed in by the crowd, and
the police had a hard task to keep the way
clear for them. They reached the Ghezireh pro-
menade at a quarter past nine and after
marching three times round the stand erected
for notabilities, and the tent in which the
speeches of the evening were made, dispersed.
A large crowd had assembled at Ghezireh to
wi toons the events of the evening, and Mans-
field Pasha, the officers of the police, and the
policemen themselves must be congratulated
on the order which was maintained, A great
number of carriages were allowed into the
grounds and greatly increased the possibility
of danger to the numerous pedestrians, but as
far as can bo ascertained at present no acci-
dents occurred.</p>
<p>The bands of the Inniskilling Fusiliers and
the Egyptian Cavalry were in attendance and
played alternately throughout the evening,
and there was also a native band which played
almost incessantly. In the centre of the
promenade a large stand was erected, and at its
side was the reception that in which the
speeches of the evening were delivered. The
first speech was in Arabic and was delivered
by Ibrahim Halbaouj Bey, and the French
speech was delivered by Maltre Manusardi.
His Highness the Khedive was represented by
Prince Ibrahim Pasha Helmy, on whose ar-
rival at a quarter to nine the Khedivial
Anthem was played.</p>
<p>As the gorgeously illuminated dahabiehs
wended their way to and fro on the short
stretch of the river in front of the promenade,
they kept the air lively with the blowing of
whistles and syrens, and every now and then
their decks would become blue, red, or
green from the blaze of Bengal lights, or would
tend a rocket whizzing into the air.
I	On the conclusion of the speeches the dis-
play of fireworks took place, and excellent it
was. Rockets, squibs, Roman candles, Cathe-
rine wheels, and every kind of work Imagine
ble followed each other in quick succession,
and the display was terminated by a set-piece
in which Mohamed Aly was figured sitting on
horseback, whilst a splendid effect was given
by a series of coloured lights on the Mokattam
Hills.</p>
<p>The pyrotechnic display being ended, the
signal was given for the formation of a torch-
light procession which made its way back to
town headed by a detachment of Egyptian
Cavalry and accompanied by the Egyptian
Band.</p>
<p>Thus was the memorable day ended, and the
committee who were charged with the respon-
sibility of making the arrangements and fixing
the programme can congratulate themselves
on achieving a great success.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE ANARCHIST ARREST AT CAIRO.
Great interest has been aroused in Italy by the
news of the recent arrest at Cairo of Jaffei, one
of the alleged accomplices of Bresci, the assassin
of King Humbert, although the prisoner is
not the most important among those who even
indirectly participated in the murder. Vittorio
Jaffei is aged twenty-seven, and began his
career as a Customs guard. In this capacity
he met Anarchists along the Swiss frontier,and
was converted to their doctrines. He then
deserted into Switzerland,where he met Bresci,
and plotted with him the crime, after the
committal of which, on a report from the
Italian authorities, he was arrested at Berne,
bat after a long discussion between Italy
and Switzerland was not surrendered to
the Italian police, because the Swiss law of
extradition, which is very liberal, forbade it,
although Jaffei was also accused of having
threatened the life of the present King. Jaffei
did not feel safe in Switzerland, and as soon aid
he was set at liberty left for Africi, and went
to Zanzibar, where he became a Mohamedan.
But he aroused the suspicion of Signor Merca-
telli, Italian Consul-General there, who is an
ex-journalist, and was in Italy at the time of
the crime. Signor Mercatelli had him watched
until the police, having sufficient evidence,
arrested him at Cairo, although he was dis-
guised as a priest</p>
<p>The chief accomplice of Bresci was a man
named Luigi Granotti. He came from Paterson,
New Jersey, with Bresci, and they stationed
themselves at each exit to the enclosure where
King Humbert was, with the intention of
killing him. The King left by Bre3ci’s side,
whereupon Granotti disappeared completely, •
and has never been traced.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE PIGMIES AT CAIRO.
In the House of Commons Earl Percy, reply-
ing to Sir Brampton Gordon, stated that the
attention ot the Mkrquis of Lansdowne had
been called to the proposed importation of
pigmies from the Congo Forest His Majesty’s
Government had no legal power to prevent
the introduction ot the pigmies into Eogland
in the absence of proof that compulsion
had been used, bat Colonel Harrison, who
was bringing them over, had been informed
that their importation for purposes of exhibi-
tion was very undesirable, and must be entirely
on his own responsibility and at his own
risk. Colonel Harrison had undertaken that
they would be well cared for and eventually
returned to their own country.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>UPPER NILE EXPEDITION.
According to a telegram from Wadelai,
Major Powell-Cotton, who is on an expedition
from the Nile to the Zambesi, has arrived there.
He left the Lado Enclave for the Congo Forest
at the end of February.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>NILE VALLEY COMPANY.
The following news has been received from
the mine manager, dated Allagui, 3rd inst,
giving the return for the month of April:
‘Twenty-two tons of ore crashed yielded 278oz.,
7owt. of specimens gave 2,991oz. Ore crushed
includes fines from specimens. Struck vein in
crosscut No. 5 8haft to-day, distance from shaft
55ft. The quartz is 1ft. Sirs, wide; not yet
assayed."</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CORPORATION OF WESTERN
EGYPT.
At a meeting of the board of directors of the
Corporation of Western Egypt (Ltd.) hold on
the 3rd inst it was unanimously decided,
having regard to the fact that the corporation
has in baud ample funds (being cash at ban-
kers’, moneys on deposit, and investments in
first class soourities) for all purposes, to post-
pone for the present the final call of 6s. per
share. The usual three months' notice will be
given to shareholder! when the cell is made</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ARMY AND NAVY.
(From our Correspondent).
London, day 6.
Captain N. T. Borton, Royal Warwick Regi-
ment, who for the past eight yea: s was attached
to the Egyptian Army, has elected to go on
retired pay, after fifteen years’ service. He was
with the Warwicks in the Khartoum expedition
of 1897-98, and was mentioned in despatches
for his services at the battle of Omdurman. He
was recently employed as Inspector of Prisons
in Egypt</p></div>
<p>The 2nd Battalion the Buffs, at Bulford
Camp, has been ordered to embark early next
month for the Cape, from where it returned a
couple of ye-re ago. This battalion was ori-
ginally put under orders for Egypt, then for
India, and in this year’s trooping programme
it was placed on the roster for a spell of service
if Malta. On arrival at the Cape it will proceed
to Harriamith, 0. R. C.</p>
<p>Next month the 1st Battalion Royal Innis-
killing Fusiliers will have a regimental march
thongh . Connty Donegal, which forms part of
the 27th Regimental Distriot The Loogh-
Swilly locality will be visited. It may be re-
membered that last year the battalion marohed
through a large part of the counties ot
Londonderry and Tyrone with very good recruit-
ing results The move of the Inniskillings to
Belfast will not take place till the antumn.
The 12-inch Mark VIII. wire gun, which
has come in for such severe criticism recently,
is an accurate weapon of enormous range and
energy. Without its mornings it weighs 45
tons and it measures 37 feet in length and its
calibre, as its name indicates, is 12 inches. The
projectile weighs 850 lbs. and it is propelled
on its course by the explosion of 167 lbs. of
cordite with sufficient force to pierce eight
inches oi Krnpp armour at 3,000 yards, and it
has an effective range of nearly 11 miles. In
the construction of these guns several miles of
steel wire are required. The wire is wound on
a stoel tube which is rifled to take the pro-
jectile. This tube seems to be the weak part of
the gun. The tube wears out in the ordinary
coarse through erosion and the enormous velo-
city of the projectile, which passes through it
at the rate of 2,400 feet per second, and in the
case of the “Majestio’s" guns the tubes split.
This in no way affects the safety of the gun as
it is constructed to withstand the explosion
of the charge without the tube. The latter can
be replaced very cheaply, and that gives the
gnn a new lease of life. In the battleships of
the “Kiog Edward" class this gun has been
increased to 56 tons.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>PUMPS IN EGYPT.
Mr. John Gwynne writes as follows to
"African Engineering:’’—
Our attention has been called to a state
ment in a recent issue of the “Times" Engineer-
ing Supplement, in which their Egyptian
correspondent alleges the superiority of French
over British pumps for Egyptian require-
ments.</p>
<p>As a firm who, for many years past, have
made a speciality of pumping machinery for
Egypt and the Sudan, and have made personal
investigation of requirements on tho spot, we
would like to point out that the above allega-
tion has no foundation whatever on fkot
Thongh French and Swiss makers have supplied
pumping installations, the results as to effi-
ciency in these foreign plants are not to be
compared to those of the best British makers.
We are satisfied that we can deliver more
water for the coal consumed than any of these
Continental makers. It is possible that the
Egyptian correspondent of the ‘Times" is not
a technical man, and the only excuse for his
statement that we can suggest is, either that
he has been misled on the subject of coal oon-
sumod, or that he has taken a Continental
plant in conjunction with which a super-
heater is used, and compared it with a British
plant which is not provided with a superheater.
A superheater, of course, applied to a pumping
installation, from whatever sonroe that installa-
tion may emanate, will effect a saving of ooal,
bat whether the expense and wear and tear of
six months’ working of these machines will pay
for the saving effected is a question. Users in
Holland have probably had a larger experience
in this class of pumping plant than anyone
else, and it is to be presumed that were there
anything in this contention, tho Dutch would
have availed themselves of this practice. The
foot, too, that in Holland British pnmp makers
hold the market, in spite of the proximity of
Holland to the Continental manufacturers, is
a clear proof of the superiority of British
pnmpa.</p>
<p>The report prepared for the Egyptian Go-
vernment by Mr. A L. Webb in 1897, and
published by the National Printing Press, of
Cairo, clearly shows that “Invincible" pumping
engines have given a higher efficiency than
any machines in that country.
On page 216 of Sir William Willoooks’,
C. M. G., work, “Egyptian Irrigation," pub-
lished in 1889, he says:—
"Indeed, if it were not that the quality of
English engines is so high, and the Gwynne’s
pumps themselves nearly indestructible, pump-
ing machinery would have secumbed to the
Persian wheels."</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>LAND AND MORTGAGE OF EGYPT.
The directors of the above company recom-
mend a dividend at the rate of 11 percent.
for the six months ended March 81, making
with the interim dividend 10 per cent for the
year. This compared with 9 per cent, for the
previsional year</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SPORT AND PLAY.
ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.
SECOND SUMMER MEETING.
The following are the handicaps for the
2nd Summer Meeting :—
1st Day, 25th May.
May Handicap.—Omar Bey Sultan and
Bakn Bey’s g.a.h. Rachid, 10.4 ; Ishack Bey
Hussein’s ch.a.p. Farhan II., 10.2, and b.a.p.
Moofid, 10.0 ; Hussein Bey Sionfi and Mr. A.
J. Michaelides’ b.a.h. Mashkour, 9.10 ; Mo-
harrem Pasha Chehim’s g.a.g. Mizzaud, 9.8 ;
Ibrahim Bey Cherifa. c.a.h. Gladiateur, 9.7 ;
and b.a.h. Valentino, 9.7 ; Mr. P. W. Stoat’s
g.a.h. Shewiman, 9.10 ; Capt. G. B. Byrne’s
ch.a.h. Fitz, 8.0; Mr. £ Karam's ch.a.b.
Cwor de Lion, 8.7 ; Mr. A. J. Sursock’s b.a.b.
Roi de l'Air, 11.7, and oh.a.h. Vinicius, 9.0,
Khalil Pasha Khayat’s g.a.h. Banaback, 10.10,
and g.a.p. Sadik, 8.13 ; Hassan Pasha Moh-
sen’s b.a.h. Gogo, 9.0.
2nd Day, 27th May.</p>
<p>Khedivial Club Cup.—Omar Bey Saltan
and Ahmed Bey Bakri’s g.a.h. Rachid, 10.0 ;
Prince Omar Pasha Tousaoun’sg.e.o.b.h. Fahd,
10.7 and br.e.c.br.h. Monftakhar, 10.10;
Bey Hussein's b.a.h. Moofid, 9.7 ; Moharrem
Pasha Chehin’s br.e.c.b.h. Mabronk, 10.7 ;
Hussein Bey Sionfi and Mr. A. J. Miohaelidea’
b.a.h. Mashkour, 9.3 ; Ibrahim Bey Cherif s
o.a.L Gladiatenr, 9.0, and b.a.h. Valentino,
9.0 ; Hassan Pasha Mohsen’s e.o.b.h. Good
Day, 11.0 and b.a.h. Gogo, 8.7.
Owners’ Handicap.— Prince Omar Pasha
Tonssoun’a g.a.p. Kohailan, 8.0, and b.a.h.
Hadban, 8.0 ; Omar Bey Saltan and Bakri
Bey’s c-a.p. Saad Doghan, 8.0, and g.a.p.
Kohilan Taier, 8.0 ; Capt G. GRlson’s gj^h.
Sirnr, 8.10 ; Saleh Bey Yaghen’s b.a.p. Abon
Arkoub, 8.3 and oa.p. Ide, 8.0 ; Ishaok Bey
Hussein’s o.a.p. Farhan II, 11.7 and g.a.p.
Saber, 10.2 ; Khalil Pasha Khayat’s gAp.
Latiff, 10.0, g-a.p. An Revoir, 9.8, and g.a.p.
Sadik, 10.6 ; Moharrem Pasha Chehin’s g.a.p.
Agib, 9.4 ; Mr. M. Tneni’s b.a.p. Caprice, 10.2,
b.a.p. Viking, 8.5, and g.a.h. Petrone, 8.7 ;
Elie Bey 8arsook's and Mr. Tneni’s b.ah.
Amory, 8.5 ; Mr. £ Karam’s c.a.h. Nimrod,
8.0,	and o.a.h. Eclipse, 8.10 ; Ibrahim Bey
Cherifs b.a.p. St Frusquin, 9.4 ; Ibrahim Bey
Cherif and Elie Bey 8araook’s b.a.p. Mikado,
9.4 ; Mr. A. J. Sursock’s b.a.p. Sans Pareil,
9.0,	and g.a.p. Royal Oak, 8.0; Mr. £ Bustros'
g.a.p. Roland, 9.12, and g.a.p. Mephisto, 8.0 ;
Mr. J. Chalom’s g.a.p. Fahr, 8.0.
CRICKET.</p>
MR<p>MARSDEN’S XI. ». E. T. C.
A return match was commenced between
Mr. Marsden’s XI. and the £ T. C. on Satur-
day, 13th inst, and ended in a draw.
The £ T. C. batted first aid Messrs.
Cheesmsn and Stacey put up 99 before being
separated. For the A. C. C., Mr. Macaulay
played well for 67. Scores :—
£ T. C.
Mr. Stacey, b. Aubrey................. 63
„ Cheesman, c.Mustard, b. Aubrey... 51
„ Collier, b. Aubrey.................... 4
„	R. MoLean,	b. Marsden............ 13
„	Hanley, run	out ................... 9
„ Thurston, Lb.w., b. Aubrey.........	0
„ G. MoLean, 0. Mnstard, b. Marsden 15
„ Henley, b. Aubrey..................... 12
„ Harvey, Lb.w., b. Mustard ......... 0
„	Scarth, not	out ................... 21
„	Incledon, b.	Marsden ................ l
Extras .................................. 13
Total	........... 202
Mr. Marsden’s XI.
Mr. Morrison, b. R. MoLean............ 7
„ Weodon, b. £ MoLean................ l
„ A. Mnstard, 0. Stacey, b. Henley... 1
„ Aubrey, a Cheesman, b. R. MoLean. 3
„ Macaulay, b. Stacey	............ 67
„ Dawson, b. Thurston	...	  22
„ Dorling, st Hanley, b.	Henley	1
„ Diokins, not out ...................... 9
„ Lowick, not out ...................... 1
„ Pappo, did not bat.................
„ T. H. Marsden, b. Scarth ............. 38
Extras .................................. 7
Total for eight wickets	........... 157</p>
<p>Calendar of Coming Events
„ ALEXANDRIA.
May.
Mon. 15 Alhambra. Italian operetta 00m-
pany. 9 p.m.
Tuee. 16 Behera Co.'s Offioes. Extraordinary
General Meeting. 8.80 p.m.
Sat 20 San Stefano Casino. Opening Ball
of Season.
Race from Sidi Gaber to Alexandria
by pupils of Sootoh Softool. 6p.m.
8nn. 21 San Stefano Casino. Conoert 10 a.m.
Gabbari. Pigeon Shooting. 2.30 p.m.
Tubs. 28 San Stefano Casino. A. LM. &
D. S. Conoert. 9.15 p.m.
Than. 25 A. S. 0. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting.
Sat 97 A. S. C. grounds. 2nd Sommer
Meeting.
OAI RO.
May.
Tuee. 16 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
British Military Band. 9 to 11
p.m.
Pri. 19 Zoological Gardens. Performance by
Ghiuh Boys' Band in afternoon.
Esbekieh Gardens. Performance
by British Military Band. 9 to
11 p.Di</p>
<p>Cheap Prepaid Advertisements
Under this heading advertisements are in
sorted at the following rates :—
ONCE 8 TIKES 6 TIME-
15 words . . . P.T.	5	P.T.	10	P.T.	15
30 words ...	„	8	„	16	„	24
Every 10 words, \	?	,	.
beyond 30. . . / ”	2	-*	4	••	6
The address is counted. The advertisement
must appear on consecutive days for above
rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged
for advertisements not appearing consecutively.
All such advertisements must be prepaid, and
to this rule no exception whatever will
be made. Letters in reply to advertise-
ments will be posted to any address If a
few stamps are sent by the advertiser to
cover postage.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>A QA&US INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES XL AND TRADE MARKS REGISTER, - of all important bonnets firms oi Gnat Britain lha Continent, aid Egypt t Ch eclating an over Europe and America. Pries—One pound Sterling. Poet Free. AGARVB INTERNATIONAL HOTEL GUIDE sent poet free to all fint elate Hotels throughout Europe, America, the Colonies and Egypt. The best reftnoee book for traveller!.
ADVERTISING AGENTS.—1The best public Advertising sites in Alexandria belong to G. Vestri & Co., Advt Agents, St Catherine's Square. Special rates for permanent clients. Moderate terms. Prompt despatch. 25642-31-12-905
A RABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Snefik, "Egyptian Gazette’^ offices.	26888-
EXPERIENCED NURSE would take charge L of infant for free passage to England June, July. Apply, No. 25,949, "Egyptian Gazette” Office.	26949-6-2
EOR SALE.—Cart, Donkey, and Harness. A £25. Apply, No. 25,952, “ Egyptian Gazette” Offioe.	25952-6-2 (GENUINE PANAMA HATS for sales, very u good quality, very cheap prioe. At Mal- luk’s, Moubky, Cairo.	25959-12-1
TNSTITUTR1CE de Saint Mary’s Cairo dd- A sire situation poor lee vacances. Prdfdrerait voyager. S'adresser an Direoteur. 25928-6-6
T ANCASTER HOUSE Sharia Wabonrel- AJ Moyah, Cairo. Comfortable apartments, with or without board. Terms very reasonable. 25699-15-6-905A
FOUNTAIN CAMP, for boys daring sum- HA mer holidays. Apply, Peroival Mayall, B.A., Headmaster, English School, Cyprus. 25921-48-7
RINGING LESSONS recommended by the J famous tenor Jban de Reszke given by ierr B. Weohsler of Heidelberg University. Voioe production systematic. Apply for trial 6880H, press extracts, Herr B. Wechsler, Post Office, Cairo.	.	25929-12-6
3ELL CHEAP.— Engine Press, eta ; best J condition ; presses hundred bales daily oasily. No. 25,939 "Egyptian Gazette” offioes. 25939-6-4
TO LET.—Furnished house with five rooms, A situated in the best quarter of Alexandria, 0 let for 3 months, July, August, and September. Apply to A. J. Venieri, P. 0. Box 349, Alexandria.	25946-6-3
TTNE DAME ANGLAISE offre sos services poor le massage tant reoommandd par beau- coup do doc tears, massage do figure dgalement xiur en effacer les rides et rendre au corps et 1 figure la fralcheur et la sautd de la jeuuesse ; striotement secret: prix moddrds. S’adresser No 25,962 "Egyptian Gazette.”	25962-3-1
VOUNG MAN, knowing good English, be- A sides French and Greek, seeks situation. Apply No. 26,947 "Egyptian Gazette Offices.” 25947-8-3</p></div>		-			-
<div type="item"><p>STATIONERY ENGRAVING
BOEHME & ANDERER.
NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB,
CAIRO.
GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKE.
Speciality t
Account Book mttdo to ordmr.
ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS & MAGAZINES.
Sodflrera Outlary.
DAVIES
BRYAN
& Co.
ContinentalHotelBuildings,
CAIRO,
St. David's Buildings,
ALEXANDRIA,
and 35-37 Noble Street
LONDON, E.O.
English Tailors
Drapers
and Outfitters.
Beg respectfully :to an-
nounce that they have
received their various
stocks in the latest
styles suitable for the
present Season.</p>
<p>A large assortment of
Blacks, Blues, Scotch,
Irish & Harris Tweeds.
All garments cut by ex-
perienced English Cut-
ters, fit and style gua-
ranteed.</p>
<p>A varied stock of
Ladies’ Blouses, Boas,
Skirts, Belts, &c.
Careful attention is
suitable for Tours up
the Nile.
GENTS’
OUTFITTING:
The latest novelties inTies,
Collars, Shirts, Cloves,
Hosiery in all the newest
makes, (Camel Hair brand
a speciality).</p>
<p>We are also making a special display
in the Drapery Department, con-
sisting of Household Linen, Blan-
kets, Calicoes, Eider-down Quilts,
Cushions,4o.,4o., which are mark-
ed at such figures as to command
attention.</p>
<p>Boots & Shoes in the latest
shapes, Bags, Trunks & all
Leather goods in great va-
riety. _
Also a large assorted supply,'"of the
following artioles:—
HATS, GAPS, UMBRELLA8,
WALKING-STICKS, RUGS,
STUDS, BRUSHES AND ALL
TOILET REQUISITES, dO.
Davies Bryan & Co.
Cairo ft Alexandria,</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

