<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2021-01-24">January 24, 2021</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-02-15/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-15">Wednesday, February 15, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/mode/1up" status="incomplete">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-ad-etc02"> The Eastern
                                Telegraph Company, Limited.<lb/> Le réseau de cable télégraphiques
                                sous-marins de cette compagnie<lb/> constitue le moyen de
                                communication le plus<lb/> direct et le plus rapide d'Egypte pour
                                l'Europe, l'Amérique<lb/> du Nord et du Sud, L,Afrique orientale,
                                méridionale<lb/> et occidentale, les Indes, l'Australie, la
                                Nouvelle-Zélande, la<lb/> Chine et le Japon.<lb/> Pour assurer une
                                transmission rapide, les télégrammes<lb/> doivent porter
                                l'indication <hi rend="bold">Viâ Eastern</hi>.<lb/> Voir le temps
                                moyen de transmission le plus récent jusqu'à<lb/> Londres au
                                belletin journalier publié dans ce journal.<lb/> STATIONS EN EGYPTE.
                                Alexandrie, le Caire, Suez,<lb/> Port-Tewfik, Port-Said, Suakin.
                                Bureau principal à Londres.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7124">7,124</measure>]</cell>
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, FEBRUARY 15, 1905.</cell>
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->

                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->

                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->

            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/page/n1/mode/1up">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/page/n2/mode/1up" status="verified">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PARLIAMENT OPENS.</head>
                        <head>THE KING'S SPEECII.</head>
                        <head>"C.B." ATTACKS GOVERNMENT.</head>
                        <head>THE WAR AND INTERVENTION.</head>
                        <dateline>London, February 14, </dateline>
                        <p>The love Speech states that His Majesty's rebution whether countries
                            continue friendly TW is Japanese war still, anbappily, conthat but the
                            Government has been careful</p>
                        <p>terve neutrality in the strictest manner. Thu eynilifist of things in the
                            Balkans occaWolin auxity. Tlie teorganisation of the gendarmerie ras
                            produced sume amelioration, but radical return, and especially financial
                            ones, are still reguntexi. "The speech notes with satisfaction Hit
                            Russia and Austria have lately wiusseu propiosala to the Porte for this
                            purposes. "Ttiv Convention between Great Britain an Fratfue has been
                            duly ratitiei, and Chanel lak tu strengthen the Indiantly relations w
                            puy exist between the two countries. The rechtentias the meeting in
                            Parig yt the lutakatu wbich has been appainted dur the prepunu ul
                            apportioning responpidity lur the uplurale fuciuent in the</p>
                        <p>H UF SS --- Sir H. Campbell banurante canta to the fiscal question stil
                            uwentietoerythtok elst. He vigorously Welches the truserirett fur
                            canging w</p>
                        <p>utta ethuigd the teeling of the country byd Langkali tidubitably, that
                            the prolouga</p>
                        <p>Hi thejrezent situation is a public danger w a usurparul of power.</p>
                        <p>With icterend to the war he hoped that luoni latest it would tuurace the
                            earliest op party during Ingimundo intluence on the alte or pice.</p>
                        <p>Lord lansdowne said he cousidered that intervention in hintay tu be
                            traught with the Wurst testails. Il Was utilecessary to say that</p>
                        <p>tald ali opurtunity arise, the Goverument would avau, tbem-elves of it.
                            (leuter.,</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SITUATION IN RUSSIA.</head>
                        <head>MORE HOPEFUL OUTLOOK.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, February 14. </dateline>
                            <p>"The Russian Coinmittee of Ministers at their meetings on Saturday
                                and yesterday instructed the Minister of Finance to frame a blume
                                tor impruinig ihe lot of the workmen by shorteuing the hours, by
                                distinguishing between strikes and public disorders, by providing
                                medical assistance, and by limiung the powers of the. Factory
                                Tuspectors. These questions will be subuntted to a speciat
                                commissiour which will tear the evidence of masters and men.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Lodz, February 14. </dateline>
                            <p>The situation here is somewhat more hopefal. The workmeu in any of
                                the factories have resumed work.</p>
                            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ADMIRAL TOGO. SAILS FOR UNKNOWN DESTINATION.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Torio, February 11: </dateline>
                            <p>Adrdiral Togo bas lett kure for an unknown destination, going
                                probably towards the Soutli.</p>
                            <p>(llavas.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Kuke, February 14. </dateline>
                            <p>Admiral Togo has sailed, his destination * being unknown.</p>
                            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH STEAMER WRONGLY SEIZED.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Tokio, February 14.</dateline>
                            <p> The British steniner "Eartry" has been released, the capture having
                                been a mistake.</p>
                            <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GERMAN STRIKES.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ESSEN, Febroary 14. </dateline>
                            <p>Work is being resumed more and more in the Rubir basin.</p>
                            <p>Yliarus.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>CARLT NDOTET.</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley. Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Tan spatara troca Alpsandria. Pritl is every weet Vors solemne charges. Soley
                        in she flasonable Kolieb balot, Visitate from Chiu dlight at</p>
                    <p>M ahar tation. * AOUTLISA, Pepider</p>
                    <p>SZCZE</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>. CAIRO. Opon all the year round. ELECTRIC MOLLET. DERATE ENANGER</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>CAIRO GRAND NAMMAM.</p>
                    <p>Near Shepboard's &amp; Continental Hotels. TURKISH BATHS</p>
                    <p>PLAIN BATHS, XRAY</p>
                    <p>ELECTRIC LIQHT BATHS. NANNAGE *121k-ID F 10X11.. terol Drews, DV. Prasooner
                        ornarod Dr. M. Ross</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section">

                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BRINDISI MAIL </head>
                        <p>will be distributed at the G.P.O., Alexandrin, at 7.45 a,m. to
                            morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WHITE STAR</head>
                        <p> liner "Romanio" arrived at Alexandria this morning from Boston and
                            Naples with about 150 tourists on board for Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALHAMBRA THEATRE. --</head>
                        <p>A gala performance is announced for Friday next in honor of the artistic
                            director of the ballet troupe, Sig. Euzo Longhi.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>On the 9th and 10th inst. 25 vessels passed through the Canal, 20 of
                            which were British, 1 Dutch, 1 German, 1 Austrian, 2 French. The
                            receipts for the two days were frs, 703,792.82, making the total from
                            1st inst. frs. 3,761,733.51.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ORIENTAL CONGRESS. --</head>
                        <p>The Egyptian Government has decided to take part in the Congress of
                            Orientalists which will be held at Algiers during the present year, and
                            Sultan Effendi Muhamed, Abdul Aziz Jaoniche, and Sheikh Hamed wil
                            represent Eypt at the Congress.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPT AT ST. LOUIS.--- </head>
                        <p>Mr. John Wanamaker, of Philadelphia, has purchased half of the Egyptian
                            authropological exhibit at the World's Fair, St. Louis, which included
                            an ancient sarcophagus and a mummy (200 B.C.), for the Philadelphia
                            diusuun. The price paid for the exhibits aggregated about $70,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAKE WALK COMPETITION. - </head>
                        <p>One of the chief incidents of the forthcoming Cairo 'Tradesmen's Ball is
                            to be the grand cake walk competitiou. It is expected that this
                            competition will actract a number of entries. A valuable prize is to be
                            presented to the most perfect "cake walker."</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHARITY LOTTERY. </head>
                        <p>Mime de la Boulimiere has received a beautiful Sèvres vase from the
                            President of the French Republic for the Lottery which she has organised
                            in aid of the home for the aged, the orphanages, and the dispensaries in
                            Old Cairo. The lottery is to be drawn at the French Agency to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AN IMPORTANT DISCOVERY.</head>
                        <p>M. Berthelot, secretary of the Louvre Museum, believes that he has
                            discovered the secret of the ageut usou un emuaming in ancient Egypt.
                            Aiter &amp; labo riuus uxalmination of the sarcophage of the fitch and
                            sixtu dynasties, which dates back &amp; Iar as 3500 B.O., M. Berthelut
                            Las come tu thu decislou that the oil employed Was numpay castor oil,
                            such as is still used in tyypt, whicu has uudergone some vXlua Lou, but
                            rutanud during the long perlud its preservative qualities.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>OUR VISITORS.</head>
                        <p>Every day our newspapers give a list of the illustrous guests who are
                            attracted to Egypt by the delightful climate. Several of these devole
                            part of their leisure to the study of French, English, German, Arabie,
                            etc., at the Berlitz schools, at Alexandria, aud especially at Cairo,
                            where there is very much stir. The renown of the system is universal,
                            and besides there is the advantage of the transier tickets, which allow
                            the tourist to continue in Europe or America the lessons begun in Cairo
                            or Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A GUIDE TO EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>To the capable hands of Dr. Wallis Budgy, of the British Museum, has been
                            entrusted the task of writing Cook's Handbook of Egypt and the Sudan"
                            (Thoma Cook aud Son), and he has succeeded in making a subject,
                            interesting enough in itself, still mune interesting by the Wealth of
                            knowledge brought to bear on it. Profusely illustrateu with maps and
                            sketches, the work enables even the stay-at-home traveller to almost
                            believe himself in the land of the Pharaohs, while to those fortunate
                            enough to Visit the East it is absolutely indispensable.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The BRISTOL HOTEL.-- </head>
                        <p>Mr. Bauer, the manager of the Briswi Holei, Cairo, bas taken over tuu
                            luase of this popular resurt of visitors t the Capital direct from the
                            proprietors of the builuuy. Mr. Bauer, who has already greaty improved
                            this hotel, mtulids to rearrange tue whule builuing and rejuruish it
                            anew, 80 that il will be in every respect one of the most upw-date
                            establishments of tue kind in the Capital. This news will be received
                            with great pleasury by the onents of the Bristol Hotel, wuch bas been so
                            excellently managed for some time past by Mr. Bauer.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PHILOPTOCHOS. --</head>
                        <p>Tuat excellent Greek benevolent society, the Poiloptuchos of Alexaridris,
                            is giving its annual grand "Vegione" at thu Zizinia Theatre next
                            Saturday evening under the patronage of the collowing ladies ut the
                            committee : Mesdames A. Pangulos (president p. i.), C. Sitadmo
                            vice-presiueut), Virginie Emm. Benachi (treasurer), 0. M. Salvago, A. C.
                            Zervudaclit, M. Sinaudino, G. C. Zervudachi, Const. Chyremni, N. Tsamis,
                            F. Franghiadi, c. Rodocanachi, C. Mavroskoufi, JA. Anastasiadi, A.
                            Valassopoulo, 4. Prazzica, J. Sevastopoulo, E. O. Zervudachi, J.
                            Lagonico, G. Jacovidi, and A. Assimacopoulo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>OFFICIAL SALARIES.- </head>
                        <p>The question of the proportions that should prevait between official
                            salaries and the recent abnormal rise in price of all the necessities of
                            life in Egypt is to be seriously considered by the Government, which has
                            approved of the institution of a committee charged with the study of the
                            situation with a view to improvement. This committee, which will be
                            presided over by Mr. Macbell, the Advisur to the Minietry of the
                            Interior, will consist of the Director-General of the Accounts
                            Department to the Ministry of Finance, the Director-General of Customs,
                            and the Direotor. General of the Survey Department,</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO AGRICULTURAL SHOW.</head>
                    <head>LIST OF PRIZE WINNERS.</head>
                    <p>Owing to the bad cotton season of 1904, 1 fewer 1st prizes have been given
                        this year than in recent exbibitions, but the average of the exhibits is
                        very fair notwithstanding, and there are some interesting features which
                        deserve special notice. The Daira Sanieh have obtained two special 1st
                        prizes, one for Ashmouni cotton grown as far south as Erment, ! and one for
                        excellent Afifi grown at the same place. The better known varieties of
                        cotton, Jannovich, Afifi, Ashmouni, Alume, are well represented, and of the
                        new and less known varieties there is an excellent show of Nubari and a
                        beautiful example of Charara from Me.. noufieh, with excellent samples of
                        Voltos and Kerki.</p>
                    <p>The grain exhibits are decidedly good, the | Princesses Nimet and Anineh
                        Hanem, Omar</p>
                    <p>Bey Sultan, Priuce Omar Pasha Toussoun, Riaz Pasha, Boghios Pasha Nubar, and
                        A. Zeid Bey Tautawi being prominent among the prize winners. The Kom Ombo
                        Company's exbibit deserves special mention, as it includes wheat harvested
                        on the 4th inst, and barley harvested on the 15th January, 1905 L</p>
                    <p>Some interesting pot experiments with various fertilisers are well worth
                        notice, while among the animals and poultry exhibited, Prince Omar l'æ ha
                        Toussuun's specimens are particularly five. The mats and straw work
                        exhibited are very prettily designed and look durable. The following are the
                        prize-winners for cereals :Class.</p>
                    <p>64. Red Saidi Wheat.-1. Omar Bey Sul-! tan ; 2. M. Bey Mahfaz ; 3. A. Zeid
                        Bey Tan tawi ; 4. Prince Omar Toussoun.</p>
                    <p>65. White Wheat from Upper Egypt.11. Ali Awad ; 2. A. Zeid Bey Tantawi.</p>
                    <p>67. White Egyptian Wheat : a) grown in Gharbieh Moudirieh. 1. Abdu Eff.
                        Girgis.</p>
                    <p>b) In Menoufich. No award.</p>
                    <p>c) In Charkieh.--1. Princesses Amineh and Nimat lancm ; 2. Teftish Katr
                        Hammam.</p>
                    <p>d) In Behera. 3. Riaz Pasha.</p>
                    <p>69. Any Variety of Foreign White Wheat grown in Egypt. -1, Princesses Amineh
                        And Nimet Hanein ; 2. Mah. Bey El Ghonomy. ]</p>
                    <p>70. Native Barley.--1. Princesses Aminehi and Nimat Hanem ; 2. Riaz
                        Pa-ba.</p>
                    <p>72. Beheri Beans. -- 1. and 2. Princesses Amineh and Nimat Hanem ; 3. Riaz
                        Pasha.</p>
                    <p>73. Saidi Beans.-1. A. Said Bey Radi; 2. Omar Bey Sultan.</p>
                    <p>74 Native Maize.-1. Sheikh Abd el Baki Abdullah, Omar Bey Sultan, and the
                        Princesses Amineh and Nimet Hunem. (Seven 2ud, six 3rd, and two 4th prizes
                        were awarded).</p>
                    <p>75 Foreign Maize grown in Egypt.--1. A. Zeid Bey Tantuwi and Prince Omar
                        Toussoun; 2. Omar Bey Sultan.</p>
                    <p>76 Millet.-1. A. Zeid Bey Tantawi ; 2. Omar Bey Sultan.</p>
                    <p>77 Saltani Rice.- 1. Moh. Boy Tewfik Shaheb; 2. A. Eft Girgis.</p>
                    <p>78 Sabaini Rice.-1. Abd el Baki Haroun; 2. Seif el Nasr Buy Tantawi and Ibr.
                        Sidi Abmed.</p>
                    <p>79 Any other variety of Rice.-1. Mitwalli el Kloh ; 2. Wali Bey Ali.</p>
                    <p>[In all the above classes first prize winners obtained a silver gilt, the
                        second a silver, and other prize-wippers a bronze medal.]</p>
                    <p>81 Saidi Lontils.--1. Omar Bey Sultan.</p>
                    <p>82 Earth Nuts.-- 1. Abd el Mohamed Bey Moussa ; 2. Kassim Bey Mourad.</p>
                    <p>83 Linseed.-- 1. Moh. el Tahawi, 2. Seif el Nasr Bey Tantawi.</p>
                    <p>84 White Sesame.-1. Kassim Bey Monrad.</p>
                    <p>85 Brown Sesame.--1. Kassim Bey Mourad; | 2. Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun.</p>
                    <p>(In these classes first prize winners obtained | a silver, others a bronze
                        medal.]</p>
                    <p>86 Fenugreek. - Silver Medal and 1st. Princesses Amineh and Nimat Hassan ; 2.
                        Omar Bey Sultan. | 87 Baali Bersim Seed. -Equal 1st: Princesses Amineh and
                        Nimat Hassan and Boghos Pasha Nabar.</p>
                    <p>88 Miscawi Bersim Seed.-Equal Ist : Princesses Amineh and Nimet Hanem and
                        Rinz Pasba.</p>
                    <p>89 Colza. -Omar Bey Sultan. Yeal. 2. Riaz Pasba and Boghos Pasha Nubar.
                        Gelban. -Teftish Arnent. Rayana.--Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun.</p>
                    <p>Behøri Beans.--2. 8. Bey Ahmed Abaga. Special Silver Gilt Medal to Wadi Kom
                        Ombo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive, after attending KourbanBeyram prayers yesterday morning at
                        Koubbeh Mosque, proceeded to Abdeen Palace to hold the Kourban-Beyram
                        reception, which was nutnerously attended.</p>
                    <p>On Monday the Khedive gave audience to Sheikh Mohamed Abdou, Grand Moufti of
                        B:ypt, who gave a description to his Highness of his recent trip to the
                        Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE E. J. MANUK.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of the late Mr. E. J. Manuk, whose sudden death on Sunday came as
                        a shock to the many friends he possessed in Cairo, took place on Monday
                        afternoon, amidst a large</p>
                    <p>concourse of people. The chief mourner was | the deceased's brother, Mr. E C.
                        Manuk, of</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, and the mortal remains of the | deceased were followed to their
                        last resting J place by everyone distinguished in the world of finance and
                        of commerce, of which Mr. Mamuk was a prominent member. There was an
                        iminense quantity of wreaths. The burial service was held at St. Joseph's
                        Church,</p>
                    <p>Ismailia, and the interment took place in 1 &amp; temporary vault in the
                        Latin cemetery. A number of shops on the line of ronte of the fa neral were
                        closed as a sign of respeot for the deceased.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT. A TRIP TO KARNAK.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From our CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                        <dateline>Keneh, Sunday. </dateline>
                        <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught are expected to reach Luxor tomorrow.
                            They will remain at Luxor till Thursday. Instructions had been issued by
                            the Ministry of the Interior to the Moudir to proceed to Luxor in order
                            I to be in attendance on the Doke during his stay there. The Moudir,
                            accompanied by the Police Commandant, is leaving at noon for Luxor. I
                            learn that the railway authorities have arranged to send a special train
                            from Cairo to Luxor on Wednesday for the purpose of conveying the Royal
                            party back to Cairo. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Luxor, Monday. </dateline>
                        <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught spent last night at Arment and arrived
                            here this morning at 10 o'clock. All the consular agents and the
                            moudirieh officials were waiting at the lauding-stage to welcome the
                            Royal visitors. The two Princesses landed first and rode to ] Karnak,
                            one og horseback and the other on a donkey. The Duchess and inite
                            followed later, and afterwards the Duke, with General Sir J. Maxwell.
                            All went on donkeys. The party returned about noon, and the Duke and
                            Duchess went on board their yacht after a short walk on the quay, while
                            the Princesses went on a visit to the town. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(PROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                        <dateline>Luxor, later. </dateline>
                        <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught changed their landing-stage from the
                            Anglo-American Company's platform to a landing-stage at Karnak, which
                            the Government had already prepared for them, and which, I suppose,
                            faci. litated their visit to the ruins. About 3 p.m. they went to visit
                            the Tombs of the Kings, where they took tea.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EX-EMPRESS EUGENIE.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Luxor, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>The ex-Empress Eugenie and suite arrived here this afternoon about 4 o'clock
                        from Cairo in a dababieh. The distinguished lady landed at about five and
                        paid a short visit to Luxor Temple, afterwardsproceeding to the Luxor Hotel,
                        where she took tea and perused the latest telegrams.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> PRINCE OF SWEDEN'S VISIT. </head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>5. Luxor, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>H. R. H. Prince Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden and Norway is paying a visit to
                        Luxor incognito on a private dababieh. Yesterday he dined at the Luxor
                        Hotel, and to-day he has been visiting some antiquity shops and merchants.
                        Two plain-clothes policemen sre keeping watch over him.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER'S TRIP. </head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Luxor, Sunday. </dateline>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Cromer, accompanied by Lady Beatrice Thynne, arrived here this
                        morning on their stram dahabieh. The distinguished party stopped here for
                        about two hours, daring which time Lady Cromer visited Luxor Temple. They
                        afterwards proceeded to Assouan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUPREME CONSULAR COURT. </head>
                    <p>Mr. Pigott, the acting Chief Justice of His Majesty's Supreme Consular Court
                        for the Dominions of the Sublime Ottoman Porte, will arrive here on Saturday
                        next from Constantinople and will proceed direct to Cairo.</p>
                    <p>There are no cases down for hearing at Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXCAVATIONS ON THE CANAL</head>
                    <p>At the last meeting of the Academy of Inscriptions and Belles lettres of
                        Paris it was announced that the board of the Suez Canal Company had decided
                        to commence archæological excavations in the region traversed by the Saez
                        Canal. The work will be enfanted to M. Clédat, of the Cairo Archäological
                        Institnte, and the excavations will begin at Tel el-Herr.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FITZNER QUARTETTE.</head>
                    <p>The following is the programme of the second concert to be given at the New
                        Khedivial Hotel, Alexandria, on Friday, 17th inst., by the Fitzner Quartette
                        - 1. GLAZOUNOW : Quatuor Ré-majeur (Op. 70)</p>
                    <p>a) Andante Allegro b) Allegretto o) Adagio</p>
                    <p>d) Allegro. 2. DVORAK: Lento (Dumky)</p>
                    <p>CHERUBINI: Scherzo. 3. BEETHOVEN : Quatuor Mi mineur (Op.59</p>
                    <p>No. 2) a) Allegro b) Molto Adagio o). Allegretto</p>
                    <p>d) Finale presto. Tickets (P.T. 40 each, or P.T. 100 for family of 3) may be
                        had at Hack's music stores, Cherif Pasha Street.</p>
                    <p>(2-1)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>TYROL</p>
                    <p>Weissenstein Castle 3410 . ft. First-class private hotel near
                        Windisch-Matrei; Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieste). Bracing
                        air. Good Mountaineering centre. Tennis Pishing. Best June, September. Apply
                        Proprietan</p>
                    <p>98986484</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GEN. STOESSEL AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>DEPARTURE FOR RUSSIA.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                        <dateline>Suez, Tuesday.. </dateline>
                        <p>The Messageries Maritimes mil steamer "Australien," having General
                            Swessel, Mme. Stoessel, and 498 officers and men of the Port Arthur
                            garrison on board, artived at Saen at 9 o'cloek this morning, en rute
                            for Port Said, where they will embark on board the Roskian steamer
                            "Saint Nicolas" for Odessa. .</p>
                        <p>The "Australien" entered the Canal at 1.30 this afternoon. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From Our CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Tuesday. </dateline>
                        <p>The Messageries steamer "Australien," with General and Mme. Stoensel and
                            the officers and men accompanying him, is nowin the Canal and is due at
                            Port Said early to-morrow morning.</p>
                        <p>The "Saint Nicolas" reached bere from Odessa yesterday, and is now
                            awaiting their arrival </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From our CORRESPONDENT.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Wednesday, - </dateline>
                        <p>E: General Stoessel transhipped from the. 8.8. "Anstralien" to the 8.8.
                            "St. Nicolas" at 9.30 a.m. to day. The latter steamer leaves for
                            Theodosia at 3 o'dlock this afternoon.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER TURBINE STEAMER. </head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Tueeday, </dateline>
                    <p>Another new tarbine steamer, the "Lanka” (Capt. Wilson), arrived at Port Said
                        this morning bound for Colombo. She was built by Messrs. Denny and Co., of
                        Glasgow, for the British India Steam Navigation Company. Her speed from
                        Glasgow, which she left on the 4th inst., has averaged 147 knots, but she is
                        capable of 19. She has accommodation for 48 first-class passengers, and will
                        probably run between Calentta and Rangoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE “C. O. D.” SYSTEM. </head>
                    <p>We understand that the suggestions contained in our leading article of
                        Thursday last bave been received with a considerable amount of favor by the
                        authorities, and that steps will be taken to introduce the cash-on-delivery
                        system of the postal service between Egypt and the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>We have good reason to believe, too, that the opposition to the establishment
                        of the system between Egypt and England is likely to be overcome.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SMUGGLING AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>The Coastguards at Alexandria have been very busy the last few days in
                        seizing contraband goods in the shape of firearms, hashish, ammunition,
                        powder, etc.</p>
                    <p>On Sunday morning, 143 kilos of hashishi was seized near the landing-stage
                        inside the enclosure of the Ports and Lighthouses Ad. ministration.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday, on searching the Italian 8.8. "Nina," the Coastguards found two
                        large portmanteaux, containing 70 kilos of hashish, | and also the following
                        treasure trove : 101 breech-loading rifles of all kinds, including
                        Martini-Henry, Chassepot, and Gras, 11 revolvers, some of them exquisitely
                        mounted with ivory handles, 1,490 ball (rifle) cartridges, 1,474 ball
                        (revolver) cartridges, 250,000 per cussion caps for Arab sporting guns, 19
                        tins of sporting powder, and 4,900 choice Havana cigars.</p>
                    <p>The night previous to this haul the smugglers had kept the Coastguards baay
                        in the harbour and there were some exciting chases.</p>
                    <p>It is surmised that the rifles and ammunition were intended for the Tripoli
                        coast, where the vessel would land them on her return voyage. The arms are
                        too unwieldly. to be landed at Alexandria without detection. This is the
                        largest haul of valuable contraband that has been made at Alexandria this
                        year.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellerman 8.8. "Sardinia," now on the berth for Liverpool, will sail for
                        that port on Sanday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</p>
                    <p>Beat and most comfortable, unique for ita position on Nile bank. Under Gesmaa
                        Manage ment. Moderate cbargos. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerta twice daily * 41-07 Portretom , Moral a angeende.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>BRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</p>
                    <p>BRAND BIA 8.. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>WY8B3-16.7.0</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>“AU DE ROUGE.”</p>
                    <p>QENDRAL DRAPERY ESTABLISHMENT.. (Central Tramway Station).</p>
                    <p>CAIRO. P. PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR. DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH</p>
                    <p>TEXTILE MANUFACTURES. Ladies' Fanoy Bulk Blouses and Skirts, and Fancy
                        Material for Evening Wear. Also Fans, Fancy Pins, Artlicial Flowers, Pearl
                        Neok. lets, and Chitons.</p>
                    <p>Ladies' and Genti Pocket Band. Kerohias lo Rial Irith Line</p>
                    <p>W.111</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="notesHelouan">
                    <head>NOTES FROM HELOUAN. </head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A RECORD SEASON. </head>
                        <byline>(From our ConanODAT) 1.</byline>
                        <dateline>Hédias, Monday </dateline>
                        <p>The reason at Hietotas ir to prove e record one, the hotele pensions are
                            early all fall, and the work in consequence presents quite a Thoongo in
                            the management of the way has already down evidenes that de confort and
                            convenience of</p>
                        <p>p ages and to be the ded to, but mucha velito to be done this two termini
                            are still surrounded with n aid loafers. The authorities would be walle
                            d if they retained a portion of the phutuna separated off for first and
                            second on egors, especially as no waiting rooms to provided. Further,
                            there is a great want of a te lounge wooden costs for people who arrivo
                            * to mi nutes before the arrival of the train to Hellows apon. The
                            lighting of the stations magtit be greatly improved. Seeing that this
                            towns of Heloman has now an excellent electrio supty, why should its
                            station remain asboot in darkness, the sole supply of light at present
                            consisting of some ancient oil lampe 1</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WANTED_A BANK - </head>
                        <p>Whilst mentioning, local improvements I should like to point out the wait
                            of enterprise on the part of the various big Helouan alrehdy oontains
                            son t thousand inhabitants, each year &amp; langely intruning number of
                            visitors, and yet not one of the Byptian banks has a branch bare The
                            establishment of one would prove most wel. come.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>POST OFFICE COMPLAINTS. </head>
                        <p>Again, a considerable datoe of annogunos to residents and visitors are
                            the short hours that the post office is open auch day, it seine nothing
                            short of a publio scandal that it shoäld be closed at all during the
                            day. At present one is debarred from even purchasing a postage stamp
                            during at least five hours of the ordinary working day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RACES. </head>
                        <p>The races instituted by the Holocan Sporting Club, last year, have
                            'proved great Success this season, the attendance at anch of the first
                            two meetings has been all that dould be desired, and there is every
                            prospect of another good day at the meeting to be held next Friday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GOLFING.. </head>
                        <p>The Helouan Golf Club is again proving great attraction to visitors, the
                            weekly com, petitions being keonly contested. The Nango. vich Company,
                            by whom the links are maintrained, have generously doubled the start
                            this season, and in consequence the links, hava been greatly improved
                            and have never beda in better order.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>H.B.M.': Consal-General at Alsandha and Mrs. Gould gave a largely attended
                        "At Home" at the British Consulate last night. The new codisalar residente
                        adapta itaoli admirtbly to social fandtions, and the many groots of Mr. and
                        Mrs. Gould, including a number of forsiga Consuls and a representative
                        gathering of the British colony, enjoyed a most pleacaat evening Mr. and
                        Mrs. Gould will be at home and to-morrow evening.</p>
                    <p>Eighty passengers landed yesterday after noon at Port Said from the P. and 0.
                        8.8. "China" (Capt. G. K. Wright, RNR). Among the most distinguished were
                        Mr. H. W. and Lady Hope, Sir Gerald Fitagozald, Sir A Coote, Barts, and Lady
                        Coote, Sir R. H. Brown, and Mrs. Ivor Guest.</p>
                    <p>Mr. N. Kalomiris, F.R.O.8., and Mn. Kalomiris arrived at Alexandria from
                        London by the 8.8. "Senegal."</p>
                    <p>HD8' 7. The following passengers loft Cairo on Mon. day by the P. 8.
                        "Oleopatra" for the Nila trip :</p>
                    <p>Mr., Mrs. and Miss Nahgal. M. P. R. Stow, Mr. Dunaker, Mr. Wondort, Mr.
                        Bouche, Mr. Kemna, Ms. Kleiser, Mn Kaly, Alise Perlenghi, Mr. and Mn.
                        Ulrici, Mr. and Mr. Bastert, Mr. and Mrs. Tuskett, Mn, and Miss Woulfe, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Reschks Mr. and Mn. Loewy, Mr. and Mme P. Ceingray Mr and Mrs. de
                        Rognelenil, Mr. and Mrs. J.Conte, Mr. and Mn. J. M. Conte, Miss Caswell, Mr.
                        and" Mrs. Nelson Leo.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left Assiout yester day by the P.S. "Tewfik." :- Mr.
                        and Mrs. Dymond, Mr. W. P. and Mrs. Blackburna Maze, Miss Meares, Miss G.
                        Manres, Mr. P. Sharp, Mr. J. Lombart, Mn. Brimolins, Mis. Thomley Taylor,
                        Mr. J. M. Hurløy, Mr. and Mrs. Vautier, Dr. Edward and Mrs. Batma Seidl,
                        Miss Ely Seidl, H, E. Otto Rittar von Pohl, H. B. Edward Ritter von Pahl, ME
                        and Mrs. Peythien, Mr. Oscar and Mr. Sabak, Mr. Frederick and Mro. Paterson,
                        Mr. R. H. and Mr. A.W. Collins, Mr. Ignace, Miss Anne and Miss Alla
                        Zahrovsky, Mr. Hairy Lan-' gridge, Mr. and Mrs. Amold in Min A. Kohler, Mr.
                        and Mrs. A. J. W. Dennek Baronesa van der Borok Hofratio, MnFaite les, Mrs.
                        Anda Dreital, Mn. Miller Frankel, Mrs. de Kemel, Mr. and Mr. Boissot, MK. O.
                        Neumant.</p>
                    <p>The following prasetigers left Shelial today hy the P. 8. "Mennon":-Mr. and
                        Mis Dunn, Mr. G. W. Dennis, Mr. Kavier d'Udoka d'Acoz, Mr. and M. Henri
                        d'Udal... d'Aoor. Mr. Koritzky, Mt. Schilling Mn. Arrigo Fraus, Miss &amp;
                        Maroet, Prof Korder, Miss A, Goldachaidt, Mr and Mr. Hool, Mr. Geox Cohen,
                        Mr. Grandor, Mt. H. A. Klap Woloh, Mini W. Making Mr. Edward A. Feld</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/page/n3/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/page/n4/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-15/page/n5/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>For LONDON, by the 8.8. Sigyn, sailed op the 6th Febrary </p>
                    <p>Sté deg Huileries et Savonneries, 1,970 bags oil cake </p>
                    <p>Kafr-el-Zayat Cotton Coy Ltd, 9,058 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>Behrend &amp; Co., 770 tons cotton seed, 1,018 bags oil cake </p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Ltd, 480 tons cotton seed </p>
                    <p>A. Panzieri, 251 cases aggs </p>
                    <p>R. Mordo, 100 cases ages </p>
                    <p>Salonica Cigarettes Co., 2 cases cigarettes</p>
                    <p>Ste An. Le Khédive, 2 cases cigarettes paper </p>
                    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son, 10 packages effects and curios.</p>
                    <p>M. L Carasso, 1 case leather </p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 4 cases soap </p>
                    <p>B Hatioun, 5 cases curios </p>
                    <p>A. Werther &amp; Co. 11 bags gum </p>
                    <p>Pout PORT SAID et MASSAWAH, par le bateau italien "Tebe", parti le 6 février </p>
                    <p>A. Duropoulo, 10 damejeannes anisette </p>
                    <p>A. Papadakis, 16 colis provisions</p>
                    <p>D. Liacachi, 12</p>
                    <p>F, G. Cotsiomiti, 12</p>
                    <p>A. Paniopoule, 10</p>
                    <p>A. Stross, 15 barils verrerie </p>
                    <p>Divers, 65 colis divers </p>
                    <p>Pour PORT-SAID et ODESSA, par le bateau russe "Korniloft", parti le 7 février
                        : </p>
                    <p>Divers, 21 colis légumes </p>
                    <p>Pour MARSEILLE, par le bateau italien "Margarida", parti le 7 février : . </p>
                    <p>N. E. Tamvaco, 1,712,913 kilos gr. de coton </p>
                    <p>Pour LA SYRIE par le bateau ott. "Marigo", parti le 7 fevrier </p>
                    <p>Divers. 200 colis divers </p>
                    <p>Pour TREBIZÓNDE, par le bateau ottoman "Alexandria", partie 7 février : </p>
                    <p>Divers, 36 sacs riz, 120 barils vides, 57 colis peaux, 21 colis divers </p>
                    <p>For PIRÆUS and CONSTANTINOPLE, by the 8.$. "Ismailia", sailed on the 8th
                        February </p>
                    <p>Various, 1,377 bags rice, 480 bags sugar, 25 bags henna, 522 packages
                        vegetables, 16 packages gum, 9 packages skins, 5 packages sundres</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
