<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-24">January 24, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7105 ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, JANUARY 24, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VLADIMIR’S DAY. BRITISH NAVAL MANŒUVRES. TSAR IN HIDING. DOCKYARDS ON FIRE.</head>
                    <p>ESTIMATED KILLED- 2,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL STRIKE AT MOSCOW.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>Yesterday is known as “Vladimir’s Day,” being the name of the Tsar’s uncle,
                        the Grand Duke Vladimir, a notoriously violent reactionary, to whom his
                        Majesty confided the maintenance of order.</p>
                    <p>The exact whereabouts of the Tsar is unknown. The information is carefully
                        concealed.</p>
                    <p>The ruthless firing on unarmed crowds has horrified the public. On all sides
                        one hears scathing comparisons between the bravery of the military against
                        the defenceless public and their conduct in Manchuria.</p>
                    <p>Inie former mutual distrust between the educated reformers and the workmen
                        has vanished.</p>
                    <p>The novelist Maxime Gorki, addressing a meeting of Liberals associated with
                        himself and Father Gapon, said that the revolution had commenced and would
                        continue.</p>
                    <p>Father Gapon, who is unhurt and in hiding, has written to his comrades saying
                        : “We have now no Emperor, innocent blood lies between him and the people.
                        Hurrah for the beginning of the people’s battle for freedom. I will be with
                        you this evening.”</p>
                    <p>The proceedings last night at Vassili Ostrow are still shrouded in mystery.
                        It is reported that the troops invaded the quarter shooting and sabring
                        every one they met. Some estimates give the casualties as 2,000 killed and
                        5,000 wounded. No official statement has yet been issued on the subject.</p>
                    <p>Large fires have broken out near the Warsaw Railway Station.</p>
                    <p>People are amazed at the colossal blunder</p>
                    <p>of the Government in neglecting such an opportunity for strengthening the
                        people’s affection tor the autocracy. Millions of workmen have been added to
                        the ranks of the intellectual malcontents.(Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>(Official). Until yesterday at 8 o’clock there were 76 killed and 233
                        wounded. The centre of the city is quiet this morning, but ferment continues
                        in the outlying quarters. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Sevastopol, January 23.</p>
                    <p>The vast dockyards here are on fire. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The morning was quiet, but about 5 o’clock the troops again fired on the
                        people who were assembled on the Newski Prospect.</p>
                    <p>Some electric light employés have struck. The city is partly in darkness.</p>
                    <p>Independent observers estimate that yesterday’s casualties are far beyond the
                        official figures. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Moscow, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The workmen here have proclaimed a general strike for the 26th inst.</p>
                    <p>Householders are alarmed and are arming. The people are clamouring for news
                        from St Petersburg, which the censorship is stopping.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The morning was quiet. Patrols are preventing people from gathering.</p>
                    <p>Captains Davidoff and Kazefi, who were in command of the saluting party on
                        the 19th inst., have been arrested.</p>
                    <p>In the evening, fresh collisions took place on Newsky Prospective.</p>
                    <p>One regiment refused to leave in order to put down the riot at Riga.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Sevastopol, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>A fire has broken out at the dockyards of the Admiralty. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Moscow, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The workmen of numerous works have gone on strike. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The newspaper telegrams state that 2,000 people have been killed at St.
                        Petersburg. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH MINISTRY.</head>
                    <dateline>Paris, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The Ministry is constituted as follows : M. Rouvier, President and Finance ;
                        M. Chaumie, Justice ; M. Delcassé, Foreign Affairs ; M. Etienne, Interior ;
                        M. Berteaux, War ; Thomson, Navy ; M. Clement, Colonies ; Gauthier, Public
                        Works ; M. Bienvenu Martin, Public Instruction; M. Dubief, Commerce; Ruan,
                        Agriculture. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>U.S.A. AND SAN DOMINGO. SIGNING OF TREATY.</head>
                    <dateline>Washington, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The United States and the Republic of San Domingo have signed a treaty by
                        which the former establishes a financial tutelage over the latter, at the
                        same time guaranteeing her territorial integrity, (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH NAVAL MANOEUVRES. WORLD-WIDE PARTICIPATION.</head>
                    <dateline>London, January 23.</dateline>
                    <p>The Admiralty announces that the English fleets throughout the world will
                        participate in the 1905 manœuvres on a war basis, in order to test the
                        strategic efficiency of the recent re organisation. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Reunion des Familles Society are giving their second ball of the
                            season at Monferrato's Hall on Saturday next.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Wife Murder</head>
                        <p>A native clerk living at Gabbari yesterday killed his wife by dealing her
                            a blow on the head with a bar of iron. The man escaped and his
                            whereabouts is unknown.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Fatal Accident</head>
                        <p>occurred near Demer dache on Sunday, when the ghaffir who was attached
                            to the Princess Fatma Hanem’s property was run over and killed by the
                            Pont Limoun-Marg train.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Norddeutscher Lloyd S.S. “Schleswig,”</head>
                        <p>which arrived at Alexandria yesterday from Marseilles and Naples,
                            brought 91 first-class and 17 second-class passengers, who left for
                            Cairo by special train.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>12 vessels passed through the Canal on the 20th inst., 8 of which were
                            British, 2 Dutch, 1 Austrian, 1 Danish. The day’s receipts were frs.
                            277,708.22. From the 1st to the 20th inst. the total amount received in
                            dues was frs. 7,320,330.20.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fire at Telephone Office</head>
                        <p>At about 10 o’clock last night a fire broke out in the telephone central
                            office at Kom el-Dik, which caused a complete interruption of the lines
                            connected with this office. The Telephone Company inform us that they
                            will re-establish communication as early as possible.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Prize Distribution</head>
                        <p>The third annual distribution of prizes to Mrs. Emily Elliott Anastes’s
                            pupils takes place this year to-morrow in Mr. G. B. Alderson’s garden,
                            commencing at 4 p.m. punctually. Prizes will be given by the Rev. Canon
                            and Mrs. Ward. Judging by the prettily got-up programme received, a
                            treat is in store for those invited.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Abbas Helmy Theatre</head>
                        <p>As was to be foreseen, Sig. Gravina, the clever comedian of the Italian
                            operetta company, had a most successful benefit night yesterday, when
                            Santarellina, in which he is inimitable, was performed. The large
                            audience was kept in roars’ of laughter by Sig. Gravina’s antics
                            throughout the evening. The other performers also did well.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cairo Scientific Society</head>
                        <p>A meeting of this society will be held at the School of Medicine,
                            Kasr-el-Ainy, Cairo, to-morrow, when Mr. Craig will read “Some notes on
                            a visit to Entebbe,” with lantern demonstration, and Dr. Elliot Smith
                            will read a paper on “Some new facts concerning the superiority of the
                            human brain.” Dr. Elliot Smith will also show a cast of the brain of the
                            okapi. This meeting is open to anyone who cares to attend.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cercle Khédivial, Alexandria</head>
                        <p>The annual general meeting of members of the Khédivial Club was held
                            yesterday evening, Mr. Robert J. Moss in the chair. The balance sheet of
                            1904 was submitted and unanimously approved and passed. The ballot for
                            committeemen for 1905 gave the following result : Messrs. Robert J.
                            Moss, Adr. R. Giro, Hassan Mohsen Pasha, J. R. Aghion, A. Bim-senstein,
                            Paul Cavafy, A. Cesana, A.v. M. Colucci, Ed. Friedheim, F. C. Haselden,
                            Av. M. Romano, Em. Stross, Av. Alfred Tilche, Dr. A. M. Ruffer, J. R.
                            Reeves, Av. C. Castro, H. J. Lancashire, and H. R. C. Blagdeu.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>All Saints’ Church, Ramleh</head>
                        <p>The annual general meeting of the congregation was held at the Parsonage,
                            Bulkeley, on Saturday last, Canon Ward in the chair. The aocounts for
                            1902 were passed and Messrs. C. A. H. Alderson, K. P. Birley, hon.
                            treasurer, and W. R. B. Briscoe, hon. secretary, elected as the
                            committee for 1905, with Mr. W. P. Chataway as supplementary member Mr.
                            James Hewat, who received a vote of thanks for his honorary audit of the
                            accounts, was again elected auditor. Votes of thanks were accorded to
                            Mrs. R. J. Moss for her gifts to the church during the past year, to
                            Canon Ward for taking the chair, and to the outgoing committee.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Keiserlich Deutches Konsulat. BEKANNTMACHUNG</head>
                    <p>Jm diesseitigen Handelaregiater ist bei der Komrranditgeaellachaft R. Kuater
                        A Co. eingetragen wo den :</p>
                    <p>Die G. sellechaft ist aufgelost. Die Firma ist erloachen. Die Prokura dee
                        Kaufmann Harry Ablitt in Alexandrie ist erloschen.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrien, den 23 Januar 1905.</p>
                    <p>Der Kaiserhche Konsul.</p>
                    <p>J, No. 811. L.S. 258264</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DUKE OF CONNAUGHT. ARRANGEMENTS FOR ARRIVAL</head>
                    <p>T .R. H. the Duke and Duchess of Connaught are expected to reach Alexandria
                        on board H. M. S. “Essex" on Thursday morning probably about 11 o'clock, and
                        will at once leave tor Cairo, where they are due to arrive about 4 o'clock.
                        As before stated, their Royal Highnesses will proceed to Abbeen Palace where
                        they will be the guests of the Khedive.</p>
                    <p>On Thursday night H. H. the Khedive will give a banquet at Abdeen Palace in
                        honor of T. R. H. the Duke and Duchess of Connaught The Princes of the
                        Khedivial Family, the Ministers, Lord and Lady Cromer, the foreign
                        diplomatic Agents, and the personnel of the British Agency have been
                        invited.</p>
                    <p>Their Royal Highnesses will leave Cairo on the following night for Khartoum,
                        and their programme up river will probably be as before stated, but it has
                        been decided that the Royal party will make their own arrangements, while
                        Nhugovich Bey will cany out all the necessary arrangements during their stay
                        in Cairo both this week and on their return.</p>
                    <p>The following is published in Army Orders :</p>
                    <p>His Royal Highness the Inspector General of the Forces is expected to reach
                        Alexandria and Cairo On 26th inst.</p>
                    <p>" He will be met on landing at Alexandria by the Brigadier General
                        Commanding, Commanding Officers, Hoads of Departments, at Alexandria, and a
                        Guard of Honor, consisting of 1 Captain, *2 Subalterns, a duo proportion of
                        Sergeants, and 100 rank and file, with the King's Colour and Band, to bo
                        detailed by the Brigadier General Commanding, Alexandria</p>
                    <p>“ He will be met at Cairo railway station by the General Officer Commanding
                        in Egypt, Commanding Officers, Heads of Departments, in Cairo, and a Guard
                        of Honor, consisting of l Captain, 2 Subalterns, a due proportion</p>
                    <p>of Sergeants, and 100 rank and tile, with the King's Colour and Band, 2nd Bn.
                        Royal Inni-skilling xxxxx."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will receive Prince Arfat ed Dawlah Khan, Persian Ambassador at
                        Constantinople, at Abdeen Palace to-day and will return the Prince’s visit
                        at the Continental Hotel.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been graciously pleased to bestow the following decorations
                        :</p>
                    <p>Medjidieh -Grand Officer (2nd class) M. George Zervudachi, notable of
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Commander 3rd class) ; Soliman Zeitoun Bey. Omdeh of Kafr-el Hamam, M.
                        Miltiadi Avierni, and M. Charies Bacos, notables of Officer (4th class) M.
                        John Zoucas, engi- Osnianaeh Officer (4th class) Youssef Zouhny Bey and
                        Ahmad Rifat Bey, notables</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT'S PROSPERITY.</head>
                    <p>The value, in Egyptian pounds, of specie declared at the Egyptian Customs
                        during 1094 was as follows :</p>
                    <p>Gold Imported, L E. 7,042,949.</p>
                    <p>Silver Imported, ,, 593,915.</p>
                    <p>Gold Exported, „ 2,724,157.</p>
                    <p>Silver Exported, „ 6,733.</p>
                    <p>These figures are very significant of the extraordinary prosperity of the
                        country, no less than L É. 4,288,792 having been added to the net wealth of
                        the country in specie alone during the last twelve months.</p>
                    <p>A. L M &amp; D. S.</p>
                    <p>It would really have been difficult to devise a more attractive programme
                        than that which has been arranged for the recital to be given to morrow
                        evening at Mon-ferrato's - Hall by Mr. H. Scott-Leslie under the auspices of
                        the Alexandria Literary, Musical and Dramatic Society. The versatile
                        entertainer will contribute the following items : Musical monologue, " The
                        Lesson of the Water Mill," humorous sketch, “Matilda and the Builder (The
                        Girl from Kay's), character sketch, "E can't take a roise out 'o oi,” a
                        dissertation on mediaeval poetry, “Taffy was a Welshman," a ghost story, the
                        following song», "The Horse the Missus dries the clothes on."</p>
                    <p>Nothing New," "Something quite original,"</p>
                    <p>‘ He J. Hann, “I'm tired," and short stories. He will be supported by Mr.
                        David W. Norton pianist) and members of the society. Mr. Norton will play
                        Rachmaninoffs Prelude—C. Diez. Minor, selections from The Country Girl, and
                        the solo, "lmperial Patrol." Miss Mun-Gavin will sing "Voices of the Past”
                        and ' Beloved, it is Morn, ’ with violin obbligato by Miss Gibson, Mr. R. M.
                        Nixon will contribute ‘The Outpost's Vigil" and "Blow, blow, thou Winter
                        Wind," and some members of the choral union will give the madrigal “True
                        Love" from The Cingalee and the glee, "The Old Norse Song." With such a
                        plethora of talent, the hall should be filled to its utmost capacity.
                        Messrs. Davies Bryan &amp; Co. are selling non members' tickets at P.T.
                        15.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Cunard S.S. “Cypria” will arrive on Thursday and will immediately begin
                        loading for Liverpool and American ports.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Amas is" arrived at Liver-pool yesterday morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel In Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Jentral position. Under English management</p>
                    <p>81-11-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SACRILEGIOUS THEFT. LE. 8,000 STOLEN FROM HOLY CARPET'S ESCORT.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Suez, Tuesday. 10.50 a.m.</dateline>
                    <p>This year’s pilgrimage has already met with a most unfortunate contre-temps,
                        even | before the Mahmal has left Egyptian territory.</p>
                    <p>I learn that a case of specie belonging to the I Mahmal, and valued at L B.
                        8,000, was stolen yesterday on the train near Genife station.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARRIVAL AT SUEZ </head><byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Monday.</dateline>
                    <p>The special train conveying the Holy Carpet t arrived at Suez at 3 o'clock
                        this afternoon, and on arrival of the train at the station, a saluté of 21
                        guns was fired from the fort. Thousands of pilgrims, mingling with the
                        natives of Suez, paraded the streets with flags, and the town presented a
                        lively aspect</p>
                    <p>At about 4 o’clock the procession of the Holy Carpet took place. It was
                        escorted by cavalry, infantry, and artillery, numbering 407 officers and
                        men, under the command of Miralai Mohamed Bey Rifaat, as well as by
                        detachments of Coast Guards, and the military band. Towards evening the
                        Mahmal was con-veyed to the docks by the same special train, to be placed on
                        board the Khédivial steamer ' Rahmanieh," which is due to sail on Wednesday
                        for Jeddah.</p>
                    <p>This is a record year for the pilgrimage on account of the large number of
                        Egyptian pilgrims, which exceeds 16,000, as against</p>
                    <p>12.000 last year.</p>
                    <p>The pilgrims are conveyed by the Khédivial steamers to Tor, where they purge
                        five days' quarantine, and thence the same company’s steamers carry them on
                        to Jeddah.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN INVESTMENT AND AGENCY, LTD.</head>
                    <p>The rush of investors yesterday to subscribe to the Egyptian Investment and
                        Agency, Limited, was extraordinary. All day long the National Bank of Egypt
                        was besieged by masses of people, with the result that the amount tendered
                        for subscription in Egypt was» £3,150,000, whereas the total capital of the
                        company is only £200,000.</p>
                    <p>The amount over-subscribed in London is also very large.</p>
                    <p>Owing to this rush there will necessarily be some delay in the allotment</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN LAND INVESTMENT CO.</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Land Investment Company is one of the latest of the many similar
                        ventures, which are being daily launched at Alexandria. It objects are
                        described as follows</p>
                    <p>L'achat et vente do terrains à bâtir, propriétés baties ou biens ruraux en
                        Egypte ou au Soudan, ainsi que toutes affaires ou opérations, dont le
                        caractère ou le but serait de nature à faire valoir ses acquisitions ou a
                        contribuer au développement des affaires immobilières en général.</p>
                    <p>The capital is LE 100,000, divided into 20.000 shares of LE 5 each, which
                        have all been subscribed by the following:—</p>
                    <p>Shares LE</p>
                    <p>A. Bartau Pasha 16,200 81,000</p>
                    <p>Ismail Pasha Kamel Yaken 1.000 5,000</p>
                    <p>Kalil Pasha Kayat 600 3,000</p>
                    <p>Augusto Luzzatto 500 2,500</p>
                    <p>Tigrane Gamsaragan 1,000 5,000</p>
                    <p>Michel Reizian Bey 200 1,000</p>
                    <p>Yrvanthe Agathon Bey 200 1,000</p>
                    <p>Emanuel Stross 300 1,500</p>
                    <p>Total 20,000 100,000</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE.</head>
                    <p>The annual general meeting of members of the British Chamber of Commerce will
                        be held in the offices of Messrs. Carver Bros &amp; Co., Ltd., Alexandria,
                        on Tuesday, 7th February, at 4 p.m.. The following business is to bo
                        transacted :—</p>
                    <p>1 To pass the accounts and balance sheet for 1904.</p>
                    <p>2. To receive the committee's report of the past year's work.</p>
                    <p>3 To fill vacancies in the committee.</p>
                    <p>4. To consider a proposal to alter No. 5 of the articles of association By
                        the following additions :—</p>
                    <p>A committee of 12 shall bo elected by the Cairo members to sit in Cairo,
                        subject to the rules which govern the Alexandria committee. Minutes of the
                        Alexandria and Cairo committees to be exchanged and the Alexandria committee
                        to remain the executive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO RACES.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Lient-Colonel G. M. Mackenzie, commanding, and
                        officers, 2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will play the following
                        programme at the Cairo races to morrow afternoon :</p>
                    <p>March—"Tho Thunderer”—Sousa.</p>
                    <p>Overture “Stradolla”—Flotow.</p>
                    <p>Entr'acte—“Rose Mousse”—Bose.</p>
                    <p>Selection—“Reminiscences of the Plantation"</p>
                    <p>—Chambers.</p>
                    <p>Valse—“Amoretten Tanze"—Gnng'l.</p>
                    <p>Song—“A Child's Song of Hope"—Myddleton. Morceau—"La Lettre de Manon"—Gillet
                        Selection—"A Country Girl"—Monckton.</p>
                    <p>Regimental March.</p>
                    <p>Khédivial Anthem.</p>
                    <p>God Save the King.</p>
                    <p>R. Watson Ramsey, Bandmaster,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Sir John Maxwell left London last week for Egypt where he will join the Duke
                        of Connaught. He has not been in Egypt since he was hurriedly summoned from
                        Khartoum in January, 1900, by Lord Kitchener, to take part in the South
                        African war.</p>
                    <p>Mr Walrond, Lord Milner's private secret ary, who has been visiting Cairo,
                        left yesterday for South Africa.</p>
                    <p>The Financial Adviser and Mr. H N. Bowdon-Smith returned from Khartoum
                        yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel include Lady Londesborough, who
                        arrived by the "Bremen,” Mr. Beadleston, Col. and Mme. R. de Planta, Hon.
                        Mrs. Ronald Greville, Dr. and Mme. Aufachlaeger, Prof, and Mrs. D Vail, Mr.
                        William McEwan, Mr. and Mrs. C. B. Burr, Miss M. Beardsley, Mias J. T.
                        Sullivan, Mr. Edgar Anderson, and Mr. J. W. Wyatt.</p>
                    <p>Dr. John Garner has been promoted from assistant inspector to inspector of
                        the Sanitary Department.</p>
                    <p>Kaimakam Patterson Bey, Sub-Commandant of the Cairo City Police, has been
                        granted two months' leave, dating from Sunday.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo for the Nile by the P. S. "Amenartas"
                        yesterday; Mrs. Colls and friend, Dr. John and Mrs. Adcock, Mr. W. H.
                        Sharpe, Mrs. Fred Sharpe, Mr. R. Thompson, Mrs. Ewart, Miss Doweling, Mrs.
                        Pitt, Mrs. Poole, Mrs. Henry Wild, Miss</p>
                    <p>R. D. Wild, Mrs. and Miss Bagshaw.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left by the “Ra-meses the Great” to-day :—Mr. and
                        Mrs. Allred Ashby, Mr. and Mrs. C. F. Adams, Mias E 0. Adams, Mr. Harold
                        Arrowsmith, Mr. and Mrs. Bone Mr. J. A. Bleackley, Miss Bruster, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Bendit, Mr. and Mrs. James W. Benson, Miss M. D. Beardsley, Mr. and
                        Mrs. C. P. Burr, Mr. and Mrs. Paul Chabrier, Miss Elsie Cope, Miss Lilian
                        Cope, Mrs. de la Camp, Prince de Tonnay Charente, Miss Campbell, Surg.-Maj.
                        General Campbell Fraser, Mr. and Mrs. A. R. Garland, Mr. W. A. Gardner, Mr.
                        Gardner (Jn.), Mr. and Mrs. Julius Hirschter, Mrs. E. H. Holliday, Count de
                        Hunolstein, Miss Hubard, Mrs. Allen Haigh, Commander and Mrs. Knolles, Miss
                        Alice Logan, Gen. Lar-nac, Mr. Sotus Madsen, Mr. Consul Emil Muller, Miss
                        Elise Muller, Duo de Mortemart, Mrs. Kate Mitchell, Mr. Otto Nielsen,
                        Mrs.</p>
                    <p>S. T. Poetlethwaite, Miss C. S. Postlethwaita, Mr. and Mrs. W. Pendle, Miss
                        Pendle, Mrs. J. W. Paxton, Miss Gertrude Paxton, Marquis d’Audiffret
                        Pasquier, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Plummer, Mrs. F. H. Rogers, Miss C. Rogers,
                        Master F. H. Rogers, Mr. 0. Rosenkranz, Mr. Lensing Reed, Miss Julia
                        Sulilvan, Hr. A. J, Samerville (Jn.), Mr. Harold Phelps Stokes, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Morefield Storey. Mrs. Louise Sibeth, Miss Helene van Villeneuve, Mr. Arthur
                        Whitaker, Miss Whitaker, Mr. and Mrs. Ingram Whitaker, Mrs. P. C.
                        Woodruff.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers are leaving Assiout by the "Amasis" to-day : Mr. and
                        Mme. Felipe A. de Llavallol, Miss Ines Llavallol, Miss M. Elena Llavallol,
                        Mme. E I. de Elia, Mme. A. E de Ortis Basualdo, Mr. S. Ortis Basualdo, Miss
                        F. Ortis Basualdo, Miss Anna T. Ortis Basualdo, Miss M. Kin, Mrs. David
                        Anderson, Misses Anderson, Mme. de Weertt, Master de Weertt, Mrs. T. H.
                        Smallman, Miss E C. R. Smallman, Miss Hammer, Mr. Bannister Fletcher, Miss
                        Nora Walls, Miss Rath Buchanan, Mrs. P. A. Hearst, Miss Louise de Cistne,
                        Miss Antonia de Cistne, Miss J. C. Egan, Mr. A. and Mrs. Callame, Mr.
                        Fernand Mosselman, Miss Alice Noerbel, Miss Marta Cicognara, Mr. Louis
                        Voyeler, Mr. L La Ferme, Mr. and Mrs. G. U. Clausen.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. "Schleswig," arrived yesterday from Marseilles and Naples :—</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. von Alten, Mr. Abellini, Baron Z. van Brakell, Mrs. F. Bennett,
                        Mr. and Mrs. H. Biagosch, Miss H. Biagosch, Mr. Victor Bigler, Mr. A. and
                        Mr. E Bonigal, Mr. and Mrs. Louis Bendid, Mr. and Mrs. J. Munroe Coats, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Coats, Miss Creswell, Mr. and Mrs. Hermann Cohn, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Gustavo Cohn, Mrs. and Miss Crowley, Miss Dunn, Mr. and Mrs. F. Dinger, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Emerey. Baroness Frauk, Mr. Ew. Fischer, Mr. Félix Fuld, Dr. Johann
                        Guthmann, Mr. Robert Guthmann. Mr. and Mrs. Walter Goldschmidt, Mrs.
                        Gobbart, Mrs. Goebel, Hon. Lady Harvey, Mr. F. Hardee, Mr. and Mrs. Paul
                        Haffter, Mr. W. Hùttner, Mrs. Alfred Harrison, Miss Harrison, Mr. Horsham,
                        Miss Marie von Kramsta, Dr. and Mrs. Ludwig Korn, Mr. and Mrs. Carl Kropp,
                        Miss Clara Kropp, Miss Johanna Kaltenbacb, Mr. and Mrs. I. H. Krahforst, Mr.
                        Rudoll Koritzky, Mr. W. T. Koch, Mr. and Mrs. Maurioe de La Bouglise, Mr.
                        Auguste Le Brun, Miss M. A. Lamy, Mr. Hermann E. Lawford, Miss Johanne von
                        Len-gurke, Mr. and Mrs. J. Livingston, Mr. L. de M. Macmillan, Mrs. Carl
                        Müller,Mr. and Mrs.J. D. Miller, Mr. and Mrs. Meller, Mrs. H. F. Mao-uulay,
                        Mr. Thomas O’Hagan, Mr. and Mrs. Meyer, Miss H. Porter, Mr. G. A. Pfizer,
                        ;Miss Emma Potthoff, Miss Phipps, Mr. and Mrs. Carl Poensgen, Miss Poensgen,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Petera, Mr. R. Pilling, Mr. H. H. Peace, Miss Reeves, Miss
                        Eleanor R. Ralph, Miss M. E Richardson, Mr. W. H. Rider, Director and Mrs.
                        Hava, Miss Lucie Sulzer, Mr. Scoles, Mrs. da Silva, Mr. and Mrs. S. H.
                        Valentine, Baron E de Wecker, M. and Mme. Wirth, Mr. Wirth, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Paul Wiesenthal, Mrs. Wetzler, Dr. Wm. Hunter Workman, Mrs. J. Bullock
                        Workman, Mr. Edmond Walmisley, Mr. Georg Zeidler.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="chroniqueFinanciere">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE</head>
                    <p>La semaine avait bien débuté, avec tendance marquée à la hausse, lorsque
                        toutrà-ooup l'apris#-midi du 19, une réaction s'est produite, causée par les
                        réalisations et les nouvelles politiquw inquiétantes. Les dépéchas d'hier
                        ont fait dégénérer le recul en vraie débandade.</p>
                    <p>Trop vite oublieux, en effet, de la débâcle récente, certains spéculateurs,
                        entraînés par la hausse, avaient pris dee positions intenables pour leurs
                        faibles moyens. Aussi, quand la réaction est arrivée, ont-ils dû se retirer.
                        Un petit parti baissier fort bruyant s’est organisé et, profitant d'un oôté
                        de l'extrême resserve des acheteurs et de l’autre des réalisation» et de
                        l'incertitude du marché, il a réussi, an partie au moins, à casser Isa prix.
                        La valeur la plus éprouvée sous oa rapport a été la National Bank ; elle
                        avait aussi été la plus favorisée ; elle avait haussé de prés de 2 £ 1/2 en
                        deux jours.</p>
                    <p>On avait voulu marcher trop vite. Au fond, pourtant, la situation n'est pas
                        mauvaise, si l'on considere qu'il n’existe presque pas da position de fin du
                        mois, le petit publio ayant de ou réaliser ou se défaire avec perte.
                        L'avenii est donc asses not. Les détenteurs qui restée sont pour la plupart
                        dee capitalistes an état d&lt; soutenir le choc d’une forte baisse, sans
                        trop m laisser impressionner. 11 va sans dire que si les bourses de Paris et
                        de Londres sont fortement affectées, on en ressentira ici le oontre-ooup, au
                        moins dans une certaine mesure. En tout cas, on espère, aussitôt le calme
                        rétabli, qu'une bonne reprise aura heu, ru l'abondanoe manifeste do capitaux
                        sur cotre place. Un fait symptomatique de oette richesse est l'expédition
                        faite en Europe samedi dernier par une banque locale de un million de livres
                        sterling ; il wt très rare, en effet, qu’en pareille saison on expédie du
                        numéraire à l'étranger ; c'est presque toujours le contraire qui a lieu.
                        ^</p>
                    <p>La National Bank a eu, on peut le dire, les honneurs de la semaine. Elle a
                        passé de 24 1/f i 26 1/2 pour retomber hier soir en cloture f 24 1346 La
                        Nouvelle Emission a suivi h même mouvement et clôturé ferme à 23 7/8, Le
                        chiffre des transactions a atteint plusieurs milliers de titras par
                        jour.</p>
                    <p>L'Agricole, qui était aussi ferme au début a 10 1/16, a atteint 10 13/16 pour
                        finir à 1( acheteurs, en assez bonne tendance.</p>
                    <p>De 14 1/2 la Delta Light tombe en clôtun à 14 3/16. La Deferred est à 16 SL
                        sans aflai-res.</p>
                    <p>Les Privilégiées Tramways d’Alexandrie onf fluctué entre 143 1/2 et 146.
                        Elles clôturent acheteurs à 144. Les Dividendes sont au prix</p>
                    <p>de 360 — 365 nominal.</p>
                    <p>La Ramleh Railway débutai 8 7/16, fléchit i 8 1/8 et reprend a 8 1/4.</p>
                    <p>D’importantes affaires ont eu lieu en Sait &amp; Soda, mais le mouvement ne
                        se dessinera sur cette valeur qu'après l’assemblée du 27 courant En
                        attendant le cours suit les fluo--tuations générales ; il tombe (le 43 i
                        89/9, pour reprendre légèrement vers la fin à 40/3 ferme.</p>
                    <p>En Nungovich nous fléchissons do 10 1/8 i 9 9/16, pour remonter en clôture i
                        9 3/4. La rumeur d'une fusion a été officiellement démentie.</p>
                    <p>L'Anglo-American Nile recule de 5 5/16 à 5 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>La Crown Brewery u’a pas présenté une grande animation durant cette semaine
                        Le cours a fluctué de 216 i 220 pour clôturer</p>
                    <p>i 215.</p>
                    <p>De son côté, la Brassorie des Pyramides débuta i 126, monta i 130 et
                        réactionne i 128.</p>
                    <p>La Banque d'Athènes suit la baisse générale. Après avoir touché un moment 125
                        1/2, elle fléchit i 118 1/2 pour finir hier soir i 119 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Contrairement aux autres valeurs, les Baux du Caire gagnent du terrain :
                        après avoir fléchi un instant de 1,105 à 1,070, elles reprennent bientôt à
                        1,120 en clôture.</p>
                    <p>Les Eaux d'Alexandrie restant délaissées à 15 7/8.</p>
                    <p>Commo les Eaux du Caire, la‘Khédivial Mail donne lieu à une bonne demande et
                        remonta de ce fait de 3 13/16 à 4 1/8 acheteurs. L'Ordinary hausse également
                        da 11 à 13 shelling.’.</p>
                    <p>Les Obligations Crédit Foncier réactionnent de 300 à 296 en clôture.</p>
                    <p>Los Markets fléchissent aussi de 23/9 à 23 vendeurs.</p>
                    <p>Une grande activité a régné sur Is Corpora tion of Wostern Egypt (Oasis). Le
                        prix a subi do violentas fluctuations ; de 1 3/4 il a haussé jusqu’à 2 7/16,
                        pour retomber aussitôt à 1 9/16 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui, midi et demie).</p>
                    <p>Ce matin, sur d’importants rachats, les cours de certaines valeurs regagnent
                        en partie le ter rain perdu.</p>
                    <p>Ainsi la Banque Nationalo remonta de 24 3/4 à 25 1/2, l’Agricole de 10 à 10
                        1/2, laDaira de 21 3/4 à 22 1/16, la Nungovich die 9 3/4 à 9 13/16, la Delta
                        Light de 14 3/16 à 14 5/16, et les Privilégiées Tramways de 144 à 145
                        1/2.</p>
                    <p>La hausse de la Khédivial Mail atteint 4 1/4.</p>
                    <p>Le marché en général est plus ferme et la tendance meilleure.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Manage ment. Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
