<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 11, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section"><head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>PORT ARTHUR</head>
                        <head type="sub">PRISONERS FOR JAPAN. MINES DESTROYED.</head>
                        <p>Port Arthur, January 10.</p>
                        <p>On the 6th inst. 5,000 men of the Russian garrison marched from Pigeon Bay 15 miles to Chang-ling-tsu railway station, and thence took the train for Dalny. Pathetic scenes occurred.</p>
                        <p>The Japanese have already repaired the railway and changed the gauge as far as Port Arthur. Trains will be able to enter here in a few days.	(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, January 10.</p>
                    <p>Large batches of Port Arthur prisoners are arriving in Japan daily.</p>
                    <p>It is officially announced that hitherto the mine-clearing vessels have destroyed 395 mines within a radius of 40 miles from Port Arthur.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>GENERALS STOESSEL AND NOGI.</head><head type="sub">HONOURED BY THE KAISER</head>
                        <p>Berlin, January 10.</p>
                        <p>Emperor William has conferred the Order of Merit on Generals Stoessel and Nogi. (Havas)</p>
                        <p>Berlin, January 10.</p>
                        <p>The Kaiser has confered the Order of Merit on Generals Stoessel and Nogi in recognition of their heroic bravery at Port Arthur. 	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>FRENCH SENATOR AND THE WAR.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>M. Gouin, senior Senator, in his opening address to the Senate, said that he hoped the new year would see the end of this bloody war between two Powers, one of which has seen so many of its soldiers immolated in the finest defence ever known, whilst the other has gained the admiration of Europe by the greatness of the bravery which it has displayed.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>The Enquiry Commission has again discussed its mode of procedure privately. (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>FRENCH CHAMBER OF DEPUTIES.</head>
                        <head type="sub">ELECTION OF M DOUMER.</head>
                            <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                            <p>M. Doumer has been elected President of the Chamber of Deputies by 265 votes against 240 polled by M. Brisson.	(Havas.)</p>
                            <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                            <p>The Chambers have reassembled. Doumer, a notable opponent of M. Combes,
                                has been elected President of the Chamber by 265, defeating M. Brisson, who polled 240	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO.</head>
                        <p>Tangier, January 10.</p>
                        <p>M. René St. Taillandier will leave to-morrow for Fez in order to give advice concerning reforms to the Moorish Government, who have declared that they will abide by it.	(Havas.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>GOLD FOR JAPAN.</head>
                        <p>San Francisco, January 10. The S.S. "China” is shipping half-a-million of gold to-day from here for Japan. (Reuter.)</p></div></div>
                <div type="item"><p>one night only
                    Saturday, January 14, at 9.30. KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>Under the distinguished Patronage and in the presence of: E. B. GOULD, Esq., I.S.O., H.B.M.’s Consul-General; Brig. General G. M. BULLOCK, C.B., and Admiral Sir MASSIE and Lady BLOMFIELD.</p></div>
                
                <div type="item"><p>H. SCOTT LESLIE
                    (The well-known London Entertainer and Raconteur)
                    Will give a Humorous and musical
                    RECITAL
                    Supported by Mr. David H. Norton,
                    Pianist (Queen's Hall, London).
                    -
                    -
                    -
                    -
                    ADMISSION P.T. 20.
                    M*4 M</p></div>
                <div type="section"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item"><p>A Rifle Meeting is to be hold in Cairo early in March, after the manoeuvres.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at G.P.O., Alexandria, at 7.45 a.m. to-morrow.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Inspection.—Major-General Slade, C. B., will inspect the detachment of the 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade at the Citadel, Cairo, to-morrow morning at 9.30.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Bracale Orchestra plays at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, on Wednesday afternoon and Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, and Saturday evenings.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>A GamBling Hell was raided on Monday morning by the Cairo police. It was situated in Rue el-Mahdi and baccarat was being played at the time the descent was made.</p></div>	
                    <div type="item"><p>The Italian Cruiser "Urania" (Capt. J. Tutinelli Reudina) arrived at Port Said on Monday from Massowah, bound to Taranto. She carries 7 guns, and has a crew of 124.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Zizinia Theatre.—Owing to the indisposition of Signa. Angelica Pandolfini, there was no performance yesterday evening. This evening the 29th performance of the season will be given, when Siberia will be staged.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Camel Post—Owing to the train service between Haifa and Kerma, and vice-versa, having been discontinued on the 31st December, 1904, all mails between these two places are now carried by camels, and the money order service to and fromm stations on this line—other than Kosha—has ceased.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Hired Transports "Plassy” and "Dilwara" are due to arrive at Port Said on the 17th and 18th inst., respectively. Military details proceeding home in the "Plassy" will leave Cairo by the 6.15 p.m. train and Alexandria by the 3.30 p.m. train on the 16th, and those to go in the "Dilwara" will leave Cairo and Alexandria by the trains leaving at the same hours on the 17th instant.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Late Menshawi Pasha has bequeathed by his will properties producing no less a sum than £40,000 a-year to various mosques and charitable institutions in different parts of the country. His eldest son, who was sentenced eleven years ago to penal servitude for 20 years for acts of brigandage, has addressed a petition to the Khedive and the Government for a remission of the remainder of his sentence.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Indicateur Egyptian for 1905 has made its nineteenth annual appearance, and, usual, contains all the essentials which are so conspicuous a feature of this old-establlshed directory. Mr. Stefano Pottandi, the editor of the work, is to be congratulated, for many new features have been added to this year's directory, which is the best of its kind in the country.	Tantah and many other provincial centres have been included in this edition.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Recital. — Mr. Scott-Leslie, the society entertainer, is giving a recital at the New Khedivial Hotel on Saturday next, at 9.30 p.m. Mr. Scott-Leslie, who is an artiste to his finger tips, is almost too well-known to need any recommendation on our part. He comes with an excellent reputation, and we hope to see a large audience greet him on Saturday. He is assisted by Mr. David W. Norton, pianist (Queen’s Hall, London), and his programme includes pianotorte selections, musical monologues, songs, character sketches, and funny stories, at telling which Mr. Scott-Leslie is an adept.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Cairo Hospitals and Nursing Homes. — As a proof of the immense increase in the population of Cairo, and especially the European portion, during the past twenty years or so, it is interesting to note that whereas in 1882 there were only three hospitals, viz., the European General Hospital at Abbassieb, since, disused, the Kasr el Aïni Hospital, and the Hospital for the Insane, there are now no less than fifteen hospitals and nursing homes in the Metropolis, scattered over an area extending over ten square miles. In this number are included the different military hospitals for both British and Egyptian troops.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>E.T.C. Dramatic Entertainment at Suez. —The festivities in Suez to commemorate the recent visit of a Port - Said football team culminated on Friday last in an entertainment in the E. T. C. theatre, given by the "Exiles" Dramatic Club. The first part of the programme was vocal. "Good-bye, Dolly Gray" was well rendered by - Mr. Durrant, but it must have been very sad for poor Dolly, who should have felt convinced of the absolute finality of the poor man’s departure. Messrs. Churchill, Dug-more, and Blyth were all good, but the “clou" was undoubtedly the ventriloquial sketch by Mr. O. D. Harris; in fact, it has seldom been our experience to hear a better sketch of this variety off the professional stage. The second part, an original farce, '"The Mummy and the Mummer,” by Mr. O. D. Harris, made many of the audience wonder whether we have not in this gentleman a future Pinero. All the recent political and social events in Suez were cleverly brought in by the young author, and  we hope an occasion will soon be found to give this talented young dramatist an occasion to  write another local sketch.</p></div></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head><p>
                    On Monday night the Khedive was present at the performance of Les Trois Anaptistes at the Khedivial Opera House.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday morning, his Highness gave a private audience to the Grand Mufti, Sheikh Mohamed Abdou.</p></div>	
                <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE INTERVIEWED</head><p>
                    A French journalist has published in the Parisian newspaper “Gil Bias" an interesting account of an interview which be had with the Khedive on December 20. The article concludes with the following anecdote :—</p>
                    <p>"Et pour terminer une anecdote que le Khédive nous a racontée au sujet du mariage d’uue de ses sceurs qui alla visiter l’Exposition de Saint-Louis l’été dernier avec son mari. Je laisse de nouveau la parole à Son Altesse.</p>
                    <p>— J’ai toujours eu, nous dit-elle, la plus grande envie d’aller aux Etat-Unis et, certes, je ne me serais jamais douté que la princesse, ma sœur, y irait avant moi. Elle m’a, du reste, rapporté une collection magnifique de photographies, dont plusieurs ont été prises dans des circonstances extraordinaires. La princesse eut le malheur de se trouver dans un accident de chemin de fer, mais au lieu de perdre la téte, comme presque toutes les personnes qui l’en-touraient, elle photographia toute la scene! Il eu fut do meme quand elle se trouva a bord d’un bateau à pétrole qui prit feu.</p>
                    <p>" Voilà qui est vraiment intéressant : le calme et la présence d’esprit de la princesse égyptieune sont tout-à-lait dignes du pays ou elle les déploya—le pays des femmes libres et fortes. "</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>HOLY CARPET.</head><p>
                    The departure of the Holy Carpet will take place with trie usual ceremonial on Thursday, 19th inst., at Cairo. The Khedive will preside and all the Government administrations will be closed on that day.</p>
                    <p>The Mahmal and its escort will leave on the 20th and 21st inst. by special trains for Suez en route for Jeddah.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of the Interior has decided that persons desirous of accompanying the Mahmal caravan as pilgrims must be at Suez at the latest on the 19th inst, when they must await the Mahmal. No pilgrim will be allowed to leave Cairo by the special train which will convey the Mahmal.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head><p>
                    The Khedive has been most graciously pleased to confer the 3rd class Osmanieh on El Miralai G. F. Gorringe Bey, C.M.G., D.S.O. Sudan Government.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been moat graciously pleased to approve of the following promotions;</p>
                    <p>El Bimbashi W. B. Drury, Sudan Government, to be Kaitnakam.</p>
                    <p>El Bimbasbi R. C. K. Owen, Sudan Govern-ment, to be Kaimakam.</p>
                    <p>Captain A. E J. Wilson, Northumberland Fusiliers, having reported his arrival in Egypt from England, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army, with the rank of Bimbashi and has been posted to the 13th Sudanese.</p>	
                    <p>Paragraph 3, "War Office Gazette” No. 49, of 1904, striking El Kaimakam N.T. Borton Bey, Sudan Government off the strength of the Egyptian Army from 1-12-04, has been cancelled.</p>
                    <p>The following transfers and appointments have been approved from dates stated:— El Kaimakam A. Cameron Bey, Officer Commanding, Arab Battalion, to Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi W. F. Sweny, 11th Sudanese, to be Acting Officer Commanding, Arab Battalion, 1-1-05. El Bimbasbi H. D. E. O'Sulivan, 12th Sudanese to Sudan Government, 1-1-05. El Bimbashi F. G. Poole, D.S.O., 4th Battalion, to Sudan Government 1:1-05. .El Bimbashi J.C. Gruhame, D.S.O., 12th Sudanese, to Sudan Government 1-0-05. El Bimbashi J. H.M. Arden, 1st Battalion, to 4th Battalion, 1-1 05. El Bimbashi K. B. Airey, Department of Supplies, to Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi L. W. Le M. Carey, 10th Sudanese to 16th Battalion, 1-1-05. El Bimbashi R. L. Moore, Cavalry, to Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi A. Wise, 16th Battalion, to 1st Battalion, 1-1-05.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE BENSILUM CASE.</head><p>
                    The verdict in the enquiry into the circumstances attending the death of Mr. Angel Bensilum will not be given until Friday next. The enquiry has been continuing at H.M.’s Consular Court, Cairo, but there are some more witnesses to give evidence, including Herz Bey, in whose employ the deceased was. The jury consists of Messrs. Biancardi, Spiro, and Heath. The report of the discovery of the body of Mr. Bensilum in the Nile appeared in our columns recently.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>EGYPT AND JAPAN.</head><p>
                    Some Turks living in Cairo sent a telegram of congratulation to the Mikado on the fall of Port Arthur, to which his Majesty, has replied through his Minister of the Imperial Household thanking them for their telegram.</p>
                    <p>Two leading Armenians of Cairo also wrote to Marshal Yamagata congratulating him on the recent triumphs gained by the Japanese over the oppressors of the Armenian inhabitants in the Caucasus, and sent a small case of cigarettes manufactured specially at their factory and stamped with the arms of Japan and the Marshal's initials for his
                        own use. They have just received a letter of thanks in reply, of which the two Armenians are very proud.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE RUSSIAN SQUADRON</head>
                    <head type="sub">MOORED AT PORT SAID.</head><p>
                        (From Our Own Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Port-Said, Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Batrovsky’s Squadron was off the port at 2.30 p.m. and the ships are now all moored in the positions specified in my wire of yesterday. They will be permitted to take fresh water, provisions, and a limited quantify
                        of coal.</p>
                    <p>The squadron consists of 4 cruisers, “Oleg,
                        "Izumrud," "Rion,” and "Dnieper,” and 3 torpedo-boat destroyers, “Rezvi,” “Gromki,” and "Grozin."</p>
                    <p>The time of entry into the canal is not yet fixed.</p>
                    <p>The British yacht .“Emerald,” which preceded the last squadron and cruised in the Red Sea, has also arrived from Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The Coast Guard cruiser “Abbas” entered the harbour after the fleet.</p>
                    <p>The town is full of Russian secret agents, but there is only one Japanese here.</p>
                    <p>The Russian Diplomatic Agent, and Russian Naval Attache arrived from Cairo last night, also a force of extra police.</p>
                    <p>The same precautions will be taken as were taken when the last fleet passed.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that nothing is known at the British Agency in reference to the alleged protest made by the Japanese Government against the supply of fresh water and provision to the fleet</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>SUEZ CANAL PILOTS.</head><p>
                    While the present agitation against the treatment meted out to shipowners generally by the Suez Canal Company is before the public, an opportunity is afforded of drawing attention to another instance, in which justice, at least, is not done to British shipowners, namely, in the pilotage service.</p>
                    <p>To deal with the 4,000 ships which annually either transit the Canal or touch at Port Said and Suez, the company employs some 94 pilots of various nationalities, as follows:--</p>
                    <p>No. of Pilots National percentage of shipping 	in transit.</p> 
                    <p>Greek 	29	 0.2</p>
                    <p>Italian	 20	 1.9</p>
                    <p>French	16 7.0 </p>
                    <p>Austrian 14	 3.4</p>
                    <p>British 	11 	60.6</p>
                    <p>German 2	13.1 </p>
                    <p>Dutch 1	 5.9</p>
                    <p>Danish 1	0.3</p>
                    <p>The figures speak-for themselves. Surely the number of British pilots should be increased proportion to the percentage of British vessels.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>PORT OF ALEXANDRIA.</head><p>
                    We are glad to see that the London newspapers are beginning to take up the question of dock deficiency at Alexandria, and Mr. Cornish's article on the subject has been quoted at home.</p>
                    <p>The "Standard" of December 31st, in the course of some oomments on the subject from its Manchester correspondent, remarks :—</p>
                    <p>In the course of an interview yesterday with a representative of the firm of Messrs. Gough and Crosthwaite, who are among the largest shippers from Manchester to Egypt, our correspondent was informed that there had been, and were now, delays in the discharging of cargoes at Alexandria, owing to the lack of proper dock space. In some instances the delays were very serious, especially in the case of vessels which had to proceed up the Syrian Coast alter leaving Alexandria. The shipments to the last-named port were steadily growing, the increase in the last ten years having been somewhere about fifty per cent, and it was absolutely necessary, in the interests of the country generally, that steps should be taken as promptly as possible for affording proper facilities for loading and unloading boats with despatch. He was greatly pleased to find that the International Chamber of Shipping had taken up the question, and hoped it would be pushed forward with vigour.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>A LETTER OF MOHAMED.</head><p>
                    Cairo magazines are not often honored by newspaper notice written by learned profes-ssors, but the November number of the verna-cular contemporary Hilal has obtained the signal honor of a disquisition by Professor Margoliouth in the latest issue to hand of the Athenaeum. The occasion was the publication in the Hilal of of a photographic reproduction of the supposed original of Mohamad’s letter to the “Mukaukis.” Of this document an account was given by M. Belin in a letter to Reinaud, published in the Journal Asiatique for December, 1854; a certain M. Etienne Barthélemy declared that he had discovered it in the binding of a MS. purchased by him at Akhmim. Sir W. Muir, in his 'Life of Mohamet,’ vol. i. p. lxxvii (1857), said it was desirable that the genuineness of this singularly acquired document should be further discussed by the scholars of Europe; and in the Zeit-schrift der DM.G., x. 543 (1856), there is a brief note by Rӧdiger, who thought the genuineness doubtful, yet on the whole probable. Nӧldeke, ‘Geschichte des Korans’ (1860) pp. 140, 302, expressed his conviction of its genuineness: "Ein Original, an dessen Echtheit nicht zu zweifeln ist" The photograph, reproduced by Zaidan, was taken from the original before it went into the collection of relics of the Prophet
                    in Constantinople</p></div>
                <div type="section"><head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID</head>
                    <head type="sub">(FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT).</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>ACCESSION DAY.</head>
                        <p>Port Said, Tuesday.</p>
                        <p>A reception was held at the Gouvernorat by the Governor, assisted the Sub-Governor, on Sunday. The consular representatives and prominent citizens called and paid their respects. The Lyre Band played selections of music on the terrace of the Gouvernorat during the reception, and a guard of honor saluted the consular representatives upon their arrival and departure. After the recep-tion the guard marched past to the music of the Lyra Band.</p>
                        <p>The whole of the proceedings were favored with most beautiful weather. A word of praise in due to the extremely smart turn-out ff the police. The march-past was perfectly executed, and the bearing of the men was smart and soldiery.</p></div> 
                    <div type="item"><head>WELL-DESERVED HONORS.</head><p>
                        News Has’ just been received that the Khedive has conferred the Order of the 3rd Class Meedjidieh on the Sub Governor, Hassan Bey Kassib. The news has given the liveliest satisfaction here, both gentlemen being held in high esteem, in their official as well as in their private capacity.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head><p>
                        H.M.S. "Essex" is due at Alexandria on the 26th inst. The Duke and Duchess of Connaught will atonce proceed to Cairo, whence they will depart on the following day for Luxor. They are due at' Luxor the 28th inst., Assouan the 29th inst., Wady Halfa the  39th inst., and Khartoum on the 2nd proxo.</p>
                        <p>The Duke arid Duchess will be accompanied by the Princess Margaret and Patricia of
                            Connaught.</p>
                        <p>Nothing is as yet known as to the duration  of the stay of the Duke and Duchess of Connaught at Khartoum. It is quite possible that the Duke of Connaught will take the opportunity of having some big game shooting on the White Nile.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head><p>
                        Yesterday's plague bulletin records a fresh case, a death in hospital, and a cure at Suez, and a cure at Port Said.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>CAIRO FETES</head><p>
                        At the last meeting of the Cairo Fêtes Committee, held at the Grand Continental Hotel, it was decided to add to the programme of the festivities to be given in Cairo this season, and of which we have already published the list, a high-class concert, to take place on .Wednesday,18th instant, at the Savoy Hotel.</p> 
                        <p>The battle of flowers at Ghezireh will be held on the 5th February and the Grand Corso, or Carnival procession in town, has been finally fixed for the 7th March.</p>
                        <p>A working or executive sub-committee composed of seven members has been formed to carry out the details of the several projects that have already met with the approval of the general committee, or any others which, ay be decided upon later on in the season.</p>
                        <p>A vote of thanks was at the last meeting accorded to .Mr. Baehler for tbe excellent arrangements made at Shepheard’s Hotel, which greatly contributed .to trie success of the ball that was held there last Wednesday.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>“ORIENT AND OCCIDENT.”</head><p>
                        A new publication has made its appearance under this title. It is a weekly moral and religious magazine, and is to be conducted on the broadest lines, as indicated by the motto adopted, “God bath made of one blood all nations of men for to dwell on the face of the earth.” Part of the first number is in English, a second part in English and Arabic, and the remainder in Arabic only. A very ably  written article, and one of great general interest, is entitled ''What the West has learned from the East.” Another, on “The Drink Question in Egypt,’’ is well worthy of being carefully studied.</p>
                        <p>We welcome the new magazine, and heartily wish its editors the Revs.WH.T. Gairdner and D.M. Thornton, every success in their attempt to rouse interest in subjects of such importance as those that they propose to bring to the attention of their readers. The effort is one worthy of support, and should be instrumental in bridging racial enmities and prejudices, or at least lessening the harm they do. So long as the fact is fully recognised that it is possible to work for good quite independently of religious belief, and that there is no necessity to intrude dogma into efforts for the moral and social advancement of the people;-- so long and no longer will efforts of this nature deserve the success they seek to obtain.</p>
                        <p>“Orient and Occident” is published at Bait Arabi Pasha,Cairo, and the annual subscription is P.T.  25, post free.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head><p>
                        The Ellerman S.S. “Britannia” sailed yes-terday for Liverpool direct with general cargo.</p></div></div>
                <div type="item"><p>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM
                    r - " ..wvn ffaiii mir iutr-.V- n</p></div>
                <div type="section"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <div type="item"><p>Nungovich Bey will accompany the Duke and Duchess of Connaught on their trip to Khartoum, where they will arrive on the 2nd February.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Earl of Londesborough and Lord George Cholmondeley, who are at present at Khartoum, are expected back at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, about the 18th inst. Lady Londesborough will come out from England the same week.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>After visiting the Pyramids in the company of the Marquis Salvago-Raggi, the Marquis di Rudini left on Monday night for a fortnight's trip to the Sudan.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>H.E. the Governor of Alexandria left for Cairo this morning, and will probably remain four days in the Capital.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Brevet Major Martyn, Royal West Kent Regiment has been selected  for employment with the Egyptian Army.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Capt. Collins, D. S. O., Royal Berkshire Regiment' will shortly leave the depot at Reading and join headquarters at Alexandria.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Mr. Monroe Coats and a big party are expected at the Savoy on the 23rd inst., arriving by the “Schleswig.”</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>Mr. and Mrs. Livingston, who were at the Savoy for a long time two  years ago, are expected there shortly.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>In consequence of Mr. Wakeman Long’s appointment as judge of the Native Tribunal, Me. Demetriades, with whom the new judge was associated, has taken into partnership Mr. Frederick Leveaux, who is an English solicitor and a member of the Cairo Bar.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>Mrs. Robert Goelet’s steam yacht, the "Nahima," is now out of dry dock at Greenock,
                    and is expected to leave for the Mediterranean next week.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said; are Mr. and Mrs. A. Robin-son, Mr. Hugh Cayley, Mr. von Posch, Mr. Glucther, Mr. Barthell, Mr. Henry Lants, Mr.
                    Louis Dohme, Mr. S. V. Schieston, M. and Mme. Maximoff, Commandant and Mme. Schwank, Herr von Blucher, Mlles. von Blucher, Mr. Rhouberg and Baron von Koenig.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>The following are the passengers by the P.S. “Rameses, which left Cairo yesterday : Mr. S. Bourgeois, Mr. and Mrs. Steinmeyer, Mr. and Mrs. G. Brauer, Mr. Alfred John, Mr. H. J.
                    Martin, Miss M. A. Martin, Mr. R. Jackson, Mr. and Mrs. Thott, Dr. and Mrs. Frank Vanderoel, Mr. and Mrs. E. Raymal, Miss Creardson, Miss Lindsay; Mr. Julian B. Huff, Mr. Evander B. Schley, Mr. Girardelli, Mr. and Mrs. Fairchild, Miss Regina Jaffe, Mrs. Grete Kreffer, Mr. and Mrs. A. Congreve, Mr. and Mrs. W. P. Beaver, Miss Mary Chamberlain, Miss Edith Furst, Miss Waterhouse, Miss H. Agnes McKelvey, Mrs. H. Schou, Mr. C. E. Day, Mr. and Mrs. W. G. Henshaw, Misses Henshaw, Master Henshaw, Miss Grimes, Mr. Henry Swindells, Miss Marie Booth, Col. Robt. J. Pratt Saunders, C.B., Capti Ulgo. Bedinello, Miss Augusta Bedinello Mr. Wm. Johnston, Miss E. W. Johnston, Mr. William H. Reeves, Mr. Egon von Szentivanyi.</p></div></div>
            <div type="item"><head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                <head type="sub">ARRIVALS.</head>
                <p>Le paquebot Salazie, des Messageries Mari-times arrive hier de Marseille, avait a bord:</p> 
                <p>Mr. Jas. Peekie, Mr. E. R. Alderson, M. Leon Moch, Mr. Arth. Moch, Mr. AIgnier, Mr. et Mme J. Moray, Mr. Alchewtki, Dr. Loew, Mr. Arloing, Mr. L. Laurens, Mr. Sezary, Mr. Billard, Mr. Vacher, Mr. J. W. Barrett, M. et Mme de Grandcourt, M. Louis de Grandcourt, Mme Chauliaguet, M. et Mlle Robinson, Mme Clarke, M. et. Mme Zeky bey Kahlar, M. et Mme Barbier, M. Bijard, Frere Etienne, M. Nicolas, M. Antony, M. Assayas, M. Deater, M. Smith, M. R. Hacco, M. C. Shakespeare, M. F. Lebon, M. Triadon, Freres Sylvanus and Pergentinus, M. Pritmann et 22 passagers de 3 éme et 4 éme classe.</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>NOTICE</head>
                <head type="sub">TOURIST FACILITIES AT KHARTOUM.</head>
                <p>A steamer will meet the express train due at Khartoum North on Mondays and Fridays, and will leave the Station Landing Place for the Post Office landing Place Khartoum at 7 a.m. conveying Officers, Officials and others who may Wish to land at that point.</p>
                <p>The Steamer will return to the Station Landing Place and leave at 8 a.m. for the Hotel direct conveying tourists and their baggage, afterwards proceeding to Omdurman. Post office is ten minutes walk from the Hotel.</p>
                <p>Passengers not in possession of through tickets to Khartoum or Omdurman will be charged fares as under:—</p>
                <p>Khartoum. Omdurman.</p>
                <p>1st Class	P.T. 5	 P.T.10</p>
                <p>3rd Class	P.T. 2	P.T. 3</p>
                <p>Trips are arranged to Omdurman, the battlefield of Kerreri and the Blue Nile.</p>
                <p>Messrs, Thos. Cook and Son’s Agent</p>
                <p>(Signed) E. E. Bond, Miralai,</p>
                <p>Director of Steamers and Boats</p>
                <p>25225-1-8</p></div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

