<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">September 19, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-26">June 26, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bam01">
                <head>Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</head>
                <p>Despatch weekly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Mails from
                    Alexandria to Cyrpus and the Syrian Coast and vice-versa.</p>
                <p>For particulars of freight, passage, etc., apply to the Agent Ed. A. Minotte.
                    1099-25.2.905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-iob01">
                    <head>IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK.</head>
                    <p>CAPITAL: £10,000,000.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFIOE IN CONSTANTINOPLE. CHIEF AGENCIES: LONDON &amp; PARIS.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES IN ALL THE PRINCIPAL TOWNS IN TURKEY.</p>
                    <p>Agencies in Egypt : ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, &amp; PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>Advances on Merchandise and Securities in current account and for fixed periods.
                        Purchase and sale of stocks and Shares on the London and Continental exchanges,
                        letters of credit issued, valuables reoeived in safe custody. Drafts, cheques
                        and telegraphic transfers issued on the principal towns of the world. Foreign
                        exchange purchased, bills discounted, bills, invoices, annuities and dividends
                        collected and every description of banking business transacted. 18-4-906</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma04">
                    <p>Numbering Machines and Dating Stamps</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Cairo Bulac Road</p>
                    <p>Stationary Engraving and Printing Office</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-alf01">
                    <head>The IDEAL MILK FOODS for HOT CLIMATES. The 'Allenburys' Foods.</head>
                    <p>The "Allenburys" Foods give strength and Stamina, and supply all that is
                        required for the formation of firm flesh and bone. They promote perfect
                        health, and give freedom from digestive troubles and the disorders common to
                        children fed on farinaceous foods, condensed milk, or cow's milk. </p>
                    <p>ALLEN &amp; HANBURYS Ltd., LONDON, ENGLAND. </p>
                    <p>Depot in Cairo:— E. Dell Mar, 25, Août.</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dlc01">
                    <head>D C L Scotch Whisky</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt &amp; Sudan</p>
                    <p>G. G Drossos &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Late Prazzica &amp; Drossos.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria. Cairo. Port-Said and Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>1080 31-5-905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jbc01">
                    <head>John B. Caffari's "Economical Stores"</head>
                    <p>Cairo and Alexandria</p>
                    <p>The Perfection of Quality and Value.</p>
                    <p>In Sterling Silver, "Welbeck" &amp; Silver Plated Goods</p>
                    <p>Provisions, Wines, Cigars, Crockery, Brushes, &amp;c., &amp;c., at</p>
                    <p>Price List on Application.</p>
                    <p>16-11-904</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-vdt01">
                    <head>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE PAVING COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>Hamilton House, Bishopgate St Without, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>CONTRACTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE</p>
                    <p>Pyrimont-Seyssel, Servas (France) Ragusa (Sicily), Guanipa, (Venezuala), Mine
                        Owners.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN BRANCH - FIRST ASPHALT FACTORY ESTABLISHED IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Moharrem-Boy Factory, 171, Mahmoudieh Canal, Alexandria.- Office in Cairo:
                        Haret-el-Mashady (Ismailieh Quarter).</p>
                    <p>For Sales of Mastic Asphalte Blocks, Trinidad Refined Bitumen, Bricks in
                        Compressod Asphalte for Paving, Compressed Asphalte Roadways. — Contractors for
                        every description of Asphalte Works in the whole of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>25-45-14-7-905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sde01">
                    <head>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED</head>
                    <p>KHARTOUM: CAIRO Office, Sharia Kasr-el-Nil.</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT. Six days White Nile Tourist Trip dep. Khartoum Tuesdays.
                        Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at all Cairo Tourist Agents. -
                        Special Steamers for private charter. - Trips arranged and transport of goods
                        undertaken to all places on White and Blue Niles within navigation limits.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT. Shipyard for construction of sternwheel steamers, barges,
                        stream, motor launches, etc. Contractors for supply and erection of all classes
                        of machinery, buildings, irrigation pumps, etc.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENTS FOR Dudbridges Oil Engines from 1 to 25 B.H.P. as supplied to Sudan
                        Government. Seamless xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mil01">
                    <head>Milner's Safes</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt</p>
                    <p>G. Marcus &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Large Stock Kept in</p>
                    <p>Alexandria<lb/>Rue Constantinople Maison A. N. Abet</p>
                    <p>Cairo<lb/> Hoss Issa rue Neuve</p>
                    <p>Tanta<lb/>Sharia El Alail.</p>
                    <p>17 11-905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                    <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                    <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                    <p>7-8-90</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah02">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria.)</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Patronized by the Elite.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>21440-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cgg01">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>NICOLA G. SABBAG</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, 2, Rue de la Gare du Caire</p>
                    <p>Telephone; No. 559.</p>
                    <p>24528-15-3-905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hbc01">
                    <head>HOTEL BRISTOL. CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Full South, Electric Light, opposite Esbekieh Gardens, Large Verandahs, Moderate
                        Charges,</p>
                    <p>CHAS. BAUER, Proprietor.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel is beautifully fitted up and is in the most central part of Cairo.
                        Terms for pension fare at the rate of ten shillings a day. Special terms for
                        officers of Army of Occupation. 24,882-31-10-5</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hdi02">
                    <head>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper</head>
                    <p>Made in 70 Colors</p>
                    <p>An artistic wall covering.</p>
                    <p>This celebrated water paint is made in two qualities for Inside and Outside
                        work</p>
                    <p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
                        tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only requires
                        the addition of water to make it ready for use. It is quickly and easily applied
                        with a whitewash brush, with half the labour and at one third the cost of paint.
                        HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing to the eye. It appeals
                        alike to artistic and practical house decoration.</p>
                    <p>HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special value in hot climates. Owing to its cool, pleasing
                        colours, great weather-resisting and germ-destroying properties, it lends itself
                        to every kind of wall, wood, brick or stone coating, possessing all the
                        advantages of paint, colour- wash, and disinfectant at one third the cost of oil
                        paint. It never blisters in the hottest sun, and the fact that it can be washed
                        adds greatly to its sanitary advantages.</p>
                    <p>Supplied in Tins and Iron Kegs.</p>
                    <p>Sole Manufacturers :</p>
                    <p>SISSONS BROTHERS &amp; CO., LTD., HULL.</p>
                    <p>Stocks are held In Cairo by Frank Ratcliffe, Sanitary Contractor and Engineer,
                        Sharia Saptieh.</p>
                    <p>In Alexandria by Ramadan Youssef, Sanitary Contractor, Rue Sesostris.</p>
                    <p>General Agents: George Morris &amp; Co.. Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun01">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>A great economiser and saver of time, health, and strength.</p>
                    <p>Laundry worries went out of woman's life when Sunlight Soap came into it.</p>
                    <p>It is the purest Soap going.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun02">
                <head>Sunlight</head>
                <p>WORK WELL DONE . . GIVES TIME FOR PLAY.</p>
                <p>Hard work is not easy unless you use Sunlight Soap.</p>
                <p>It shortens the wash-day and brings comfort.</p>
                <p>It has the Largest Sale in the World.</p>
                <p>Soap</p></div>
            <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-gwy01">
                <head>GWYNNES, Limited.</head>
                <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                <p>Telegrams--GWYNNE, LONDON.</p>
                <p>Telephone--544 BANK</p>
                <p>Codes-- ABC, 4th and 5th Editions, A1.</p>
                <p>MORNING &amp; NEAL'S.</p>
                <p>Trade Mark — “INVINCIBLE."</p>
                <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT Centrifugal Pumping Machinery In
                    the world, suitable fcr all purposes, including RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE,
                    IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL
                    MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                <p>These Pumps can be driven by Steam, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other power,
                    for Lifts of from 1 ft. to 500ft., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a Minute.
                    Makers of the Mex Pumps.</p>
                <p>Results Guaranteed.</p>
                <p>Over 50 Years' Practical Experience.</p>
                <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet Egyptian
                    requirements.</p>
                <p>London Offices— 81, Cannon Street, London, E.C.</p>
                <p>The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd: Rue de la Gare du Caire,
                    Alexandria.</p>
                <p>Works- Hammersmith, London, W</p>
                <p>23362-11-12-904</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-rea01">
                    <head>ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>Incorporated A. D. 1720.</p>
                    <p>Chief Office: ROYAL EXCHANGE, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>FUNDS IN HAND EXCEED £4,500,000 CLAIMS PAID £40,000,000</p>
                    <table rows="2" cols="2">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>FIRE</cell>
                            <cell>MARINE</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</cell>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>CAIRO … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                            <cell>SUEZ … Mr. GEO. MEINECKE.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>21281-216905</p></div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-lea01">
                    <head>Lea and Perrins' Sauce.</head>
                    <p>By Royal Warrant to His Majesty the King.</p>
                    <p>The original and genuine Worchestershire.</p></div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE , MONDAY, JUNE 26, 1906.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE Morocco question. A GAME OF BLUFF. GERMAN ANSWER TO FRENCH NOT</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, June 25.</dateline>
                    <p>It is understood that tho German answer to the French note will be presented
                        in a few days, but Prince Radolin, will discuss its pur- port with M.
                        Rouvier before its arrival. The impression now prevails in France that there
                        is no ground for apprehension, and that a pacific solution is possible.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE. ARRIVAL AT DIVONNE.</head>
                    <p>London, June, 24. The Khedive has left om his homeward voyage ; the Earl of
                        Cromer, Sir James Reunell Rodd, Sir E. H. Vincent Corbett, and General Slade
                        bade him farewell at the station. (/f.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Earl and Countess of Londesbourgh entertained Ins Highness the Khediv at
                        dinner on the 16th just, at their residence, S, South Audley-street. letter
                        in the evening a concert was giveu, and Lord and Lady Loudes bo rough wore
                        honored by the presence of their Royal Highnesses tho Crown Prince and Crown
                        Princess of Sweden and Norway, their Royal Highnesses Prince Eugt'ue and
                        Prince William of Sweden and Norway, and her Royal Highness Prince *
                        Frederica of Hanover. The London Symphony Orchestra took part in the
                        programme.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, June 24.</dateline>
                    <p>ic Franco-German question is following a course. The "Echo de Paris" learns
                        England has entirely approved of M. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TROUBLES IN LODZ. A TALE OF BLOOD.</head>
                    <p>Lout, June 24. A general strike has been proclaimed here. There was
                        intermittent lighting all day yester day barricades were erected in the
                        streets, which have been stormed by tho troops. There were 2oo wounded</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW HELLENIC CABINET FORMED BY M RALLI</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Athens, June 25 M. Ralli has formed the Cabinet. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Athens, June 26. M Raili has formed a Cabinet. The Delyau nists declined to
                        participate in it. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH CRUISER COLLIDES WITH GERMAN SHIP FERR</head>
                    <p>H.M. s cruiser "Carnarvon," bound for Gibraltar, collided with the German
                        liner "Coblenz." The "Carnarvon" has taken her passengers on board, and
                        towed the ‘Cobletu here in a leaking condition. (Reuter )</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London. June 24. Hardwicke Stakes 1, Bachelor’s Button , 2, Oueen of the
                        Earth , t, Flower Seller (A)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London, June 24. Surrey beat Derbyshire by 235 runs Essex beat Australians by
                        19 runs. Sussex beat Cambridge University by 65 runs. The match between
                        Lancashire and Worcestershire has been drawn. (HmUtr) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Boulac district of Cairo during
                        tomorrow night and at daylight on Wednesday will be poisoned by the
                        police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Small pox has broken out in Kashtamua village, El Derr district, Assouan.
                        Instruc- tions have been issued by the moudirieh relative to the
                        notification of cases and the limewashing and cleansing of house* where the
                        disease has appeared.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Sm Canal —17 vessels passed through the Canal on the 22nd in«t., 14 of which
                        were British, 2 German, l Austrian. The receipts for the day were fra.
                        479,683.41, making the total from the 1st mat. fra. 6,165,349.86.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Union Artistique Francaise. — At the umeetiug of members on Saturday, M J.
                        Paul was unanimously elected president His place as "comunssaire de
                        surveillance will be taken by M. A. Bartolotti</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Mahmal Theft -A court martial as recent yesterday under the presidency of
                        Kamakam Gibson Bey for the trial of those officers of the Mahmu escort who
                        were in charge.! the Sierra at the time of the robbery</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Hellenn Schools.—At 1030a.m. yeater day the annual distribution of prizes to
                        the fourth class of the gymnasium and commercial department of the schools
                        of the Greek com- munity of Alexandria took place. The cere momy was
                        attended by his Beatitude Mgr Photios, Greek Orthodox Patriarch, and his
                        clerical stall. M. N. Scotides, Hellenic Conaul- General at Alexandria, M.
                        Benachi, president of the Greek community of Alexandria, and many other
                        well-known members of the Hellenic colony An eloquent speech was delivered
                        by M.Georgem .head master of the school. The distribution lasted till noon.
                        To-day the summer holidays of these schools commence.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE STATE RAILWAYS. FORMATION OF NEW BOARD.</head>
                    <p>We understand that Major Johnstone, whilst in England, selected a gentleman,
                        thoroughly expe rienced in railway matters, who will be appointed as his
                        special secretary. It is also said that a new board will be created,
                        consisting of Mus- tapha Pasha Fehmy, Sir Vinoent Corbett, Sir William
                        GaitUu, M. Barois, and Scandar Pasha Fehmy. The duties of the new board will
                        be to consider and approve of all schemes involving the expenditure of large
                        sum* of money, and they will only be called together to consider such
                        questions. Beyond this, Major Johnstone and his colleagues will have entire
                        responsi- bility in the management of the railways, and we understand that
                        the former’s position will more resemble that of general manager of au
                        English railway than it has formerly done, as was suggested in the report of
                        the Railway Commission which visited this country. We publish this
                        information under all reserve as we have received no official communica-
                        tion concerning the changes which ate to be effected, but we believe that
                        our anticipations will be found to be in the main correct.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN SICK AND WOUNDED.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Suet, Sunday.</dateline><p> Yesterday afternoon the American
                        steamer "Garonne" arrived at Sues from Shanghai with Russian sick and
                        wounded, on their way home on "parole." The vessel entered the Canal towards
                        evening bound to Odessa.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SERIOUS STABbING AFFRAY SHIPS STEWARD ATTACKED</head>
                    <p>A serious affray took place in Alexandria harbour on Saturday at abont 1
                        p.m., just as tho S.S. "Avon" (Captain Lancaster)'was about to weigh anchor.
                        The passengers had all beep embarked, and as it was lunch-timethe steward,
                        J. E. Garnham, went to the galley to see about the meal. He found that the
                        cook,.named John Raghy, had not prepared anything, and on asking for
                        explanations he was furiously attack- ed by the Utter with a large kitchen
                        knife measuring about lj feet. The man, who must have been intoxicated,
                        inflicted an ugly gosh on tho steward’s right check, and the pair closed
                        together, a terrible struggle taking place, in which the steward received
                        stain in the head and the right arm. When the pair were separated by persons
                        on board who heard the scuffle, the steward was seen to have suffered
                        considerably at the hands of the aggressor. He was losing blood freely. The
                        captain bandaged up his wounds and finally sent him to the Deaconesses’
                        Hospital, while the infuriated cook was taken to the British Consulate and
                        placed in the lockup. A preliminary enquiry into the circum- stances of tho
                        case was held by Mr. Gould on Saturday afternoon, when the prisoner was
                        remanded for trial. The S.S. "Avon" left the harbour at 7.30 p.m. on
                        Saturday. We understand that the wounded steward is doing as well as can be
                        expected.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport"><head>SPORT AND PLAY. </head><div type="item"><head>A.S.C. GYMKHANA.</head>
                    <p>THe weather was favorable, a cool sea, breeze | rejuvinating the Sun from
                        disturbing anybody’s comfort The attendance, considering the date, was very
                        fair, a Urge number of ladies being present, and the events were keenly
                        contested. The presence of quite a strong Cairocontingent greatly to the
                        interest of the proceedings Mr. M. de C. Findley and Mis. Findley, the Hon.
                        P. 0. Lind- ley, Mr. and Mi* Gould, Sir William Garstin and Mr. Webb, Major
                        Hopkinson, and many Other well-known Anglo-Egyptians watched the</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TENT PEGGING.—There were 9 entries for the tent pegging, which was wail won
                        by Mr. Simonds, who took all his pegs in very nice style. Second honors were
                        divided between Messrs. Richmond and Trafford, who took two</p>
                </div></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PLAGUE.</head>
                    <p>The plague bulletin for last week, which is presented to us by the Sanitary
                        Department, it somewhat alarming. As many as 26 cases have been notified
                        during the week, which 18 deaths have been recorded and only one cure
                        effected, namely, that of a European at Mit- Ghamr. Of the 26 new cases, 9
                        have occurred at Alexandria, 10 at Damanbour, 4 at Garois (Menoufieb) 1 at
                        Fort Said, 1 at Zifta, and 1 at Barchoum-el-Sogra, Toukh district. Since
                        January t, 1905,103 cases have been notified, as compared with 647 during
                        the corresponding period last year. Yesterday's bulletin records a fatal cut
                        at Alexandria, the victim being a native boy found dead at his home in Bab
                        Sidra Barraui. Tbi* boy was a brother to the one who died on the previous
                        day. A fatal case is reported from Port Said, 3 cases from Damanhour, one
                        case from Ashmoun, and a recovery from Zifta.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUARANTINE AGAINST ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mesfr--. Walker and Meinxrauu * reno- vated stores in Uid Bourse-street were
                        opened to the public at 6 p.m. ou Saturday, aud from that hour until closing
                        tune there was a continuous stream of vunton to the splendid establishment
                        winch the firm hare arrauged in the most modern style The new arrange oieut
                        of the premises is a great improve- ment ou the oid. all the goods in the
                        firm s various departments being nOw. visible at a glance. Almost everything
                        from a needle to gramaphone may be had from the firm, who are- to be
                        oougratulated ou their up to date methods. Visitors were lavishly
                        entertained on Saturday at a well stocked buffet.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DOG POISONING</head>
                    <p>The police, I hear. have, with - it previous notice or permission, sent down
                        others to Ki1 54 and poisoned all the dogs on the station, irrespective of
                        ownership or whether the dogs were "pariah. ' The action has caused some
                        dissatisfaction</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THEFTS OF TELEGRAPH WIRE</head>
                    <p>Several times of late most daring thefts of telegraph wire have been
                        committed on the Canal Company’s lines close to the office. Friday night
                        again saw a complete Freak in communication between here and all canal
                        stations, and on investigation being made it ias found that whole lengths of
                        wire had been stolen from the post within a stone s throw of the office.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE "RAYAS’ REFLOATED</head>
                    <p>Port Arthur, June 24 Hie Russian cruiser "Bayan has been sue ieesfully
                        refloated. (Rtultr. war amongst the residents here, was held yesterday—and
                        for the fourth time the married men won, after a hard tussle. The teams were
                        the same as before.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate charges.
                        Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi
                        Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>W .RKJ1XN Knty.mhed - Yesterday morning the now* reached
                        the Menshieh caraool that two workmen who were engaged in pulling down tt„.
                        old Wakts building in Prank-street bad bvn buried alive by the oollapee of
                        the wail* ,S i|«rinUndent Lynn, of the Fire Brgado. with bis men,
                        immediately started for the scene of the accident, aud found that the men
                        were .'lire, the roof teams baviug fallen in such a way as to shield them
                        from the falling stones Stimulants werHaifa, June 16.e passed in through a little opening
                        in the wali and the rescue party set to work to remove the debris. rescue
                        party set to work to remove the debris. Great care was necessary if a
                        further fall which might buve had fatal consequences was to be avoided, but
                        the men were finally brought out and were found to be suffering from very
                        slight injuries, which were treated at the hospital.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HBDJAZ RAILWAY.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Haifa, June 16.</dateline><p> Field Marshal Kiazim Pasha,
                        Military Director of Works on the Imperial Hedjaz Railway, is expected to
                        arrive here very shortly on an inspecting trip. Seven windmills on the
                        Reinsch system are to be constructed for the Hedjaz railway. These windmills
                        are to be used for raising water.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>HACK SCURRY.—For bonk fide Hacks, 14.1 and under, that have never run in a
                        race at any race meeting in Egypt (Gymkhana except *d) and do not belong to
                        any racing stable. Catch weights, over 11 st Distance 3 furlongs. —A field
                        of 16 tamed oat for this event, which was easily won by Mr. Donaldson’s
                        Derry Boy, followed by Mr. Hoyami's Crieri and Mr. Trafford’. Port Said. Mr.
                        Donaldson could not draw the 11 it catchweight by sores lbs. and the prize
                        was therefore awarded to Mr. Hoyami.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>WHISTLING COON RACE-This was the moat amusing event of the day. The com-
                        petitors, after sprinting for 60 yards, lined np in front of their partners,
                        who were posted at the fence beside the judge's box, and a won- derful
                        combination of melodies filled the air for Condition of some of the
                        sprinters, wbose exertions on foot reduced their whistling powers</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>We are assured that a lady to whom "The British Grenadiers" was whistled,
                        wrote down the name of the air a* "Bill Bailey," red that "There is a tavern
                        in the town" was confused with The Honeysuckle and the Bee." Mm. Moore was
                        the winner, Capt Basset's "Home, Sweet Home" being quickly recognised, and
                        Mrs. Gedge was second, Mr. Hemp's "Auldlang Syne" being equally
                        unmistakable. Our con- gratulations to the Berkshires on their musical</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GROUNDING OF THE "FOYLE.’’</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Suez, Sunday.</dateline><p> The British steamer "Foyle," laden
                        with rice from Rangoon for Alexandria, is still aground near Hanish Island
                        in the Red Sea, and her position is practically unchanged. Owing to the bad
                        position in which she grounded, the salvage of the steamer and cargo is
                        doubtful In the forehold there is 14 feet of water.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TUB S.S. "HELENE RICKMERS."</head>
                    <p>The German steamer "HELENE RICKMERS" which was ashore at Ras Garib, is still
                        at San waiting for the lighters, which were left behind full of cargo owing
                        to the bad weather. A tug was despatched from Sun a few days ago in search
                        of the lighters, bat has not yet returned. A survey was held, and the
                        steamer was found to have sustained no damage whatever. It appears that
                        while the "Helene Rickmers" was aground she threw overboard over 4,000 bag*
                        of rice.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Sues, Sunday. A telegram from Constantinople states that arrivals from
                        Alexandria are subjected to 48 hours' quarantine and disinfection, while the
                        rats on board must be destroyed. A telegram from Rome announces that
                        arrivals in Italy from Alexandria are submitted to the measures and
                        dispositions prescribed by sanitary maritime ordinance No. 5 of 1902,
                        against plague According to this ordinance, all passengers, on arriving in
                        an Italian port, must be medic- ally examined, and all personal or domestic
                        effects which are not quite clean must be disinfected.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CATTLE PLAGUE</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Contagion of Example Shortly after midnight last Saturday a thief boarded
                        the Cairo-Luxor express on the way to Magbagha and got into a first-class
                        carriage which was occupied by Said Effendi Saleb, of the Native Parquet,
                        and bis family. The thief s investigations into the contents of the
                        luggage</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXTRAORDINARY NEGLIGENCE</head>
                    <p>In our issue on the 7th inst. we referred to the discovery of a corpse
                        dressed in European clothe* in a quarry pit near the Salt and Soda Company's
                        works at Mex. The corpse was declared both by the . caracal and by the
                        hospital staff to be that of a Sudanese. M. Georges Kanaan, a Syrian
                        pharmacist, whore brother had been missing for some time.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Right Rev. Jamas Bellotd, formerly Viear Apostolic of Gibraltar, died at
                        Neiareth House, Southend, on Tuesday morning, after a long illness. Born in
                        London io 1847, be wa* for twenty six years a British military chaplain,
                        serving in the Zulu War and in the Egyptism Expedition under Lord Wolreley.
                        He was wounded at Tel-el-Kebir.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Seti" sailed from Malta on Saturday morning and is due here
                        to-morrow evening with passengers, mail, and general cargo</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>C1GAR AND UMBRELLA RACE-Thir teen entries made a big field in this race. One
                        or two parasols suffered and one of the competi- tors planted his saddle
                        dangerously near his pony's tail. Mr. Bartlett was first off but dropped the
                        parasol be wielded, and Mr. Richmond came in winner</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>LADIES’ BICYCLE RACE. (Last in wins).— Won by Miss B. Allen. Mrs. Kelham was
                        a good second.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>POTATO AND BUCKET COMPETI- TION.-There were 20 entries for this event, but
                        most of the performers seemed rather at sea. Mr. Jenkinson and Mr. Donaldson
                        were finally given an extra ran, which was won by the former, who made the
                        best individual ran in the event, getting in two potatoes out of three.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EGG AND SPOON RACE ON PONIES— This event brought 18 entries, including one
                        lady, into the field, and was won by Mr. Hemp. Very few competitors arrived
                        with their eggs unbroken. At the dose of the meeting, which did not last too
                        long, Mrs. M. de C. Findlay kindly distributed the prizes, and receiv- ed
                        the cheers of all present. The sheeting was thoroughly well organised by the
                        A. S’O. was thoroughly well organised by the A. S'G. stewards and was
                        greatly enjoyed by all present. The band of the 2nd Royal Berkshire Regiment
                        played selections of music during the afternoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB.</head>
                    <p>The attention of owners is drawn to the fact that by the new issue of the
                        Turf Guide that comes into force on October 1, the maiden is increased to
                        P.T. 5,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList"><head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <head>DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>Le paqoebot "Cleopatra," da Lloyd Autri- chieo, parti samedi pour Trieste,
                        avait k bord : M. A. Adas, M. Achilopoulo et 6 de famille, Mine Aghioo et
                        enfant, Mine C. Aghionet enfant, M. et Mme J. Arbib, M. et Mme J.
                        Borehgrevink, M. Blau, M. 8. H. Carver, M. C. Chevalier, M. Lton Oalamaro,
                        Dadour bey, M. et Mme B. Bman et 8 enfant*, Mme Francis et fils, 8.A. le
                        prinoe Fouad pacha, Mi et Mme H. Harari. M. Herxbruch et 8 de famille, M.
                        HfraaH, M. et Mm Vita Israel et enfant. MUe Israel, Mile Jaere, M. et Mme L
                        Jabe. et enfant, M Kamel el WeM, Mohamad hey el Wekil, A. Klinger, M. et Mme
                        Mitre. M A Mieli, M R de Maoeare et 2 reform. S B. et Mme de Martino pacha,
                        M et Mme Nungovich bey, M. A. Neumann, Mme R de Pitner et filles, M. et Mme
                        Rolo et 4 de fam., M Riga bey, M. R Stress, M. Lionel Bandars, A. Sorokinn,
                        M. et Mme Harry Stern at 8 enfant*, M. le Dr Toortoulia. Mm* Maroal Tilcbe
                        et 4 enfant*, 8.B. et Mme Tito Hako- Ician pacha, M. 8. Visviki et 8 da
                        famille, M. et Mme Carton de Wiart. M. H. Wrigfa, Mme A de Wolfi. tain et *
                        enfanta, Mme Blaeoo vich, M R Barooh, M Brookahanfa M. R Bouohery, M. De
                        Farro, Mme Gosdenorioh, MU* M. Gonjoy, Mem Holier, M. W.G. Hen, M. Lotto et
                        4 de braille, Bcsura Louisa et Qgrrieda, MD* G Maestro, MU* Msestar, M. et
                        Mme Moroni. M. H MoUik. M. C. Maehin- tosb, M. 8. Press, M. A. Pram, Mme
                        Tories rich. M. Wolffaohm</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <p>TH1 I9YFTIAH SiZlTTS, MONOAT, JOTS 26, 1906. RECLEMENT SUR LA RACE Lo "Journal
                    Offioiol" viont do publior la ri> glouicnt sur la rago. En void la taxte: Des
                    mesures a prendre dans les cas de rage Article Premier Lorsqu’un chien est
                    attaint do rage ou sul- poot, declaration en Bara faito A l’autoritA ad-
                    ministrativa dans la plus braf dAlai possible. L'obligation de fairo la
                    declaration incoiu- bora an propriAtairo du obien, k touta peraonno chargAo da
                    soin ou do la gardo rlu chien, ainsi qu’A tout vAtArinaire appelA k lo soignor.
                    Si Li declaration n’a pas AtA faito, las personnes d- doasus so runt routes
                    passiblos das poinos prA vnes par la prAsente loi, a moins qu’elles no fassent
                    valoir un empAcheinont legitime. La declaration sera faito : Dans las gouver-
                    norats, an gouvernorat ou kism, k Ismaiiia, au sous-gouvernorat ; dans las
                    chafs-lieux das moudiriehs at des^marksz, au markaz; dans les villages, A
                    l'omdoh ou au posto do police lo plus proche. Art. 2. Les personnes tenues do
                    fairo la declaration on vortu de 1'art lor, soront egalemont tenues, sans
                    attendro l'intorvention de l'autorite ad- ministrative, soit d'abattre lo chien,
                    soit do l'enformer et dele tenircompletcmantisoie des personnes et des animaux.
                    Art. 3. Lorsqu'un cas da rage ou un cas suspect ost sign ale k l'autorite
                    administrative, tout agent autorise A cet effat par lo Ministro de 1’IntA-
                    riaur, pourra procedor a uno ouquAte, afin do constator si d'autres chiens ont
                    AtA, soit mordus jiar le chien enrage ou suspect, eoit en oontact avec lui. Cea
                    agents auront k cot effet tons let pouvoirs pour oonvoquer et entendre des 1A-
                    moins, qoi appartiennent k unoflioier de police judiciaire, agissant en matiAre
                    de Ilagraut delit Art. 4. Tout chien suspect pourra fltro abattu par les eoins
                    do l'autorite administrative sans quo l'abatage puisse donnner droit k aucuno
                    indem- nite ; toutefois, si le propriAtairo accepte do payer les frais de son
                    entretieo au taux do P.E. 2 par joar, il pourra Atre mis en fourriAro et tenu en
                    observation jusqu’A l'etablissement du diagnostic. En cas de rage conatatAe,
                    l'abatage do chien onragd ainsi quo de tout chien qu'il aura mordu, sera
                    obligatoire. Art. 5. Tout chien qni a AtA en contact avec un nn chien atteint de
                    rage ou suspect, ou qni a dte mordu par nn chien suspect, pourra At re abattu,
                    sans que l'abatage puisse donner lieu a aucuno indemnity k moins que le
                    propriAtairo n accepte de payer les frais do son entretien an taux P.E. 2 par
                    jour, auquel cas l'adminis- tration aura la facultd do mettro le chien en
                    fourriAro et do la tenir en observation juaqn’A dtablissement du diagnostic. 11
                    en sera de mdmo pour les chions qui ont mordo des personnes lorsqu'il y a des
                    raisons de craindre 1'existence de la rage. Art. 6. Ancon cadarre de chien
                    atteint de rage ou suspect, ne sera enfoui sans information prda- lablo de
                    fautoritd administrative, qui pourra fairs prooAder k l'autopsie. Art. 7. Tout
                    propridtaire d’un chien, touts personne en ayant le soin ou la charge, devra
                    ftciliter, en tant que de besoin, l'exdoution par l'auto- ritd administrative
                    des dispositions qui prd- cAdent. . Art. 8. Les dispositions qoi prAoAdent
                    seront appli- cables k tout autre animal atteint do rage ou suspect: Des
                    precautions contre la race Art. 9. Dans toots localitd oh un cas de rage ou des
                    cas suspects auraient dtd oonstatds, le moudir ou le gouyerneur pourra par un
                    ArrAtA qui entrera en vigueor 3 jours aprAs sa publication, ordonner que les
                    chiens circulaot dans les rues ou endroita publics, soient muselds ou ten us en
                    laisse. 11 pourra en outre, s'il y a lieu, ordon- ner que les chiens, mfiwo
                    tenus en laisse, soient muBelds. Dans l'un on l'autre cas, il ordonnera en mdme
                    temps qn'ils soient munis de colliers portant sur one plaque en metal, le nom du
                    pro- pridtaire, avec indication de es demeure. Art. 10. Lee mnselidres doivent
                    Atre fait or de maniAre k empAoher les chiens de mordre, tout en Ieur pennottant
                    de boire. Art. 11. Dans tonte localitd on un ArrAtA pris en vertu de l'aiticle 9
                    serait en vigueur, lee chiens circulant dans les rues ou endroits publics, en
                    contravention de eet Arrdtd, pourront Atre aaisis par la polioe et oondoita en
                    fourriAre. Si le chien saisi est muni d'nn collier indi- qnant le nom et la
                    demeure da propridtaire, la 1’olioe en evisera le propridtaire qui pourra rd-
                    clamer le chien pendant nn ddiai de 7 jours ' contre paiement des frais de son
                    entretien au taux de P.E. 2 par jour. Co psioment n'ioter- rotnpra paa les
                    poursuites pdnales. Si le chien u'est pas muni d'un oollier por tant les
                    indications ci-dessus ou si le proprid- taire ne le rdclame pas 'Ians le ddiai
                    ci deltas, le chien restera k la di-position de la police. Art. 12. L’aotoritd
                    administrative pourra faire pro odder k tout moment k l’empoisonnement on k la
                    destruction de tooteantre man id re. dos chiens trouvds errant dans lee rues et
                    endroite publics. Dob peoalites Art. 13. Tonte infraction aox dispositions de la
                    prd sente loi on des arrdtd* pris en exdention de laprdsente loi, sen pnnie
                    d’une amende n’ex eddant pas L B. une. BULLETIN DB LA BOURSE (AukmrdJuU d midi 4
                    demit) Le marchd demeure calms aveo tondanco inddeise. Los changomonta de la
                    cote sont pen appro ciables : La Banquo Nationalo repreud de 25§ k 25 3/4
                    l’anoionne dmission et de 25 7/8 k 26 U uouvello,la Khedivial Mail do 4 1/4 k 4
                    5/16, et la Delta Light de 12 1/2 k 12 11/16. Par oontro la Braque d’Athdnos
                    oontinuo k teenier do 120 k 119 1/2, lTnvostmont de 1 5/16 k l 9/32, la Diira do
                    28 AH7 15/16, lei Eitates de 27/32 k 13/16 et la Crown Bravery do 201 k 200. THE
                    KHEDIVIAL MAIL STEAMSHIP AND GRAVING DOCK COMPANY LIMITED. NOTICE is heritor,
                    given that the half- yoarly S\ / Cumulative I’roforonco dividond coupon No. 13
                    will be paid by the Imperial Ottoman Bank, Alexandria, or Messrs. Qlyn Mills
                    Carrie and Co., London, on and after Juno 30th 1905. 26167-6-1 MOVEMENT MARITIME
                    DU PORT D'ALBXANDRIB SRRTVilS 24 jnin Constantinople ot Pirde ; 40 h., vapour
                    anglaii lsmailieb, cap. ‘ Qatteschi, ton. 2,335, A la Khedivial Mail. Rangoon ot
                    Port-Said; 20 h., vap. ang. Glon- lochy, c. Stallard, ton. 2997, A Worms and Co.
                    Saloniquo ot Pirde ; 2 j., vap. hell. Prin- cesso Sophie, capitaine Xenios, ton.
                    421, k Nanoponlo. Odessa ot Sudo; 1 j , vap. russe Roino Olga, cap. Iudieff,
                    ton. 2,479, a la Cie Basse. 25 jnin Hall; 17 j., 8/4, vap. ang. Lorenzo, cap.
                    Wing, ton. 2,031, k Barker and Co. Cardiff; 14 j., 1/2, vap. ang. Peterson, cap.
                    W. Jones; ton. 1,790, A Nimuim. GAnes et Messine; 63 b., vap. ital. Singapore,
                    cap. Cossovich, ton. 2,472, k la Cie Florio Rubattiuo. Lamaquo et Port-Said ; 1
                    j., vap. ang. Eape- nLza, cap. Berry, ton. 424, A Minotto. 26 jnin Smyrne et
                    Pirde; 70 b.. vap. ott. Alexandros, cap. Pittas, ton. 717, A Ismiridi. Trieste
                    et Brindisi; 60 h., vap. autr. Habsburg, cap. Klansberger, ton. 2,420, au Lloyd
                    Autrichien. Sulino; 4 j., 3/4, vap. hell. Elpidophoros, cap. NiAmanotakis, ton.
                    1430, A Caffari. 8yrie ot Port-Said ; 15 h., vap. russe Tzar, cap. Emorli, ton.
                    1,524, A la Cie Russe. DEPARTS 24 join Candie ; vap. hell. Athenes, cap.
                    Catramatos. Port-Said ot Syrio ; vap. aug. Minioh, capitaine Damir. Mersino;
                    yap. ang. Bear, cap. Yeroyanni. Brindisi eb Trieste ; wp. antr. Cleopatra, cap.
                    Ivellicb. Liverpool; vap ang. Avon, cap. Lancaster. Ergasterie; vap. ang.
                    Silvertou, cap. Lister, sur lest. Constantinople; vap. ang. Cleftonian,
                    capitaine Enos, sur lest. Piombino ; vap. ital. Luigia, csp. Dodoro.
                    Administration des Chemins de Fer des Telegraphes et du Port d’Alexandrie a V18
                    Le Conseil d'Administration a l'honnsor de porter A la connaissance dn public
                    qn'il recevra jusqn'an jendi 20 jniUet 1905, A midi des offyes poor la fonmitnre
                    pendant 3 ana, du papier hdliogTaphique nAoeesaire au servioe de la
                    Voie,conformi!meut aux conditions dn cahier des charges, A oonsulter an bureau
                    des Etudes du dit servioe, au Cairo. Les offres devront ft re aooompagoAes d'une
                    feuille de papier timbrA de 30 milliAmes. Elies serout adressAes par la poste
                    sous pli reootnmandA A :—"Monsieur le President Cho- mins de fer de l’Etat
                    Cairo," et sous double enveloppe, celle intArieure portant la sns- oription
                    snivante “Offre pour Papier hA- liographiqne.” Le Conseil ne s’engage pas A
                    aooepter l’offre la pins basso, ni A donner suite aox son- missions prAsentAea,
                    et il se rAaerve le droit de divisor la commands. Le Cairo, le 22 join 1905.
                    26159-1 MONICIPALJTE D'ALEXANDRIE AVIs’ Lo mardi 4 juillet pr. de 11 h.and.m. A1
                    h. p.m. la Municipality procAdera A la veDtenax eucbA res publiques prAs des
                    cimetiAres europAena sis A la Porte-Bosette, d'une quantitA de 600 m3 environ
                    des pierros extxaites des terrains des Portifioations divisAeen lota de 40 A 100
                    m8. Les acheteurs deyroat payer le droit d’en- chAre de 2 % et ddpoeer le 10 %
                    de la valeur de la marchandise achetAe, au moment de la vente et effoctuer le
                    paiement intAgral A la Caisse Municipals le lendemain du jour de ['adjudication.
                    I Is auront A supporter les droite do carrihre au prolt de la rille et devront
                    enlever les pier- res achetAes dans un dAlai de dix jours, sous peine de folio
                    enchAre pour compte de l’adjudi- cataire. L' Admin is trate u r W. P. Chataway.
                    Alexandrie, le 24 Join 1905. 26161-3-1 ALEXANDRIA GENERAL PRODUCE ASSOCIATION
                    SECTION rOTOSHIKRK Questionnaire do join 1905.—(PriAre do rApondro avant le 4
                    juillet, en voua servant de la langue qne vons prAfArez). 1. La tempAraturo du
                    moia do join a-bello AtA favorable aux ootonniers 1 2. Les cultures sont-elles
                    retardAeson plus avancAes en comparaisou deoellesde l'annAe passAo, A oette
                    Apoque 1 3. Les ootonniers sont-ils en bon Atat 1 on ont-ils AtA contrariAs par
                    quelque oiroon- stanoe? (et laquellel) 4. L’eau pour les irrigations estelle
                    abon- dante 1 ou bieu ostelle suthsante 1 on bien est- ello insuffuante 1 5. Los
                    vers du coton sont-ils apparns en jnin 1 Et ont-ils fait dos dAgute 1 6.
                    Avez-von9 d'autres observations A fairo ear la perspective de la nonvelle
                    rAoolte, en gAnAral 1 Le Prisident, C. db Tscuodl BOURSE KHEDIVIALE CONTRATS
                    Fluctuations de 9h.30 A lh. p.m. Cotoru F.O.F.Br. Dans la matinAo; prix pins
                    hantponr juillet taL 14 3/16 A —I— ; plus baa pour juillet 14 1/16 A —I—.
                    Grainet de coton Dans la matinAe ; prix pins hant pour jail. P.T. 60 1/4 A —/—:
                    pins bas poor jail. 60 -/- A —I—. * Remarques (De Midi A lb. p.m.) Cotons.—La
                    faiblosse du inarchA s’Atait accontnAe sous' le poida de I'offre, mais l'avant-
                    bourse de Liverpool Atant vonue en hansse, nos cours se sont raffermia do
                    noavean et la clOtnre a en lien aux prix de 1'ouvertore pour la rAoolte aotuelle
                    et en amAlioration sensible pour le novembre. La tendance de la place est pour
                    des prix plus AlevAs pour la Douvelle rAcolte. Oraines de coton.—Ls calms a
                    pereistA et la cote aujonrd’hni a AtA an petit pea en baisse. PAves.—March A nul
                    et cours soutenns seule- ment A cause dn disponible. Bourse KhAdiviale, le 24
                    join 1905</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, JUNE 26, 1205.</head>
                <p>TARDON ON GOLF. if anyone has the right to lay down the law j on goll, nays the
                    "Evening Standanl," it ia the m m who has won tho open championship four times—a
                    record only equalled by the two Morrises, "Old Tom" and "Young Tom.” And in this
                    book Harry Vardon shows that he is as jjoi 1 at preaching as at practioo. As an
                    instruc- tor be is detailed but lucid. Thoroughly as he goes into the question
                    o( grip, stance, swiDg, . ■md the correct use of each club, his explana- tions
                    never become involved,and are materially helped out by a numbor of excellent
                    reproduc- tions of the author porformiDg the strokes cot only in the right but
                    also, by way of awful illustration, in the wrong way. These latter poses, wo
                    hasten to add, Vardon found it "most inconveuient andjdifficalt" to assume. But
                    they wear a fairly familiar look, somehow. Vardon addresses himself to an
                    audience alike of beginners and of proficients. He keeps the "fancy" strokos in
                    a separate cate- gory, howevor. To the boginner he is at the same time
                    encouraging and depressing.' It is never too late to start. Even at forty or
                    forty-five wo can reach scratch or very near it, but—at least three months'
                    persis- tent and laborious practice is a tine qua non. As a shining example ho
                    points to Mr. Balfour as having, it is stated, "spent a miserable fortnight in
                    bunkers only, learning how to get out of them from every possiblo position.” It
                    is interesting Jo hear that in Vardon’s opinion the Premier isnowa very good and
                    steady player, and might be still better but for Parliamentary cares. Which is
                    the master stroke in golf 1 That is another very interesting point on which he
                    records his opinion. He awards tho palm to none of the ordinary shots, however
                    perfect 1'he greatest is tho stroke to which a big pull or slice is
                    intentionally applied for the accom- plishment of a specific purpose, which
                    could nut be achieved in any other way.</p>
                <p>“I call it the master shot because, to ac- complish it with any certainty and
                    perfection, it is oo difficult even to the experienced golfer, because it calls
                    for tho most absolute command over the club and every nerve and sinew of the
                    body, and the courageous heart of the true sportsman whom no difficulty may
                    daunt, and because, when properly done, it ia a splendid thing to soo, and for a
                    certainty results in material gain to tho mab who played it" The best course in
                    the world, in Vardon's estimation, is Sandwich. He acknowledges that he is at
                    varianoe here with many of the best authorities on the gamo, but Ire gives good
                    reasons for his choice. Prestwick and Hoy lake be puts next, but his verdict on
                    St Andrews, passed, of course, before the reoent championships, is one of
                    distinctly modified praise. It is "a good oourso generally, but its bunkers are
                    badly placed." And here the author is certainly uot alone in his opinion. lu the
                    lighter portion of his book, which, we must add, is written in really admirable
                    style, Vardon has collected a number of delightful golf auecdot.-, with
                    comparatively few chest- nuts among them. His visit to America in 1900, when he
                    won the American Champion- ship, was notable, among other thing*, for the
                    achievements of the reporters, who, trne to their tradition of sensationalism,
                    annonnoed, one that he "carried away the green with his drive,” another that he
                    "dropped dead at the hole.” Pacts, however, were as queer as fiction iu some
                    parts of tho trip. On one Florida course men with sticks had to bo kept con-
                    stantly employed on the greens to keep the locusts ofl the lines of the pntts
                    !</p>
                <p>But the best stories are to be found in the chapter "Conoeming Caddies.” There
                    was a busy day on/jne occasion at North Berwick, when all the regular caddies
                    were out, and fishermen were drafted into the service. A well known player
                    engaged one of them, though the recruit acknowledged that he only knew very
                    little of the game.</p>
                <p>“This player happened to be left-handed, and took np his etanoe on the first tee
                    aooord- ingly, whereupon the son of the sea at once’ adopted tho part of tutor,
                    and with some warmth and show of ooutempt exclaimed loudly, ‘I dinna ken much
                    about the game, l-t ye dinna keen a wee bit Mon, ye're stand- ing on the wrong
                    side of the baw! Awa’ to . the other side ?' ”</p>
                <p>More disconcerting and less amusing (to the player) was the following experience
                    "Two golfers of some Highland eelebritywere playing a match one day at Luff
                    ness, and after a hard round they came to the eighteenth tee all square and but
                    this one bole to play. At this critical stage of the game the caddie of one of
                    them approached bis master and nervously whispered to him, 'Please sir, wad ye
                    do your very best here, for there’s money on this match.' And the goiter did try
                    to do his very best indeed, but he pressed and he foozled, and he lost the hole
                    and the match. Sympathetically he turned to his caddie to ask him what wus the
                    amount of the lost wager that he might pay it for him and soften his
                    disappointment ‘It was a penny, sir,' said Use boy.”</p>
                <p>Mr. Balfour figures in more than one plea- sant little incident "He has a
                    remarkable memory for the caddies who have served him, and onoe, when on the
                    tee, just about to engage in a foursome, he re- cognised one of his opponents'
                    caddies as a boy who on a former occasion had carried his own clubs, and be
                    nodded to him kindly. Natarally the caddie was immensely pleased, and torn ing
                    to one of bis colleagues fie remarked, ‘Ye see boo we Conservatives ken aue
                    anither ” But we are inclined to think that the finest illustration of the
                    "humanity" of the club- carfying class is to be fonnd in a story of a famous
                    caddie nazped Sandy Smith. He "am- or,e day carrying for a player who had the
                    good fortune to be no fewer than six holes np on his opponent by the time the
                    eighth hole was reached. At this green something having gone wrong with tho
                    reckoning of the strokes, there was a mild dispute as to whether the hole had
                    been won by Sandy's man or whether it had boon halved. Bventually it was agreed
                    that it was halved, bat as the players moved away to the next tee, he who was
                    six down being ont of earshot in front, his opponent remarked to Sandy, ‘You
                    know, Sandy, I still think I won that holo after all.' Sandy seemed shocked at
                    such a cold-blooded greed for holes, nnd re- provingly, vory seriously, and
                    sharply said to his employer, ‘Haud yor tongno, sir; haud yer tongue. Wad ye
                    break the man's heart Vardon has much that is interesting to tell, too, in the
                    way of reminiscence and of his observations in great matches. And whatever he
                    has to say he says well. It is a book worthy of a place in the library of every
                    golfer.</p>
                <p>In “Country Life in Amerioa,” Mr. H.K. Job, an Amerioan naturalist, gives an
                    account, illustrated by photographs, of an egret rookery he discovered in a
                    southern State, unknown to the hnnter and rigorously protected. Ho says :—</p>
                <p>A long sail up a series of narrow, tortuous creeks, between walls of impassable
                    mud and through immonse salt marshes, found ns anchored at the desired locality.
                    Even before the anchor took the mud, late in the afternoon, I had seen the sun
                    glance on the dazzling whiteness of several dozens of egrets at they flew to and
                    from the marsh, immaculate amid the southern mud whieh sticks like glue. After
                    one false start, we found a man who knew the location of the rookery, in e greet
                    oypress swamp. First we tramped a mile over a wood- land trail, whan we came to
                    an arm of muddy wator under high, over-arching trees, and a small flat-bottomed
                    skiff. Working two pad- dles wo glided along, and soon emerged in a great area
                    of cypress trees growing out of the water. Alligators and turtles splashed be-
                    fore us, end buzzards end ospreys wheeled overhead. From the cypress branches,
                    with their delioate needle-foliage of pale green, hung the streaming grey moss.
                    Pairs of wood-duck started up now sad then from INDIAN BANKS.</p>
                <p>These are the boatmen and gaffers of the St' and bost krown in the whole of
                    England—the the water with" resounding ' wing-beats. Lawrence and those of the
                    California islands, Crit-rkn Horeilonts the old-fashioned rteort- • . . First
                    weN met, as wo con tinned to particularly at Avalon Bay, Santa Catalina.1 of tho
                    louugcr flourished in bygone days, when I navigate this eypreea sea, scattered
                    nests with At the latter place there are 100 boatmen 1 the Haymarket was rural
                    in aspect as well as eggs of the yellow-crowned night-heron. Then also of
                    striking individuality in their methods. 1 in name. The famous Gaming House
                    stood et w* began to meet individuals of the familiar Here the ground of Santa
                    Catalina Channel is j tbo corner, next to Piccadilly, notorions even j
                    black-orowned night-heron of the north, also open, and tho boats aro larger,
                    being 18ft. or ' in that dissipated ago, and near by was the breeding, and soon
                    emerged into a more open 20ft., eight or ten horse-power launches, rigged
                    Piccadilly Saloon, which had an oven worse aroa where the trees grew more
                    sparsely and with chairs for the anglers, awnings, and reputation. Long ago wore
                    those haunts re- not so tall. At every rod of progress dozens every oomtort The
                    boatmen and gaffers of this moved, and a new order of things was intro- J and
                    scores of egrets and the smaller, dark- squadron of perhaps 200 boats of various
                    duoed when the Criterion was bnilt One of | coloured little blue heron, with
                    Bombers of kinds, all hailing from tho town nnd bay of the features of this
                    splendid building has the bluish but white-breasted Louisiana heron, Avalon,
                    have a number of sports that attract hitherto been ita long bar, opening to the
                    street; kept springing into the air. Then, as the no little attention on tho
                    Pacific slope. These 1 —a glistening, brilliant picture in mosaic,, abnndanoe
                    began to lessen, we returned to the are tournaments, races, tags of war, Ac. 1
                    lincrusta, elegant draperies, and eleotrio lighta ! heart of the rookery to
                    spend tfcf day. . . . In these tournaments the tug-of-war of boat- Now this has
                    disappeared, to give place to a It was a wonderful sight, well worth travel- men
                    and gaffers is extremely exciting. Thn fi-st c’a«s n froshmant-room, similar to
                    those at ■ ling far to see. Upon any sadden noise, hun- men select their best
                    ten rowors, and each man the Trocsdero and Lyons' Popular Cafe, and , dreds of
                    these different herons would spring chooses a skiff and oars. The sterns of the
                    itsfnnctions havebeon relegated to the "collar,” from trees everywhere about
                    Then they wonld boats are festenod five feet apart, five on a 1 with eni ranees
                    from a Hick street. A general return and aUght upon the tree-tops, tho side, the
                    middle boats being held on a line.' scheme of rearrangement has been effected on
                    delicate snow-white plumes from the baoks of Each side of five men lias a
                    captaiD, and has ! the ground floor,bnt the removal of the famous the egrets
                    straying out bewitahingly in tho arranged its men to produce the greatest
                    effeot. bar may bo taken as one more, and the latest breeze. Nearly all day long
                    we paddled about —a man of great strength at the stern, another indication of
                    that change of taste which the lacustrine forest, and I revelled in tho at the
                    opposite end—and the entire team is n o letu days are witnessing. sights and
                    sounds of this wonderful place, composed of men of groat physical strength ; By
                    what means is this transformation being whioh is probably the largest and
                    perhaps the and endnrauoe.« The shore is lined with effected ( Not by
                    legislation, asseverates an ' only ogret rookery in North America. The thousands
                    of spectators, the "tug” being authority of experience. As well, he observes, 1
                    only reason that it exists to-day is because it direotly along the shore uot
                    sixty feet from try to control the current of the winds as make is guarded by
                    armed wardens who will arrest it ; while on the sea side are boats filled'
                    people sober and refined by legislation. The^or, if necessary, shoot any perron
                    found upon with admirers. All is ready now, and attempt has never succeeded,
                    never wilL The the property with a gun. crack goes the revolver in the hands of
                    tho' peop’e are working ont their own salvation.* , judge. Twenty oars strike
                    the water with a j Refinement is following upon education. Even ; crash, and a
                    roar of cheers rise from land j the bar lounger is a human being, with human i
                    HORSES IN BATTLE, and sea. 8uch a tug-of-war is a novelty to tastes. He most
                    have food as well as drink, j many and requires much more effort than and
                    sometimes other drink than that whioh. Under present conditions little
                    consideration on land ; and it often is several minntes 1 robs him of his
                    reason. To obtain that homust is shown to horses wounded in battle. Unless
                    before either side is seen to move. Thau ' spare a moment from his customary
                    beat and so slightly injured as to reach safe quarters, suddenly one team that
                    has polled in better ' seek ont the refreshment-room. Perhaps he has they are in
                    most oases either mercifally pot form gains a foot Loader oome the cheers ’ been
                    unfairly dealt with in that respect Little ont of their misery, or, if this be
                    not possible, and shouts from the excited backers on or no effort has been made
                    to supply his are left to die. Those who would see to them shore and boat The
                    opposition pull with' natnral wants. Tea or coffee he could not are afforded no
                    protection. They are not the energy of despair ; one man misses a have, ur his
                    demand for it was half heartedly sheltered by the Red Cross, bat are treated as
                    stroke, the others lose heart, bat pall with , met But others have accurately
                    seized the belligerents. With a view to bringing about a desperation. Yet the
                    winners slowly but situation. They have met the demand and change in this
                    respect the Chnroh 8ociety for surely take them along, and finally drag been
                    rewarded. The pnblio have appreciated Promoting Kindness to Animals has
                    approach- them over the line to defeat Such a contest! their efforts and
                    patronised them. Conse-' ed all the signatories to the Geneva Conven- lasts
                    fifteen or twenty minutes, and is ex-' quently, while the refreshment-room of
                    the tion, pointing out that the Convention is defi tremely exoiting. j superior
                    kind, not a whit behind the lioensed cient in its provision for the relief of
                    the Next comes the water polo, in which house in its embellishment* and
                    attractiveness, sufferings of wounded animals, and urging that teams oontest in
                    bathing suits, Bwimming has been expanding and filling a larger plaoe the words
                    "sick," "wounded," and "disabled” instead of riding, knocking the large ball in
                    the pnblio eye, the drinking bar has been used in the Convention shall bo mado
                    applio- about with their hands. This will be followed ' recediug, until there
                    has arisen a wholesome ' able to animals and men alike. The Swiss by a swimming
                    match along the beach, tbo 1 oonviotion that it has lost ita priority of plaoe.
                    Federation has arranged a meeting of repre- crowd of observers following and
                    cheering ! And with this ignominy there natarally onmea 1 sentatives of all the
                    great Powers with a view the oonteetaute to the echo. When the ' about the
                    dethronement of the habitual ■ to extending the terms of the Convention, winner
                    comes in he is borne on the shoulders j lounger from his leaning pedestal. He
                    has no ' when it is expected this matter will be brought of the others. On
                    special occasions, as great. friends now outside his own class ; no sym-'
                    forward. A month ago the Ambassadors of holidays, these and other sports always
                    are pathiser to hold him up as a man of parts and j Russia, Germany, Turkey, and
                    Amenca were indulged in. Those at night are the most a downright good fellow.
                    All are agreed that seen, and their promise obtained to forward a attractive,
                    when the rocks and bay are alone be is not worth considering, and that he
                    memorial on the subject to their respective illaminated with fireworks and fire
                    of various1 must be frowned out of existence. Possibly, as Governments. I*st
                    week a small deputation, Although the movement for establishing peasants' banka
                    in India seems tOj.mako very slow progress, it has undoubtedly gained ground in
                    some localities. The ryot is, as m rule, conservative in all his tendencies,
                    -and it has been found very difficult to oonvinoe these humble tillers of the
                    soil that the time has come to break off financial relations with the village
                    usurer. But even their obstinate addic- tion to ancient ways cannot g6t rid of
                    the gain ooosequent on obtaining advances from banks at 12 per cent, instead of
                    paying ten times that rate to some grasping money- lender on the same security.
                    On first estab- lishment, the new institutions are invariably regarded with
                    suspicion and dislike, all manner of libellous stories being disseminated by the
                    pests they seek to supplant In one instance, the ryots were induoed to believe
                    gthat the very latest devioe of the Siroar to disoover the innovation was the
                    hidden taxable resources of the agricultural popu- lation. But the temptation to
                    obtain loans on such comparatively easy oonditions led some of the more
                    enlightened peasants to make trial of the new system, and when no harm resulted
                    to these bold experimentalists, the more timorous embarked in the venture. It is
                    calculated that by fixing the rate of interest as high as 13 per oent adequate
                    provision is made for famine years and their inevitable losses. But that theory
                    still requires to be put to the test; even the usurers suffer heavy losses at
                    such times.</p>
                <p>HORSES IN BATTLE. Under present oonditions little consideration oolours, one huge
                    rook resembling a volcano a last resource, there may be devised for his and
                    belohing fire like a veritable Pefee. Than special use a floating lounge moored
                    on the from the outer channel a ship appears, lighta , Thames, like the famous
                    ooffse-house of Ad- gleamiug from every point, and mimio cannon- diaon's time
                    whioh rose and fell with the tide balls rise, increasing until a vivid bombard-
                    ment is on between the land and the ship. Out from the black oomors a long fiery
                    sea-serpent steals, winding in and out, up and down. Every boat, lanDch and
                    other craft has been decorated with lights and lanterns and fastened together,
                    constituting a singular and beautiful parade that can be pompared diaon's time
                    whiob rose and fell with the tide</p>
                <p>THE PRIEST AND THE TIGER only to a searefpent and ita convolutions. and lanterns
                    The Rev. Father Froger, Principal of 8k ng a singular Joseph’s College,
                    Bangalore, write* to the local be pomparad papers describing an experience when
                    oyclirg A SEA KING’8 GALLEY. only to a sea-serpent and its convolutions. from
                    Wellington to Octacamundby the Kota- giri road—this being the road,itis
                    understood, which cornea into Octacamund from the Snowdon direction. Aooording
                    to the “English- A SEA KING'8 GALLEY. man's” summary, the Rev. Father waa
                    riding' , quietly along when he saw what looked like a ... . ... .. , tiger
                    Bitting on a rock on the bare hillside „tk a.» e""*V!*"* 'r b"? * tiger been,
                    .parent, to Pother Frege.', garter of. .aoler, boned re tie .e. end enow. ^
                    ta.ded negbt down the oU»r ~rohor. b... h„l to eb.ndrn, the hllUda p0IM„ul,,
                    th«. J-tbeerortb. treeaure loot in.British ,u, ,llgh, incline in bu Inrer in the
                    n»d, ship in theLowerElbe forty years ago.There is and ^ cyoIod for ^ lifo until
                    the upward in the university at Christiania a vessel which grada became too
                    steep and be had to get off has endured better than either of these relic.
                    Apparently, the beast did not pursue after be of tragedy. It ia the galley of a
                    Viking lord hvj lott ,ight 0f the oyoliat, but the unpro- which, buried in a
                    mound near the seashore yoked atUck ia an nnoanal occurrence, a thousand years
                    ago, waa brought to light, Mp6Cu||y with Nilgiri tigers. There seems perfectly
                    preserved, five and twenty year* ago, littta doubt that tigers are unusually
                    numerous at Gokatad, Sandetjord, Norway. In it they tbia yMr, and in the
                    vicinity of Kotagiri bears had deposited the remains of the Viking, to a„d
                    panthers are also said to be in unaoous await the last pipe to pnt to sea.
                    Nearly t^gd numbers.</p>
                <p>eighty feet in length, with places for thirty- ________________—____________
                    consisting of 8ir H. Vinoent, M.P., Dr. NiohoUs, Professor Hob lay, apd the Rev.
                    P. Lvwronoe completed the work by waiting upon the repre- sentatives in Bug land
                    of Austria, Italy, the Netherlands, Japan, Switzerland, and Sweden. In each case
                    they were promised oordial assist- ance. At the Japanese Legation Professor
                    Hobday pointed ont that at the oloee of the present war the Geneva Convection
                    would probably assemble to discuss points, and the society trusted that this
                    wonld be one of them. Japan had ooe of the bert equipped and organ ised
                    veterinary services in the world, bat in spite of that none of those composing
                    it were able to go on the field of battle except as oom- bxtants. It was
                    desirable that there men should be able to render assistance to the wounded
                    animals by tending them on the field or bringing thorn into hospital under
                    protection of the Red Cross. Visoount Hayaahi replied that he appreciated the
                    laudable endeavours of the society, and should have great pleasure in submitting
                    the memorial to his Government two oarsmen, the vessel was as fit to take the
                    ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIYIHBA. sea as when she was bnilt They had buried i ■■
                    her in the blue day, which >ad acted the rh. t*» kdhnj t>*w» x*jti »o4 lufUsS t>
                    part of preserver as well as ioe oonld have viamooio. mw nu. done. The Viking's
                    bones crumbled when ex- ■*“ pOMd to the light, hot the itoot gtlkjr rru good
                    enough to take its plaoe in another , ^ m ui prims. Viking expedition to the
                    ooeat of Britain. i«r-n **■.*««. xxsuu "Learning Languages by Telephone, is the
                    title of an article in the "Daily Mail." Tel^_ phone girls, we understand, have
                    learnt quite a lot of language that way.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <p>DR. LE CLERC'S Fills far tha Liver Kidneys BTHAMTLOUOIIte ENGINES TO PLOUGH 8 TO
                    80 PBDDANS PBR DAY. lhaioiiwiitf fAlsuMrie .fSo*/ jp ■ ™»:WH fnnv *• iitas,
                    loiagn elto aura requ das demands* pax group* rteidani daqs not* ntone me, afin
                    dapermettre k la Somite d examin* sans re- tard tour* dereandm, an me da
                    canaliaer' at dft IWr aocCfder das onnoesrions d'eau. L6 Oairs,' toW Janrier
                    1905. La Direuteur, 25S2-40*-26 f Aatiar P. Pntnro. lYHOUBSALK BUY BBS'; I
                    STORE-K'BKPttRS, A'ND OTH HR TRADHR8. — If yoa are not a fftader of '‘African
                    Com- merce,” the British Trade Medium for Ail Africa, send 7d, for a copy to
                    Ttife Mahage^" ‘'Afrioail Cottinteroo," Tower Chambers, Moorgate Street,
                    EiOffdon; B.C. Annual Subscription 7/6 "poet free. CREDIT LYONNAIS Alandrie, to
                    83 join 1905. L'Administratenr, M67-8-3 I tS^ni.T'' W.P; OMttrwxf. 0 A PIT Air
                    260,006,000 DB FRANCS .NOUVEAU RECEDE PURBATIF IDEAL pr rsaasSE; “^eSrPIJBGEN
                    thi IwrmiH aiziTTi, moNua*. Jfrsa ' w. nos. Expoftf \rAMFKftets. Poor PORT-SAID
                    (to -C/bis^A, par ft tftteau russa "Tsaritxa,”parti tol6 juin : DiVfcs, *15*
                    safe rg*irtty*J8 saos rii, 1,067 cAistimaths,’ 29 euMdivtrs 0?Aa^* 4 Co., **1*0
                    balloa coton , R. 4 O^timlAnaun, . » „ ■> 1 375 bailee ootou • For MALTA
                    'iJ^^OOL, by theS.S^ ''Flavian," Bailed on the 17th Jane : j Bank of Egypt, 25
                    batoa ootton i J.PtoataCo. 8*0 ,. - ‘ CBoreml,' Bouaehi Co., 844 .. . „ J Coary,
                    2*4 ■> i F. C. Bainw Co, 50 ,. ) Skondaraui, . t'* L, 93 . I Carver Bros. Co.
                    Ltd, 264 „ „ i F. 0. Lindemann, 324 „ >■ j G. Fiauger Co, 35 „ j Peel 4 Co, 140
                    „ B.Barki, 590 „ Mohr Fenderl, 125 „ „ I Anglo-Egyptian Bank, 98 „ „ T.
                    Ghirghie, 374 tegs Wot Ah. Ayonb, 620 „ ,, Aly Moh. Saleh. 200 „ C. Pariaei. 80
                    „ Carlton Hall, 16 barili oognas B. J. Coary 4 Co, 750 ardebs beans Khedivial
                    Mail, 1(4 UtdVeau, 406 bags Isaac Eli, 30 bales wool Hq1x. ChJ61 batoswool, 'T I
                    Barker Qpi,. 301 tons ootton seed Carver Bros. 0o. Lt^ 200 tons ootton seed Th.
                    Insholwood, liPlSS^Aints, 19 barrel* oil Cook 4 Bcta'A1 ***** httry Divert*,
                    445-tocurii, MHahh^ktihu; 10 barito video, 24 oolis divers , ! Pour
                    CONSTANTINOPLE,' ’par to' bateau grto "Marie JUfae,*^aim le 20 join : j to 20
                    join Divers, 800 10 saos heane, 100 p asphalte, 14 oolis pea ax, 29 oolis divere
                    > bailee coton italien "Perseo,” parti to 22 jnin: POOR DESTUCAT10HS DtVDtSBS G.
                    Gatti, 23 ohevaui. 3Hn«i WbrAnS1 et 1 ceri M. Fahii, 2"ballos cuir B. Trabjhi, 5
                    ball* ouir Divere'tT4Bll#dKer£' I Divers, 39 oolis divers A. L Camso, 6 sacs
                    gomme J. Planta A Co, 16 bailee coton G. Franger Co, 50 „ „ Peel A Co, ,130 „ R.
                    0. Lindemann, ' 91 „ „ W. Trapp 'Co.; 31 „ „ ' Bottcn Co, 60 „ „ Carver Bros. Ca
                    Ltd, 90 „ „ Cboremi, Benachi Co, 30 „ „ • R MalEscd Co, 61 „ 559 bailee ooton
                    Poor POUTLAID,—par- le bateau italien ARRIVAGES A MlkRT-^IrBASSAL du mois do
                    jaillet 1904 )a Coton ■ Gtainee do eoton : Fives 1, S/B — Ard. : 702 sacs 750
                    3,116 1,279 1,135 3,132 ■ 1,251 ,149 1,595 1,295 1,511 5,05 „ 1,757 3.505 \57l
                    5.1 i in :: m I " V, 1,630 3,611 1,316 I NJL „ Pn-R- i ■ 1,352 3,763 2.396 1,327
                    184 Aid. 22.645 Sacs 92,717 ttolika est. relevto (toe Registro in anon pause to
                    c du*OoU’ft jftillst O O A. Xi .S . Dunlop* Best Ssailton HU StUsAeld ml 100
                    painsj tdttssiu "’iSusAsU oltodiT*. “ Wtaroos B-wtTkaA par le bateau* on *c^m. -
                    18.0 „ — 18.0 „ - l 18.6 „ — 18 0 — 17.0 " — *in»T.« „ - •7.6 ., - 27 8 n —
                    '-87.0 . — *7.6 „ — G. MARCU S Go. soI* iOJBrm rii mriiris MILNER’S SAFE
                    COMPANY, LIMITED. Trousatlantio Sira Invaianoe Company, Limited or BAwnui. loonu
                    also buioubt bibxbo The National ftsstfrtnn G«apiiiy af’Inland. Fire IoBoraaoe
                    Polioiea granted on all approved Descriptions of Property, at moderate rates,
                    AfiUXANDBIi, Msiian A. R; 'AtaV. Ba» OdnatsnHnople. CAIRO, Hoahjii* 1MU40I rOUn
                    BOKBSY E. MaiKson Co, 50 ball* boton Carv* Brea; Up. Ltd. 50 „ ^ 100 bail*
                    6oton_ , .. ir NOLI S -OflUSiCl L-'■ .JIT... Shg." in k — Tourteaux.. ... ...
                    ... „ 6/. »— Graines do ooton __... „ 6/ „ — Oignona ............. „ — ,, — % 2
                    : - -a. i \t Cotoal ai. ’.l^^^Sga li/’^S- C4real*.....................Ifei rf.-r
                    , Tourteaux.. ... ... „ „ 6/ » — j Graines de ooton ....... „ 7/ „ — oigMn. x.
                    btto-nutln^IA I Ptvea. _ Oignons . . 4 SuBu* Fives. Z1JTL Barealone-' ~ w ' UO
                    ID Annr».X t.- ' \ 8t-PeS3parg/V jji- Naw-YoA. Bombay..... Atoxamdria to 22 join
                    1906 EOYPTIAlf MARttHTfl/ LIMITED ' La dlnoicipalite met an oonoours un posts
                    seaento insatobr* et dec dsote* aliaentairw M8) de to ola*«; «U >5> 40 LB. par
                    moi. aveo rfr. 10 1- tj «H » — Toots perionne qoi dtoiMnR ptondto part „ 10 „ 11
                    Wtofiooura' tot’pti-fo de‘pWtofftw'hW'de- „ — m —[ taande tub* to 90 juille*
                    1906, dernier detoi, et d* - resaettre an y*a*to*p« Mo.iiptofi* ainsi que tout
                    doonment oOostatant sef ton- . « . T.i" Allen, Alderson Go. Egyptian Delta Light
                    Railways Co, Limited. - - (Tonneottons made witu the most important-trains of
                    the State Rtilway in the Previn,-. oru IT Ahin FYOI l JSIVE AGENTS FOR 'If
                    BobeHi;,Gli4rbtetifU.k..Mieh 'harkieh and Galionbieh ThnwjhurcM /or goods betwe^
                    SOLE AND tADLUOlVt MWPIIO run dl l«rtbnl df the Ootoptny tod 0«r lOO principal
                    ,*UioK, o/ tUSlat, y^i/iouv .rcu^rr.i 'MkSSB.3. RltiiTON, PRUCrOcl 00., LIMITED,
                    Lincoln. x Lower tiypt. GooL> miy also be throngh-bwkod from or to #n/*rtation
                    on ^fdouan Fixed and Portable Steam and Oil, Engines, Com Mills. s Railway. The
                    Company has 70 stations opeded for publioTolegraph'Sorvloe in oonjuflotion with
                    'Paten Tibbto-making'THrashing Machines. all offioee of the G ivamraent
                    Telegraph Department. For tint tabla, tariff and information Messks. PLATT
                    BROTHERS CO., LIMITED, Oldham. Cotton Ginning Maohinery. Miwses. JOHN FOWLSB 4
                    CO., LQflTED, Luos. Steam Ploughing Maebiuory and Sundries. THE,CENTRAL OYOLONE
                    CO., LIMITED, London. Grinding and Pulverising Maohinery. ■ Mksss. OAMMELL,
                    LAIRD CO., LD., or Shsifibld. : Steel Ralls, qtringB, buffers, a — • Patent sand
                    blast files. M188B8. MERRY WEATHER A SONd, London. Steam and Manual
                    FirwJtoginee. Mmsbs. F. REDD A WAY A CO., LD., Pe*idliton, Manohbstbb. The Camel
                    Brand-Belting, eta, etc. mmJHSt?- am .... The (Laval) Patent Steam
                    Turbinas.—Kleotncal Dynamoe and Motoru. MoCORMfOK’d REAPERS A MOWERS. PLANET
                    JUNIOR AGRICULTURAL IMPLEMENTS. - HowHoeb Seed, Drills, eta, eta . OIHVBR
                    PLOUGHS. Aswnt Ir* Oalro 1 v *l. A. FATTOOOI. Asent In Khartoum 1 RlETI A
                    BBRTELLI. es. E HU HR. LIMIT Lisds. CLEAN WALLS AND WHITE CEILINGS ARE ALWAYS
                    POSSIBLE AT A IlfNllUON COST PROVIDED TOO USE (REGD.) EJLESKEL (beod-) THE GREAT
                    SANITARY WATER PAINT ECONOMICAL - EFFECTIVE. Composed bfifrtttly first clast
                    non-poisonous materials Thoroughly incorporated and finely ground • MADE CAWD» A
                    CIRCULAR OtVlNO FULL WARTIOULAR* "Olt ARRUCATldl# TO TtW! MARUFACTURtRr THOS.
                    HFNHHEliWOOD- it CO.. ■ Af.lCKAWriUI* Sodete AixmyiiR de Em du din AVIS let
                    Sooidtt dee Eaux do Cal* port# i to oonnaiseanoe du Publio, quo eon installa-
                    tion poor la distribution dee Eaux k Koob beb-Zeitoun et Matarieb -Slant
                    adhevfa, eUe est prtto 1 fdnmir dansles ditee loes^W-, Tean -pc/or -iu
                    txJflsOmiHatioo,1" atrittage • dos KWhid Mill Stesnnhip ud Gnviiig n.A
                    n---------11—.'1.J pock ifluipanj uiHucu, Uoe place d^SM^Hu^f^touan drie, A LB.
                    10 pdMoiv^taff^^Jfhte, to* Direction de la 46mnpagnie^P#Vra W demandea des
                    pouttlimts jnljwau 3f ju*^ oonraat Lea candidate doi vent fitra Az.-a de 28 k 40
                    Mu'H^WWtn, IhbgUis' iff, Pfin^Sls J l’Arabe. De bonnes rdMiwnceu * tins garanrie
                    de Connections made wil’i the most important trains of the State Riilway in
                    theProvim .^ Ml Hohora, GhArbieh, L) ik.ii-lieh "harkieh and Oalioabieb Through
                    ttrcirj tor goods between *111 kttttttnl Of the OijtoptuJ tad owr 100 principal
                    stations qj the State flailwayin Coper at, I Lower Egypt. Goo-Li may also be
                    throagh-bjoked from or to •any-station on Halounu Bail way. The Company has
                    70’statione opeded for publio Telegraph'Servioe in oonjuflotionwith all offioee
                    of the Givemraent Telegraph Department.' For time tables, tariff, and
                    information apply to the offioee at Cairo, Alexandria Dara-inhour, Tantah or
                    Zaguzig 21416317129 )5 (HKLOUAN BRANCH.) rBagusig * and information 214WSr-lT9
                    )S Bsb-sHouok... Dop. 0.2-3 8. 6:9.1010.10- Helouan ... ...Arr. 17. 7 8.48 9.47
                    lOAil: SR Helouan Dop. Bab-sl-Lowk... Arr. 6.25 !t.»3:8.lA9.1510.1512.* 6 1.20
                    7.10 j 8M !s. 3 9.5 10.6812 «| 1.68 1 1 i 1 1„,L 3 15 4.186.16 4.—j4.66 6.68 8
                    80 T*M00 10.1611.16 10A3 11.66 Ttos*' Cook Son (Egypt), Ltd. MECHANICAL AND
                    BLBCimCAL ENGWfiBHS, ^ALSO • SHIPBUILDBaS, 40.. 4C. All classes of engineuing
                    work and supply of stotee^mdettaken. Poatoom Dqdr fbr *isfaigv*ueljof tbe
                    largnat sitq BOULAO rENGlHeHWbftK» BuawCHza AT 8iiabis. Bsss-ElrBuwD (tAIBO)r'
                    ALBLANDRLA AND KHABTOTM. ' ■‘‘‘•tlqtiK JAoTetvl*g rrir RICHARD GApftfiTT, 4
                    'SONS; WD. | STOBWASSKR 4 WINTER PUTTIE 1 Mwdiq moitakv «umtEn8 _____. „ ;
                    ottaMunos'in). reSitio.'CMB. a *tS.vUiUsl Woo n ... 1 OBO. AN(SD8ija,'L'n).
                    COCHEiN 4 CO. ANNAN, un>. rUcUBt btnsag robUr, : • •ttt'dtohmo yeMai tathal
                    MUrm. ttMmm ga-‘^a.B.,gai.B0fT co. ms. CB0MPT0S^-at- i.TD. 1 ixaa coorm m»
                    cibqsb co. ltd. ! OflUBBf 4-80N‘8 LOOK; 4 BAPE 00. WD .
                    ■•tnfato^WiKUsUMoUvAWeWari'Laaai-q.bBlMlBB I ewitoMBeetoL cgcHRAn 4 oo. Annan,
                    ltd. ' Tta'doobnta pMat NHIobI team. SnauunnTANGYR3' GAS mm* wIOr PmduoRrPtonts,
                    COOPER PATENT STEAM DIGGER, specially smtabtofek smanaattoWiton.
                    TMgrapkioAddrtu: "ENQINKHU, Qd.IIlJ' and "KSQIFKHH, ALEXANDRIA." Works Offi* to
                    totavSkaria B^B-Hadeed (Csiao). 85298 Alexandria Offioo and Stores, Abn- Dirdar
                    Btre*, No. 12. 10.12.905 STEINEMANN, MABAEDI Cu The Egyptian Engineering Stores.
                    MERCHANTS, CONTRACTORS MACHINERY IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRIA Solo Agente for :Egypt,
                    Aria* Minor add Syria for Messrs. CLAYTON 4 SHU’ff LBWORTH, Lnooln,’portable
                    41Lted Engines 4 Boilers, Com mills, Thrashing, Strawbruising 4 Cutting
                    Maehinoa. Messrs. GALLOWAYS, LTD., Jfenebestor.-lThe largest Boiler Works in the
                    World. WALTER A. WOOD, Mowing and Reaping Machine 06. Hooeiok Palls, N.Y.
                    (America) Reapers, Mowers, Harvesters 4 RaJwe. PIQUET 4 Oo., Lyqna. -*■ Pronoh
                    fltoam i Engines. AVBLING 4 PORTER, LIMITED, Rooheeter.—Steam Rollers and Steam
                    Ploughs. LBS TANNERIES LYONNAISB8, Oulline (Rhine).—Beat Leather Belting. B. S.
                    BINDLEY, Burton, Dorset—Vertieal Engines and Boilers, speoially designed for
                    driving Electric Dynamoe 4 Centrifugal Pumps, eta, etc. HILLAIRBT HUGUEOT,
                    Paris.—Btoetrimans. L. DUMONT, Paris.—Centrifugal pumps. E.P.-4B. TURNER,
                    LTD.,Ipswich.—Pk»f Milla 91188*24.5.905 ORENSTEIN a koppkl, ltd. •» Soto Agtate
                    for -Egypt and Sudan of CO MPTO IE MET ALL URGIQ UB BGYPTIBN LE CREDIT LYONNAIS
                    Hit tout* opera- tions de btaque, telles que: Avanoes sat tltres ; Ouvertnre de
                    oomptee oouranta oontre d£ pOts de vstours; Emission de traites et ohlques,
                    emission de lettres de Credit, paiement par tdl-Sgraphe sur lea principal*
                    viitos de la Franoe et de ! l’fttaaSer; Garde de titrea; Reoonvrement d’effets
                    sur l'Bgypte et l'etranger : Le Credit Lyonnais reqoit d* fonds ou on oompte de
                    depOt et deli we d* born k eoheanoe fixe aux taux suivanta: 2% am bona do 1 an
                    et au-deli. ERRffSSBA a jj\ jSfcffia APIOL DuOKETaHOMCLIx GUIHIT RET A RDM.
                    OOULIURS SUPPMSSIQJIf MS IPOQUU j VEGYPTIAN GAZETTE at t% rent* i dans Us rues
                    du Coir* tone to* *oin a | 7 k.80, exempt* Ue dinumcha et jours find* de Da >it.
                    Trim Cedes, d'AUxmndris, is Txntsk, I omwW de Ksfr-zmpet ttMeMapt «-/ro *rto*. t
                    P.r.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
