<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexander Caliendo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-20">October 20, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-11">April 11, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BRITISH BUDGET. TEA DUTY REDUCED. AN UNSATISFACTORY YEAR.</head>
                    <dateline>LONDON, April 10.</dateline><p>House of Commons— The budget surplus for 1904-1905 is
                        £1,414,000. The estimated surplus for 1905-1906 is £2,972,000. The budget
                        reduced the tax on tea by two pence on the lb after the 1st July. The sugar
                        and income taxes remain unchanged. A Considerable portion of the surplus is
                        to be devoted towards redeeming the national debt. Mr. Austen Chamberlain
                        said the past year had been an unsatisfactory one both commercially and
                        financially. The revenue on sugar promised to be an expanding one. The
                        revenue on tea was £210,000 short of the estimate chiefly owning the
                        merchant holding their supplies back during the past quarter, in the hope of
                        a reduction in the duty. The consumption of spirits and beer was steadily
                        diminishing. He had reduced the tax on tea because the article was one of
                        daily consumption in every household and came mainly from the British
                        colonies. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COMING SEA FIGHT. WHEREABOUTS OF FLEETS.</head>
                    <p>Amsterdam, April 10. The Russian fleet is expected at Batavia. (Havas.)
                        Singapore, April 10. Rear Admiral Enquist was in command of the Baltic Fleet
                        which passed here. A steamer has sighted Admiral Enquist’s squadron at
                        anchor 150 miles from Singapore. Four Japanese warships were sighted off
                        Cape St. Jaques on the 7th inst. (Reuter.) Batavia, April 11. Presumably
                        Admiral Rodjestvensky with most of his battleships is at Muntok (Banca
                        Island). (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE OF RUSSIA.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 10. The report that the Russian frontier guard on the
                        Upper Oxus has been detached to reinforce the Kushk garrison is denied here.
                        It is added that the troops hitherto at Merv will remain there. No troops
                        have arrived in Turkestan from Orenburg except some Cossack reliefs.
                        (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MORROCCO. A FRONTIER INCIDENT.</head>
                    <p>Tangier, April 10. The lieutenant in charge of the surveillance of the
                        frontier yesterday chased away some bands of the Pretender who were
                        attacking the Moorish troops near Oudja. (Havas.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INSURRECTION IN CRETE SITUATION BECOMING WORSE.</head>
                    <p>Canea, April 10. The situation is becoming worse. The insurrection is
                        spreading. (Havas.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The “Journal Du Caire.”</head>
                        <p>- M. Fernand Braun, of the Berlitz Schools, has taken over the Alexandria
                            service of this newspaper. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW DOCTORS</head>
                        <p>- M. Evanghelle, Magnis, Salomon Khouri, and M. Louis Benzes, physicians,
                            have been authorized to practice in Egypt. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PLAGUE</head>
                        <p>- During last week four cases of plague were reported throughout Egypt;
                            one at Alexandria, two at Tant el-Ghezireh, and one at Maghagha. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SANITARY DEPT.</head>
                        <p>- Dr. Percy G.S. Williams, of London, has been appointed assistant
                            inspector to the Sanitary Department at a salary of L.E 360 a year. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE HOTEL SANATORIUM,</head>
                        <p>Al Hayat, at Helouan, will not remain open for the whole summer, as last
                            year, but will close its doors on the 20th May. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>UM RUS GOLD MINES OF EGYPT (Ltd.) </head>
                        <p>- The first batch of allotment letters in respect of the new issue of
                            shares of this company has been posted from London. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE FRENCH CRUISER</head>
                        <p>“Ensernet” arrived at Suez yesterday from Djibouti, and will probably
                            return to that port after a short stay there. She carries 17 guns, and a
                            crew of 275 men all told. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GREAT NUMBER</head>
                        <p>of tourists who have busted Egypt this season, has has the result of
                            flooding Sicily with visitors on their return to Europe. Taormina is at
                            the present moment crammed with visitors. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAGUE</head>
                        <p>- The following are the localities where deaths from cattle plague
                            occurred last week: 14 at Mina-el-Kamh, 19 at Zagazig, 3 at bit Ghamr, 1
                            at Chibine el-Kom, 2 at Menouf, 2 at Ghizeh, and 1 at Embabeh. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRINCE COLIBRI,</head>
                        <p>who is said to be the smallest man on earth, has come down to Alexandria
                            after a most successful season in Cairo, and will be on view fro,
                            tomorrow at 5pm, in a room adjoining the Alhambra Theatre. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>H.M.S. “Diadem,” for China, and the French cruiser “Chateaurenault,” for
                            Cherbourg, left Port Said yesterday. The “Diadem” has arrived at Suez,
                            where she will remain several days for coaling purposes. She will take
                            about 1,500 tons of coal. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KASR El-Nil Bridge</head>
                        <p>- A credit of L.E. 600 has been opened for moving the overhead telegraph
                            wires that go along Kasr el-Nil bridge. These wires are to be taken
                            under the river bed and will not therefore be liable to any injury owing
                            to the opening of the bridge. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ZEITOUN.</head>
                        <p>-The roads in Zeitoun (writes a correspondent) are in a deplorable
                            condition. This state of the roads causes much needless cruelty to
                            animals dragging loads of stones, coal, petroleum, etc. It is to be
                            hoped that the attention of the Tanzim Department will be drawn to the
                            fact. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE LOTTERY LAW.</head>
                        <p>- The Alexandria Gouvernorat was besieged this morning by crowds of
                            street lottery ticket vendors, who complained of the conduct of the
                            police in stopping their means of livelihood. The authorities of the
                            Gouvernourat replied that the police were only carrying out the law.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN DIRECTORY</head>
                        <p>for 1905 (Rizzo &amp; co., Cairo) is a great improvement on its
                            predecessors, and judging by appearances this eminently useful
                            publication has come to stay. It is exceedingly well got up and is
                            replete with all that information which is usually to be found in a
                            first-class directory. All the provincial towns of Egypt are included,
                            also the Sudan. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO IMPROVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>- Considerable improvements are to be made in Cairo. The Sharia Abbas is
                            to be carried long the old track of the Matarieh railway line and thence
                            to Kasr el-Nil Bridge. This scheme will give an open highway, free form
                            the heavy traffic in the central part of the city, from Koubbeh Palace
                            and Abbassieh, as well as from the Cairo railway station to Kasr
                            el-Doubara, etc. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE LAST HOMEWARD TRANSPORT</head>
                        <p>of the season,the “Sicilia” (Capt. G.H.G. Weston, R.N.R), arrived at
                            Port Said yesterday morning from Bombay for Malta and Southampton. The
                            troops on board numbered 971, consisting of details and the 38th Brigade
                            of the Royal Field Artillery, composed of the 24th, 34th and 72nd
                            Batteries. The officer commanding is Lt. Col. Watkins, Royal Horse
                            Artillery. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MENA HOUSE.</head>
                        <p>-The management of Mena House Hotel are offering special terms to
                            residents desirous of spending the Easter holidays there, and no doubt a
                            great number will avail themselves of this opportunity to spend a few
                            pleasant days at the pyramid. Despite the advanced season the hotel is
                            still nearly full, and on Sunday last, at luncheon time, the big dining
                            hall has the appearance of being in the height of the season. In the
                            evening again, many drove out to dine and spend the evening inhaling the
                            delicious fresh air of the desert. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BELGIAN CLUB</head>
                        <p>at Alexandria et on Saturday, on the occasion of the 70th birthday of
                            the King of the Belgians, and despatched the following telegram, to his
                            Majesty at Brussels: “Reunis occasion soixante duxueme anniversaire, the
                            presents respectueuses felicitations.” The following reply was received
                            from the King’s secretary, M. Carton de Wiart:- “Le row me charge de
                            remercier la Colonie Belge de see sentiments partriotiques.” The Belgian
                            Club was founded two months ago and already numbers over fifty members.
                            The premises of the club are temporarily located by the Place des
                            Consuls. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate, English
                        Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern sanitation,
                        Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TYROL. </head>
                    <p>Weissenstein Castle 3410 ft. First-class private hotel near Windisch-Matrei;
                        Sation, Lienz (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good mountaineering centre.
                        Tennis. Fishing, best June and September. Prospectuses and Photographs,
                        “Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo. 25365-48-28 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ABYSSINIAN BANK. A LINK WITH EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>Writing from Adis Abeba on March 12, Reuter’s agent says:- The consummation
                        of the scheme for the establishment of a State Bank of Abyssinia is a
                        triumph for Sir John Harrington, who has shown the Emperor Menelik very
                        clearly the many advantages which such an institution in proper hands would
                        secure to his country. I understand that the capital is to be apportioned as
                        follows: one-half to the National Bank of Egypt, whose agent, Mr, McGil
                        Ivray, has been here for the last month arranging the details; one quarter
                        to an Italian group of financiers, and the remaining quarter to a French
                        syndicate, under the auspices of M. Ilg. the Kings Conseiller d’Etat. There
                        is a rumor here that Sir John Harrington has been offered an important
                        position in the bank when it is established. His acceptance would be a
                        serious loss to British diplomacy here, though an undoubted gain to the
                        bank. Speaking if the National Bank of Egypt’s monopoly in Abyssinnia, the
                        “African world” says:- There is no doubt that by means of railroads and the
                        Nile waterways a valuable trade route will be established sooner or later
                        between Abyssinia , the Sudan, and Egypt.To Sir Ernest Cassel and the
                        National Bank of Egypt is due the credit for taking a step which cannot fail
                        to promote progress in this direction. Their scheme paves the way for the
                        introduction on a large scale of British capital into Abyssinia, and
                        provides an important financial link between the country and Egypt. French
                        and Italian financiers certainly have a hand in the new Abyssinian Bank, but
                        the National Bank of Egypt holds half the stock and is the controlling
                        factor. The value if this is clear from the agreement, which gives the
                        Abyssinian Bank a minting and banking monopoly for fifty years, with the
                        right to issue bank notes and establish entrepôts throughout Abyssinia. The
                        possibilities of such a monopoly, from the British point of view, are
                        boundless, and Sir Ernest Cassel is to be congratulated on having carried
                        through so important an enterprise. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST AND INVESTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Extraordinary scenes were witnessed yesterday at the Anglo Egyptian Bank at
                        Alexandria, on the occasion of the subscription to the issue of the Egyptian
                        Trust and Investment, Limited. The subscription opened at 9am. and by 11
                        a.m. the capital of the company (£200,000) had been covered forty times
                        over. At midday, when the bank closes, hundreds of persons were still
                        waiting to put in their applications, and the bank was thronged with an
                        excited crowd all through the afternoon. The struggle to get to the counter
                        was very keen, and even when the bank closed in the evening hundreds of
                        would-be investors had not yet sent in their applications. Before the bank
                        opened this morning crowds were gathering a the doors, and in the course of
                        the forenoon the applications were coming in in such vast numbers that it
                        was decided to close the list at midday today. Telegrams from London state
                        that the applications have been very numerous, and at Cairo alone the
                        capital has been subscribed several times over. The management in Egypt has
                        decided to work day and night in order to complete the allotment, and to be
                        in a position to return the surplus cheques, at an early date. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT. </head>
                    <p>In reference to our paragraph of Saturday, the engineer in charge class from
                        El Der in the Oasis of Kharga that water has been struck at a depth of 145
                        feet in the first bore-hole put down, a plentiful supply being now
                        available. The option of acquiring the land adjacent to the bore-hole will
                        be exercised by the corporation forthwith as part of the 20,000 fed dans
                        which they are entitles to take up under their concessions from the Egyptian
                        Government annually for 30 years. A most favorable agreements has been
                        entered into with the omdehs and sheikhs of the Kharga Oasis relative to the
                        boring of wells and supply of water on locally owned lands. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXPORT OF GUM ARABIC.</head>
                    <p>During the month of february, 849,806 kilos of gu, arabic, valued at L.E.
                        19,121, were exported from Egypt. In the same month of 1901, the exports
                        were 617,408 kilos, of the value of L.E. 13,889; an increase in 1905 of
                        232,398 kilos value L.E. 5,232. From the first of January to the 28h of
                        February 1905 the exports to Englands and her Mediterranean possessions were
                        259,649 kilos, value L.E.5,842. Germany, 283,423 kilos, value L.E. 6,377.
                        Austria-Hungary, 129,773 kilos, value L.E. 2,921. France and Algeria,
                        310,799 kilos, value L.E. 6993. Italy, 57,250 kilos, value L.E. 1,289.
                        turkey, 1,487 kilos, value L.E. 33. America, 123,844 kilos, value L.E.
                        2,787; and to other countries 233,813 kilos, value L.E. 5,261; an increase
                        over 1904 of 484,902 kilos, value L.E. 10,916. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS. </head>
                    <p>The S.S. “Cyprian Prince,” from Antwerp and London, left Malta on Saturday
                        last and is due here on Wednesday next, with passengers and general cargo.
                        The Ellerman S.S. “Flaminian” arrived at Liverpool from Alexandria on
                        Sunday. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PENNY POST. SUGGESTED EXTENSIONS TO EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The Postmaster General is to be asked by Mr. Henniker-Heaton, M.P. whether he
                        will open negotiations with the Egyptian authorities for the extension of
                        the penny post to Egypt. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTS TRADE. CUSTOM RETURNS FOR FEBRUARY.</head>
                    <p>The imports into Egypt during February last are values at L.E. 1,385,341,
                        this being an increase on the corresponding month of last year of L.E.
                        131,074. From the 1st January to 28th February the imports amounted to L.E.
                        3,164,448, an increase of nearly half a million on the figures for the first
                        two months of last year. In this increase, it is not very satisfactory to
                        find that the United Kingdom only shares to the extent of L.E. 77,429. it
                        is, however, a better record than last year, when British imports declined
                        by L.E. 75,810 for the first two months of the year. There was also but a
                        very small augmentation in the imports from British possessions in the
                        Mediterranean, which amounted to L.e. 27,945, as against L.E. 24,507.
                        Imports from British possessions in the Far East declined considerably, from
                        L.e> 169,647 to L.E. 135,153. While British exports to Egypt make but a poor
                        showing during the first two months of the year, every other country has
                        profited by the increased trade of Egypt. America particularly has nearly
                        doubled her exports to Egypt, the figures for that country having risen from
                        L.E. 28,473 to LE 55,945. German imports increased by L.E. 33,801, French by
                        L.E. 68,277, Belgian by L.E. 13,744, Austrian by L.E. 11,498, Italian by
                        L.E. 26,822, Russian by L.E. 81,914, and Turkish by L.E. 25,425.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE RAILWAY CONTRACTS. </head>
                    <p>With regard to the new rolling stock we hear from a well-informed source that
                        one or more of a new consignment of trucks, supplied by a Belgian firm, have
                        derailed on a curve near Alexandria, which is reputed to be the sharpest on
                        the whole State railway system. The last consignment of trucks, received
                        from a British firm in September, 1904, did precisely tho same thing. A very
                        slight alteration set the British trucks right, and it is believed that the
                        Belgian trucks, of which there are fifty of the type in question, can be
                        altered as easily. The Belgian firm concerned has supplied tho state Rail-
                        ways Administration with large numbers of trucks, which have proved very
                        satisfactory and are not dear. We hear, however, that the Railway
                        Administration has given the last order fur trucks to a good British firm
                        whose price is a little higher. The Belgian company is said to have been a
                        little careless over this particular contract, and the placing of the latest
                        order with a British firm may be regarded as a hint to" tho company to take
                        tho greatest possible trouble over the fulfillment of the con- tracts that
                        may be given them in future. In this connection our readers will be in-
                        terested to bear that the Finance Ministry has opened credits of over
                        three-quarters of a million to be spent on the railways, of which L.B.
                        420,000 are for the purchase of new roll- ing stook.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUMMER ROTATIONS.</head>
                    <p>Summer rotations on canals in the Delta will commence on the 1st May. The
                        first programme will allow six days working follow- ed by fifteen days
                        stoppage for outlets and lifting machines, and four days working follow- ed
                        by five and six days stoppage on canals irrigating rice. The programmes will
                        be pub- lished shortly. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive spent yesterday on his estates at Mariout and returned to
                        Montazah Palace , in the evening. His Highness will not return to Cairo
                        before Saturday next,as he will on that day inaugurate tho Horticultural
                        Show at San Stofano. The date of his Highness’s final departure from the
                        Capital for the summer will be pub- lished shortly in the “Official
                        Journal." </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DUKE OF THE ABRUZZI. </head>
                    <p>The Duke of the Abruzzi was entertained to lunch yesterday at the Mohamed Aly
                        Club by the acting Italian Consul, Sig. Monzani. This morning at 10 o’clock
                        His Royal High- ness, accompanied by Sig. Monzani, visited the
                        Italian-Schools and the Banco di Roma, where he was received by the
                        director, M. de Beaupuis, and some Italian capitalists. The Duke afterwards
                        assisted at the inau- guration of a flagstaff at the headquarters of the
                        Italian Mutual Aid Society. His Royal Highness will hold a reception of the
                        Italian colony to-morrow afternoon, from 4 to 5, on the “Liguria.” The
                        "Liguria" will probably leave Alex- andria on Thursday morning. The crew of
                        the “Liguria” disembarked yesterday evening and were received by the members
                        of various Italian clubs and societies on the quay. The latter afterwards
                        escorted the sailors through the town in a torchlight procession to the
                        Alhambra Theatre, where they were entertained.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>1.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE POLYTECHNIC COLLEGE. SCHOOL DESERTED.</head>
                    <p>We bear that the pupils out on strike have received a letter from the head
                        master of the Polytechnic College suspending them for a week. They have
                        replied that they will not return to the college at all unless better terms
                        are offered, and meantime the school is deserted. The parents of the boys
                        who have left the school have received notices from the head master
                        informing them that if their sons do not return within a week they will all
                        be expelled for good. The boys have already informed the authorities of the
                        school that they will not return at all unless their demands are complied
                        with. The present situation therefore is of a threaten- ing character, and
                        we hope that some way out of the difficulty will be discovered. We are
                        informed that “Maison a louer” has been chalked up on the school gate. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL ASSEMBLY.</head>
                    <p>The following were the resolutions adopted by the General Assembly on Sunday
                        :— 1. That the modification of ‘hodjeta’ should be untaxed when the hods had
                        been modified in consequence of the Survey Department’s operations ;
                        proposed by Sidky Pasha. 2. That the Helouan Railway should be carried on to
                        the El Saff district, north of Atfeh ; proposed by Moh. Eff. el Miligni. 3.
                        That ‘sefi’ irrigation should be extended to the eastern part of Ghizeh
                        Province. 4. That the provincial councils should be charged with tge work
                        undertaken by the Meglis el Hasbi and the commission of sheikhs; proposed by
                        Ibrahim Bey Murad. 5. That the Mehkemeh Sharieh should be reformed, their
                        cadis and functionaries better paid, the judges chosen for merit and offices
                        found worthy of the Mehkemeh Courts; by Ibrahim Bey Mourad. 6. That omdehs
                        and sheikhs, when brought before councils of discipline, should be allowed
                        professional legal assistance, and should be able to appeal against the
                        judgments of those councils ; by Osman Bey Mourad. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL DECORATIONS.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive has been pleased to bestow the following decorations and ranks:-
                        Osmanieh. Grand Cordon (1st class): Bakaa Essaltana Mirza Aly Azghar Khan,
                        Consul-General for Persia in Egypt. Grand Officer (2nd class); Zaim
                        Eddawlah, Docteur Mirza Mohamed Mahdy Khan Rais- el-Hokama. Medjidieh. Grand
                        Officer (2nd class) : Mihran Khan, Persian Consul at Alexandria. Commander
                        (3rd class) : Kamel Taymour Bey, notable of Alexandria, and Frederic Bo-
                        nola Bey, secretaryf the Khedivial Geogra- phical Society. Officer (4th
                        class) Taeb Bey, secretary of the Consulate General of Persia, and Aka Mo-
                        hamed Aly, moein ettoggar. Mirmiran. . Seifoullah Youssri Pasha, notable of
                        Cairo, and Hussein Chahine Pasha, notable of Cairo. Moutamaiz. Ahmed El-Alfy
                        Bey, notable of Charkiee, and Mansour Abou Hussein Bey, notable of
                        Menoufieh. Sanieh. Mahrouss Ismail Bey, notable of Beni-Souef, Docteur
                        Mohamed Amin Azab Bey, doctor at Zagazig, Gad Mahgoub El-Heut Bey, notable
                        of Charkieh, Saleh Echawarbi Bey, notable of Galioub, Haroun Badawi
                        Echawarbi Bey, no- table of Galioub, Mansour Abed Boy, notable of
                        Galioubieg, Boulos Hanna El-Kichtah Bey, notable of the district of
                        Samalout, Ghibrial Moussa Bey, notable of Menoufieh, Daoud Ammoun Bey,
                        advocate in Cairo, Imam Fahmi Bqe, advocate in Assiout Salissah (with title
                        of Bey): Mohamed Ibra- him Waly Bey, notable of Assiout, and Eakha- roun
                        Ishak El-Mankabady Bey, notable of Sohag. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHARITY BAZAAR.</head>
                    <p>A charity bazaar for the benefit of the proposed Israelite Hospital at
                        Abbassieh was held on Sunday at MM. Cattaui’s grounds in the Ismailieh
                        quarter of Cairo. The sales went off excellently, the kiosks being besieged
                        by buyers. Miles E. Cattaui, N. Rossi, and R. Mosseri sold bric-a-brac; the
                        teas were sold by Mile Aline Mosseri and Mile Leonie Curiel, while other
                        refreshments were under the care of Miles L. Suares and J. Mondolfo. Mme
                        Maurice Cattaui Bey presided over the lottery, and the Miles Gallico over
                        the “petits chevaux.” Among the many buyers were Count B. de Kosziebrodzki,
                        M. von Hahn, Mr. Riddle, Mme and the Miles de Villebois, Mme De Martino, M.
                        and Mme A. Cattaui, M. and Mme Rolo,| Mme Naggar, Mmo Ismalun, M. and Mme
                        Chalom, and many well-known members of the Israelite community of Cairo. The
                        Bracale Orchestra played throughout the sale.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE </head><p>(Auiourrdhui d midi et demit)</p>
                    <p>Bien quo la hausso ne soit pas generale, beauooup do valeurs out Sgfcrement
                        repris kla suite d’achats adrieux. De 00 nombre aont la Banque Nationals qui
                        remonte k 27 7/16, l’Agrioole k 181/4, laDaira k 27 8/16,1’Anglo American
                        Nila k 5 18/16, lea Eanx d’Alexandrie k 16 7/16 et les Baux da Cure k 1275.
                        1 Quelques valeurs second sires solvent le , mfime mouvement: l’lnveatmen*.
                        remonto k , 2 7/82, les Oasis k 1 7/32, lea Cotton Mill k 5/6, lee Market, k
                        24,1a ^lt and 8odak 89/9. Paroontreon flfohitk 48 snr la BdMraet k 4 7/16
                        sur la Khedirial MaiL Le DOBibn de transaction. 4t4oouskfonhle.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL. </head>
                    <p>Prince and Princess Arisugawa of Japan are due at Port Said on the 6th proxo.
                        by the North German Lloyd “Prinz Heinrich." Lady Cromer’s brother, Lord
                        Alexander Thynne, who is homeward bound from the Cape on the "Walmer
                        Castle," has been for the best part of the last three years private secre-
                        tary to Sir Hamilton Gould-Adams, Lieutenant- Governor of the Orange River
                        Colony. He represented the City of London on the London County Council till
                        1900, when he went to South Africa with the Imperial Yeomanry. Lord
                        Alexander, who is the Marquees of Bath's only brother, is thirty-two, adfine
                        rider, and a splendid shot, and is likely to be offered a high post in the
                        new South African Colonies. The Right Reverend Bishop Morley, D.D,
                        Archdeacon of the Church of England in Egypt, left yesterday with Mrs.
                        Morley by the Aus- trian Lloyd s.S. “Bohemia” for Venice whence he will go
                        to Moran to take a chap- laincy until June, when he will proceed to England.
                        M. Maximoff, Russian Consul-General in Cairo, has come down to Alexandria
                        and is staying at the Carlton Hotel, Bulkeley. M. Maximoff will be shortly
                        leaving Egypt permanently in order to represent Russia at Cettinje. We also
                        notice amongst the latest arrivals at the Carlton Mr. and Mrs. Meimarachi,
                        Mr. Alf. Chamass, Mr. H. Wilson, Mr. and Mrs. Adamopoulos, Mrs. Mille, Mrs.
                        Boganos and companion, Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Mosseri, Dr. Mosseri, Mr. G.
                        Bavastro, Mme. Vve. Sebah, Sir. Alex Dahan, Mr. Wm. Crosseley. Mr. A.S.
                        Ades, Miss Cobb, Miss Adamson,Mr. R. Sidney Wright, and Mr. A.G.K. Levick.
                        Mr. Vincent Corbett, the Financial Adviser returned to Cairo yesterday.
                        Baron Max Oppenheim, secretary of lega- tion for Germany in Cairo, left
                        yesterday for Algiers as delegate of the German Empire at the International
                        Congress of Orientalists. Mr. Maurice Sheldon Amos, judge at the Native
                        Tribunal of First Instance of Cairo, passed the advanced examination in
                        Arabic held on April 4, 5, 6 and 8. The following are the names of the Coun-
                        sellors of the Court of Appeal who were present at the banquet given in
                        Shepheard’s Hotel on Saturday in honor of Judge Coghlan : — Saleh Sabit
                        Pasha, Mr. Bond, Mr. Holtz, Afifi Bey, Hanna Bey, Mr. Will- more, Magdi Bey,
                        Yehia Bey, KaasemBey, Saad Bey, Chawky Bey, Zoolficar Bey, Mr. Halton, Mr.
                        Royle, Mr. Dilberoglne, Mr. Perry, Mr. Satow, Ziwer Bey, Helmy Bey, Kahil
                        Bey, Mchrez,Bey, and Said Bey. The Khedive has promoted Mohamed Tew- fik
                        Chehabeddin Bey, of Belcas, to the rank of Sanieh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. MARK’S, ALEXANDRIA. "THE HOLY CITY."</head>
                    <p>It is proposed to render this remarkably popular work by an augmented choir
                        in St. Mark’s Church on Tuesday, 25th inst., at 5.45 m. “The Holy City” is a
                        sacred cantata, com- posed for the Birmingham Musical Festival in 1882 by
                        Alfred R Gaul, Mus. Bac. Cantab., organistand choirmaster of 8t Augustine’s
                        Church, Edgbaston. Mr. Gault cantatas have attained a greater popularity
                        with amateur choral societies than those of any other com- poser. It is
                        interesting to mention that his music has been performed in Persia, Rus-
                        sia, China, India, South America, South Africa, the United States of
                        America, France, and most of the English colonies. Like all his cantatas,
                        "The Holy City" appeals succesfully to those who love choral sing- ing, and
                        who take an interest in sacred nar- ratives set to thoroughly singable music
                        which can at once be appreciated. With the exception of two hymns ("No
                        shadows yonder by Horatius Bonar, and "For thee, O dear, dear country,” by
                        J.M. Neale), a verse from Milton’s poem ‘At a Solemn Music’ (“List l the
                        Cherubic Host,") and three verses from the Te Deum, the words are entirely
                        scriptural and are admirably chosen. The work consists of the prologue
                        (added by the composer in 1901), an obviously appropriate and beautiful
                        introduction. Part I. “Contemplation” is the fundamental note in the
                        treatment of the subject, which is suggested by the following passages of
                        Scrip- ture: "Here we have no continuing city." “Thy kingdom come." The
                        desire for a higher and better life is expressed in the words of a tenor
                        solo, “My soul is athirst for God." In Part II “ Adoration " is the ketnote.
                        The subject is announced in a bass solo, “I saw a new heaven and a new
                        earth," with its pianissimo “Sanotus” sang as a chorus. The desire and pro-
                        mises of Part I. are represented are realised in Part II. The whole cantata
                        is an uninterrupted flow of charming melody and effective choral writing. To
                        the choir of St. Mark’s, and to those who assist them, lovers of sacred
                        music will be grateful for introducing to Alexandria this deservedly popular
                        work. The rendering of the cantata will occupy not more than 1 1/6 hour.
                        Those present will be invited to contribute towards the expense incurred by
                        the choir in purchasing the music, hiring a piano, etc.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
