<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Jacob Amador</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10-26-16</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-12-19">December 19, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7374] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, DECEMBER 19, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="section">
                    <head>CONDITION OF ODESSA.</head>
                    <head>ANARCHY AND DESTITUTION.</head>
                    <head>ALIENS ask for foreign cruisers.</head>
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service)</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>London, Tuesday, Deo. 19. An alarming state of anarohy and destitu- tion
                            in reported as existing at 0 iersa. The alien residents are demanding
                            that foreign cruisers should be sent to ensure their eeoape.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                        <p>The Holy Carpet. All Government offices will be closed od Saturday next
                            on the oooasion of the ceremony of the Holy Carpet.</p>
                        <p>Training Ship. The German training ship Charlotte (Capt. Meyer) arrived
                            at Alexandria this morning and will remain in this harbour nntil the eud
                            of tbe month.</p>
                        <p>Coptic Council. The Coptio Patriarch has deolareJ in favor of the
                            reoonstitution of the Coptio National Council, and the eleotions will
                            take plaoe in Cairo on the 23od inst.</p>
                        <p>Poutrel-Davey Case. The heanug of the appeal lodged by the Hon. A. J.
                            Davey against the verdiot of the Mixed Courts in the Poutrel-Davey oase
                            will take place at the Mixed Court cf Appeal on the 37th iDSt.</p>
                        <p>Trial of Cadi. The ooanoil of discipline which judged Sheikh Abou Khetwa
                            will hold another sitting at the Ministry of Justice on Sunday, for the
                            trial of Sheikh Mahmoud El Abshilu, the Cadi of the Kafr el Zayat
                            Mehkemeb.</p>
                        <p>Old Bourse Palace Ber. Messrs. Wa ker and Meimaraohi, Limited, inform
                            thepoblic that their nfreshment saloon in Old Bourse-street, Alexandria,
                            will in fatnro bs open from 8 a m. to 3 a m. An excellent orchestra
                            performs every day from 6 p.m. to 1 a.m. [Advt.]</p>
                        <p>Cairo Scientific Society. A meeting of the society will take place at the
                            H-.hool of Medioine on Thursday, 31st in»t., at 4 80 p.m. The following
                            papers will be read: "Note on Looal Attraction in tbe Nile Valley’’ (Mr.
                            J. T. Craig); "Notes on Mummies” (Dr. Elliot Smith.)</p>
                        <p>Tsar’s Name Day. To-day being the name-day of H.I.M. the Tsar of All the
                            Ru-sias, a religious servioe was he’d at the Hamziwi Church, Cairo, at
                            whioh M. 8myrooff, M. Voivodsky, and M. Max’moff, with the personnel of
                            the Russian Diplomatic Agency and Consulate/.were present.</p>
                        <p>Suicide in Cairo. A German named Abel Fritz, residing in the Esbekieh
                            quarter of Cairo, oommitted suicide on Snnday evening by shooting
                            himself through the head with a revolver. On enquiry before the German
                            ooDsular authorities it proved that the uufortunate man had been
                            suffering for some time past from an ihourable disease and evid- ently
                            decided ia a mome nt of pain or despair to put an eud to his life and
                            sufferings.</p>
                        <p>Garrison Church, On Friday evening next, at 6 o’olook, the new organ in H
                            B.M.’s Garrison Charch of St. George, Mostly ha Pasha, will be dedioated
                            and opened. There will b3 a short servioe and an address by the R*v.
                            Canon Ward, M.A., obaplain of St. Mark’s. Mr. Heaton, organist of St.
                            Mark’s, has kindly promised to give a recital of snored musio. AU are
                            cordially invited. The servioe will last abont 50 minntes.</p>
                        <p>Shepheard’s Small Dance, The first of the usual Monday small dances took
                            plaoe at 8hepheards’ last Dight the musio being supplied by the Tzigane
                            Band under thr direction of the celebrated "primaa” Caroli. At
                            dinner-time several dinner parties were given in the restaurant. Among
                            many others there we notioed : Mr. and Mrs. Johnson aDd a party,
                            inolnding Lady and Miss Lambton ; Mrs. Nawe and Miss Nash ; Mrs.
                            McMillan and party; Mr. and Mrs. Whitshoose snd party ; Connt Jamoiski,
                            Sir WiUiam and Lady Fry and party ; Baron and Baroness Budden- brock,
                            Baron voo Tottau, Mrs. and Miss Hurst and Miss Wilkea, Mr. Mrs. and.the
                            Misses Barr, Vioom'e de St Exupdry, Mr. aud Mrs. Chick, Mr. and Mme de
                            Vilmorin, Messrs. Ewart, Neville, eta</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                        <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                        <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                        <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                            charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron
                            Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                        <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                        <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                        <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>
                        <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                        <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
                        <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A CONGRESS AT SINAI.'</head>
                        <head>PRINCE IMMANUEL DISSATISFIED</head>
                        <head>ANGLO-ZIONIST SOCIETY FORMING.</head>
                        <p>Prinoe Immanuel of Jerasalem, otherwise Mr. E. J. Goldreioh, says the
                            "Daily Mail," s dissatisfied with .the present attitude of Sion'sts, and
                            is organising an Anglo-Zionist iooiety, the first oongress of whioh will
                            be leld on the uninviting Sinaitio Peninsula in 1907.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>After presiding over the Connoil of Minie- ars, H. H. the Khedive gave
                            audience yesterday to Count Thaddens fiolesta de lotziebrodzki,
                            Diplomatic Agent for Austria- Hungary, who presented M. von Oeliorenne,
                            Austrian Minister tn diaponibilitf, and MM. I. Matassek and Mrorios
                            Cattaoui. Hie Highness afterwards gave audience to Prinoe laidar and
                            Mohamed Ali Bay Sharara, Idoudir of Fayoum. H.H. the Khedive will
                            probably leave Cairo o-day for bis estates at Lmeilia.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARRIVAL OF WARSHIP.</head>
                        <p>H.M.S. Minerva, a twin-screw protected iruiser of the 2nd class, arrived
                            at Alexandria rom Malta yesterday afternoon, to relieve 3.M.8.
                            Carnarvon. The la‘ter vessel intends saving for Malta to day should the
                            state of he sea at the entranoe to the harbour permit. The Minerva is a
                            vessel of 5,600 tons and an ndicated horse power of 8.000 N.D. (9.600
                            ?D) She was commissioned at Devonport or service with the Mediterranean
                            fleet on 9th iune of last year by Captain Arthur W. Vaymootb.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>
                        <p>This oompany, under the new reorganisation cherne, will s'ill have the
                            same London board « before for the preeent. There has been some
                            igitation in favor of moving the ohief lirectorate to Egypt, but this
                            has been aban- , loned, and oomplete harmony now reigns be- tween the
                            looal directorate in Egypt and the London board.</p>
                        <p>A very favorable deal has recently been 1 soinpleted by this oompany at
                            Alexandria in i (be purchase of 65 per oeut. of the Gourbal Mtate. The
                            estate consists of 49 feddans t )f excellent bnilding land, and a very
                            large i profit may reasonably be expeoted to remain. , 'he oompany has
                            also purchased an excellent i wilding estate in the Nasrieh quarter of i
                            3airo. olo«e to the Ministry of Finanoe, for irbirh it has already
                            received an offer showing considerable profit.</p>
                        <p>Some excellent business bas, we understand, been done by the company in
                            the neigh- i bourhood of Khartoum. A large number Df other real property
                            negotiations are now procefding or are under consideration by the
                            jompany, wh~.se prospects, now that the preliminary unfortunate
                            misunderstanding has been done away with, are in every respect most
                            encouraging.</p>
                        <p>Mr. Maok, of the London board of th;s oompany, left for England
                            yesterday, after having arranged everything to the satisfaction of the
                            Egyptian shareholders.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BANQUE D’ORIBNT.</head>
                        <p>"Here von Strait, the Director-General of the Greek National Bank, has
                            made a declaration,” writes the Athens correspondent of the "Frank-
                            furter Zsitung,” “concerning the ohanges that are to be expected in the
                            recently founded Barque d’Orient on the oreation of the Dew Deutsche
                            Ori*ntbank. The Greek National Bank,’ says Here von Streit, 'only
                            concurred in the foundation of the Btcqne d’Orient in order to pnt an
                            end to the entire interruption of business relations with Germany that
                            had been oaused by the State bankruptoy, and at the same time to see
                            itself side by side with the bank of a powerful nation in Turkey.’
                            Perfect equality in business relations was established between the two
                            banks at the time the oompany was formed, but only on reoeiving the
                            aaaursnoe that the Greek element should have the preponderance in the
                            oonduot and direction of business transactions. Difficulties arose,
                            however, from the aotion of the Na'ionalbank fur Deutschland in seeking
                            to infiaenoe the seleo- 'ion of the personnel of the governing board,
                            and so interfering with the unity and promp- titude of its so*ion, and
                            that in the interest of the German element — a courte of aotion whioh
                            the Greek National Bank naturally opposed...”</p>
                        <p>The solution of the difficulty now proposed is that the Banque d’Orient
                            should be left en- tirely to the management of the Athenian board, on
                            wbioh Greek preponderance should be assure!. The Binque d’O isnt would
                            retain its branches in Smyrna, Salonika, Alexandria and Cairo, while the
                            branches in Constantinople and Hamburg would be handed over to the
                            National bank file Deutschland for further oession to the Deutsche
                            Orientbank.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                        <p>The Moss liner Peti sailed from Liverpoo on Saturday and is due here on
                            the SOt in«t. with passeogers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                        <p>The Mom liner Tabor arrived at Liverpoo yesterday morning.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHICAGO BANK FAILURE.</head>
                        <head>CAUSES SHORT BUT SHARP PANIC</head>
                        <head>ALLIED BANKS’ TIMELY ASSISTANCE.</head>
                        <head>(Gazette's Special Service.)</head>
                        <p>London, Taeeday Deo. 19. * The failure of John Walsh’s bank in Chioago,
                            announced yesterday, oaused a great sensa- tion. The timely assistanoe
                            of the allied banks, however, has completely restored oonfidenoe. After
                            a short but sharp panic, prices are dosing near Saturday’s level. Jnited
                            Copper broke twenty points, but rallied afterwards. AU John Walsh's
                            enter- prises have been taken over by the allied banks.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CONNAUGHT HOUSE SALE OF WORK. </head>
                        <p>The two days sale of work which was ‘ opened at Connaught House, Cairo,
                            yesterday 1 afternoon for the benefit of the Yonng Wo- | men’s Christian
                            Association should he a great suooess, judging from the largS^umbers
                            whioh J attended yesterday. The rooms had been moat tastefully deoorated
                            and the manner in wbioh the several stalls had been laid out was quite
                            artistic.</p>
                        <p>Unfortunately, Lady Cromer wee unable to * attend, and her abaseoe was
                            greatly felt, but drs. Bollock very kindly consented to open the sale.
                            The oeremony commenced with a short prayer by the Very Rev Dean Butoher,
                            ).D., who also made an excellent speech in * which, after expressing the
                            general regret alt at the absence of Lady Cromer and the gratitude of
                            the oommittee to Mrs. Bullook for filling the gap thus oaused, he gave a
                            bort sketch of the progress of the Young fomen’s Christian Association
                            in Bgjrpt- In I* a few well-chosen words Mrs Bollock declared the sale
                            open, and after a vote of thanks to dra. Bullook had been moved by
                            Crookshauk ’*»ha and oarried with aoolamation, the stalls c were
                            surrounded by reedy purchasers.</p>
                        <p>The principal stalls were the English stall, consisting ohiefly of
                            children’s garments, end presided over by Mrs. Alban, Mrs. Bullook. irs.
                            Botcher, and the Hon. Mrs. Davey ; the i lootoh stall, with woollen
                            goods, presided over by Lady Rogers, Lady Willoooka, Mm. Graham, and
                            Mrs. L’Eetrange Johnstone; the Irish stall, with li^en goods, presided .
                            over by Mrs. Johnson Pasha, Mrs. Milward. and Mrs. Trevithiok ; the
                            American stall, with 1 cakes and sweets, presided over by Mm Crookshank
                            Pasha and Mrs. Btoct ; aed the Continental stall, presided over by Mrs.
                            looker and Mme. Fabrioius Pasha. Besides the*e there were the Connaught
                            House stall, eavily laden with London goods, end a ohil- . drop’s stall
                            on whioh toys, dolls, and books abounded, and the tee-room, when refresh
                            ; rnenta were served at a moderate prioa, was well-patronised.</p>
                        <p>Want of space prevents os describing the various stalls and their burdens
                            in detail, but eaoh reflected great oredit on those who were responsible
                            for their arrangement, and what is more important, each was well
                            patronised, and at the dose of the evening their bnrdens were
                            considerably lighter. Should the second day prove as sncoessfal as
                            yesterday the organising oommittee will be able to con- gratnlate
                            themselves on the ample manner in whioh their efforts have been repaid.
                            We should imagine, however, that snoceu, such as is their due, is
                            already assured, for, although ' we have no idea of yesterday’s takings,
                            they must be considerable if all those who were present did their duty.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ</head>
                        <head>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</head>
                        <p>Suet, Monday. 1 The following distinguished passengers em- barked here
                            for Mombasa yesterday morning, by the M.M. mail steamer Melbourne:
                            Prince d’Arenberg and his son, M. Tellier, M. De Ohoisenl, and M.
                            Ledonx. I understand they are going to inspeot the Victoria Niarza Lake,
                            and for this purpose a speoial train ' will be placed at their disposal
                            on arrival at Mombasa.</p>
                        <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. Co. have decided to open an agenoy at
                            Caiffa from the 1st January next M. Ant Catoni, the oom- pany’a present
                            agent at 8nez, has been ap- pointed .to open the new agenoy, and he is
                            leaving Soez on Bnnday next to take up his new post He will be replaced
                            by M. Da La Noe, who many yean ago was also agent at Baez. M. and Mme A.
                            Catoni were very po- pular at Soez, and all who knew them deeply regret
                            their departure.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
                        <p>By kind permission of Lieut Col. C. J. i Markham and officers, the bend
                            of bs 1st i Batt King’s Royal Rifles will perform the r following
                            programme of marie on the terrace, Grand Continental Hotel, oe Thursday
                            after noon:—</p>
                        <p>1. Spanish MArch... La Mattchiche.......... Borel-Clerc 2.
                            Overture........ Tancredi............... Rossini 3. Selection....... The
                            Blue Moon.......... Rubens 4. Liedr Ohne Worte Fruhlingalied..........
                            Mendelssohn 5. Rusian Dance.... Pas de Patineurs....... Godfrey
                            (Piccolo, Corpli H. Arnold). 6. Selection No. 3. Il Trovatore...........
                            Verdi 7. Valse............ River of Years......... Liddell 8. Polka,
                            Two-Step.. Laughing Water......... Hager Regimental March. - Khedivial
                            Anthem. God Save the King Thomas Brown, Bundmaster.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="4"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RECENT DISTURBANCE.</head>
                        <head>WHO WAS RESPONSIBLE.</head>
                        <head>A REPLY TO “EGYPTIAN PATRIOT.”</head>
                        <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—I should be glad tor
                            inserting the s following few lines in your esteemed “Egyptian c
                            Gazette.”:—</p>
                        <p>“Had not they attacked the Egyptians—the Greeks—nothing would have
                            ooourred,” aeys the much vexed for the accusation thrown on his
                            compatriots "Egyptian Patriot" Allow me, please, to oootradiot The
                            incident between the two Greeks, of the loweet-olaae, whioh had as a
                            oonseqnebee the wounding of the native, cannot be the sole reason of
                            Sanday’s riot for a man who has a bit of common sense. Many inch
                            aooidents have ooourred before which Lad no snob disgraceful
                            oonseqnenoes as those of Snnday’a last. Should the natives, of low-
                            class, not be injured by the lest (holy) speeobes of the sheikhs and the
                            disonssion in the street of the "Hub el Diana’’ (Holy War), no men sen
                            believe thel they, who otherwise live in the harmony would raise the
                            arms against them. If the aeoident that obliged them to fight the
                            Enzopaans, haul not happened, they would find another reason (whichever
                            might be) to attack, and always of oonrse the Greeks, being very
                            numerous.</p>
                        <p>The "Egyptian Patriot” seems—against his g kssnmnoe—inspired by his
                            fanatioism, and not e by oommon sense and jastioe, otherwise he j would
                            not mention in his letter, that the Mixed Courts should be entitled with
                            right to diaanse the Greek rondents—end only the Greek residents—as if
                            be had never read the criminal lists of the different Courts—to see who
                            ere the most accused for murders, etc. </p>
                        <p>Last Thursday evening, about nine o’olook, i ping from my offioe home, in
                            oompany of a 1 riend of mine, we met in the Qaai Eagrnie s [the most
                            frequented street) two Arabs who t mid lendly: "We will kill all the
                            Nonstranis.” las there been shot a native again? </p>
                        <p>The same thing has happened long before t unday, when the International
                            Fleets were i erderod to go far the “famous demonstration.” a —Yours
                            truly, A Young Greek Lover of Good Egyptian People. Pert Said, 17 Dec
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TRIAL OF RIOTERS.</head>
                        <p>The trial of the seoond batch of rioters at the Native Coart, whioh began
                            yesterday, was . continued this morning, when a number of witnesses for
                            the defence were heard. The trial, whioh presentee no feature of
                            interest, was itill proa-ding as we went to press. It is npected th*t
                            jsdgment will be delivered this afternoon. </p>
                        <p>A third hatch will be brought up tor trial tomorrow, and the trial of the
                            first batch of prisoners, began on Sunday, will be oontinned cn Saturday
                            next.</p>
                        <p>Among the prisoners arraigned on Snnday was a man who alleges that he is
                            a descendant if the Prophet, and who has 14 previous oon- notions to his
                            credit !</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>OPENING UP THE SUDAN.</head>
                        <p>In an article under the heading of 1 "Developments in the Sudan,” the
                            City editor cf the "Standard” says: With the opening of the Sudan
                            Railway shortly by Lord Cromer, a most important step will have been
                            taken in the direction of developing the resonroee of the
                            Sudanandinorsasing the oommeroialimportance of Khartonm. Only a few
                            years ago the oost and abonr of oonveyanoe between Egypt and the la dan
                            was heavy and wearisome, the Nile route having to be followed, with the
                            alter- native of the no less arduous though some- what shorter journey
                            by oamel from Snakin, vift Berber, while, even in recent times, the jour
                            ey from Cairo to Khartonm has taken something like foor days, with
                            almost daily transfers from one kind of oonveyanoe to another. Now,
                            however, the mode of transit will be comparatively rapid and simple, and
                            some id— of the shortening of the distanoe may be gathered from the faot
                            that after the open- ing of the new railway, Kh\rtonm will he within
                            eight days’ journey of London. With these improved facilities there will
                            naturally be a groat redaction in the freight ohaiges, and it is felt
                            that a considerable and important impetus it about to be given to trade
                            and to business with the Sndan. The whole of the oountry is extremely
                            fertile, and, with that attention that the Government of the Sndan
                            intends to devots to irrigation, the prospects ahead appear te be meet
                            promising, and al- ready have had a considerable influence upon the
                            value of land round about Khartonm, prices of bnilding sit— in the city
                            within the past six months having risen anything between 100 and 500 par
                            cent 1 n view of the recant over specula- tion in Egyptian land, it may
                            be hoped that future prospects in t ha Sndan will not be too promptly
                            disconntod by excessive speculation ; bnt, at the same time, it would be
                            unwise to leave out of sight the great oommsroial possibi- lities of the
                            country, which is shortly to be more closely linked with the gnat
                            commercial oentres byAbi opening ot the new railway.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW KHED1VIAL HOTEL</head>
                        <p>C A I R O Built in 1904. Modern House, Splendid situation. Electric Light
                            Lift. Pension P.T. 50, Arrangements for families</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="5"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CAIRO KUTTABS.</head>
                        <head>SOME INTERESTING STATISTICS.</head>
                        <head>A SATISFACTORY TALE OF PROGRESS.</head>
                        <p>The following are some extracts from the speech of Sheikh Cherif at the
                            distribntion of grants-in-eid on Snnday last</p>
                        <p>Gentlemen,—Yon are aware that the qnes- tion of the improvement of the
                            exi-ting knttabs and the oreation of new institutions of this class has
                            long ooonpied the minds and formed the snbjeot of the discussions of
                            Egyptians, This is explained by the fact that the knttabe are the only
                            means for the propagation of elementary ednoation in Egypt, and the ne-
                            oessary base for all superior education and instruction, whioh are
                            indispensable for the improvement of the nation and its assured
                            prosperity. The Government, being preooon- pied with the interest of the
                            country, is taking aotive steps for the improvement of these schools.
                            The inhabitants of the oonntry have been qniok to understand the objeot
                            of the State’s endeavours, and a general movement is on foot to seoond
                            them. Egyptians realise the absolute neoeseity tor the propagation of
                            instruction and ednoation in an epooh in whioh it has beoome impossible
                            for men to remain in ignoranoe and darkness.</p>
                        <p>The Ministry of Pnblio Instruction, repre- Mating the Government in all
                            that oonoerns education, has considered it beat to pursue its endeavours
                            toward this end in a regular and gradoal manner to aeonre good results,
                            and has resolved so to continue them, what- ever obstacles it may
                            enoonnter. The Wakf knttabs, whioh are not numerous, have assnr- ed
                            resources, and oannot be abolished, are the first that have teen taken
                            in hand. After nomerons difficulties a satisfactory resalt has been
                            arrived at in the oaee of these schools, and the Ministry has tin— tamed
                            its atten- tion to the free knttabs. In spite of obsta- alee it has been
                            able to attract more than half ef these institutions which have
                            submitted to be inspected by the Ministry, obtaining a money grant paid
                            yearly to the most de- serving. </p>
                        <p>Since the application of throe measures, i.e., siuoi 1898, certain
                            important measures have been taken of whioh the following are the
                            chief:— ’ </p>
                        <p>1. The yearly increase of the Bndget for the knttabs. 2. The inorease of
                            the number of inspeotors and snb-inspeotors, of whom there are now 81.
                            3. The inorease in the nnmber of the hours in the normal onnionlnm of
                            the Government schools and knttabs eaoh Thursday and Friday to oomplete
                            the training of.the knttab teachers. 4. The foundation of normal schools
                            for male and female teachers in the knttabs. In two years three schools
                            of this sort have been founded, whioh now train 18 i male and 40 female
                            students. ‘ * 5. The institution of annual examinations bo test the
                            professional capabilities of fikis and arils. 6. —The elaboration of
                            programmes, regula- tions, and roles for the organisation and discipline
                            of the knttabs and the normal sohools......... Despite the short time
                            that has elapsed since the adoption of these measures, their application
                            nnder the control of the Ministry has given, notably this year, remark-
                            able results, as the following facts indicate :—</p>
                        <p>(1).—The nnmber, which increases very year, of knttab wakia and free
                            knttabs that plaoe themselves under the oontrol of the Ministry. The
                            former nnmber 109, with 194 male and 17 female teaohers, the latter
                            4,859, with 6,395 mala teaohers and 33 school mistresses.</p>
                        <p>(2).—The development of the training of teaohers for the knttabs, whioh
                            has made speoial progress siooe the institution of teach- ing oonrses
                            and the foundation of normal sohools. To this development the excellent
                            results of the examination of fikis and arifii last August are
                            das............................ The most satisfactory feature is this,
                            that the majority of those who passed the examine- tions have obtained
                            plaoaa as teaohers. Some, having clearly understood the objeot of thair
                            training at the sohools where they were pre- pared for the examination,
                            preferred to open knttabs themselves rather than aoospt the offer them
                            of employment in existing knttabs.</p>
                        <p>(3). The knttabs under the oontrol of the Mioiatry have made real
                            progress in manage- ment,raligioaa instruction,and in instr otion in
                            other matters, as is proved by(a)the inorease of papila, especially of
                            girls, in the— knttabs. ... (b) by the yearly inowase in (be numbers ot
                            kattafas that deserve e subvention. There are at proa—t 517 first-class
                            knttabe in receipt of grants amounting to LB. 5,098.430 milL and 2,148
                            of the seoond olaas reoeiving grants amounting to LB. 8,185.800
                            mill....(c) The nnmber of advanoed pupils increases every year in tiro—
                            knttabs, — will be shown by statistics shortly, to be published. I hast—
                            to say here that the teaohing of the Kona and of religions prinoip'oa is
                            the objeot of porti- on]— can on the past of the Ministry. The
                            statistics of knttab pnpils learning the Koran by heart give
                            figures..which show that the arrangements of the Ministry are favorable
                            to the learning of the Koran.</p>
                        <p>With the aid of the Ministry of Finance the , Ministry of Public
                            Instruction attempted an important reform which is intimately connected
                            with the improvement of the knttabe. This reform consisted of giving
                            elementary in- dustrial training to certain pupils of the kuttabe with a
                            view to develop the test for professional occupations and to make the
                            people understand that the instruction given in the kuttabe is
                            indispensable for the young <cb n="6"/> both for the aooomplishment of
                            their religious duties and tor the needs of daily life. The H experiment
                            all but failed last year. Bnt the KB attempt has been renewed this yeir.
                            The H Ministry has entered nto an understanding pB with the head of the
                            model workshops at IJj Boulao to the effeot th»t the apprentices of
                            these workshops ere to be chosen from H amoDg the pupils of the Wakf
                            kuttabe.</p>
                        <p>While the Ministry worked to obtain these excellent results it attempted
                            to improve theB knttabs themselves, which were in an in- desoribable
                            state of dilapidation. Bat in view of its moderate resoaroes all that
                            oonld be done under this head was the minimum of repair necessary to
                            preserve the buildings. The real need was their reoonstrnotion, which
                            demanded earns whioh the Ministry was never likely to dispose of. Thns
                            the que-tion of im- proving the sohoolhonses appeared to pres—t an
                            inanrmoantable obstacle, when, at ri»« most critical point, by a
                            providential chanoe, the Wakfs Administration, happily inspired by the
                            goodwill of its direotor, H. E. Abd el Hamil Pasha Assam, came to the
                            aid of the Ministry by m«king an annnal inorease of L B 6,000 in its
                            budget for the improvement of these knttabs and particularly of the
                            kuttab buildings. The Ministry has set apart this year the sum of LE.
                            5,000 lor the construction of six new knttabs, three in Oairo and three
                            in the provinces, and for the repair of 11 knttabs in Cairo. It will be
                            in a position to reconstruct gradually every knttab whioh requires
                            repair.... At the same time the public, which clearly realised the
                            objeot of this improvement of the kuttabe and has grasped the neoeseity
                            of the oombination of all classes in developing instruction, has set to
                            work in every part of Egypt.</p>
                        <p>Everywhere buildings suitable for kuttabs are being constructed, some by
                            individuals, some by subscription, especially since the Government has
                            decided to give free grants of land for the construction of kuttabs. Up
                            to date 758 suitable buildings have been con- structed and 187 others
                            are in course of construction. Local oommittees have been formed for the
                            improvement and extension of ednoation and have oolleoted considerable
                            sums for the purpose. </p>
                        <p>The best method of insuring tint these buildings shall always be nsed at
                            kattafas, Le., at soholastio establishments where teaching is given
                            exclusively in Arabic and includes the Koran, religions instruction,
                            caligraphy, ele- mentary arithmetic, etc, is to make buildings wakfs,
                            and qua wakfs, to endow them with property sufficient to ensure their
                            main- tenance continuance in perpetuity. Let us hope that the notables
                            of the country will grasp the advantages of this course and hasten to
                            adopt it By so doing they will give proofs of their foresight and of
                            their zeal in sustaining the dearest interests of the nation.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <p>Lady Prioe-Fotbergill if leaving England shortly for Egypt, —d early in
                            the New Year the will join her oonsin, Mr. Theodore Bant, in a tear
                            through Palestine.</p>
                        <p>Surgeon-General Sibthorpe, who has gone np the Nile, is — old Indian
                            Medioal Servioe officer, whioh servioe be entered in 1870. He served in
                            Afghanistan from 1887 to 1889 and received the medal with olasps —d also
                            did good work in Burma (1885-86).</p>
                        <p>The Right Hon. E lmnnd Robertson, LLD., K.C., D.L, who has] represented
                            Dundee in Parliament in the interests of the Liberal party sinoe 1885,
                            is staying at the Grand Hotel, Helonan. Dr. Robertson was Civil Lord of
                            the Admiralty from 1893 to 1895. He is a keen politician and hat
                            written,several articles and pamphlets, inolnding a very interesting
                            pub- lication on American Home Role.</p>
                        <p>The Rev. E. J. Hardy, Senior Chaplain to the Forces, is living at the
                            Hdtel d’Angletene, Cairo. Mr. Hardy’s latest book “John China- man at
                            Home" has be— bo well received that, although it was only published
                            about a month ago, a seoond edition has already been called for, and is
                            now in preparation.</p>
                        <p>Ahmed Fai'k Pashs, ex-Mondir ofQbsrbieh, has won hie oase against the
                            Govemfltont in wbioh he claimed the right to a fall pension on his
                            retirement.</p>
                        <p>Among the many residents who have al- ready booked rooms at Mona House
                            Hotel for ’Xmas are : Major and Mrs. Delavoye, Miaa Molones, Mr. P.W.
                            Jones and party, Mr. John Bell and party, and Mr. Boys.</p>
                        <p>The following were the passengers by the P. S. Cleopatra, which left
                            Cairo yesterday for the Nile:—Mr. and Mrs. H.A. Thorndike Mr. and Mme.
                            Ph. le Viemorin, Capit de Saint Exapery, M. Jacques de Dorlan, M.de
                            Terbecq, M. F. Lofebvre, Mrs. F. Jacobi, Miss R. Jacobi, M. and Miss le
                            Breton, Mr. and Mrs. F. N. Houghton.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RACE MEETING, GHBZIRBH</head>
                        <p>By kind permission of Lt. Col C.J. Mark ham and officers the Band of the
                            1st Batt. King’s Royal Rifles will perform the following programme of
                            music at the race meeting to- morrow :-</p>
                        <p>1. March......... Roumaine.................... Ganne 2. Overture.......
                            Poet and Peasant............ Suppé 3. Valse.......... Donau Wellen.
                            ............ Ivanovioi 4. Selection...... The Catch of the Season.....
                            Hainee 5. Pairol......... The Rose, Shamrock and Thistle. Sousaj 6. A
                            Selection of Hunting Songs. 7. Piccolo Solo. The
                            Laks'Festival.............. Brewer (Soloist, Opl. H. Arnold). 8.
                            Characteristic American Indian March, Navaho Alstyne Regimental March.-
                            Khedivial Anthem. God Save the King </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
