<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10-10-16</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-07-01</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN • GAZETTE, SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905.</head>
<div type=“item”>

<head>RUSSIAN, DISORDERS.</head>

<head>MUTINY SPEEADING</head>

<head>“ODESSA BOMBARDED.</head>

<head>THE POTEMKIN SURRENDERS!</head>

<p>Sevastopol, June 30.)

Four battleships, one cruiser and several

torpedo boats left here yesterday evening under

the command of Admiral Kruger, with orders

to sink the “Potemkin” if she refuses to sur-

render, and then assist in restoring order in

town.	(Reuter.)<p/>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Odessa, June 30.

The "Potemkin” began to bombard the

town at 11.30 yesterday evening.

The transport "Vecha” has joined the muti-

neers.

The central railway station has been burnt.

The funeral of the sailor who was shot tor

presenting the petition for better food, was a

great popular demonstration. There was do

disorder. Neither police nor troops were on the

route.

The burnt ships include the “Satatow” of

the Volunteer Fleet.	(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Libau, June 30.

The seamen here have mutinied and wrecked

the barracks. 'The Cossacks and artillery have

been called out and fighting has ensued, but

there are no details.	(Reuter.)</p>

<p>ODESSA, June 30.

Nii e vessels have been burned, but it is

believed that none of them were British.

Machine guns were used to clear the streets.

Two more regiments have arrived. (Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>St. Petersburg, June 30.

It is reported that a mutiny has broken out

at Cronstadt, and that the sailors have stoned

a number of officers. The troops at Peterhof,

where the Tsar is, have been reinforced. (R.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Washington, June 30.

The American Consul at Odessa telegraphs

that the fleet arrived at noon, and that the

"Potemkin” surrendered without firing a shot.

(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Odessa, June 30.

Martial law has been proclaimed.

The funeral of the sailor, whose death was

the cause of the mutiny, took place yesterday.

The police did not make an appearance.

Owing to the arrest of the sailors, the

"Potemkin” bombarded the town. The sailors

were released.	(Harm.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>THE “PERES VIET” REFLOATED.

Port Arthur, June 30.

The battleship “Peresviet” has been refloat

ed here.	(Reuter)</p>

<head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head>

<head>EARLY SETTLEMENT EXPECTED.</head>

<p>Paris, June 30.

It is announced that M. Rouvier will hand

a note to Prince Radolin to-day accepting the

conference, regarding Morocco.	(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Paris, June 30.

It is expected that the Franco-German inci-

dent will be settled next week.	(Havas.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>EGYPT’S JUDICIAL REFORM.<head>

<p>Paris, June 30.

The Chamber of Deputies has agreed to the

prolongation of the judicial reform in Egypt.

(Havas.)</p>

<head>EAST FINSBURY ELECTION.</head>

<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>

<p>The Plague.-Yesterday’s bulletin records

a fatal case at Port Said and another at

Ashmoun.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>A Foundling..—A lining new-born child

was found yesterday in the Haret el Balkatria,

and was sent to the hospital.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Public Instruction.—Mr. Dunlop will select

25 gentlemen whilst he is in England to add

to the staff of Government school instructors.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Course the Nile.--A credit of L.E.

6,350 has been opened for an examination of

the course of the Nile near the Upper

Cataracts.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Crown Casino.—A variety company makes

its debut this evening at the new theatre

which has been built at the Crown Casino,

Ibrahimieb.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the

Esbekieh district of Cairo during the night of

Monday and at daylight on Tuesday will be

poisoned by the police.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>French Comedy.— The Gonnet Levy-French

comedy company arrived at Alexandria this

morning and opens this evening at the Eden

Theatre with the 3-act comedy Mme Mongodin.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Suez Canal.— 9 vessels passed through the

Canal on the 28th ulto., 4 of which were

British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Turkish. The

day’s receipts were fra. 207,947.32, making the

total from 1st June frs. 7,714,139.54.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>SPEECH BY LORD CROMER.</head>

<head>THE CONDITIONS OF EGYPT'S

PROGRESS.</head>

<head>(Special Cable to the Gazette.)</head>

<p>London, June 30.

The Earl of Cromer has received the honorary

freedom of the Skinners’ Company. His lord-

ship, in replying to. the toast of his health,

declared that the Anglo French Agreement

had been of unmixed benefit to all who had

to deal with the local affairs of Egypt and

wore now relieved from the constant friction

and annoyance that haul marked the past.

The story circulated in the Press to the effect

that representations had been made to H.H.

the Khedive as to the presence of British

troops in Egypt was purely mythical. Four

conditions were necessary to secure the uniform

progress of Egypt : first, no hurry; second,

that Egyptian affairs should be kept outside

the domain of British party politics ; third,

that the utmost care should be taken not to

force Western ideas and exotic institutions

upon the Egyptian people before the country

was ripe for their assimilation; fourth, that

Egypt should continue in the future as in the

past to be governed in the interests of the

Egyptians themselves.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>(Reuter’s Telegram)<head>

<p>London, June 30.

The Earl of Cromer, speaking at the banquet

of the Skinners’ Company, dwelt upon the

benefit to Egypt caused by the Anglo-French

entente, and the valuable co-operation of the

Egyptian Government. His relations with the

 Khedive were most satisfactory.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Fatal Accident. — An Italian named Gae-

tano Flatino, aged 65 years, was run down by

a cab in the Attarin quarter yesterday. His

skull was fractured and he expired within a

few minutes after being conveyed to the

French Hospital.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>“Under the Mosquito Net.”—The notes

under this title which we usually publish in

our Saturday’s issue will not appear during

the next few weeks. The concluding portion

of the article entitled "The Principles of

Heredity" is also similarly postponed.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>

<p>At- Thursday’s meeting of the Legislative

Council, Ibrahim Effendi Abd el Al, the new

Fayoum delegate, was presented to the mem-

bers, and the proposal for the formation of an

Armenian Catholic community discussed. It

was • finally decided to have these proposals

printed and distributed among the members

of the Council

The Coined meets again on August 1.</p>

<head>PUBLIC WORKS.</head>

<p>Coal Imports. — From 1st January to 29th

June, 458,233 tons of coal were imported into

Egypt Wales sent 260,729 tons, Newcastle

87,864, Scotland 65,132, Yorkshire 26,876 and

other places 17,632 tons.During the same period

of last year the imports amounted to 482,943

tons.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Shepheard’s Buildings.—A short while ago

we informed the public that the shops which

form part of the buildings of Shepheard’s

Hotel were to be pulled down and larger ones

erected in their place. The work of destruction

has already been commenced and four of the

shops are being rapidly demolished.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Sudan Mines.—Application has been made

to the committee of the London Stock Exchange

to appoint a special settling day in Sudan

Mines, Limited—Further issue of 400 shares

of £1 each, 2s 6d paid (Nos. 1 to 200 and 401

to 600); and 3,896 shares of £1 each, fully

paid (Nos. 7,605 to 11,500).</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>LIBERAL GAIN.</head>

<p>London, June 30.

Mr. Baker, Liberal, 2,320, Mr. Cohen, Con-

servative, 1,552; in succession to Mr. Richards,

deceased. This is a Liberal gain. (Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>HOME CRICKET<head>

<p>London, June 30.

Kent beat Yorkshire by six wickets.	(R.)</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</head>

<head>ALEXANDRIA.</head>

<head>Oz PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED</head>

<head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer</head>

<p>& .HOTEL COMPANY.</p>

<p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO</p>

<p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>

<p>Agents at Alexandria:—</p>

<p>ALEXANDRIA RCNIil WAREHOUSE CO. LB.</p>

<head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>

<p>The best hallway home between Egypt and England is

VIAREGGIO. near PISA</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Mainline expresses stop. Pina woods, Sands Sea, bathing;

mild climate, English Pension, villa Shellay. Eve: home comfort  </p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>PUBLIC WORKS</head>

<p>Among varions credits that have been

opened by the Ministry of Finance we note

the sum of LE. 11,000 for the necessary

repairs to the Tewfikieh School, LE. 4,750

I or the construction of new agricultural roads

in Ghizeh Province, LE. 1,500 for repairs to

the Alexandria Mixed Court of Appeal, LFL

950 for the improvement of the harbour lights

at the entrance to the port of Alexandria, and

smaller credits for the purchase of the necessary

material for the sinking of artesian wells in the

mining districts, for the purchase of pomps,and

for the purchase of dog muzzles rendered

necessary by the new law relating to rabies.<p>

<p>Alhambra Theatre.—The excellent Italian

operetta company which is holding the boards

of this playhouse continues to attract large

audiences. This evening, the company will

stage Suppe’s popular operetta Donna Juanita.

To-morrow afternoon La Gran Via will be

given with the first and second acts of I

Grandtieri.</p>

<p>Seizure of Hashish.—On Wednesday and

Thursday last the Coastguards made seizures

of no less than 500 and 200 okes of hashish on

the small islands oil Agamc. It had been de-

posited on the islands by the smugglers while

awaiting an opportunity to pass it to the

shore, which is so well guarded that it is

now a matter of extreme difficulty to land

hashish. Before the transfer of the above

large quantities coaid be managed the Coast-

guards got wind of its concealment and

seized it.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>The Kanaan Affair.— The Native Par-

quet of the Minet-el-Bassal Kism has presented

its report to the Gouvernorat on the Kanaan

affair. We are glad to hear that an enquiry

has been opened on the subject, and hope that

it will be possible to discover who was respon-

sible for the extraordinary mistake made by

some one in the Native Hospital who ordered

the burial of the corpse without a proper

inquest, and noted the discovery of the body of

a Sudanese 1 Why not a Japanese or an

Eskimo ?</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>“King’s English.”—A very interesting ar-

ticle appeared a short time ago, showing the

great differences in the language, add espe-

cially of pronunciation, in different parts of

England, and a witty allusion was also mud?

to. '“American English.” It admitted, however,

that many modem Americanisms were in use

in the time of Shakespeare, but the universal

opinion- is that there is only one English

worthy 'of the nine, which is “King’s

English,” and special care is taken to keep

only to the form throughout all the Berlitz

Schools, [b. 2vt] .</p>

<head>THE S.S. “ST. KILDA.”</head>

<head>CREW LANDING AT PORT SAID</head>

<head>INTERVIEW WITH CAPTAIN.</head>

<head>HOW THE VESSEL WWAS SUNK.</head>

<head>(From our owmn Correspondent.)</head>

	<p>Sfiez, Friday.

As I advised yon this morning by wire, I

proceeded on board the Russian cruiser

“Dnieper” (ex “St. Petersburg”) In order to

interview the crew of the sunken British

steamer “St. Kilda,” but the officer on duty

absolutely refused tO allow me to see any of

the British offCoers, saying that it was strictly

forbidden. He added at the same time that

they would probably oe landed at Fort Said,

I understand, however, that the S.S. “St.

Kilda” left Hongkong for Yokohama on the

4th June, with a cargo of rice, cotton, and

hemp, and when 40 miles out she met the

Russian Cruiser "Dnieper,” which signalled to

her to stop. A "prize crew was subsequently

put on board, and next- day, when the crew

had been removed, the cruiser sank the “St.

Kilda” after firing ten shots. All the personal

effects belonging to the crew were lost. 41 of

the Chinese crew belonging to the “St Kilda”

were transferred to the Dutch steamer “Flores”

and landed at Singapore, while the British

officers were retained and brought here.

It is remarkable that' the “Dnieper,’’ in spite

of the long voyage and the heavy seas she en-

countered, has the appearance of having been

recently drydocked. She is heavily armed with

large and small machine guns, and fitted with

wireless apparatus. She is also flying the naval

flag. J

At about 9.30 a.m. to-day the Russian com-

mander paid an official call on the commander

of the British battleship "Canopus,” which was

duly retamed. The same offcoial calls were

exchanged later on between the battleship

“Goliath,” which arrived at 10.30 a.m., and

the “Dnieper.”

The battleship “Goliath” was reported by

the “Canopus” as approaching Suez at 7 a.m.,

>eing in wireless communication with her.

Finally the battleship "Canopns” entered

the Canal at i 1.15 this morning. *

The "Goliath” left at 1.40 this afternoon,

and the “Dnieper” at 1.55 for Port Said, where,

!, understand, she will take in about 300 tons

of ooal, not having taken anything at this

port.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>(From our own Correspondent.) ,

Port Said, Saturday.

After considerable difficulties had been put

in my way I at last obtained an interview

with Captain Jones, of the S.S. “St. Kilda.”

Captain Jones states that' the “St. Kilda”

left Hongkong on Jane 2 last. The Europ%p

crew refused to proceed to Japan and were

lauded at Hongkong on Jane 3 and impri-

soned. A Chinese crew was shipped and

the "St. Kilda” sailed for Yokohama on the

same day.

'On Jane 4 theRassian cruiper “Dnieper”

stopped and.captured the “St. Kilda,” putting

a prize orew on board. The ships proceeded at

a speed of nine knots in oompany into deep

water and at 6 a.m. on the 5th Jane an un-

successful attempt was made to sink the

“St. Kilda” by means of dynamite, after

the crew had been taken off. The Russians

then opened fire with their quick-firers and

sank the captured vessel with 16 4.7 inch

projectiles at 10 a.m.

The “St. Kilda” was bound from Rangoon

to Yokohama with a cargo of rice, cotton, and

sugar. The “Dnieper” had been warned of

her departure by Russian agents at Hong-

Jcong. After the vessel had been sank the

Chinese crew were put on board the S.S.

“Flores,” bound for Singapore.

The prisoners, who were thirteen in number,

were well treated on the “Dnieper,” being each

allowed a cabin and having perfect freedom

of movement abont the decks.

The commander of the “Dnieper”' refused

to receive the visit of the captain of H.M.S.

•’Lancaster” this morning. The Russian cruiser

carries eight 4.7q.f. -guns and 27 pieces of

smaller calibre ; she is bound for Liban and

the prisoners have received orders to disembark

at Port Said to-night.	.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>DANGEROUS GAMINS.<head>

<p>We wish to call the attention of the autho-

rities to the dangerous use of catapults in the

streets by European and Arab boys. These

gapiins appear to be supplied with up-to-date

weapons, and samples of their ammunition

which we have seen look most formidable,

small bolt heads and chopped iron bars being

the pattern most in favour. Every evening

parties of boys may be seen in the quieter

streets, especially in the Moharrem Bay quarter,

shooting at the small birds whioh settle on the

tamarisks planted'by the road. We imagine'

that the use of catapults on the public roads is

forbidden, and there can be no doubt about the

i'legality of their nse when missiles are fired

into gardens with disastrous consequences to

windows and grave risk to the eyesight of

those who happen to be in the line of fire.

Even the Mohamed Aly-sqnare is rendered

unsafe : the windows of St Mark’s Church

have repeatedly been broken by stones and

lamps of iron. Mr. Casimatis, of the Anglo-

Egyptian Bank, whom is also in charge of part

of the business administration of the church,

has made an interesting collection of ammnni-

tion fired into the windows and has captured

two of the culprits, whom he handed over to

the police—without any obvious result. This

morning the bowab of the church^w^s struck

on the left side of the face by a stone from a

! catapult which infiioted a very nasty wonnd.

Had the missile struck the unfortunate man

an inch higher he would probably have lost

the sight o^one eye. We hope that the autho-

rities will take steps to render the repetition

1 ot the offence highly dangerous to the offenders.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>

<p>The following is the programme . of the

Wagner concert to be given to-morrow, com-

mencing at 10.30 a.m. :—

1 Huldigungs Marsch.

5	Ouverture do Rienzi,

3	Proludo Lohengrin.

4	Entire dos dieux dana le Walhall do “l’or du Rhin.”

6	Ouverture doe Maitre-Chantours.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

<p>The Moss liner "Raineses” sailed yesterday

afternoon for Liverpool, via Malta, with pas-

sengers, mails, and general cargo, including

4,247 bales cotton.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>

Obtainable from every respectable Firm

In Cairo, Alexandria & The Sudan.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>CAIRO TO PORT SAID.</head>

<head>MENZALEH CANAL AND

NAVIGATION CO.</head>

<p>This new company, founded last year, hopes

to inaugurate the Port Said to Matarieh

branch of its service across Lake Menzaleh

about the middle of October. The Matarieh

to Damietta section will also be completed

soon after, dredging operations being now

hastened for that purpose. The distance

between the former two places is some 28

kilometres, and the same distance separates;

Damietta from Matarieh, where the lake service

works in conneotion with the passenger trains

of the Compagnie des Chemins de for de la

Basse Egygte to Mansonrah and at the latter

town in coincidence with those of the Sta’e

Railways.	c

In October therefore there will be a through

service between Cairo and Port Said by rail-

way and passenger steamer. For the latter

traffic there are two stern-wheelers for passen

gers besides two togs and six lighters for

the freight traffic. All these were constructed

in England, brought oat in sections, and put

together at Karpati, near Port Sail, by the

Anglo-American Nile Steamer Co., who have

entered into a contract to work the lines of

the Menzaleh Canal and Navigation Company

for two years from the date of inauguration.

The steamers have good accommodation each

for a certain number of first and second class

passengers, besides 15^> of the third class.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>GERMANY AND TURKEY

VERSUS

ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST.

BY W. M.</head>

<p>THE DANGER

(Continued.)—^

-The great line that runs tike an artery

rom Constantinople to Konieh is to be carried

on across the Taurus to branch off eastward

to Bagdad and Koweit, southward to Aleppo

and the Syrian system, is a military line par

excellence. Its two branches will one day aid

the German Empire to strike Britain in Aria

and Afhoa. German diplomacy in Turkey has

never ceased to keep the question of Egypt

and Arabia alive and to suggest the possi-

bility that a new Turkish army may

day inflict on Britain the Btroke of Exoatibnr, \

from whioh there is no recovery, cleaving in 1

twain the Empire withont the slightest inter

ference on the part of the fleet on whioh

England’s hopes are centred.

The Turko-German Staff aima at nothing

less than an immediate advance on Egypt

by an overwhelming Ottoman army, should

war unhappily break out between Germany

and Great Britain after the comply., 0f

the Ottoman strategic tines. The snooessof

the invasion would involve the suppression of

the Mixed regime, the substitution of a dele-

gate of the Soltan for our enlightened Sovereign

and his British friends and advisers, while the

direoting power—which wonta not

its position too strongly -» would be the

German Empire. “ Delenda eat Carthago ”

and “ Unsere Zukonft liegt am Wasser"

have an identical meaning in Germany. Her

chief continental rival has been beaten down at

Mukden and Tsusima by her adversary’s ally,

and the Turkish. alliance. originally d—

against Russia or England may now be direoted

exclusively against the latter. Beware, England,

or the day of yonr overthrow will see this ful-

filment of the German dream and the wings of

the eagles overshadowing half the world !

Neither in the Suez Canal, which a few

merchantmen oould block to-morrow, nor in

the straits of the Dardanelles, impregnably for

tified by Von der Goltz and Brialmont against

all the navie&of the world, oan England

her future foe* Her influence in ^ypt^ her

share in the - Sudan, her domination in the

Aden Protectorate, Uganda, and East Africa

are doomed, and these lost, will not the decay

of British prestige lead to the loss of India

from internal causes, unless—

Yes, that will be the inevitable consequence

of Britain’s Egyptian and Arabian policy,

which has earned the frown of the Shadow of

Allah, unless l er people, bringing into play the

foresight and sagacity that , have made them

great, have reoonrse to the sole Remedies that

oan conjure the peril.

(To be continued).</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY CO.<head>

<p>A correspondent writes:—Apropos of acc

cidents on this railway, they are of almost

daily occurrence now. On Friday last the

Nesleh engine broke down as it was about

to leave for Fayoum ; another engine was

sent, bat never reached its destination, and

as no other was available passengers and

train had necessarily to wait until one of

the other branch trains arrived at Fayoum,

when -that engine was sent and succeeded

in returning home with its unfortunate com-

panions “hoars late.”

The Shawashna train on the same day

was never seen at Fayoum. A few days ago

a funeral party ordered a "special” for 3 p.m.

for Daire el Azab; they arrived and had to

sit in the train in the broiling afternoon

sun until 5.30 p.m., when the engine from

Lahoon took the train. No other was available.

Last year the traffic receipts were published

pretty regularly and always showed an increase.

It would interest many to know' why they

are now suppressed, as LE. 300 a month

will not cover the decrease of receipts, and

from what can be gathered it is likely to

be still more. It really is time the public

were better served and these directors were

stopped Splaying at railways,” for I am told

that the native who is “running the show” at

the moment, seising the moment'of chaos,

actually threatened to resign “playing at

puff puffs” unless he got more pay, and, in

the face of this large and continued decrease

of receipts, I hear he&4So have an increase

of P.T. 200, so that the fiuce may continue—

“Great Soot 1”</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

<head>SPORT AND

PLAY.</head>

<head>SALVAGE OF “FOYLE” PROBABLE.</head>

<head>( From oui Correspondent. )</head>

<p>Suez, Friday,

The S.S. “Foyle” is now slightly making

water in No. 2 hold, and about 70 tons of rice

las been thrown overboard.

Owing to the fine weather, disoharge is

continuing satisfactorily, and up to the 24th

inst., over 800 tons of dry rice, and 500 tons

of damaged rice, haul been discharged into

lighters and landed at Perim.

It is now expected that the “Foyle” will be

shortly refloated if the weather continues

favorable.

The divers report that tittle damage is visible

but fear it is considerable underneath the

forepeak.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>THE MISSING SUEZ TUG.</head>

<p>Suez, Friday.

The lighters laden with rioe belonging to the

German steamer “Helene Riokmers” have been

seen lying at anohor 20 miles south of Ras

Gharib^ lighthouses, but nothing has been heard

of the tog. Strong northerly winds prevail and

a heavy sea is running in the Sum Gulf, so

it is expected that the tng has taken shelter.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<head>“TROTTER EGYPTIEN.”</head>

<p>The following is the programme of the fourth

day’s racing at the Hippodrome, Round Point,

which takes place on the 22nd inst:—

Prix de Hadra.—P.T. 700 (400 200 100).

Pour chevaux ambleurs (Rahouan) atteles on

months. Eprenve nniqne—4 tours de piste

2364 metres—Entree P.T. 50.

Egyptian Maiden.—P.T. 6.000 (3.000-1.500-

1.000-500—Poor ohevaux arabes et indigenes

mf Jen (qni n’ont jamais gagne de premier

prix)—En denx dpreuvee 3 tonrs de piste 1784

metres. Entree P.T. 500—(Cette conrse am*

lien s’il y a an moins 6 engagements).

Prix de la Promenade.—P.T. 300 de Sweep-

stakes. Poor cbevanx de la m®me dearie

attelei en paire A des voitnres americaines A

qnatre rones caontchontdes. Pour ohevanx

de tons pays. Seront exolns lea trottenrs de

conrse. Le.ler reoevra an objet d’art et le

65% sur les entrdss. Le 2me le 35%—

Eprenve nniqne.—Distance 4 tours de piste

2364 mdtres.

Grand Handicap International. — P.T.

5.000 (3.000 1.000 700 300) En 2 eprenves—

Pour tons chcvaux de Ire, 2me, 3me, 4rre

classe avec rendementi de distanoe anivant

la vitesse opnstatde en Egypte. Les ohevanx

qni n’ont pas de vitesse constatde partiront

scratch. Distance 3 tours de piste 1.780 m.

minimum. Entree P.T. 300.

Conditions G£n£rales.—Les courses sont

sonmises aux rdglements da Trotter Egyptian.

Les inscriptions seront oloeee le 15 juillet

A 4h. p.m., et devront Stre adressdes avec le

montant des entries an Seordtaire du Trotter

Egyptian, Mr. O. della Marra, Rond-Point, ex

Vdlodrome, Alexandria</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>The Rev. F.'^B. N. Norman-Lee, S.O.F., and

Mn. Norman-Lee are leaving on the 4th inst

by the P. & 0. “Egypt” for England. Mr. and

Mn. Norman-Lee take tins opportunity of

thanking their numerous friends for their kind

enquiries and sympathy daring Mrs. Norman-

Lee’s severe illness. Mr. Norman-Lee will be

away for four months and daring that time his

duties at Alexandria will be performed by the

Rev. Arthur H. Manning, acting chaplain to

the Forces, who is staying at the Miramare

Hotel, Ramleh.</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>A cable from London states that Baron de

Knsel Bey, manager of the Egyptian Tnut

and Investment, Limited, has left for Egypt

viA Brindisi, and iB dne at Alexandria on

Wednesday next</p>
<div type=“item”>

<p>Dr. Warpoek, medical superintendent of Ab-

bassieh Asylum, left Egypt yesterday for

England on three months’ leave of absence.<p>

<p>Mr. S. G. Violate left Alexandria to-day for

a short holiday in Greece,</p>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905</head>
<head>THE MOST ANCIENT TEMPLE</head>
<head>AT THEBES.</head>
<head>(Continued)</head>
<p>Many new fragments of reliefs from the
enclosure wall of the pyramid-hall have been
found this year ; especially noticeable is a
fragment of a shrine with a relief depicting
King Meutuhetep and his wife, who would
seem to have been a Nubian, judging from
her portrait. The portrait of the King, though
small, is very line. The name of a new King,
Ra-kha- .... has been found, and also re*
mains of shrine-inscriptions of the KiDg Men-
tuhetep, who bore the "Horns" name Neter-
hetjet.</p>
<p>It will be remembered that on the front or
eastern face of the temple-platform, on either
side of the ramp, there are colonnades, each
consisting of a double row of square columns.
These colonnades, of which the northern was
excavated last year, the southern this season,
were designed to protect sculptures engraved
on the facing wall of the platform. The same
arrangement was adopted by the architects of
the neighbour-temple of Queen Hatshepsu,
and it is permissible to suppose that the later
architects copied this feature from the earlier
tempi •. The sculptured facing-wall, originally
built of large limestone blocks like those of
the similar wall in the North Court, is now
nearly destroyed, but during the excavations
we found many fragments of its reliefs ; hunt-
ing scenes, in which the King ^ seen chasing
antelopes and other big game of the desert;
boats carrying soldiers or passing across the
river in solemn religious procession ; heaps of
enemies slain by the King's arrows, &c. Men-
tuhetep was certainly a warrior, and waged
war against the Semites ; the slain enemies,
yellow men with pointed beards, are called in
an accompanying inscription Aamu—i.e., no-
mads of the Sinaitic peninsula. Up to the
present we have not found any corresponding
mention of Punt or the Punites, though we
know that a King of this dynasty sent an
expedition to that laud of theT^r south.</p>
<p>The excavation of the temple began last
year with the discovery, on the north side, of
a court, with facing-walls of magnificent ma-
sonry, separating it from the temple of the
XVIIth dynasty. On the opposite side of the
platform, the southern, we have this /ear
found another court, corresponding to the
other one, and bounded by the southern horn
of the Deir el-Bahari cliffs. So that we now see
that the whole width of the space within the
circus of cliffs was occupied by the two tem-
ples, which at the time of the XVIIIth
dynasty the visitors coming from the Nile
saw before him rising side by side against the
background of the cliff*. It is the aim of the
Egypt Exploration Fund to enable the modern
visitor to see the same sight, and it is qgr
wish to enable him to do so as quickly^
possible. Three sides of the platform have b;en
laid bare ; what has to be done now is 4 to
excavate the back part of the temple and to
ascertain how far it goes back westward
towards the mountain, whether it joins this
directly or whether there is something between.
At present we can see a few columns, and
remains of a building of the XVIIIth dynasty ;
we may discover the passage to a shrine,
perhaps even the shrine and rock-cut tomb of
the King himself.</p>
<p>In the Southern Court we found remains of
a gallery of statues which one of the Kings of
the XIIth dynasty, Usertsen III., had erected
in his own honor. There were at least six
standing statues of black granite. They pro-
bably stood on the platform, and were broken
and thrown down into the court All have
been broken off at the knees, and the lower
parts of all have disappeared. Four have the
heads in a fairly good state of preservation,
except the nose. They are all alike, showing
that each is a portrait. Perhaps a certain
difference between them might suggest that
they represent the King at different ages.
They are very good specimens of the Royal
type of the XIIth dynasty, a thoroughly
Egyptian type ; curiously, there is a great
similarity between the face of Usertsen and
that of the mummy of the Princess Tua, found
by Mr. Theodore N. Davis in the Valley of the
Kings, although she lived about a thousand
years later than our king. That we have a
portrait of the king is also shown by the fact
that the statues of Usertsen III, with exactly
the same face, in red granite, have been found
by M. Legrain at Karnak. These are also good
specimens of what we might call the Theban
school of sculpture. This is a point of view
which has too often been left in the shade by
the students of Egyptian art. Art has too often
been considered as being uniform through the
whole country, and its various modifications
have been classified chronologically, while no
sufficient account has been taken of local tastes
and local traditions which might preserve in
Egypt longer than anywhere else, owing to the
conservative character of the Egyptians.</p>
<p>Later dynasties worked in the temple, for
instance the Ramessides of the XIXth and
XXth; but it may be doubted whether these
kings did not do more ham than good to the
construction. Siptah, who left a representa-
tion of himself offering to the cow of Hathor
on the western face of the pyramid-ban, seems
Jp have been the chief later renovator,’in his
<div type=“item”>
time it is evident that the temple was falling
into rain, as in the North Colonnade rough
Ramesside graffiti are scratched upon the
pillars, and subsidiary brick piers were built to
sustain the falling roof. The beautiful walls of
large limestone blocks were very soon used as
quarries. But in the time ff XVIIIth dynasty,
and probably up to the reign of Rameaes II., it
seems to have been in a good state of preserva-
tion. We have found a great many statues and
steles, more or loss fragmentary, which belong
to this epoch, when the two temples of Deir
el-Bahari existed side by side. The monarchs
of the XVIIIth dynasty seem to have specially
reverenced Mentuhetep, since it was from him
that they derived their origin. Both Amenhetep
I., the second king of the dynasty, and Mentu-
setep were venerated as tutelary demons of
the necropolis of Western Thebes, Mentuhetep
more especially at Deir el-Bahari, his burial
place. On a small stele we have representations
of funerary statues of both these kings, and we
have found the actual statues themselves ; one
of them, a great Odiride figure of Amenhetep
in Sandstone, painted red and white, has been
brought back to England. The XVIIIth
dynasty representation of these actual statues
is a very interesting find. Two votive statues
save been found of Faiser, a XIXth dynasty
governor of Thebes, whose tomb is known
in this neighbourhood. A very beautiful
trophy is a cow’s head in alabaster, the eyes
of which were originally inlaid with lapis lazuli;
this is of the best possible work of the XVIIIth
dynasty sculptors; it no doubt belongs to one
of the images of Hathor preserved in the shrine
built to that goddess by Hatshepsu. This hue
work of Egyptian art will also be exhibited
in July.<p>
<p>It will be remembered that an important
result of last year's diggings, from the anthro-
pological point of view, was the collection of a
large number of small votive offerings, of the
time of the XVIIIth dynasty chiefly, which
lad been thrown out when broken or useless
ay the sacristans of the Hathor-shrine into the
court between the two temples, which thus
became a dust heap. A large number work-
men’s tools, hoes, baskets, &c., were also found.
This year no further discovery of votive offer-
ings is to be recorded, with the exception of
fragments of blue glazed faience ; but a larger
number of tools has been found than last year;
especially worthy of mention is a small bronze
graving tool, mounted in a wooden handle,
which was evidently intended tor cutting
hieroglyphs. This object has been kept at Cairo.</p>
<p>These discoveries of antiquities of a later
period are interesting ; but what gives to this
excavation its importance is all that belongs to
the XIth dynasty. Of the art and architecture
of this dynasty but little was known before
these two last seasons’ work; but now we have
a more intimate knowledge than ever before of
the peculiar character of both, and of the per-
fection of workmanship to which the sculpture
of this early period attained. This, the first
temple yet discovered of the Middle Kingdom
period, and the oldest temple in Egypt of
which so much has been preserved, is of a
character quite different from any other ancient
building to be seen elsewhere in the valley of
the Nile. Besides, history has gained from
this work the name of at least one new king,
possibly the names of two new kings, of this
dynasty. This is enough to show how import-
ant it is to science that this excavation should
be completed as soon as possible. The western
end of the temple remains to be excavated.
That further important results will be gleaned
and more interesting antiquities found, we do
not doubt. We commend this work to the
friends of Egyptian antiquity, whose monetary
support could not be given for a worthier
object, and we trust that the Egypt Explora-
tion Fund will be able to find the necessary
resources for completing the thorough explora-
tion of the oldest temple at Thebes.</p>
<p>In conclusion, it should be said that the
Egypt Exploration Fund’s exhibition of the
temple-reliefs, statues, and other objects dis-
covered this year at Deir el-Bahari will be held
in the rooms of the Society of Biblical Arch-
eology, 37, Great Russell-street, W.C., daring
the month of July, by kind permission of the
council of that society.</p>
<p>Edouard Naville.</p>
<p>H. R. Hall.</p>

<div type =“item”>
<p>WANTED.— Good Waiters for Hotel, speak-
ing English and French. German preferred.
Apply No. 26,198 "Egyptian Gazette”.</p>

<head>EGYPTIAN HOTELS</head>
<head>A RECORD YEAR.</head>
<p>The eighth annual general meeting of the
shareholders of the Egyptian Hotels, Ltd.,
was held on June 21 at the restored offices
of the company, No. 5, Lothbury, London,
E.G., Lord Claud Hamilton, chairman of the
company, presiding.</p>
<p>The secretary (Mr. William B. Peat) read
the notice convening the meeting and the
auditors’ report.</p>
<p>The Chairman said : Before proceeding with
the business of the meeting, I desire on
behalf of myself and my colleagues to express
our regret at the loss of our distinguished
colleague, Sir Robert Herbert, whose valua-
ble services we very much appreciated. I
think I shall not be too sanguine in assuming
that the results of the year’s trading, as
disclosed by the report and accounts, already
in your hands, have met with the entire
satisfaction of the shareholders, and that these
results fully justify the policy of the Board
which has been backed up by the able assist-
ance rendered by Mr. Baehler, the manager
of the hotels. This great progress of the com-
pany has followed the gradual, but now finally
completed, removal of the system of dual man-
agement of the hotels. Under this system the
hote’s were managed by the Compagnie Inter-
ternationale des Grands Hotels from Paris, and
the deadweight of management expenses involv-
ed by that administration render a dividend
to the ordinary shareholders a somewhat
remote contingency. We have now got past
that stage of the company’s- history, and
on# capacity of the present time to pay
a 10 per cent, dividend on our ordinary
shares, and to place the equivalent of a year’s
preference dividend to reserve, marks a re-
cord in the company’s existence. I will now
briefly refer to the accounts. On the credit
side of the profit and loss account it will be
observed that the profits of the hotels for the
year amount to £39,734, or about £6,300
more than in the preceding year. On the
debit side it will be seen that a large portion
of this sum has, as usual, been applied in
payment of the service of the debentures,
which requires the setting aside annually
of £13,305. The remaining expenditure
shown in the profit and loss account
amounts to £5,572. This includes £2,571
written off the compensation for the cancella-
tion of the agreement with the Compagnie
Internationale des Grands Hotels, and the
earn of £80J as a final payment to that com-
pany under its agreement with us. We have
therefore been able to effect a large increase in
the expenditure as compared with former
years. Turning to the balance-sheet, it will be
seen that the sale of surplus lauds has con-
tinued; the amount received during the year by
way of installments, or otherwise, for the part
chase of land is £2,128, and this sum has been
expended in the purchase of debentures which
have been cancelled. Practically nothing has
been expended on capital account daring the
year.</p>
<head>ISMAILIA HOTEL GIVEN UP.</head>
<p>Hotel Victoria, Ismailia, the lease of which
was taken over from the vendors to the Egypt-
ian Hotels, Ltd., has been given up on account
of its being unremnnerative. In recent years
the traffic, which formerly made Ismailia a
convenient place of call; has been diverted, and
it is no longer possible to make the small hotel
there a commercial success. It will be observed
that our goodwill account is gradually dimin-
ishing, and the compensation p«d to the
Compagnie Internationale des Grands Hotels,
which originally amounted to £17,997, has
been reduced to £10,284. The directors hope
that, given another good year or two, they
will be able to write off this last item out of
profits. We have sufficient oash on deposit to
pay our dividend, and to more than meet aH
onr ourrent liabilities. As regards the liability
side of the balance-sheet, I have little to say.
The debentures outstanding are diminishing,
partly by the operation of the sinking fund
and partly by purchases effected with the
proceeds of land sales. Some legal diffi-
culties connected with the title of one of
our hotels, of too technical a nature to
explain, and which have heretofore involv-
ed considerable legal expenses, are now,
the directors believe, within reach of settle-
ment, and in dealing with this they are acting
under the advice of the company’s solicitors
and in accord with the solicitors of the trustees
of the debenture holders. To fill the vacancy
caused by the death of Sir Robert Herbert, the
Board propose to recommend the election of
Mr. W. B. Peat to a seat on the Board, as
indicated m the directors’ report. The abound-
ing prosperity of Egypt, and the increasing
favor with which travellers regard the Valley
of the Nile as a holiday and health resort,have
done much to improve the position of our
company, and to enable us to hold out to the
shareholders a good prospect for the future.
The same causes have led to a substantial
appreciation of the value of our surplus lands
at Ghezireh Palace. Up to the present, sales of
these lands have been made to the total value
of £40,262,opt of part of the proceeds of which
the estate itself has been developed with
roads, an ample supply of water, and electric
light. Negotiations have been on foot for some
time to grant to a local syndicate an option on
the unsold portion of the estate at a price
which would materially enhance the prosperity
of the company and expedite the redemption
of the debentures.</p>
<head>EFFICIENCY OF THE HOTELS.</head>
<p>We are informed by Mr. Baehler that the
hotels have been maintained in a thorough state
of repair and efficiency out of revenue. While
Wb are much indebted to Mr. Baehler and the
resident directors in Cairo for their untiring
efforts to place the company on a dividend-
paying basis, we do not fail to appreciate the
value of our connection with our good friends,
Messrs. Thomas Cook and Son, who are so
ably represented on our Board by Mr. Harrison,
their managing director in Egypt. I now beg
i to move that the directors’ report and accounts
l for the year ending 80th April, 1905, as
I submitted to the shareholders, be received
and adopted</p>
<head>TO THE WOMEN OF THE UNITED STATES.</head>
<head>Successful Home Treatment.</head>
<head>Dr. Hartman’s Cure</head>
<head>for Female Diseases-A Generous Offer</head>
<head>to Women.</head>
<p>MRS. J. P. COADY, Treasurer of the
Ivy Leaf Club, 1,702 6th Avenue,
Council Bluffs, Iowa, writes:
“Peruna la no experimental medi-
cine. / have used It oft and on now
for three years. At that time I was
cured of Irregular and painful men-
struation. Since that time I have
taken It for Indigestion or whenever I
felt overworked and In need of a tonic,
and I have always found that It was of
great benefit to me. J am therefore
pleased and happy to say a word In Its
praise and shall gladly Indorse It to
my friends. ’’—Mrs. J. ft Coady.</p>
<p>Miss Hattie Grace, 254 West 40th St.,
New York, writes:</p>
<p>“PerunaMhas changed me from a
fretful. Irritable, nervous woman Into
a healthy and a happy one. Nothing
seems to worry and to fret me any
more. Since early womanhood I suf-
fered with bearing doyvh pains and
nervousness. I was thin and worried,
but Peruna restored me. Those who
knew me before cannot understand
the change, but I can sum It all up In the
blessed word, Peruna.”—Hattie Grace.</p>
Mrs. Elizabeth Ferguson, No. 181 51st
St., Brooklyn, N. Y., President West
Brooklyn Audubon Society, writes:</p>
<p>“I am pleased to tell what a blessing
Peruna has been to me. Several years
ago my constitution seemed broken
down and / cared little whether 1 lived
or died. I bad taken so much medi-
cine that the sight of a bottle made me
sick. I had read about Peruna curing
women, and I thought perhaps It would
help me. I bought a bottle and before
It was finished / felt better. I kept on
taking It, and after three months'
faithful use I was a well woman and
able to do the work and undergo the
strain of younger days.’’—Elizabeth
Ferguson.</p>
<p>In view of the great multitude of wo-
men suffering from some form of female
disease and yet unable to find any cure,
Dr. Hartman, the renowned gynecolo-
gist, has announced hi* willingness to
direct tho treatment of as many cases as
make application to him during the
Bummer months without charge.</p>
<p>The treatment will be conducted by
correspondence. The doctor will p»e-
scribe all medicines, applications, hy-
gienic and dietary regulations necessary
to complete a cure. The medicines pre-
scribed can be obtained at all drug
stores. This offer will hold good only
during the summer months. Any wo-
man can become a regular patient by
sending a written statement of her age,
condition of life, history and symptoms
of her derangements.</p>
<p>All cases of female diseases, Including
menstrual Irregularities, displacements,
ulcerations, inflammations, discharges,
Irritation of the ovaries, tumors and</p>
<div type =“item”>
<p>dropsy of the abdomen, should apply at
once and become registered as regular
patients. All correspondence will be
held strictly confidential.</p>
<p>As is well known, Dr. Hartman Is the
president of The Hartman Sanitarium,
an Institution which has a department
devoted exclusively to the treatment of
female diseases. He is thus brought to
see thousands of such cases every year,
the most of whom return to their homes
to be treated by correspondence. The
principal remedy he relies upon in such
cases Is Paruna, which every woman
should hive who has any affection of
this kind. Those wishing to become
patients should address Dr. S. B. Hart-
man, Columbus, Ohio,</p>
<p>No one knows better than Dr. Hart
man how much the women suffer with
diseases peculiar to their sex. No one
knows better than he does how many
of them suffer with such diseases.
Patiently, hopefully, wearily, and often
silently, they eke out a miserable exist
ence, year after year.</p>
<p>No martyr In poetry or heroine id
romance.makes a more touching appeal
to human sympathy than the woman
burdened with the cares of a family
trying to carry the extra load of torn
tormenting and over present female
disease.</p>
<p>Dr. Hartman's sympathy for such is
unbounded, and his willingness to help
them limited only to his power.</p>
<p>Mr. B. A. Harrison seconded the motion,
which was unanimously agreed to without dis-
cussion.</p>
<p>The Chairman then moved that a dividend
of 5 per cent on the preference shares and 10
Ter cent on the ordinary shares for the year
encling 30th April be declared;</p>
<p>Mr. Harrison seconded the. motion, whioh
was adopted.</p>
<p>The Chairman proposed that Mr. E. Har-
rison, one of the retiring directors, be re-elected
a director of the company.</p>
<p>Mr. Baehler seconded the motion, whioh was
unanimously passed.</p>
<p>The Chairman said that in the report they
would have noticed that one of the retiring
directors was Comte Albert du Chastel. That
gentleman had intimated his intention of offer-
ng himself for re-election; bat since the issue
if the report he had signified to the Board his
intention of not offering himself again in that
capacity. A vacancy therefore existed. The
Board were in negotiation with a gentleman
who, they thought, would serve the interest of
the company by occupying the position ; but
rations preliminaries had to be settled Wore
h^ could be elected, and therefore, he was
going to move, at the conclusion of the meeting,
that this meeting be adjourned till that day
week in order to give them an opportunity of
sleeting the gentleman in question. He now
desired to move that Mr. W. B. Peat be elected
a director to fill the vacancy caused by the
death of Sir Robert Herbert.</p>
<p>Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
was adopted.</p>
<p>The Chairman also moved that the firm of
Messrs. W. B. Peat and Co. be appointed secre-
taries of the company.</p>
<p>Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
was approved.</p>
<p>The Chairman then moved that the fees of
the directors as from 1st May, 1905. be rein-
stated to the amount provided by the articles
of association—namely £1,200 per annum.
Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
was agreed to.</p>
<p>On the proposition of Mr. Baehler, seconded
by Mr. W. B. Peat, Messrs. Turquand, Youngs
and Co. were appointed auditors of the com-
pany.</p>
<p>The Chairman then moved that the meeting
stand adjourned till 12.15 on 28th instant,
with a view to appointing a director in place
of Comte Albert Chastel, who since the issue of
the report, had intimated his intention of not
offering himself for re-election.</p>
<p>Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
was agreed to.</p>
<p>Mr. Baehler moved a cordial vote of thanks
to the Chairman and directors for their services
daring the year.</p>
<p>Mr. W. B. Peat seconded the proposal, which
was agreed to amid applause.</p>
<p>The Chairman, on behalf of the directors,
returned thanks far the vote thus accorded.
and remarked that he was sure all were pleased
at the year prosperous rendition at which tho
company had now arrived.</p>
<p>The proceedings then terminated.</p></div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
