<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>John White</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-01">October 1, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-03">June 3, 2016</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7205] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JUNE 3, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, JUNE 3. 1905.</head></div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE NAVAL BATTLE.
                THE MODERN NELSON. RUSSIAN EXPLOITS.</head>
                
                <p>Tokio, June 2.</p>
                <p>On the opening of the battle Admiral Togo signalled —"The destiny of our Empire
                    depends on this battle, and the country hopes that you will all do your utmost."
                    (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>ST. PETERSBURG, June 2.</p>
                <p>The captain of the “Izumrud” reports 10 casualties. After escaping from the
                    disaster he made the Bay of Vladimir instead of Vladivostok on account of
                    insufficiency of coal. He there ran on a reef in the darkness, landed the crew,
                    and blew up the ship. </p>
                <p>The captain of the torpedo-boat "Bravi," which took 175 men rescued from the
                    “Oslyabia” to Vladivostok, reports 14 casualties. He burned all the ship's
                    woodwork on account of his coal running out. (Reuter.</p>
                <p>Tokio, June 2.</p>
                <p>The sinking of the Russian cruiser “Zhentebug" is confirmed. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>A JAPANESE INVASION. POPULARLY DISCUSSED IN RUSSIA.</head>
                <p>St. PETERSBURG, June 2.</p>
                <p>The possibility of a Japanese bombardment and invasion of the Baltic sea ports is
                    popularly discussed in Russia. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>ANGLO-JAPANESE AGREEMENT.
                SPEECH BY LORD LANDSDOWNE.</head>
                <p>LONDON, June 2.</p>
                <p>At a Conservative dinner at the Holborn Restaurant, Lord Landsdowne, referring to
                    the hope expressed by Sir Ed. Grey that the Anglo-Japanese Agreement would be
                    maintained, said that at no time on either side had there been any question
                    whatever of withdrawal from the alliance. It is our opinion that, when the time
                    comes when we must consider the renewal of the agreement, the only practical
                    question will be whether we should not seek some means of strengthening and
                    consolidating it. The alliance has been a potent instrument lor maintaining
                    peace, and if it be possible so to modify it that it would prevent the spread of
                    a conflagration when it has begun, but prevent the conflagration from breaking
                    out, all true lovers of peace would recommend such modifications ,</p>
                <p>There has never been a moment when our relations with France were upon a firmer
                    base, and if the inner history of the anxious mouths lately passed be ever
                    written, it will show that our understanding with France has greatly mitigated
                    the friction and trouble inevitable when a great war is still in progress. Our
                    alliance with Japan and our agreement with France are alike with no selfish or
                    aggressive purpose in view. Our sole object has been to secure peace and
                    restrict the evils of war. (R.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PEACE OVERTURES</head>
                <p>PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT'S OFFER OF SERVICES.</p>
                <p>WASHINGTON, June 3.</p>
                <p>Count Cassini called on President Roosevelt yesterday. The President expressed
                    the earnest hope,as a friend of Russia, that she would seek to conclude peace
                    with Japan in response to the wish of the entire civilised world. The
                    prolongation of the war would mean increased Japanese demands. He pointed out
                    that Russia could hardly hope to win, and that influenced solely by motives of
                    humanity he offered his services as a mediator or an intermediary in any way
                    acceptable to Russia. Count Cassini replied that he was without instructions,
                    but that be personally believed that Russia would continue the war, because the
                    moment is not advantageous for the discussion of peace Russia has not lost any
                    of her own territory and nothing in the present situation necessitates suing for
                    peace. He promised, however, to communicate President Roosevelt's view and offer
                    to the Tsar. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>LONDON, June 3.</p>
                <p>The "Standard" learns from Washington that the American Ambassador at St Peters
                    burg has been instructed to communicate Pre-dent Roosevelt’s conception of the
                    position of Japan, namely that an indirect proposition for peace would be
                    acceptable, and the slightest opening in that direction would be utilised.</p>
                <p>The "Daily Chronicle" reports that President Roosevelt has communicated to Count
                    Cassini information received from the Japanese Minister relative to Japan's
                    footings regarding the situation. (Reuter.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PARIS BOMB OUTRAGE. SUPPOSED AUTHOR ARRESTED.</head>
            
                <p>Paris, June 2.</p>
                <p>The supposed author of the attempt on King Alfonso's life is Ferras, a Spaniard.
                    The police have arrested another Spaniard, Vallina who stated that he had been
                    preparing the attempt for a month. ( Havas. )</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>BOMB OUTRAGE AT BARCELONA</head>
                <p>BARCELONA, June 2.</p>
                <p>A bomb exploded at the military governor 's palace, causing serious damage. Ten
                    arrests have been made.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>WHITBY ELECTION</head>
                <p>London, June 2.</p>
                <p>Mr. Buxton, Liberal, has been elected by 4,547 votes against Major Beckett,
                    Unionist, (4,102). (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>GOVERNOR OF GIBRALTAR RESIGNS.</head>
            
                <p>LONDON, June 2.</p>
                <p>The War Office announces that Lieut. General Sir M. Nicholson has been permitted,
                    for private reasons, to resign the appointment of Governor of Gibraltar.
                    (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                <p>QUARANTINE against arrivals from Leith in Egyptian ports has been removed.</p>
                <p>The Plague—Yesterday’s bulletin records two cases (one fatal) and a death in
                    hospital at Daman hour.</p>
                <p>Assiout Moudirieh.—In the Budget for 1906 a sum of LE. 4,000 is to be allotted
                    for completing the Moudirieh building at Assiout.</p>
                <p>Egyptian Estates, Ltd.—This company has now received notice from the President of
                    the Stock Brokers' Association of Alexandria that an official quotation has been
                    granted for the company’s shares.</p>
                <p>As Asylum Case.—The Greek Consulate-General at Cairo is enquiring into the
                    alleged sequestration of Mr. J. Valenzda in Abbassieh Lunatic Asylum. He is a
                    Greek notable of Beni Souef and has a fortune of £ 10,000.</p>
                <p>THE Ghirgeh.Scandal.—The Assiout Court of 1st Instance will sit to morrow to try
                    the accused officials, Hassan Bey Wassif, Moudir of Ghirgeh and the Judge of the
                    Tahta Mehkemeh Sharieh for the fraud which they are accussed of having committed
                    in the Rifai affair.</p>
                <p>Coal Imports.—From Jan. 1 to June 1 the imports of coal into Egypt amounted to
                    361,183 tons, of which Wales sent 210,966 tons, Newcastle 68,434, Scotland
                    45,329, Yorkshire 21,221, and other districts 15,243 tons. During the
                    corresponding period of 1904 the imports were 416,405 tons.</p>
                <p>Egyptology at Liverpool.—The well known Egyptologist, Mr. John Garstang, reader
                    in Egyptian Archaeology at the University of Liverpool, will be unable to
                    deliver a full course of lectures during the summer term, 1905. A public lecture
                    will be delivered this month on his return from Egypt.</p>
                <p>Sad Death.—A Greek boy of ten years met his death under painful circumstances
                    yesterday. He was playing on the staircase of bis parents' house with a pair of
                    scissors in his hand, when he stumbled and fell, the scissors entering his left
                    ear and passing almost right through his head. He was at once removed to
                    hospital, but expired on reaching it.</p>
                <p>The Onion Crop. - The total shipments of onions from Alexandria up to date amount
                    to 2,060,000 bags. This is the biggest crop ever known. Last year s shipments up
                    to date were only 1,445,000 bags. The quantity of onions tail in the country is
                    still large, and as there is no further demand for export, Egypt will use the
                    existing stock for its own consumption, and will have no need of taking any of
                    the Syrian crops, which come in through the autumn and winter. '</p>
                <p>All Saints', Cauro.—Dean and Mrs. Butcher are leaving Egypt tor the summer on the
                    6th inst. Mrs. Butcher will not be “at home" to-day nor on any subsequent
                    Saturday till further notice. The Rev. J. T. Burns will be staying at Church
                    House from Saturday till Monday, every week. Notices for him, and letters, will
                    be sent down to the Villa Eden in Boulac on other days in the week, They should
                    however reach Church House before 11 a.m. The Shoubra service will be
                    discontinued until further notice.</p>
                <p>Alhambra Theatre.--- Il Duchino (Le Petit Duc) was produced last night before a large and fashionable audience, the performance
                    meeting with great success. Signa. Im bimbo was a sprightly and vivacious Duca,
                    and was well supported by Signa. Sevres as the Du chessa, while Sig. Berardi as
                    the tutor was excruciatingly tunny. The piece will be repeated to-night.
                    To-morrow, II Venditore di Uccelli will be given as a matinee, and in the
                    evening a gala performance of Ali Baba will be given under the patronage of
                    Baron Acton, Italian Consul General, on the occasion of the Festa dello Statuto. </p>
                <p>Suez Canal.--Sir. Howard Vincent has given notice to ask the Chancellor of the Ex
                    chequer if his attention has been called to the declaration on May 22, of a
                    dividend for the past year by the Suez Canal Company, which will give the
                    British Government a dividend tor the past year of nearly 28 per cent., free of
                    taxes, on the investment of £4,000,000 in 1875; and, if so, whether he will
                    consider the desirability of refunding to British tonnage passing through the
                    canal last year some proportion, say, 5 or 10 per cent, of the dividend, having
                    regard to the charges it had to meet to earn such an income for the company</p>
                <p>POLICEMAN Shoots AN ITALIAN—A most unfortunate and serIous affray took place
                    yesterday evening in Sisters-street, Alexandria, in which a member of the
                    Alexandria City Police (an Italian) was seriously implicated While in plain
                    clothes he had a discussion with a compatriot in a drinking place in the street
                    The subject of the discussion is believed to have been a woman, and the two
                    Italians grew more and more excited until from words they came to blows. The
                    policeman drew a loaded revolver and held it at his compatriot in a menacing
                    manner. The latter sprang at him and in a fierce struggle endeavoured to disarm
                    his opponent But the policeman succeeded in holding on to the weapon, and,
                    getting his arms free, he emptied the contents of two of the chambers into the
                    man’s body, who fell writhing to the floor. The injured man was at once conveyed
                    to the European Hospital, and it is not expected that the two wounds he
                    sustained will be mortal. According to the latest accounts he is progressing as
                    satisfactorily as can be expected under the circumstances. The policeman was
                    arrested and disarmed, and subsequently handed over by the authorities of the
                    Alexandria City Police to the Italian Consulate. It is needless to state that he
                    will be expelled from the police force.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>STRANGE CASES IN CAIRO.
                ALLEGED VACCINATION SCANDAL.</head>
                <p>Considerable sensation has occurred in Cairo owing to the report that two deaths
                    have taken place in the Capital within the last few days as the result of
                    vaccination.</p>
                <p>The German Consulate has opened an enquiry into the circumstances attending the
                    death of Mr. Heinrich Klein, a young German who died at one of the Cairo
                    Hospitals on Thursday evening after an illness of some days, which is alleged to
                    have been occasioned by some vaccine given him by a local medical man.</p>
                <p>A Cairo contemporary remarked yesterday —</p>
                <p>Une certaine emotion regne en villa a la suite de deux deces survenus a la suite
                    de vaccination. On dit—et nous reproduisons ces bruits sous toutes reserves—que
                    les instruments qui out servi a l'operation n’auraient pas ete suffisamment
                    sterilises. Sur trois cas de vaccination, deux ont eu une issue fatale.</p>
                <p>It is sincerely to be hoped that a satisfactory explanation of these cases will
                    be discovered, as if it is found that the deaths ensued owing to the reason
                    given above, a serious set back might be given to the progress of vaccination in
                    Egypt. During last year 408,981 successful vaccinations were performed, as
                    compared with 408,856 in 1903. it would be a great pity if this steady progress
                    in vaccinating were checked owing to the alarm arising from the fatality in
                    Cairo. The importance of vaccination in Egypt is very great, and we may mention
                    that, out of 185 cases of small-pox which were reported in Cairo last year,
                    one-half occurred amongst the European population, more especially amongst the
                    Greeks. This large number of cases amongst Europeans appears to be due to want
                    of vaccination on their part. Many of the Greek patients were treated at the
                    hospital for infectious diseases, and it is reported that those who contracted
                    the disease severely and died had never been vaccinated.</p>
                <p>The vaccine produced at the Cairo Vaccine Institute has up to now given very
                    satisfactory results. There were no less than 4,155 cases of small-pox, of which
                    854 terminated fatally, in Egypt last year.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                <p>The Regent has received a telegram inform ing him that H.H. the Khedive left
                    Constantinople for Vienna yesterday afternoon.</p>
                <p>On his voyage to Constantinople the Khedive called at Rhodes on the 26th May and
                    embarked on board the S.S. "Amphitrite" his eldest daughter, who has been
                    staying on that island for some time past owing to the delicate state of her
                    health.</p>
                <p>This Princess will probably return with her mother from Constantinople to
                    Alexandria in the autumn.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE POLICE SCHOOL</head>
                <p>A sum of L.E. 60,000 will be allowed for in the 1906 Budget for the construction
                    at Abbassieh of a new police school. The present site of the school is at
                    Boulac. The institution holds an important place, for here cadet officers and
                    non-commissioned officers an trained. An extra grant for this school, amounting
                    to L.E.</p>
                <p>1,394, was made in the Estimates for the current year, thus enabling 40 cadet
                    officers and 160 oadet non-commissioned officers to be trained. This is six
                    officers and 120 non-commissioned officers more than in 1904. A new building is
                    much required. Plans and estimates are being prepared, but in view of the very
                    targe demands for public buildings of all sorts, which are being pressed on the
                    Government from every quarter, work on the new school cannot be begun tor some
                    months yet.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>SPORT AND PLAY</head>
                <p>RACING</p>
                <p>LONDON, June 2,</p>
                <p>OaksStakes. 1, Cherry ; 2, Queen of the Earth ; 3, Amitie. ( Reuter.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>BOULAC  CRICKET TEAM.</head>
                <p>Through the individual efforts of players Boulac have up to date been able to
                    ward off defeat. The chief features during last month’s cricket were the
                    excellent batting performances of the Rev. J. T. Burns, Mr. W. B Davies, J D.
                    Streeter, the fine bowling displays by Messrs. W. Greenbalgh, R. Appleby, J. T.
                    Burns, and J D. Streeter. Boulac may not be what one would call first-class in
                    England, but they are precious near it, in the fielding department.</p>
                <p>On the 28th April Boulse v Detachment of K.R. Rifles. Won by 1 ins. and 3 runs, W
                    B Davies 19 not out. </p>
                <p>On the 1st May (Shem-el-Nessim) Boulac played a day 's match with the Bands of
                    the Inniskillings, and the former team won handsomely by 1 ins. and 158 runs. J.
                    D. Streeter 77 and Rev. J.T. Bums 50.</p>
                <p>On the 19th May Boulac v Staff and Depts. Won by 24 runs. W. D. Davies 18 runs.
                    R. Appleby 4 w. for 5 runs.</p>
                <p>On the 26th May Boulac v. Band K.R Rifles. Boulac won by 7 w. and 97 runs. R.
                    Entis 76 n.o.</p>
                <p>In all Boulac have played 7 matches; won 5, drawn 2. lost 0, up to date. The 3
                    first batsmen and bowlers on the list are as underwritten.</p>
                <p>Rev. J.T Burns 5 1 50 10 27.25</p>
                <p>J. D. Streeter 4 0 77 103 25.75</p>
                <p>W. B. Davies 2 1 36 101 23.25</p>
                <p>W. Greenbalgh 30 1/2 5 53 14 3 11/14</p>
                <p>R. Appleby 21 2/3 5 36 9 4</p>
                <p>Rev. J.T . Burns 33 5 68 12 3,67</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>NEW MUSIC HALL FOR ALEXANDRIA</head>
                <p>Alexandria is at last within measurable distance of possessing a music ball which
                    will be worthy of the city. We say this in no disparagement of the
                    establishment, known as the Alhambra, which has been conducted with remarkable
                    success by Mr. Conegliano for some years past Mr. Conegliano, however, has
                    hitherto laboured under a great disadvantage in that his tenure of the theatre
                    site has been a most uncertain one. Now, as we announced yesterday, the
                    proprietor of the Alhambra has signed a ten years’ lease with the owner of the
                    ground, Mr. G. B. Alderson, and his tenure is secure et least for that
                    period.</p>
                <p>The result of this agreement is that a new music-ball is to be built on the plot
                    of ground contiguous to the present Alhambra, on the south side, which is now
                    used as a garden. The theatre will be larger than the existing one, with
                    attractive boxes and the additional feature of a gallery. It will be entirely
                    constructed of iron, and will comprise every modern contrivance against the
                    chances of an outbreak of fire. The plans have been prepared and are to be sent
                    in a few days to England, where the theatre is to be built and sent out here to
                    be put together.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>HUTCHINSON NURSING HOME</head>
                <p>Our Cairo Correspondent writes"--- Cairenes, unlike Alexandrians, cannot complain
                    of a want of Nursing Homes, for there are now three such institutions in Cairo,
                    the latest being the Hutchinson Nursing Home, which was opened about a fortnight
                    ago and which I have had an opportunity of visiting. This horne is well adapted
                    to both surgical and medical cases, the rooms on the second floor being set
                    apart for the former cases and those on toe first floor for the latter. The
                    tourist, too, who has come to Egypt for change and rest, and who is not actually
                    ill, but feels himself unable to stand the bustle and racket of hotel life, will
                    find himself well-cared for here, and he will also have the services of the
                    resident medical officer at his disposal, should he require them. Patients,
                    however, may be attended by their own doctors.</p>
                <p>A visit to this Home shows the great care with which every detail in the planning
                    and furnishing of it has been thought out, and not a single possible want of a
                    patient has been left unsupplied. Every room is fitted with the latest
                    electrical conveniences, in the way of stoves, lights, and fans, is furnished in
                    the most luxurious manner, and has the advantage of being differently arranged
                    and furnished to any of its companions, so that every taste is suited. Separate
                    parte of the house are also apportioned to the nurses, to the Goanese servants,
                    and to the Arabs. There are in all twelve single rooms set apart for patients,
                    and in addition to these they have both an exceedingly comfortable and
                    well-arranged diningroom and a lounge which will compare favorably with any
                    first-class hotel drawing room.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>KARIANS IN EGYPT</head>
                <p>Prof. Sayce has completed a study of some Lydian and Karian inscriptions discovered in Egypt, and lately published in a more or less revised form. Two new characters --one identical with the Cypriote to and the other with the apparent value of a — are the chief features of these, and it should be noted that most of them are to be need boustrophedon. The paper will shortly be published in the Proceedings of the Society of which Prof. Sayce is the President, and, with his former communications on the subject, make up all the Karian and Lydian texts yet discovered. Most of them are of but a few lines each, and the Lydian and Karian alphabets seem to be the greatest acquisitions that they have yet yielded. It is a pity that those interested in the subject do not turn their attention to the Greco-Egyptian Magic Papyri, among the so-called "gibberish” incantations  of which are several words ending ia -anda, which may not improbably turn out to be Karian. The settlement of many Karian mercenaries in the Fayoum and elsewhere must certainly have left traces in the literature of their adopted country, could we only hit upon them.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Britannia" arrived at Liverpool yesterday.</p>
                <p>The Ellerman S.S. "Athenian" sailed hence yesterday tor Liverpool direct with a
                    general cargo including 1,954 bales cotton.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>SAN STEFANO CASINO</head>
                <p>The following is the programme of music to be played by the Bracale Orchestra at the Casino to-morrow, commencing at 10 a.m.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
                <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                <p>x.10.904</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                    Sudan.</p>
                <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM CYPRUS</head>
                <p>TRADE COMBINATION.</p>
                <p>( From our correspondent. )</p>
                <p>Nicosia, May 36.</p>
                <p>The idea of combining together for trade purpose* cannot yet be said to have made
                    much headway among the commercial community of Cyprus. The people of Larnaca and
                    Limassol are now, however, to have an opportunity of becoming familiarised with
                    this method of doing business, as a steamship company has lately been formed at
                    both places, mainly for cargo trade with Egypt, while an important brick and
                    tile factory has just commenced operations at Limassol as a societe anonyme.</p>
                <p>It is to be hoped that the two steamship companies will not work on rival lines,
                    but that they will see the wisdom of uniting together and so acquire sufficient
                    power to do a useful and profitable carrying trade with our nearest markets.</p>
                <p>If the brick and tile factory succeeds in producing good-building material at a
                    moderate price it should have a successful future. There is an evident tendency
                    in this island to use roofing tiles in place of the mud roofs, and it is
                    regarded rather as a mark of superiority for a villager to roof his building.
                    Several mud cottages were washed away in the Limassol district during the last
                    winter season, and this should stimulate the taste for bricks, which will not be
                    so easily affected by wet weather.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PREVALENCE OF SCALE DISEASE.</head>
                <p>There are complaints of scale disease among the carob and fruit trees in various parts of the island. On the other hand it is reported that the unusually heavy winter rains have washed the scale from many orange and lemon trees which had been affected, and that a larger crop of fruit yielding better prices has resulted.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>
                <p>The Legislative Council, which reassembled only on the 17th inst., brought the present session to an end on the 22nd inst.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>EMPIRE DAY</head>
                <p>Wednesday, 24th inst., being "Empire Day," and the birthday of the late Queen Victoria, was kept here as an official holiday.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>FOOD AND DRUGS ACT</head>
                <p>
                    A Food and Drugs Act has been an important piece of local legislation during the past session.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>ESTABLISHMENT OF BONDED WAREHOUSE</head>
                <p>The “Cyprus Gazette" of 19th inst. publishes an Order by the High Commissioner, approving of a general bonded warehouse being established in the Customs stores at Larnaca in which goods destined for local consumption or for re-exportation may be deposited.	</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE SOAP INDUSTRY</head>
                <p>There is also gazetted an Order in Council reducing the import duty leviable on vegetable oils used in the manufacture of soap from the £2 per 100 okes heretofore charged ; provided that such oils are rendered unfit tor alimentary purposes at the expense of the importer and under the supervision of the Customs. This reduction of duty should give a considerable impetus to the local soap industry. Some years ago there were seven or eight soap factories in the island, the import duty on oils then being at the rate now fixed by the new order. The duty, however, was raised to £2 per 100 okes in order to prevent the importation of cotton seed oil for adulteration with the native olive oil, and as a consequence this industry  was crippled and there exists to-day only one small soap factory. It is generally felt that the reduction in the duty is a wire measure.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>EXODUS OF OFFICIALS</head>
                <p>There will be a great exodus daring the next few weeks of officials going on leave. Among those going by to-day’s mail is Mrs. Collet, wife of Mr. Wilfred Collet, C.M.G., Commissioner of Nicosia, who is shortly proceeding to England prior to taking up the duties of his new appointment as Colonial Secretary, British Honduras.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                <p>The Sirdar, H. E. Sir F. R. Wingate Pasha, arrived at Cairo this morning by the
                    7.20 train from Luxor. He was accompanied by Miralai Matchett Bey, Financial
                    Secretary Said Bey Chokar, and several English and Egyptian officers. He will
                    leave for Europe on the 10th inst.</p>
                <p>Lieutenants C.K. Magill and G. R. V. Steward, of the 2nd Battalion R.
                    Inniskilling Fusiliers, have been granted leave of absence, the former for three
                    months and the latter for four months.</p>
                <p>Sir Rudolph Slatin Pasha leaves Alexandria this afternoon for Trieste en route
                    for Vienna, where he will await the arrival of the Sirdar and they will go to
                    England together.</p>
                <p>A large number of persons are leaving Egypt on Tuesday by the P. and O. S.S.
                    "Arabia." Among the Alexandria departures are Mr. Mr. and Mrs. Haselden, Mr. B.
                    S. Seed end family, and Miss Evans, Mrs. W. T. Smith and Miss Lamb. Altogether
                    about 30 bookings from Alexandria have been taken by the steamer.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>DE VERE TRUST</head>
                <p>The usual half-yearly meeting of the above Trust was held by kind permission of
                    Idris Bey Ragheb. M W. G. M of Egypt, in the committee room of the Grand Lodge
                    on Tuesday evening last, 30th May. There were present: Dr. W. C. Mackenzie,
                    Messrs. P. Plunkett, and F. A. Beale, president. The minutes of the last
                    half-yearly and extraordinary meet-ing were read, passed, and confirmed. Mr. G.
                    Scott-Dalgleish wrote regretting his inability to he present owing to another
                    meeting. The President next produced the balance-sheet for the half-year ending
                    May, which, after being audited, was unanimously accepted The balance-sheet
                    shows a net total of credit amounting to L.E. 387.621, a considerable increase
                    over the balance of the last half-year. It was notified that the monies had been
                    invested in accordance with the wishes of the trustees and that the bonds had
                    been deposited with the Trust bankers.</p>
                <p>A letter was read from Mr. Jas. Edgell, J. P. (the trustee in England) who was
                    watching the local trustee's interests over Dora and Reggie De Vere. A good
                    amount was given of the program they were making with their stadias, etc. It was
                    proposed that a hearty vote of thanks be accorded to Mr. Edgell for his greet
                    kindness to three orphan children ; he had them at his home on every occasion,
                    and be was using every endeavour to gain admission into the Duke of York's Royal
                    Military School for Reggie, the necessary certificates being asked for from the
                    trustees. A cordial vote of thanks was also expressed to the Permanent Committee
                    of the National Grand Lodge of Egypt, for their kindness in again voting the sum
                    of L.E. 20 from the Benevolent Fund for the year 1904.</p>
                <p>The President intimated that he had now been three years president of the Trust
                    and in thanking the trustees for their help and sup port, tendered his
                    resignation. Dr. W. C. Mackenzie proposed re-election, strongly urged by Mr.
                    Plunkett. The President, whilst acknowledging</p>
                <p>lodging the honor and confidence of the vote, thought that as the work was now
                    all in a satisfactory and smooth condition, some other member of the Trust
                    should have a turn as president. Dr. Mackenzie still strongly urged Mr. Beale to
                    accept the position for a farther period, which was finally agreed to by him. At
                    the same time the trustees wished it to be placed on record that they fully
                    appreciated the fact that it was owing to his untiring efforts that the funds
                    were in such a satisfactory conuition.</p>
                <p>A copy of the balance-sheet follows for the information of those who so
                    generously came forward in the cause of charity :—</p>
                <p>RECEIPTS.</p>
                <p>L.E. M.</p>
                <p>7.12.04 Balance at National Bank . 364.499 Deposited in National Bank</p>
                <p>current account ... ...</p>
                <p>Residue of estate of late W.</p>
                <p>Bro De Vere ... 4.280</p>
                <p>Annual donation from National Grand Lodge of Egypt for 1904 20.000</p>
                <p>Total L.E. 388.779</p>
                <p>EXPENDITURE.</p>
                <p>L.E. M.</p>
                <p>15.4.03 Paid to Mr. Edgell on Reg-</p>
                <p>gie's account 9.760</p>
                <p>Paid to Mr. Edgell for Dora from 16.6.05 to 15.6.06. .. 12.675</p>
                <p>3 Bonds City of Alexandria</p>
                <p>Municipality 4 % Loan 302.371 Brokerage and stamping ... 1,158</p>
                <p>Cash Balance at Bank ... 62,825</p>
                <p>Total LE. 388.779</p>
                <p>GENERAL CASH STATEMENT.</p>
                <p>L.E. M.</p>
                <p>30.5.05 Balance at Bank.. 62.825</p>
                <p>3 Bonds City of Alexandria</p>
                <p>Municipality Loan 302.371</p>
                <p>In Mr. Edgall's hand for Dora and Reggie 22,425</p>
                <p>Total L.E. 387.621</p>
                <p>LIABILITIES.</p>
                <p>Nil.</p>
            </div>
            
           <div type="item"><head>BANQUE INDUSTRIELLE D'EGYPT</head>
                <p>EN LIQUIDATION</p>
                <p>Le public est informe qu'une quatrieme repartition d’Aetif a raison de dix
                    piastres tarif par Action Privilegiee sera distribues a partir du 5 Juin 1905
                    aux guichete da Credit Lyonnais a Alexandrie contre remise du coupon N 4. 96071
                    1 3</p>
            </div>
            <div type="article">
                <head>EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO. LTD.</head>
                <p>AVERAGE TIME occupied in transmission of Egyptian telegrams from England to
                    Alexandria on Friday, 2th June, 1905. </p>
                <p>OUTWARDS.</p>
                <p>Between the hours of 10 a.m. and 6 p.m. (Cairo time)</p>
                <table rows="6" cols="3">
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell>FROM</cell>
                        <cell>MESSAGES HANDED IN AT The Company’s Offices. H. M.</cell>
                        <cell>MESSAGES HANDED IN AT Postal Telegraph Offices. H. M.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>London</cell>
                        <cell>27</cell>
                        <cell>47</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Liverpool</cell>
                        <cell>27</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Manchester</cell>
                        <cell>32</cell>
                        <cell>1 00</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Glasgow</cell>
                        <cell>30</cell>
                        <cell>1 18</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Other Provincial Offices</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>53</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <p>Delay due to interruption landlines.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>