<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-28">June 28, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bam01">
                    <head>Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</head>
                    <p>Despatch weekly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Mails
                        from Alexandria to Cyrpus and the Syrian Coast and vice-versa.</p>
                    <p>For particulars of freight, passage, etc., apply to the Agent Ed. A. Minotte.
                        1099-25.2.905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-iob01">
                    <head>IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK.</head>
                    <p>CAPITAL: £10,000,000.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFIOE IN CONSTANTINOPLE. CHIEF AGENCIES: LONDON &amp; PARIS.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES IN ALL THE PRINCIPAL TOWNS IN TURKEY.</p>
                    <p>Agencies in Egypt : ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, &amp; PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>Advances on Merchandise and Securities in current account and for fixed
                        periods. Purchase and sale of stocks and Shares on the London and
                        Continental exchanges, letters of credit issued, valuables reoeived in safe
                        custody. Drafts, cheques and telegraphic transfers issued on the principal
                        towns of the world. Foreign exchange purchased, bills discounted, bills,
                        invoices, annuities and dividends collected and every description of banking
                        business transacted. 18-4-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma04">
                    <p>Numbering Machines and Dating Stamps</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Cairo Bulac Road</p>
                    <p>Stationary Engraving and Printing Office</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-alf01">
                    <head>The IDEAL MILK FOODS for HOT CLIMATES. The 'Allenburys' Foods.</head>
                    <p>The "Allenburys" Foods give strength and Stamina, and supply all that is
                        required for the formation of firm flesh and bone. They promote perfect
                        health, and give freedom from digestive troubles and the disorders common to
                        children fed on farinaceous foods, condensed milk, or cow's milk. </p>
                    <p>ALLEN &amp; HANBURYS Ltd., LONDON, ENGLAND. </p>
                    <p>Depot in Cairo:— E. Dell Mar, 25, Août.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dlc01">
                    <head>D C L Scotch Whisky</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt &amp; Sudan</p>
                    <p>G. G Drossos &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Late Prazzica &amp; Drossos.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria. Cairo. Port-Said and Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>1080 31-5-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jbc01">
                    <head>John B. Caffari's "Economical Stores"</head>
                    <p>Cairo and Alexandria</p>
                    <p>The Perfection of Quality and Value.</p>
                    <p>In Sterling Silver, "Welbeck" &amp; Silver Plated Goods</p>
                    <p>Provisions, Wines, Cigars, Crockery, Brushes, &amp;c., &amp;c., at</p>
                    <p>Price List on Application.</p>
                    <p>16-11-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-vdt01">
                    <head>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE PAVING COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>Hamilton House, Bishopgate St Without, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>CONTRACTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE</p>
                    <p>Pyrimont-Seyssel, Servas (France) Ragusa (Sicily), Guanipa, (Venezuala), Mine
                        Owners.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN BRANCH - FIRST ASPHALT FACTORY ESTABLISHED IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Moharrem-Boy Factory, 171, Mahmoudieh Canal, Alexandria.- Office in Cairo:
                        Haret-el-Mashady (Ismailieh Quarter).</p>
                    <p>For Sales of Mastic Asphalte Blocks, Trinidad Refined Bitumen, Bricks in
                        Compressod Asphalte for Paving, Compressed Asphalte Roadways. — Contractors
                        for every description of Asphalte Works in the whole of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>25-45-14-7-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sde01">
                    <head>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED</head>
                    <p>KHARTOUM: CAIRO Office, Sharia Kasr-el-Nil.</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT. Six days White Nile Tourist Trip dep. Khartoum
                        Tuesdays. Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at all Cairo Tourist
                        Agents. - Special Steamers for private charter. - Trips arranged and
                        transport of goods undertaken to all places on White and Blue Niles within
                        navigation limits.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT. Shipyard for construction of sternwheel steamers,
                        barges, stream, motor launches, etc. Contractors for supply and erection of
                        all classes of machinery, buildings, irrigation pumps, etc.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENTS FOR Dudbridges Oil Engines from 1 to 25 B.H.P. as supplied to
                        Sudan Government. Seamless xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mil01">
                    <head>Milner's Safes</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt</p>
                    <p>G. Marcus &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Large Stock Kept in</p>
                    <p>Alexandria<lb/>Rue Constantinople Maison A. N. Abet</p>
                    <p>Cairo<lb/> Hoss Issa rue Neuve</p>
                    <p>Tanta<lb/>Sharia El Alail.</p>
                    <p>17 11-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                    <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                    <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                    <p>7-8-90</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah02">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria.)</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Patronized by the Elite.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber
                        Station.</p>
                    <p>21440-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cgg01">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>NICOLA G. SABBAG</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, 2, Rue de la Gare du Caire</p>
                    <p>Telephone; No. 559.</p>
                    <p>24528-15-3-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hbc01">
                    <head>HOTEL BRISTOL. CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Full South, Electric Light, opposite Esbekieh Gardens, Large Verandahs,
                        Moderate Charges,</p>
                    <p>CHAS. BAUER, Proprietor.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel is beautifully fitted up and is in the most central part of Cairo.
                        Terms for pension fare at the rate of ten shillings a day. Special terms for
                        officers of Army of Occupation. 24,882-31-10-5</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hdi02">
                    <head>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper</head>
                    <p>Made in 70 Colors</p>
                    <p>An artistic wall covering.</p>
                    <p>This celebrated water paint is made in two qualities for Inside and Outside
                        work</p>
                    <p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
                        tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only
                        requires the addition of water to make it ready for use. It is quickly and
                        easily applied with a whitewash brush, with half the labour and at one third
                        the cost of paint. HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing to
                        the eye. It appeals alike to artistic and practical house decoration.</p>
                    <p>HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special value in hot climates. Owing to its cool,
                        pleasing colours, great weather-resisting and germ-destroying properties, it
                        lends itself to every kind of wall, wood, brick or stone coating, possessing
                        all the advantages of paint, colour- wash, and disinfectant at one third the
                        cost of oil paint. It never blisters in the hottest sun, and the fact that
                        it can be washed adds greatly to its sanitary advantages.</p>
                    <p>Supplied in Tins and Iron Kegs.</p>
                    <p>Sole Manufacturers :</p>
                    <p>SISSONS BROTHERS &amp; CO., LTD., HULL.</p>
                    <p>Stocks are held In Cairo by Frank Ratcliffe, Sanitary Contractor and
                        Engineer, Sharia Saptieh.</p>
                    <p>In Alexandria by Ramadan Youssef, Sanitary Contractor, Rue Sesostris.</p>
                    <p>General Agents: George Morris &amp; Co.. Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun01">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>A great economiser and saver of time, health, and strength.</p>
                    <p>Laundry worries went out of woman's life when Sunlight Soap came into it.</p>
                    <p>It is the purest Soap going.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun02">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>WORK WELL DONE . . GIVES TIME FOR PLAY.</p>
                    <p>Hard work is not easy unless you use Sunlight Soap.</p>
                    <p>It shortens the wash-day and brings comfort.</p>
                    <p>It has the Largest Sale in the World.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-gwy01">
                    <head>GWYNNES, Limited.</head>
                    <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                    <p>Telegrams--GWYNNE, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Telephone--544 BANK</p>
                    <p>Codes-- ABC, 4th and 5th Editions, A1.</p>
                    <p>MORNING &amp; NEAL'S.</p>
                    <p>Trade Mark — “INVINCIBLE."</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
                        In the world, suitable fcr all purposes, including RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE,
                        IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL
                        MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                    <p>These Pumps can be driven by Steam, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other
                        power, for Lifts of from 1 ft. to 500ft., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a
                        Minute. Makers of the Mex Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Results Guaranteed.</p>
                    <p>Over 50 Years' Practical Experience.</p>
                    <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet
                        Egyptian requirements.</p>
                    <p>London Offices— 81, Cannon Street, London, E.C.</p>
                    <p>The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd: Rue de la Gare du Caire,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Works- Hammersmith, London, W</p>
                    <p>23362-11-12-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-rea01">
                    <head>ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>Incorporated A. D. 1720.</p>
                    <p>Chief Office: ROYAL EXCHANGE, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>FUNDS IN HAND EXCEED £4,500,000 CLAIMS PAID £40,000,000</p>
                    <table rows="2" cols="2">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>FIRE</cell>
                            <cell>MARINE</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</cell>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>CAIRO … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                            <cell>SUEZ … Mr. GEO. MEINECKE.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>21281-216905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-lea01">
                    <head>Lea and Perrins' Sauce.</head>
                    <p>By Royal Warrant to His Majesty the King.</p>
                    <p>The original and genuine Worchestershire.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. WEDNESDAY. JUNE 28. 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY'S REPLY.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COUCHED IN FRIENDLY TONE</head>
                    <p>Paris, June 27 Prince Radohm presented Germany's reply to the French note of
                        the 22nd inst. It is understood that it insists upon the necessity a
                        Congress and considers a previous discus sion as to its scope unnecessary,
                        but the gene ral tenour is so amicable that it appears to facilitate the
                        granting of the purely formal consessions to which Germany appears attach
                        value. It makes it difficult for France to refuse a Conference, especially
                        as her excep- tional position on the Moroccan frontier is fully
                        acknowledged. The prohibition of tho importation of muni- tions, which has
                        already placed the Sultans force at Ujida in a most critical position, has
                        been withdrawn. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Paws, June i M. Rouvier has received Germany’s reply which persists in
                        demanding a conference with- out any previous understanding. The reply is
                        couched in a friendly spirit, which will facilitate the granting by France
                        of purely formal con- cessions. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 9.30 p.m.
                        to-day. !</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Moilki Saidna Hussein was celebrat ed last night in the quarter of Cairo
                        that bears the name of the nephew of the Prophet</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Prize Distribution —M. Buusquol, French Consul at Cairo, will prosido over
                        the dis tribution of prizes to the pupils of the Ecole Jeanne d’Arc Fagalla
                        at 5pm this (Wednesday) afternoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TROUBLES IN WARSAW. EXODUS OF JEWS.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Warsaw, June 27. The soldiers have stormed and destroyed six barricades.
                        There are 10 wounded in other conflicts with Cossack patrols. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lodz, June 27. The repetition of the massacre has been pievented by an
                        overwhelming military force and heavy rain 20000 Jews have quitted the town
                        (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 27. A Ukase invests tho Governor General of Warsaw with
                        supremo military powers, which General Trepoff is proceeding to Warsaw to
                        exercise on his behalf. There have been 672 arrests, mostly Jews, and the
                        prisons are full. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH AMNESTY</head>
                    <p>Paris, June 27. The French Government has introduced a bill granting amnesty
                        to M Deruulede and his . exiles, and also covering offences relating to
                        strikes. the press, and the informing scandals (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN SOUTH WEST AFRICA</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OFFICIAL REPORT ON FIGHTING</head>
                    <p>Berlin, June 27. The German official despatches show that desperate fighting
                        lasted 14 hours, but that finally Marengo s position was captured They deny
                        the capture of Warmbad ( Neuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found between the Pont des Anglais and the Ghizeh
                        Mou- dirieh during the nights of Thursday and Friday and at dawn on Friday
                        and Saturday, will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Zeitoun.— We hear that the Ministry of Public Works proposes to undertake the
                        con- struction of metalled roads at Zeitoun in the autumn. The construction
                        of a new railway station will also be commenced.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A Jailbird.— Shamroukh Meloka, brother of tho notorious Androus, has just
                        been released from prison, where he has passed 6 years. He has been sent to
                        the El Dorr Markas, where he will remain under observation by the
                        police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DISTRIBUTION OF PRIZES.</head>
                    <p>The prize distribution to the cadets of the Military School, Cairo, took
                        place at 8 o'olock this in morning before a large gathering of officers.
                        Amongst those present we noticed Kaimakam Herbert Bey, A.A.G., Kaimakam
                        Anderson Bey, Director of Stores, Bimbashi Carey, officer commanding 16th
                        Battalion, Miralai Zaky Bey, A.A.G., Miralai Tewfik Bey, Kaimakam Sabri Bey.
                        D.A.A.G., the whole staff of the school, , and a large number of junior
                        officers. Mr. Biyau, senior master, read his report on the indoor work of
                        the school, with the results of the recent examinations, and this was
                        follow- ed by Mr. Plunkett's report on the outdoor work, football, athletic
                        sports, etc., after which Miralai Matchett Bey distributed the prizes. In
                        making his address to the cadets Matchett Beyy expressed his great regret
                        that neither the Minister of War nor H.B. the Sirdar were able to attend,
                        but this was made impossible by the time of the year at which the distribu-
                        tion was held. I The proceedings were then brought to a con- clusion by tho
                        cadets giving three times the "Eftendimez Chok Yasha." A fuller account of
                        the ceremony, with a list of the prizes and commissions, will be publish- ed
                        i. o n issue of tomorrow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>
                    <p>Tho Legislative Council will meet to-morrow. The Prosident will present
                        Ibrahim Effendi Abd-el-AL the new delegate of the Fayoum province, to the
                        members of the Council. The Council will examine the question of forming the
                        Armenian Catholics of Egypt into a 'Community "</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Gardner Brown Bioscope and Va riety Company have arrived at Alexandria
                        from Malta and will give three performances at the Garrison Theatre,
                        Mustupha, commenc- ing tomorrow evening, before proceeding to Cairo</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Victoria House and Nurses Home.- Miss Waeber, the matron, has gone to Europe
                        on three months' furlough, and her place will be taken by Miss Harbord. The
                        registry office will be closed during Miss Waebers absence and will be
                        opened again on 1st October.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Suez Canal.— 19 vessels passed through the Canal on the 24th and 25th inst,
                        of which 10 were British, 5 German, 1 American, 1 Turkish, 1 Italian, 1
                        French. The receipts for the two days were frs. 526,503, making the total
                        from the 1st inst. frs. 6.962,326.62.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Um Rush. The Committee of the London Stock Exchange have fixed Wednesday,
                        July 19, as a special settling day in Um Rus Gold Mines of Egypt, Limited -
                        Further issue of 30,000 shares of 1 each, 10s paid (Nos. 150,001 to
                        180,000)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWEDEN AND NORWAY</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NAVAL AND MILITARY MEASURES</head>
                    <p>Christiania. June 27. Sweden is adopting certain naval and military measures
                        which are creating a dis agreeable impression here, although it is ex-
                        plained that they are purely precautional. It is generally believed that
                        notwithstanding the aggressive language of the Swedish Conserva tives, the
                        disunion will be peacefully arranged. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>"Avon" Stabbing Cadr —The trial of John Raghy, cook of the S.S. "Avon," on
                        the charge of stabbing the steward of the ship, J. E. Garnham, under
                        circumstances already related in our columns, will take place at H.B.M. s
                        Consular Court, Alexandria, on Saturday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Plague. — Yesterday’ss bulletin records a fatal case at Alexandria, the
                        victim being a native who worked in a cafe near Mohamed Aly square, and who
                        was found dead at his house. Three new cases and two deaths are reported
                        trom Damanbour, and one case from Toukh district.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Pigmies seem to be in rather an awk ward position. They have beheld many
                        won ders and miracles, says the "Express," but of these they must remain
                        silent when they return home, or they will certainly be burned to death as
                        being possessed of devils. This will be a blow to publishers in the Ituri
                        Forest</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET</head>
                    <p>London, June 27. Worcestershire beat Leicestershire by an innings and 207
                        runs. M.C.C. beat Cambridge University by 4 wickets. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Cotton Worm.— The School of Agri culture has placed the services of two
                        of their instructors, Mr. W. Cartwright and Mr. G Bonaparte, at the disposal
                        of the Ministry of the Interior for cotton-worm duty, and these two
                        gentleman hare accordingly been posted to the Mudiriehs of Ghizeh and
                        Behera, res pectively</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>AFal-kAlarm — Androns Meloka's exploits appear to hav^. had their effect in
                        putting travellers by train very much on the ywi rive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONCESSION BY THE PORTE.</head>
                    <p>We learn from Constantinople that after two years' efforts on the part of the
                        British Embassy, the Porte has finally agreed to grant the same privilege —
                        namely, exemption of Customs duty on coal—to the ships of the Khedivial Mail
                        Company as that enjoyed by the other foreign mail steamers. The Porte's
                        objection as regards the Khedivial Mail Com pany has been that their vessels
                        ply between Ottoman ports, and, therefore, do not come under the same
                        category as the other foreign companies, whose ports of origin are in
                        foreign countries As a matter of fact, however, tho Turkish Government has
                        never been able to forgive the Khedivial Company for transferring its ships
                        to the British flag, hence all the trouble over this and other
                        facilities.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DREDGERS PROPOSED FOR WHITE NILE.</head>
                    <p>The Council of Ministers has approved the proportion of the Ministry of
                        Public Works that Mr. Dapuis, Inspector General of Irriga tion in the Sudan,
                        should be sent on a mission to the United States and Canada and, if pos
                        sible, should also visit Holland and Germany, in order to examine on the
                        spot the different types of dredgers which are in use in those countries,
                        and which are of the most advanced form and of great working capacity. Mr.
                        Dupuis will spend some two months in examining this question, and will
                        present his report on the results of his inspection immediately after his
                        return to this country. It is considered that these dredgers are necessary
                        tor ameliorating the condition of the White Nile for the purpose of
                        increasing the supply of water in Egypt</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRICE OF LAND AT GHEZIREH</head>
                    <p>In reference to the great rise within the past year or so in the price of
                        land for building purposes near Cairo, in localities that have of late
                        greatly appreciated in public estimation, we may instance that in the
                        neighbourhood of Ghezireh Palace Hotel. No plots heeo can now be had under
                        P.T 3on per square metre. The sites belonging to the Ghezireh Land Company,
                        which purchased three years ago some 81 feddaus in this locality, are
                        selling at from P.T. 62 to P.T. 156 per square metre, the latter price being
                        asked for the more attractive lots bordering on the Nile. The land was
                        divid- ed into 133 lots, of which 65 have already been disposed of. To the
                        south of the above property the War Office owns a small one, whilst between
                        the latter property and the public gardens, in which is situated the grotto,
                        the lands belong to the Government, one side of these lace the road running
                        parallel with the Nile branch or canal, and the other the Ghezireh Palace
                        property, which is also being rapidly built over.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE YEMEN CAMPAIGN.</head>
                    <p>Renter's Agency states that the reinforce- ments for the Yemen have also
                        arrived at Hodeida with the exception of the Malaria Red if (Reserve)
                        Brigade and will, according to the latest advices,ad vance on SanAt by
                        Menakha, while the other will move by Tais. The Otto man authorities wish to
                        recapture Sanaa, lbb,- and the other towns in the possession of the Imam’s
                        forces before treating with the rebels. It may be presumed that their real
                        aim is the complete destruction of the insurgent forces, after which
                        pourparlers will be greatly simplified. Another telegram states that the
                        insurgents are on the march to Mecca and that Faizi Pasha, who has arrived
                        at Hodeida, declares that it is absolutely impossible to stop their advance.
                        It this statement is reliable it point# to an extension of the revolt from
                        the Yemen province to the Azir district, which is inhabit ed by the Beni
                        Kahtan, Beni Thakif, and Beni Otaiba Bedouins. Tais, from which one of the
                        Turkish co- lumns is to start, is close to the frontier of the Aden
                        protectorate and about 70 miles from the coast Menakha, which it about the
                        same distance from Hodeida, is only 40 miles from Sanaa, but an army
                        advancing to the recapture of the headquarters of the Vllth Army Corps will
                        be obliged to fight its way across a formidable mountain range whose highest
                        peaks are over 7,000 feet above sea level.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>1SMAILIA.</head>
                    <p>Last year, with the view of encouraging owners of vessels, after discharging
                        coal at Port Raid, to load at Ismailia, and to prevent, if possible, the
                        complete decadence of the latter town, which is practically owned by the
                        Baez Canal Company, the latter adopted a very wise measure to try and
                        counteract the injury to the place brought about by the opening of the new
                        through line from Cairo to Port Baud The measure was that such vessels
                        should pay only the very reduced tax of 2 frs. 60 c. per registered ton for
                        the double journey from Port Said to Ismailia and back, instead of the usual
                        rate of 4 francs each way, the through rate from end to end, i.e., From Port
                        Said to Suez, or vice versa, being now 2 Ir 5o c. per ton. The advantage to
                        exporters from the districts near, like Zagazig, Tantah, and even Benha, was
                        great, since ship- pers from Ismalia economise the heavy railway freigbt
                        from the latter station to Port Said, which is more than the very moderate
                        charge ot 2 fr. 60c. fixed by the Canal Company. The company furthermore
                        proposed,should the experiment prove remunerative, to construct moles and
                        jetties for the accommodation of vessels, and do all it could to facilitate
                        loading operations. From what we hear, it does not seem that the result so
                        far has come up to expectations, and the town appears to be languishing for
                        want of some enterprise that will stimulate its gradually dying trade, which
                        was however never of much account The decision taken two years back by the
                        P. and O. and other large com panies to embark and disembark their local
                        passengers at Port Said instead of Ismailia, as formerly, was another nail
                        in the latter's coffin, for we hear that tho management of Shepheard's
                        Hotel, who rented formerly the Hotel Victoria at Ismailia from Mr. Marini,
                        the proprietor, has decided not to renew the lease of ten years which has
                        just expired.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>It now appears that Mohamed el Maghazi, who boarded a first class carriage
                        near Maghagba aud was seized by tbs occupant*, was after 1 all an employe of
                        the 8urvsy Department who 1 jumped on to a moving train without a ticket, 1
                        and climbed into the first carriage that pro- ' seated itself.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TRUTH ABOUT FASHODA.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CURIOUS REVELATIONS BY</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COLONEL MARCHAND</head>
                    <p>Colonel Marc recently contributed to the "Matin" an important and most
                        interesting account of the origin of the Fashoda expedi- tion. It was on
                        Nov. 16, 1895, that M. Ber- thelot, Minister of Foreign Affairs, signed and
                        approved of his plan for French intervention in the Bahr el-Ghazal and on
                        the Nila The scheme, however, lay dormant until the follow- ing spring, when
                        the Sudan expedition was announced by England. The attitude of the French
                        Government changed immediately. M. Guioysso, the Minister of tho Colonies,
                        im- plored the writer to start as soon as possible, and if he had obeyed he
                        would have left within forty eight hours, vompletely unpre- pared for a
                        journey over 10,000 kilometres of country. M. Barthelot, who bad so for-
                        gotton himself as to) tell Lord Salisbury that he declined all
                        responsibility for the consequences to which the Sudan expedi- tion might
                        lead, quitted the Quai d'Orsay a few days after he had used such peculiar
                        language, and as M. Leon Bourgeois, the Pre- sident of the Council, could
                        not find anyone to succeed him he took his place. About the first thing that
                        M. Bourgeois did was to send for Colonel Marchand, preparations for whose
                        journey were then hurried on. This was in March, 1896, and a few weeks later
                        the Bourgeois Ministry fell, and was replaced by the Meline Cabinet, with M.
                        Hanotaux at the Ministry of Foreign A Hairs. M. Andrfi Lebon, the new
                        Minister of the Colonic-, was not so generous in the matter of resources as
                        M. Bourgeois would have been, but the writer was again enjoined to start as
                        soon as he could. The first convoy sailed from Bordeaux on April 25, the
                        others being transported in the steamers that followed. Colonel Marchand
                        himself left Marseilles on June 25, 1896, at which date the troops which
                        were to accom- pany him across Africa for the occupation of Fashoda, if they
                        arrived there before the British army, were completing their movement from
                        Timbuctoo on Dakar and on Libreville, in the French Congo. The writer says
                        that his officers and his own companions in the expedi- tion were not aware
                        of its destination until eighteen months afterwards, when they were in the
                        very heart of Central Africa. It has often been affirmed that M. Delcasse
                        had something to do with the organisation of the Fashoda expedition. Colonel
                        Marchand, how- ever, terminates his instructive explanation with the
                        following emphatic words which close "M. Deloasec, whom I hardly knew, and
                        who from February, 1895, to July, 1898, had no share in the Government-the
                        very reverse, indeed, was the case—had nothing, absolutely nothing, to do
                        with the consideration, the pre paration, and the execution of an expedition
                        of which he only became informed to pot an end to it in October, 1898. All
                        that has been said contrary to this affirmation, which 1 make on my honor,
                        and which is based on history itself, which can easily be examined, is only
                        e tale, which 1 wish now to demolish with one blow, as 1 think that the time
                        has come for me to do so." Thus does Colonel Marchand dispose of one of the
                        charges brought against the late Minister of Foreign Affairs, which was to
                        the effect that, although be had been an active promoter of the Fashoda
                        expedition, he deserted Colonel Marchand when England adopted a resolute
                        attitude. Colonel Marchand's explanation has created quite a sensation in
                        political circles.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ATTEMPTED MURDER IN A THEATRE.</head>
                    <p>During a performance at Minieh of an Arabic drama bearing the thrilling title
                        of Love and Revenge, by Sheikh Salema Hegazi and his company, a dentist
                        suddenly rose from bis seat and rushed upon one of the occupants of a box
                        with drawn dagger. The victim of the dentist's onslaught shouted for help,
                        and the police, aided by the cooler-headed spectators, disarmed and arrested
                        his assailant. An Arabic contemporary states that the dentist, whom we will
                        call Mr. X, had been very intimate with Y, the individual whom be attempted
                        to stab. The two lived in the same house, and X eventually was trustful
                        enough to leave his wife in Y’s charge while paying a visit to his old borne
                        in Syria. The dentist returned in due course and found neither his wife nor
                        the furniture. The ingenious Y had informed X's father and mother in- law
                        that he had fled the country owing to debts caused by the extravagance of
                        his wife. They promptly sold the furniture and took B their daughter away
                        with them. Y then brought in other lodgers, whom he considered more
                        profitable acquaintances than the luckless X. whose resentment at the brutal
                        practical joke played upon him was, no doubt, too violently expressed, but
                        can easily be unders- tood.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Le paqnebot "Equatenr," des Messageriea Maritime* arrive do Marseille le 27
                        join avail hbotd: M. et Mmo Buhl. M. et Mme Hadji*, M. et Mme Call, M. I.
                        Bialobo, Mme Sehraber. M. Boudon, M. I. A. 8. Watt, Sergent Lidell, M. S.
                        Tahemy, M. Norman, M. Alex. Tarabotti. M. Le Hoax, M. Benoit, M. Debbat,
                        Rev. A. H. Manning, M.Aim6 Boudamar, Dr A. D, Louliaa, M. et Mme Jos.
                        Conloossi, M.Ceysen*. M. Clogstom et 11 passagers de 3me et 4me clase. Per
                        Moss 8 3. "Seti" arrived yesterday from Liverpool, Gibraltar, Algiers, and
                        Malta : — Mr. and Mrs Altohedijan, 4 children and none, Capt Powell, Mr.
                        Aquilina, Mr. Bubs- giar, Mr. Cafiro, Mr. and Mr*. Gardner Brown, Mr. G.
                        Gulliver, Mr. Leo Montegue, Mr. end Mr*. Moriaaoni, Mis* A B. Romeino, and
                        11 deck passengers</p>
                </div></div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord Edward Cecil Pasha, D.8.O., is expect ed to arrive et Cairo next
                        Wednesday on the completion of his leave.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. H. Boyle will leave for England early in July</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Capt. McMurdo, head of the Slave Trade Department, is expected to arrive in
                        Cairo from his inspecting tour up the White Nile on friday next.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The death is announced of Doctor Roger, former medical surgeon attached to
                        the French Ethiopian Railways, and chief medical officer who accompanied the
                        Rothschild Mission across Abyssinia and Uganda.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Major R N. Gamble, D.S.O., 2nd Battalion R. Berkshire Regiment, has been
                        granted leave of absence for three months.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. C. Aquilina, proprietor of the Carlton Hotel, Bulkeley, has returned to
                        Alexandria from Malta.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice Pastor
                        Kahle, Dr. end Mme. Wild. Mr. Saint Port Mortier, Mr. Cameo. Mr. Vincent, M
                        and Mme. Doom moot, Mahmoud Bey Saddik, Mr. A. Kings Brothers. Mr. T. A.
                        Sean, Major Persse Bey, Major Matthews, Capt. Rome, Capt C. Ehyall, Orphi
                        Bey, Gibson Pasha, Capt Adams, Mr. and Mr*. 8. Heath, Mr. and A Sou, Mr. T.
                        A. W. Peacock, Dr. and Mr*. Hayward, Dr. and Mr*. Wilson.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesCyprus">
                    <head>NOTES FROM CYPRUS</head>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUMMER SEASON COMMENCES.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Nicosia, June 22.</dateline><p> Several storm* have been
                            reported daring the last few day* as having occnrred in various parts of
                            the Island. Yesterday it was learnt that a portion of the road leading
                            to Mt Troo- dos had been rendered impassable to traffic owing to debris
                            that had been washed down by heavy rains. Unfortunately this road will
                            have to be much used this week, in consequence of the departure today of
                            his Excellency and the Secretariat for the summer quartan on Troodos.
                            The summer season may now be said to bare commenced, and will probably
                            continue, as usual until about the second week ot October, when, as a
                            rule, the Government returns to Nicosia. The heat in the plains has.
                            been so far much lass severe than usual -. nevertheless most officials
                            will welcome the change to higher altitudes, lie battalion of the King’s
                            Royal Rifles has already arrived at Troodos from Polemedia Camp.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GREEK SCHOOL COMMITTEE.</head>
                        <p>This week was held the first election, under the new Education Law, of
                            the Creak School Committee for Nicosia. As a good deal of party feeling
                            exists in the Island owing to the divisions censed by the vexed
                            Archiepiscopel question, which still remains open, this new opportunity
                            for a party display caused con- siderable excitement, and it is not yet
                            general- ly known which party was successful at the</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A MOSLEM CEREMONY.</head>
                        <p>The ceremony of inaugurating the newly-built minaret of the Eomerie
                            Mosque in Nicosia took place yesterday in the presence of his Excellency
                            and Indy King Ham an and several officials. The function was largely
                            attended by the Moslem community.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BNCOURAGING PLORICULTURK</head>
                        <p>A public garden has been laid out at Limas sol this winter. This was a
                            pet scheme of the late High Commissioner, Sir William p. Haynes-Smith,
                            and is likely to add largely to the attraction* of that town. . It it
                            gradually getting planted, and in course of time should provide a
                            pleasant lounge for the residents. The Government Nursery Garden adjoins
                            it, where a number of plants are raised and can easily be transplanted.
                            There is also a Govern- ment Nursery Garden at Larnaca, and both a
                            nursery end an experimental garden at Nico- sia. Forest end trait trees
                            in large nursery are raised in these gardens, as well u many flowering
                            plants and shrub*, palms, etc., in pots, which are sold to the public at
                            very low cost. Grafts and buds are also obtain- able, and it is the
                            object of the Govern- ment by this means to encourage tree planting and
                            the cultivation of good kinds of fruit Similar gardens are doing useful
                            work in other part* of the Island, bat there is room for an extension in
                            this direction. It is hoped that before long they will be used for the
                            practical purpose of demonstrating various methods of cultivation.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="page" n="4">
                    <head>TH* WmUJ OlMWl; WEDICESBAT, JBNB 23,. 1*06.</head>
                    <p>O.N’-THB IIKDJAZ R VILWAY. South of Denia, the cultivation rapidly ceased,
                        and for two or three hours wo ra-> through oountry that bore the greatest
                        like nos to the Marioat steppe at the end o' April. There was the same burnt
                        grass and grey boulders, but if the ground was les stony on the data it was
                        far more rocky o the slopes of the low hills which we passed from time to
                        time. On the west the hill cou:: try of Edom was marked by low rounded
                        summits. Eastward stretched immonso open plains that gavo the same
                        impression of spa ciousness as the Arabian desert soon from the Canal near
                        el Kantara or from tho railway at Zeitoun. The foreground was yellow brown,
                        relieved by t>c visional grey patches anj dotted with the dark green desert
                        scrub, tho background was an almost uniform fawa co- lour which deepened to
                        a dull red wheu the sun began to set. As far as natural feature*,
                        inhabitants, or cultivation went this section of tho lino was a ‘perfect and
                        absolute blank.' There were hills, it is true, but their Ion» glacis and
                        rounded summits doprived them of any pfeturesqueoess.</p>
                    <p>There wore no Bedouins, goats or camels to bo scon and the only men we passed
                        were the littlo groups ot soldier railwayman at two or three stations where
                        the eugino nn 1 the passengers took in water for a few m: notes. On this
                        sefition, too, tho rails were worn and the train left each of these stations
                        with a horrid jerk. Some of the passengers were always on their feet
                        whenever this oc curred and were always thing violently into tho laps of
                        their vis-kvis by tho sudl>n shock, to the groat contentment of all llioir
                        fellows.</p>
                    <p>At night fell wo began to enter close, brokon oountry, full of low stoay
                        hills covered with boulders and withered grass, and aoimod by dry wadis near
                        which tho vegetation was still fairly fresh. The comments of a London daily
                        on the good that the Hodja* line will do by "opening np ths country to
                        trade" recurred to me just then and I felt that the writer of the article I
                        had >n mind oonld nover have seen this part of the world, which looked
                        incapable of supporting any indnstry but the raising of an inferior breed of
                        goats. There were pockets among these low hills where I expected to see
                        signs of a rain crop, but either the soil was bad or the Bedouins did not
                        tronblo to sow barley a* thoir cousins do in the Marioat district. At about
                        7 p.m. 1 opened a tin of meat, which, by the way, disagreed with me
                        mightily, and was rather annoyed at the in- tense cariosity shown by the
                        occupants of the carriage, who believed—so 1 afterwards learnt from the
                        guard,—that 1 was eating pork. After all I bad no reason for my annoyance.
                        Do not snme Englishmen wbo have, not left their island still hold that the
                        Frenchman subsists on salads, frogs, and snails, and does not the
                        nntravelled Haul ascribe an unchanging diet of "pellel" and "biftock" to the
                        carnivorous Saxon ? Still 1 felt inclined to make a diversion and having a
                        big of lemons and some soda water 1 stood lemon squash to the occupants of
                        my end of the carriage, who seemed highly satisfied therewith and always
                        thanked me most po'itely. After my meal I tried to sleep ou my boards and a
                        conch made of a greatcoat and a rug but the carriage required a thorough
                        disiDfeotion and insect powders were poworlres, all the wingless and
                        irritant species being well ropre anted. Near 'Arnnjn 1 fell off the board
                        and rema'ued awake and angry till we ran into the station.</p>
                    <p>AmmAn (Rabb.ath Ammon) is a garrison to sin. Turkish soldiers and Circassian
                        colonists are posted there, and there is a small popula- tion of fellaheen
                        and settled Be lonins with a few Italian workmen and a handful o' Syrians.
                        The great R imsn cistern is the fe stare of the place—I mcstreto theourious
                        to Biedeker for its measurements and history—the town itkplf be:hg simply a
                        colleitioa of tents and dirty hovels. Prom a military pnint of view the town
                        is of some importance. Corn is grown on the mountains bard by ; there is
                        pemanent Water in the heads of the Zirka which rise iu the 'AmmAn hills, and
                        the garrison both 1 defends that section of the line where damage 1 Would bo
                        hardest to repair and watches the 1 Bedouins who roam about the edge of the
                        1 desert and who, till lately, blackmailed the 1 fellaheen, killed stray
                        Turks, and arranged 1 attacks ou terrific 1 tourists with the aid of 1 the
                        venal dragoman. The arrival of the Circas- 1 sians has changed all this,
                        though I gather 1 that the Tcherkeia can be a more expert and 1 redoubtable
                        highwayman than the most piotu- 1 the air by way of impressing him with his
                        ] prowess before asking him to stand and dolivet. I 1 walked about ths Amman
                        station and the | steep bill above it for some time, bat the grouud was full
                        of holes, and the attentions 1 received from the dogs of the placo were so I
                        persistent that I returned to tho oarriage and 1 triod to sloop. After
                        various misadventures ,1 suoceoied, only to be awakonod by tho terrific
                        shock with which wo started, and the lamenta- tions of a soldier who had
                        broken a window in trying to shut it and was being reviled by tho guard. Wo
                        were far less crowded on this part of the journey—Hamdulillah I —so that,
                        the atmosphere produced by the closing of all the unbroken windows and tho
                        nse of quantities of tobacco was jost boarablo. 1 awoke ot about 3 am.
                        feeling very aoro and unhappy and found the train running tbrongh a steppe
                        which was a littlo yellowor bat otherwise an exact replica of the oountry
                        whioh wo had paasod between Dents and Amman. At about 6 a.m. we passed a
                        caravan (lying two Osmanli flags marching along a sort of cart-track to
                        Katraneh. A few tatterdemalion.! with rifles redo ahead on mules, then came
                        in single file 8 camels carrying women and bales, a cart carry- ing packed
                        tents and projecting tent polos, some women and children and a soldier
                        riding slowly on a bay Arab. From the camels to the children ovary member of
                        the caravan seemed to be walking in his sleep. Tho soldier and the
                        nondescripts on males waved to ns,and thou relapsed into an apathetic
                        progress, and it was only when I got out on the tail board of tho Cirri age
                        and felt the wind and saw how tho women were huddling their clothes round
                        their bodios, that 1 realise! that they wore all numb- ed with the oold of
                        the desort morniug. (To be continued).</p>
                    <p>SCI)AN CAMPAIGNING. BENNETT BURLEIGH REMINISCENT. The veteran War
                        Correspondent Mr. Ben- nett Burleigh writes to the "Daily Telegraph" on the
                        subject of rifle shooting "I have seen most of the fighting in Egypt and tho
                        Sudan between the years 1882 and 1898. Indifferent as was the shooting of
                        onr soldiers in those days, it was their great supe- riority in marksmanship
                        overtbatof the enemy that won ns so many victories withbutahandful of
                        troops. We ought to have been eaten np or drivon into the sea more than
                        onoe, say as at El Magfar, Hassassip, and Tamai. The Marine*, by their
                        steady fire discipline, had much to do with saving the situation at all
                        three of these actions ; and at the surprise at Hassassin lock, the 60th
                        Rifles, who deployed to the front at the ‘ double’’ out ol camp, instantly
                        checked the further advance of Arabi Pasha’s horse and foot. They were
                        pounded with Krupp cannon- shells, but the riflemen never budged, except to
                        creep nearer to the foe. Wheu the machine- guns were temporarily lost at
                        Tamai, Genera' Sir Gerald Graham ro formed Davis's broken brigade, uot in
                        square but in line, and order- ed them forward to recover the groond and the
                        battery. That day, at Colonel Tuson’s (of the Marines,! request, 1 acted for
                        the nonoe as gal- loper. Firing steadily as they advanced, stage by stage,
                        the Dervish Fcny-Wuizy, who is the finest fighting-man the world over after
                        his methods, was slain in heaps, and driven from the guns across the nullah,
                        or khon. It is the lead rather than the steel that piles np the butcher's
                        bill in ail modern wars. If the Der- vishes had pat more trust in their
                        Remington rifles, what a different story there wonld have boon to tell of
                        £udan warfare ! la their, famous charge at Omddrmtn, the 21st Lanoers
                        inflicted relatively little hurt upon the enomy, until, Wheeling to the
                        left, they dismounted and opened fire with their carbines. It was then that
                        the Dervishes decamped out of the nnllah. Our casualties at Abu Kra came
                        from tho good shooting of a few of the Mahdi's black Kordofan hunters.
                        General Stewart, 8t. L*g*r, Cameron, and others being killed by the Dervish
                        fi-e, which came pelting at times like hail amongst ns. I was hit in the
                        neck, and it was only by poshing forward and oocnpying a knoll, from which
                        we oonld get at these deadly marksmen, that farther loss was avert- ed and
                        the situation saved. We had with ns not a few excellent rifle-shots,
                        including ser- geants in the Berkshire and other regiments who ware in the m
                        mated infantry and camel corps contingents. I recollect many an oocaiion
                        when *e used to creep oat, and, at ranges from 900 to 1,30.) yards, break np
                        the oonstant attempts made by the Dervishes to drill their CORPORATtSPOF
                        WE8TBBN</p>
                    <p>EGYPT, LTD. ( From "A1 Mokattam." ) Much interest hits bhen eXoited by the
                        Ou- psny of the Oases. We have rooeiitly met an Egyptian engineer whb has
                        resided nearly SO’ years in Australia and was. engaged‘m gold digging and
                        other mining in that oOuntry. He has sinoe been seat by gold'mining
                        companies to Um Rns and elsewhere to superintend Egyptian miners and teach
                        them their srortr in those mines and has been sent by the Oases Company into
                        the oases to prospect for mine1 rals there and remained there three months
                        till he became fully acquainted with what was going on. His name it Shimi
                        Bat ran. We askod him what ho saw there, and he replied,1 "So far as search
                        for mines, which was an important part of my work^ is oonoorned, I saw many
                        traces of old workings which may some day be again profitable. I was down
                        147 fret in one old shaft ahd fotnid affjofti-' ing it, 100 yards asJa^i
                        traces of connect- ing workings, bat was' obliged to give up for the time
                        owing to the heat and sand after digging about 12 feet into it. "I found,
                        however, many andentalmn work- ings white and rose colour and all colours in
                        veins up to 18 incites thick. I marked the various beds by flags. I found a
                        bod of (coal) lignite at about 16 to 20 foot deep, 3 to 6 inches thick, and
                        1 sunk below it to 85 feet hopiog for another vein, and I am of opinion that
                        it Is absolutely necessary to make farther search before anyone can fay
                        whether there is or is not plenty of coal there; also proper prospecting
                        should bo done for gold. Four or five prospectors should be sent ont through
                        all the oases, for there is certain to be plenty of valuablo minerals." We
                        asked him about the land, and he said the soil was liko that of Nile
                        Islands. He himself saw north of Um Dabadib a vast tract of land with tracos
                        of houses and trees showing that it had boon cultivated, and had no doubt
                        that if cnltivutod again it wonld be equal to any land in Egypt. "Also
                        ^heikb Mnstapha Hanadi, Omdeh of Khorgoh, told me that cotton would grow
                        there as well as in Egypt, and all the land, once water is brought to it,
                        produces as well as the best -land in Egypt, and thought the oases land jost
                        as the land in Egypt."</p>
                    <p>And we asked him whether there was water enough and he said that every proof
                        exists and every experiment that had been tried shows that there is plenty
                        of underground water. And the water rise* in artesian wells, and all the
                        cultivation is done by them. The oompany sank an artesian well between
                        Khargeh and the Deir, and another well in the Derr, and the water is flowing
                        from both day and night and the laud around is being cultivated. "I dug S’x
                        wells (ordinary) between Khargeh and the Deir and Mehriq and in moit of them
                        found sweet water, some at 4 metres and sOme at 6 metres. Each well c let
                        about 300 piastres to sink and the oases water is generally as sweet as the
                        Nile, in fact I think there is plenty of sweet svater in the oases, and an
                        enormous extent of land can be cultivated by boring iells."</p>
                    <p>We asked if there were many inhabitants in the oases. He answered, "They are
                        not many and they do not pay proper attention to their cultivation, being
                        lary and indolent. When I returned to the Nile Valley I met many people of
                        Upper Egypt who said they wished to go and take op lands in the oases if the
                        railway went there."</p>
                    <p>We asked about the railway, and be said : "All I know is that the company
                        means to make one and is going about it, and it is poiitively certain that
                        oine tho railway goes the oases will thrive and prosper exceedingly, but
                        without the railway their riches must : remain undeveloped. However that is
                        certain 1 to be done some time. (Communicated). 1</p>
                    <p>THB KING AND THE HOSPITALS. How A Ovv/A'tom OK THE 8mHK and Abscesses in Back
                        were Treated. (2 a Friend of the King's Hospital Fund). The interest of His
                        Majesty King Edward VH. in the Fund for the Hospitals is eXplfiin- ed bV His
                        Majesty’s sense of the noble servioo rendered tb'hU bumbler'subjects: Onoe
                        within the wards of a' Hospital Ml are equal. There, withbut fee, the
                        poorest sufferer receives tho aervioos of the very greatest surgeon* and
                        physicians in the' world. The King, when ho jwu1 operated1 ojloii for
                        Appendicitis in Corona tibn Year, had no greater skill and no different
                        jtteatmout than what is bestowed on any patient in our Hospitals.M</p>
                    <p>This fact' lends absorbing interest to the history ol a poor Scottish boy who
                        was recent- ly treated’ in the Glasgow Children’s Hospital. He had had
                        scarlet fever, and, as often hap- pens, thufterrible fever left
                        aftereffects. His spine'began to be deformed : it had curvature and there
                        were abscesses, for which he sras operated upon by the very ablest surgeons-
                        the same men who would have been called ill if one of the Eoyal Pamily had
                        suddenly needed operation while in Scotland.</p>
                    <p>But despite all thoir care little John Fraser (for that is his name, End his
                        parents live at 1 Maxwell-plaoe, Southside, Glasgow) did not get better. He
                        was painfully weak and thin, redoubtable highwayman than the moat piotu- m,n
                        in front 0! Metemoeh But one may be too resque Bo louin who ever cavortel
                        round a reminiioent of the Sudan, and even of the peaceful trader lilhiing
                        and firing shots in 1 hiroio oampaign." British Chamber orCoiaorecx—We would
                        rell the attention of persons interested in Egyptian txade to the work of
                        the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, whose office in Alexandria gives
                        information as to standings trade, Ac., to its members, and whose monthly
                        publication reviews onr commerce. The annual subscription is £1 and all
                        British traders should beoome members. Our London offioe, 86, New Broad-
                        street B.C., acts as London agenoy to "be Chan bar.</p>
                    <p>John Fraser in the Children's Hospital. and the doctors frankly said that
                        little oonld be done to dry up the fearful abscesses or reduce the lump on
                        his spine. He oould hardly eat, and only walkod with great difficulty. "If
                        you only knew what he suffered from the pain in his back," said his father,
                        "and how the abscesses seemed to be sapping the fife out of him, you srould
                        not wonder I am thankful to see him so well to-day. It is all due to Dr.
                        William*’ pink pills for pale people. He began to talte them lost Juno. From
                        the time he got through the contents of the first box, I observed a distinct
                        change for the better. Very soon his back began to heaL I first heard of
                        this Wonderful medicine through reading an adoount of one who had suffered
                        like my son, and had been speedily cored of spinal disease by these
                        pills."</p>
                    <p>"There’s my daughter Jeanie, too," added the mother, Mrs. Fraser. "After
                        having her touUrf removed she lost a qaaotity of blood, and became so weak
                        and thin that I grew alarmod. But I gave her Dr. Williams' pinlr pills, and
                        she soon began to male new blood. Before long she was as healthy and bright
                        a lassie as you wonld sfieanywhere."</p>
                    <p>Where the best medical skill the world can give has been used in vain, Dr.
                        Williams’ pink pills for pale people have, in the above and many other
                        cases, fluted. Till reason is that they make new blood. Thus they are the
                        greatest of all tonics, the readiest and safest mfldifline in the commoner,
                        as well as the severest, ailments. Mothers know why they find their
                        daughters need new blood more than men ; bat men oan be ena-mio, too. The
                        weak back, easy fatigue, lack of interest in life, indigestion and general
                        nervous weakness vfihich trouble both men and women, need new blood to oare
                        them, apd these pills make Hew blood. Vor many, Dr. Williams' pink [fills
                        have proved the turning point in develop- ment, changing weakly
                        constitutions, threaten- ed with detune and deafh to sound, over- rent,
                        changing weakly constitutions, threaten- ed with detune and deafh to sound,
                        over- flowing health, because they make new blood. 8old in Egypt by all
                        ohemiats at P.T. 13 per bbx or P.T. 70 per 6 boxes. Con be bought at the
                        genera! depfit: Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel du Nil 8t (1st ff for), and
                        Alexandria, Rue Stemboal, No 8.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Delta Ugbt Railways Ltd. D1VIDBND WARRANT No. 15 BEARER WARRANT
                        COUPON N-\ 12. An Interim Dividend at the rate of 2 % for tho half year
                        ended 31st Maroh 1905, (subject to Iaoome tax) on the Preference Share
                        Capital will be payable on and after the 23rd June' 1905, at the National
                        Bank cf Egypt, London dr Coho and’ Alexandria, at the current rate of
                        exchange. Registered Share Dividend Warrants will be po-txl on the 23rd
                        June. 26171-5-1 N OTIC E.</p>
                    <p>TUB GENERAL ADMINISTRATION OF THE WAKFS informs the publio that on the 1st
                        July, 1905, fron9 a-m. to 4 p.m., at ths Djlogation of the Alexandria Wakfs,
                        in Ruo ol Maukii, behind the Mcashieh police caraool, an aootion sale will
                        be-held of the following Qheits : 19 fed., 8 kit, 0 sab., forming a Gheit
                        si- tuated at El Mandara, known as Gheit el Asaafiri. 84 fed., 4 kir., 9$
                        sab., forming a Gheit si- tuated in the same place, known as Gheit el
                        Kariri. 8 fed., 16 kir., 4 sab., forming a Gheit si- tuated at Sidi Bishr,
                        known as Ghoit el Mehammara Total : 57 feddans, 4 kirats, 131 sahmes. Any
                        person wishing to bid for the above properties, either in whole or in port,
                        most attend at the Delegation on the day above- mentioned to obtain a cahier
                        des charges and make his offer. The deposit must not be less than 20 %. The
                        Administration does not bind itself to accept any offer, and in case of
                        refusal the bidder will only be entitled to the return of his deposit,
                        observing the clauses indicated in the cahier des charges. 26144-2X-2</p>
                    <p>Municipality d’Alexandrie a TT s La Municipality met en adjudication le
                        dallage des trois rues au quarrier Menayor. Le cautionnement est fixd k L.B.
                        65. Le oahier des charges est dfipoed au Bureau de la Voirie oh il pent
                        fltre consults par les interessda tons les jours de 9 h. k midi, loa jours
                        toils exoeptls. Les offres devront fit re odressfios sous pli eaohetl i
                        Monsieur l'Administratenr de la Municipality avant le 11 juillet 1905. Biles
                        pourront figalonrent fltre dlposles en ilanoo de laDfilfigation le mfime
                        jour i 5h.pjn. L’eaveloppe'devra porter en outre la men- tion : "Soamission
                        pour Dallage de trois rues aa qnartier Menayer." Le oautionnement on le re$n
                        d’uno banque, d’aprfi* I os conditions dd Cahier das charges, devra fltre
                        remis sfiparfiment au Servioe' de la Comptabilite Gflufirole
                        avantj'qaverture dee offres ot au plus tard le ll juillet k midi. Toute
                        offre quf no reimpllt pas Ids conditions oi-dessua sere fleartye.
                        L'Admimstratenr (signfi) W. P. Chataway. Alexandria, le27 join 1905. 26172 3
                        1 ComdMate Betaiqae d'Metaadrie AVIS La CommunauU- Hellfiniqao d'Alexaudric
                        a ll’houneur d'informer le public qu'ello recovre rjnsqa'au 12 juillet 1905
                        k 5 h. p.m. des offres jpourla construction d'uno Edole Profe-- ..Q- L»
                        plans, devls,-cahier dei clauses ot cm. ditions gfinfireles, ot cahier dei
                        clauses tj h- niqces dfiposfis aux Birea-ix do la Commc nautfi peuveut fltre
                        ooisultei tons les jours de 9h. k midi et de 3li k 5b. p.m , les jours
                        tojfli exceptfis. Les offres seront._elres*!es i Mouaiour le Pr6sident do
                        laCommunautd Helldniquo d’Alox andrie etsous double envoloppe.oello
                        inttrieure portant la suscription suivante : * "Offre pour In oonatruction
                        d’uno K.-ole Profmionoelle." La Communaute ne s'engago pas k accepter
                        1’offre la plus basso ni k douner suite aux soumissions plenties.
                        Alexandria, le 15/28 join 1905. 2C17I 7a 1</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <head>THU EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JUNE 29, 1905.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INDEMNITIES OF WAR SOME RECENT CASES.</head>
                    <p>In principle war indemnities may be regard- ed as "the coAts ol the action" ;
                        in practice they are apt to become confounded with the object ot the
                        quarrel. This was emphatically m tlie case of the ransom extorted from K-
                        'ine by the Gauls after the battle of the Allia ,,,330 B.' When Brennos
                        tlsng bis sword and shield into the scales and cried, "Vn- victia," be
                        atbnned a principle which is pro Kibly as ancient as human uature, and which
                        has been tairly steadily maintained ever since. The amount of a war
                        indemnity often depends iiite as much upon the auxiety of the van , ashed to
                        escape further homiliation as upon ;Le victor's precise bill of expenses,
                        tin the , ther haud, the sum is frequently reduced tlirough the sheer and
                        manifest inability of the crushed combatant to pay the price of his own
                        overthrow. Indeed, it is almost impossible to find an example in which some
                        disturbing factor does tot interfere with the precise operation of the
                        general law. Napoleon, for instance, cost Great Britain alonp the greater
                        part of £831,000,000 before he was finally suppressed at Waterloo , but
                        under the TREATY OF PARIS (1815). France paid only ........ £28,000,000 to
                        England, Pmssia, and Rnssia together. In the impoverished condition of Lonis
                        XVIII.'s dominions, however, it »as thonght advisable to spread even this
                        comparatively modest reimbursement over a period of five years, and it was
                        divider! into fifteen instalments of £1,.110,000 each, one of which fell due
                        every four months. Coming to more recent times, we find in 1^71 what is
                        always regarded as the supreme exaiup’e of a war indemnity. Under the TREATY
                        op FRANKFORT, 1871, France paid a ransom of . . £200,000,000. In demanding
                        this colossal sum Bismarck had in bis mind two distinct intentions; They
                        were to replenish Germany's emptied war chest and by crippling her
                        antagonist financially to pre- vent her from reviving to a condition in
                        which she could have renewed boAilities before time bad soothed her wounded
                        pride and assuaged the desire for "la revanche." That the latter purpose
                        might more completely be fulfilled, payment in cash, and over a very short
                        period, was imposed. The first instalment was £20,000,000, and it was
                        provided by the stipu- lations of the treaty that it should be banded over
                        one month after the French Government had obtained possession of Paris from
                        the Commune. A further £40,000,000 was to be liquidated before the end ot
                        the year, £20,00o,imore on May 1, 1872, and the balanoo of £1801000,000 on
                        May 2, 1874. Moreover," interest at the rate of 5 per oent had to be paid
                        until tho money had actaally changed hands. The manner in which France
                        discharged this enormons debt is one of the most remarkable displays of the
                        latent wealth of a nation to be found in history. To the astonishment of the
                        whole world, the entire £2u0,O00,OO0 was placed at the disposal of the
                        conqueror six months before the expiry of the prescribed term.</p>
                    <p>Another large indemnity of recent times was that exacted by Rnssia from
                        Tnrkey in 1878, aftet the Tsar’s armies had fought their way to the gates of
                        Constantinople. The terms agreed to at San Stefano underwent consider- able
                        modification at the subsequent International Congress, bat under the
                        TREATY OP BERLIN, Turkey undertook to pay..£32,000,000. It was stipulated,
                        however, that the Ottoman Government, never a very prompt settler of
                        accounts, should be allowed a long period of years in which to find the
                        money. Some of it is still owing. Japan has a precedent of her own in this
                        matter, an indemnity having form- ed an important feature in the fruits of
                        her triumph over China in 1895. The amount demanded was considerably
                        increased after the intervention of Russia, Germany, and France had deprived
                        the victorious islanders of the Liao-tung peninsula and the fortress of Port
                        Arthur. Under the eventual TREATY OP 8HIMONOSBKI, China paid 200,000,000
                        taels. This woald beequivalent toabout£26,000,000 in English currency.
                        Turkey was very anxious to obtain a substantial indemnity from Greeoe in
                        1897, but a financial commission appointed by the Powers reported that the
                        defeated bel- ligerent oould not arfford to satisfy the Otto man demand, and
                        £4,000,000 was in'theend fixed upon as the outside limit of the pecuniary
                        compensation in this case. At the conclusion of hostilities between the
                        United States and Spain was seen the nnosual spectacle of the victor paying
                        an indemnity, as a kind of sb change in return for territorial concessions
                        that seemed rather more than the circumstances of he case required.</p>
                    <p>Hansa Steamship Company Ocean Steamship Company (Alf. Holt and Co.) ... — ...
                        ... Cay wr Irvine and Co. (Clan Line)... Norddeutechor Lloyd Meseagoriea
                        Mari times Goo. Smith and Sons (City Line) .. Hamburg-Amerika
                        Line............. Austrian Lloyd................ „. T. and J. Harrison
                        (Charento Steam- ship Company) ................. „ Henderson Bros. (Anchor
                        Line) ... British India Steam Navigation Co... Netherland Steamship Company
                        ... Bibby Bros, and Co............... Orient-Pacific Steam Navigation Co.
                        Rotterdam-Lloyd ................. P. Henderson (British Burmese) ... China
                        Mntnal Steamship .......... Hatch East-Africa Line P. C. Strick aud Co.
                        (Anglo-Arabian Company) ^........ ............ Dutch-Australian Line
                        ........... T. J. Brocklebank and Co. ....... Rickinsons and Sons (West
                        Hartle- pool Company) ................... R. Alexander and Co. (Hall Line)..
                        Kunciman and Co. (Moor Line) Italian General Navigation ...... Bucknall
                        Bros. (British Colonial) ... James Marks Wood................. J. Macdonald
                        and Co. (Anglo-Amer- ican Oil Company) ............... Th. Wilson Sons and
                        Co........... M. Samuel and Co. (Shell Line) Other companies and Government
                        shipping…….</p>
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL TONNAGE.</p>
                    <p>SUDAN AND-UGANDA.</p>
                    <p>SOME INTERESTING DETAILS FROM</p>
                    <p>THE REPORT OF THE COMPANY. BRITAIN’S WORK IN EGYPT. The report of the Suez
                        Canal Company- gives some interesting details with regard to the various
                        shipping companies whose vessels used this great waterway laet year. As wo
                        pointed out when dealing with the summary of tho report the progress made by
                        British ship- ping at Urge is very marked, and it now appears that tho
                        number of passages made by British vessels was 2,679, with a total net
                        tonnage of 8.834,000, Germany, tho near- est competitor, recording 542
                        passages, with a net tonnage of 1,969,000. The distribution of this tonnage
                        amongst the various lipes, as given in the report, is as follows Company.
                        Tonnage.</p>
                    <p>PeninsnUr and Oriental.............. 1,06-1,500 653.300 516,700 475.400
                        451,800 444.300 423.600 378.600 363.400 ._ 358,300 ... 318,600 o... 262,600
                        ’ ... 248.000 ... 223,000 Co. 213.800 ... 202,800 ... 193,600 ... 174,000
                        ... 165,900 Duteh-Australian Line ............. 153,900 T. J. Brocklebank
                        and Co. ......... 149,500 Rickinsons and Sons (West Hartle- pool Company)
                        ..................... 148,400 R. Alexander and Co. (Hall Line).. 128,2(0
                        Kunciman and Co. (Moor Line) 127,300 Italian Goneral Navigation 123.000
                        Bucknall Bros. (British Colonial) ... 119,500 James Marke
                        Wood................... 116,900 J. Macdonald and Co. (Anglo-Amer- ican Oil
                        Company) ................. 116,700 Th. Wilson Sons and Co........... 113,900
                        M. Samuel and Co. (Shell Line) 103,700 Other companies and Government
                        shipping........ 4,706,800 Total.............. 13,401,800</p>
                    <p>As printed, this list is calcnUted in some respects to produce a slightly
                        wrong impres- sion of the status of the various lines. Por example, the Hall
                        Line and the City Line are both owned by the Ellerman Lines, Limited, and if
                        these two totals were added together, as they Bhonld properly be, that
                        oompany would rank third on the list, as against the total tonnage of any
                        other—British or foreign—and teoond if compared with British lines only.
                        This mast be regarded as a highly satisfactory rooord for a combination
                        which has been in existence only about four years. Of the list as a whole,
                        it may be said that it is most credit- able to British shipowners, and shows
                        very clearly their greatly preponderating share in the business of the
                        Canal.</p>
                    <p>A FRENCH COLONI AL OFFICIAL* OPINION. In tho course of an interview with the
                        re- presentative of the "African World" M.Salesses Administratenr-en-chef in
                        the Prench Colonial Service aud Director of the Nigor-Konakiy Railway, made
                        the following observations on his visit to the Upper Nile, Uganda, and
                        British E. Africa.</p>
                    <p>"Haviog been kindly supplied with letters commendatory by M. Dolcassc, I
                        visited Egypt, and at Cairo wi s received by Lord Cromer and Lord E-lwaid
                        Cecil, Agent General for the Sudan at Cairo, to both of whom I am most
                        grateful—as, indeed, to the British officials everywhere--for many
                        kindnesses.After having inspected the Egyptian railways with the aid of M.
                        Barois, the French administrator of Egyptian railways, I was able to see the
                        Assouan dam, thanks to Sir William Gantin. It is magnifioent; a groat work.
                        At Wady- Halfa I inspected the workshops of the Sudan Government Railways,
                        through the kindness of Captain Midwinter, the assistant manager of the
                        line. A railway U being Uid from Atbara to Sheikh Bxrgut, now called Bandar
                        Sndan, and fifty mile* of the work had already been completed. At Khartoum,
                        in the Sirdar's absence, 1 »oi received by Colonel Henry. Khartoum looks
                        well. It is astonishing how much has been done in so short a time. It U said
                        that the country between KassaU and Khartoum and the banks of the Blue Nile
                        is exceedingly rich and good ooontry. I left Khartoum by steamer for
                        Gondokoro. There are four steamers at work clearing the sudd, a work which
                        is indispensable for the navigation of the White Nile. After visiting Lado
                        and Gondokoro I was provided by Mr. Spire, Col- lector of Gondokoro, with
                        forty carriers, and traveled tho Uganda Protectorate on foot, visiting the
                        posts ot Nimnle, Wadelai, and Bulraba (on Lake Albert Nyanza), Hoima and
                        Kampala, and finally Entebbe, on the shores of the Victoria Nyanza, the main
                        town of Uganda. 1 saw on this part of my journey very many buffalo,
                        elephants, harts boost, oribes, waterbneks, and some baheoiceps of Schwein-
                        furth. At Entebbe 1 was the guest of Mr. Wilson, the Acting Commissioner of
                        the Uganda Protectorate.</p>
                    <p>UGANDA PROSPECTS. "I found the ooontry looking very well and prosperous. The
                        people are chiefly oatives, but there arc also Indian traders and a few
                        Euro- peans. The natives are peaceable, a fine race physically, and not very
                        difficult to govern. I think it is a wise policy to have built the Uganda
                        railway, and that several other lines should be bnilt rather than money be
                        spent on outting new roads, inasmuch as horses and mules die, and the
                        country is too wet for oamels. Prom Butraba to Entebbe the climate is
                        perfect, and I think the country is van suitable for Europeans. It is the
                        land of the elephant. Thera is much trade in ivory, and they have good hopes
                        for rubber. I believe it would pay the country to build two railways, the
                        first trom Gondokoro to Nimule, 100 miles, and the other from Butraba to
                        Entebbe, 200 miles. There is a sufficiency of good native labour, and the
                        oost would not be great, if the management were intelligent. 1 left Entebbe
                        and crossed the Viotoria lake by the steamer • Winifred," oalling at Jinja,
                        where I saw the Ripon Palls, that is, the beginning of the Nile, At Kisomu
                        (Port Florence) I took the Uganda railway, and stopped at Nairobi, where I
                        had the pleasure of meeting the general manager of the line, Mr. Currie, to
                        the excellence of whose direction I wish to testify. The line is well bnilt
                        I believe, ss 1 have said, that fur* ther railway construction in Uganda is
                        necess sary, and that when Uganda is folly develop* ed, both it and the East
                        African Protectorate will be successful colonies. The climate of the East
                        African Protectorate is admirably suited to Europeans. It is astonishing to
                        see ante- lopes, giraffes, zebras, gazelles, ostriches, and more
                        occasionally lions and rhinoceroses along the line. Leaving Nairobi I
                        reached Mombasa, where I crossed Lord Milner, who had oome from Durban, and
                        was inspecting the Uganda railway.</p>
                    <p>THE COST OF AN ARTIFICIAL SEA. EGYPT EXPLORATION PUND. In seeking for a
                        reservoir for the supply of Egypt during the dry season, it is not to be
                        wondered at .that the reconstruction of the ancient Lake of Moeris should
                        have been care- 1 fully considered. As, however, in the bed of tho lake is a
                        fertile province, with a cultiv- able area of 400,000 acres and a value of
                        80,000,000/., its construction on its original site is oat of the question ;
                        but there exists a tmailer depression in the Libyan hills immediately to the
                        sooth, to which no suoh objections apply. This depression is' known ss the
                        Wady Rayan ; and Mr. Cope Whitehouse, the disooveror of Lake Moeris, ' has
                        for yean insisted that in taming theWady . Rayan into an artificial lake or
                        reservoir lay the true solution of the problem of Egypt's ! water supply. In
                        area at a level of 29 metres j above that of the sea would be about 700
                        square kilometres, or 270 square miles When full, its greatest depth would
                        be 70 metres, though only the upper 4 or 5 metres would bo used annually,
                        giving a possible supply cf some 3 milliards of oubio metres out of a total
                        contents of 20 milliards. Mr. Cope Whitehouse maintains that the entire work
                        necessary can ho done at a oost of 600,000/ He has offered many times to
                        undertake the contract for the work on the basis of this estimate, or to
                        carry it oat as a private speculation, subject to equit- able terms of
                        purchase by the Egyptian Go- vernment when oompleted. It is unpleasant to
                        know that these offers have been rejected again and again ; not because of
                        any engineer- ing reasons, but that the Government preferred to leave a
                        great part of Egypt trows tored until they possessed the inclination and
                        money to do the work themselves. However, whether it is to cost 600,000/. or
                        2,600,000/., the estimate of Sir W. Willoocks, the outlay will bring an
                        enonnons and immediate return, and the names of those who have assisted in
                        bringing it to completion will deserve remembrance among the greatest
                        benefactors of Egypt. ("Engineering.")</p>
                    <p>A PIGMY TRIP. The pigmies who have temporarily exchang- ed Darkest Africa for
                        Dampest England had their first motor ride yesterday, says Monday week's
                        "Pall Mall Gazette," bat there seems to be no means of obtaining a
                        satisfactory state- ment of their impressions. Their only remark on the trip
                        was, "Umgari," which is supposed, we are told, to be Pigmyeae for "good."
                        But it seems just as likely to be the equivalent of the "No pusbee, no
                        pollee, go like bailee," which is the first rooord ed sooonnt by a Chinese
                        descriptive reporter ot an electric tramway. The majority of the party spent
                        the journey in slumber, bat the yoangest made np for this stolidity by
                        tasting the lubricating oil and emptying the remainder over the vehicle,
                        after which be overhauled the machinery to inch purpose that the homeward
                        trip was completed m a cab. Understanding that they were to traverse the del
                        ole te mileage of the Brighton road, the distinguished tourists were allowed
                        to wear their full equipment of spears and arrows, but, as there were no
                        signs of the Marquis of Queensberry being on the warpath, the expedition was
                        fortunate enough to return scatheless.</p>
                    <p>The following letter appears "iu^the "Times":— Sir,— Onr attention has been
                        called^to a communifui paragraph with regard to the establishment of a
                        British School of Arohmo- logy in Egypt, which has appeared in several of
                        the morning papers. While we refrain from discussing the desirability or the
                        prospects-of such a school, we must express our surprise that in this
                        announcement the existence of the Bgypf Exploration Fund through the aid of
                        which Professor Flinders Petrie has in the main been enabled to carry on hie
                        important work in Egypt, is entirely ignored. The tyt is thst, although the
                        arrangement between Professor Petrie and the fond is for the present
                        suspended by mutunl consent, he has during the past nine yean not only
                        received from-the fond a regular salary and has been allowed travelling and
                        personal expenses while in Egypt, bat he has also had placed at his disposal
                        an aggregate sum of upwards of £7,000 for the purposes ot exploration. We
                        venture, through your kind assistance, to remind the subscriber* to the
                        Egypt Exploration Fund of this fact, and to express a hope not only that
                        existing subscriptions may not be diverted elsewhere, bat that the fond
                        which liu already done so much in the past to make known in this ooontry the
                        history of ancient Egypt may reoeive a still wider support</p>
                    <p>Although for the moment it is doubtful whether, from financial
                        considerations, large exoavations can at present be undertaken by the fund,
                        the committee hope that work may be resumed at the unique temple of Mentu-
                        hotep at Deir-el-Bahari and brought to a dose in the ensuing season.</p>
                    <p>Yours faithfully, JOHN BVAN8, President, HERBERT A. GRUBBER, Treasurer, Egypt
                        Exploration Fund, 37, Great Rossell- street, W.C., Jane 16. COTTON GROWING
                        IN THE WEST INDIES.</p>
                    <p>Evidence of the confidence that is felt in the fntnre of ootton growing in
                        the West Indies is afforded by the announcement in the "Agricultural News,"
                        the official organ of the Agricultural Department of the West Indies, that
                        it is proposed, in view of the progress made in oonoeotion with the Sea
                        Island ootton industry in the West Indies, to ereot a small plant at
                        Barbados for sx tree ting and refining the oil to be obtained from the seed.
                        The project is receiving the support of the British Cotton Growing
                        Association. The establish- ment is expected to be ready to begin opera-
                        tions early next year, and it will be the first Ootton oil factory to be
                        orected in the British West Indies. As to its immediate outlook, it is
                        estimated that the total crop of Sea Island ootton for the current season
                        will be about 8,000 bale*, which will probably yield some 1,660 tons oi
                        seed. The yield of crude oil is about 45 gallons per ton of reed, so that if
                        the whole of the seed were available for the factory the ontpat of erode oil
                        woald be eboat 74,900 gallons.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <p>on*run OAZSTTI, WEDNESDAY, JUNE 28, 1908. DELEGATION MDN1C1PALE ( Communication
                    OfficieUe ) La Delegation Municii>alo a'oit rcunie lo 27 juiu 1905 k 5 h. p.m.
                    sous la prAaidenoe de M Amb. A. Ralli. Presents: MM. Penderl, Ahmed Bey Eyoub.
                    Abani Boy, Dr Schiesa Bey, Dr Q. Valensir. membros, W. P. Chataway,
                    administrateor, I. Sodky bey, secretaire. Contirmant une do sea prAoSdoutes de
                    ibo rations, ot do l'avis conformodu vctflrinire cu chef, la Delegation decido
                    do mottro on adjudi cation lafooruiture du sang recueilli it l’abattoir ainsi
                    quo dos animaux morta dostines k IV qnarrissago La Delegation decide do mottro
                    on adjndi cation la lournitnro do 3,500 m„ do tuyaux do diffArants diamitros
                    nAcossairea k ses sorvico- Eilo adopte une proposition du Ojuvernor.it tondant k
                    allouor aux agents do la police lo 10 dos ohcaissemonta effectoes par onx stir
                    la vento dos plaques fournies aux oochers. Lo tarif dos voituros devra fltre
                    egaloment public eu uu grand nombre d'exemplaires, pour Ctre mis k la
                    disposition dos intArossAs. La Delegation autoriso la Cio du Gat ii iustallor 2
                    kiosqnos pour tranformateurs, d'un modelo rond, ruo Pirona ot avenue Moharrem
                    Bey, pris l'immoublo Francis Boy. Deferant k uno domando do la societe inter-
                    uationalo do la repression do la traito dos blanches, la Delegation proposora
                    d'allouer a cotte societe pour cotto acuAo ot k titro do donation, une 6ommo de
                    LE. 50. La Delegation proud note d’une.lettro minis- tcriollo du 24 juin
                    approuvant lo nouvol ac- coid intorvenu avoc l'ontrepriso Almagik. La Delegation
                    proud note d une lettre 'lo la Compsgnie des Eaux du 23 juin veraant a la
                    Municipality la moitiA du surplus du 10% dos bAnAficea realises dans lo dornior
                    oxorcico so cloturant au 31 mars 1905 ot so muntant pour la part do la
                    Municipalite k L.K 732. Elio proud u-jto do la lottro du 24 juin do S.E. lo
                    Miuistro do l’lnteriour tranamottaut 1'arrOte do la taxo sur lei voituros ot
                    baitiaux approuve par la Couseil des Mioistros. La Delegation decide dc
                    velocigraphier ot distribuer aux membros pour sou oxamen k la procliaine seance,
                    lo rapport do Mr. Fierz sur la reglcmontation dos installations cloctriquos EUe
                    proud connaissauco du rapport du 14 juin du Comite charge de i'examou do la ques
                    tiuu do l'augmentatioa du nombro dos pouts du Malimoudieh ot adopte les
                    propositions y coutenuos. La Delegation adjugo la fourniture de four- rago k
                    divers, oouformemoat au rapport des servioos. Elio adjugo a M. i’iiiolante, au
                    prix do LE. 69 3/4 1'ompiorremeut do la ruo du Musce. Delegation accopto, do
                    l'avis oonformo du Tanzim, la cession d'une rue par M. Stagni du co’.e de la rue
                    Kosette au quartior Grec, et do deux ruoa par Mr. Davies Bryan, k Mo- harreui
                    Boy. Elio prend conuaissance du rCglomcnt minis tcriol du 22 juin 19"j, sur la
                    rage, lequel sera uommuniquA au Comite du Contentieux. 1a tC-aucu eet levee k 7
                    b. 1/2 p.m. La Tour des Romains Aprksavoir longtemps prAconiaA la demoli- tion
                    do la Tour dos Romains, M.. Zonro vient Ffltro charge par les services
                    techniques do la Municipality do prooeder lui-memokee travail. Flusieurs blocs
                    du sommet ont dejk ete decro- ches, mais lo travail n'avanco quo loutement,
                    attendu qu'il faut user des plus grandes pre- cautions ponr eviter des
                    accidents. BIBLIOGRAP3IS Coins d’Egypte Ignores * Cost une revelation quo la
                    succession de tableaux documentairoi prAsentA) avao tant d'art par M. Albert
                    Guyot sur la Haute-Bgypto. Nous voilk loin des reconstitutions romanos- quas,
                    des descriptions fantaisistes, des ex- plorations superficiellee qui ont forme
                    l’opinion des "snobs" sur cetta terra imprAgnAe encore du symbolisms naturiste,
                    oontomporain da- premiers etonuoments de 1’hommo et dos pre- miors essaii de
                    gen6.se rol'gieusa II revit lk, Sans un decor immuable, dtns les mccurs do
                    habitants, dans les peintures naives des oqo vents ot des sepultures, dans les
                    mines qnl sortent mirkcnleuscment d'un sol qui a tente maints conqu6rants, lo
                    drame d’Osiris-Autinous ai voisin de oelui d'Abel et Cain ; olios ressns citent
                    k nos youx, griAe k l’enchantement d'un recit oil la conscience da I'arcbeologue
                    soutient eA virement leehirme d'une poAtiqueevocation, lessaiutes retraitos des
                    anachorktas si calom cie- par Anatole Franco jet Flaubert: Scbe noddi, la valMo
                    de Birel-An, Antinoc, avoc ra double et coutradictoire destines, Saiut-Ma-
                    oaire,8aint-8imA m, Saint Jean Lycopolis. Nous retronvons enfiu, k Damiette et k
                    Mansourah, lea traces visibles de la demiire A tape des croi sades. Et force
                    nous est de oonclure, avoc l'auteur, quo l'histoire, la plus anguste et la plus
                    titree qui se rencontre au monde, n'ost pcubfltre, apri* plus de soixante-dix
                    siiclos ic UarmaoArc 1. PmrU. TO WHOLESALE BUYERS' STORK- KEEPERS, AND OTH E R T
                    R A D B RS . — If you are not a reader of "African Com- merce,” the British
                    Trade Medium for All Africa, send 7d. for a copy to The Manager, “African
                    Commerce," Tower Chambers, Moorgate Street, London, E.C. Annual Subscription 7/6
                    post free. BULLETIN DB LA BOURSE ( Auhurdkui d midi et demit) Par suite des
                    meilleures nouvolles politiques et surtout do la hauss9 k Lindres et k Paris, le
                    rnarche- roprond ici sur toute la liguo, avoc transactions asset nombrousos ot
                    tendanco k la hausse. Lx Banque Nationale romoute de 25 11/16 k 25 13/16
                    l'ancienue emission et do 25 15/16 k 26 1/3 la uouvelle, Taction Credit Fonoior
                    do 791 k 305, l'Agricolo do 13 3/3 k 13 1/2, la Banque d'Athines de 119 1/2 k
                    120 1/2, la Daira do 23 k 23 1/3, la Khedivial Mail do 4 5/16 k 4 3/8 ot F
                    Alexandria Water de 14 1/4 k 14 5/8. MOme mouvcuient snr los petite* valours qni
                    haussent l'lnvestment do 11,4 k 1 9/32, la Delta Land de 2 1/16 k 2 3/16, les
                    Estates de 13/16- k 27/32, et la Salt Soda do 33/3 k 34,3. Domain k 10 boures a
                    lieu la vente aux on- chcros par voie de justice do 300 Estates, 200 Investment,
                    etc. A. Cholmis, 4 cais. oigarettes P. 8chwitx, 207 barils vidos A. Drelier, 440
                    barils vides Depfit Bii.ro de Graz, 1,160 barils vides P. M. Statirk, 28 ballcs
                    peanx A. E. Funk Socc., 493 barils vides L Dolacovias, 284 barils vides j A.
                    Frick, 19barils poisson frais Divers, 27 colis divers Pour PIOMBINO, par lo
                    batoau italien “Luigia," parti le 24 juin : F. Panelli, 47 tODnes vioux for
                    EASTERN TELEORAPH CM". AVERAGE TIME oocnpied in transmission of Egyptian
                    telegrams from England to Alexandria on Tuesday, 27th June, 1905. OUTWARD8. The
                    ! Postal Company's Telegraph U. M. London 11 Liverpool 13 Manchester 15 Glasgow
                    43 Other Provincial Offices — 1. 9 Anglo-American Nila Steam er Se HOTEL
                    COMPANY. ■ilVER I RAIS PORT Of 03D3 BEIWEEI AIEXA1DRI1 A CAIR. Thrwa Sailings
                    a-Waak. 4ftnit at Alexandria AlEZAiMlA KflNSEf WAKEH9UIE CO. LO. EXPORT MAN
                    IFESTS. For MALTA and MANCHESTER, by the S.S. "Soottish Prince," sailed on the
                    21st Carver Bros. Co. Ltd, 795 bales ootto.i Peel A Co., 1,597 „ G. Rieckeu, 49
                    „ Choremi, Benachi A Co., 675 „ „ II. Bindernagol, 70 „ „ Mohr Pender!, W. Getty
                    A Co., Birch Co, H. A 0. Lindemann, E. Mallison Co , P. C. Baines Co., 0.
                    Prauget A Co., 119 25 50 3,755 bales cotton J. A A. Aboucbauab, 1,576 bags oil
                    cake Butternorth A Smalley, 48 packages machi- nery, 49 bales belts J. Ross Co.,
                    350 empty casks L. Heller, 200 barrels molasses Livanos fr., 1 case cigarettes
                    PonrLASYRlE par le bateau fran$. “Portu- gal," parti le 22 juin : Divers, 114
                    colis provisions POCB KOBE Peel Co^ 700 holies coton Ponr MAP SEILLE, par le
                    bateau franj. “Congo,” parti le 23 join : POCK MARSEILLE Bonded Stores, 92 cais.
                    conserves J. B. Caffori, 6 chevaux Divers, 56 oolis divers P. C. Baines A Co.,
                    94 bailee coton G. Frauger A Co., 139 „ „ Mohr Penderl, 57 „ „ j J. Planta A
                    Co., , 31 „ „ Birch Co., 33 „ Choremi, Benachi A Co., 30 „ „ 384 bailee coton
                    P0OB LK IIAVBE Carver Bros. A Co. Ltd, 50 hallos ooton G. Frauger Co., 100 „ „
                    Moursi, 25 „ „ 175 balles coton Griva fr., 600 sacs gomme G. Frauger Co., 1
                    farde cafe POUR TUNIS Tchamkerbi, 3 balles taboo Por LEITH, by ths 3.S
                    “Midlothian," sailod on the 23rd Jane : Huileries Sav. d'Egypte, 2,302 bags oil
                    cake G. Morris Co., 20 bags peas, 1 barrel pitch Behrend A Co., 1,018 quarters
                    barley, 120 tons cotton seed Barker Co, 3,925quarters barley Pour BRINDISI et
                    TRIESTE, par le bateau autr. "Cleopatra," parti le 24 juin : P. C. Baines A Co.,
                    31 balles ooton E Mallison ft Co., 62 „ Carver Bros. Co. Ltd, 290 „ „ Mohr ft
                    Penderl, 238 „ Choremi, Benachi Co., 120 „ „ Peel 4 Co., 64 ., „ j J. Planta
                    Co., 336 „ „ i R. ft 0. lindemann, 182 „ „ I 1,323 bailee ooton M. L. Carasso, 3
                    fardes gomme Kyriati h., 10 cais. cigarettes Ste Le Khedive, 12 cais. oigarettes
                    Eredi Albertini, HI barils vides Dimitrino ft Co., 16 oois. oigarettes STOCKS
                    AND SHARES Cloring Price*, today at 1 p.m. •maraa BANKS. Dotxmtor** Lst. 14
                    Imperial Ottoman Bank — „ 25 {J Nat. Bank of Egypt ... — „ — do do New 26} Pos.
                    426 — National Bank of Groeoe — L.R — 1*5 Banque Industrielle... — Pcs. 805 —
                    Credit Ponder Bgyptien [Lottery Bonds 312 lot. 18 l Agrionltnral Bank ... Fob.
                    120 } Banqne d'Athknes — let. 1 9/32 Egypt Investment Co. — Pos. 1000 —
                    Agrio.-indust. Egypt... 520 Pond. 1050 LE. 44 Bohera Company... 5} lilt 2 /’j
                    EgyptDelta LmdCa... — „ 6 3 Wardan Estate Coy.... 5 „ 4 1 land A Mortgage. ... —
                    „ 28 } New DaitaSanieb Pond. 181 „-----------Corporation of Western u> oif 03 J
                    27/ — New Egyptian Co. ... Egypt Estates Ltd. ... 27/32 COMMXUCIAL INDOSTUIAL
                    Lit 30 — Alexand. Bonded Storos Pref. — — H AngloEgypt. Spinning Co. — „ 23 —
                    Bourse Khediviale ... — „ 75 — prof. Cairo Sowage Transport Ord. 60 Pcs. 200 —
                    ex Cr. Brewery Alex. Pond. 105 „-----------do do 6% Debs. 500 „ 116 — do Cairo
                    Pond. 61 8h. 4,9 — Egypt Cotton Mills ... — „ 22/3 — do Markets ... 100 „ 84/3 —
                    do Salt and Soda Pond. — Pos. 70 — Ciments d'Egypte.. ... 15 Lst — Egypt Trust
                    Invest. 1A „ 7 i Katr-el-Zayat Cot Coy. 102* „ 9 Nangovioh Hotels ... 103J „ 36
                    — Soarressage ot Depots 102 „ 25 — Societe Presses Libras 102 NAVIGATION * WATXB
                    WORKS. lot 5 f ex Anglo - American Nile fto. Co. — „ 4 3 Khedivial Mail 3.3.
                    fto- Co. Ponds. 16/3 „ 14 jj ex Alex. Water Company — Pcs. 1110 Cairo WaterCoy.
                    Ponds. 1040 Ltt. • 22 } Tan tab Water Co. Ponds. — RAILWAYS * TRAMWAYS. Let 12 J
                    Delta Light ................ 103} „-----------Delta laght Det... ... 14 „ 9 —
                    Payoam..............- — „ 26 } Keneh-Aseonan........ — Pcs. 156 — Alexandria
                    Trams ... 480 ------do „ Ponds. 843 Lst. 7 } RamlehRailway... — — Furnished by
                    Reid Bernard 10, St. Marks Buildings, Alexandria, and Sharia Koar-el-N il,
                    Cairo, who undertake the sale and purchase of Stocks and Shares, on the local
                    Bonne and also on the London Stock Exchange. BOURSE KHEDIVIALE CONTRATS
                    Flaotaations de 9h.30 k lb. p.m. ’ Colon* F.G.F.Br. Dans la matinle ; prix pins
                    haatpour jaillet taL 14 3/16 k —I— ; plus bos ponr jaillet 14 3/32 k —I—.
                    Grain** de coton Dans la matinAe ; prix pins haut ponr juiL P.T. 60—/— k —/—:
                    pins has poor jail. 59 15/40 k —/—. Remarques (De Midi k lb. p.m.) Cotons.—Aprts
                    le cxlmo da matin ily a un pen de rafiTermiuoment et retonr aux cours
                    d'ouverture, mail vers la fin la faiblesse a prAdominA de uonveau et.la olOtore
                    a eu lieu en baisse, au mAme dugrd taut pour la rAootto actuelle quo pour lo
                    uovembre. NAanmoins, au fond, la sitnation roite la mime et un pen de mieux da
                    dehors nous ferait de suite bausser. Grainos de ooton.— MarehA faible et la
                    presaion ox erode par quelquei intArassAs a prodnit de l'effet sur les oours.
                    PAves.—Marche nuL Bourse KhAdiviale, le 27 juin 1905. oopie de la dApAche di
                    l'alkzandbu gkhiral phodooi k la LIVXBPOOL COTTON ASSOCIATION (Conn pratiquAs oe
                    jour k la Bourse KhAdi- riale k 9h. 45 a m.) TaL 14 7/82 Isrraison Jaillet „ 14
                    11/32 „ Aoflt „ 18 19/32 „ Nombre ., 13 15/32 „ Janvier MarohA ferme Am rages de
                    oe jonr, k Minot-el-Bassal, can tars 792 (Conn pratiquAs oe jour k la Bonne
                    KhAdi rials k 19h.45 p.m.) TaL 14 3/16 LivTaison Jaillet „ 14 6/16 „ Aoftt „ 13
                    6/8 . Nombre „ 18 1/2 „ Janvier ■knWfeo, RARCHR DKMINET-EL-BASSAL 28 juin
                    1905.—(1 lh.55 a.m.) Coton* — Clflture da marohA du 27 join : Soutenu, mais
                    transactions modArAes. Pair, Fnlly Pair, Good Fair, Pally Good Pair et Good:
                    Sans ohangement Hants-cams n tatoum Pair, Polly Pair, Good Pair, Pally Good Fair
                    et Good: Sans changemont ABASH 2mo qoalitA, Ire qualitA, oxtra: Sans chango-
                    mont iannovicu 2mo qualitA, Ire qualitA, extra: Sans ohange- ment Btat da marohA
                    de oe jonr, cotons: Sou tonus Les arrirages do oe jour se chiffrent par cantors
                    1491 oontre mAme jonr 1'onnAe prAoAdente cantors — Grain** de coton.—En baisse
                    Diaponible Tioket MitrAfifi—58 Rjen Haute-Egypte.—57 Rian BU*.—Permoi Qualitf
                    Satdi.—Cond. Saha P.T. — k -- BOOra: „ „ „ 104 k 110 Fete*.—En hausse Saidi.—95
                    Fayoum : disponible : 94 QualiH Said* . Cond. 8aha P.T. 98 k 108
                    Lentille*.—Rarea Disponible : Rien Cond. Saha P.T. 110 k 125 Oraet.—Soutenues „
                    ConcLSaha P.T. 6 J k 65 Mai*.—Sans changemont Disponible : Rien „ Cond. Saha
                    P.T. 98 k 100 HULL Grainttde coton.— Plus fkcilos five*:— M6me situation
                    LONDkra' Griint* de ooton.—Sentences COTON AMERICA! N ' LtVKHPOOL Puturs jail,
                    aodtij 4.97 ^7 points de hausse) „ oot-nov.: 4.9 J (7 points de hausse)
                    Disp-mible : 5 05 (2 points de hausse) NXW-TOBX Middling Upland: 9/0 (20 points
                    do hausse) Future jail.; 9 00 (29 points de hausse) „ oot : 9.18 (27V)ints de
                    hausse) Arri,-v*w du jour, balles 18,000 . Contra mAmejesr, Fanneo darnikrc,
                    balle* 2.60C , _ Exportation du 27 Coton Bal. 110 Gr. de cot Ard. 500 PAvos „ 50
                    depuis le 23 Bal. 4152 Ard. 6251 70 Exportations probables de la semaine : Coton
                    Balles 6.000 Grainos de colon Ardebs 24,000 FAves „ 6,000 Le* prix nicanti ont M
                    pratiqud* ee jour OM.B. (BASSK-Baypn) par Cantor Provinco BAhAra Damanhour. _ _
                    De P.T. 140 k 235 Provienoe Garbieb Kafr-Zayat.. _ _ Dc P.T. 260 k 290 Tan tail.
                    „ 255 „ 285 Provinoe Monoufieh Menonf _ ..........Do P.T. 215 k 255 SECTION DES
                    GRAINES ET CBRBALK3 PUX TBANOO-STATION : DIBrONIBLN TICXXI Graines de ooton
                    Afifi P.T. 58 — k P.T. — „ Haute-Egypte „ 67 — „ „ — Fives Soldi „ 95 — „ „ — „
                    Fayoomi „ 94 — „ „ — ABRIYAGE9 3a morcredi 28 join 1905 Documents de F
                    "Alexandria General Prodnoe Association." CHDQNS DB FSB BARQDKb Cotons ._ — —
                    8/B 99 — Grainos do coton... saos 1802 — BlAs Soldi _ _ „ — — „ BAhAra _ _ ,.
                    484 — Fives Soldi- _ „ 274 — „ BAhAra.. _ „ - - Orges — — — Mais _ _ — „ — —
                    LsntUles.. — ... „ 13 — Coton*.—Total des orrivagos depuis le lor septembre 1904
                    jnsqn’k oe jonr, canUrs 6.197,486 Grains* de coton.—Total des arrivagea depuis
                    le ler septembre 1904 jusqu’k oe jonr, Ard. 3,471,988 Contra mime jonr en 1904 :
                    BASQUES ET CTKMIN8 DX FEB Coton — — — — — — 8/B — Graines de ooton.. — — — sacs
                    1402 BlAs Saidi - - -------------------- PAvds Saidi ._ 620 6259 Lentil! as — —
                    — — — . , Ooton*.—Total des arri rages depuis le ler septembre 1903 jotqo’k ce
                    ionr, oontsrs 6,457,726 , . Graines de ooton. -Total dee amvages depuis le ler
                    septembre 1903 jnsqn'k oe jonr Ard. 3,517,284 CONTRAT8, (llb.55a.rn.) Conre de
                    la Bourse de Minetel-Bassal Ooton F.G.F.Br. Novembre—N.R. TaL 13 19/32 k —
                    Janvier _ — „ 18 15/32 „ — Mars - ... - „ 13UI/16 „ — Jaillet „ - „ 14 5/32 „ —
                    Aoftt........... ,, >4 9/82 „ — Grain** d» colon \ N.-D.-J. - ... P.T. 60 - \ k
                    — JaiUet.......... „ 69 15/40\„ — Aoftt............... 59 35/40 L 60 Five* Said*
                    \ Bept.-Oot.- - P.T. 95 — l\l/2 Coton* : Nonvslle rAoolto.—Le novembre a dAbntA
                    k 13 5/9, mais s’eat de suite calm A k 13 19/32. RAoolto sotnelle.-Le juillet a
                    onvort k 14 7/32. Pee d'affaires. Graintt de coton: Nonvslle rAoolto— Presque
                    sans affaires, oours ferme*. RAcolte actuelle.—Le premier prix pour le jaillet a
                    At A de P.T. —. Fiver Saidi Nouvelle rAoolto.—MarohA nuL Exterleur DApAcbes
                    partiouliires da 27 juin 1905 PRODUIT8 EGYPTIBN8 LimrooL Ooton: Btat dm March/.-
                    Soutenu Ditp..—P.G.P.: 7 1/4 (sans ohangement) Futmn Juin: 6 62/64 (1 point de
                    baisse) RES U M E Dh LA SITUATION L’OTONNIE RE au 2 juin AMERIQUE: 1905 1904
                    Ballot Balles Recettcj aux porta Semaino... 80,000 14,000 Reo. du lor. Sept
                    Export Angleterre 9,494,000 7,050,000 Semaino— ... 40,000 5,000 Export
                    Angleterre du lor Septem. Export. Continent 8,791,000 2,451,000 Semaine — ...
                    Export Continent 30,000 21,000 du lor Septem. 4,231,000 3,260,000 Stock porta
                    430,000 213,000 Insight Semaine... 114.000 27,000 Insight du 1 Sept Connnm.
                    Mondial* 12,651.000 9,795,000 AmAricain. ... 220,000 86,000 Visibly supply ...
                    Visiblo supply 2,201,000 1,137,000 general 8,594,000 1,642,000 AMKRIC AIN
                    LIVERPOOL: 1905 1904 Bailee Balles Vontes Somaine... 48,000 28,000 Forwarded
                    95,000 60,000 Importation 140,000 16,000 Exportation 8,000 6,000 Stock _ 850,000
                    498,090 Fiottaut 160,000 38,000 EGYP I BN LIVERPOOL: 1905 1904 Balles Balles
                    Ventcs Somaine... 4,900 3,000 Forwarded 9,000 8,000 Importation 7,000 3,000
                    Exportation 2,500 1,000 Stock ... .1. ... 42,000 38,000 CEREAL 'M-ArR K BT ROD
                    EL FARAG(National Bank’s Shoonah, Satobday’s Prices Wheat, Tagari... Ard. P.T.
                    Ill to P.T. 113 Middling „ „ 115 ,, ,, 117 Mawoni......... 125 „ „ 132 Beans,
                    Tagari..... „ 98 „ „ Zawati... „ „ 105 „ „ Old........ „ - „ Lentils, Tugari....
                    „ 94 „ „ Zawati „ „ 108 ., , Barley, Tnguri... „ „ 70 „ , „ Zawati........ 75 „
                    , „ Shami... „ „ 73 ,, , „ Hamawl. „ „ — „ Dura Shami ... „ „ 100 „ , Rafis
                    ............... 98 „ , HpllU.................. 170 „ , Tennis........... „ „ 70
                    ,, , Hnmmos .......... ,, ,, 170 ,, , Cereals in Boat at 8ahkl
                    Wheat.........Aid. 2500 Beans ......... „ 1500 Lentils....... „ 300
                    Barley................. 150 „ Shami. „ 800 „ Llamawi „ — Dura Shami ... „ 50 „
                    Rofia - „ 50 Helba - _ 150 TO-DAY'S EXCHANGE QUOTATIONS Banks’ Banks London
                    cheque. — — — „ 3m. bank paper .. — j, 3m. house paper — Paris cheque — — — — „
                    3m. bank paper — — „ 3m. bouse paper — — 3m. bank paper. — — Germany cheque — —
                    — „ 3m. banK paper — Italian cheque. — — — Vienna ft 'Trieste oheque —
                    Constantinople cheque— — •Less one per mills brokerage. TBLBQRAMME HAVAS BOURSE
                    do 27 join 1905 CODRfl DM VALKDBfl A TERMS, CLOTORl PARIS Rente Prancaise 8 % .
                    — ... Fr. 98 55 Actions de ones . — — — „ 4497 — Lots Turns... — — — — „ 131 —
                    TuroUnifiA.. — ........... „ 88 85 Detto Bgyptionne UnifiAe.. ... „ 106 — Dalra
                    Banish ... — — — „ 101 — CrAdit Fonoier Bgyptien— — „ 804 — BxtArienr eepsgnol —
                    — — „ 90 90 Obi. Banque Nat. de Grice — „-------- Banque d’Athtaes, nouvellas
                    101 — 804 — 80 90 MAtropolitain — — — — , Change snr Londrae, Snore N* 8
                    disponible — — , 8ucre N' 8 limble le 4 de mars LONDRES 121 — 89 20 25 14} s
                    anglais — — — £ 90 fa itee—Paris 8, Londres 9}, Berlin 8. REUTER'S TELEGRAMS
                    CLOSING REPORTS Livkrpool, June 27, 12.55 p.m Sales ol tho
                    day./T~^>...-.....bale) s.(KW of which Egyptian ........ i il American (new
                    crop) Maize Spot peroental.......................♦s/i .Amer.
                    fntares(July-August) ... 4.90 „ ,, (Nov.-Dea)............ 4.89 AmoricAU Middling
                    ......... 5.05 Egypt fully good lair, deliveryfJuno) 6 62 61 ••
                    ................TJaly) 6 60 01 „ (August) 6 60,61 „ (Nov.) 6 54 61 » >■ i. ..
                    (Nor.) 6 51 61 Bgjpt Brown fair per lb. d. —6 3/15 ,, ‘ „ good fair — „. 6 15 is
                    „ „ good — — — - 7 13,16 „ fully gtwd lair.................. ... 7 4/16 Egyptian
                    Saidi Beans now (per 480 lbs.) 29 9 London, June 2; Consols (Juljr)
                    .................... 90 • Egyptian Unified............................105 -
                    Private Disoount m. bill............ 2 Niw-Yoax, June 27 Jpot Cotton... — _ — —
                    9 5o American Futures (July) — _ _ 9 „ „ (August) — — 9 06 „ ,. (November) . — 9
                    23 i, „ (December)— — 9 29 Cable transfers — — — — dol. 4.87} Cotton day's
                    receipts at all U.-3. Porta.. — — — —bales 18.0iW LnroBLPOOL, June 27. American
                    fntares (July-Angast) — ._ 4.97 London, June 27. Private disooont (3 mQntb
                    bills) — 2 } % Bar Silver (por 01 d.).. — — 27 — Consols (July) .. — — — — 90 —
                    Rio Tinto*......... — — — ... 61 • Rand Minos Now — — _ _ 9 ■ Egyptian Unifiod —
                    — — — 104 / 1, Railway — _ — — 101 f „ Domain. — — — 101 — Ottoman Dofenoe — — —
                    — 103 } Turkish Unified . — — — — 87 J Italian Rents 4 % - „ „ 105 X Ottoman
                    B.-nk — — — — — 14 4 National Bonk of Egypt _ — — 25 J Dalra Sanieh — _ — — 101
                    — Now Daira... — — — — — 28 — Jrock Monopole.. — — ____ _ 53 } JreekRent4% — u.
                    — — 41 j Chartered* of S. Africa — — — 1 15,16 Agricultural Bank — — — — 13 3 ,
                    New Egyptians.................... _ 1 j Nile Valley Gold Mine ... New — 1 } Fho
                    Western Oasis Corporation } premium Delta Light (Bearer shores) —12 } to 13 —
                    Egypt oot seed toHnll(June) 5 12/16 nominal German Beet Sugar (Juno) _ _ 11/7}
                    Paris, June 27. Cots Taros.. ----- 131 — CrAdit Lyonnais — — — _ 1097 — Ottoman
                    Bonk... — — — _ .606 — Cheques on London....... „ _ 25.14} jogar White No. 8
                    (Jane) — — 33} CrAdit Fonoier Bgyption — 80S — tanquo d'Athknos.................
                    120 — Land Bank of Egypt .............. 225 — SHARE LIST dsoKD at un
                    "Association dm Cooums in VAlices d'Alkxahdrh”. Clflture d'aujoard'bai k 12h.45
                    pun. ;rio. Bank of Egypt let 18 A * - it. Bonk of Egypt „ 25 f J „ 26 mleh
                    Railway — „ 7 * „ — Nat. Bank of Egypt „ 25 }} „ 26 } Ramleh Railway — „ 7 A „ —
                    ? Egyptian Delta Bail- way BX.-C. _ _ „ 12 }| „ — } Tram. d'Alexondrie... Fos.
                    154 — „ 156 — „ „ div. „ 840 — „ 315 - Alexandria Water— Lst. 14 g
                    „-------------- Book dn Cairo... — Fos.--------„ — — Dalra Sanieh _ _ let 28 A „
                    — 1 BAhAra _ _ - LK *4-,. - - Bourse KhAdiviale — let —__ — — Egyptian Markets —
                    „ 22/ "22/3 — Anglo-Egyptian Spinning _ - „ — H „—23/38 Biire d'Alox. Priv. Pos.
                    200 — „ 204 — Spinning _ - „ — H „ —28/39 Biire d'Alox. Priv. Pos. 200 — „ 204 —
                    .. .. Div. „ 105 — „ 110 — „ du Cairo Priv. „ 116 — „ — r- .. .. Div. „ 60 — „
                    61 - B^pt Cotton Mills Lst 4/6 — „ 4/9 — „ 8alt 48oda— ,, 84/ -.34/3- Hi .. -- 9
                    — --- » A .. - t Presses Iibrei— — „-------------„--------- Oblig. CrAdit Ponder
                    Bgyption 8 % - Pos. 814 — „ 815 - Lots Taros. _ _ „----------------— Banque
                    Nationals de Grtoo ... — — , __^ ___ Banqne Industrielle.. LK — Jt ", — } Cassa
                    di 8oonto.. — Pos. 176 — „ 164 — Anglo-American Nile let. 5 } „------ Banqne
                    d'Athknes — Pcs. 120 — „ 120 } Deferred Delta.. — let. 14 } „----- Nungovich
                    Hotels— „ 9 — .,--------- Delta Land 2 — l Egyptian Invest, ft Agenoy Ld....
                    Trust Investment lend Bank Cbaik Padl .......... Butreprises Urbaiues 1S: 122 *
                    „ ---- * ft .. ASSOCIATION DBS C0URT1BB8 BN MARCHANP SB {Service tp/cial)
                    Dtptcux d'ocvkrtork ITVFBPOOL, loh a m AmAriooin Fatnrs : jail.-aoflt: 5.03 „
                    oot-nov.: — 8econde DApflohe, 10h.5 s m. Fatnrs : jniL-ooflt: 5.04 „ oot. nov.:
                    6.03 Troisime DApflohe, 10h.I5 am. Future : juiL-noflt: 5.07 „ oct-nov: 6.06
                    _________ DBRNIBKB HBUKB (Clflture de la Boune KhAdiviale lb. p m ' Coon do
                    FAssociation des Courtiers en Merchandises Ooton F.G.F.Br. Novembre .. TaL IS
                    5'8 k — 21 32 Janvier’. - _ 13 1/2 „ — 17/32 Man - - ...... 13 11/16 „ - 23/32
                    Jaillet- _ _ „ 14 5/32 „------ Aoflt - - - „ 14 9/32 „------ Grain** de ooton
                    N.-D.-J. - P.T. 60 - k----------------- Jaillet— — — „ 58 30/40 „--------------
                    Aoflt............... 59 15/40 „ — 20/40 FmnaBn* - P.T. 95 1/9 k H -f</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
