<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2018-06-27">June 27, 2018</date><gloss>1</gloss></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-06">July 6, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent></bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <head type="sub">No. 7233] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.
                    </head>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
            <div type="item">
                    <p>A LOUEE Chambres meublées, avec ou sans pension, Rue Chérif Pacha, vis-à-vis
                        Bourse Khédiviale, 2e étage, Alexandrie.</p>
                    <p>26196-6 a-2</p>
                    <p>ARABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Shefik,
                        "Egyptian Gazette" offices. 25888-</p>
                    <p>BLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5. £9, No. 7 £11. W.T. Emmens, 99 Rue Attarine,
                        Alexandria, Address, Post Office Box 35.</p>
                    <p>30 6-905a</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH MASTER desires post as tutor during summer holidays. Apply, L.
                        Vigour, English school, Cyprus. 26165-12-10</p>
                    <p>GENTLEMAN wishes furnished room with or without board in an English family in
                        town. Apply, with full particulars, to C.M., P.O.B. 613, Alexandria.
                        26198-3-3</p>
                    <p>HOUSEKEEPER. —German lady wants situation ; speaks Greek and Arabic; prefers
                        a place where she could have her little daughter, age 4, by her. Apply, No.
                        26,197, "Egyptian Gazette” offices. 26197 3-3</p>
                    <p>LOST —Sunday, 2nd inst., on the Ramleh road, Fox-terrier Dog, white, marking
                        black and tan in the face, large black mark on the neck and black saddle,
                        black spot and black tail with white point. Finder rewarded. Buyers warned.
                        Apply to P.O. Box 303, Alexandria. 26,202-3 3</p>
                    <p>LANCASTER HOUSE, Sharia Wabour-el-Moyah, Cairo. Comfortable apartments, with
                        or without board. Terms very reasonable.</p>
                    <p>25599 15a 6 905</p>
                    <p>TO LET, furnished, at Ibrahimieh (Ramleh), splendid villa ; 10 rooms (6
                        bedrooms), drawing-room, etc. ; large umbraged garden 8,000 piks ; electric
                        light, etc, etc. Apply to Mr. Haye, Villa des Roses, Ibrahimieh, near Doctor
                        Cognard, or to the post-office.</p>
                    <p>post-offioe.</p>
                    <p>26147-15-13</p>
                    <p>WANTED Sole Agency for England for agood Cigarette Manufacturer by firm of
                        Cigar Importers with large connection. References exchanged. Apply, Whitaker
                        and Lofthouse, King’s Arcade, Bradford, England.</p>
                    <p>26206<hi rend="bold">-3</hi>-1</p>
                    <p>Calendar of Coming Events  </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.  </p>
                    <p>July.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 6 Windsor Hotel. Orchestra. 6 to</p>
                    <p>11.30 p.m. every day. Mex. Prinea’s Restaurant des Bains.</p>
                    <p>Roumanian orchestra, every afternoon. Sundays, morning. Alhambra. Italian
                        operetta company in <hi rend="italic">Scompartimento Signore Sole.</hi> 9
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Jardin des Variétés, (ex Ciccolani) <hi rend="italic">La Figlia di Madame
                            Angot </hi>9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Eden Theatre. French comedy company. 9.15 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sat. 8 Cricket. A. C. C. <hi rend="italic">v.</hi> E. T. C. Commence 1.30
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Marina. Alexandria Swimming Club. Members meet 4 p.m. British Rifle Club.
                        Practice at Mustapha Range.</p>
                    <p>San Stefano Casino. Small Dance. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sun. 9 San Stefano Casino. Concert 10.30 a.m. and 5 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 12 Khedivial Yacht Club. Regatta. Thurs. 13 A.C.C. grounds. A.C.C. <hi
                            rend="italic">v.</hi> Victoria College. 1.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 14 Alhambra. Celebration of French National Fête.</p>
                    <p>Sat. 15 A.S.C. Skye Meeting.</p>
                    <p>Khedivah Palace Casino. Reunion des Families Society’s Ball.</p>
                    <p>9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.  </p>
                    <p>July.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 6 Theatre des Ambassadeurs. 9 p.m. Theatre des Nouveautés. 9 p.m.
                        Esbekieh Theatre. Italian Comedy Company. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">Fri. </hi>7 <hi rend="bold">Zoological Gardens. Performance
                            by Ghizeh Boys’ Band in afternoon Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
                            British Military Band. 9 to 11 p.m.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">Sat. 8 Credit </hi>
                        <hi rend="bold">Foncier Egyptien Extraordinary General Meeting. 4 p.m.
                        </hi>Tues. <hi rend="bold">11 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British
                            Military Band. 9 to 11</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>THE “POTEMKIN.”  </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">ANOTHER DECLARATION OF WAR.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">SHIP AT THEODOSIA.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Kustendji, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The Russian destroyer "Stremetelni” has arrived, seeking to capture the
                        “Potemkin.” <hi rend="italic">(Reuter.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Sevastopol, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The “Potemkin” has arrived at Theodosia in the Crimea, and requested coal,
                        provisions, and a doctor.</p>
                    <p>The “Pobiedonosets” has joined Admiral Kruger’s squadron. <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Reuter.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">SULINA, </hi>July 5.</p>
                    <p>Another Russian torpedo-boat, manned by officers, has arrived here seeking
                        for the “Potemkin.” <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Better.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Theodosia, July 5<hi rend="bold">.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>The men of the “Potemkin” have re-issued a declaration of war. It is reported
                        that they previously appeared at Akerman and compelled the authorities to
                        furnish coal and provisions. <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Better.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Theodosia, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The “Potemkin” has arrived and has asked for provisions. <hi rend="italic"
                            >(Havas.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>MARRIAGE.</p>
                    <p>RELLE—MUNGAVIN. — at the Cathedral of the Holy Trinity, Gibraltar, on the lst
                        July, by the Venerable the Archdeacon of Gibraltar, Eva Jessie Hyde,
                        daughter of Mr. and Mrs.</p>
                    <p>J. H. MunGavin, Alexandria, to Herman John Relle, of Fayal, Horta,
                        Azores.</p>
                    <p>THURSDAY, JULY 6, 1905.</p>
                    <p>THE “POTEMKIN'S” CRUISE.</p>
                    <p>The “Kniaz Potemkin” continues her cruise and has levied a contribution on
                        the town of Theodosia, while the destroyers sent to pursue her appear to be
                        exploring the Roumanian coast. Admiral Kruger’s squadron has been rejoined
                        by the repentant “Pobiedonosets,” bat we should like to know the exact moral
                        and material condition of his division. Russian official wires explain
                        nothing; the “Kniaz Potemkin” surrendered, so they told us, a few days ago,
                        but there seems to be no doubt that not only did she refuse to haul down the
                        red flag but that the “Pobiedonosets” joined her for a time, forcing Admiral
                        Kruger to steam back to Sevastopol lest a worse thing should happen.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile the rebellious crew of the battleship are steaming about the Black
                        Sea threatening seaports and Russian merchantmen and, so far, evading the
                        destroyers sent in pursuit The situation has been paralleled in South
                        America, and some of our readers may remember the Brazilian naval revolution
                        and the blockade of Rio by the "Melloist" fleet. But in the Brazilian
                        revolution the fleets of neutral Powers were able to safeguard neutral
                        interests and to protect neutral shipping. But the Black Sea is open to only
                        two fleets, the Russian and the Turkish, both disorganised, the one by
                        neglect and the other by revolt, and should the squadron of Admiral Kruger
                        be unable to check the depredations of the “Kniaz Potemkin” and the rebel
                        battleship help herself to coal or provisions at the expense of neutrals,
                        either the Turkish fleet will assume the duties of a policeman, or the
                        Powers may be obliged to send their ironclads up the Dardanelles. The last
                        alternative is the more probable, for a Turkish fleet capable of
                        encountering the redoubtable “Potemkin” could not be made ready for months,
                        but what a blow to diplomacy would be the overthrow of all the arrangements
                        that generations of Foreign Ministers and Chancellors have laboured to
                        secure ! The Sultan’s comments on the situation must be interesting.</p>
                    <p>STRIKE AT PUTILOFF ARSENALS.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, July 5. The workmen of the Government arsenals at Putiloff
                        have joined the strike. <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Better.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, July 5. The Cossacks have killed several of the strikers from
                        the Putiloff works. (<hi rend="italic">Havas.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>SITUATION IN ODESSA.</p>
                    <p>Odessa, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The situation is improving. The work of clearing up the débris has begun. The
                        strikers are returning to their work, and the ships have recommenced
                        loading. The coasting service has been resumed, and many troops have left,
                        though they are kept within easy reach. <hi rend="italic">(R.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>NEW RUSSIAN WAR MINISTER.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, July 5. General Roediger replaces General Sakharoff.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Reuter.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">St. </hi>Petersburg, July 5. General Roediger has been
                        appointed Minister of War. <hi rend="italic">(Havas.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>ITALIAN ROYAL VISIT TO JAPAN.</p>
                    <p>Rome, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The Queen-Dowager of Italy is preparing to visit Japan. <hi rend="italic"
                            >(Reuter.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>GORDON-BENNETT MOTOR RACE.</p>
                    <p>WON BY FRENCHMAN.</p>
                    <p>Clermont Ferrand, July 5. The Frenchman Théry, the winner in 1904, has won
                        the Gordon-Beunnett motor race in the Auvergne course. Two Italians were
                        second and third. The Englishmen were outclassed.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Reuter.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>FRENCH WORKMEN S PENSIONS.</p>
                    <p>Paris, July .5</p>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies has commenced the debate on the Workmen’s Pensions
                        Bill.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="bold">
                            <hi rend="italic">(Havas.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </p>
                </div>    
                
                
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TSAR’S DESIRE FOR PEACE.</p>
                    <p>PROPOSAL FOR IMMEDIATE armistice. </p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, July 5.</p>
                    <p>It is understood that the note of the Government to President Roosevelt
                        pointed out that the selection of Russian representatives indicates the
                        Tsar’s sincere desire for a lasting peace. (<hi rend="italic">Reuter.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Washington, July 5.</p>
                    <p>The Russian proposal for an immediate armistice has been transmitted to
                        Japan, through President Roosevelt. <hi rend="italic">( Reuter.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>RACING.</p>
                    <p>London, July 5.</p>
                    <p>July Stakes. 1, Gorgos ; 2, Alcanzor ; 3, Adamas. <hi rend="italic"
                            >(Reuter.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>HOME CRICKET.</p>
                    <p>London, July 5.</p>
                    <p>Third Test Match, England 295 for 5 wickets. Tyldesley century.
                        Gloucestershire beat Worcestershire by 145 runs.</p>
                    <p>(Later). The Third Test Match has been drawn.</p>
                    <p>Australians 224 for 7 wickets. Noble 62.</p>
                    <p>After an admirable defence the match was drawn at 6.18 p.m. owing to bad
                        light</p>
                    <p>County Championship, Lancashire won 9, lost none, drawn 4; Surrey won 7, lost
                        2, drawn 3 , Sussex won 7, lost 2, drawn 4.</p>
                    <p>Surrey beat Northamptonshire by 9 wickets. Warwickshire beat Essex by 8
                        wickets. <hi rend="italic">(R.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>LOCAL AND GENERAL. </p>
                    <p>Anti-Rabic Institute.—The Sanitary Department is about to construct an
                        Anti-Rabic Institute at Cairo.</p>
                    <p>San Stefano Casino.—On the occasion of the charity performance in the theatre
                        of the Casino, there will be a night fête this evening, with a display of
                        fireworks.</p>
                    <p>Bank of Egypt.—The directors of the Bank of Egypt, Ltd., have declared an
                        interim dividend at the rate of 8 per cent, per annum for the half-year
                        ending 30th June,</p>
                    <p>1905.</p>
                    <p>Norddeutscher Lloyd.—Commencing with the departure of the 26th inst., the
                        sailings of the Norddeutscher Lloyd S.S. “Schleswig” for Marseilles will
                        henceforth take place at 4 p.m., and not at 5 p.m., as hitherto.</p>
                    <p>Narrow Escape.—A Greek, while getting out of a moving train at Sidi-Gaber
                        station, slipped and fell back between two carriages. Luckily for him he
                        dropped clear of the rails and escaped with slight injuries.</p>
                    <p>The Reunion des Familles Society have decided to give the remainder of the
                        open-air balls of the season at the Casino of the Khedivah Palace. The next
                        ball will take place on Saturday, 15th inst., commencing at 9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—18 vessels passed through the Canal on the 3rd inst, of which 11
                        were British, 2 German, 2 Austrian, 1 Norwegian, 2 Dutch. The day’s receipts
                        were frs. 512,425.28, making the total from 1st inst frs. 1,042,084.46.</p>
                    <p>Police School.—Last Tuesday Khalil Effendi Hamdi, Commandant of the Police
                        School at Boulac, presented the 27 pupils of the school who had passed their
                        final examinations with success, to the Adviser to the Minister of the
                        Interior.</p>
                    <p>Stabbing Affray.—One of the crew of the French S.S. “Senegal” stabbed a young
                        native in the abdomen yesterday. The victim was removed to the Government
                        Hospital, while his assailant was arrested and handed over to the French
                        consular authorities.</p>
                    <p>Swords and Triggers. — We are informed that Mr. G. Menasse, Alexandria
                        correspondent of “L’Egypte,” has been challenged to a duel by Mr. K. Zouro,
                        on account of certain remarks in reference to the white slave traffic which
                        appeared in a recent issue of our Cairo contemporary.</p>
                    <p>Settling Days. — Application has been made to the committee of the London
                        Stock Exchange to appoint a special settling day in Egyptian Gold and Gem
                        Syndicate, Limited-- 6,623 Vendors’ shares of £1 each, fully paid (Nos.
                        28,371 to 34,993), and National Bank of Egypt--Further issue of 50,000
                        shares of £10 each.</p>
                    <p>Ministry of Public Instruction.—Professors Gustav and Anders Retzius, of the
                        University of Stockholm, and C. M. Furst and the family of M. Axel Key have
                        kindly offered to present several important scientific works to the library
                        of the School of Medicine at Kasr-el-Aini, Cairo. The Minister of Public
                        Instruction has accepted the generous offer with hearty thanks.</p>
                    <p>PROGRESS IN EGYPT. LORD CROMER'S SPEECH. </p>
                    <p>HIS RELATIONS WITH THE KHEDIVE.</p>
                    <p>(From our own Correspondent.)</p>
                    <p>London, June 29.</p>
                    <p>I have cabled you the principal points of the important speech which Lord
                        Cromer made to-night, when, as the guest of the Worshipful Company of
                        Skinners, he was entertained at a banquet in the Company’s Hall, Dowgate
                        Hill, after having received the honorary freedom of this Worshipful
                        Company.</p>
                    <p>The Master (Mr. G. St. John Roche) was in the chair, supported by, amongst
                        others, the Right Hon. W. C. Gully, M.P., the Earl of Kilmorey, Mr. Robert
                        Spencer, M.P., and others.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer, in the course of his response to the toast of his health,
                        proposed by the Chairman, said : It is not my duty te enlarge on the wider
                        and more general aspects of the agreement with France which was recently so
                        successfully negotiated by Lord Lansdowne, under whom it is my privilege to
                        serve,(cheers)—but I wish to say—and I think I can say it without
                        indiscretion—that it has been an unmixed benefit to all who have to deal
                        with the local affairs of Egypt, to be relieved from the constant friction
                        and annoyance which were the inevitable accompaniment of the state of
                        affairs which existed prior to the signing of that Agreement. (Cheers.) The
                        Worshipful Master has alluded in flattering terms to the part I have taken
                        in the regeneration of Egypt: I could have done nothing whatever without the
                        loyal and persistent co-operation of the Egyptian Government, and whilst I
                        am dealing with the Egyptian Government I take this opportunity of
                        mentioning that the story which has gone the round of the Press, and which
                        the Worshipful Master has repeated, in connection with my representations to
                        the Khedive as to the presence of British troops in Egypt, happens to be a
                        pure myth. No such incident as is alleged ever occurred, and my relations
                        with the Khedive are of the most satisfactory description. (Hear, hear.) I
                        was glad to hear the Master mention the Irrigation Department, because,
                        though it is invidious to mention names, I cannot refrain from alluding to
                        Sir William Garstin, who, by his assistance in connection with the control
                        of the water supply, has raised himself to the rank of one of the greatest
                        hydraulic engineers in this or in any other country.</p>
                    <p>NO NEED FOR HURRY.</p>
                    <p>The Master has spoken of the progress made in Egypt A good deal has been
                        done, but there remains much to do. There are a few conditions which I think
                        it is very desirable to secure if that progress is, as I hope, to be uniform
                        and steady. The first of these conditions is that we should not be in a
                        hurry. (Hear, hear.) Whatever good work has been done in Egypt has been to a
                        very great extent due to the fact that the action of the Government has been
                        deliberate, and that there has been continuity of policy extending now for a
                        long term of years. The second condition, which I hope also may be fulfilled
                        in the future as it has been certainly through several years fulfilled in
                        the past, is that Egyptian affairs shall be kept out of the somewhat
                        dangerous swirl of British party politics. (Cheers). The third condition,
                        which I hope will be fulfilled, is that, whilst every reasonable occasion
                        will be taken to profit by any real aptitude the Egyptians may show for the
                        management of their own affairs, great care and caution will be exercised
                        not to force Western ideas and exotic institutions on the Egyptians
                        themselves before the country is ripe to assimilate those ideas and
                        institutions. (Cheers). The fourth and last condition is that Egypt will
                        continue in the future as in the past, to be governed in the interests of
                        the Egyptians themselves. (Renewed cheers.) That, gentlemen, is a very sound
                        principle—a principle which, I venture to say, applies to other countries
                        besides Egypt. (Laughter and cheers). It is not only a just principle, but
                        one which I venture to think is conducive to the best political and
                        commercial interests of Great Britain itself.</p>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL GOOD MANNERS.</p>
                    <p>As I am speaking in the commercial capital of the world, I would like to say
                        something of commercial affairs in which I take a deep interest, not only
                        because it is my duty to do so, but also because I come of a family which
                        has for many generations been connected with the trade of the City of
                        London. The first remark I have to make is that, if in my new capacity of a
                        skinner I was going to trade in skins in Egypt, the first thing I would do
                        would be to Send out a commercial agent who had good manners, and who knew
                        some language besides his own, and who would find out what sort of skin
                        Egyptian customers wished to buy. (Much laughter.) If I venture to allude to
                        the subject of good manners, it is because it has always appeared to me that
                        good manners are almost as valuable an asset in commercial as in diplomatic
                        affairs. We must remember that we have to compete with the foreigner, not
                        only in respect of quality of goods, but as regards tact, judgment and
                        conciliatory address.</p>
                    <p>LOCAL COMPANY PROMOTION.</p>
                    <p>There is also the subject of finance, to which</p>
                    <p>I desire to allude. Some years ago we were</p>
                    <p>anxious to attract British capital to Egypt. For a long time British
                        capitalists turned a deaf ear. Confidence is a plant of slow growth in the
                        bosom of the investor, but when it once takes root it sometimes grows with
                        almost excessive rapidity, and whereas at the begin</p>
                    <p>ning we suffered from the first disadvantage, we are now suffering from the
                        second. Capital is now flowing from England and other countries rapidly into
                        Egypt, and provided, as is often the case, it is devoted to sound commercial
                        industry it is very welcome ; but we want no mere company mongering.
                        (Cheers.) We do not want companies whose share capital is watered to the
                        extent that all trace of the original spirit has almost entirely
                        disappeared. (Laughter and more cheers.) We shall certainly do our best to
                        resist the invasion of these gentlemen, but when I say we shall do our best
                        I ought to explain that neither the Egyptian nor the British Government can
                        do very much in that direction, nor can they exercise any effective control
                        unless laws and regulations are very stringent If they are not stringent
                        there is reason for fearing, and almost a certainty, that they will be
                        unfavorable to legitimate enterprise, and that commerce will be seriously
                        hampered. The public themselves must be their own principal guardians—(hear,
                        hear)—and those who are asked to invest in companies that are now floated, I
                        would advise to look carefully to facts, and to judge for themselves whether
                        au enterprise is a good one. Th<hi rend="underline">ere especially
                        </hi>would I advise them, in cases where quotations are made from official
                        and other reports, to go to the origin of those reports, and to see whether
                        the conclusions that can be drawn are in fact the conclusions that they are
                        invited to draw by the company promoters. In these circumstances the context
                        is often very important. I make these remarks, not with the view of driving
                        capital away, nor do I make them in condemnation of some companies which are
                        very good, but the British name has hitherto stood very high, and I should
                        be extremely unwilling that that name should be in any degree tarnished.
                        (Cheers.)</p>
                    <p>Lord Kilmorey and Mr. Gully acknowledged the toast of the Houses of
                        Parliament.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Gully described himself as in a state of suspended animation. At present
                        he was of the House of Commons, but not in it. He had to introduce himself,
                        as the gladiator in the arena, ‘ Ave Cæsar, morituri te salutant,” but from
                        information derived from the newspapers he understood that that was the last
                        time he would have the opportunity of responding to the toast of that branch
                        of the Legislature in which he had hitherto sat. (Laughter.)</p>
                    <p>THE LEBANON.</p>
                    <p>A Lebanon correspondent writes :—</p>
                    <p>One cannot help feeling a certain disappointment that the inhabitants of the
                        Leba- non, with all their good qualities, have not succeeded in ruling
                        themselves more successfully. There are some very commendable features in
                        the administration of the Lebanon Government. The roads are well looked
                        after, titles to land are honestly and carefully registered, and public
                        security is far better than in many parts of rural Egypt. But there are
                        certain disagreeable features which I should like to emphasise. Clerical
                        influence is not always an unmixed blessing, and in my opinion the strong
                        Maronite element in the Lebanon is inclined to allow too much political
                        influence to its priestly leaders. Moreover, some of the Emirs are inclined
                        to adopt a ‘family’ policy, claiming for their clans the monopoly of certain
                        posts. At present the disputes between the higher Maronite clergy and the
                        Mutassarif have led to a most deplorable amount of friction ; and while I do
                        not hold a brief for Muzaffer Pasha, who is doubtless a better soldier than
                        he is an administrator, I should like to point out that the Governor’s ideas
                        as to the government of the province are more advanced than those of many of
                        his opponents, and if he has shown too strong a liking for centralisation,
                        and a certain disregarded for public opinion, his opponents are in many
                        oases entirely wedded to the old system of keeping certain posts for members
                        of a certain religion quite irrespective of their abilities or merits,—a
                        system unfortunately sanctified by the constitution of 1860, which has
                        outlived its usefulness.</p>
                    <p>Thus we hear of the case of a sheikh who is not generally supposed to be a
                        shining example of honesty but is being vigorously backed by the clergy for
                        the kaimakamship of, say, the Metn ; we have the officers of the militia
                        forces appointed, not for their tactical ability or technical
                        qualifications, but for their religion. If Captain A. is a Maronite, Captain
                        B. must be a Druse, though he may be incapable of drilling a squad, much
                        less a company ; and this system prevails in almost every department of the
                        Government. That the system involves bribery and corruption goes without
                        saying. Some comment was recently aroused among Syrians residents in Egypt
                        by the case of an amazingly useless member of a Druse clan, who had sat for
                        some years in the Majlis el Idara, and who, finding his term of office
                        drawing to a close, determined to be re-elected. His family considered that,
                        brains or no brains, he had a right to his position ; several of the
                        Maronite members of the Idara had found him so pliable and useful a tool
                        that they resolved to support him. The Governor opposed the appointment, but
                        in vain ; certain venal sheikhs were paid £10 a head, and the incompetent
                        member was returned to the council, to the disgust of the few who realise
                        that such methods of election will never make the Lebanon prosperous or
                        contented, and can only increase the disunion that is still the bane of
                        Syria.</p>
                    <p>SIR F. WINGATE HONORED. COMMEMORATION DAY AT OXFORD. </p>
                    <p>London, June 30.</p>
                    <p>Commemoration Day at Oxford was celebrated yesterday, the proceedings being
                        characterised by much dignity and decorum. The honorary degrees conferred
                        numbered only seven, as compared with 37 last year. The Sirdar, Sir Francis
                        Reginald Wingate, was among those honored with the degree of D.C.L.</p>
                    <p>Although the undergraduates were sparsely represented, the Sheldonian Theatre
                        was crowded, the fair sex being largely in the majority. Few incidents
                        occurred to enliven the proceedings before the arrival of the Vice-
                        Chancellor and the heads of Houses, an organ recital by Dr. Varley Roberts,
                        of Magdalen College, occupying the interval</p>
                    <p>At twelve o’clock, to the strains of the National Anthem, the
                        Vice-Chancellor’s procession enter<hi rend="underline">ed an</hi>d took
                        their seats, and Convocation was formally opened! The procession included
                        the Vice-Chancellor, the Warden of All Souls,’ the Dean of Christ Church,
                        the Warden of New College, the Rector of Exeter, the Provost of Oriel the
                        President of Magdalen, the Senior and Junior Proctors, Sir W. Markby, Dr.
                        Ince, Dr. Bigg, Dr. Driver, Dr. Butty, Dr. Burney, Dr. Dixey, Dr. Driver,
                        Dr. Wilson, Dr. Holdsworth, Dr. R. W. M. Pope, Dr. Whitmarsh, Professor
                        Holland, Professor Esson, Professor Napier, Professor Poulton, Professor
                        Turner. Habitués of the Eicænia in former years will readily appreciate the
                        change which has come over the scene by the feet that the Proctors walked
                        across the theatre and took their seats without a single expression of scorn
                        or discontent, and that the Vice- Chancellor was permitted to open
                        Convocation without any sarcastic references to his false quantities or
                        parts of speech or exhortations to “speak up” and “cut it short.” The
                        recipients of the degrees met with a cordial reception, Major-General
                        Wingate, Governor- General of the Sudan, in general’s uniform, his breast
                        covered with glittering stars and orders, Holman Hunt the artist, painter of
                        the renowned Keble College picture, “Light of the World,” and Paul Sabatier,
                        the French savant securing the heartiest applause.</p>
                    <p>Sir Thomas Raleigh, formerly Reader in English Law, in the absence of Dr.
                        Goody, Regius Professor of Civil Law, presented the recipients of the D.C.L.
                        degree.</p>
                    <p>Sir Francis Wingate was introduced as a distinguished and accomplished public
                        servant, a successful leader in war, who destroyed the power of the Khalifa
                        and restored his captives to their country. Sir Francis was now the chief
                        guardian of peace and leader of subject nations in the arts of peace, he had
                        re-built the cities of the Sudan, provided the people with schools, and
                        brought European science to the aid of the agriculturist. His services to
                        medical science, his exploration of Christian antiquities as far as the
                        border of Abyssinia, and his literary works, had given him additional claims
                        to honor.</p>
                    <p>At the conclusion of the proceedings in the Sheldonian theatre, a numerous
                        and distinguished company was entertained at luncheon at All Souls’ College
                        by the Warden and Fellows, Sir Francisand Lady Wingate being among those
                        present</p>
                    <p>SALVAGE OF THE ‘‘ASSOUAN.”  FINDING OF ADMIRALTY COURT.</p>
                    <p>In the British Admiralty Court on the 28 th ulto. Mr. Justice Bargrave Deane
                        heard a claim by the owners, master, and crew of the Hamburg Amerika liner
                        “Ambria,” for salvage services rendered to the Khedivial mail steamship
                        “Assouan.”</p>
                    <p>It appeared that the “Ambria” found the "Assouan” in the Red Sea on March 9,
                        drifting about with a broken shaft. The disabled vessel had on board 1,000
                        Mecca pilgrims homeward bound from Jeddah. She asked to be taken in tow, and
                        the captain of the “Ambria” agreed to do so, and after towing for three days
                        brought the “Assouan” to safe anchorage in Suez roadstead. The owners of the
                        “Assouan” contended that the towage was of an easy character, and that, with
                        the exception of the broken tail shaft, their vessel was staunch and
                        seaworthy. Hence the Court was asked to fix the sum.</p>
                    <p>His Lordship said that in the experience of the Trinity Masters it was a
                        serious matter to take in tow a ship with a thousand pilgrims on board. The
                        services were well rendered, and he awarded £1,600.</p>
                    <p>THE PLAGUE.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday’s plague bulletin reports two fresh cases and two deaths at
                        Alexandria and one death at Toukh. There are now 22 cases under treatment
                        The cases admitted to hospital in Alexandria were those of a Greek woman
                        living in the Kom el-Nadoura quarter, and a native girl of Abouchoucha,
                        another member of whose family was found dead on the 20th ult. One of the
                        two victims reported as being found dead in to-day’s bulletin is the mother
                        of this girl, while the other was a Sudanese ostler who was found dead in a
                        stable at Moharrem Bey. This man was a cousin of the ostler who was found
                        dead from plague in another stable on the 19th ult.</p>
                    <p>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</p>
                    <p>By kind permission of Lieut.-Col. R. C. C. Cox and officers, 2nd Batt. Royal
                        Inniskilling Fusiliers, the band will perform the following programme in the
                        Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Friday) evening</p>
                    <p>March—Heldenruf—F. Leitmann.</p>
                    <p>Morris Dance—E. German, overture—Rosamunde—Schubert.</p>
                    <p>Concert Polka—Liliputian—M. Brower.</p>
                    <p>(Soloist—Lce.- Cpl. O’Neal.)</p>
                    <p>Selection—Falka— F<hi rend="italic">.</hi> Chassaigne.</p>
                    <p>Walzer— Dream of the Ocean—Gung’l.</p>
                    <p>Fantasia—Voyage in a Troopship--G. Miller.</p>
                    <p>Mazurka—Sabre au Clair—E. Missa.</p>
                    <p>Regimental March.—Khedivial Anthem.</p>
                    <p>God Save the King.</p>
                    <p>E. Webster, Band Sergeant.</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. “Portugal” arrived at Marseilles from
                        Alexandria yesterday morning.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail liner “Fayoum” sailed from Suez yesterday with cargo and
                        passengers for Port Sudan and Suakin.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Britannia” sailed from Malta yesterday evening and is due
                        here on Sunday morning with passengers, mails, and</p>
                    <p>THE S.S. ‘ HELENE RICKMERS.”</p>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Suez, Wednesday.</p>
                    <p>The fourth lighter, which was not towed up to Suez by the tug yesterday, is
                        sailing up by herself, and the whole lot of rioe ex S.S. “Helene Rickmers,”
                        I understand, will be reshipped to destination by the first steamer of the
                        same company. The rice is expected to be in more or less good condition.</p>
                    <p>NOTES FROM PORT SAID. </p>
                    <p>THE “ST. KILDA’S” CREW.</p>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Wednesday.</p>
                    <p>Among the passengers to embark on the P. and O. mail steamer “Egypt,” which
                        left for Marseilles and London last evening, were Mr. Tarrell, local
                        director of Customs, who is replaced, whilst on leave, by Mr. C. Rowlett ;
                        and Captain Jones, of the “St. Kilda.” The remaining twelve men of this
                        ill-feted ship's crew are to leave for home in a day or so.</p>
                    <p>NAVAL NOTES.</p>
                    <p>H.M. first-class cruiser “Amphitrite,” which arrived here from the China
                        Station yesterday early, is to leave for Malta, Gibraltar, and England at 10
                        a.m. to-morrow (Thursday).</p>
                    <p>Launches armed with small quick-firers and practice torpedoes from the
                        “Lancaster” and Suffolk” were out all this morning at target practice.</p>
                    <p>Landing parties of marines from the same vessels were ashore early also and
                        they had an hour’s shooting at a floating target.</p>
                    <p>Class I.</p>
                    <p>Boat Start. Finish. Sailed by </p>
                    <p>1 Minnie 3.30.28 5.06.05 N.W. deCourcy</p>
                    <p>Tier-el Mina 3.33.15 5.07.35 Borg </p>
                    <p>Jenny3.30.28 5.08.00 T. McClure </p>
                    <p>Celtic3.37.20 5.09.38 Capt. Evans</p>
                    <p>Coot 3.34.05 5.10.15 A. S. Preston</p>
                    <p>Banshee 3.46 20 5.11.33 Mr. S. Dorling</p>
                    <p>Leman3.48.25 5.17.00 „ de Planta</p>
                    <p>Sans-Pareille 3.59.15 5.19.11 „ Delaquis</p>
                    <p>Class II.</p>
                    <p>1 Derphil4.00.06 5.35.31 Prince Aziz</p>
                    <p>Shamrock4.16.33 5.43.40 Lieut. Bassett</p>
                    <p>Jessica4.07.18 5.43.52 Grafton Bey</p>
                    <p>Akraba4.10.36 5,44,15 Sagh. Phillips</p>
                    <p>St. George4.22.30 5.46.39 Major Feetham</p>
                    <p>Gumrook 4.19.05 5.47 50 Mr. Macauley</p>
                    <p>Masr 4.20.02 5.48.00 „ Ravelli</p>
                    <p>Calypso 4.27.31 5.50.50 „ O. Werner</p>
                    <p>The wind was rather fresh from the N.W. and just suited the “Minnie,” which
                        carried off the cup in Class I., likewise the “Derphil” in Class II.</p>
                    <p>The "Gumrook” was disqualified in Class II., for fouling the starting flag on
                        the second time round.</p>
                    <p>At the conclusion of the races Mrs. Gould kindly presented the prizes to the
                        winners.</p>
                    <p>The handicap will be again changed next week for the monthly races.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB. </p>
                    <p>The members met, as usual at the breakwater on Saturday last at 4 p.m. The
                        attendance on this occasion was very good, there being no less than 19
                        active members present and four juniors. The afternoon’s meeting opened by a
                        club team race (16 yards) composed as follows. Team A : Messrs. Broscomb,
                        Ecclestone, Grant, Lupton, Potts, and Wood. Team B : Messrs. Borman, Darton,
                        Hemgell, Mace, Webb, and another. The race was very keenly contested by both
                        sides, and resulted in a win for Team B by about 10 yards.</p>
                    <p>A 30-yards dub race for the junior section was then held and ended in an easy
                        win for Master Randall, Master Mitchinson coming in second, closely followed
                        by Master Naser.</p>
                    <p>A water polo match was played off between two teams recruited on the spot,
                        and classed as Teams A and B, Team A carrying the day by 4 goals to one.
                        Team A had one goal cancelled for scoring while touching.</p>
                    <p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL </p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer and Sir Eldon Gorst were present at a meeting of the Committee of
                        Imperial Defence in Whitehall-gardens last week.</p>
                    <p>Mustapha Bey Maher, the Governor of Assouan, had the honor of lunching with
                        her Royal Highness Princess Henry of Battenberg on Thursday week.</p>
                    <p>Corbett Bey was among the passengers by the Khedivial S.S. “Prince Abbas,”
                        which sailed yesterday for Greece and Turkey.</p>
                    <p>Lieut-Col. R. C. C. Cox, 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, has been
                        granted leave of absence on urgent private affairs for two months. </p>
                    <p>Miralai Saad Bey Rifaat has been appointed Commandant of the Sinai.</p>
                    <p>A requiem mass for the repose of the soul of the late E.C. Manuk will be held
                        at St Catherine’s Cathedral on Saturday next at 8.30 a.m. Friends of the
                        Manuk, Gantes, and Vella families are asked to consider this notice as an
                        invitation. </p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr.
                        E. J. Williams, Mr. and Mrs. N. H. Beyts, Mr. E. G. Beyts, Col. and Mrs.
                        Rawnslay, Mr. W. McQueen, Mr. J. Daoud and family, Mr. J. W. Egbert, Maj.
                        Paxton, Miss L. C. Barney, Mr. R. P. Smithard, Mr. E. Purser, Mr. H.G.
                        Finlaison and family, H. Bacoom Bey, Mr. and Mrs. C. H. Rowlatt, Capt. W.
                        Jones, Mlle H. Sinigolli, Mr. A. J. Lowe, Mr. W. Clark, Mr. G. B. Middleton,
                        Mr. J. A. B. Jones, Mr. R. Holt, Hr. N. A Morcom, Mr. P. Smith, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Hook, Miss Eagar.</p>
                    <p>SPORT AND PLAY.</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB. REGATTA</p>
                    <p>The following is the result of yesterday's</p>
                    <p>PASSENGER LISTS. </p>
                    <p>ARRIVALS.</p>
                    <p>Per P. &amp; O. S.S. "Macedonia," arrived at Port Said on Tuesday from
                        Marseilles: Lieut.</p>
                    <p>R. Pigot, Mrs. R. R. Kabalkin, nurse, and 2 infants, Mr. P. Smith, Mr. U. A.
                        Marconi, Mr. W. E. Hosking, Mr. R. Kabalkin, Mr. P. Gadsby, Mr. Ralli, Mrs.
                        Brewster.</p>
                    <p>Per S.S. “Osiris,” arrived at Port Said yesterday from Brindisi: Capt.
                        Sweeny, Baron de Kusel.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot Khedivial “Prince Abbas" partis hier pour Pirée, Smyrna, Metelin,
                        Dardanelle et Constantinople avait à bord :—</p>
                    <p>Aly bey Zulficar et famille, Abdallah bey Abaza et fils, Ahmed bey Emin,
                        Mohamed bey Tewfick Hadki, E. K. Corbett bey, Ibrahim bey Edhem et famille,
                        M. et Mme Nicolas Vicenzidi et famille; M. et Mme P. Stangala, Mme
                        Stiepovich et famille, Mme Ahmed bey Ziver et famille, M. et Mme A.
                        Agostino, institutrice et famille; M. et Mme Jean Zerbini et famille, M. et
                        Mlle George Homsy, Mme C. Migurski et famille, M. et Mme Nicolas Psolekidis
                        et famille, M. et Mme J. Ventura et famille, M. et Mme Frederic Macy, Mohil-
                        din Turc, Pr. Sciaparelli, A. Groutas, A. Compas, R. Barda, F. Botton, A.
                        Studerus, A. Roux de Lusignan, M. Cosadino, C. Xenophon, G. Stangala, G.
                        Silvani, G. Venetocles, N. Chronia, Geo. Polymeris, J. Politimides, A.
                        Dracos, N. Caloyeros, Ibrahim Gad, Hassan Assar, J. Athineos, B. Wexler, M.
                        Orfanos, D. Yoannou, C. Zanis, A Melkonian, D. Geromi, Emin effendi, Mohamed
                        Edhem, H. Calothy, K Pandelides, Ahmed Agha Neghib, E. Brooke; Mahmoud
                        Abou-el- Ela, M. G. Gibara et famille, Mmes Adelgisa Hanem, J. Martin, E. A.
                        Charrel R. Ventura, M. Demirdjian, V. Vlahos, Mme Tarsian et famille, H.
                        Mitzelos, T. Lazzaris, Melek Hanem<hi rend="underline">, Khalifa</hi>
                        Mahmoud Hanem, M. Courtidis, E. Papadopoulos, G. Forani, C. Djamjam, Mlles
                        Sotiropoulos; Galeatzas, Theophanos, Ghiomis, Penzon et 283 passagers de
                        pont.</p>
                    <p>CALENDAR OF THE WEEK.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">(Coptic and Mohamedan.)</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Sun. 2 Peaches and pearl abundant Mon. 3 Day of Assemblage of the Nilometer.
                        Tues. 4 Announcements are made respecting the rise of the Nile.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 8 Avoid relaxing food and drinks.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 6</p>
                    <p>Fri. 7 Locusts die if there are any.</p>
                    <p>Sat. 8 The use of strong perfumes may be</p>
                    <p> discontinued</p>
                </div>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                

                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
