<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-27">January 27, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7108 ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, JANUARY 27, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SITUATION IN RUSSIA. MOVEMENT CHECKED. PROCLAMATION TO WORKMEN. A RUSSIAN CALUMNY. ALLEGED ANGLO-JAPANESE INTRIGUES.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 26.</dateline>
                    <p>By order of the Tsar, General Trepoff and the Minister of l Finance issued
                        issued a proclamation explaining to the workmen that they are being
                        exploited by sell-seeking and evil-disposed persons who nave misled them in
                        a manner rendering the intervention of an armed force inevitable. The
                        workers forget that the Government has always been careful for their needs
                        and is ready now, as always in the past, to listen to the just desires of
                        the people and to satisfy them whenever possible. The workers must, however,
                        assist the Government by the restoration of order, by returning to their
                        work, and by boycotting the inciters of disorder. Their needs are near to
                        the Emperor's Heart as are those of all loyal subjects, Only recently the
                        Emeror ordered a consideration of the question of workemen's insurance, and
                        He Has now directed the Ministry of Finance to draft a law for shortening
                        the hours of labour, and to take measures for making it legally possible lor
                        the working classes to discuss and make known their needs. The Government
                        will protect all those who return to work.</p>
                    <p>The Municipality Has voted by a large majority 2,500 sterling towards the
                        relief of the wounded and the families of the killed. A further 200 has been
                        voted towards the improvement of the ambulance stations, in view of a
                        repetition of the tragedy. This vote was originally coupled with a motion
                        strongly denouncing Sunday's brutanty, which, however, the President refused
                        to accept. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 26.</dateline>
                    <p>The city is resuming its normal aspect. The shops are re-opening. Some troops
                        are being withdrawn, and there is a partial resumption of work. The
                        Government is confident that the movement has been checked, though it is
                        resolved to continue the repressive measures.</p>
                    <p>The police yesterday posted notices in Moscow alleging that the strike
                        movement was due to Anglo-Japanese intrigues and that the strikers were
                        supported by British money.</p>
                    <p>A similar notice was posted at Odessa today.</p>
                    <p>Sir C. Hardinge protested against this calumny. He received assurances that
                        measures would be taken to prevent the repetition</p>
                    <p>of the publication.</p>
                    <p>The British Embassy here is guarded by sentries. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Libau, January 26.</dateline>
                    <p>A party of terrorists are marching through the streets compelling workmen to
                        strike. The telegraph wires have been damaged(Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Helsingfors, January 26.</p>
                    <p>At a demonstration here yesterday evening, the police attacked 5,000 workmen
                        with swords and whips. There were a lew casualties. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN COTTON.</head>
                    <p>SCHEME TO REDUCE ACREAGE.</p>
                    <p>New Orleans, January 26. An influential Southern Cotton Convention here has
                        adopted a scheme reducing the acreage by 25%. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindist Mail will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 3 p.m. on
                            Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fire</head>
                        <p>During the fire, which broke out on the 22nd inst. at Debelchian
                            village, near Kair Zayat, a large number of houses were destroyed, and
                            two women and a child perished in the flames. The damages are estimated
                            at L.E. 890</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>18 vessels passed through the Canal on the 24th inst., of which 8 were
                            British, 4 German, 2 Dutch, 1 Italian, 1 Russian, 1 Austrian, 1 Swedish.
                            The day’s receipts amounted to frs. 515,766.56. The total amount
                            received from 1st to 24th inst. was frs. 8,864,080.96.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Temperance</head>
                        <p>Mr. Samuel Smith, M.P., will, deliver an address on temperance and
                            kindred subjects in the lecture-room of the American Mission, near
                            Shepheard’s Hotel, Cairo, on Saturday evening at 6 o’clock. All are
                            invited to attend.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Royal Visit</head>
                        <p>The arrangements during the stay in Cairo of the Duke and Duchess of
                            Connaught have been placed in the hands of George Nungovich Bey.
                            Nungovich Bey and Mr. Wild were at Abdeen Palace yesterday to receive
                            the distinguished guests on their arrival.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Shepheard’s</head>
                        <p>With regard to Monday’s grand ball at Shepheard’s, we learn that the
                            cotillon will begin at midnight. All the invitations have already been
                            issued, and the management have had to refuse a large number of
                            applications for tickets, so as to obviate a crush. Tables for dinner in
                            the restaurant or grill-room on that night should be ordered beforehand,
                            and only persons provided with invitations will be allowed to book
                            tables.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Local Publication</head>
                        <p>“The Revue d’Egypte et d’Orient,” in its new dress, is a considerable
                            improvement on past numbers and shows that it is more firmiy established
                            than ever among local publications. The January number is brimful of
                            interesting articles written by men whose names are a guarantee of the
                            genuine value of their contributions. We wish our little contemporary
                            continued prosperity, and congratulate its able editors, M.M. Fernand
                            Braun and George Vayssié.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Abbas Helmy Theatre</head>
                        <p>Signora Emma Bellincione, the great Italian opera singer, arrives at
                            Alexandria on Monday next by the Austrian Lloyd steamer and will give a
                            series of live performances at the above theatre. Signora Svincher, who
                            has created such a furore in Cairo by her perfomances at the Verdi
                            Theatre, will also give five representations at this theatre, the season
                            beginning on Tuesday next, when the company comes down from Caire. “La
                            Bellincione," as she is called, brings with her a lew other lights in
                            the operatic world, and an unusual musical treat is in store for
                            Alexandirans. Subscriptions may be booked at Messrs. Montferrato's. The
                            following are the prices fixed for the series of ten performances :
                            Stage boxes, L.E.60 ; first-tier boxes, L.E.30 ; second-tier boxes,
                            L.E.22 1/2 ; orchestra stalls, L.E.3 ; stalls, L.E.2 1/4.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Per S.S. “Seti,” sailed on Wednesday for Manchester :</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Herslolf, Miss Smith, Mr. G. Hill, Mr. J. Townsend, Mr. Amhiotroi and
                        Mr. D. Hanmanol, Mr. J. L. Lonsdale, Mr. and Mrs. Soler and infant, Mr. and
                        Mrs. J. Jones and child.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot “Memfi” de la Cie Florio Rubattino parti hier pour Gènes avait à
                        bord : Mlle Umpbebley, M. O. G. Brooke, M. B. Daniels, Mmes C. et M. Kerker,
                        Mme Mullins, Mme Dairs, M. L. Levin, M. G. Mattei, M. et Mme Pots, M.
                        Vernen, M. et Mme R. Vignal, ing. et Mme Castelli, M. et Mme Perry S. Heath,
                        M. A. P. Andrade, Mlle Ida Rosa, Père Michele, Sœur M. Colomba, M. et Mme E.
                        Pestavino, M. et Mme Gaet. Anza, M. et Mme G. Young, M. et Mme E. V. Kellett
                        et fils, Mme Betty Eugrinie, Sœur M. Agnès, M. F. Salvatori, et 47 passagers
                        de 3me classe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT. ARRIVAL IN CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>THE RECEPTION AT THE STATION</p>
                    <p>At 5:20 p.m. yesterday the vice-regal train. bearing their Royal Highnesses
                        the Duke and Duchess of Connaught, steamed into Cairo station to the sound
                        of salutes of 21 guns from the Citadel and Abbassieh. H.H. the Kbedive and
                        Prince Mohamed Aly, the Karl and Countess of Cromer, the Ministers and
                        Advisers. Maj. General .Slade, C.B., Mrs. Slade, Col.</p>
                    <p>Colville and the principal officers of the Army of Occupation, Lewa Lord
                        Edward Cecil Pasha, Kaiumkain Palmer Bey, and all the officers of the Head
                        Quarters and District Staffs and heads of departments of the Egyptian
                        Army,</p>
                    <p>Miralai Mansheild Pasha, etc., were waiting to receive the Royal visitors,
                        and two guards of honor, composed of 100 N.C.O.’s and men of the 2nd Royal
                        Inniskilling Fusiliers, under Capt. Roe, and 100 N.C.O.’a and men of the
                        16th Egyptian Battalion, with the colours, were drawn up within the
                        station.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive exchanged the most cordial greetings with the Duke and Duchess of
                        Connaught, who both looked very well, and expressed his pleasure at once
                        more meeting them in Cairo. After a similar interchange of courtesies
                        between the Royal visitors and Lord and Lady Cromer, major-general and Mrs.
                        Slade, and the principal members of the group of official and military
                        dignitaries who were assembled on the platform, the Duke of Connaught made a
                        brief inspection of the guards of honor, complimenting the Khedive and
                        Maj.-General Slade on the fine appearance of the troops. The Royal party
                        left the station to the strains of the National Anthem.</p>
                    <p>Thu Khedive and the Duke of Connaught then entered a State carnage and drove
                        towards the Palace, escorted by the Cavalry of the Body Guard, and followed
                        by the Duchess of Connaught, accompanied by Prince Mohamed Aly, and other
                        carriages containing the duel participants in this interesting scene.</p>
                    <p>The streets were lined by large crowds and kept clear by the police, whose
                        arrangements were excellent. British and Egyptian and other national flags
                        were flown everywhere, the white and pale blue of the Hellenic colours being
                        very prominent. The hotel fronts of Shepheard's and the Continental were
                        crowded with residents amd visitors anxious to see the Khedive and his Royal
                        guests, who graciously responded to the salutations that greeted them.</p>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive gave a banquet of 130 covers in honor of the Duke and
                        Duchess of Connaught at Abdeen Palace yesterday evening. Among the guests
                        were the Princes of the Khedive family, H.R.H. Prince Gustav Adult of Sweden
                        and Norway, the Ministers, the Earl and Countess of Cromer, the diplomatic
                        agents, the advisors, the under-secretaries of State, Major General Slade,
                        C.B., the heads of departments, the staff of the British Agency,</p>
                    <p>The Royal party leaves Cairo for up-river this evening under the arrangements
                        of the Sleeping Car Company.</p>
                    <p>A very large crowd is expected to attend the races on the K. S. C. grounds
                        this afternoon which will be graced by the presence of H.H. the Khedive and
                        his Royal guests.</p>
                    <p>We omitted to mention in our account of the Duke and Duchess of Connaught's
                        arrival at Alexandria yesterday that Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of
                        Alexandria, presented a line bouquet to her Royal Highness as she landed at
                        the Arsenal wharf, and on reaching the kiosque Miss .Muriel Murray, the
                        pretty little laughter of M Murray Bey, Inspector of lighthouses, presented
                        a most artistic bouquet. It was composed of purple violets, white lilac,
                        lilies of the valley. The Duchess was very pleased with these gifts and
                        asked for the mother of the girl to be presented to her.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive proceeded to Abdeen Palace yesterday morning amd attended
                        midday-prayers at the Mosque of Saidna Hussein.</p>
                    <p>The receipts from the fetes on the occasion of the recent anniversary of the
                        Khedive’s accession amounted to L.E. 893, mills. 770 and the expenses to LE
                        841, mills. 400, which leaves a surplus of L.E. 52, mills. 370 to be carried
                        over for next year's fete.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army">
                    <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                    <p>The following officers are to take part in a staff rule ; -Major E. R. O.
                        Ludlow, D.A.A.G, Major A. H. C Kenney Herbert, D.A.Q.M.G., Captain T. E
                        Bayley, Staff Captain, Captain W H. Rotheram, R.E., Captain F. F. Duffus,
                        A.S.C., and an officer, R.A.M.C. They will proceed by a train leaving Cairo
                        at 6 a.m. on Tuesday, 31st inst., and each officer will be accompanied by
                        his servant, his horse, and one syce.</p>
                    <p>38 N C O.'s and men of the 2nd Battalion Rife Brigade, under charge of an
                        officer, will arrive at Cairo by the 7:20 am train on the 31st inst., from
                        Khartoum, to await passage home.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Menes" sailed from Malta yesterday morning and is due hero on
                        Sunday evening with passengers, mails, and general</p>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S, "Salazie” arrived at Alexandria from
                        Marseilles at 4 a.m. yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The Cunard S.S. “Tyria" arrived at Liverpool yesterday morning and the 8.8.
                        "Veria” sailed yesterday afternoon for Liverpool with a fall cargo,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT’S BANKING DEVELOPMENTS</head>
                    <p>COMPTOIR D’ESCOMPTE</p>
                    <p>The great French banking house, the Comptoir National d’Escompte, has secured
                        the Palazzo Antoniades in Cherif Pasha street, Alexandria, as premises for
                        its agency here. This is the only private house standing by itself in Cherif
                        Pasha-street and it will be a magnificent site for a bank. It has been
                        leased to the Comptoir National d Escompte for a period of ten years at a
                        rental of L.E. 2,000 a year, including the garden and all the appurtenances
                        of this fine mansion. The bank has also obtained the option of renewing the
                        lease at the end of the term.</p>
                    <p>The bank intends to build on to thé garden at the back of the building and to
                        turn the house into large and commodious banking premises. Mr. Llewelyn, who
                        is to represent the bank as general manager for Egypt, will stay at
                        Alexandria permanently and will take charge of all - the bank's operations
                        in this country.</p>
                    <p>The building will bo transformed immediately and the bank will be fully
                        installed early in the coming summer.</p>
                    <p>The Comptoir National d'Escompte has a capital of 150,000,000 francs, fully
                        paid up, m 300,000 shares of 500 francs each. It is a Société Anonyme, which
                        took over the business of the Comptoir d'Esoompte de Paris, which went into
                        liquidation in 1889. The duration of the company is 50 years from 1st May,
                        1889. The business of the Banque de Dépôts et Comptes Courants was taken
                        over from July, 1892, for 30,000 fully-paid shares. It is one of the
                        greatest banks in France and on a par with the Credit Lyonnais. The
                        directors anticipate a rapid development of business in Egypt. An agency in
                        Cairo will be opened next year and it is probable that the bank will also
                        extend its sphere of operations to the Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN INVESTMENT AND AGENCY.</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Investment and Agency, Limited, yesterday received the final
                        list of subscribers in Egypt and the officials of the company are hard at
                        work getting the allotments ready.</p>
                    <p>Over 2,450 applications for more than 3,250,000 shares were received here,
                        and wo learn that the public will get 2-5% on most applications for above
                        500. Below that figure, and in a few other cases, letters of regret will
                        have to be sent. These it is hoped to post to-night or to-morrow. The
                        allotment letters will follow next week.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DELTA LIGHT RAILWAY CO.</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Delta Light Railways (Limited) announces that coupons tor
                        accumulated arrears of dividend on the 5 and 1/2 per Cent Cumulative
                        Preference Shares to the 30th September, 1904, are now ready for issue.
                        Share warrants to bearer and registered certificates must be lodged either
                        at the offices of the company, 211, Gresham House, Old Broad-street, Loudon,
                        or with the National Bank of Egypt, Cairo or Alexandria, for endorsement
                        shares Nos. 1 to 63,324 are entitled to Coupon F for 14s. per share, less
                        income tax ; shares Nos. 63,325 to 74,437 are entitled to Coupon G for 1s.
                        4d. per share, less income tax , and Shares Nos. 74,438 to 85.540 are
                        entitled to Coupon H for Is. per share, loss income tax</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT.</head>
                    <p>No trace whatever has been discovered of either the money stolen from the
                        Mahmal caravan or the thieves, and it has transpired that though it was the
                        intention of the authorities to couple the specie van and the van containing
                        the guard some ingenious person interposed no less than 16 other trucks.
                        Under these circumstances it is hard to say whether the theft took place at
                        Abbassieh or during the journey, and it has not been established that the
                        specie van was under observation during the whole of the time that it was
                        standing on the line at Abbassieh.</p>
                    <p>We should have thought that the simplest precaution would have been the most
                        effectual, namely, to put a couple of soldiers with loaded rifles into the
                        specie van ; but this plan, which is universally employed in India, never
                        seems to have struck the responsible authorities. Meantime, £8,000 have
                        disappeared, and as far as we can see this will figure in next year’s
                        accounts under the heading of "Unforeseen Expenditure."</p>
                    <p>provincial councils.</p>
                    <p>By Khédivial decree the Provincial Councils of Assiout, Keneh, Girgeh, Beni
                        Souef, and Ghizeh are to meet on Sunday next at 9 am. at the Mondiriehs to
                        take the oath and to elect delegates to the Legislative Council.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN ALEXANDRIA SCANDAL.</head>
                    <p>This morning, the case brought by Mr. Ninci, commercial manager of the
                        Sucreries et do la Raffinerie d’Egypte Company at Alexandria, against his
                        wife, Mrs. Olga Ninci, nee Coustantinides, came on for hearing before the
                        Italian Consular Court at Alexandria Mr. Ninci is asking for a separation
                        from his wile on account of her adultery with Judge Constantine Dimaras,
                        President of the Hellenic Consular Tribunal at Alexandria</p>
                    <p>Mr. Ninci was represented by Maître Mario Colucci and the lady by Maître
                        Guidotti. The hearing of the case was adjourned this morning for a week on
                        the application of Maitre Guidotti on behalf of Mrs. Ninci.</p>
                    <p>Judge Dimaras left Alexandria this morning or the Pineus by the Russian
                        packet. News has been received from Athens that the</p>
                    <p>judge has been deprived of his official position,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The ex-Emprees Eugénie, travelling incognito as the Countess de Pierrefond,.
                        arrived at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, last night from Port Said.</p>
                    <p>The suite of the ex-Bmpress is composed of ten persons.</p>
                    <p>The ex Empress Eugénie before she left Paris lor Egypt declared in an
                        interview : Life is hard, but the great thing is courage. I once used the
                        phrase, ‘U n’y a rien comme l’audace,’ under very trying circumstances, and
                        it gave me courage. Be not cast down. Adversities will come, but what of
                        them. Give courage to others, it is better than money. I am speaking of
                        moral courage, which is a great and lofty virtue. The ethical ride of life
                        should be developed, and then all would be happier. Courage springs from
                        love, and love has been called the greatest thing on</p>
                    <p>Sir Thomas Lipton arrived at the Savoy Hotel last night.</p>
                    <p>Among other arrivals at the savoy yesterday evening were Mlle, de Bassano,
                        Comte Primoli, Comte Chary, and M. Pietri.</p>
                    <p>The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire, who are now in Cairo, expect to be away
                        from England for two months.</p>
                    <p>The Duke of Devonshire was presented to the Khedive at Abdeen Palace
                        yesterday by Lord Cromer.</p>
                    <p>Prince Aria el-Dowlat Riza Khan Danish, Persian Ambassador to the Sublime
                        Ottoman Porte, left Alexandria to-day for Constantinople by the Russian
                        packet</p>
                    <p>The Countess of Lovelace and Sir Edmund Veruey arrived at Port Said yesterday
                        from Malta by the S.S- "City of Corinth," and left by the evening train for
                        Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Earl and Countess Howe, with Sir Edward and lady Colebrooke, have left London
                        for Egypt and a trip up the Nile m the guests of Sir Ernest Cassel.</p>
                    <p>The Hon. John Ward will accompany Sir Ernest Cassel’s party to Egypt- Mr.
                        Ward, who is now on the Riviera, will join the party at Marseilles
                        to-day.</p>
                    <p>The latest arrivals at Shepheard's Hotel include Sir Robert and Lady Pullar,
                        Major-General Campbell-Fraser, Baron Pidoll, Baron Pycke de Peteghem,
                        Vicomte de Sapucahy, Oberslentuaut and Mrs. von der Plawitz, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Beeckmann, Mrs. James W. Byrue and family, Mr. and Mrs. Basuardo and family,
                        Mr and Mrs. Marshall P. Wilder, Mr. and Mrs. de Thierry, Baron Drasche,
                        Baron Voi-rensky, Baron de Wecker, etc.</p>
                    <p>Many large dinner parties are to be given belote the concert, organised by
                        the Comité des Fetes, takes place at the Savoy this evening. Next Saturday’s
                        dance promises to be exceptionally successful, nearly all the tables in the
                        restaurant being already engaged.</p>
                    <p>The Hon. J. W. Riddle, American Diplomats Agent, entertained a party to
                        dinner at the Savoy Restaurant yesterday evening, the guests including M.
                        aud Mme. Maskens, Fabricius Pasha and Mme. Fabricius, the Hon. F G Morgan,
                        M. and Mme. de Gorostarzu, M aud Mme. Maximoff, Comte Amvabeue, M. and Mme.
                        de Hoeltzke,Comte and Comtesse Antoine de Zogheb, Judge and Mrs. Tuck. Mr.
                        and Mrs. Linooln Tangye have left Maxstoke Castle, Warwickshire, en route
                        1er Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Ronald Greville has come to Egypt with her father, Mr. McEwan, who has
                        been seriously ill. He was ordered to a warmer climate, and Mrs. Greville at
                        once cancelled all her engagements in order to accompany him.</p>
                    <p>Mr. George Faber, M.P. for York city, has arrived in Egypt for a stay of some
                        duration, and hopes to return to England to resume his</p>
                    <p>Parliamentary duties in March. He is accompanied by his wife, who was the
                        youngest daughter of Sir Frederick Graham of Nethberby and Lady Jane
                        Hermione, daughter of the 12th Duke of Somerset.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesOther">
                    <head>Notes from Keneh.</head>
                    <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                    <p>Keneh, January 21. Mr. Clapcott, the newly-appointed English judge for
                        Assiout Tribunel, has been delegated by the Ministry of Justice for Keneh
                        Tribunal. He is expected to arrive here tomorrow His visits here will he on
                        Sunday and Monday of every week, during the hearing of criminal cases ; on
                        the other days of the week he will be resident at Luxor.</p>
                    <p>A new branch of the National Bank is to be opened here. The agent, who is an
                        Englishman, has arrived here for the purpose of finding suitable
                        premises.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COMMISSION MUNICIPALE</head>
                    <p>(Communication Officilelle.) Commission municipale seat réunie le 85 janvier
                        1905, à 4 h. p.m, sous U présideoœ de S.B. Mahmoud pacha Sidky.</p>
                    <p>Présents : MM. Amb. A. Ralli, vice-président, Ahmed bey Byoub, Ahmed bey
                        Yehia, Hussein bey Riez, A. Cumbo, L Esooffier, P. Fender), P. Glymenopoulo,
                        Maasour bey Youseff, A. de Menasce, 0. Rothaker, A. Padoa bey, Dr J. Schiess
                        bey, T. Suzxarini, Dr G. Valensia, G. Zervudachi, G. Zouro, membres, W. P.
                        Cha-taway, administrateur, 1. Sedky bey, secrétaire.</p>
                    <p>En ouvrant la séanoe, le Président dit qu’il est assuré d’être l’interprète
                        des sentiments de l’Assemblée entière eu exprimant ses regrets pour le
                        départ do LL. EK Michalla et</p>
                    <p>Said bey.</p>
                    <p>Lu services éminents rendus à l'institution municipale par ces deux hauts
                        fonctionnaires et la sympathie qui s’attache à leur personne, auraient avivé
                        davantage ces regrets, si la Commission u’éprouvait en même temps du plaisir
                        pour l’avancement acoordé à l’un et la retraite honorable qui couronne la
                        carrière de l’autre. Lour souvenir restera toujours vivant dans cette
                        Assemblée, qui leur transmet k oette occasion ses vœux les plus
                        sincères.</p>
                    <p>Après quelques paroles du Vice-Président, l’Assemblée entière s’associe aux
                        sentiments exprimés.</p>
                    <p>la procès-verbaux de la Commission des 30 novembre, 3 et 21 décembre 1904,
                        sont approuvés.</p>
                    <p>Mention est laite dé l’envoi à tous les membres du procès-verbal de la
                        Délégation du 3 janvier 1905.</p>
                    <p>Au aqjet de cette communication, un éohango d idées a lieu relativement à la
                        question du ooutrôle par la Municipalité de la Compagnie du chemin de fer de
                        Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Cette question est renvoyée à l’étude du Comité du Contentieux.</p>
                    <p>Communication est donnée d’une lettre de S.K. le Ministre do l’Intérieur du
                        18 janvier 1905 inlormant qu’il approuve le budget de la Muqffcipalité pour
                        l’exercioe 1905.</p>
                    <p>Lecture est également donnée d’une lettre du 21 janvier 1905 de SJL le
                        Ministre de l’inté-neur informant que dan» sou opinion, la ques* Uon de la
                        rage doit faire l’objet d’une réglementation générale, et ceci afin d’éviter
                        que sur uue question qui intéresse le pays tout entier, il puisse y avoir
                        une règlementation différente à Alexandrie et dan» les autres villes. C’est
                        dans oet ordre d’idées que 8.E. le Ministre a dès A présent demandé au
                        Comité do Contentieux d’élaborer sur les chions et la prévention de la rage
                        un projet de règlement qui serait applicable A toute l’Egypte.</p>
                    <p>11 estime qu’il ne saurait dono sanctionner la décision municipale mai* U g
                        plaisir A féliciter la Municipalité poor son initiative en cette matière
                        importante et pour la contribution que ses travaux apportent A l’étude de la
                        queauou par le Gouvernement.</p>
                    <p>La Commission oonsidérant l’urgence qu’il y a dans la circonstance A adopter
                        des mesures efficaces contre la propagation de la rage, décide d’iusister
                        auprès du Gouvernement pour qu’il veuille bien sanctionner le projet de
                        règlement qu elle lui a soumis.</p>
                    <p>Dès que le Gouvernement aura promulgué son règlement, la Municipalité pourra
                        ajouter, s’il y a lieu, A celui qu’elle a déjA élaboré, toutes les
                        dispositions nouvelles pour mettre en harmonie les deux règlementations.</p>
                    <p>Communication est ensuite donnée d’une lettre du 22 Juin de S.K le Ministre
                        de Fin teneur, informant qu’il consent A oe que la Municipalité prenne
                        possession d’un espace de terrain do 45 mètres de profondeur sur 173 da
                        longueur, du domaine de l’hOpital indigène, en laçade de la rue d’Allemagne,
                        pour être trans-tormé en parc.</p>
                    <p>La Commission remercie le Gouvernement ainsi que M. le Dr Schiess Bey
                        promoteur de cette proposition.</p>
                    <p>Vu la lettre du 18 janvier de S.E le Ministre des Finances et la
                        correspondance échangée avec F Administration des'chemins de fer, au . sujet
                        de l’élargissement du pont dn Gabbari, la Commission émet un avis favorable
                        A la contribution de la Municipalité dans lee dépenses nécessitées par oe
                        travail, mais oomme a oette question se rattachent des questions
                        d’alignement et d’expropriation des routes accédant au dit pont, la
                        Commission, avant de prendre une décision définitive, prie les membres de
                        l’Assemblée représentant le Commerce d’Exportation, de se rendre compte de
                        l’importance dos expropriations éventuelles et d’en faire rapport a la
                        Commission.</p>
                    <p>La Commission prend dbnnaissanoe d’une lettre de M. André, ingéuieur
                        paysagiste, professeur A l’école d’horticulture de Versailles pour l’art des
                        jardins offrant ses services pour l’élaboration d’un projet d’ensemble pour
                        les parcs de la ville, sans engagement de la part de la Municipalité.</p>
                    <p>L’Assemblée accepte cette proposition. Communication est donnée d’un état
                        préliminaire dos oomptes de l’année 1904, accusant un solde disponible de
                        L.B. 31,197.</p>
                    <p>Cet état sera suivi ultérieurement des développements qu’il oomporte.</p>
                    <p>LÀ Commission approuve les propositions du Comité dos fiuauoea au sujet du
                        classement dn personnel.</p>
                    <p>Elle adopte A ce sqjet la manière de voir dti Comité en oe qui oonoerne
                        l’amélioration du système de retraite du personnel municipal, la suppression
                        des indemnités fixes de déplacement, l’interdiction aux ingénieurs de la
                        Municipalité d’accepter des occupations au dehors pour oompte des tiers.</p>
                    <p>La Commission porte lee appointements de MM. Plot bey et Breocia,
                        respectivement A LK 480 et 480 par an.</p>
                    <p>Une question relative aux membres provisoires de la Délégation, sera réglée A
                        l’oooaeicra de l’élaboration du règlement intérieur.</p>
                    <p>La Commission approuve un état d’estimation des exoédents et emprises
                        nécessaires Dour le redoneaent dm voies publiques.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
