<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Riley Ouellette</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-03">October 3, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-19">April 19, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, APRIL 19, 1905. </head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. ALLEGED BREACH OF FRANCES NEUTRALITY JAPANESE PRESS
                        COMMENTS </head>
                    <p>Tokio,April 18</p>
                    <p>The prolonged stay of the Baltic Fleet in Kamaranh Bay is causing protests
                        here, as it, involves a breach of French neutrality. The Japanese comment
                        upon the stay of Baltic Fleet at Kamaranh in the most severe manner. The
                        “Asahi” charges France with deliberately concealing the presence of the
                        Baltic Fleet. The “Ji Ji” declares that the russians are simply using
                        Kamaranh as a naval base and that Japan must ask Great Britains co-operation
                        under her alliances. (R) </p>
                    <p>Paris,April 18</p>
                    <p>The “temps” demands the proofs that france has violated her neutrality and
                        declares that the baltic fleet at Madagascar was never within the three-mile
                        limit, and nothing shows that Rodjestvensky is less careful in Indo China.
                        (Reuter) </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>Japanese Domestic Loan</head>

                    <p>To be issued on 1st may </p>
                    <p>Tokio, April 18 </p>
                    <p>The Japense domestic loan of __ will be issued on the 1st of may (reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POLAND. ESTABLISHMENT OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</head>
                    <p>Warsaw,April 18</p>
                    <p>The Government General of Poland has summoned a conference with a view to the
                        establishment of a system of local government in the rural district of
                        Poland similar to the Russian Zemstoves. It is announced that Governments
                        considering the question of allowing the Polish language to be used in
                        official transactions (Rueter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GRAND DUKE SERGIUSS ASSASSIN CONDEMNED TO DEATH</head>

                    <p>Moscow, April 18</p>
                    <p>Koliach, the assassin of the Grand Duke Sergius has been condemned to death.
                        He declared that he was a prisoner of civil war and not a criminal (reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL CRUISE STAY AT ALGIERS PROLONGED </head>
                    <p>Algiers, April 18</p>
                    <p>The King of England has decided to prolong his stay here. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COLLAPSE OF ITALIAN STRIKE CONDEMNED BY SOCIALISTS </head>
                    <p>Rome, April 18</p>
                    <p>The Italian railway strike has collapsed. Even the socialist leaders
                        condemned it (R.) </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LIMOGES STRIKE. QUIET NOW RESTORED. </head>
                    <p>Paris, April 18.</p>
                    <p>The porcelain strikers at Limoges attempted to storm the prison in order to
                        release their comrades. They erected barricades to prevent the troops
                        interfering. The troops repeatedly-charged the men, but were driven back by
                        bail of stones. Finally, some of the soldiers tired without receiving
                        orders, and several strikers were killed and wounded. The barricades were
                        eventually carried’.(Reuter) </p>
                    <p>Limonges, April 18. </p>
                    <p>Quiet has been restored. It is. confirmed that there were two killed and
                        eight wounded among the workmen, while seven officers and 60 troops were
                        injured with various projectiles.(Havas) </p>
                    <p>Paris, April 18.</p>
                    <p>Chamber of Deputies.- M. Rouvier and M. Etienne, while regretting the
                        occurrences at Limoges, stated that the government fired without receiving
                        orders, after sixty of them had been injured. The Chamber passed by 422
                        votes against 59 an order of the day of sympathy with the victims and
                        confidence in the Government to put down the conflict. (Havas.) </p>
                    <p>Paris, April 18. </p>
                    <p>Seven officers and 63 soldiers were wounded at Limoges. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Windsor Pharmacy</head>
                    <p>Kasr-el-Nil Square, CAIRO. BEST CHEMICAL PRODUCTS. English and Foreign
                        Prescriptions carefully prepared by Certified Chemists. ALWAYS IN STOCK
                        LARCE ASSORTMENT OF ENGLISH PROPRIETARY ARTICLES &amp; SPECIALITIES </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Holidays. — On Good Friday and Easter Monday the banks will be closed and
                        business will- be suspended on the Bourse.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Alexandria Police. — Captain Favoro, matnour of the Custom-house caracol, has
                        ben transferred to Minet-el-Bassal kiss CeMlastal kism </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Tantah Fair- The Mouled at Tantah has been a great success up to now, and by
                        yesterday 50,000 people had come into the town by railway. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kamranh Bay, where the Russian fleet has been staying, is off the coast of
                        Annam, just beneath the fifth degree of latitude north of the Equator. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Port Police will shortly be detached from the Potts and Lighthouses
                        Administration, and will be placed under the Alexandria Gouvernorat. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Popular University.— A lecture will be given this evening at 9:15 on Auguste
                        Comte et la Philosophie Positive,” by MM. G. Dumani and R. Canivet. Entrance
                        is free </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <p>San Stefano Casino is now open for the season. The hotel will be opened on
                        the last Saturday of this month, and the club dances will commence in the
                        middle of May. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Khartoum Cotton.—The cotton plantations in the neighbourhood of Khartoum have
                        produced a crop, of 2,200 cantars which is above the estimated crop, which
                        was put at 1,200 contars. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fatal Accident-A native labourer was run over and killed by a ballast train
                        at Gabbari to-day. The train ran over the man's chest. It was not before
                        some time had elapsed that bis body was removed to hospital </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Rodah Property- The Director General of the Wakfs has submitted to the
                        Superior Council of that Administration the protests of the heirs of Aly
                        Pasha Cherif against the sale of the property at Rodah to Messrs. Zervudachi
                        &amp; Co. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Suez Canal.On tho 15th and 16th inst. 23 vessels passed through the Canal, 16
                        of which were British, 1 French, 1 German, 1 Italian, 1 Austrian. The
                        receipts for the two days were frs. 663,466.08, making the total from the
                        1st lint. frs. 5,142,020.62. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A Journalistic Case. -Judgment by consent has been given in H.B.M’s Consular
                        Court at Cairo in a case brought by Mr. William Houghton against the editor
                        of a Cairo daily newspaper in favor of tho plaintiff for £27 odd, for
                        contributions supplied by Mr. William Houghton, and published in the
                        newspaper in question. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Missing National Bank Notes, which disappeared between Cairo and Ghirgeh
                        some days ago, are still untraced. The Post Office official, who gave tho
                        receipt at Cairo, has been placed under arrest. The G.P.O. consider that tho
                        public should in future always insure value contained letters and packages,
                        so as to avoid giving temptation to the postal employés. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Attempted Suicide—An Italian, aged 56 living in Attarin street, Alexandria,
                        attempted to commit suicide yesterday by discharging the contents of a
                        pistol into his right ear. Although he inflicted a dangerous wound he did
                        not expire, and was removed to hospital, whore he lies in a critical
                        condition. Want of work was the motive which drove him to commit the rash
                        act. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Marsa Matrough —The commission selected by the Legislative Conned in order to
                        discuss with the Government the scheme for drawing up some administrative
                        regulations in regard to Marsa Matrough, was received on Monday by the
                        President of the Council of Ministers. A few modifications in the
                        regulations which are considered necessary wore proposed. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Hellenic Assizes.—Only six cases, of thefts and attempted homicide, will come
                        before the uprooting sitting of the Hellenic Assize court at Alexandria. The
                        case of the Cretan Menegakis, who is charged with the murder of bhis
                        compatriot Zagaki, at the Café des Pyramides, will not be heard at this
                        sitting, as the judicial enquiry into the affair is not yet terminated, and
                        the dossier has to be sent to Athens. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>aster at Ramleh- Ramleh this charming seaside resort with its beautiful
                        surroundings, will have many visitors during the Easter holidays. Besides
                        the number of tourists staying at the Beau-Rivage, many applications for
                        accommodation have been received at this hotel, and the management is
                        offering specially reduced terms to residents and tourists who wish to pass
                        Easter near tho sea, where beautiful spring weather prevails at present.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALDERSON'S CARDENS, BULKELEY.</head>
                    <p>EVERY SATURDAY AT 5 P.M. A grand Variety entertainment will be given by the
                        Royal TOOKEY FAMILY and other Artists. </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PYRAMIDS AND SPHINX. MR COVINGTON’S EXPLORATIONS. INTERESTING
                        DISCOVERY.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Covington, who iS at present at work on tho Great Pyramid, has relocated
                        the exterior end of the King’SChamber south air channel discovered by Col.
                        Howard-Vyse in 1837. The original discoverer made no arrangements for
                        keeping the aperture permanently open, and it has in consequence, become
                        choked by débris and sand falling from above Were tills air channel, with
                        those of the well shafts, kept clear, the oppressive beat of the interior
                        passages of the Great Pyramid would be much abated, and a temperature of
                        under 70% degrees secured. To keep the passage clear Mr. Covington proposes
                        to place a sheet-iron funnel 30 inches-long and nine inches square at the
                        exterior aperture of the air channel. This will keep débris stones, etc,
                        from finding their way into the passage, which is only 9 inches square and'
                        therefore blocks easily. Mr. Covington is also at work in the hope of coming
                        across the external outlet of the' Queen's Chamber, south air channel. The
                        interior end of the passage was only discovered by Weyman-Dickson in 1872,
                        after he had chiseled through 5 inches of stone. Manifestly this end of the
                        passage had not been carried through and the pass channel may have no outlet
                        on the exterior of the Pyramid. It was, of course, not boxed, but allowed
                        for in the building of the successive courses. Professor Flinders Petrie
                        suggested that its issue is to be looked fur at the 85th course, but Mr.
                        Covington has had to give up the search, alter fruitlessly exploring a
                        radius of 35 feet round the spot suggested. During his search be made -a
                        discovery of some interest, and we give an extract Dorn the finder’s report
                        addressed to Professor Maspero :— "Ou Friday last, while searching for the
                        undiscovered exterior end of the Queen's Chamber south air channel, I found
                        embedded in the hardened débris on the 84th course of the Great Pyramid,
                        directly below the outer end of the King’s Chamber south air channel, two
                        fragments (counterparts) of a triangular-shaped high-grade limestone, which
                        originally measured some 17 + 16 +10} inches, two edges being bevelled at an
                        angle of 71 degrees and the other at about 50 to 75 degrees. Deeply incised
                        in thé dressed surface was the full tenth part of an 18-inch diameter
                        circle. The stones, from,' 2 to 2 inches thick, had been let into the
                        pryamid casing atoue probably for astronomical purposes. The reverse side
                        and the bevelled edges retained small patches of bufi-culourod cement." The
                        finder adds that in two respects the find may be considered important : with
                        the exception of the inscription mentioned by Herodotus, this is the only
                        record of any stone-bearing characters of any kind being found on the face
                        of tho Pyramid. This is the only known stone that has been let in to the
                        Pyramid casing. Mr. Covington hopes that the undiscovered air passage exit
                        may turn up on the 76th coursé It runs up from tho Queens Chamber at its
                        start at an angle of 37 degrees, which should bring it out at this
                        point—always supposing that the angle does not alter. Considerable interest
                        is being taken in the clearing of the Sphinx, and a meeting of the committee
                        formed for this purpose will probably be called about the end of the month
                        to go into, some questions of detail and to appoint executive and finance
                        committees. We learn that, if approached on this subject by the responsible
                        authorities, the Prisons Department will agree to supply the services of one
                        or two hundred able-bodied tenants of theirs who would, of course, receive a
                        small wage from the Excavation Committee. Instoad of carrying the trench
                        loading from the paws of the Sphinx to the cultivation due East, it is to be
                        taken S.E to avoid the destruction of personal property, and to avoid a
                        large sand hummock which promised groat difficulties. This course will
                        enable the excavators to complete the work at a cost below the original
                        estimate of LE 4,000. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>

                    <p>The Khedive spent yesterday at Koubbeh Palace. His Highness will hold his
                        last reception in Cairo at Abdeen Palace on Monday, May 1. His Highness has
                        signed the decree conferring,the Grand Cordon of tho Modjidieh on Hatrari
                        Pasha. The Khédivial ordinance appointing Youssef Pasha Zia Chief A. D. C.,
                        Lewa Moharrein Pasha 1st A. D. C., and Watson Pasha A. D. C. to his Highness
                        was signed on Monday. Ahmed Pasha Zeky will remain Grand Master on
                        Ceremonies to the Khedive. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

                    <p>The S.S. "Kaffir Prince," from Antwerp, left Malta on Tuesday and is due here
                        on Saturday next, with passengers and general cargo. The "City of Oxford,”
                        of the Papayanni Line, left Liverpool yesterday and is due here about the
                        2nd proxo. The Cunard S.S. “Cypria” will arrive here from Fiume on 24th
                        inst. , and will immediately begin loading cargo for Liverpool and American
                        ports. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PLACE HOTEL,</head>

                    <p>Open all the year round,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN REFUGEES’ RETURN</head>

                    <p>Ship’s Decks Crowded. (From our Correspondent). Suez, Monday. Yesterday
                        afternoon the Hamburg-Amerika liner "Andalusia” chartered by the Russian
                        Government, arrived at Sues from Shanghai with 800 Russian refugees from
                        Port Arthur and other Far Eastern towns. The "Andalusia” entered the Canal
                        in tin evening bound to Odessa, and her decks were so crowded with men,
                        women, and children, that the majority of the deck passengers wore sleeping
                        on long cone chairs, while the first and second-class was quite full. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW WAR SECRETARY</head>

                    <p>Lewa Lord Edward Cecil Pasha has been appointed Under Secretary of State for
                        War in place of Sir Edward Zohrab Pasha, retired. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="councilMinisters"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>

                    <p>On Monday the Council of Ministers agreed to grant L.E 100 to the committee
                        formed at Alexandria, for the suppression of the “white slave” traffic, and
                        L E. 600 to enable the over-head telegraph wires at the Kasr el-Nil Bridge
                        to be replaced by a line laid under the waters of the Nile. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MATARIEH CONCESSION. </head>
                    <p>The concession agreed on in theory for the laying of thé new Matarieh line
                        provides that the speed of the trams is to be, from Cairo to Gbamra, that of
                        the ordinary tramcar, from Gbamra to the terminus, a much higher speed will
                        be allowed. It is stated that the Government will cede to tho company an
                        area of 20,000 kilometers between the Matarieh railway line and the old Suez
                        road, at the price of £1 per feddan. Not more than one-sixth of this land is
                        to be built on, the remainder being kept clear for the benefit of the public
                        health. The houses to be built are not to be sold by the company, but merely
                        lot to tenants. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HAGAR-NAWATIEH BRIDGE. </head>
                    <p>The bridges on the Egyptian Railway Administration's system have always been
                        a great source of trouble and expense, and the difficulties which the
                        Administration has had to face from this cause have been enormous. The Nile
                        bridges at Embabeh, Benha, and Kafr Zayat have now been placed in a fairly
                        good condition, but the bridge over tho Mah-moudieh Canal at Hagar-Nawatieh
                        has recently given rise to considerable apprehension and anxiety. The fault
                        appears to be due to the fact that the steel was not properly tested at
                        first. The bridge was entirely reconstructed a year ago, and totally new one
                        being put up. Lately some of the longitudinals connecting the girders showed
                        signs of cracking, and the Administration has had to replace them by new
                        ones. It is believed that the bridge will now be able to stand the strain of
                        the traffic with safety. The Administration has in the person of M. Husson a
                        very capable bridge engineer, and he ought to be given a free hand to
                        undertake everything necessary for the safety of the bridges throughout the
                        Administrations system. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST &amp; INVESTMENT. </head>
                    <p>We are authorized by the general manager of the Egyptian Trust and
                        Investment, Limited, to state that the excess cheques in respect to
                        applications marked 1 to 500, Alexandria, will bé ready at the office of the
                        company, 6 Rue de l'Ancienne Bourse, on and after Thursday, 20th inst,
                        between the hours of 9 and 12 a.m. The applicants must present their
                        receipts duly filled up with the amounts due to them, and it is also
                        necessary that they present at the same time their allotment letters as a
                        proof of identification. The first batch of letters of allotment and regret
                        for Cairo have been posted to-day. The allotment of shares in this company
                        is being dealt with as expeditiously as possible, and the company is
                        endeavoring to satisfy all parties. All the claims of the small capitalists
                        have been considered, and generally speaking their interests have been
                        carefully looked after. This has caused a very good impression for, As a
                        rule, this class of person receives very little consideration in allotments.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN PROPRIETARY, LIMITED. Registered April 4. Capital, £10,000 in £1
                        shares. Object, to acquire, develop, turn to account, sell, dispose of or
                        otherwise deal with mines, mining workings and claims, alluvial ground, or
                        any interests in Egypt Or elsewhere; prospect and explore mines and ground
                        opposed to obtain minerals or precious stones, and to carry on the general
                        business of miners, metallurgists, concessionnaires, owners of forests and
                        robber plantations, timber out-ten, timber and lumber merchants, &amp;. No
                        initial public issue. Table A mainly applies. Registered office : 19 and 21,
                        Queen Victoria-street, London, E.C. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable in Alexandria. Facing the sea Central
                        position Central position. Under English management 11-11-904 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesAssiout">
                    <head>NOTES FROM ASSIOUT.</head>

                    <head>AMERICAN MISSION SCHOOL</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent)</byline>
                    <dateline>Assiout, April 12</dateline>
                    <p>A few days ago a very interesting musical and literary entertainment took
                        place at the American College. About three hundred people attended, and it
                        proved a great success. It may be here remarked that the entertainment was
                        carried through wholly by the students themselves. It contained songs by
                        some ladies invited for this purpose, pianoforte solos and duets, quartettes
                        and declamations given by Students. One or two minor details might be
                        brought to the notice of the president of the school. Some of the boys
                        appear before the public 'in galabiehs and somewhat unclean. True it is,
                        some of them are poor, but it does not cost much, to have them dressed in
                        uniforms, even at the expense of the school itself. Again, some of the
                        declamations given were of a kind completely useless for the student; he
                        loses a lot of time in learning a long story by heart, to recite it before a
                        number of people, without adding to his store of information or bettering
                        his school life. The time spent in such things might be usefully employed in
                        studying lessons or learning something practical. But on the whole, thanks
                        are due to the managers of this school perhaps things will go better in the
                        future. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOMETHING MORE ABOUT CRIME </head>
                    <p>The Court of Assiout delivered one more death sentence on Monday. A certain
                        Bekhit Has-saiieio, from Aghanna (Tabta), murdered, a few months ago, the
                        omdeh of his village, in the hope of his (the murderer’s) nephew taking his
                        place. He was arrested and was condemned yesterday. The way in which the
                        criminal carried out his intention Was horrible. He slew the victim with a
                        knife before sunset, in a place about 100 metres from the village, and after
                        killing him, cut his fingers and stabbed his dead body in nine different
                        place. This death sentence is the fourth of its kind passed by tho Assiout
                        Court since 1st March. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXECUTIONS.</head>
                    <p>The death penalty is carried out now, according to the new regulations, in
                        the precincts of the prison. People merely hear of them, and I really think
                        that the old system of public executions is more effective. The fellah has
                        not yet arrived at that stage of civilization where he suffered much moral
                        pain. He needs something to strike his sensesin order that they may be
                        affected, and I feel certain that if these four sentences were carried but
                        publicly in Assiout, a very long time would pass without one hearing of such
                        crimes being committed. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW JUDGES</head>

                    <p>Owing to the increase of crimes presented to the Assiout Court, three more
                        judges have been appointed to our bench, via, Mohamed Bey Dorwich, Mustapha
                        Bey Beheri, and Mr. Charles Blackstone Clapcott; the latter, having come
                        recently from England, has an interpreter, Abdel Rauf Zaki Effeudi. Three
                        more criminal sittings have been added, and thus we have now five sittings a
                        week instead of two. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY. </head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                        <p>The first cricket match of the season at Alexandria will be played on the
                            A.C.C. grounds on Saturday next, 22nd inst, between the A. C. C. and the
                            2nd R. Berks. Regitment, Play will commence at 1.30 p.m. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB. </head>
                        <p>Members are hereby notified that the polo ground will be under water on
                            the 20th and 21st inst </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Per S.S. “Hohenzollern, left Alexandria for Marseilles today Mr. E Almaggiar,
                        Mr. Askari, Mr. W. Ivon Bcutivegni, Captain Comm. Fritx da Chine, Mr. Th. R.
                        and Miss Clay, Mme. Howe Davis, Dr. and Mme. Detwiler, Miss Fritze, Mme.
                        Gaudy, Comte de Galarza Santa Clara, Mr. Rudolf Geigy Merian, Mr. Gustav
                        Gericke, Mr. and Mrs. Bladworth Hardie, Miss Hardie,. Dr. and Mme. J.
                        Kochenburger, Mr. Rodolf Koritxky, Miss Johanna Kneisel, Directeur Alb.
                        Kœchlin Hoffmann, Mr. Allen Lewis, General and Mrs. Fred. Lance, Captain
                        Lance, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Mond, Misses Mond, Mrs. E Mariotti, Mrs. and Mias
                        Moore, Mr. Maurice MacMillan, Mr. MacMillan jr., Mrs. Juhn Attwood Matthews,
                        Mr. S. Manuel, Mr. Max Mailer, Mr. Predecki, Miss M. M. Plum, Mr. van der
                        Ploeg, Mrs. Richir, Airs. Ritter, Mrs. Ella Schulie, Mrs. General-director
                        Schmoll, Consul Leopold Strabo, Mist Grote Strobe, Mrs. Seligman, Mr.
                        Steuerrat Sebittuy, Mr. Emil Sano, Miss Rathe Su-droezka, Mrs. Thomas, Mr.
                        and Mrs. A. L Wright, Mrs. M. Young, Miss Yonng, Lt CoL I.I. Harrison, Mr.
                        Browne,Commandant General Wacuez, Mr. Strati, Miss Harley, Mr. Habert Rick,
                        Mr. I Aitken, Mr. W. Lenme, Mr. 0. Straub, Mrs. and Mme Daloey. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <head>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSNER BEER</head><!-- lacking rest of ad -->
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>H.I.M, the Sultan has been graciously leased to confer the Order of the
                        Iftikhar on HH Prince Mohammed Aly,brother of the khedive. </p>
                    <p>Mme de Martino has been appointed lady-in-waiting to H.H the Khedivah
                        Brig-General Bullock C.B returned to Cairo yesterday from Alexandria. Mr.
                        Mihran Khan Kalifalan Persian Consul at Alexandria arrived from Marseilles
                        yesterday by the Messageries Maritimes steamer. Canon Ward is leaving
                        Alexandria for Jerusalem on Friday, 28th inst. He will preach at St. George
                        Collegiate Church on the following Sunday. Mrs. Chastaway asks us to state
                        that she has been obliged to postpone her garden and children’s party from
                        the 28th inst. until Friday, May 5. The River Club dinner given in Shepards
                        Garden last night was well attended among those present being the Hon. A.J
                        Davey Sir John Rogers Messrs R. W. Stout Shakour Bey J. Maudaley, R.E Stone,
                        H.S Phillpotts H.H Antony, G.Bigga F.P Watson , H. As </p>
                </div>



                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN INSTITUTION FOR CAIRO</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of The Egyptian Gazette Sir.—I am pleased to see from the
                        letters of "No Surrender" and "Anti-Bigot" that there are some people whose’
                        minds are able to grasp the fact that narrow minded fanaticism is not
                        Christianity nor the spirit of bigotry the "same mind that was in Christ
                        Jesus." I was tempted to exclaim "It is enough. I even I only am left..and
                        they seek my lyfe to take it away." Alter long residence to Cairo I confirm
                        all that was said in the 'Mosquito Net”’ of Saturday last, and could add
                        a.lot more that was not said. If any man think there was an exaggeration let
                        him put himself under my guidance, and without police escort, I will show
                        him things which will make him a sadder and a wiser man. I will let Him see
                        sights which will freeze the very marrow of his bones, and yet I will show
                        him nothing which is not sought after earnestly by thousuds of young men in
                        this city, no number of Englishment being on the list There is a Trinity of
                        Evil at work, Drink, Gambling ud Impurity, and of these three, the last is
                        the worst Unless the Social Evil in Cairo is changed, it will continue to
                        grow until the city be ravaged by an epidemic to which the Plague at London
                        will be nothing What then are we going to do? Are we going to sit down
                        quitely and watch the triumph of the evil ine? I beg pardon, I mean) I for
                        one am not. As long as I have a voice to raise, and an oppurtinty to raise
                        it, people shall hear, whether they will hear, or whether they will
                        forbear,their duty to the thousands of young men, yes and the thousands of
                        unfortunate women, who are to be found on the sstreets of cairo at any time
                        after dark. I speak to you, my brothers, For a silent voiceless cry From the
                        streets of of Egypt's cities Goes up to god on high. By the love ye bear
                        your mothers. Your sisters of your wives, I bid you sheild the honor Of
                        other women's lives If all who are ready to help on the work of forming an
                        institute for young men at Cairo will send me a card at my residence, No.9,
                        Sharia Soliman Pasha, we may be able to unite and do something more useful
                        than carry on a wordy war with our friends-I am,etc. Henry C. Sims Cairo,
                        April 18.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>BULLETIN DB LA BOURSE (Aukm-ïfri à midi d limit) Le marohé est absolument
                        sanj affanrea “&amp;* réalisations, les fêtes ' et one position ’de U place
                        excessivement chargée oontribnut'à faire fléchir les oours, , , ■ La' baisse
                        est générale : L’Agrioole tombe k 18 1/i,, la Béhérai 48, U Daïra à 28 ik la
                        DelU Light k U 1/16 et la Ramleh Railway à 8 1/8. . ... -j Voilà poor les
                        grosses valeara ; les attires ne •ont pas plus favorisées : en Markets on
                        fléchit à 28/6, en 8alt &amp; Soda à 66/Ctn Investment k 2 1/8. u-H La
                        Bourse sera fermée k partir de demain jnsqn'à lundi proqbain
                        inolosivement.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
