<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-10">November 10, 2016</date><gloss>1</gloss></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-07-07/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-07">Friday, July 7, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent></bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/mode/1up">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, FRIDAY, JULY 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.
                    </head>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/page/n1/mode/1up" status="incomplete">
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>NOTICE. </head>
                    <p>During the absence on leave of Mr. R. Snelling, Editor and Manager, "Egyptian
                        Gazette," Mr. Philip P. Graves will act as Editor and Manager of the
                        "Egyptian Gazette" and is authorised to sign all cheques, receipts etc.,
                        addressed to the "Egyptian Gazette."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH TRADE IN EGYPT. </head>
                    <p>Mr. Freeman's report on the trade and commerce of Alexandria for 1904, just
                        issued, is highly interesting reading, more especially for those who are
                        perplexed by the fact that British trade seems to be gradually losing the
                        largest share of Egyptian imports. The wonderful prosperity of Egypt is, we
                        believe, better realised on the Continent than at home, and the Continental
                        manufacturer and merchant are naturally eager to make the most of so
                        tempting a market. There are openings without number for trade in Egypt, but
                        if British manufacturers are to find their way into these openings they must
                        have agents on the spot and send more and better trained commercial
                        travellers. Local requirements must be carefully studied and learned, to get
                        a market. To hold it, regular visits at fixed intervals are necessary. Mr.
                        Freeman gives us an illustration of these points which we quote:-- "The
                        agents at Alexandria of a British firm dealing in carpenters' and
                        blacksmiths' tools, and also in Sheffield <cb n="6"/>goods in general, wrote
                        to this Consulate as follows : 'The difficulty with our principals arises
                        from the fact that the native does not use the same tools as the British
                        workman. Many modifications and additions have consequently to be made so as
                        to adapt the tools to what is required on our markets. If it were a question
                        of a few articles only, the difficulty could easily be overcome by sending
                        home samples, but as there are a thousand and probably more lines that have
                        to be attended to you will easily understand how impossible it is for an
                        agent who is neither a carpenter nor a blacksmith to send them all the
                        particulars they want......The British firms do not take the trouble or care
                        to incur the expense of sending out competent men to see what others are
                        doing.' "</p>
                    <p>Not only do our firms not send out enough competent men, but, if we are to
                        take up the hint dropped in Lord Cromer's recent speech, they sometimes send
                        ill-mannered representatives. Speaking on the subject, Lord Cromer remarked
                        that "we have to compete with the foreigner not only in respect of quality
                        of goods but as regards tact, judgment, and conciliatory address." In fact,
                        the British commercial traveller in Egypt must be a linguist and something
                        of a diplomatist, if he is to succeed, while his employer must abandon his
                        highly conservative attitude or lose ground to his foreign rivals. If we
                        take the case of credit we discover at once that the foreigner allowing six
                        months is far more likely to succeed in getting orders than the Briton who
                        usually allows one month and rarely more than three. It is hopeless to
                        struggle against the conditions of trade in Egypt, and firms that refuse to
                        give long credit are likely enough in the long run to fail to maintain
                        themselves in the market. Our imported articles are as a rule well-finished
                        and of a high class, our firms have a good reputation, and our travellers
                        are, as a rule, well paid, and yet we fail to gain ground because British
                        manufacturers will no more believe their "man on the spot'' than the British
                        public will believe an expert.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> THE "POTEMKIN." <lb/> INHABITANTS OF THEODOSIA PANIC-STRICKEN. <lb/>
                            MUTINEERS SHOT. </head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Theodosia, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The mutineers summoned the authorities on board, and demanded 500
                                tons of coal, provisions and tobacco, within 24 hours ; otherwise
                                the town will be bombarded. They requested the Mayor to distribute
                                to the inhabitants proclamations demanding the cessation of the war
                                and the convocation of the Zemstvos, and exhorting the people to
                                join the revolution. The inhabitants are panic-stricken, and are
                                fleeing from the town. The municipality has decided to deliver the
                                provisions, but not the coal, as there is none in the town. <hi
                                    rend="italic">(Reuter.)</hi>
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Theodosia, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The majority of the inhabitants have left, believing that the
                                "Potemkin" would bombard the town. The Sevastopol fleet has left to
                                attack the "Potemkin." (Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Theodosia, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The authorities have removed the population and only the troops and
                                the police remain. A boat from the "Potemkin," approaching the shore
                                this morning, was received by infantry fire and two other crew were
                                killed. The 'Potemkin" then fired a shell over the town, but without
                                doing any damage, and withdrew to the offing. Yesterday she
                                overhauled a Russian merchantman and took off her cargo of cattle,
                                provisions, and money. The Black Sea trade is paralyzed. ( Reuter.)
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. Petersburg, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Sixty-seven of the ringleaders of the "Pobiedonosets" have been
                                removed to the prison at Kertch ; it is believed that they will be
                                shot. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ODESSA, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Forty-five of the mutineers of the "Pobiedonosets" have been shot.
                                (Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> THE PEACE COMMISSION. <lb/>MIKADO'S FAREWELL TO
                            PLENIPOTENTIARIES.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The Mikado gave a farewell lunch to Baron Kamoura and the staff of
                                the Peace Commission. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The Mikado has bidden good bye to the plenipotentiaries who are to
                                negotiate for peace. (Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> NEW JAPANESE LOAN. </head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>London, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Great Britain, the United States, and Germany each make up
                                £10,000,000 of the new Japanese loan which is issued at 90, at 4 1/2
                                %, to run for 30 years. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SOCIALISM IN GERMANY. A FRENCH "UNDESIRABLE."</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Berlin, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The Government has forbidden the French Socialist Deputy M. Jaurès to
                                lecture jn Berlin upon the international duties of Socialists with
                                reference to war, on the 9th inst;, on the ground that the German
                                Social Democrats would utilise the occasion ( to advance their
                                antinational efforts. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Paris, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Prince Radolin has informed M. Rouvier that Germany declines to have
                                M. Jaurès at the Berlin Conference. (Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOUNDERING OF French SUBMARINE.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Bizerta, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>A French submarine with 13 on board has foundered in the lake here.
                                (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Ferryville, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The submarine "Farfadet" has sunk with 13 hands. Attempts at rescue
                                are being made. </p>
                            <p>(Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>UNITED STATES. MR. HAY'S SUCCESSOR.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Washington, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Mr. Root, formerly Secretary of War, succeeds Mr. Hay. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GORDON-BENNETT RACE. CUP TO BE RETURNED TO DÇNOR.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Paris, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The cup will be returned to Mr. Gordon-Bennett, owing to the decision
                                of the 28th June of the Automobile Club of Franoe to no longer take
                                part in the contests. England is the only country besides France,
                                whose three competitors completed the course. ( Reuter.) = V"""</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HENLEY REGATTA.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Henley, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>Grand Challenge Cup. The Leander beat the Sport Nautique of Ghent by
                                2A lengths. </p>
                            <p>Diamond Sculls. Kelley beat Blackstaffe easily. Time 8 minutes and 10
                                seconds, which is a record. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RACING.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>London, July 6.</dateline>
                            <p>The Princess of Wales Stakes. 1, St. Denis ; , Exchequer ; 3,
                                Lancashire. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="nativePress">
                    <head>NATIVE PRESS OPINIONS. LORD CROMER'S SPEECH.</head>
                    <p>In discussing Lord Cromer's speech, "Al Moayad" remarks that the better the
                        relations between Abdeen and Buckingham Palace, the better for Egypt, and
                        that the attitude of the extremists, whose idea of patriotism is a
                        systematic opposition to all that has to do with the Occupation, is
                        brainless and even opposed to the principles of the Koran. With Lord
                        Cromer's four conditions the "Moayad" expresses its agreement subject to one
                        or two reservations. While admitting that a direct control of Egyptian
                        affairs by Parliament would injure Egypt, it remarks that Parliament must
                        never lose its control of what are, after all, its agents in Egypt, and must
                        be able to check any abuse of their powers. In this connection, it is
                        earnestly to be desired that some means existed of bringing the Egyptian
                        point of view before Parliament as clearly as Lord Cromer's point of view is
                        set forth in the Blue-books. The caution in the introduction of Western
                        ideas must not be exaggerated, for Egypt has made great strides, and
                        finally, while there is no question of Lord Cromer's sincere devotion to the
                        good of Egypt, many of his projects have been diverted from their end by
                        those charged to carry them out. </p>
                    <p>"Al Lewa" expresses its disagreement with "Al Moayad's" views. Opposition to
                        the British Occupation is an absolute necessity, and it is strange that ' Al
                        Moayad,''''after 14 years in opposition, should abandon its policy and
                        support Lord Cromer's views. The opponents of the Occupation are the only
                        veritable patriots. If Lord Cromer's wishes for the welfare of the Egyptian
                        people are sincere, he should permit them to occupy many of the important
                        positions now reserved for Englishmen, and reduce the expenses caused by the
                        Occupation. The Egyptians were the first civilised race in the history of
                        the world and are to-day as capable of assimilating modern civilisation as
                        the Japanese or the English themselves. The future will show their capacity
                        beyond dispute. </p>
                    <p>A Cabinet Council.will be held to-morrow ât San Stefano under the presidency
                        of <persName>H. E. Fakhry Pasha</persName>, Acting Regent. </p>
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Mousky district of Cairo during
                        to-morrow night and at daylight on Sunday, will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                    <p>Ras el-Bar.—A temporary post office for all branches of the service,
                        specie-packets excepted, has been opened at Ras el-Bar, near Da-mietta, for
                        the bathing sèà«Qn. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL,</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Double Execution at Alexandria.</head>
                        <p>—<persName>El Sayed Ali Selim</persName> and <persName>Ramadan
                                Mnrsi</persName>, who murdered a female egg-seller at Souk ElBprsim,
                            will be executed at Hadra priaon on Moniky, 10th inst. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>—Yesterday's bulletin records two cases, one of which was /atad, at
                            Alexandria. \ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>—8 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th inst., of which 3 were
                            British, 2 German, 1 Ottoman, 1 French, 1 Dutch. The day's receipts were
                            fra. 226,420.69, making the total from the 1st inst. frsl 1,267,505.15.
                            * </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Plague Precautions.</head>
                        <p>—The medical officer in charge of the Labbane quarter has ordered a
                            cordon to be drawn round two houses where deaths have occurred which are
                            believed to be directly due to bubonic plagnè. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hashish Smuggling.</head>
                        <p>— A Greek subject, named <persName>Nicolas Aasimacopoulos</persName>, was
                            arrested this morning while attempting to smuggle four torbas of
                            hashish, which were wrapped round his legs, through the gates- of the
                            Custom house. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>'Quis Custodies Ipsos Custodes V</head>
                        <p>—The secret police arrested <persName>Constable Alexandrello</persName>,
                            of the City Police, at 6 a.m. to-day on disembarking from the S.S.
                            "Athens." This man was implicated in the recent shooting affray in
                            Sisters-street. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                        <p>—<persName>El Kaimakam Herbert Bey</persName>, Assistant Adjutant
                            General, Recruiting Department, will take over command of the Cairo
                            District from <persName>El Miralai Matchett Bey</persName>, who
                            proceeded to Khartoum on temporary duty yesterday. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Dramatic Performance.</head>
                        <p>^- The Ernesto" Rossi dramatic clnb will give a performance at the
                            Pyramids Theatre on the 12th inst. of an Italian version of Bisson's
                            comedy Les Surprises du Divorcé. The caste is a strong one and the
                            performance should meet with thé usual, success. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ramleh Railway Crossings.</head>
                        <p>—It appears that automobiles and carriages are frequently driven at great
                            speed over tnlf level crossinj on the Ramleh Railway, especially at
                            Bulkeley, which renders the precautions taken by the company valueless,
                            notwithstanding the special watchmen placed on duty at these crossings.
                            The dangers to which automobilists and carriage drivers expose
                            themselves are most serious, as with this exaggerated speed it is
                            certain that more often than not the watchmen have hardly time to signal
                            to them before they are on the line. Consequently, we are asked by the
                            company to appeal to the public, when driving over these crossings, to
                            slacken speed in order to avoid any chance of accident. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>«RAID HOTEL ISKHARi, ÀLSXAKDBI4. ••* MU BAY, WINE INCLUDED' }» f ARISTON
                        AERATED WATERS Guaranteed Distilled. ALEXANDRIA : I mrtlrItfAL!?.?.!,. » ■
                        7. Em 4.1. Pert* I "Su," Kiulï.'ÏÇ',</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p><persName>Dr. Rucker-Jenisoh</persName>, German Diplomatic Agent, will leave
                        Cairo for San Stefano on Sunday. </p>
                    <p><persName>Judge Bond</persName>, vice-president of the Native Court of
                        Appeal, has left for Zurich. </p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. II. Boyle</persName>, Oriental Secretary to Lord Cromer, left
                        yesterday by the Rubattino boat for Europe. </p>
                    <p><persName>Count von Wedel</persName>, First Secretary at the German
                        Diplomatic Agency, is expected hack in Cairo on Monday or Tuesday next. </p>
                    <p><persName>Abdallah Bey Sfqr</persName> leaves for Italy to-day. At Rome he
                        will meet the Maronite Patriarch, whose yisit to Europe has given rise to a
                        variety of conjectures. </p>
                    <p><persName>Major B. W. Longhurst, R.A.M.C.</persName>, has been granted an
                        extension of leave from July 14 to January*18,1906. </p>
                    <p><persName>M. Skinder</persName> has been appointed architect the Egyptian
                        Land and Q^ral Trust. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SYRIAN PROTESTANT COLLEGE. 36th ANNUAL COMMENCEMENT EXERCISES.</head>
                    <byline> ( From a Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <dateline>Beyrout, July 2.</dateline>
                    <p>-For over three decades the Syrian Protestant College stood, as it were, on
                        an eminence as a beacoYof knowledge shedding a growing light on Syria, and
                        in its later phases of development it has' plainly become one of the most
                        potent educational factors in the Near East. One has but to glance at the
                        latest edition of its prospectuses, of Which à judicious distribution is
                        annual'y made, to realise the magnitude of its infiuen o and the scope of
                        its field of action. This magnifioent institution recruits its army.of about
                        * 700 stadents from various countries. Its radius of power extends from
                        Armenia in the East to Greece and the Ionian Isles in the West, and from
                        Asia Minor in the down to Egypt in the South. But ils influence has been
                        mostly felt in Egypt, directly through the preponderant number 6Î seekers
                        for knowledge that the Land of ' the haraohs has always supplied, and
                        indirectly but no less mightily through the Syrian settlers who constitute a
                        strong intellectual element in Egyptian life, and who, under the strong,
                        capable, and judioious guidance of British rulers, are contributing largely
                        to the progress of the country. Therefore any event of public character in
                        this birthplace of learning should not fail to appeal to the interest of the
                        readers of the "Gazette." </p>
                    <p>The commencement exercises this year began on Saturday, 24th June, ten days
                        earlier than the usual and traditional time. This has been determined by the
                        early arrival of the Imperial Medical Commission from Constantinople.
                        Although the exercises commenced on Saturday yet they may be considered to
                        have been publicly inaugurated by the Baccalaureate service on Sunday, when
                        President Howard Bliss delivered his annual valedictory and exhortatory
                        address to the medical and pharmaceutical graduates. The scene was, as it
                        may easily be imagined, one calculated to call forth deep aud stirring
                        emotions and inspire thoughts of the noblest kind, and the young President's
                        fiery eloquence rose splendidly to the occasion. The meeting was well
                        attended by students and many of the public. The blessing was fitly given by
                        the old President Emeritus, whose appearance in public functions at the
                        college is still inspiring and recalls to the hearts of older students happy
                        memories of the godd old days. </p>
                    <p>The exercises closed on Wednesday with the ceremony of thé distribution of
                        prizes And diplomas. The principal and striking féature of that day was the
                        processional march. At Ada Dodge Hall the procession, consisting of the old
                        graduates, the faculty, and the staff of teachers, formed* and proceeded to
                        the Memorial Hall at 3.30 p m. preceded by the American Consul and the
                        Imperial Medical Commission. The President and members of the Faculty wore
                        their "academic gowns, and as it marched forth with measured step and took
                        ito-feeats on the platform in the Memorial Hall* the procession presented a
                        sight of unusual solemnity. </p>
                    <p>The closing event was a delightful entertainment on Wednesday evening at the
                        President's, Marquand House, wound up by a series of hilarious and comic
                        songs, lustily sung by a part of the American staff of teachers. The
                        entertainment is given principally in honor of the Imperial Medical
                        Commission, composed this year of <persName>General Mahmoud Hakki
                            Pasha</persName>, a distinguished officer, <persName>Colonel Ahmed rehmi
                            Bey</persName>, and <persName>Major Escret Roushen Bey</persName>. The
                        reception wa3 held in the president's class-room, a hall of spacious
                        dimensions, but which, owing to the large crowd, could afford only standing
                        room. This, coupled with the orrid heat of June, made it particularly
                        ncomfortable to the invités, and called forth uggestioiis from some of them
                        for an enlargement of the hall, which would not be inadvisable considering
                        the growing importance of the' college. Bat the welcome was so hearty, and
                        there was such a general air of conviviality, that the heat and other
                        little, discomforts were forgotten. Besides, to those blessed with a sense
                        of hnmonr and that rare power of selfdetachment, there wag afforded a rich
                        fund of /amusement by the presentation of the ijhtés to the Imperial
                        Commission. This distinguished body was victimised by a presentation of
                        almost all the large crowd of Quests, and for about half an hour there was
                        something like a pantomimic show of a fFe of ladies and gedtlemen coming
                        forward with lifferent degrees of grace and awkwardness to hake hands with*
                        the three commissioners, who cut curious figures, repeating with lutomatic
                        sameness the stiff, jerky, and deep German bow in reply to each
                        introduction. After the ordeal they withdrew to the cooler recesses of the
                        garden on which the hall opens, to indulge in timely refreshments and the
                        necessary accompaniment of the fragrant weed. </p>
                    <p>These entertainments form a cheerful ending for the graduates of a year of
                        hard study, wakeful anxieties, and stirring emotions, and no doubt
                        they-procure the hospitable President and his charming wife many a farewell
                        word of blessing from the grateful pupils who are to face the hard realities
                        of life. </p>
                    <p>I had almost forgotten to add that 28 medical students were presented to the
                        Commission for the final examination. Of these one did not complete his
                        examination, one failed to pass, 36 took the oath of office before the
                        commission and received their oollege diplomas. Their Turkish diplomas will
                        he sent to them later. </p>
                    <p>Nine pharmacy students were presented to the commissioners for final
                        examination. Of these all passed pud took the oath and reomy-eft diplomas.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAS-EL-BAR. THE EGYPTIAN MARGATE.</head>
                    <byline>(From a Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <p>Now that the summer has begun in earnest, many dwellers in inland towns will
                        be thinking of making a move soon to some favored spot by the seaside where
                        the invigorating ocean breezes will once more brace the jaded residents of
                        the interior. For those who have the means San Stefano is incomparably the
                        Queen of Egyptian summer resorts,but-to those to whom money is a primary
                        consideration, and others who prefer a free-and-easy and happy-go-lucky
                        existence, I know of ho better place close at hand than Ras-el-Bar, not far
                        from bamietta. </p>
                    <p>I very much doubt whether the frequenters of this little place, which springs
                        into life with the advent of the great beat, would seek to qualify its
                        attractions by comparison with those offered elsewhere, say at Ramleh or
                        Port Said, but I do not hesitate to say that it possesses a charm of its
                        own, and I am not surprised when I discern the same familiar faces there
                        £®ar after year. ' </p>
                    <p>» The season proper at this Egyptian Margate, if I may term it so, does not
                        commence in earnest until the middle of July, and is in full 8 wing until
                        about the end of September, iothat the hotel-keepers and others who minister
                        to the wants of the strangers have, in a sense, to make hay while the sun
                        shines, although, considering the shortness of the season, no one can say
                        that the prices charged are exorbitant. The majority of the visitors are
                        Levantines and Egyptians, leavened by a fair number of Europeans of all the
                        nationalities that inhabit this country. </p>
                    <p>The hotels, if one can honor them with this name, and dwellings ajfe mainly
                        if not entirely constructed of the native rush mat fastened to wooden
                        uprights and are slighly raised from the land or ground in the same manner
                        as bungalows in India. Naturally, in a country like Egypt, where rain is
                        unknown for nine months at least of the year, snch habitations are possible,
                        but one could not calmly contemplate what would happen to the whole place
                        were it visited by a good monsoon 'rain of an hour's duration. </p>
                    <p>Of course, of amusements of the fashionable kind there are none to hegnile
                        the time, but for those who love sea-bathing, fishing, and an bnt-of-door
                        life, Ras-el-Bar is a small paradise. The bathing ui the best in Egypt, and
                        eaoh hotel has a hnt wherein batherrssan undress and dress. There are a few
                        shops, sujch as the inevitable bacals, a good barber, ^chemist, and last,
                        hut not least, a branch post-office. There is also from June, to October a
                        small body of police under the orders of a native officer. </p>
                    <p>» I should not omit to mention, for the information of would-be new-comers,
                        who may like to give the place a trial, that there is a regular steam boat
                        service that carries the mail between Damietta and Ras-el-Bar, the trip
                        occupying about an hour and running in coincidence with the arrival of the
                        passenger trains from Mansourah. Daring the busy season the Egyptian Railway
                        Administration runs an express train weekly each way which starts from Cairb
                        every Thursday. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAIRO HOTELS.</head>
                    <p>In reference to the recent rise in the shares of the two leading hotel
                        companies of Egypt, it is worth noticing that the principal reason of the
                        rapid appreciation within the past few months of this class of securities is
                        the enormous increase since two years or so in the value of the land on
                        which the Grand Continental and the Savoy Hotels are built in the case of
                        the Nungovich Hotels Company, and in the case of the Egyptian Hotels
                        Company, of the land at Ghezireh, which has been and is being 3old at
                        rapidly increasing prices, </p>
                    <p>The former company bought the New Hotel, now the Grand Continental, àboùt six
                        years ago, including the land it stands on and the furniture it contained,
                        for £105,000, which, at the time, was considered the lull value. The
                        presentvalue of the land alone, which measures 11,000 squarè metres, at the
                        modest price of £20 per square metre, represents an increase of no less than
                        £4 per share on the entire share capital of the company, not reckoning the
                        building, furniture and good-will of a concern that pays yearly dividends of
                        ten per cent. </p>
                    <p>The Savoy Hotel, as it is, was bought about a year later than the other from
                            <persName>Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoum</persName>,we believe for
                        £55,000. The land is 5,000 square metres in extent, but owing to the'
                        extraordinary increase in the price of land in the best part of the Ismailia
                        quarter the site alone to-day is worth the fifty five thousand pounds,
                        without counting the palatial buildings erected on it. This* repre-^ sente
                        an increase in value of at least £2 per share on the whole of the share
                        capital. With these figures before us can one wonder that the £4 shares of
                        the Nungovioh Hotels are now worth £10 or thereabouts, and those of the
                        Egyptian Hotels at an equally high premium ? . </p>
                    <p>As we mentioned a few weeks back, the former company have pnrobased by
                        preemption a portion of the estate of the late Sabet Pasha, adjoining the
                        Savoy Hotel, and on the ground so acquired they are to erect additional
                        buildings to accommodate the large and ever-increasing clientèle that
                        patrorises this hotel during the winter season, besides enlarging the
                        restaurant and making other mnoh-needed improvements. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>BECK GO'S PILSENEj) BEER BREMEN. ' T1AB8 SO HOHMT COKFRITIOB MB QUALITY.
                        R.B,—Inferior Salads now Mag oftnd to lfa H" aMCtolo fOOâ MÜM. Beware of
                        otDly OfOMt «feMjjton matof foWAhl**» liiAlto Ini »</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="section" feature="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID-.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SUBMERGED DREDGER,</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Thursday.</dateline>
                        <p>Work on the submerged dredger "Pharaonrp' II." is now being rabidly
                            pushed towards com- ' pletion. t learn that the vessel is to be raised
                            by qaite a novel method,' which' should prove most interesting. As I
                            noted some time back, she lies bn her side, and a kind of bed is being
                            .dredged ont along her side, at the bottom'of which is to be placed a
                            patent slip cradle. A cutting is to be made in the hank into which the
                            dredger lying on the cradle is to be towed. The entrance to the basin
                            will be closed, and it is then to be pumped out and the vessel attended
                            to as if she lay in a dry-dock. Hopes are expressed that the "Pharaon
                            II." will be hanled into the basjn in two weeks' time. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHARITY CONCERT.</head>
                        <p>The massed bands of H.M.S. "Suffolk" and 'Lancaster," by permission of
                            the captains and officers of the vessels, are giving a concert on
                            Saturday evening in aid of the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to
                            Animals. The concert is to he held in the garden of the Eastern
                            Exchange, which is being very prettily arranged. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FOURTH OF JULY AT MANSOURAH. </head>
                    <byline>(From a Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline> Mansourah, July 5.</dateline>
                    <p><persName>Mr. W. L. Lawton</persName>, of the Jewell Export Filter Co.,
                        having just completed the installation of a plant of these filters at the
                        new waterworks in this town, entertained his numerous friends on the
                        dahabieh "Ariadne," kindly lent for the occasion by <persName>Mr.
                            Dale</persName>, yesterday. Anchored in mid-stream, the rigging dressed
                        with the flags of all hâtions, that of the star-spangled banner
                        predominating, with a tapestried awning overhead, and palm-branches arched
                        over the columns around the sides, file dahabieh made a gay show by day. At
                        night, the numberless coloured lights, strung on high amongst the rigging
                        and all around, with their reflection on the waters, had quite a fairy-like
                        appearance. On the island in mid-stream two cannon had been placed, the
                        thunders of which were interrupted by the authorities, it being against the
                        Government regulations to fire artillery within 250 metres of the town, but
                        our oourteous Moudir : kindly the fireworks, rockets, Roman candles, etc.,
                        on this special occasion, the first time, in the annals of Mansourah, that
                        this American fête has been celebrated in such a public maimer.
                        Unfortunately the members of the American Mission were absent, having been
                        called away the previous day to attend a meeting at Alexandria, so that
                            <persName>Mr. Lawton</persName> was the only citizen present, but he war
                        a host in himself, and reoéîved his guests for afternoon tfh at 5 o'clock on
                        the deck of the dahabieh. This fonction over the company crossed over to the
                        island amid-stream, where the gentlemen entertained the ladies by engaging
                        in athletic sports. On their return to the boat, they found a sumptuous
                        dinner spread out on a table which had been prettily decorated with flowers
                        and plants by <persName>Mrs. Dale</persName>. Toasts, songs, and musio
                        followed to a late hour of the night. </p>
                    <p>Mr. Lawton was ably assisted in the efforts to celebrate his national
                        fête-day by Messrs, <persName>McCrae</persName>,
                            <persName>Anderson</persName>, and <persName>Holeman</persName>, whose
                        hearty co-operation went far to make the affair the success that it was.
                        During the evening, muoh was said in praise of our most energetic Moudir,
                            <persName>Mustapha Pashà Maher</persName>, for the many improvements he
                        has introduced into the town, amongst them the paving of the main streets,
                        their present cleanliness and order, and the construction of a, carriage
                        drive and promenade along the hanks of the river, south of the town into the
                        open country. This drive is to be planted with trees, which will form a
                        shady avenue*, A new street has already been commenced, orossing the town,
                        and opening up a route from the river to the open fields by the cemeteries.
                        Not only has the Moudir had "Beni Adam" at heart in his endeavours to
                        benefit the town, but his establishment of a branch of the Society for the
                        Prevention of Cruelty to Animals has been so successful, with the active and
                        able support of his officers, the police, and our veterinary surgeon Dr.
                        Trydel, that it is an exception now-a-daysto fin da siok animal about the
                        streets, and whereas the S.P.C.A's hospital was formerly crowded with siok
                        beasts, many having to be shot, all the stalls are now often empty. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.</head>
                    <p>The lengthy text of the judgment of the Court of Appeal in the Rifehi case
                        has been given to th* Press. It leaves no manner of doubt as to the guilt of
                        the acoused, while it, admits the presenoe of extenuating circumstances. « </p>
                    <p>We hear that <persName>Hassan Bey Wassif</persName> has been sent to the
                        infirmary at Menshieh prison owing to a slight indisposition. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S/^Persian Prince," from Antwerp, left London yesterday with general
                        cargo for Malta and Alexandria. </p>
                    <p>The 8J3. "Tuscan Prince," from Manchester, left Malta yesterday and is doe
                        here on Monday morning next, with passengers and general cargo. </p>
                    <p>The Khédivial Mail S.S. "Irauilia"' will leave Alexandria on Wednesday fo*
                        Pima* Smyrna, Mitylone andOoMtontmopk </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="notesCyprus">
                    <head>NOTES FROM CYPRUS</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DESTRUCTIVE RAIN STORM,</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Nicosia, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>As mentioned in my last week'p notes, a good deal of inponvenjeLoe upst
                            threatened to travellers on the NioosiarTjroodos road in consequence of
                            t£e. dw»g9.c«iued by tbeheavy rain storm in the ftfados jange. At 0al*fc
                            the mountain, stream, whiph had . beoome greatly swollen, washed away
                            portion of the road which, winds in and; out at that point, and, many
                            tons of debris, were deposited. The Public Works Depart. ce£p promptly
                            to the rescue, and of men </p>
                        <p>Knd women were very qmclfo pnt to worjf to repair, the damage. little
                            delay or inconvenience was canari, tot the officiala wbo were then on
                            their way to their Troodoa encampments, and the road was opened to trafo
                            after an interval of some 24 hours or so. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW RAILWAY LINE.</head>
                        <p>The railway is now laid to within four miles of Nicosia, and the whole
                            line, from Nioosia to Famagusta is expected to be completed by about the
                            1st August, I hear that the Government is already using the completed
                            portion for the movement of grain from the threshing floors to the grain
                            stores, which have beén established at one or two along the line. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SALE OF GRAIN.</head>
                        <p>The Government has advertised for sala the following grain of this year's
                            harvest, which represents tithe and recoveries from the seed corn
                            advances : </p>
                        <p>Wheat 316,500 kilns (English bushels) Barley 411,000 „ </p>
                        <p>Vetches 42i«50 „ </p>
                        <p>Oate 50,600 „ „ „ </p>
                        <p>all of which quantities, with the exception of vetches, which ère tery
                            slightly in exceM, aie less than those advertised for sale last year. I
                            understand that practically the whole of this has been sold, and at
                            higher priées than in 1904. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INVESTIGATION OF FLORA.</head>
                        <p><persName>Mr. Jens Holmboe</persName>, a Norwegian expert botanist, is
                            now in. Cyprus fpr the purpose of investigating the flora of the Island
                            on behalf of the Botanioal University of Christiania. He has already
                            spent Borne months in Cyprus and contemplates remaining some little time
                            yet. . ~ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOOD AND DRUGS ACT.</head>
                        <p>The Food and Drugs Act passed hist session by the Legislative Council
                            provides, among other things, that any purchaser of any ai* tide of food
                            or of a drug or medicine shaU be entitled, on payment to an analyst of
                            the sum of five shillings, to have snch article or drag or medicine
                            analysed by him, and to receive from th$ analyst a certificate of the
                            ijesult of his analysis. It also defines what is tP be regarded as
                            adultemtioit under the Act, and hew toffenoes are punishable. Duly
                            authorised persons are empowenMi to purchase any such artides jor tfiè
                            rntprm purpose of analysis, and power is given to the. Court to destroy
                            the subject matter of any charge. It is hoped that the 'enforcement of
                            this la* may have a salutary effect.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JEWISH COLONISATION; -</head>
                        <p>A small ohiftlik near Lamaoa has lately been acquired by the Jewish
                            Colonisation Society, and it is intended In course of time to import a
                            limited number of Jewish people as settlers, who will be taught to carry
                            on certain agricultural and industrial undertakings there. It is toe
                            soon to predict ho* "this will answer, hut, if wisely managed and a
                            capable, industrious, and intelligent colony is formed, with a fair
                            amount çf oapfcl at its disposal, it may not be uhrçasonabk to
                            anticipate good results both to the oblony; and, as on object lesson and
                            a means of extending the trade of the'Island, to Cypriw' ih general. \
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="passList" status="verified">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot <name>"Tebe"</name> de la <orgName>Cie Florio Rubattino</orgName>
                        parti hier pour <placeName>Gènes</placeName> avait à bord : </p>
                    <p><persName>M. et Mme V. Oliva</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme
                            Fiandro</persName>, <persName>Cav. Giordano</persName>,
                            <persName>Filippo Grasso</persName>, <persName>Lombardi Boccia et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>F. V. Pinto</persName>, <persName>I. Tawil
                        </persName>, <persName> F. Petroni</persName>, <persName>J.
                            Suares</persName>, <persName>M. Magrin</persName>, <persName>C.
                            Garbua</persName>, <persName>Av. Socolis</persName>, <persName>Leonida
                            Crespi</persName>, <persName>A. Ezri</persName>, <persName>Dom. V.
                            Pinto</persName>, <persName>M. Blattner</persName>, <persName>Carlo
                            Naggiar</persName>, <persName>Callari Musso</persName>, <persName>Mme M.
                            Mieli</persName>, <persName>Antranikian et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>M. et Mme E. Nahman</persName>, <persName>Mme Vve Anastasia et
                            fille</persName>, <persName>Mme. Beneducci</persName>, <persName>Ludwig
                            et fils</persName>, <persName>Wahby Ibrah. Bey</persName>, <persName>V.
                            Spozio</persName>, <persName>F. Ermolli Bey et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Padre Carlo</persName>, <persName>Mme A. Alice</persName>,
                            <persName>Mme. Boccia</persName>, <persName>Mme Collingwood</persName>,
                            <persName>Mlle L. Quin</persName>, <persName>Drosso Bey et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>E. Berty et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Dr. U. Musso</persName>, <persName>B. Muller et
                            famille</persName>, <persName>Soeurs Landi</persName>, <persName>A.
                            Bircher</persName>, <persName>Mme Serveuse</persName>, <persName>Aziz
                            Nader et soeur</persName>, <persName>G. Muller</persName>, <persName>H.
                            Boyle</persName>, <persName>Av. I. Mosoa et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>Prof. E. Van Dick et fille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme A.
                            Salinas</persName>, <persName>G. Bennici et famille</persName>,
                            <persName>D. Simha</persName>, <persName>Anna Sassoli</persName>,
                            <persName>Moh. Bey Tewfick</persName>, <persName>Mme B.
                            Aghion</persName>, <persName>Baron V. Morana</persName>, <persName>M. et
                            Mme Mezzacapo Granato</persName>, <persName>B. J. Naggar</persName>,
                            <persName>M. et Mme Bazagan</persName>, <persName>Wispo et
                            Secrétaire</persName>, <persName>Mme Pucciarelli</persName>,
                            <persName>M. et Mme A. Cangiani</persName>, <persName>A.
                            Invernizzi</persName>, <persName>Bianca Brandani</persName>,
                            <persName>G. Diacono</persName>, <persName>Mme Ida Srapaolo</persName>,
                            <persName>L. Lamberti</persName>, <persName>R. Rossi</persName>,
                            <persName>Emerson</persName>, <persName>fam. Mieli</persName> et 70
                        passagers de eme classe.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/page/n3/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="shareMarket">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
                    <byline> (From our Financial Correspondent). </byline>
                    <dateline>London, June 30.</dateline>
                    <p>After finishing last week and opening the present one in a state of "nerves,"
                        with weak prices all round, there was a general recovery on Tuesday, when it
                        was realised that the Morocco scare had been very much overdone. The
                        tendency now is decidedly better, the only uncertain factor being what
                        effect the state of anarchy, which is spreading rapidly in Russia, may have
                        on the Paris market. The rumours which have been current during the last two
                        or three days as to, a new Japanese loan are apparently well founded, the
                        amount spoken of being 30 millions more of 4 1/2 % stock, divided equally
                        between London, New York, and Berlin, and offered at 91. Coming so close on
                        the heels of the last issue, it cannot be so much the want of money that
                        prompts this issue as a challenge of Credit, so to speak, and, perhaps, also
                        the desire to get at the money market before the opponent does so.</p>
                    <p>There is little that is new to say about Egyptian stocks. Bank shares finish
                        the week rather firmer, Nationals at 26 and Agriculturals at 13 5/8. Dairas
                        are also taken better at 28 1/8. Mines are still dull and lifeless.</p>
                    <p>The remarks made by Lord Cromer last night, when dining at the Skinners'
                        Company, in reference to new promotions in Egypt, are looked upon in the
                        market as most satisfactory. It is felt that the Government can do so much
                        to prevent wild-cat schemes, and his lordship's statement that "they will do
                        their best to resist the invasion of the mere company-monger" is a strong
                        assurance, at all events, that the investor will have a fair run for his
                        money.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="cottonMarket">
                    <head>THE COTTON MARKET </head>
                    <p>Kearsley and Cunningham's Weekly Report. </p>
                    <p>Liverpool, June 29.</p>
                    <p>There has been an improved demand for Egyptian Cotton this week, and
                        quotations are raised 1/4 @ 5/16 per lb. In futures a large business has
                        been done, and the following are the closing values :—</p>
                    <p>June 7.11 Aug. 7. 7 Oct. 7. 4 Dec. 6.58 July 7. 7 Sep. 7. 4 Nov. 7. 0 Jan.
                        6.54</p>
                    <p>American Futures.—The Market this week has again displayed great activity ;
                        an enormous business has been done, and prices have advanced rapidly and
                        materially ; to-day's closing values being 32 @ 33 points higher than those
                        of last Thursday. The same influences hate again been at work, extraordinary
                        manipulation compelling very heavy covering, here and in the American
                        Markets, aided by continued unfavorable weather conditions, no doubt
                        somewhat exaggerated, but serious enough in view of the unusual lateness of
                        the Crop. It is, of course, possible that prices may be forced still higher,
                        but at about 5 1/4 per lb. we consider the position dangerous, and would
                        only advise purchases in case of sharp and sudden reaction.</p>
                    <p>The following are the closing quotations :— Jane 5.17 Sep./Oct 5.16 Jan./Feb.
                        5.16 June/July 5.17 Oct./Nov. 5.16 Feb./Mar. 5.17 Jnly/Aug. 5.16 Nov./Dec.
                        5.16 Mar./Apl. 5.18. Aug./Sep. 5.16 Dec./Jan. 5.16 Apr/May 5.19</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="bulletinBourse">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demie) </p>
                    <p>Le marché est excessivement ferme et accuse une hausse notable. Vers la fin
                        il y a eu de l'animation sur toute la ligne.</p>
                    <p>Parmi les valeurs dont la hausse est la plus sensible, signalons la National
                        Bank qui monte de 25 15/16 à 26 1/16 l'ancienne émission et de 26 1/8 à 26
                        9/32 la nouvelle, l'Anglo- American Nile de 5 3/8 à 5 9/16, et la Delta
                        Light de</p>
                    <p>12 3/4 à 12 7/8.</p>
                    <p>Mais c'est l'Agricole qui a eu les honneurs de la matinée tant comme affaires
                        que comme demande. Le cours est monté de 18 11/16 à</p>
                    <p>13 7/8 acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>Nombre d'autres titres suivent le mouvement de la hausse : la Banque
                        d'Athènes remonte à 121, la Delta Land à 2 5/16, la Daïra à 28 3/8, la Salt
                        and Soda à 34/6, la Nungo- vich à 9 1/16, les Privilégiées Tramways à
                        158.</p>
                    <p>Les Estates sont demandés à 29/32.</p>
                    <p>Par contre la Béhéra réactionne légèrement à 43, l'Alexandria Water à 15 1/8
                        et la Ramleh Railways à 7 1/16.</p>
                    <p>La tendance du marché est excellente et tout fait pré voir la continuation de
                        la hausse.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="shippingMovements">
                    <head>MOUVEMENT MARITIME DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</head>
                    <p>ARRIVÉES </p>
                    <p>7 juillet</p>
                    <p>Smyrne et Candie ; 3 j., vap. hell. Athènes, cap. Catramatos, ton. 399, à
                        Kechayas:</p>
                    <p>Gravosa ; 4 j., 3/4, vap. autr. Dardania, cap. Scioletich, ton. 2,265, à
                        Giurassevich.</p>
                    <p>DÉPARTS </p>
                    <p>6 juillet</p>
                    <p>Syrie; vap. franc. Sénégal, cap. Vincenti.</p>
                    <p>Messine et Gènes ; v. ital. Tebe, cap. Mancini.</p>
                    <p>Barcelone et Marseille; vap. franç. Marie Elizabeth, cap. Bonafos.</p>
                    <p>St. Nazaire et Dunkerque ; vap. ang. Grecian Prince, cap. Hodson. </p>
                    <p>Constantinople; vap. ang. Peterston, cap. Jones, sur lest.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WARDAN ESTATE COMPANY. </head>
                    <p>NOTICE IS HEREBY GIVEN that Holders of shares issued in accordance with the
                        terms of a Circular dated l7th March 1905, and published in the "Egyptian
                        Gazette," "Journal du Caire" and "Bourse Egyptienne" under dates 18th, 20th
                        and 21st March 1905, on which £3 per share was due on allotment and the
                        balance of £3 10/- per share is due to be paid on 10th July 1905, are now
                        given the option of either paying this balance of £3 10/- per share on the
                        10th July 1905 or deferring the payment to the 10th January 1906, in which
                        case interest at the rate of 3 % per annum will be charged for the six
                        months. </p>
                    <p>Interest at the rate of 7 % per annum will be charged on all payments in
                        arrear after the 10th January 1906, and the Shares will be liable to
                        forfeiture as per Article 8 of the Statutes. 26213-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>NOTICE </head>
                    <p>Is hereby given to all persons having claims against the estate of the late
                            <persName>Miralai Boulnois Bey</persName>, Officer Commanding the Bahr
                        el Ghazal district (Major, Royal Artillery) that such daims must be
                        forwarded endorsed as such to the Assistant Adjutant General, War Office,
                        Cairo, to arrive on or before the 7th August, 1905, after which date they
                        will not be taken into consideration. 26212-6-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>SOCIETE ANONYME DU BEHERA</head>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>Messieurs les porteurs d'Actions Ordinaires sont informés qu'en vertu de la
                        décision prise par l'Assemblée Générale Extraordinaire des actionnaires du
                        27 juin dernier, un dividende extraordinaire de £ 2 (deux) par action
                        ordinaire sera payé à la Banque Impériale Ottomane à Alexandrie, à partir de
                        Lundi 10 courant, contre présentation du coupon No, 7 des susdites
                        Actions.</p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur-Directeur Signé : E. W. P. Foster. </p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 5 juillet 1905. 26210-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Fayoum Light Railways Company </head>
                    <p>Les Coupons Nos. 3 et 4 relatifs aux 4500 Obligations de la 1re émission
                        seront payables respectivement à partir des 10 juillet 1905 et 9 août 1905,
                        et les Coupons Nos. 2 et 3 relatifs aux 720 Obligations de la 2me émission,
                        seront également payables respectivement à partir des 10 juillet 1905 et 9
                        août 1905, an Siège de la Société an Caire de 9 à 11 heures a.m. à raison de
                        seize shellings par Obligation.</p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur-Délégué 26211-1 Khaled Loutfi. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head>Administration des Chemins de Fer et des Télégraphes </head>
                    <p>AVIS </p>
                    <p>Le Conseil d'Administration a l'honneur de faire savoir au Public qu'à partir
                        du 8 Juillet courant, l'horaire d'ouverture du bureau télégraphique de la
                        station de Port-Saïd sera comme suit :</p>
                    <p>de 8 h. a.m. à 1 h. p.m. et de 3 h. p.m. à 6 h. 30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Le Caire, le 6 juillet 1905.26209-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Administration des Postes </head>
                    <p>Un bureau de poste provisoire admis à toutes les branches du service excepté
                        les groups, a été ouvert à Ras El Bar pour la saison balnéaire.</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 6 juillet 1905 26214-1</p>
                </div>
                <!-- add material -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- add material -->
                <!-- add bourse khediviale -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Remarques</p>
                    <p>(De Midi à lh. p.m.) </p>
                    <p>Cotons.—Sur les premières dépêches de Liverpool, la fermeté s'etait
                        accentuée, mais une certaine réaction ayant commencé à se produire par la
                        suite, les cours ont faibli et la clôture a été calme. Toutefois,
                        contrairement an juillet qui est revenu an prix d'ouverture, le novembre se
                        trouve avoir gagné quand même 7/32 sur le premier cours pratiqué.</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton.—La séance a fini calme pour la vieille récolte et très
                        ferme pour les 3 mois. Les dispositions cependant sont toujours les
                        mêmes.</p>
                    <p>Bateaux partis :</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/page/n4/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RELICS FROM SINAI AND EGYPT. LONDON UNIVERSITY COLLEGE EXHIBITION.</head>
                    <p>The exhibition opened last week at University College, London, of collections
                        made during the past year by the working parties of the Egyptian Exploration
                        Fund contains interesting relics from ground already broken.</p>
                    <p>Drs. <persName>Grenfell</persName> and <persName>Hunt</persName>, in
                        searching among the rubbish heaps of Oxyrhynkos for papyri of Roman and
                        especially early Christian ages, have found other interesting objects, such
                        as vases with designs in reliefs and a richly coloured glaze, figures and
                        dishes, carved ivory panels, bronze statuettes, such as a Demeter, admirably
                        modelled, and an Aphrodite grasping Eros by the arm so roughly as to suggest
                        coming chastisement. There are lamps, coins, and all the usual "finds," but
                        the gem is a small marble head of Hera, exquisitely worked. Stone weapons
                        are there in plenty from near Thebes, with "finds" from Lithom and other
                        places, while on the walls hang numerous copies of figures and hieroglyphs,
                        made by Mrs. Flinders Petrie and other ladies, from tombs, seven of which
                        were opened for the purpose. As these become rarer year by year, by the
                        influence of time, the ravages of treasure-seekers, and the transportations
                        of whole structures to other countries, the value of such permanent records
                        is sufficiently obvious.</p>
                    <p>But the results of investigations in the Sinaitic Peninsula are the most
                        important feature of this year's exhibition. We have long known that, from
                        very early days, its mines were worked by the Egyptians. Sculptures, stelae,
                        hieroglyphic inscriptions, which have been partly deciphered, prove this
                        nation to have held the country long before the Exodus. Professor Petrie's
                        party worked in the turquoise mining district, that is, in the upper part of
                        the Wady Maghara and especially at Sarabit el Khadem, near the western
                        coast, well north both of Serbal and the traditional Mount Sinai. The gem is
                        found in a red sandstone which is a little older than the chalk of England.
                            <persName>Major Macdonald</persName> made an attempt to revive the
                        industry about forty years ago, but found it unremunerative. He was
                        followed, within the last decade, by a company, whose efforts were also, and
                        more deservedly, not successful, for their reckless methods irreparably
                        injured some of the most interesting Egyptian antiquities—and some mining is
                        still done by the Arabs. Turquoises are not uncommon, but the majority are
                        of little value. The mines, as we now learn, were open even in the first
                        Egyptian dynasty, the oldest monument representing one of its kings,
                        Mersekha, who flourished, according to Professor Petrie, about six thousand
                        five hundred years ago, i.e., 4600 B.C., "clubbing" a captive chief. Other
                        sculptures commemorate kings of he third dynasty, and dozens of inscriptions
                        were cut between this date and the end of the twelfth dynasty—about 2500
                        B.C. Thus, many centuries before the Exodus, not a few before the days of
                        Abraham, Sinai was in Egyptian occupation. Some have thought that copper
                        also was worked about Sarabit el Khadem. That, however, Professor Petrie has
                        proved to be a mistake ; the heaps of black material, supposed to be slag,
                        are hematite, a natural iron ore, which, if coal were handy, might be
                        valuable ; but the main copper works are six miles away, in the Wady
                        Nasb.</p>
                    <p>Sarabit el Khadem was evidently an exceptionally holy place. On the edge of
                        the upland, near the brow of a lofty cliff, are the ruins of a great temple,
                        and the neighbouring hills are dotted over with tiny sanctuaries—all,
                        probably, for the same purpose, revelation through dreams. These sanctuaries
                        consist of a rough stone wall surrounding a larger upright block ; the one
                        sheltering the sleepers from the wind, the other marking the spot where they
                        might "see visions" and "dream dreams." Like the pillar set up by Jacob,
                        these indicated a Bethel; the temple itself being evidently the most sacred
                        spot of all. It is remarkable, not only for its progressive growth, but also
                        for being Syrian in type, though Egyptian by construction. It is, of course,
                        now in ruins, but a model gives an excellent idea of its original
                        structure.</p>
                    <p>It was the sanctuary of the goddess Hathor, and her primitive shrine was a
                        rook cave. This must have existed so far back as the third dynasty—or nearly
                        seven thousand years ago; for the name of Seneferu, one of its kings, is
                        still clear. Kings of the twelfth dynasty—or about 2500 B.C.—reconstructed
                        the shrine and made a road, ornamented with stelæ, part of which still
                        remains. Their successors of the eighteenth dynasty much enlarged it by
                        adding a long vestibule with two small courts, curving with the contour of
                        the hill-side and terminating in a gateway. This was about 1500 B.C., and at
                        a later epoch a structure, cut up into a number of small chambers, was
                        placed in front of this. The whole is enclosed by rude walls, which were
                        added by Amen Hotep III. The neighbouring ground is covered with ashes, in
                        great part remnants of sacrifices at least as old as the twelfth dynasty. In
                        that shrine at first, in those chambers, when pilgrims became more numerous,
                        the votaries slept, and it marked the holiest place, like the Kiblah of a
                        mosque. But this temple has a feature still less Egyptian—two small courts,
                        each of which has a stone basin for purification. Thus this characteristic
                        feature of every Mohamedan mosque must have existed in Syrian worship
                        fifteen centuries before the Christian era.</p>
                    <p>The site has yielded many interesting relics from the date of Seneferu
                        onwards, not the least remarkable being the head of a statuette, in dark
                        stone, representing Thyi, a queen of the eighteenth dynasty, well preserved
                        and admirably executed. They also found some fragments of vases, with
                        yellow-coloured designs in relife on a purple ground, recalling the Portland
                        Vase. One represents King Ramesu III. in his harem, and thus is rather more
                        than three thousand years old. It may seem, at first sight, strange that
                        Egyptian kings should build sanctuaries for the gods of Syria, but local
                        deities were not to be despised in their own lands, as we can see from a
                        very curious record written about the year 1200 B.C, of which Professor
                        Petrie gives a summary in the new Volume of his History of Egypt. </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD BEACONSFIELD'S FIRMNESS. <lb/>THE SECRET HISTORY OF THE BERLIN
                        CONGRESS.</head>
                    <p>Mr. A. N. Cumming was a fellow patient with Lord Rowton at Wiesbaden in 1898,
                        and they had many talks about Lord Beaconsfield and the political questions
                        of the time. Freed by the death of Lord Rowton from the condition laid down
                        that he would publish nothing of their conversation during his lifetime, Mr.
                        Cumming has an interesting article in the July "Nineteenth Century" on "The
                        Secret History of the Treaty of Berlin," as narrated by Lord Rowton.</p>
                    <p>Within a few minutes of the arrival in Berlin of Lord Beaconsfield with Lord
                        Rowton to attend the famous Congress, a message arrived from Prince
                        Bismarck, and at 10.30 at night the English Premier called upon the
                        Chancellor. Lord Rowton waited outside, strolling about under the trees.</p>
                    <p>"Whilst I was walking there, what was my surprise to hear my own name called
                        out, 'My dear Monty !' I turned in astonishment, and beheld Count
                        Schouvaloff, who wasthen, as you know, the Russian Ambassador in London. We
                        were old and intimate friends in London, where we saw a great deal of each
                        other. 'My dear fellow,' said he, 'what in the world are you doing here ?' I
                        replied, 'I am waiting for Lord Beaconsfield, who is now closeted with
                        Prince Bismarck.' His face fell. Obviously he had come upon the same errand,
                        and Lord Beaconsfield had forestalled him. That was the first move, and I
                        have no doubt at all that already at that first interview Bismarck had taken
                        the measure of his man in Lord Beaconsfield, and I traced from that a great
                        deal of what subsequently occurred."</p>
                    <p>At the Congress the English representatives put forward four points which
                        were described as an ultimatum for the acceptance of Russia. The Russians
                        declared they were so important that they must refer them to the Tsar
                        himself, and a diplomat of high rank must proceed to St. Petersburg for his
                        Majesty's orders. The Congress, therefore, adjourned.</p>
                    <p>"On the morning after that decision," Lord Rowton told Mr. Cumming, "Lord
                        Beaconsfield came into my room. He said, 'I have quite made up my mind what
                        to do. It seems to me impossible for Russia to concede these points, and, if
                        they refuse, I have sketched out my plan. We will return to England at
                        once.' Arrived in London, he would make his report to the Queen. 'A
                        declaration of war will follow.'"</p>
                    <p>He requested Lord Rowton to make the necessary arrangements for the journey
                        to England. To get there within the time essential to Lord Beaconsfield's
                        plans, a special train from Cologne was required; and this Lord Rowton
                        ordered by telegram. This telegram "was the turning point of the whole
                        affair."</p>
                    <p>"The Congress met again for a final decision on this matter at the appointed
                        time. Whilst the meeting was going on I waited outside as usual. After a
                        sitting of a couple of hours the door opened, and I noticed particularly
                        that the Russians came out first, Schouvaloff at their head. Lord
                        Beaconsfield, as was his custom, came out last of all, and, when he was
                        going away, he took my arm and said, 'My dear Corry, I have seen what I
                        never expected to see. Russia has given way on all four points.' "We
                        subsequently discovered, of course, that my telegram to the station-master
                        at Cologne had been promptly transmitted to Prince Bismarck. He thereupon
                        saw that Lord Beaconsfield was in earnest. He knew, and this we did not
                        discover until a good deal later, that, as a matter of fact, the Russians
                        had received orders from the Tsar practically to submit to anything rather
                        than go to war with England. He knew that, but we did not. Both at the first
                        interview, of which I told you, and after that lucky telegram of mine to
                        Cologne, he saw that Lord Beaconsfield was in earnest. He had taken the
                        measure of the man ; he told the Russians what the fact was, and the result
                        was that they gave in.</p>
                    <p>"I may tell you further that the Russian pretext that they must consult the
                        Tsar upon the question of those four points was a mere blind. They did send
                        off a messenger, one of their highest diplomats, but we learned later on
                        that he left the train at Königsberg, and did not proceed any farther."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BAGDAD RAILWAY. <lb/>THE SECOND ANNUAL REPORT.</head>
                    <p>The report of the second year's activity of the Bagdad Railway has just been
                        published for 1904. It deals mainly with the construction of the section of
                        the line from Konia to Eregli and Bulguriu ; this is the first section of
                        the Bagdad Railway; it is 135 miles in length, and starting from Konia, has
                        eleven stations inclusive of Konia and Bulguriu. The work of laying down the
                        line made such good progress, that the line could be thrown open to traffic
                        on October 25, 1904, and by December 31 the gross receipts amounted to
                        £2,776, which is at the rate of £77 16s. 9d. per kilometre per year. The
                        kilometre-guarantee of £3,894, due from the Turkish Government under the
                        terms of the convention, was paid in full by the Dette Publique Ottomane in
                        February, and the net profits for 1904 amounted to £32,205. On the whole,
                        the German Press maintains almost absolute silence concerning the progress
                        of the laying down of the Bagdad Railway.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SISTINE CHAPEL. </head>
                    <p>It is said that the cracks in the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel which for
                        closeon four centuries have caused anxiety are to some extent fraudulent,
                        having been painted in a kind of grim humour by Michael Angelo when he
                        decorated the ceiling,</p>
                    <p>Whether the story is apooryphal is difficult to say, but, at any rate, the
                        false fissures, if there are such, have been accompanied by real cracks of
                        late, and all who have seen or have heard of the Sistine Chapel will be
                        relieved to learn that the repairs which have been in progress have just
                        been completed.</p>
                    <p>For many, of course, Pope Sixtus the Fourth's Chapel owes its interest to the
                        conclaves which it has witnessed, those secret meetings into which three
                        score and ten priests enter as equals to choose from among them one to sit
                        on the Chair of the Fisherman. Chanting the "Veni Creator," they go in,
                        these princes of the Church, in their crimson robes, and they come out as
                        they went in, all save one, who has changed his red robes for white, his hat
                        for a tiara, his crozier for the cross and keys.</p>
                    <p>Nobleman and peasant, statesman and saint, all in their turn have come out
                        from the Sistine Chapel, elected to hold office in the longest dynasty the
                        modern world has seen, to be crowned with the triple crown while "Sic
                        transit gloria mundi" is still ringing in their ears.</p>
                    <p>But apart from all this, there are few who can think of the Sistine Chapel
                        save as the culminating point in the art of the Renaissance, as the epitome
                        of the great revival when Florence taught Rome and Rome still taught the
                        world.</p>
                    <p>Perugino and Botticelli, Ghirlandajo and Signorelli are among the men whom
                        Sixtus commissioned to paint frescoes on the walls, on the one side from the
                        Old Testament and on the other from the New, so that incidents from the life
                        of Christ might be confronted by scenes from the lives of those who in the
                        Old Law acted as His types. </p>
                    <p>Under these frescoes of the great Florentine masters, the last word, one may
                        say, of the quattrocento, were to have hung tapestries, Raphael's cartoons
                        for some of which are to be seen in London at South Kensington. But it is
                        Michael Angelo who has added most glory to the Sistine Chapel in the
                        prophets and sybils which he painted on the roof, and in the great "Last
                        Judgment" at the east end over the High Altar.</p>
                    <p>He who had been hailed as having inherited the mantle of Phidias and
                        Praxiteles, who was architect of the great new basilica, most perforce be
                        made to earn other laurels, so thought Pope Julius, by limning the roof of
                        the chapel in the Vatican. </p>
                    <p>Everyone knows how the great master who declared that painting in oils was an
                        occupation for women and idlers spent four years on the roof of the chapel.
                        While he was engaged upon it he refused admission to all, but the Pope,
                        thinking that he, at any rate, could watch the work, was summarily treated
                        by having paint dropped on his head from the scaffolding above. Julius II.,
                        however, recognised the painter's genius and did not resent his
                        eccentricities.</p>
                    <p>Another example of the grim vengeance of Buonarotti occurred when Paul III.'s
                        ceremonaire pointed out to the Pontiff the scandal which the nude figures in
                        the "Last Judgment" would give.</p>
                    <p>The Pope took the hint, and commissioned someone to paint in drapery over the
                        most naked figures; Michael Angelo had his revenge by painting a portrait of
                        the Master of Ceremonies with ass's ears in Hell ; the latter complained to
                        the Pope in order that he might have the figure removed, but Paul declared
                        that it was impossible, had he been in Purgatory something might have been
                        done, but being in Hell there was no release. More than two centuries and a
                        half have passed, and not only the hand of time, but the blackening of
                        tapers and of "the good strong, thick; stupefying incense smoke" have left
                        their mark, and have dimmed the colours of the fresco, but Massei Biagio,
                        like Midas with ass's ears, still writhes in Hell.</p>
                    <p>It was nearly 70 years after Sixtus IV. had begun the chapel that Michael
                        Angelo laid down his brush on completing the Last Judgment ; the first della
                        Rovera Pope had been succeeded by the infamous Innocent VIII., who in his
                        tarn was replaced by the yet more infamous Alexander VI.</p>
                    <p>After the Borgia came the second della Rovera—Julius III., the warrior
                        pontiff who would fain be painted, not with a book, but with a sword in his
                        hand, "for," said he, "I know nought of letters." Then came two Medici
                        Popes, Leo X. and Clement VII., and finally under the Farnese Pope, Paul
                        III., the great chapel was finished.</p>
                    <p>It was the last, as it was the most supreme, example of didactic painting. In
                        it was reached the climax of art which aimed at setting forth the mysteries
                        of religion and the history of the Church that all might see, and seeing,
                        understand.</p>
                    <p>All through Italian art in the Middle Ages and until the Renaissance we find
                        painting made the handmaid of religion, representing the symbolism of the
                        Scriptures or the lives of the saints, and if one excepts the preaching of
                        the friars, acting as the main source of instruction in religion which
                        offered itself to the people.</p>
                    <p>But with revival of learning the practice died out Pagan influences when
                        acting on men who lacked the genius of a Buonarotti produced a group of
                        painters in whom what was gained in technical knowledge made no amends for
                        what was lost in the sensuous appeal which the less perfect painters by
                        their very simplicity effected.</p>
                    <p>And before long came the great bathos in the history of Italian art, within
                        fifty years of<cb n="4"/>its climax was reached its anticlimax. Scarcely was
                        Michael Angelo cold in his grave; one may say, when the great horde of
                        mannerists swept over the churches of Italy, covering with gilding and crude
                        colours what formerly had been dignified by simplicity, leaving their
                        Assumptions or Ascensions in every church with pompous schemes worked out
                        with wretched skill, leaving an impression on the mind of thousands of
                        cupids rolling about in a company where they alone were not involved in
                        bellying drapery.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL GALLIENI'S REPLY.</head>
                    <p>The Governor-General of Madagascar is not only the most able administrator
                        France possesses, but as is so often the case, he is a man with a sense of
                        humour as well. Owing to former scandals, a very salutary rule has been made
                        in France that no officer shall draw pay for two or more appointments at the
                        same time. But General Gallieni is at one and the same time drawing pay as
                        Governor-General, as a general officer, and as General commanding the troops
                        in Madagascar, so that on the whole he receives 180,000 francs, or rather
                        over £7,000 per annum, which, after all, is not too much for the great
                        services which he has rendered to his country. But this abnormal state of
                        things worried M. Dumergue, the late Minister for the Colonies, though he
                        did not venture to order General Gallieni to conform to the role, because
                        the General is a power at the Colonial Office, and is, moreover, considered
                        indispensable in Madagascar, in spite of the fact that two or three
                        highly-placed men are doing all they can to step into his places M.
                        Domergue, therefore, wrote privately to the Governor-General, and begged him
                        to see that no officer in the Madagascar army of occupation transgressed the
                        role. The Minister flattered himself that he had put the case very cleverly,
                        but he had to acknowledge himself beaten when he got the delightful answer
                        :— "Sir, I have the honor to inform you that not one of the officers under
                        my orders is drawing double pay." General Gallieni, therefore, continued to
                        receive his 180,000 francs.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DOG-BITE AS BLACKMAIL.</head>
                    <p>A novel and singular system of fraud has just been brought to light at
                        Nuremberg. A man named Niell conceived the idea of levying blackmail by
                        means which have hitherto escaped the attention of the most astute of his
                        precursors. He made a regular inventory of all fairly well-to-do people in
                        the city who kept dogs, and "worked" them in turn district by district. His
                        plan was to watch for circumstances which might give colour to his story,
                        and then going to the dog's owner to complain that he had been bitten,
                        showing some slight abrasion on the leg to clinch his story. He never asked
                        for money, but always threatened a summons, and with equal regularity
                        accepted the pecuniary offers made to him "to settle the thing." Niell had
                        kept his business running steadily for two years before he fell into the
                        hands of the police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TUNIS IN A WATER FAMINE.</head>
                    <p>One scarcely likes to think of a large European population in an African
                        city, placed on an extremely limited water supply in an African summer.
                        That, however, is the prospect which threatens Tunis. The extent and
                        rapidity with which the European population has increased has entirely
                        outstripped even the estimated supply, which, on the other hand, to
                        aggravate matters has not realised the estimate by quite a third. As if this
                        was not enough, such water as there is bears traces of naphthous
                        contamination. At present the supply is cut off for 12 hours a day, and the
                        hours will have to be still further restricted. If the heats are great, the
                        consequences to the public health may be terrible.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PIGMIES AT ST. STEPHEN'S.</head>
                    <p>Five of the African pigmies now on a visit to London were entertained at the
                        House of Commons yesterday week. There were four men and one woman. The
                        former were dressed as Haussas, each wearing a blue Norfolk jacket, blue
                        cloth breeches, black putties, and red fez. They were armed with small bows
                        and arrows and with spears. The woman was in a white robe relieved with
                        colour and wore a necklet of beads. As they stood beneath the lofty dome of
                        the central ball, and later against the high palace wall of the terrace, the
                        graceful minuteness of the little people was effectively seen.</p>
                    <p>A gentleman who has travelled widely in Africa spoke with some authority in
                        associating the visitors with the true race of pigmies. "What dear little
                        baby men," was the instructive exclamation of a lady bystander. Dr.
                        Hutchinson, M.P., who received the lilliputian strangers, entertained them
                        to tea on the terrace, their preference being towards sardines, hard-boiled
                        eggs, and chocolates. They were photographed by Sir Benjamin Stone.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABYSSINIAN CONVENTION.</head>
                    <p>The French Government, Reuter's Agency is informed, has still under
                        consideration the counter proposals put forward by Italy with reference to
                        the negotiations now in progress between Great Britain, France, and Italy
                        for the conclusion of a convention dealing with Abyssinian affairs. Fresh
                        proposals were formulated by France and presented to the Marquis of
                        Lansdowne last month, and were duly communicated to the Government in Rome,
                        whose reply was received a few days ago and communicated to the French
                        Government. It should be stated that perfect agreement exists between the
                        three Governments regarding the preservation of their interests in Ethiopia
                        on the basis of Abyssinian independence, and that the proposals and
                        counterproposals referred to are connected merely with matters of detail.
                        That a convention has not already been signed is probably due to the fact
                        that other more pressing questions have been engaging the attention of the
                        French Foreign Office.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RISE IN PRICE OF WOOL.</head>
                    <p>War in the Far East has been partly responsible for a remarkable rise in the
                        price of wool, due to the large purchases of clothing and blankets by the
                        Japanese Government. Wool has advanced from threepence to sixpence a pound
                        on the prices three years ago. This, to the owners of large sheep farms,
                        means, of course, large fortunes. It benefits Australia, unfortunately, but
                        little, for the high prices are partly due to the drought and disease in
                        that country during the last year ; but the demand in the United States is
                        steadily increasing, so the industry in the colonies may eventually become a
                        prosperous one. Needless to say, the change is highly unwelcome to the
                        manufacturer and the purchaser of carpets and other woollen materials.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="prepaidAdvertisements" status="incomplete">
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>ADVERTISING AGENTS-The best public Advertising sites in Alexandria belong
                            to G. Vestri &amp; Co., Advt Agents, 8t Catherine's Square. Special
                            rates for permanent clients Moderate terms. Prompt despatch.</p>
                        <p>25642-81-12-905</p>
                        <p>ARABIC LESSONS given by an Egyptian tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Shefik,
                            'Egyptian Gazette' offices. 25888-</p>
                        <p>ENGLISH MASTER desires post as tutor during summer holidays. Apply, L.
                            Vigour, English school, Cyprus. 26165-12-11</p>
                        <p>TO LET, furnished, at Ibrahimieh (Ramleh), splendid villa ; 10 rooms (6
                            bedrooms), drawing-room, etc. ; large umbraged garden 3,000 piks ;
                            electric light, eta, eta Apply to Mr. Haye, Villa des Boses, Ibrahimieh,
                            near Doctor Cognard, or to the post-office.</p>
                        <p>26147-15-14</p>
                        <p>WANTED Sole Agency for England for good Cigarette Manufacturer by firm of
                            Cigar Importers with large connection. References exchanged. Apply,
                            Whitaker and Lofthouse, King's Arcade, Bradford, England.</p>
                        <p>26206-3-2</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-07-07/page/n5/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
