<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10/12/16</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-23">January 23rd, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7104 ALEXANDRIA, MONDAY, JANUARY 23, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <cb n="1"/><head>OPEN REVOLUTION IN RUSSIA</head>
                    <head>PEOPLE’S APPEAL TO THE TSAR.</head>
                    <head>CONFLICTS WITH TROOPS. - THOUSANDS KILLED.</head>
                    <head>INDESCRIBABLE SCENES. - A NIGHT OF HORROR.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 21.</dateline>
                    <p>The situation here is most serious. The town is in partial darkness. The
                        papers will probably be unable to appear. The civil employes at the Arsenal
                        have joined the strikers. It is feared that the railway and telegraph
                        operators will also join. A monster demonstration was held on Sunday in
                        front of the Winter Palace, in order to present a petition to the Tsar. The
                        petition, which was the most remarkable and outspoken document ever
                        presented to an autocrat, declared that the people were insulted and treated
                        like slaves, burdened with labour beyond their strength, stifled by
                        despotism and the intolerable yoke of officialdom the injustice of which had
                        reached its limit. Death was preferable to the fearful sufferings of the
                        people. National representation was indispensable, immediate convocation of
                        the representatives of all classes was the sole balm for the people’s
                        wounds. The petition says “Satisfy these demands and you make Russia happy
                        and glorious. If you do not reply to the people's prayer, we prefer to die
                        in the Square before your Palace.</p>
                    <p>The Prefect has issued a notice forbidding gatherings and processions, which
                        workmen and the public are warned to avoid, as the employment of the
                        military may cause accidents.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 21.</dateline>
                    <p>The prefect's notice was issued especially in view of the notification that
                        400,000 men are to march on Sunday afternoon to the Palace. They will be
                        headed by a young priest, <persName
                            ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q299681?uselang=fr">Father
                            Gapon</persName>, in canonicals with crucifix, who is heart and soul in
                        the movement. The workmen will insist upon seeing the Tsar himself.</p>
                    <p>It is noteworthy that the garrison here is about 40,000, largely composed of
                        reservists. Hitherto the police have been absolutely passive. People are
                        nervous and excited. Everyone is buying candles anticipating a stoppage of
                        the gas and electric light. The newspapers have not been published.</p>
                    <p>A deputation of three workmen has gone to Tsarskoe Selo, with the object of
                        trying to deliver the text of the petition, so as to enable the Tsar to
                        consider it before the monster demonstration.</p>
                    <p>Father Gapon has selected 400 picked men to act as a bodyguard to the Tsar if
                        the latter consents to meet the people. Gapon also has a personal bodyguard
                        of 50 men in order to prevent his arrest.</p>
                    <p>All the cavalry regiments are concentrated here, from the surrounding
                        barracks. Other regiments are being hurried up from Reval, Riga and
                        elsewhere, as it is feared that the troops of the ordinary garrison would
                        not fire on the demonstrators in the event of disorders.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>The strikes are spreading, but no disturbances have occurred. (Havas.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, January 22 3 p.m.</dateline>
                <p>Several conflicts took place about 1 o’clock. It is stated that 80 of the
                    strikers have been killed or wounded.</p>
                <p>The Tsar remained at Tsarkoe Selo.</p>
                <p>The Pope Gapon has been arrested.</p>
                <p>The effervescence is general. The disturbances continue. (Havas.)</p></div>
                <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, January 22, midnight</dateline>
                <p>About 2 o clock the crowd invaded the approaches to the Winter Palace. The troops
                    fired, 130 men and women being killed.</p>
                <p>At 3.40 p.m. a conflict on Nevsky Prospect caused the deaths of thirty
                    people.</p>
                <p>Pope Gapon was not arrested ; he is wounded. Another priest Pope Serge, has been
                    killed.</p>
                <p>The workmen are barricading themselves in</p>
                <p>the Vassili Ostroff quarter.</p>
                <p>It is rumoured that they have taken possession of the dynamite factory.</p>
                <p>The troops are bivouacking.</p>
                <p>It is believed that the number of killed and wounded amounts to several
                    thousands. (H.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg January 22.</dateline>
                <p>Early in the morning ike Cossacks and other troops marched to the Winter Palace.
                    Detachments of cavalry and infantry, each 150 strong, were stationed at various
                    points of the city, but the artillery were concealed from view. 15,000 strikers
                    started from the Neva works for the Winter Palace. Their route was barred by
                    Cossacks, who fired three volleys in blank, charged the strikers with heavy
                    whips, and finally drove back the demonstrators. It is unknown bow many were
                    killed and injured.</p>
                <p>A furious conflict took place between the soldiers and the strikers round the
                    Winter Palace square. The troops, who were driven hack by the weight of the mob,
                    fired repeatedly and finally dispersed the crowd. There were 150 killed and
                    wounded. The strikers are now infuriated and are erecting wire entanglements,
                    tearing down the telegraph poles, and raising barricades. They are organising an
                    armed resistance. Sanguinary conflicts are taking place all over the city.</p>
                <p>The Police Superintendent is among the killed and Father Gapon among the
                    wounded.</p>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <p>(Later). Fatal conflicts between the strikers are taking place in every quarter
                    of the city. The excitement is increasing. The crowd on Nicholas Bridge was
                    stopped by the infantry and Uhlan Cossacks. The strikers appealed to the
                    soldiers not to shoot their brothers. The infantry laid down their rifles but
                    the Cossasks charged, wounding many. The Tsar remains at Tsarkoe Selo.</p>
                <p>Many women and children have been killed and wounded. The scenes are
                    indescribable. The air is rent with cries of women and the angry shouts of men.
                    The city appears to be plunged in an open revolution. A night of horror is in
                    prospect. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 22.</dateline>
                <p>The mob has erected two barricades at Basilisland from which they refuse to
                    retreat despite the repeated volleys of the troops. They are also trying to
                    erect barricades on the Nevsky Prospect.</p>
                <p>At five o’clock the hiring was going on in every quarter of the city. The troops
                    were firing recklessly, but one regiment is reported to have refused to fire.
                    All classes appear inflamed alike. A number of wounded officers fell into the
                    hands of the mob. Their swords and epaulettes were torn off. The ambulances are
                    busy everywhere. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>St. Petersburg, January 23.</dateline>
                <p>There was a lull in the fighting in the centre of the city during the evening,
                    but continuous firing was heard in the workers’ quarter at Basilislaud, which is
                    plunged in darkness.</p>
                <p>An accurate estimate of the casualties is impossible, but it is believed they
                    number l,500.</p>
                <p>It is rumoured that a force of strikers, marching on Tsarskoe Selo, were driven
                    back by the troops alter a sanguinary conflict. The centre of the city was
                    practically deserted during the evening, except for the troops who were camped
                    in the snow. Some infantry have been withdrawn and replaced by bluejackets.</p>
                <p>The troops destroyed the barricades at Basilisland soon alter their erection,
                    killing 30 persons. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>St. Petersburg, January.28</dateline>
                        <p>The troops prevented the rioters from going to Tsarkoe Selo. (Havas.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
                <head>ANOTHER JAPANESE SCARE.</head>
                <dateline>London, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>The "Times” has reason to believe that Admiral Rodjestvensky will not attempt to
                    reach the Far East for at least three months.(Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>London, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>The "Times” says that Admiral Rodjestvensky intends cruising in the western
                    waters of the Indian Ocean, thereby reliering France from her awkward position.
                    (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>Durban, January 22.</dateline>
                <p>A collier which has arrived here reports that the Baltic Fleet left Madagascar on
                    the 14th inst.</p></div><div type="item">
                <p>The fleet prepared for action on the 13th in consequence of rumours that the
                    Japanese were approaching. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>THE JAPANESE FLEET.</head>
                <p>George Town (Pulo Penang), January 21. Four Japanese warships have been sighted
                    off the Lankave Islands 40 miles north of Penang. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>NEW FRENCH CABINET.</head>
                <dateline>Paris, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>M. Loubet has asked M. Rouvier to form the Cabinet (Havas.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>Paris, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>President Loubet has summoned M. Rouvier. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <dateline>Paris, January 22.</dateline>
                <p>M. Rouvier has practically completed his Cabinet. The members have decided to
                    adhere to M. Combes’ programme.</p>
                <p>M. Delcasse is the Minister for Foreign Affairs. (Reuter.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>THE ROYAL CRUISE.</head>
                <p>Algiers, January 21. The Duke and Duchess of Connaught have left for Tunis.
                    (Havas.)</p></div><div type="item">
                <cb n="3"/>
                <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                <p>The Nubia (Sudan) Development. Co. (Ltd.) announce the third call of 5s. per
                    share, making the shares of the company fully paid.</p>
                <p>Salt and Soda Co. — Mr. E C. Friend, manager of the salt works at Mex, is leaving
                    the service of the Egyptian Salt and Soda Company very shortly.</p>
                <p>Arrest of Young Turk.—Capt. Ahmed Bey Said, the alleged “Young Turk,” arrested in
                    the Splendid Bar at Cairo last week, was set at liberty on Saturday
                    afternoon.</p>
                <p>Abbas Helmy Theatre.—Signora Gemma Belincione will leave Venice to-morrow en
                    route for Alexandria, where this celebrated Italian singer has been engaged for
                    the Abbas Helmy Theatre.</p>
                <p>Suez Canal. On the 19th inst. 15 vessels passed through the Canal, 10 British, 2
                    French, 1 Austrian, 2 Swedish. The receipts for the day were frs. 484,450.03,
                    making the total amount received in dues from 1st inst. frs. 7,201,701.98.</p>
                <p>Alhambra Theatre. — As their stay is drawing to a close, we should advise all,
                    while there is yet time, to go to the Alhambra and hear the clever duettists
                    Raphael and Colombel, who are taking the place by storm. The fact that they
                    appeared at the Alhambra in London for close on three months is a sufficient
                    indication of their talents.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                <p>We do not hold ourselves for the responsible opinions expressed by our
                    correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit - within
                    certain neccessary limits - free discussion</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>CAIRO JOURNALISM.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                    <p> Dear Sir,—I beg to enclose the copy of a letter, which I have sent to the
                        Managing Editor of the “Egyptian Graphic," and I hope that in the interests
                        of every British subject, as well as those of justice and fair play, you may
                        see your way- to inserting it in the columns of your worthy and esteemed
                        paper, which has always to my knowledge (of 20 years) refrained from what
                        can only be designated as “stabs in the dark. Thanking you in
                        anticipation,</p>
                    <p>l am,</p>
                    <p>Yours very truly,</p>
                    <p>J. W. Conodon.</p>
                    <dateline>Cairo, 22nd January, 1905.</dateline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Monsieur Alfred Grégoire,</p>
                    <p>Managing Editor "Egyptian Graphic,"</p>
                    <p>Cairo.</p>
                    <p>As through the medium of the "Egyptian Graphic" No. 3 of 15th inst., of which
                        periodical you are the managing editor, you have thought it to udder a
                        grossly libellous and defamatory article against me in my proper name</p>
                    <p>I hereby give you the opportunity of publishing not only in the "Graphic,
                        “but in the un-mentioned, an article which shall, as far as possible, amend
                        the damage you have done me, together with your humble apology for the
                        scurrilous, dastardly and cowardly attack made, without the slightest
                        provocation, upon the reputation of a person you have had no dealings with,
                        either directly or indirectly, and, evidently, do not even know.</p>
                    <p>I demand also the name of the actual writer of the article in question, and I
                        will then decide upon what further action I shall take in the matter,
                        reserving now to myself my rights to sue you for damages or otherwise.</p>
                    <p>l am,</p>
                    <p>J. W, Conodon.</p>
                    <p>(A British Subject). The “Egyptian Gazette"</p>
                </div></div><div type="item">
                <head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A meeting of the Municipal Commission will be held at 4 o'clock next
                        Wednesday, afternoon, when the following matters will be discussed:</p>
                    <p>1. Communications diverses.</p>
                    <p>2. Organisation des Services.</p>
                    <p>3. Classement du personnel.</p>
                    <p>4. Question relative aux membres provisoires de la Délégation.</p>
                    <p>5. Proposition do M. Cumbo, tendant à l'élaboration d'un arrête prescrivant
                        le badigeonnage des maisons.</p>
                    <p>6. Proposition de Mr. Zouro au sujet des pouls publics et projet de la
                        Délégation &amp; oet égard.</p>
                    <p>7. Demande de crédits et virements.</p>
                    <p>8. Réglement ot application du droit sur les carrières.</p>
                    <p>9. Offre de Mr. O. Joseph pour la construction d'une jetée promenade au Port
                        Est.</p>
                    <p>10. Nominatiou d'un ingéniour on remplacement de Mr. Marichal.</p>
                    <p>11. Expropriations et excédents do Tanzim.</p>
                </div><div type="item">
                <p>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</p>
                <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                    Management. Moderate charges. Patronised by officers of Army of Occupation.
                    Concerts twice daily.</p></div><div type="item">
                <cb n="4"/>
                <head>THE BALL AT ABBEEN.</head>
                <head>DETAILED REPORT.</head>
                <p>It was announced on Wednesday that the list of invitations to the Ball given By
                    his Highness the Khedive on the 20th instant was closed, over 1,400 invitations
                    having already been issued. Judging from the crowded aspect of the rooms at
                    Abdeen Palace on Friday evening, there can have been but few absentees from
                    this, the most important social function of the Cairo Season.</p>
                <p>In view of the enormous number of his guests, the Khedive confined himself to
                    receiving only the most important, among whom H.R.H. Prince Gustavus Adolphus of
                    Norway and Sweden was, of course, the principal. An Egyptian guard of honor
                    escorted the Prince from Shepheard's Hotel to the palace, where he arrived about
                    half-past ten. Prince Mohamed Aly Pasha and other members of the Khedivial
                    House, the whole of the Diplomatic Corps, the Ministers, and the officers of the
                    Army of Occupation and Egyptian Army, as well as all the leading members of the
                    English and foreign communities, were also present.</p>
                <p>The scene was of truly regal magnificence. The gilded saloons brilliantly
                    illuminated, formed a fitting background to the array of gorgeous uniforms and
                    beautiful gowns and the dazzling display of orders and jewels. In the ball-room
                    the private bond of the Khedive played a spirited selection and dancing was kept
                    up with great vigour, Prince Gustavus Adolphus and the members of his suite
                    proving themselves adepts at this fast vanishing art.</p>
                <p>In the early part of the evening the Khedivah received a number of the lady
                    guests in a saloon near the ball-room. The Khedive entertained the principal
                    guests of the evening at sapper in a private room, the large supper room was
                    thrown open at midnight and the long tables which lined it on three sides were
                    immediately besieged. In a short time the vast saloon became so crowded that it
                    was difficult to find standing room. The fare provided was of the most sumptuous
                    kind, and almost justified the scramble that was made to procure it.</p>
                <p>Amid such a galaxy of pretty dresses it is difficult to single out any for
                    special remark. The Countess of Cromer wore a stately gown of oyster-white’
                    satin; Mme. van der Does de Villebois looked well in a mauve dress, and her
                    daughters wore frocks of pale yellow and pale blue Crepe de Chine respectively.
                    Mrs. Pindlay was in a black dress with sequiu trimming. Lady Palmer wore light
                    blue arranged with cream-colored net. Lady Rogers also wore blue, a striking
                    gown ot dark, 'royal blue’ shade, relieved by white muslin and lace at the neck
                    and sleeves. Another most effective gown was worn by Mi»s Slade ; this was of
                    chiffon-velvet in a pale shade of yellow, with a pompadour desigu of red roses
                    and other flowers upon it : made in the princess style, it was bordered by a
                    deep, transparent flounce of black sequined lace over cream colour. Pink was the
                    prevailing color. Mrs. Mellwraith wore it, and Miss Royle's gown of the same hue
                    was very dainty and becoming. Madame Harari Pasba was attired in a smart frock
                    of orange-pink silk. Mrs. Arnold Perry’s costume of white mousseline de soie
                    patterned with pale pink roses was admired. Mrs. Hunter wore a picturesque frock
                    of black taffetas, the skirt gathered very full and the bodice à la Marie
                    Antoinette, a band of laoe-like passementerie simulating the wide effect of the
                    fichu which it replaced. Mrs. Watson looked exceedingly well in white satin with
                    flounces of fiue point d Alençon lace, and her war medals as her only ornaments.
                    Mrs. Hooker wore cre'pe de Chine of a deep violet shade. Chiffon-velvet, rucked
                    and tucked, and the skirts arranged in a multiplicity of full, rich folds, was
                    the dernier cri of fashion. Mme. de Martino Pasha wore a handsome pale-blue gown
                    of this material ; Mrs. Campbell was in grey velvet. Taffetas, very sheeny and
                    crisp, was much seen, and soft ‘Liberty’ satins were also popular. Fine nets
                    were much used, and spotted muslins were greatly in vogue for the toilette de
                    jeune fille. Another pretty girl's frock was of soft blue satin, with a
                    "three-decker' skirt, and a large bunch of Parma violets on the bodice. An
                    exquisite gown was of fine black net over white, arranged in Directoire style,
                    with narrow straps of black velvet ribbon across the front and a garniture of
                    pale blue tru-lover's knots and beautiful white lace.</p>
                <p>Among other representatives of the British colony we noticed Mr. and Mrs. A.D.
                    Alban, Mr. and Mrs. Archibald, Mr. and Miss Sheldon Amos, Mr. and Mrs. Anderson,
                    Mr. Aspinall, Dr. Beddoe, Birdwood Boy and Mrs. Birdwood, Mr. and Mrs. Brunyate,
                    the Very Rev. Dean and Mrs. Butcher, Mr. and Mm. Crawley, Mr. and Mrs. Courtenay
                    Clifton, Coles Pasha, Mrs. and the Misses Coles, Mr. and Mrs. Carey, Miss
                    Caillard, Corbet Bey, Mr. and Mrs. Dilbé-roglue, Mr. and Mrs. 8cott-Dalgleisb,
                    Major and Mrs. Garner, Sir William Garstin, Major and Mrs. Graham, Judge Halton,
                    H.E. Harvey Pasha, Mr. aud Mrs. Hooker, Mr. and Mrs. Hornblower, Mr. Harrison,
                    H.E. Johnson Pasba and Mrs. Johnson, Major and Mrs. L’Estrango Johnstone, Dr.
                    and Mrs. Keatinge, Mr. and Mrs. Kingsford, Littlewood Bey and Mrs. Littlewood,
                    Dr. and Mrs. Madden, Mr. and Mrs. Mellwraith, Dr. and Mrs. Milton, Mr. and Mrs.
                    Moore, Morice Bey, D. Morice Bey and Mrs. Morice, Sir Colin and Lady
                    Scott-Moncrieff, Mr. and Mrs. Molesworth, Dr. Mu-rison, Dr. and Mrs. Notan,
                    Purvis Bey and Mrs. Purvis, Sir Elwin and Lady Palmer, Mr. and Mrs. Arnold
                    Perry. Mrs. and Miss Rees, Mr. Reid, Sir John and Lady Rogers, Mr. and Mrs.
                    Rowlatt, Mr. and Miss Royle, Judge Royle, Dr. Sandwith, Dr. and Mrs.
                    Elliot-Smith, Judge and Mrs. Satow, Mr. Scott, Mr. and Mrs. Sheppard, Miss
                    Sheppard, Mr. and Mrs. Villiers Stewart, Mr. and Mrs. Stone. Mr. and Mrs.
                    Thubron, Mr. and Mrs. Verschoyle, Judge and Mrs. Willmore, Mr. Carter Wilson.
                    etc.</p>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <p>Soon after one o’clock the guests began. to depart, but.it was not until a much
                    later hour that the last of them had quitted the palace. The police arrangements
                    for control ling the carriages en route for Abdeen appeared to be very complete
                    ; a strong force commanded the entrance! to Abdeen Street and lined its whole
                    length. The queue was well preserved, but we are inclined to think that the’
                    manipulation of the traffic Joining the main from the side streets was not as
                    perfect as it has been on fermer occasions, and caused some unnecessary
                    delay.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                <head>DEPARTURE OF R.F.A.</head>
                <p>The 56th Battery, Royal Fiejd Artillery, has received orders to hold itself in
                    readiness to embark at Alexandria for England ou the hired transport “Dilwara"
                    about March 1 next.</p>
                <p> The Battery will be replaced in Egypt by No. 2 Company Royal Garrison Artillery,
                    which embarks at Southampton on the “Dil-wara” on or about the 14th proxo. and
                    will arrive at Alexandria about March 1.</p>
                <p>The transport “Sicilia" is due at Port Said on the 28th inst., on her way home.
                    Details for passage in this vessel will leave Cairo by the 6.15 p.m. train on
                    the 27th inst., and from Alexandria by the 3 30 p.m.. train same day.</p>
                <p>39 N.C.O.'s. and men of the 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade, with one officer and one
                    N.C.O. in charge, will arrive at Cairo by the 7.20 a.m. train on the 24th inst.,
                    from Khartoum, for embarkation in the transport “Sicilia" on the 28th idem, for
                    home.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>PRINCE LEOPOLD AT ASSOUAN.</head>
                <head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
                <dateline>Assouan, January 21.</dateline>
                <p>H.R.H. Prince Leopold of Battenberg and Dr. Stenhouse are back at the Cataract
                    Hotel, Assouan.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>THE HOLY CARPET.</head>
                <head>(From our correspondent.)</head>
                <dateline>Suez, Sunday.</dateline>
                <p>Thé Holy Carpet is expected to‘arrive At Suez by special train at noon to-morrow.
                    The procession will take place the same afternoon, and subsequently both Carpet
                    and Mahmal will be placed on board the Khédivial Mail liner "Rahmanieh” for
                    conveyance to Jeddah. Two other Khédivial mail steamers,tho "Dakahlieh” and "
                    Neghileh, ’’ will escort them, having oh board about 2,000 pilgrims. The total
                    number of Egyptians leaving this year for Mecca exceeds 16,000.</p>
                <p>Suez is unable to cope with such a rush, and consequently the majority of thé
                    pilgrims have had to camp out of the town, awaiting their turn to leave.</p>
                <p>It is noticeable that almost all the Egyptian pilgrims are well armed this year,
                    fearing an attack by the Bedouins en route to the sacredcity.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>KING OSCAR’S BIRTHDAY.</head>
                <p>In honor of the birthday of H. M. the King of Sweden and Norway, a dinner was
                    given on Saturday in one of the private saloons of the Ghezireh Palace Hotel by
                    Mr. C. Belinfante Ostberg to H. R. R Prince Gustavus Adolphus of i Sweden and
                    Norway.</p>
                <p>There wore present, besides his Royal Highness,LidyCromar, Lady Beatrice Thynne,
                    Boutros Pasha Ghali, General, Mrs. and Miss Slade, De Martino Pasha and Mme. De
                    Mar tino, Ahmed Zeky Pasha, Thurneyassen Pasha, Fabricuis Pasha and Mme.
                    Fabricius, Mr. add Mrs. Brugsch Bey, Baron Ralamb, Captain Swerre, Mr.
                    Borchgrevink, Mr. Monteur, Mr. Heggen, Prof. Jager, Mr. and Mrs. Hoy, Mr.
                    Thister, Mr. and Mrs. Silverhjein, and Mr. Mollen.</p>
                <p>Daring dinner Prinoe Gustavus Adolphos proposed the health of H. M. the King of
                    Sweden and Norway, Mr. Belinfante Ostberg proposed that of H. H. the Khedive and
                    also of H. R. H. Prince Gustavus Adolphus, the different national anthems being
                    played.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
                <p>According to the official report for the Week ending Saturday, 5 casés of bubonic
                    plague were reported during (he past week, 4 at Suez and 1 at Toukh. There were
                    3 deaths and 2 recoveries.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>CATTLE PLAQUE.</head>
                <p>During the week ending Saturday, 9 deaths only were reported, viz, 1 at Port
                    said, 1 each at Baltim (Markaz Borollos) and Seb-dassis (Markaz Mehallet el
                    Kobra), in the Gharbieh province, and 6 at Shantour, Market Bibeh, Beni Souef.
                    During the corresponding week of 1904, 5,065 deaths were reported. During the
                    past week 884 animals have been inoculated. The total of deaths hitherto
                    reported amounts to 146,791.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>POST OFFICE SAVINGS BANK.</head>
                <head>EXTENSION OF SERVICE</head>
                <p>From 1st February next the poet offices at the following places will be admitted
                    to transact Savings Bank business Kom Ombo, Omria, Armant, Matarieh (near
                    Manzala), Shibin El Kanater, Bilcas, Matai, Badrashein, Rodah,-Nakada, Abou
                    Matamir, Koubbeh, Minsha, Kutur, arid Ibrahimieh (Ramleb).</p></div><div type="item">
                <cb n="6"/>
                <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                <p>The Bishop of Delaware preached at St George s Church, Cairo, yesterday.</p>
                <p>The Earl of Crawford, K.T., who is at present staying at the Tewfik Palace Hotel,
                    Helouan, is having his auxiliary steam yacht "Valhalla" fitted out at Cowes for
                    a long cruise. The vessel is to leave port in a few weeks’ time to take her
                    owner on board.</p>
                <p>The Hon. Mrs. Ronald Greville has left London for Cannes en route for Egypt</p>
                <p>Among the passengers by the Orient liner “Orizaba,” due at Port Said on
                    Wednesaday, are the Earl and Countess of Morton ‘ the Hon. W. F. D. and Lady
                    Esther Smith, and Lord Herschell.</p>
                <p>The restaurant at Shepheard's presented an animated appearance on Friday evening,
                    when a number of people were dining there previous to attending the Khedive's
                    Ball H. R. H. Prince Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden and Norway was present. Judge
                    Halton entertained a party of five. We also notioed Mrs. Campbell, with a party,
                    and Mr. Carter Wilson among the diners. This restaurant is, nowadays, one of the
                    pleasantest dining places in Cairo, and the catering and servioe are in every
                    way equal to what is met with* at the best hotels in Europe.</p>
                <p>Capt. H. S. Logan, of the Leicester Regiment, has been appointed Bimbashi in thé
                    12th Sudanese Battalion.</p>
                <p>Lieut. N. McD. Teacher has been appointed Bimbashi in the 10th Sudanese.</p>
                <p>We are glad to hear that Mr. James Opie, secretary of the Khédivial Mail Line who
                    has been laid up for the last six weeks at the Deaconesses’ Hospital,
                    Alexandria, with a severe attack of smallpox, is now quite convalescent and has
                    left the hospital.</p>
                <p>Amongst the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said are Mr. and
                    Mrs. Weekes, Mr. E Pach Mr. J. Sohaar, Mr. &amp; B. Solano, Mr, D. A. Croall,
                    Mr. W. J. Murphy, Mr- B Roy Mr. D. Dirk, Mr. and Mrs. Asldy, Mr. and Mrs.
                    Rendle, Miss Rendle, Miss Brorter, Mr. and Mrs. Hardy, Mr. Zdandevist, Mr. G.
                    Robin, Mr. Daerks, Mr. Kisch.</p>
                <p>The following passengers left Shellal by the “Prinoe Abbas” yesterday: Miss
                    Crewdson Miss Lindesay, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Vanderpoel, Mr. and Mrs. Rayual, Mr.
                    and Mrs. Brauer, Miss Waterhouse, Mr. Wm. Johnston, Miss E W. Johnston, Mr. and
                    Mrs. Ambrose Congreve, Dr. and Mrs. Dub,Col. Robt. J. Pratt Saunders, C. B., Mrs
                    H. Schou, Capt. Ulgo Bedinello, Miss Augusta Bedinello, Mr. Girardelii, Mr.
                    Swindells, Miss Booth, Mr. F. Maitland, Miss Maitland, Misses Wauchope.</p></div><div type="item">
                <head>SAVOY SMALL DANCE.</head>
                <p>Last Saturday's small dance was attended with the usual success. The restaurant
                    was again quite full, and an additional private dining-room bad to be converted
                    into a restaurant to accommodate all who had ordered tables. The list of diners
                    would take up too much space. We may however mention Tueni Bey’s party,
                    including Prinoe Djamil Toussouo, Prince Aly Paxil and Princess Fazil, M.
                    Raphael Suares, Mme. and Mile. Sursock, M. and Mme. Michel Tueni The Duke of
                    Montremart was with Prince de Tonnay Charente and Marquis d’Audriffed Pasquier.
                    M. and Mme. Çhoremi were with M. and Mme. Benacbi and M. and Mme. Trehaki. Mr.
                    Thubron had a party of 6 ; Mr. Charles Royle a party of 7, including Miss Royle,
                    Mr. and Mrs. Drummond-Hay, and Dr. and Mrs. Warnock ; M. de Bilinsky a party of
                    8, including Mr. and Mrs. Adams, Mr. and Mrs. Garret, Miss Pidgeon, and Miss
                    Walford ; and Mr. Goshen’s party included Capt. and Mrs. Lyons, Mr. and Mrs.
                    Mansfield de C. Findlay, and Mr. Greville</p>
                <p>We also noticed Lady Clarke, Mrs. Jay, Mr. Carter Wilson, Major E Herbert, CoL
                    Watson, M. and Mmb. A. Cattaui, Mme. de Martino Pasha, Dr. Armstrong and a
                    part}- of 6, etc.</p>
                <p>The restaurant was also well filled for sapper.</p>
                <p>Owing to the increasing success of the Savoy small dances, the management has
                    decided to give an extra small dance on Tuesday, 31st inst. The Saturday’s small
                    dance will take place every week as usual.</p>
                <p>There will also be a small danoe on Friday evening next, after the concert
                    organised by the Comité des Fétes.</p></div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten miniutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo
                        alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p> 2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p></div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

