<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexander Caliendo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-30">November 30, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-10">April 10, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, APRIL 10, 1905.</head>
                <head>MEETING OF THE FLEETS. RUSSIANS AND JAPS CLOSING. ENGAGEMENT EXPECTED. </head>
                <p>PENANG, April 8. Steamers arriving here report the sighting of both Russian and
                    Japanese warships in the Straits. An engagement is expected. (Reuter.) LONDON,
                    April 8. The Standard learns from Singapore that 27 warships, believed to be
                    Japanese, have been sighted emerging 70 miles to the south west of Penang.
                    (Reuter.) SINGAPORE, April 8. The British S.S. Tara reports that she sighted 17
                    Russian ships 130 miles north of Singapore. (Reuter.) SINGAPORE, April 8. 4p.m.
                    The Russian warships, including 25 transports, are now passing Singapore,
                    steering north east. (Reuter.) SINGAPORE, April 9. The Baltic fleet, composed of
                    6 battleships, 9 scullers, 8 destroyers, 3 converted Hamburg-American liners, 3
                    volunteer ships, 16 colliers, one salvage ship and one hospital ship was
                    steaming at a speed of 8 knots. The fleet showed evidence of a long voyage in
                    tropical waters.All the ships had seaweed along their waterline. The fleet
                    passed 7 miles out and, consequently, exchanged no salutes. The Russian Consul
                    visited the Vice Admiral’s ship and conversed from a launch without going on
                    board. The fleet was burning soft coal giving off tremendous smoke which was
                    visible for miles. The fleets submarine men were at their posts all day, and on
                    the alert, and the fleet disappeared eastwards at 5 o’clock in the afternoon.
                    There is no further news regarding the Baltic fleet. (Reuter.) SINGAPORE, April
                    10. The Baltic fleet mentioned yesterday did include the most important fighting
                    units, the flagship “Kniaz Suvaroff,” the “Imperial Alexander II,” and the
                    “Borodino”-with the implement of cruisers and destroyers. Their whereabouts are
                    unknown. (Reuter.) </p>
                <p>THE CHINA SQUADRON. HONG KONG, April 8. The China squadron is preparing for sea.
                    H.M.S. cruiser “Sutlej” sails for Singapore today. (Reuter.)</p>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KING’S CRUISE. ARRIVAL AT PORT MAHON. </head>
                    <p>MARSEILLES, April 8. The King and Queen have left for Port Mahon. (Reuter.)
                        PORT MAHON, April 9 . The King and' Queen of England have arrived here.
                        (Reuter.) PORT MAHON, April 9. King Edward has arrived and was greatly
                        cheered. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INSURRECTION IN CRETE. </head>
                    <p>Canea, April 10. The Situation in Crete is more serious in consequence of the
                        elections. The British cruiser ”Juno,” with British, French, and Italian
                        detachments, has gone to Selinos, where disturbances are taking place.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN ARRESTS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 8. Several members of the Moscow Medical Congress have
                        been arrested. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OBITUARY.</head>
                    <p>London, April 9. Rt. Hon. Sir Francis Henry Jeune (Lord St. Helier) and Lord
                        Chelmsford are dead. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME FOOTBALL</head>
                    <p>BELFAST, April 8. Association.—Ireland v. Wales. Two goals each.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Windsor Pharmacy Kasr-el-Nil Square, CAIRO. BEST CHEMICAL PRODUCTS. English
                        and Foreign prescriptions carefully prepared by certificate chemists. ALWAYS
                        IN STOCK LARGE ASSORTMENT OF ENGLISH PROPRIETARY ARTICLES AND SPECIALTIES.
                        CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM. Near Shepard’s AND Continental Hotels. Turkish Baths,
                        Plain Baths, X RAYS, Electric Light Baths. GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.
                        2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WAR. TWELVE HOURS FIGHT JAPANS TURNING MOVEMENT.</head>
                    <p>ST. PETERSBURG, April 8. Linievitch reports a 12 hours fight on the 4th inst.
                        to the north of Csangtufu. The Japanese losses are considerable. The
                        Russians lost 10 men. (Reuter.) Kharbin, March 9. There is no doubt that the
                        Japanese are attempting a turning movement under the orders of General Oku.
                        (Havas.) ST. PETERSBURG, April 9. On the occasion of the regimental fates,
                        Generals Kuropatkin and Linievitch telegraphed to the Emperor reporting the
                        splendid bearing of the troops, whose devotion to the throne is unbounded
                        and whose confidence in an ultimate future victory is fervent and
                        unshakeable. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAGUE</head>
                        <p>During the week ending Saturday 42 deaths from bovine typhus were
                            reported throughout Egypt, as against 4,205 deaths during the
                            corresponding period last year.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INTERNATIONAL CHAMBER OF COMMERCE</head>
                        <p>We may remind those interested that the statutory general meeting of
                            this Chamber will be held at the Grand Continental Hotel, Cairo,
                            tomorrow at 4 p.m. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUEZ CANAL</head>
                        <p>14 vessels passed through the Canal on the 6th inst. 11 of which were
                            British, 2 French, 1 German. The day’s receipts were frs. 409,488.67
                            making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 2,049,625.15. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WAKF’S ADMINISTRATION</head>
                        <p>has appointed Maitre Frederick W. Simond, the well known member of the
                            bar of the Alexandria Mixed Tribunals, to the important position of
                            official counsel to that administration. This selection has given great
                            satisfaction. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MENA HOUSE DANCE</head>
                        <p>The last small dance of the season at Mena House Hotel will take place
                            this evening at 9.30 o'clock. There will be a special late tramway
                            service on this occasion. Mr. A. Bracale’s orchestra will play during
                            dinner and later on the terrace. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALHAMBRA THEATRE</head>
                        <p>A special gala performance is to be given this evening in honor of H. R.
                            H. the Duke of the Abruzzi and for the benefit of the unfortunate
                            artistes of Gatti’s circus troupe. The crew of the Italian cruiser are
                            to be present at the performance, which will be taken part in by several
                            artistes of Gatti’s circus. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INTERNATIONAL CHAMBER OF NAVIGATION</head>
                        <p>At a general meeting of the members of the International Chamber of
                            Shipping, held on Saturday, the committee which has been in office since
                            the creation of the Chamber, was unanimously re-elected for a further
                            period of three years. The committee is composed as follows:-—Messrs. J.
                            Ricard,president; F. Allen and G. Barker, vice-presidents ; E Minotto,
                            secretary ; F. Baldovino, Th. Ivanoff, H. de Pitner, and A.Stross,
                            members. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BANDMANN DALLAS OPERA COMPANY</head>
                        <p>The long-expected return visit of this excellent combination is now
                            definitely announced in our advertising columns. An exceptionally
                            attractive programme has been arranged, including all the latest musical
                            comedy successes from London, and commencing with “A Country Girl" on
                            Saturday, 22nd inst. The Khedive, the Earl of Cromer, and Brig General
                            G.M. Bullock have given their patronage to the performances, which will
                            be held at the Khedivial Opera House. The prices, considering the
                            expense of such a large company, are most reasonable, and even off these
                            subscribers for the eight performances receive 20 percent discount,—a
                            liberal offer which is sure to be fully taken advantage of. The
                            subscription opens tomorrow at the box office of the Khedivial Opera
                            House. This time a thoroughly good orchestra has been secured, made up
                            almost entirely of the Opera House orchestra. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Anatolia” is expected here from Odessa on Thursday night,
                        and will begin loading for Liverpool immediately. The Moss line “Tabor”
                        sailed from Liverpool on Friday afternoon last, and is due here about the
                        21st inst. with passengers, mails, and general cargo. the Messageries
                        Maritimes S.S. “Senegal,” from Marseilles, passed the Straits of Messina on
                        Sunday afternoon and is due here tomorrow. The S.S. “Ararat,” of the
                        Papayanni Line, left for Liverpool yesterday afternoon. The S.S. “City of
                        Khios,” of the Papayanni Line, arrived at Liverpool this morning. The S.S.
                        “Belgravian,” of the Papayanni Line, is expected from Constantinople
                        tomorrow morning and will leave for Liverpool in a few days. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ASSOUAN DAM. NEW THEORY OF STRAIN EXPLAINED.</head>
                    <p>(FROM A CORRESPONDENT.) London, April 3. There has hardly been time yet to
                        have received the criticisms of the wise men of Europe and America on the
                        recent decisions of the Egyptian Government to postpone—for tho present-the
                        completion, as some eminent men are pleased to call it, of the dam at
                        Assouan by increasing the height by some eighteen feet. Such men do not care
                        to commit themselves in a hurry when a fresh proposition, of a nature such
                        as this, is first put before them. We must have patience yet before we can
                        expect to receive the general opinions of scientific authorities. For one,
                        however, who has been familiar with all the details of this great work from
                        the commencement, as is tho case with the consulting engineer, Sir Benjamin
                        Baker, it is not surprising that he should give the public the benefit of
                        his views, however slight, as early as possible. They have indeed a right to
                        expect it. Sir Benjamin has informed a reporter of the "Daily Mail” that
                        this decision of tho Egyptian authorities is by no means entirely due to tho
                        theories recently propounded by the learned mathematicians. Primarily it is
                        due, according to Sir Benjamin, to the fact that during his recent visit he
                        found it neccessary to advise the authorities that the apron, or floor of
                        masonry, a small portion of which was put down last year, must be extended
                        along the whole length of the dam, so as to protect the base of the
                        structure from any mischief in future, such as might be caused by the great
                        rush of water through the sluices which at times, when it rises to the sixty
                        feet level, has such a pressure that it flows through the sluices at the
                        rate of over 36 miles an hour. The diagrams below, which I have taken from
                        the “Daily Mail,” will better enable your readers to understand this:— In
                        the opinion of several engineers with whom I have discussed the question,
                        this alone is sufficient reason for “going slow” for the present, although
                        some think the necessity for this work should have been foreseen from the
                        commencement and therefore undertaken earlier. However that may be, the
                        decision is considered a wise one, if there were no other reason to justify
                        it. But there is yet another reason, for some months ago the theory of Mr.
                        Atcherley and Professor Karl Pearson that the stresses are also in a
                        vertical direction as well as horizontal, was propounded in a pamphlet,
                        which, as soon as it came into the hands of the Egyptian authorities set
                        them, “a-thinking." Their consulting engineer was called out to examine and
                        discuss the theory on tho spot, with the result as is known. I hate seen
                        some hard things said of the Egyptian authorities as to their action being
                        too sudden, and influenced more by the present condition of land speculation
                        than the question of the stability of the dam. These ideas have found little
                        favor among those who know Egypt,—quite the contrary. It is thought that the
                        country should be congratulated as having a strong and capable Government,
                        who at once took the public into their confidence, and told them the true
                        state of affairs. Nothing could justify the Government in taking the
                        slightest risk on what for Egypt is a most interesting question. If anything
                        were to happen to the dam—of which now there is not the slightest chance—it
                        would mean that, the Blue Nile would in future would have to be spelt Blue
                        Ruin, so fearful would be the consequences of its escape. No doubt this has
                        been a disappointment to several people, who are interested in helping to
                        develop the uncultivated lands of Egypt, and who were rightly expecting that
                        the additional supply of water would soon enable them to do this. Some of
                        these are adversely criticizing the action of the Government, as for the
                        moment they have received a cold douche. But are they justified, in face of
                        all the facts which have been given to the public? If they only have
                        patience they will get all the water they want, and this sooner than is
                        generally anticipated. Land companies, which are started under proper
                        auspices and conditions, will no doubt do a great deal of good for this
                        country; for they not only find the necessary capital and organization which
                        the fellaheen have not got, but they also bring the land into cultivation
                        and a paying condition, with a view to selling it to the natives afterwards,
                        so that eventually the people will own a still further quantity of land than
                        at present. This is all in the right direction and “marking time," which the
                        “dam question" now calls for, can only be for the good of the country, from
                        whatever point of view it is looked at. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE AGRICULTURAL BANK.</head>
                    <p>The following calculation, received from a Cairo .correspondent, will be of
                        interest to the shareholders of tho above company:— £1,250,000 Ord shares
                        earn 9% = £112,500 £13150,000 Prof. „ „ „ = 112,500 £2,500,0003% + i%
                        Sinking Fund „ „ = 225,000 £450,000 Less expenses, say, £70,000 (They were
                        £45,000 last year) Statutory Reserve5 % on interest collected 22,300
                        National Bank of Egypt 9,600 Div. to Shareholders 5% on £1,250,000 . 62,500
                        4 Dividend to PreT Shares 50,000 3* '/ to £2.590,000 of Bonds plus * %
                        Sinking Fund 100,000 314,600 £135,400 of which half goes to Deferred
                        Shareholders leaving £67,700 This sum is sufficient to distribute a
                        supplementary dividend of nearly 5*%, which, added to the original, 5 %,
                        divided gives a total dividend which could be given to present shareholders
                        of 10.45 %. These figures do not include the net profit earned on overdrafts
                        at the National Bank of Egypt, which is an unknown and variable quantity,
                        but which must nevertheless be considered as an important factor in any
                        estimate of profits. The effect of issuing £1,250,000 new shares of £5 each
                        will be as follows. Existing shareholders will lend another £5, making a
                        total of £10 advanced by each shareholder on the old and new issues. The new
                        issue put out at 9%. will yield a gross profit of £112,500 Deduct 5%
                        dividend on the new issue £62,500 . 2% for expenses revolved by the
                        extension of the business £87,500 £25,000 -------- £25,000 We have £25,000
                        to divide equally among deferred shareholders and the combined issues of
                        ordinary shares. The position will then be as follows. 5% dividend on
                        original issue of 1,250,000 £62,500 * of "Surplus profit of £135,400
                        available for distribution £67,700 5% dividend to 2nd issue of £1,250,000
                        £62,500 * of surplus profit earned on1-2nd issue of ordinary shares £12,500
                        £205,200- or sufficient to pay a dividend of about 8*/, on the total issued
                        ordinary share capital of £2,800,000; Assuming that these figures are
                        correct, with the price of money at 4%, if, as we believe, one new share is
                        to be offered at par to every existing shareholder for each share of the old
                        issue in his possession, the combined values of the eld and new share will
                        be at least £20 and the value of the old share to-day £15. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST &amp; INVESTMENT.</head>
                    <p>This morning, the subscription for the-Egyptian Trust and Investment
                        (Limited) opened at the Anglo-Egyptian Bank in Cairo and Alexandria and the
                        rush to subscribe is simply phenomenal. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER EGYPTIAN FLOTATION.</head>
                    <p>The City Notes of the “Globe" of Monday last foreshadow a new Egyptian
                        flotation. After giving some details as to the Egyptian Trust and
                        Investment, our London contemporary remarks: —this is not the only flotation
                        of importance which is imminent in the Egyptian market. A concern of the
                        first magnitude is being talked of in certain City circles, which would own
                        various concessions and have a total capital of £600,000, of which £450,000
                        would be allocated to working capital. It remains to be seen, of course,
                        whether theo nature of the concessions is such as to afford sufficient
                        justification for the expenditure of so large a sum upon them. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN LAND AND INVESTMENT</head>
                    <p>The allotment of shares and the posting of letters of allotment,- letters of
                        regret, and cheque*, wore effected by midnight on Sunday. The allotment
                        arrangements were placed in the hands of Messrs. Russell and Kerr, and the
                        rapidity with which the operation was effected has given great satisfaction
                        in financial circles. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HELLENIC BANK.</head>
                    <p>The first official meeting of the provisional board of directors of the new
                        Hellenic Bank of Cairo was held yesterday morning at the offices of
                        Rostovitz Bey. The capital will probably be increased to £200,000 sterling.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE NAVIGATION.</head>
                    <p>Nile traffic is increasing every day, and the number of freight barges and
                        tourist steamers is always on the increase. There is, however, plenty of
                        room for development both in the freight and passenger services, and the
                        Germans intend to have their share of this lucrative and growing business.
                        The Hamburg-America line has decided to construct six river steamers of
                        light draught for use on the Nile. The vessels will be luxuriously fitted.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A REGRETTABLE INCIDENT. SCHOLARS ON STRIKE.</head>
                    <p>A regrettable incident, or rather a series of incidents, has taken place at
                        the Polytechnic School at Ghizeh. It appears that last Tuesday a pupil, on
                        being told to sit on a certain bench, objected that there was water on it,
                        and, backed the objection by comments that resulted in his being reported to
                        the head master. It seems that be refused to apologize and was “sent down”
                        for a week, whereupon a number of his fellow students sent in a petition on
                        his behalf. The petition was not granted and his sympathetic friends struck
                        work for a day. This was too much, and the writer of the petition was also
                        “sent down” on Thursday last Friday was a dies non, and on Saturday the
                        pupils returned in the morning and having arranged a plan of campaign
                        departed in the afternoon, and on to the present have not returned. Only
                        four appear to have declined to join the strike. The situation is not
                        pleasant and great sympathy is felt with Dr. Mackenzie, the head master,
                        whose relations with his pupils have always been excellent It is impossible
                        to say what will be the upshot of this movement among the pupils. We are
                        inclined to think that it has been engineered from Cairo “poor embeter les
                        Anglais.” </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MEHKEMEH SHARIEH REFORM.</head>
                    <p>At a meeting of the General Assembly, held yesterday, a motion was carried
                        urging the reform of the Mehkemeh Sharieh. This is especially interesting in
                        view of the fact that the General Assembly, on the last occasion that it was
                        convoked, supported a resolution to the effect that the Mehkemeh Sharieh
                        needed no refund whatever. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL ASSEMBLY.</head>
                    <p>On Saturday the General Assembly approved the following proposals which it
                        has decided to transmit to the Government: 1. To construct drains in Cairo.
                        2. To reduce the fees on wakfs, those of “ailoula and insha’ and those on
                        mortgages. 3. To construct the Esneh barrage at Jebel Sireg (Edfou) and
                        raise pumps in Upper Egypt. 4. To make the El Ramadi Canal ‘Sefi.’ 5. To lay
                        a railway between Nag Hamadi and Edfou. 6. To lay an agricultural light line
                        between Esneh and Abou Shousha. 7. To construct a permanent weir at
                        Damietta. 8. To widen the Damietta Boghaz. 9. To create registration bureaux
                        in the provinces. 10. To modify the Sharaki regulations. 11. To reform tho
                        Mehkemeh Sharieh. The demand for the creation of a Municipality at Cairo was
                        rejected by the Assembly after some discussion. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AL AZHAR.</head>
                    <p>A petition has been addressed to the Grand Mufti by several hundred students
                        of Al Azhar, begging him to resume his course lectures on the Koran. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DUKE OF THE ABRUZZI.</head>
                    <p>This morning Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of Alexandria, and Miralai
                        Hopkinson Bey, Commandant of the Alexandria City Police, called on the Duke
                        of the Abruzzi, on board the “Liguria,” in order to return the Prince’s
                        visit to, the Gouvernorat on Thursday last. The Italian colony at Alexandria
                        deserve to be heartily congratulated on the success of the ball given last
                        night in honor of the visit of H.R.H. the Duke of the Abruzzi and the
                        officers of the Italian cruiser "Liguria.” The New Khedivial Hotel had been
                        elaborately prepared for the occasion. The ball-room was graced by a large
                        portrait of the King of Italy, set up in front of the entrance, surrounded
                        by flowers. Nearly a thousand invitations had been sent out and there was a
                        most brilliant and representative gathering of all the leading members of
                        Alexandrian society. Tbe ball began at 9.30 p.m. and dancing was kept up
                        with great vigour until an early hour this morning. A well-stocked buffet
                        was prepared for the guests and a splendid supper was served at midnight.
                        The committee of organisation was constituted as follows : — Judge
                        Commendatore Moriondo, of the Mixed Court of Appeal, chairman ; Commendatore
                        Paoluoci, M. Luigi Stagni, M. Amabile Cumbo, Dr. Valensia, Dr. Torella, M.
                        A. Tilche, M. Piha, Avvocate Pennazzi, M. L. Bianchi, M. G. Degiarde, M.
                        Nicholas Sabba, M. Bellantuonis. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ CANAL COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>At a meeting of the council of the Suez Canal Company, held on the 3rd inst,
                        Dr. L.H. Ruyssenaers, Secretary-General of the Hague Court of Arbitration
                        and former Dutch Minister at Lisbon, was selected to fill the vacancy on the
                        board caused by the death of Mr. Auslijn, formerly Dutch Consul-General in
                        Egypt. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A LESSON FROM SPAIN.</head>
                    <p>The terrible catastrophe, announced in our telegrams from Madrid, of the
                        bursting of a huge reservoir with a large loss of life, should afford food
                        for grave reflection to all those who consider that the recent action of the
                        Egyptian Government, in refraining from heightening the Assouan Dam, is a
                        sign of needless timorousness. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>RUSSIAN REFUGEES.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.) Port Said, Friday. At noon today the German Lloyd
                        "Princess Alice” arrived, having on board some 150 odd Russian refugees from
                        Port Arthur. These were all transferred in lighters to the Russian S.S.
                        “Imperatrice Maria,” in waiting. This last is to sail during Saturday
                        morning for Odessa. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREEK INDEPENDENCE DAY.</head>
                    <p>Today being the anniversary of the declaration of Greek independence, a great
                        fete has been in course of preparation. This morning a crowded Greek church
                        testified to the great interest taken in the fete, and with the Greek
                        consular officials in full regalia, with numerous other uniforms, a
                        distinctly interesting and novel sight was the result. This evening a
                        special piece was played by a Greek theatrical company now here, at the
                        Eldorado, the official representatives of the Greek Government gracing the
                        theatre with their presence. After the play a public ball was held in the
                        auditorium at which considerably over 700 people assisted, principally as
                        spectators. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="navalNotes">
                    <head>NAVAL NOTES.</head>
                    <p>Port Said, Sunday. H.M.S. “Mutine," sloop, left Port Said this morning
                        homeward bound from the Australian station, where her place will be taken by
                        H.M.S. "Pegasus,” which left Suez on Friday. H.M.S. “Diadem," first class
                        cruiser, arrived on Saturday, She is bound to China to relieve H.M.S.
                        "Amphitrite.” H.M.S. "Pylades," third-class cruiser, Commander da Costa, is
                        now in the Canal, homeward bound from Australia. The French cruiser
                        “Chateaurenault" (Capt de Castries) arrived at Port Said early Saturday
                        morning from Colombo bound for Cherbourg. She has a crew of 630 men and
                        carries 8 guns. The German despatch vessel "Lorely” (Capt and Lieut.
                        Bruneninghaus arrived at Port Said at 8 a.m. today from Alexandria and
                        leaves at 5.30 p.m. for Jaffa. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALVAGE OF THE “CONGAL.”</head>
                    <p>Operations have at last been started on the Norwegian ship “Congal”, which,
                        it will be remembered was sunk in harbour by the Harrison liner "Craftsman’’
                        and has for a long time lain there, causing great inconvenience to the Canal
                        Company. The Constantinople Salvage Association were approached by the
                        owners and insurers of the vessel and two of their salvage steamers have
                        been here, but left again without doing anything, and it appears that they
                        asked £60,00 for raising her. This sum was not accepted. She is insured for
                        £5,000 and is vessel of some thirty years old, so It Is easily understood
                        that the Insurers would have nothing to do with the salving of her at such a
                        cost. The result was that a court case was started, and she was handed over
                        to the Canal Company to do what they wished with her. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The Empress Eugenie has arrived at Marseilles from Egypt and is making a stay
                        at Cap Martin. The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire have arrived in London
                        from Egypt. Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of Alexandria, and his wife and
                        son, are leaving Alexandria on June 17 by the Austrian Lloyd steamer for
                        Bridisi. His Excellency will travel through Italy and France and then will
                        proceed to England, where he will remain about a month. His Excellency will
                        leave his son in England in order to complete his education at the
                        University. - A lunch was given by the Circle Artistique at Cairo on
                        Saturday morning in honor of Coquelin Cadet with whom were Mme Moreno, Mile
                        Bouchatal, M. Jean Coqnelin, and M. Montoux. Among those present were Prince
                        Haidar, Comanos Pasha, Caetelli Bey, M. L Cattani, Dr. G. Veronoff, Me.
                        Carton fle Wiart Margosoff.Bey, Mahmoud Bey Sadik, M. L. Betrand, M. G.
                        Vidal, M. P. Oziol, and many others. Mr. Constantino Meimararhi, Managing
                        Director of Walker and Meimarechi Ltd., has arrived at the Carlton Hotel,
                        Bulkeley, for a few days.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate charges.
                        Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi
                        Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management. 11.11.906 EDEN PALACE HOTEL,
                        CAIRO. Open all the year round. ELECTRIC LIGHT, -LIFT.- MODERATE CHARGE.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>


            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
