<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Charlie Rymer</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-03</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">Monday, August 21, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="item" n="1">
                    <h1>STRUGGLE FOR PEACE.</h1>
                    <h2>JAPANESE CONFIDENT.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>ROOSEVELT AND ROSEN.</h2>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 19.</h3>
                        <p>The Conference has adjourned until Tues
                            day afternoon when the protocol will be signed.
                            Meanwhile the plenipotentiaries will consult
                            their respective Governments. The final deci-
                            sion rests with Tokio and St Petersburg. It is
                            noteworthy that the Japanese representatives
                            are confident of peace which is in contrast with
                            the Russian talk of failure.
                            The Conference disagreed on Article XI. but
                            agreed to Article XII: granting to the Japanese
                            fishing rights on the Siberian coast.	(R.)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 19.</h3>
                        <p>It is stated that M. Witte has declined to
                            entertain Article XI., but has intimated that
                            Russia has no intention of maintaining a naval
                            force in the Far East constituting a threat to
                            Japan and other Powers.
                            Baron Rosen will dine with President Roose-
                            velt to-night It is oonolnded that Mr. Roose-
                            velt is endeavouring to prevent a rupture of
                            the negotiations.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 20.</h3>
                        <p>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 20.
                            Baron de Rosen conferred for an hour with
                            President Roosevelt. It is known that before
                            inviting Baron de Rosen, President Roosevelt
                            secured the active and cordial support of Great
                            Britain, France, and Germany. He also com-
                            municated with the Mikado.	(Renter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (U.S.A.), August 19.</h3>
                        <p>President Roosevelt has called Baron de
                            Rosen to Oyster Bay, having a message to
                            communicate to him.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>LORD CURZON RESIGNS.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 20.</h3>
                        <p>It is officially stated that Viscount Curzon,
                            Viceroy and Governor-General of India, has
                            resigned. Mr. Balfour has communicated the
                            resignation to the King.	{Ranter)</p>
                        <p>Though Reuter’s brief telegram gives no
                            reason for Lord Corzon’s resignation, it is im-
                            possible to avoid the inference that it is in
                            some way connected with the recent dispute
                            between Lord Kitchener and the Viceroy. It
                            was generally stated and believed that the
                            dispute had terminated in a satisfactory com-
                            promise, but from the latest acoounts it seems
                            only too probable that after experience of the
                            actual working of the compromise, Lord Cur-
                            ton found it less satisfactory than it had ap-
                            peared on paper. On the other hand Lord
                            Curzon has now been seven years in India, hav-
                            ing been reappointed Viceroy in 1904, and is
                            known to be feeling the effects of the climate
                            and the hard work which his position involves.
                            Here, we hope, will be found the true cause of
                            his resignation, for the fact that a Viceroy had
                            retired in consequence of a dispute with the
                            Commander-in-Chief in India would be painful
                            to all who have the true interests of the Empire
                            at heart.</p>
                    </div>
                    <h2>THE CHANNEL SQUADRON.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PACIFIC GERMANY.</h2>
                        <h3>Amsterdam, August 19.</h3>
                        <p>The Channel Squadron is being feted in the
                            most cordial manner in Holland. It is stated
                            that the Channel Squadron will visit Stockholm
                            and Copenhagen.	{Renter)</p>
                        <h3>Berlin, August 20.</h3>
                        <p>The “Norddeutsche Allgemeine Zeitung” in
                            an article evidently inspired, and intended to
                            allay the excitement prodnoed by the cruise of
                            the Channel Squadron, says that the Baltio
                            visit is merely a reply to the repeated visits of
                            German warships to British ports, and that
                            every sober minded Briton or German hopes
                            that the visit will contribute to the mutual
                            esteem between the two great civilised nations.
                            ( Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Ebbirg, August 20.</h3>
                        <p>The Channel Squadron has arrived here.
                            (Renter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</h2>
                        <h2>THE ALGERIAN CHIEFS ARREST.</h2>
                        <h3>Berlin, August 19.</h3>
                        <p>Germany has instructed Count Tattenbach
                            to co-operate with the French representatives
                            in order to secure satisfaction for the arrest
                            of the Algerian chief.	(Renter) </p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>GERMAN EAST AFRICA.</h2>
                        <h2>MURDER OF MISSIONARIES.</h2>
                        <h3>Berlin, August 19.</h3>
                        <p>Bishop Spies and four missionaries have
                            been murdered in German East Africa. The
                            Governor has requested reinforcements. (R)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE FRENCH SENATE.</h2>
                        <h3>Pars, August 90.</h3>
                        <p>M. Bourgeois has been elected Senator of
                            the Marne.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>HOME CRICKET.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 19.</h3>
                        <p>Australians beat Northamptonshire by 829
                            runs. Sussex beat Hampshire by 87 runs.
                            Yorkshire beat Essex by 198 runs. Kent beat
                            Somerset by an innings and 7 runs. Worces-
                            tershire brat Gloucestershire by 8 wickets.
                            The rest of the matches were drawn. (R)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="2">
                    <h1>LOCAL AND GENERAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
                        Ain el Sherns district to-morrow night and at
                        dawn of the 29nd inst will be poisoned by the
                        police.</p>
                    <p>Sale of Land.— Mr. Antonio do Beneducoi
                        has sold to the Egyptian Estates, Ltd a
                        portion of his family's estate, for about half a
                        million francs.</p>
                    <p>A Charitable Gift.—The secretary of the
                        St. Andrew's Waterside Church Mission bas
                        received a donation of £100 from ‘ C.G.T.”
                        for the Lady Strangford Hospital, Port Said.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—18 vessels passed through
                        the canal on the 17th inst., of which 9 were
                        British, 9 German, 1 French, 1 Russian. The
                        day's receipts were frs. 356,262.96, making the
                        total from the 1st inst frs. 5,156,156.38]</p>
                    <p>San Stefano Casino.—A grand ball with
                    cotillon will be given at the San Stefano
                    Casino on Saturday next. The ball will be
                    reserved entirely to subscribers, who will not
                    receive tickets of invitation, their subscription
                    tickets taking the place of them.</p>
                    
                    <p>Fayoum Liqht Railways.—The receipts of
                    the Fayoum Light Railways Company during
                    the first ten days of the present month amount-
                    ed to L E 668.037 as compared with L.E.
                    598.857 during the corresponding period last
                    year, thus showing an increase of L.E 69.230.</p>
                    
                    <p>Coal Imports.—From the 1st of January
                    to the 16th August, 592,859 tons of coal were
                    imported into Egypt. Wales sent 323 641, New-
                    castle 138,232, Scotland 74,028, Yorkshire
                    33,934, and other places 23,024 tons. During
                    the same period of last year 617,911 tons were
                    received.</p>
                    
                    <p>The Cotton-Worm.—In consequence of the
                    practical extinction of tho cotton-worm, the
                    Ministry of the Interior has struck off the list
                    of employes temporarily appointed to cotton-
                    worm duty, twenty three moawins idara, or
                    head clerks, and ordered them to return to
                    their duties in the Gharbiah and Behera
                    moudiriehs, their-services being no longer
                    required.</p>
                    
                    <p>Brutal Assault.—A Berberin boy, while
                    crossing the street at Minet-el-Bassal, saw a
                    carriage bearing down on him. He rushed to
                    the pavement and had the misfortune to tread
                    on the foot of an Italian named Giuseppe
                    Polias. This brute, in an outburst of ill-temper,
                    caught the boy, struck him in the face, and
                    stabbed him in the nook with a knife, inflicting
                    a serious wound. The Italian is still at large.</p>
                    
                    <p>Attempted Suicide.—A young Greek girl
                    of eighteen years of age attempted to commit
                    suicide last Saturday by throwing herself from
                    thereof of a house in the Moharrem Bey quarter.
                    She was severely injured and will require at
                    least three week's medical treatmentbefore she
                    can reoover. The girls gives as tflb reason for
                    this attempt on her own life, that she was
                    thwarted in love, but refuses to give any details.</p>
                    
                    <p>Killed by a Mule. — On Saturday Aid
                    Ramadan, an arbagi, took a mule to water at
                    El Azarito, Mohsrrem Bey. He appears to
                    have tied the end of the rope by which he led
                    the animal round his waist. Being suddenly
                    alarmed, the male dashed off at full gallop,
                    and the unfortunate man fell and was dragged
                    along for some distance. His injuries were so
                    serious that he expired before he could be
                    carried to hospital.</p>
                    
                    <p>Cattle Plaque.—Four deaths from cattle
                    plague were notified in Egypt during the week
                    ending last Saturday, all of them occurring in
                    the Sannoures district (Fayoum province). The
                    number of deaths during the corresponding
                    period last year was 409. Since the commen-
                    cement of the epidemic the total number of
                    deaths amounts to 147,437, distributed as
                    follows.— Gouvernorats 894 ; Lower Egypt
                    54,291 ; Upper Egypt, 93,251.</p>
                    
                    <p>Tram Accident.—A tram car carrying goods
                    collided on Saturday evening with a passenger
                    car which had stopped at Carlton station. The
                    driver of the goods tram appears to have been
                    suddenly attacked by a fit of giddiness, and to
                    have fallen down a few seoonds before coming
                    in sight of the passenger tram. Deprived of
                    guidance his tram ran straight into the car,
                    which had halted at tbe station. Both
                    trams were derailed by the shock, but happily
                    no passengers sustained injuries. The driver
                    of the passenger car received a wound in the
                    left band, which will require four days’ treat-
                    ment. The driver of the other tram car will be
                    under medical care for five days.</p>
                    
                    <p>Bubonic Plague. — The plague bulletin
                    issued by the Sanitary Department for the
                    week ending last Saturday shows a welcome
                    reduction in the number of cases which were
                    notified, and the number of localities in which
                    the cases ocurred is reduced to one, namely
                    Alexandria. The number occurring was seven,
                    three of which are Europeans. Three recoveries
                    and three deaths are reported, and there now
                    remain thirteen cases under treatment, twelve
                    of which are at Alexandria, and one at
                    Dekerness. The total numbers of cases since
                    January amounts to 228, Compared to 775
                    during the corresponding period last year.
                    Yesteday’s bulletin reports one death and one
                    recovery at Alexandria. The fatal case was
                    that of a native woman, who was found dead
                    at her house in the Mobattea Bay quarter.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="3">
                    <h1>ABBASSIEH DESERT OASIS.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE ELECTRIC RAILWAY.</h2>
                        <p>The electric railway for whioh Boghos Pasha
                            Nubar and M. Empain gained the concession
                            at the same time as the muoh talked of Oasis
                            conoession, will start from the end of the
                            Rue Djellal, where it joins the Sharia Boulac
                            at the new Dalra Khasaa buildings, and cros-
                            sing it, will proceed past the Pont-Limoun
                            station, in the Plaoe Bab-el-Hadid, and along-
                            side the Boulevard Abbas to the Pont de
                            Ghamreh, whence it will run parallel to the
                            Marg line as far as Koubbeh, and thence across
                            the desert to the terminus, the whole length
                            being between eight and nine kilometres. The
                            speed allowed on this electric railway will be
                            seventy kilometres an hour, whilst the tramways
                            only run at between twelve and fifteen kilo-
                            metres, so that the entire distance from point
                            to point can be effected in a quarter an hour
                            or so, including stoppages on the way.
                            A tramway line will also be laid from their
                            property to the terminus at Abbassieh of the
                            tramway Company, and will be worked in
                            conjunction with the latter. This line will
                            cross that of the State Railway by a 'raised
                            metallic structure, lightly built, and supported
                            by, iron pillars. The plans and estimates for
                            the two lines are now being prepared, and it is
                            expected that the work will be taken in hand
                            in the course of the next three or four months
                            and take a year to complete.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                            <h2>THE NEW ESNEH BARRAGE</h2>
                            <p>We mentioned recently in these columns
                                that the Government proposed to construct
                                a new barrage at Esneh, and that the Mini-
                                stry of Public Works had prepared the specifi-
                                cations for the works.
                                This new barrage is intended to hold up
                                the Nile flood for the irrigation of such lands
                                in Upper Egypt as are now deprived of water
                                during the period of a low Nile, and come
                                under the designation of "sharaki." Had this
                                dam been at present in existence the full
                                effect of the existing low flood would in all
                                probably not have been felt or, at all events
                                would have been minimised. The work will
                                take three years at least, the same time as
                                the Assiout one took, as it can only be done
                                in the spring and summer when the river is
                                at its lowest.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CAIRO TRAMWAY COMPANY.</h2>
                        <p>In our issue of 80th Jane last we mentioned
                            that the Tramway Company were making
                            considerable alteration on their old Cairo line
                            between Kaar-el-Nil square and Poum-el-
                            Khalig. These alterations comprise the doub-
                            ling of the line for a distance of abont two kilo-
                            metres, and the removal of the present single
                            line from the carriage way, in order to allow
                            that part of the road to remain entirely free for
                            vehicular traffic. The new double line is being
                            laid on one side, and a pavement is being
                            made between for pedestrians. These improve-
                            ments, which were necessitated by the con-
                            stantly increasing traffic, will avoid the delays
                            occasioned by there being only one line;
                            besides improving the carriage-way, which, in
                            future, will be ten metres wide. The work is
                            expected to be completed by the beginning of
                            next month, when the new service will com-
                            mence.
                            Mr. Dessales, the General Manager of the
                            Company in Cairo, is returning from Italy
                            sooner than was expected in consequence of
                            several matters that require his attention in
                            connection with the many extensions and new
                            lines about to be begun, and will arrive by
                            the Rubattino steamer due on Sunday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE KORONFISH INCIDENT.</h2>
                        <p>Baruc Youzsef, and Ibrahim Isaao Levi, the
                            Israelites who opposed such a vigorous resist-
                            ance to the police who had entered a suspect-
                            ed hashish establishment, have been questioned
                            by the Parquet and deny the truth of the
                            charge brought against them. They assert
                            that they were passing by the house into which
                            the police had forced an entrance, when the
                            sister of one of them called to them from the
                            window, appealing for assistance against
                            burglars who had got into the house. As
                            they tried to enter, a man in civil dress
                            stopped them at the door, and threatened
                            them with his sword-stick. Thinking that the
                            man was in league with a gang of thieves they
                            threw him on the ground, and snatched away
                            his stiok. This attracted a large crowd and
                            everyone thought that it was a fight with
                            thieves, the police agents being in plain
                            cloathes. The Sheikh el hara declared that he
                            heard that thieves were attacking a house and
                            on going to find out what was happening, and
                            received a shot in the abdomen.
                            In spite of all inquiries made up to the
                            present, it has not, as yet, been discovered by
                            whom the police agent was wounded. An
                            Armenian, amongst whom some of those who
                            were involved in the trouble took refuge, has
                            been questioned by the Parquet, but with no
                            definite result. In the meanwhile, the two
                            Israelites have been handed over to the care of
                            the French Consulate to await developments.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</h2>
                        <p>The Ellermah S.S. City of Oxfprd sailed on
                            Saturday for Malta and Liverpool, with general
                            cargo including 2,368 bales cotton.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="4">
                    <h1>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>AUSTRIAN BMPBROR'S BIRTHDAY.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent).
                            Port Said, Sunday.
                            The anniversary of the birth of the Austrian
                            Emperor Francois Joseph was celebrated here
                            yesterday by the Austrian residents, “en fete.”
                            A high mass was held at the Church of St.
                            Kugenie attended by the Austrian Consul and
                            staff. This was followed by a reception which
                            in its turn gave place to a dinner held in
                            the garden of the Eastern Exchange, during
                            and after which the Lyra band played selec-
                            tions. Festivities were kept up till a late
                            hour.</p>
                        <h2>PLAGUE ON BOARD SHIP.</h2>
                        <p>The S.S. Riverton, whioh on arrival at Suez
                            appears to have had a doubtful case of plague
                            on board, was there granted “free pratique."
                            but on arrival at Port Said yesterday the
                            case for some time engaged the attention of
                            the quarantine officials, who declared it bona
                            fide plague and removed the patient to the
                            segregation depot. No communioation with
                            the shore was allowed, and the vessel left
                            in strict quarantine in the course of the after
                            noon for Malta.</p>
                        <h2>CONGRATULATIONS.</h2>
                        <p>It is with much pleasure that I announce
                            the receipt here of news from England of the
                            birth of a son to Mr. and Mrs. Tarrel Mr.
                            Tarrel is the director of Customs in Port Said,
                            and is well known to the inhabitants of Alex-
                            andria, in which town he spent some years
                            of his life.</p>
                            
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>LARGE PROPERTY SALE IN CAIRO.</h2>
                        <p>The large fine block of buildings situated
                            opposite the new Museum of Antiquities in
                            the Sharia Abbas, which belongs to the Mis-
                            sion Afrioaine, has been sold to Madame Fink,
                            the former proprietor of the Pension Fink, which
                            is now being demolished, for £17,000,including
                            the value of the site of nearly 1,000 square
                            metres. The building, which is four storied and
                            was erected about four years ago at a cost of
                            £18,000 approximately, produces now an annual
                            rental of some £900, and in it are the head
                            offices of the Tramway Company. The present
                            owner seems to have made a good bargain, for
                            when the new boulevard Abbas is completed,
                            and the leases of the present tenants expire
                            in abont 1 1/2 years the rents of the several
                            apartments are likely to be increased.
                            The Mission Africaine have a plot of vacant
                            building land in tbe vicinity, of 3,800 square
                            metres, for which an offer of purchase at £7 to
                            £8 per square metre has just been refused, as
                            it is expected that the contemplated improve-
                            ments, and the making of the boulevard, will
                            be certain to cause an increase in the value of
                            land in this district.</p>
                        <h2>THE SARKIS AFFAIR</h2>
                        <p>Now that the unnatural mother, who was
                            recently found guilty of employing her own
                            children for immoral purposes, and profiting
                            by their gains, has been punished, we should
                            like to know if any measures have been taken
                            to protect these minors, who must need the
                            most careful education, and the strictest guard,
                            after their demoralising experience. The sen-
                            tence on the mother was well deserved, but,
                            what has been done, now that the children
                            are left fatherless, and temporarily motherless,
                            without relations or friends, to protect them
                            from similar dangers in the future.
                            There seems to have been a certain want of
                            enterprise in the court which condemned the
                            woman Sarkis, but, to judge from its silence
                            on the matter, made no attempt to find out
                            who were the persons who had committed
                            the offences of which the court had ample
                            evidence. Morally they are as guilty as the
                            victims of the law, and it is most unfortunate,
                            in our opinion, that no attempt has been made
                            to take proceedings against them. Are they
                            all protected by the Capitulations.</p>
                        <h2>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</h2>
                        <p>By kind permission of Lieut-CoL C. J. Mark-
                            ham and Officers, 1st Bn. King’s Royal Rifles,
                            the band will perform the following programme
                            of music at the Ezbekiah Gardens to-morrow
                            (Tuesday) evening, commennng at 9 o’clock.</p>
                        <div type="advertisement"></div>
                        <div type="advertisement"></div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="5">
                    <h1>NOTES FROM CYPRUS.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>TREATMENT OF CATTLE.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)
                            Nicosia, August 17.
                            The export of cattle to Egypt continues.
                            Attention has bean drawn from time to time
                            in the "Egyptian Gazette” to the vary lax
                            methods practised in the shipment to end
                            disembarcation at Port Said of cattle from
                            Levantine ports, and some interesting com-
                            munications on the subject between certain
                            Egyptian authorities were lately published in
                            the columns of your journal, which strikingly
                            revealed the need of improvement in this
                            matter. I am assured that a shipment of
                            cattle from Cyprus to Egypt rarely takes
                            place without deaths ooourring from over-
                            crowding, or other ill-treatment The animals
                            are little, if at all, fed or watered while on the
                            journey, and if report be true, they often stand
                            in several inches of powdered gypsum, the
                            particles of which fill the air of the hold, and
                            tend to make Hie all hot insupportable to tbe
                            wretched beasts. Tbs often expressed opinion
                            that this state of things oosts thousands of
                            pounds to Cypriot exporters is probably no
                            exaggeration. There are both in Egypt and
                            Cyprus societies for the prevention of cruelty
                            to animals Could not they go into the subject
                            jointly, and draw np a report oontaining
                            practical suggestions for the consideration of
                            the authorities responsible for the shipping
                            regulations t The existing regulations, it would
                            seem, are either not enforced, or stand in need
                            of drastio revision, both in respeot of the spaoe
                            allowed per beast, the feeding, and the water-
                            ing. Whatever the standing regulations may
                            be, it would appear to be necessary that an
                            authorised official should accompany each ship-
                            ment to see that they are duly earned out
                            The present needless waste and depreciation
                            of animal life is deplorable, and exporters
                            would be wise if they agreed to pay a slightly
                            higher rata of freight in order to insure their
                            cattle arriving in sound and healthy con-
                            dition.</p>
                        <h2>AGRICULTURAL NEWS.</h2>
                        <p>At this time of year whole villages are
                            deserted in some parts of the Island, the
                            occupants having taken up their summer
                            quarters in the fields in order to protect their
                            ripening crops, e.g. figs, melons, olives, colo-
                            cynths, etc. This is by no means an unneces-
                            sary precaution, as many small thefts are
                            reported to the polive. The villagers erevt
                            little shanties of reeds, brushwood,etc., and the
                            owners of fig trees, especially, often find ex-
                            cellent shade beneath their wide-sprrading
                            branches. Sumach is now being collected from
                            the vineyards, the leaves of which are dried
                            and ground, and exported to Syria and else-
                            where for use in tanneries. Remunerative
                            prioee are obtained. Some promising fields of
                            ootton, of tha “Peteririn" variety, are to be
                            seen near Morphou. They are flowering well.</p>
                        <h2>NICOSIA-FAMAGUSTA RAILWAY.</h2>
                        <p>Now that the railway is open to traffic on
                            the Nicosia-Famagusta track, the question of
                            appointing officials is to the fore. There is a
                            laudable desire to give posts, as far as possible,
                            to Cypriots, but there must be considerable
                            difficulty in selecting the applicants—of whom
                            there are a great number—very few of whom
                            have ever seen a train. We hear of chemists’
                            oompounders, domestic servants, etc. becoming
                            stationmastors, train guards, and so forth, and
                            whether this is so or not, there must neces-
                            sarily be many suoh anomalies in the oase of
                            the first introduction of a railway into any
                            country. The native press would wish to see
                            all the appointments filled by natives and at
                            high rates of pay, but a little reflection on
                            their part should oonvinoe them that at least
                            the more responsible officials should be trained
                            and experienced men, and these are not to be
                            be found at present among the Cypriots. The
                            minor, unskilled officials oould hardly expeot
                            wages at the same rate of pay as the higher
                            olass men, though in time, no doubt, they will
                            beoome competent to fill the better paid posts.</p>
                        <h2>OUR VISITORS.</h2>
                        <p>The two sons of Sir Charles and Lady King-
                            Harman arrived in Cyprus last week to spend
                            their school holidays here. Messrs. Percy and
                            Wilfrid Christian have recently arrived from
                            England. Major French, R.A.M.C., and Mrs.
                            French sail this week for England on long
                            leave. Major French has been ill for some
                            time, but is now rapidly recovering his health.
                            Mr. E. 0. Antonades, of Alexandria, is at
                            present at Larnaca, superintending the erection
                            of a girls’ school, which he is building there
                            at a cost of about £1,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</h2>
                        <p>Colonel C. Rawnsley, D.S 0., commanding
                        Army Service Corps in Egypt, has been granted
                        sick leave for two months from the 23rd
                        instant.</p>
                        
                        <p>Judge and Mr. Alston are leaving Marseilles
                        for Egypt on the 22st September by the P. and
                        0.S.S. China.</p>
                        
                        <p>Captain and Adjutant J. H. Davidson, 1st
                        KRR Corps, has had his leave extended to
                        the 30th September.</p>
                        
                        <p>Mr. A. T. MCKillop, of the Finance Minis-
                        try, is returning by tha P. and 0. S.S. Arabia,
                        sailing from Manefflea on the 15th September.</p>
                        
                        <p>Dr. Herbert Milton and Dr. D. M. Beddoe
                        an expedted back in Cairo on tbe 27th
                        proximo.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="6">
                    <h1>OBITUARY</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>A GREAT PAINTER</h2>
                        <p>Paris, August 90.
                            The painter Bouguereau has died. (Havas)
                            Adolphe William Bouguereau, a French
                            painter, and Member of the Institute, was born
                            at La Rochelle, Nov. 80, 1835. He began life
                            in a business house at Bordeaux, but obtained
                            permission to attend the drawing school of M.
                            Alaux for two hours a day. His fellow-pupils
                            treated him with contempt on account of his
                            business connections, and when, at tho end of
                            the year, he gained the first prize, the excite-
                            ment was so great that a riot ensued, and a
                            formal protest was made by the pupils against
                            his receiving it, but without effect. He then
                            turned all his attention to painting, and enter-
                            ed the studio of Pieot, in Paris, and later
                            entered the Boole des Beaux Arts, where his
                            progress was rapid. In 1850 he went to Rome,
                            and in 1854 exhibited “The Body of St Cecilia
                            borne to the Catacombs,” since which time he
                            has occupied a leading portion among the
                            artists of the Modern French School. His next
                            great work was “Philomela and Proone” 1861.
                            Both these pictures are now in the Luxem-
                            bourg. “Mater Afflictorum,” or “Vierge Con-
                            solatrice,” 1876, was purchased by the French
                            Government for 19,000 franca. Among his
                            pictures exhibited at the Salon may bd men-
                            tioned "The Bather,” 1870; "Harvest Timd”
                            1879; "The Little Marauders,” 1878; “Homer
                            and his Guide,” 1874 ; Flora end Zephyna,”
                            1875; "Pieta,” 1878; "Youth and Love," 1877;
                            "The Scourging of Our Lord," 1880; “Lie
                            Virgin with Angela,” 1881; “Slave Carrying a
                            Fan,” 1882; "The Youth of Bacchus,” and
                            "Byblis," 1885; “Love Disarmed,” 1888; Love
                            Victorious,” 1887; "Baigneuaoa,” 1888; “Psyche
                            and Lore,” 1889 ; “L’Amour MouilM,” 1901.
                            M. Bouguereau executed the mural paintings
                            in the St Louis Chapel of the Church of St
                            C.otilde, and in the Church of St Augustine.
                            Many of his pictures have been engraved by
                            Francois</p>
                        <h2>SIR WILLIAM CLOWES.</h2>
                        <p>Sir William Laird Clowes, the well-known
                            naval critic and writer, passed away at St
                            Leonards last Monday; at the early age of
                            forty-nine years, having been born in 1856 at
                            Hampstead. Deceased, who was knighted in
                            1902, was the eldest son of William Clowes
                            some time one of the Registrars in Chancery.
                            Educated successively at Aldenham, King’s
                            College, London, and Linobln’e Inn, he at the
                            last moment abandoned the Bar for journalism,
                            and wrote on technical subjects, chiefly naval,
                            subsaquently devoting himself to research
                            in naval history. Some of his papers on the
                            condition of the Navy have been translated
                            into many languages, and have probably, for
                            good or evil, had an enormous influence upon
                            naval as well as public opinion. He served on
                            the Arts and General Committees of the Royal
                            Naval Exhibition of 1891, gained the Gold
                            Medal of the United States Naval Institute in
                            the following year, was elected a Fellow of
                            King’s College, London in 1896, and was
                            chosen an hon. member of the Royal United
                            Service Institution, before which he had more
                            than once lectured, in 1896. He was the author
                            of numerous books, indnding “The Naval
                            Pocket-book,” "The captain of the Mary Rose,”
                            “Blood is Thicker than Water;” and others.
                            Little more than two years ago, in the preface
                            to his "History of the Royal Navy,”he wrote,"
                            "Begun at a time when I was in my usual good
                            health. Volume I. was still in the rough when
                            I was attacked by a malady which, though its
                            action is sometimes slow, seldom spares the
                            life of its victims ; and in consequence I was
                            suddenly ordered away from England, where
                            alone I could have prosecuted the work under
                            conditions entirely favorable. Except during
                            intervals, I had to remain abroad or in the
                            Channel Islands until the autumn of 1909.”
                            Sir William married in 1882 Ethel, second
                            daughter of the late L.F. Edwards, of Mitcham.</p>
                        <h2>CAPTAIN R CECCONI.</h2>
                        <p>Our Suez correspondent writes :—
                            It is with the deepest regret that I have to
                            announce the sad death at Bert of Captain R
                            Ceoooni (Capitaine d’armement) of the Suez
                            Canal Company.
                            Captain Cecconi died yesterday afternoon at
                            4 o’clock at his residence at Port Tewfik after a
                            short illness. His funeral took place at 4 p.m.
                            to-day, and was attended by the whole Euro-
                            pean communities of Suez and Port Tewfik.
                            Numerous wreaths were sent by his friends.
                            Several officials of the Suez Canal Company
                            specially came to Suez from Ismailia and Port
                            Said, and were present at the funeraL
                            The deoeased had served the Canal Company
                            for 30 years, and his death is greatly regretted
                            by all who knew him. All steamers in port and
                            the shipping agencies have their flags at half-
                            mast.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advertisement"></div>
                    <div type="advertisement"></div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>