<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexander Caliendo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-25">October 25, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-14">April 14, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. REPORT OF FIGHT UNCONFIRMED. POSITION OF FLEET.</head>
                    <p>Singapore, April 13. H.M.S. cruiser ”Sutlej” passed the Baltic feet 550 miles
                        to the north-east of Singapore, hence Dutch report regarding the fighting
                        near the Anamba Islands is discredit. (R.)</p>
                    <p>Amsterdam, April 13. The report of the fighting between the Rus- sian and
                        Japanese fleets near the Anamba Islands is not confirmed. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>Singapore, April 13. The P. &amp; O. "Nubia", sighted the Baltic fleet on
                        Monday, 200 miles south-east of Saigon. The fleet was steaming north-east.
                        This disposes of the report of fighting near the Anamba Islands.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ETHIOPIAN RAILWAY. NEGUS'S FIRM ATTITUDE.</head>
                    <p>Adis Abeba, April 12. The Emperor Menelik has summoned the representatives of
                        the Powers to his Palace, and notified them that, unless they come to an
                        agreement regarding the extension of the rail- way towards Ababa, such
                        agreement providing for the maintenance of the independence of Abyssinia and
                        the internationalisation of the railway, he will construct such extension
                        him- self, his decision being final.</p>
                    <p>This fact is noteworthy in view of M. Deleasse’s speech on the 2nd inst.,
                        when he strongly objected to the internationalisation of even the second
                        section—the construction of which Menelik had already authorised—and
                        declared that both should retain a French character, frr which a French
                        subsidy was to be granted. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE "ENTENTE CORDIALE.”. ENTERTAINING FRENCH SAILORS.</head>
                    <p>London, April 13. In connection with the visit of the French fleet to London,
                        the Corporation will entertain the officers at the Guildhall on the 10th
                        August. Arrangements are also being made for the sailors to march through
                        the city. The Atlantic Squadron will visit Brest early in July.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FISCAL FIGHT. PROBABLE "MODUS VIVENDI."</head>
                    <p>London, April 13. The remarks of Mr. Chamberlain, in his speech at the
                        Liberal Union Club, praising Lord Lansdowne’s exposition of the fiscal
                        policy, which the latter made in the House of Lords on Tuesday when he
                        repudiated pro- tective taxation on food, are regarded as likely to lead to
                        the adoption of a “modus vivendi” between the opposing sections of
                        Ministerialists. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PANAMA CANAL. WORKS TO BE COMMENCED.</head>
                    <p>Washington, April 13. It has been decided to commence the Panama Canal works
                        immediately, and to engage 2,000 Chinese and 2,000 Japanese coolies.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL CRUISE.</head>
                    <p>London, April 13. Their Majesties left the Balearic Islands for Algiers,
                        where they will stay two days. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KAISER AT CORFU.</head>
                    <p>Corfu, April 13. The British Admiral gave a dinner, in honor of Emperor
                        William and the King of Greece. The Emperor has left for Messina. (Havas.)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE S.S. “HINDOO” RELEASED.</head>
                    <p>Singapore, April 13. Tho S.S. “Hindoo," having given a bond, has been
                        released. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEWMARKET RACES.</head>
                    <p>London, April 13. Craven Stakes- 1, St. Oswald ; 2, Shilfa; 3, Ray Hastings.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management.</p>
                    <p>21.11.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Hellenic Assize Court will open its session at Alexandria on May
                            14.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria at 8.30 a.m. on
                            Sunday. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Maltese Benevolent Society acknowledges with thanks the receipt of
                            P.T. 200 from an anonymous donor. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Port Arthur Garrison.</head>
                        <p>Twenty officers of the Port Arthurtr garrison-left Alexandria to-day by
                            the Russian steamer for Odessa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Popular University</head>
                        <p>A concert reserved to adherents of tho university will be held on Monday
                            next, commencing at 9.15 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Slave Trade</head>
                        <p>The Slave Trade Repression Department freed eleven slaves during March,
                            ten of whom were Sudanese and one Circassian.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Upper Egypt Hotels</head>
                        <p>The Council of Ministers will approve of the formation of the Upper Egypt
                            Hotels Company at its next meeting.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Sudden Death</head>
                        <p>A watchman employed by a wood merchant on the Marina was found dead
                            yesterday. Death was due to natural causes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Murderer Sentenced</head>
                        <p>Abou el Ella was sentenced to hard labour for life yesterday by tho
                            Native Tribunal at Alexandria for the murder of a fellah in Behora
                            province.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> New Company</head>
                        <p>There is some talk of the flotation of a new company which intends to
                            construct dwelling-houses in Cairo in view of the prevailing scarcity
                            and the high rent of dwellings.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Wreck</head>
                        <p>The Greek steamer, “Demetrious,” which was recently stranded on the
                            coast, near Aboukir, left dry-dock yesterday after being examined. Teo
                            damage done* to the vessel is estimated at £2,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Belgian Consulate</head>
                        <p>Our Constantinople Correspondent states that the Belgian Lega- tion there
                            has applied to the Sublime Porte for the exequatur for M. G. Riches, who
                            has beenn appointed Consul at Port Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head> Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>l2 vessels passed through the Canal on the 11th inst., 6 of which were
                            British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Austrian, 1 Norwegian, 1 Greek. The
                            receipts for the day were frs. 312,810.49, making the total from the 1st
                            inst. frs. 3,572,362.10.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Darb el Ahmar quarter of Cairo
                            during the night of Saturday and dawn of Sunday, and in the Gamalieh
                            district during the night of Sunday and dawn of Monday, will be poisoned
                            by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“The Suez Canal, its Origin, Construction, and Administration.”</head>
                        <p>The recent address given by Col. Sir Howard Vincent, M.P., to the London
                            Chamber of Commerce has been published in pamphlet from, price 1s, and
                            copies maybe obtained at Diemer's Library, Cairo. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Inhuman Daughter-In-Law.</head>
                        <p>A native woman fell from the roof of her house at Chatby and sustained
                            serious injuries. On being removed to hospital, she stated that while on
                            the roof with her daughter-in-law the latter gave her a push, which sent
                            her headlong into the street. The daughter-in-law has been arrested.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra</head>
                        <p>The members of Gatti's circus troupe, having partly replaced the
                            properties lost in the recent fire at the Abbas Helmy Theatre, are to
                            commence a series of perform- ances at the Alhambra tomorrow evening.
                            The usual circus entertainment will be given. The theatre will be closed
                            tonight for the necessary preparations to be made.</p>
                        <p>The Benefit Performance of the Giuntini circus on behalf of the members
                            of Gatti’s circus, victims of the fire at the Abbas Helmy Theatre, was
                            very successful and the sale of tickets realised frs. 4,650, which sum
                            has been handed to the Italian Consulate. All the ex- penses of the
                            performance have been paid by Mr. Rossano, the philanthropic
                            stockbroker.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Well-Directed Liberality</head>
                        <p>On the occasion of the marriage of his daughter, Idris Bey Ragheb gave a
                            donation of fifty pounds to the fund of benevolence of the National
                            Grand Lodge of Egypt. One third of this sum goes towards the upkeep and
                            education of orphan children, one third in annuities to aged and
                            distressed widows, and one third to relieve other forms of distress.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>St. Mark's Jubilee of Consecration</head>
                        <p>In connection with the commemoration of the jubilee of St. Mark's on the
                            25th inst., some may be glad to know of a series of very inte resting
                            articles on the history of St Mark's chaplaincy, written by Rear-Admiral
                            Sir Mas- sie Blomfield, K.C.M.G., in "Bible Lands”—a quarterly paper of
                            the Jerusalem and the East Mission. "Bible Lands” can be ordered through
                            Canon Ward. The subscription is 1s. per annum. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Bandmann-Dallas Opera Company</head>
                        <p>Owing to the great demand for seats for the performance of "A Country
                            Girl" by the Bandmann-Dallas Opera Company at the Eldorado Theatre, Port
                            Said, on the 20th inst., it was found necessary to open the booking
                            office yesterday, two days in advance of the advertised date for
                            booking. Those desirous of getting good seats should reserve them at
                            once, as they are all being rapidly snapped up.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>End of the Season</head>
                        <p>Spring has begun to make itself felt in Cairo, and although the rays of
                            the sun remind one already of the coming summer heat, the weather can
                            only be termed delightful. But with the advent of spring our visitors
                            leave the land of the Pharaohs, and carriage after carriage, bearing
                            passengers and luggage, may have been seen in the Cairo streets during
                            the past few days. In the hotels the furniture of some of the rooms is
                            already being stored away, and oven the number of carriages is being
                            reduced, —all signs that the season is nearing its end. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hotel Beau-Rivage, Ramleh</head>
                        <p>The beautiful weather at Alexandria just now is attracting a number of
                            visitors to the seashore, and the fashionable Beau Rivage Hotel is being
                            well patronised. Under the direction of Mr. G. Runckewitz, formerly
                            manager of the Grand Hotel Weber, in Antwerp, and tho Therapia Summer
                            Palace, in Constantinople, who has taken the Beau Rivage on lease for
                            several years, many improvements and alterations have been made for the
                            comfort of the hotel’s clients, and splendid accommodation may be
                            obtained for social functions, fetes, and ban- quets at the hotel, where
                            also promenaders may enjoy afternoon tea in the garden or on the
                            terrace. The excellent cuisine is a feature at this hostelry, and a
                            reliable European service throughout has been instituted by the
                            management. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mishap on the Line</head>
                        <p>The express which leaves Cairo at midday was an hour late yes- terday in
                            arriving at Alexandria owing to a mishap to a child. While the latter
                            was leaning out of a carriage window by Calioub another train passed,
                            and it is supposed the child received a knock and was thrown out on to
                            the line between the two trains. Both the trains were going at full
                            speed and it is extraordinary that the child was not fatally injured.
                            The train was brought to a standstill and reversed in order to pick up
                            the child, who was found close to Culioub. Scander Pasha Fehmy hap-
                            pened to be on the train and showed great energy in directing the
                            operations. When the child was discovered it was found that she had been
                            badly cut about the head. After being bandaged up and receiving first
                            aid the victim was put on the train and conveyod to Alex- andria. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Abani Pasha, Minister of War, arrived at Alexandria from Cairo yesterday.</p>
                    <p>H.E. the Governor went to Montazah this morning and attended prayers at the
                        Mosque there in company with H.H. tho Khedive.</p>
                    <p>Sig de Martini, Civil Governor of Erythrea, is expected at Alexandria on the
                        22nd inst. He willspend a few days in Cairo before proceed- ing to
                        Massowah.</p>
                    <p>Marquis Salvago-Raggi, Italian Diplomatic Agent, and Count Sorragna, Consul,
                        returned to Cairo yesterday after seeing tho Duke of the Abruzzi off.</p>
                    <p>Baron Acton, Italian Consul-General at Alexandria, is expected back from
                        Leghorn on the 23rd inst.</p>
                    <p>A native contemporary states that Hamada Pasha, local Director of Customs at
                        Alexandria, is to be transferred to the Wakfs Adminiatra- tion. </p>
                    <p>Mr. Ninci, commercial manager of the Sucreries d'Egypte Company at
                        Alexandria, left Alexandria yesterday for Italy by the Florio-Rubattino S.S.
                        “Memfi”on three months' leave of absence.</p>
                    <p>Among the visitors staying at the Beau- Rivage Hotel are : Lieut-Col. and
                        Mrs. M. Peake, Capt. and Mrs. W. H. Rotheram, Mr. and Mrs. L. Davis, Mr.
                        Edw. Burley, Mr. R. H. Willan, Mr. and Mrs. P. W. Stout, Mrs. and Miss
                        Young, Mr. and Mrs. C. Lloyd, Mr. and Mrs. E. Herbert, Mr. J. F. Kershaw,
                        and Miss A. Reid.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice Mr. F.
                        Atkinson, Mr. H. J. Ankersmit, Mr. Roberts and party, Mr. Zalotznitzky,
                        Baron von Ahlefeldt, Mr. C. von Ahlefeldt, Capt. C. A. Wilding, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Robinson, Mr. Lundberg, Comtesse Arnim, Miss Graeff, Dr. Clair Boyd, Hon. A.
                        J. Davey and family, Mr. C. de Findley and family, Mr. G. Schinas, Mr.
                        Felsmann, Baron and Baronin von Dobeeck, Mr. Jaeger, Lady Richards, Miss
                        Wringfield, Mr. Rid- dell, Miss Lehr, Mr. and Mrs. Merren, Mrs. Young, Mr.
                        H. Gildemeister, Dr. and Frau, Weber Mr. and Mrs. Bairlein, Baron Berne-
                        witz, Mr. Francken, Frl. Springfeld, Frl. Boutu, Mr. C. F. Dalaing.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-1x.7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER BALTIC SQUADRON. SAILING FOR THE EAST.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent). </byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Thursday.</dateline><p>I learn on excellent authority that a fourth squadron of
                        the Baltic Fleet will shortly set out for the Far East, and that it will
                        include two new battleships which have only been launched quite
                        recently.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE RAILWAYS CONTRACTS.</head>
                    <p>With reference to our article yesterday on the State Railways, we understand
                        that at present the orders for rolling stock are as follows:-</p>
                    <p>Delivered on in 1965 order. Locomiotives. North British Loco. Co. Glasgow 15
                        32 Franco-Belgian Co. Belgium 4 6 Henstal &amp; Co., Cassel, Germany -—- 15
                        Ateliers de Cail, France -—- 10 -—- ——- 19 63</p>
                    <p>Coaching vehicles. Metropolitan Carriage and Wagon Co., Birmingham 9 105
                        Goods Wagons. Leeds Forge Co. Leeds (30- ton wagons) -—— 100 Baume and
                        Marpent, Belgium (30-ton wagons) 100 —-— Baume and Marpent, Belgium (10-ton
                        wagons) 1,000 Baume and Marpent, Belginm (cattle trucks) ——— 50 Societe
                        Franco-Belge (brake vans) ——- 40 Mianse &amp; Delane, Belgium (brake vans)
                        ——- 40</p>
                    <p>The 30-ton goods wagons supplied by Messrs. Baume and Marpent, some of which
                        recently derailed, are having their defects remedied by the above mentioned
                        firm at their own expense. It will be remembered that a similar accident
                        happened to the wagons supplied by the Leeds Forge Company—one of the ten
                        best English firms—last year under the same circumstances.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHIPBUILDING AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>The contract for the building of four large steam barges for the Delta
                        Navigation Com- pany has been awarded to the Khedivial Mail Steamship and
                        Graving Dock Company, Ltd. We understand the five steam barges previously
                        built by the Khedivial Company, now working on the Nile, are giving the
                        greatest satisfaction to their owners.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <head>The Khedive attended midday prayers at Montazah Mosque today.</head>
                    <head>MISSION FOR ENGLISH CATHOLICS.</head>
                    <p>During Holy Week the Rev. Father Wulstan Holland, O.F.M., will conduct a
                        short mission for English-speaking Catholics at St. Joseph's Church, in the
                        Ismailieh quarter of Cairo. The mission will open on Palm Sun- day (16th
                        inst.) and will last until Good Fri- day inclusive.</p>
                    <p>Every evening, at 7.30, there will be sermon and Benediction. On Good Friday
                        morning a military service with sermon will be held at 7.30 and in the
                        evening at 7.30 will close the mission with Stations of the Cross and sermon
                        on the Passion of our Lord.</p>
                    <p>All those who understand English, civilians and soldiers, residents and
                        visitors, are most earnestly invited to attended these services.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A.S.C. SKYE MEETING. LAST NIGHT’S LOTTERIES.</head>
                    <p>The lotteries at the Khedivial Club last night in connection with to-day's
                        racing gave the following results in Egyptian shillings.</p>
                    <p>First Race. — Saclavie 55, Wassal 120, Bayard 35, Tonnerre 5, Moulk 30,
                        Derwish 50, Flying Dutchman and Negri 175, Ajax and Hercules 75, Little
                        Korosko and Zarif III. 130.</p>
                    <p>Second Race.—Sattam 65, Taib 15, Rais 220, Nimrod 5, Firefly and India 90, Au
                        Revoir and Zeidan 320, Spectre 20.</p>
                    <p>Third Race.—Togo 120, Chinaman 30, Ion 20, Klondyke and Lulu 140, Jupiter 10,
                        Caprice 160, Sir Visto and El Tahawi 320.</p>
                    <p>Fourth Race.-Amour and Sattam 65, Suleik and Kawkab 190, Vandal 55, Mam- douh
                        40, Faik 40.</p>
                    <p>Fifth Race.—Doughan and Sinounou 60, Jupitar and Derwish 40, Timsah 80,
                        Wassal and Spectre 110, Boheme 66, Solforino, Aziz and Saclavie 110, Hercule
                        and Faineant 45, Numir 10, Amik and Flying Dutchman 170.</p>
                    <p>Sixth Race.—Coeur-de-Lion 30, Boul-de- Neige 150, Au Revoir 120, Mashkour
                        240, Royalist 45, Caprice 75, Shewiman 50, Rais 50, Suari 85.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Italian S.S. "Singapore,” which was due at Alexandria on Sunday morning
                        next, left Messina seven hours behind time and will not arrive before Sunday
                        evening.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Anatolia” arrived here on Thursday evening from
                        Odessa.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Sardinia” sailed from Malta on Thursday and is expected
                        here from Glasgow and Liverpool on Monday morning.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. “Trojan Prince” left London on Thursday last, with passengers and
                        general cargo, for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. "Roumelia,” of the Papayanni Line, arrived in Liverpool yesterday
                        morning.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail S.S. "Ismailia" will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for
                        Piraeus, Smyrna, Mitylene and Constantinople.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesOther">
                    <head>NOTES FROM WAD MEDANI.</head>
                    <head>DISASTER TO PARCEL POST. </head>
                    <p>Wad Medani, March 31. The boat which was carrying the Parcel Powt from
                        Khartoum to Wad Medani last week, encountered very rough weather on her way.
                        Before she reached Kamlin a strong hurricane blew, and the contents of the
                        boat all went overboard. Fortunately, no lives were lost, the boatmen
                        managing to reach the shore. Efforts were made to recover the lost parcels,
                        and these were partially successful, but many par- cels of silk goods, etc.,
                        were completely spoilt, and the merchants to whom these were con- signed
                        have applied to the postal authorities for compensation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PUBLIC EXECUTION.</head>
                    <p>A Sudanese native, who strangled his wife two weeks ago, was hanged to-day at
                        Wad Medani before a large crowd of spectators.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS. </head>
                    <p>During the past two months a great many people have passed up the Nile, some
                        on ordi- nary pleasure trips, some on hunting expedi- tions. The river
                        scenery in winter is very lovely, everything being green on the banks of the
                        river, and the weather being perfect, no rain, little wind, and cool
                        air.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BLUE NILE.</head>
                    <p>Many engineers of late have been studying the question of barrages on the
                        Blue Nile; also a canal is projected across the Geziran from Roseires to
                        Klun, which, if constructed, will be of great benefit to three provinces,
                        viz, Sennar, Blue Nile, and Klun.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>Water was first struck on the property of the corporation at 25 feet from the
                        surface This continually increased in volume to about 100 feet, where it
                        rose to 15 feet from the surface. Other heavy bodies of water were met at
                        depths between 100 and 300 feet, when the water stood at 10 feet from the
                        surface. At about 320 feet water was struck rising to 2 1/2 feet above the
                        surface. The water in No. 1 borehole at Khargeh, which has been sunk to four
                        hundred feet, is flowing at a height of 12 feet above the surface of the
                        ground, at the rate of about 150 gallons a minute, and increasing. </p>
                    <p>There never has been any doubt to the minds of those acquainted with the
                        locality as to the practical certainty of finding artesian water at a
                        certain depth over the whole area. It has, however, been suggested that the
                        avail- able supply would not suffice to irrigate the vast area of cultivable
                        land known to be avail- able. The discovery of large bodies of water to the
                        strata at moderate depths rising to such a depth below the surface as to be
                        easily accessible to ordinary sakiehs or pumps, is of the highest promise,
                        and if the supplies prove to extend over large areas will remove all fear of
                        the necessity of leaving these areas un- cultivated. Also lands on which it
                        might be dangerous to bore artesian wells for fear of injuring existing
                        supplies can be irrigated if these supplies exist nearer the surface.</p>
                    <p>It appears that these water-bearing beds are well known to the natives, but
                        they in- variably continue to bore until they reach a true artesian
                        supply.</p>
                    <p>The discovery of the ancient Roman irriga- tion works consisting of lines of
                        subterranean channels and wells leading the water from higher to lower
                        levels in the extreme north of Kbargeh, and that this district appears to
                        have a considerable water supply that can be reached by ordinary appliances,
                        is also of importance. This district is some 15 miles in length by 1 to 1
                        1/2 in breadth.</p>
                    <p>A considerable number of new alum beds have been discovered, some portions of
                        which contain workable proportions of cobalt. Cobalic alum had previously
                        been found in Dakhleh only.</p>
                    <p>Considerable beds of phosphates have also been discovered in Khargeh as well
                        as in Dakhleh.</p>
                    <p>The water supply at the Deishar greatly in- creased on being opened up, and
                        so far as can be ascertained the level at which the water now stands
                        corresponds nearly with that of the ancient Roman water channels at the same
                        place. This is of great importance, as it tends to disprove allegations to
                        the effect that the level has sunk since the Roman occupation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST AND INVESTMENT.</head>
                    <p>The subscriptions at Martin's Bank, London, on the 10th int., for the
                        Egyptian Trust and Investment, Limited, amounted to 1,012,087 shares. </p>
                    <p>It is hoped that the allotments for Egypt will be posted in the first half of
                        next week. The office of the company at Alexandria is working day and night
                        in order to cope with the glut of applications.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GUM ARABIC.</head>
                    <p>At auction in London last week the small supplies brougnt forward attracted
                        little atten- tion and practically all were bought to or with- drawn. The
                        offerings comprised 263 bales Sudan, 68 packages Scented Aden, and 6 cases
                        Oomra. 3 cases Persian sold at 23s. for palish sorts.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round.</p>
                    <p>Electric light.- Lift.- Moderate charge</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="shareMarket"><head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Financial Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>London, April 7. </dateline><p>A great lull has generally preceded an im- portant battle.
                        The present lull, however, is, it is confidently hoped, the prelude to a
                        great peace. There are certainly “pourparlers” going on, but the secret is
                        well-kept. As it is long in the hatching, let us hope it will be a well-
                        considered and lasting one. Meantime, finan- cial affairs are still in the
                        expectant attitude, and markets have a halting tendency.</p>
                    <p>Although money has been “wanted,” the Bank directors have reflected the
                        general position, and declared no alteration in the Bank rate, which still
                        stands at 2 1/2 per cent. minimum, a good rate for helping commercial enter-
                        prise. It would appear that the Government decline to be frightened by the
                        "Brighton breakers,” and intend to continue to navigate the ship of State,
                        at any rate while foreign affairs are in their present liquid position ;
                        hence the ill effects of a prospective General Election came only to pass
                        away.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Companies which have come out, are hatched more or less “fully
                        fledged,” and they all seem likely to be able to survive the early stages of
                        their career. Their future will depend upon the uses to which they put the
                        money the public have entrusted to them. </p>
                    <p>In Egyptian stocks, as stated before, the new issue rush is being overdone,
                        and too many new things are being hurried on the heels of one another. There
                        is no doubt plenty of scope in Egypt for all of them, but a little more time
                        might be given for digestion, or the appetite may be spoiled.</p>
                    <p>There is not much of interest to report with regard to the past week's stock
                        markets, for, although the tone remains steady, business has been on a very
                        small scale. Tho most active point has been the new Japanese 4 1/2 per cent.
                        issue, to which the dealings have been large. The market was somewhat
                        over-sold before the allotment, and found itself short of stock, and the
                        premium has in consequence been well maintained above 2.</p>
                    <p>In Home Government securities the uncer- tainty of the political situation
                        has checked business, and the prices have eased off somewhat.</p>
                    <p>In the Egyptian market the rise in National and Agricultural Banks still goes
                        on, and the Agriculturals, in spite of the coming large increase of capital
                        referred to last week, are firm at 13 15/16, which looks high enough, whilst
                        Nationals are almost 28. Daira Sanieh shares were a feature yesterday,
                        rising to 27 1/2. Other prices are practically unchanged. In the mining
                        section, prices have given way again ; the revival of interest in Kaffirs
                        has usurped the attention of dealers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN MINES.</head>
                    <p>A London correspondent writes :—</p>
                    <p>What is happening in the Egyptian section of the Mining market? It presented
                        on ap- pearance of great strength a week or two ago, and it seemed
                        impossible to fix a limit to which prices might go. Then, with surprising
                        sud- denness, comes a fall in Nile Valleys to 2 1/2, Block E.s to 19/16 and
                        North Niles to 1 1/2, with the rest of the list proportionately weak.
                        Naturally, after the bright promise of the last few weeks, people are asking
                        for an explanation. The suggestions offered are of varied nature. In one
                        quarter it is supposed that a crushing, the declaration of which is expected
                        shortly, is likely to turn out badly. Elsewhere it is said that at one of
                        the properties where rich quartz has been met with, it has now been
                        definitely ascertained that the main body of the ore is barren. There may be
                        some foundation for these rumours or there may not be. The more likely
                        explanation of the fall, probably, is that various dealers have “ratted,”
                        and it has been impossible to continue the pool in certain shares. The
                        position is not a very satisfactory one from the point of view of the
                        general pu- blic, I fear.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                        English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern
                        sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR PHARMACY</head>
                    <p>Kaur-El-Nil Square, CAIRO. Best Chemical Products. English and foreign
                        prescriptions carefully prepared by certificated chemists. Always in stock
                        large assortment of English proprietary articles &amp; specialties</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-cgh01">
                    <head>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM.</head> 
                    <p>Near Shepheard’s Continental Hotels.</p>
                    <p>Turkish Baths, Plain Baths, X Rays, Electric Light Baths.</p>
                    <p>Massage &amp; Electro-Hydropathic Baths.</p>
                    <p>Medical Director, Dr. Professor Fornaric &amp; Dr. M. Resi</p>
                    <p>xxxx-xxx-xxx</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
