<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><div type="item"><head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>

<head>KING OSCAR RESUMES</head>
<head>GOVERNMENT.</head>

<p>Stockholm, May 26.</p>
<p>King Oscar has resumed the Government.
(Reuter.)</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BRITISH COLLIERS DETAINED.</head>

<p>Nagasaki, May 26.</p>
<p>Three British steamers loaded with coal for Hongkong have been detained at Moji by
order of the Government. (Nrater.)
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CRICKET.</head>

<p>London, May 26.</p>
<p>Notts beat Kent by an innings and 83 runs.
(Reuter.)</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>DERBY BETTING.</head>

<p>London, May 26.</p>
<p>10 to 11 against Cicero ; 3 to 1 Jardy ; 9 to 2 Velas ; 33 to one Rouge Croix, Silver Streak, Signorino and Llangibby ; 50 to 1 Standen,
Shah Jehan, Gasure, Polymelus, and Thrush.
(Reuter.)</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL,</head>

<p>Egyptological Work.— The sons of the late President Henry Morton have presented
seventy eight volumes on Egyptology to the New York Society Library.</p>

<p>Upper Nile Natives.— At the last meeting of the Anthropological Institute of London
Lient.-Colonel C. Delme Radcliffe gave a description of the customs of the Acholi natives of the Upper Nile.</p>

<p>Sudan Wells. — The Sudan Government has decided to dig a number of wells in the
roads from Wad Medani and Gedaref, and also in the provinces of Kordofan. The cost is estimated at £10,000.
</p>
<p>Big Deal in Cairo. — The details as to the purchase of Messrs. Sednaoui's business are, we understand, not yet terminated, and the negotiations as to thr price to be paid are still
proceeding.</p>

<p>Railways is Syria.—The Sultan has promulgated an Irade sanctioning the convention
with the Syrian Railway Company, granting to the latter the right of extending its line from Hama to Aleppo.
</p>
<p>Delta Railway Institute.—The committee of the Egyptian Delta Railway Institute at
Damanhour have organised a very attractive entertainment, which is to be given at the
institute this evening, in aid of the Petite Asile d'Alexandria.</p>

<p>Suez Canal.—13 vessels passed through.the
Canal on the 24th inst., 8 of which were British, 1 German, 1 French, 1 Italian, 1 Turkish, 1 Danish. The day’s receipts were frs. 413,730.73, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 7,434,797.02.
</p>
<p>Austro-Hungarian Agency.—The Austro Hungarian Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General at Cairo Count Koziebrodsky, is leaving by the Austrian Lloyd steamer this afternoon for Europe. Count Stadnisky will act as Diplomatic Agent during his absence.
</p>
<p>Railway and Caisse|Employes.—The Council of Ministers has decided to place the employes of the Public Debt Commission and of the Egyptian Railways Administration, who are to be dismissed on the same basis in regard to pensions and indemnity as the Daira Sanieh employes.
</p>
<p>Coal Imports.— From the 1st January to 25th May 338,178 tons of coal were imported
into Egypt. The Welsh districts sent 196,120 tons, Newcastle 68,434, the Scotch district 38,650, Yorkshire 21,241, and other district 13,763 tons. During the same period last yea 400,673 tons were received.
</p>
<p>Alhambra Theatre. — Audran’s tuneful operetta Gilda de’ Narbona, which is quite new
to Alexandria, was produced last night with a large degree of success. It will be repeated this evening. To-morrow afternoon, a matinee performance will be given of Fanfan la Tulipe, and is the evening Primavera Scapigliata will
be produced.</p>

<p>Primitive Egyptians.—Mr. Zaborowski—in a paper read before the Society of Anthropology of Paris, on the races of primitive Egypt, according to Messrs, Flinders Petrie, J. Kollman, and Chantre—maintains, against Herr Kollman, the exclusively dolichocephalic character of the early Egyptian racial types, and
repels the idea of a negro element.</p>

<p>Fire at Zagazig.-On Thursday night a fire broke out in the house of Sadik Bey. Abaza, a notable of Zagazig. The furniture of the house was destroyed, but fortunately
the confiagration did not reach the neighbouring houses, and the moudir and the commandant of the police succeeded in isolating the fire, the origin of which is unknown.
</p>
<p>Alexandria Gouvernorat.—A council of discipline is to be held this morning at the
Gonvernorat under the presidency of the Governor and an inspector of the Ministry of the Interior to try Helmi Eff. Birzi, mamour of Moharrem Bey kism. Another council is to be held to morrow for the trial of Tewfik Eff., the chief of the administrative bureau at the Gouvernorat.
</p>
<p>The Bedouin and the Smugglers.—While a Bedouin of El Ababda was making his way along the Ismailia Canal, he noticed near a village called Nawa two natives with
two camels laden with straw and beans on the way from Suez to Cairo. The Bedouin was
suspicious as to the nature of the camels' load and he went to inspect the contents. The two drivers of the camels at once fled. 80 kilos of hashish was found hidden among the straw and the beans. The Bedouin took the camels to Nawa Market, where the police took possession of the hashish.
</p>
<p>Maltese Benevolent Society.—To-morrow will be the twenty-fifth anniversary of the
foundation of the Maltose Benevolent Society of Alexandria,and the members of this excellent institution intend to have mass celebrated in the chapel of the Latin Cemetery at 9 o'clock to-morrow morning by the Rev. Father Joseph Vella, Maltese curate, for the repose of the soul of the late Salvo Grech Borg, the promoter of this society. After the mass a memorial stone will be inaugurated over the tomb of Mr. Borg. The advocate Mario Vella will afterwards pronounce a speech as president of the society. The poor families of the colony will receive alms and food to morrow.
</p>
<p>Mohamed Aly Memorial. — An Egyptian correspondent, writing to a London Contemporary on the celebration of the centenary of Mohamed Aly, remarks:— “The Municipality
of Alexandria have proposed, as a public commemoration, the construction of a lunatic
asylum. The idea has found but little favor in Egypt, where a work of the kind
is regarded as solely the business of the Government, which, indeed, has already decided upon the building of a lunatic asylum, though not in the vicinity of Alexandria. It is unlikely that the Municipality scheme will
survive the criticism bestowed upon it, and a more felicitous kind of monument will probably have to be adopted."
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>SAILORS AND SOLDIERS INSTITUTE.</head>

<p>Another very successful and most enjoyable concert was held at the above institute on Thursday evening, which, judging from the numerous encores demanded by the audience
and so kindly granted by the performers, equalled, if it did not surpass, the former one held a month ago. The well-arranged programme, in which the vocal and instrumental performances were well balanced, was carried out in a most thorough style. The songs of Mrs.Gamble and Miss MunGavin were, as on the previous occasion, highly appreciated, and the pianoforte solos of Mrs. Gordon thoroughly merited the applause accorded to them. Miss M. K. Gibson's rendering of the “Intermezzo" from Caballeria Rusticana was something to be remembered, and was received with one long and continued call for an encore. Which was given in this talented lady’s best style as was also her other, item, with its encore. The mandoline solos of Professor Rizzitano were excellent, exhibiting taste and feeling, combined with faultless execution. Two novelties; in the shape of an imitation of church bell ringing, given by Mr. O. S. Heaton, and a masterly exhibition of club swinging by Gunner S. Hall, R.G.A., made a delightful variation in the entertainment. The recitation by Drummer Peace and the pianoforte solo by Private Russell well earned the praise awarded them, while Mr. Dodwell’s two songs and three encores proved the power of a good comic song, well sung, to amuse both old and young. The proceedings closed with a vote of thanks to the performers, and to Mrs. Lawrence for organising so successlul an entertainment; and although there was no formal vote of thanks given, yet we are sure that all present felt that the success of the evening was greatly enhanced by the admirable manner in which Major Gamble precided. The hall, which was prettily decorated with flowers kindly sent by Mr. John Ross, was well filled with an audience in which the military formed a good proportion, our now friends of the R. G. A. showing a good muster. Amongst those present we noticed Major and Mrs. Gamble, Capt. and Mrs. Gordon, Mrs. Moore, Rev. R. Wormell, Mr. and Mrs. John Ross, Mr. and Mrs. Acres, Mr. and Mrs. MunGavin, etc., etc.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

<p>Mr. Brunyate, Khedivial Counsellor, is proceeding to Europe for a trip to the Dolomites.</p>

<p>Prof. Dr. Ibrahim Pasha Hassan, honorary president of the School of Medicine, left for Europe this morning.
</p>
<p>Mr. King Lewis, controller of the Direct Taxes Department of the Finance Ministry,
will leave for Europe on July 1.</p>

<p>The Khedive has been graciously pleased to bestow the rank of Mirmiran El Rafia on the well-known notable of Sharkieh Province, Amin Pasha Ek Shamsi.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT OF ALEXANDRIA</head>

<head>IMPORTANT NEW COMPANY.</head>

<p>June 1 will he an important date in the history of the industrial development of Egypt’s commercial capital for on Thursday next the Rosetta and Alexandria Rice Mills Company will be launched. As is well known, Rosetta for many years past has been the seat of the Egyptian rice industry, and rice milling is in fact the only staple of that interesting but decayed old city of Lower Egypt. There are, however, many disadvantages in this site, for the railway communication with Rosetta leaves much to be desired, and the transport by sea and canal is antiquated, hazardous, and
tedious. It is obvious therefore that Alexandria oil era far more scope for dealing with a commodity of such general importance to the inhabitants of Egypt and of the Levant generally, for the trade is developing rapidly every year.
</p>
<p>Consequently an important group of capitalists, embracing many well-known persons of
Alexandria, Trieste, and Marseilles, have combined together to start the Rosetta and Alexandria Rice Mills Company. The first step will be the erection at Alexandria of what is destined to be by far the largest rice mill in Egypt, and on Thursday next the foundations of the building will be laid. An advantageous site has been chosen on the Mahmoudieh Canal, between the Asphalte Company's works and Messrs. Abou Chanab's oil mills. The superficies of the site is about four feddans, and on this a large six-storey mill and two warehouses will be built by Mr. P. A. Gerakis, the contractor, after the design of Mr. Stienon.
</p>
<p>The company intends taking over Messrs. Behrend’s rice mill at Rosetta, and the managing directorate will be in the hands of Messrs.Behrend & Company. The capital of the company is £60,000, all of which has been privately subscribed, and there will therefore be nopublic issue.
</p>
<p>The machinery will be of the very latest description. It will be entirely automatic, and will be capable of turning out one hundred tons of cleaned rice every day, as against an average turn-out of a Rosetta mill of seven to eight tons per day. Every type of rice will be turned out, from the simple decorticated variety to the highly glazed finished article. The wants of the Egyptian fellah will to carefully attended to, and special attention will be directed to the manufacture of the “Maksous” or salted variety of rice, which native consumption specially affects.
</p>
<p>When the Egyptian rice crop ends about March, the mill will turn its attention to Rangoon rice, which can be imported in either the rough or cleaned state as suits the mill's requirements. In the latter case the cleaned rice would undergo the glazing process.
</p>
<p>The advantages which the new mill possesses are obvious, and the result will be that
the rice trade, which has hitherto been concentrated at Rosetta, must necessarily find its way toAlexandria, and the last nail will be thereby driven in the coffin of Rosetta’s whilom prosperity to the benefit of Alexandria.
</p>
<p>The mill is to be ready for work in about ten or eleven months’ time.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>STATE RAILWAYS</head>

<p>The Administration of the State Railways has submitted for the approval of the Ministry of Public Works a proposal for the expenditure of the £700,000 granted this year by the Finance Department.
</p>
<p>The proposal includes £150,000 for new locomotives, £130,000 for carriages, £140,000
for goods wagons, £75,000 for the renewal of rails and other material, £10,000 for the goods sheds at Djebel Zeitoun, £3,000 for the new construction of the bridge at Gabbari, £20,000 for level crossings and quays at Djebel Zeitoun and Gabbari, £7,540 for a new quay, £4,450 for embankments, £33,000 for improvements and enlargement of Cairo station, £2,000 for the improvoments at the stations of Zagazig. Mansourah, etc., £4,500 for improvements in the neighbourhood of Boulac Dacrour, £3,000 for sanitary installations, £22,000 for the construction of level crossings and the signaling department, £5,000 for the improvement of the Tantah station, £9,000 for improvements in the Benha and Galioub stations, £4,000 for the construction of huts for the workmen, £8,500 for a crossing bridge at Sohag station, £10,000 for expropriating the necessary land for the new Tautah-Zagazig fine, £5,000 for the land for the Achmoun-Delta Barrage line, £30,000 for doubling the line
between El Wasta and Minieb, £14,000 for doubling the line between Palais de Koubbeh
and Matarieh, and for railing on the sides of the line, etc., etc.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>NAVAL NOTES</head>

<head>(From Our Correspondent)</head>

<p>Suez, Friday.</p>

<p>H. M. S. “Canopus" and "Goliath” sailed from Suez at 6 o’clock this morning bound to
the China station.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
<head>BREMEN</head>
<p>Obtainable fmm every Reeaeetable Fine
In Cano, Albiasdsu k ru 8usia.
OUanaisa mb «•
y. j. rm*nrr. r. mkiuef..w*</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>ENGLISH PERSON, ITALIAN RIVIERA</head>
<p>Ik» tot bilteaj Uo» **«»««• FfTri usd to|Uad to
Vila 11m MrarftwsiNtatotHN
tern* ES. Itatol. Halt Ntdtra untilkse. era*
inwLalM to Mi sod fudaa.
var n</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>CREDIT FONCIER EGYPTIEN.</head>

<head>THE NEW SHARE ISSUE.</head>

<p>The Credit Foncier Egyptien has taken over the assets of the Daira Sanieh Company, Limited, for £9,900,000. The Credit Foncier Egyptien will make a share issue shortly for about £3,300,000 and a debenture issue for about £6.600.000. A syndicate has guaranteed the share issue at a price of 825 frames per share. Another syndicate will guarantee the debenture issue as soon as the percentage of the debenture is fixed. It is presumed that the new debentures will bear interest at the rate of 3/1/2 J per cent
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>

<p>On the conclusion of the Khedive’s visit to Windsor Castle as the guest of King Edward, his Highness will stay for about four or five days with Sir Ernest Cassel, at the financier’s town house in Grosvenor square.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CAIRO WATER SUPPLY.</head>

<p>A correspondent writes:—The Cairo Water Company try to explain away their shortcomings the fact nevertheless remains, that the town is on short rations of water, that the ice supply is far below the demand, and that the delivery of the same is made at all sorts of odd hours of the day. The company has certainly chosen a most inconvenient season to make any alterations whatever.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE PLAGUE.</head>

<p>Bubonic plague appears to be regaining its hold on the country. Yesterday’s bulletin reports a case at Alexandria, Port Said,and Mit Ghamr, while one patient at Damanhour was discharged as cured. The case at Alexandria was that of a native boy living at Kom el Shougafa.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CLEARING OF THE SPHINX.</head>

<p>The second meeting of the committee appointed for the carrying on to the project for
the excavation of the Sphinx was held yesterday afternoon at Judge Royle’s house. Judge Royle took the chair, and there were also present Mr. Courtenay Clifton, Mr. Allan Joseph, Prof. Dr Ibrahim Pasha Hassan,and Mr. Dow Covington.
</p>
<p>The terms upon which the granting of the concession should be applied for came under discussion and it was decided that Mr. Dow Covington should make a personal application for a conditional concession. The application state the work shall be carried out by Mr. Covington under the direct supervision and with the cooperation of the Antiquities Department. It also undertakes that the one-half of the finds, which is the right of the excavator (the other half going to the Government) shall be distributed by the committee among those public institutions in whose names contributions are made and in proportion to the
amounts so subscribed.</p>

<p>It is well to point out that any person may
contribute to the excavation fond in the name of any public institution, but that no individual will be entitled to any part of the finds.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.</head>

<head>LAST NIGHTS LOTTERIES.</head>

<p>Lotteries in connection with this afternoon’s, racing were held at the Khedivial Club last night. The following are the prices realised in Egyptian shillings of P.T. 5:—
</p>
<p>First Race.—Firefly, 75; Sir Visto, 320; Hoyama, 65 ; Coeur de Lion, 200; Mahmoud,
40.</p>

<p>Third Race.—Bon Jour, 10; Chinaman, 30; Tamerlan and Boheme, 340; Klondyke, 400; El Tahawi, 480 ; Sweetie, 300; Kendal, 45; Radium, 65.
</p>
<p>Fourth Race.—St Frasquin, 50; Amory, 60; Sansparail, 160; Roland, 1,000; Eclipse, 100 ; Latif, Au Revoir, and Sadik, 1,150 ; Abou Akab and Ide, 50 ; Sirur, 45 ; Farhan II. and Saber, 240; Caprice and Viking, 550; Agib, 200.
</p>
<p>Fifth Race. — Moofid, 190; Fahad, 520; Rashid, 130; Gogo, 800; Valentino, 320;
Mashkour, 50.</p>

<p>Sixth Race.—Suleik, 1,000 ; Peacock and Abigak, 15 ; Spectre and Mayesha, 5 ; Chutnee, 200; Fantasia, 160 ; India, 350; Petrone, 45.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>

<p>The following is the programme of music to be performed to-morrow, commencing at 10a.m.:—
</p>
<p>l OnuuHUrcio — IU	Jlcnd.t-ltic
I V>W - hoortoM-UJ-WUdWlfG
a Ovwtoro -H.mliM.ia»-tto**liU ^
• BaBat-Sw—Wa—nto</p>

<p>Entrance to the morning concert will be P.T. 2 and to the afternoon concert, commencing at 5 p.m., P.T. 1.</p>
</div>
<div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

<p>The Khedivial Mail S.S. "Ismailia’’ will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for Pirreus,
Smyrna, Mitylene and Constantinople.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>

<p>Bnlkeley, Rsrmleh.
Aomi-tKA. rnr**~.</p>
</div>
<div type="item"><head>TYROL</head>
<p>Weissenstern Castle 341
l I KUL. ft Kirtelra. private
hotel near Windiseh Matrrt ; Station. Irani
(reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best
June and September. Prospeotaras and Pho-
tographs, "Egyptian Gesetta” office, Cana
tmwr-i T</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>FAYOUM NOTES.</head>

<head>THE BRIGANDAGE CASE.</head>

<head>(From Our Correspondent)
</head>
<p>Medinet el Fayoam, Friday.</p>

<p>I am glad to be in a position to state that the united efforts of the Parquet authorities and of the officials of the Ministry of the
Interior have succeeded in discovering the whereabouts of the valuables stolen by the
brigands. They were found in a village hard by the desert that intervenes between the
provinces of Fayoum and Beni-Souef. Six men implicated in the brigandage are now
under arrest and energetic efforts are being made to lay hands on the brigand chief and other members of his nefarious gang. The Inspector of the Ministry of the Interior and the Moudir of the Fayoum are working day and night to unravel this case, and it is to be hoped that their efforts will be crowned with the success they deserve in bringing the ruffians within the meshes of the law.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY.</head>

<p>I fear that matters are not improving in
the prospects of the Fayoum Light Railway. I was recently informed by a late employe
of the company that there is a decrease of £10 per diem in the receipts of this railway, and he also declared that the present receipts of the line scarce suffice to pay the expenses. Of course I do not vouch for the truth of this information, but all accounts tend to show that the progress of the company is not rapid, nor can its future prospects be characterised as in any degree promising.
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.</head>

<p>The scandal in which Hasson Bey Wassil is accused of being implicated, has aroused great interest in the Fayoaum, where the Moudir is well-known. The general impression
appears to be that he is innocent of any share in the Rifai affair.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>THE CASSEL HOSPITAL</head>

<p>Sir Ernest Cassel's travelling ophthalmic hospital, which has been visiting the 1
Fayoum province, is to be transferred hence I to Damietta. Dr. A. Ferguson MacCallan,
who is the ophthalmist in charge of the hospital, left this week for Cairo. His assistant, Tahir Effendi, leaves with the tents and all the hospital paraphernalia next week. During the stay of the hospital here no less  than 12,402 visits have been paid by patients. Of these 637 were operated on for trichiosis, irridoctomy, cataract, and other ophthalmic complaints so common in this country. I used to visit Dr. MacCallan as a confrere, and I can state from my own experience that his success in the treatment of soft and senile cataract was most remarkable, and during his stay here he has alleviated a very large amount of suffering among the people. In the name of the inhabitants of the Fayoum I beg to thank Sir Ernest Cassel and the skilful physician in charge of his hospital, for the good that has been done in this province by the hospital.
</p>
<p>The following passages from Dr. MacCallan's interesting report on his last year's work are worth quoting:—
</p>
<p>“At the inception of the scheme, there was
some doubt as to its probable success, and as
to the readiness of the fellaheen to take advantage of it. All doubt has, however, been, set at rest by its immediate and complete success. There has never been the smallest hesitation on the part of the people to visit the hospital as patients, nor to submit themselves to whatever operation I have advised. The large proportion of women patients has been especially noteworthy. Both at Menonf and Damietta, the number of would-be patients has been much larger than the surgical staff of the
hospital could cope with. It was no uncommon thing to find in the morning 200 people anxious to obtain admission, and the same condition of affaire now obtains at Galionb."
</p>
<p>"All patients are treated free of charge, and are given bottles of drops and lotions for use at home when necessary. By far the larger proportion of the patients who attend the hospital have every appearance of poverty, and if there are more patients on any day than can be seen, the poorer patients are given preference.
</p>
<p>Dr. MacCallan concludes his report with the following words :—
</p>
<p>“The extension of the travelling ophthalmic hospital scheme throughout the country would, I feel certain; be as successful from an economic as from a philanthropic point of view. The number of inefficient workers due to the ravages of trachoma is enormous, and every child who now obtains relief at the camps is a worker saved from the ban of inefficiency."
</p>
<p>Lord Cromer remarks as follows on this report:—
</p>
<p>“One of the results of the absence of means of ophthalmic relief in the rural districts is the multiplication of quacks, who often do more harm than good to their patients. The establishment of the travelling hospitals will in some degree mitigate this evil, but the remedy so far applied has necessarily been only very partial. It is a well-known fact which is confirmed by Dr. Mac Callan, that a large proportion of the children who attend the Government schools require skilled medical treatment for their eyes."
</p>
<p>And in regard to Dr. MacCallan’s conclusion his lordship says:—
</p>
<p>"I do not doubt that Dr. MacCallan is quite
right. In view of the very large number of subjects which call for the attention of the  Government in this country, and of the further fact that the resources of the State do not admit of all these subjects being treated at the same time and immediately, I am always somewhat unwilling to state beforehand when it will be possible to take in hand any particular project for reform. I have, however, no hesitation in expresing a strong hope that before long it will be possible for the Government to provide means for extending the excellent system which, under Sir Ernest Cassel’s auspices has now been inaugurated.”
</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>CHRONIQUE JCDICIAIRE</head>

<head>TRIBUNAL CIVIL MIXTE D’ALEXANDRIE</head>

<p>Un Grace Couplet de Juridiciton
</p>
<p>L’affaire Stagni- Salinas</p>

<p>(jugement du mai 1905)</p>

<p>Ooï le M. P. en «on aria et statuant publi-
quement et contradictoirement, joint lee ut-
friras'inscrites en B. O. de U 80ae année
judiciaire sooe la No*. 2.S88 et.1,076 et re
eurent la Société Pretslli Salines et Ciosiasi
qoeleFOOMort^a^M^en leur intarnction.
position, dit pour droit que ai l'arrêt de le
Coor d'Appel d’Ancône do 1er Men 1906, ai 1e
jugement do Tribonel Consulaire A’italia à
Alexandrie en date dn 95 Septembre 1903 ne
peuvent Être exécutée per l'intermédiaire de le
juridiction mixte.
Condamne BUgni et figli aux dépens hono-
raires dei'avocat de» partie» adverse» taxé» b
P.T. 800,
Voici un bref aperçu de» motif» de det
intéressent jugement
Le 18 mars éooolé lamaiaon Fratelli Saline»
a assigné Btagni et figli en annulation de
l'ordonnanoe d’exequatur de l'arrêt de la
Cour d'Ancône rendu le 1er Man.
Le 10 mai leSté Fratelli Satinas et Ciese
disant substituée à Tanoeuhe .société Fratelli
Satinas a déclaré oonclure non seulement à
l’annulation de l’anét de la Cour d‘Ancône
mais encore b la non-exécution du jugement
du tribunal oonsulaire d’Italie.
L’exploit dn 10 mai n'ayant pae pour but
d'introduire une action nouvelle mais simple-
ment de déclarer l’intervention b l'action an-
térieure il convient d’y statuer par une seule
et même »entanna.-
L'exoeption tirée du défaut de qualité que
Stagni et figli opposent b la nouvelle soaiété
no saurait être sérieusement défendue, puisque
la Société Satinaa et Oie a suooédé fox droits
et aux obligations de l’ancienne 8té Fratelli
Salines et se trouve par le fait intéressée b
joindre son opposition b la saisie que veulent
pratiquer Stagni et figli.	‘
Au fond, la demande d'annulation de l'exe-
quatur se baae sur lé combinaison de l’art 468
u.pr.0. mixte aveo l'art 94JL o.pr.a italien, au
terme* daqnel 1'exeqaatar ne peut être aeooidé
que si 1a sentence a étépronoooée par l’autorité
judiciaire compétente et ri elle ne contient au-
cune disposition obntraire à l’ordre publia Mais
le retrait de l’exequatur peut et doit être or-
donné en dehors de ces considérations, qu’il art
munie par conséquent d’ekamioer, par le seul
motif que l’arrêt de la Coord’Anoône se trouva
en contradiction formelle aveo l’arrêt de la
Cour Mixte etgu’es droit il est oontreire au
principes généraux sur la matière, admis dans
cous les pays, qu’une autorité judiciaire aocorde .
foroe exéouloue b daa décisions étrangères qui
«ont en contradiction ayoo sesproprea décisions.
En dépit des argarqonta plus subtils que
juridiques de Stagni et ïgli, la contradiction
existe : la même question, oèlle de savoir ri
la vente des titres en jjuition oomprenait
ou non le ooupon a été soumise au .deux
juridictions qui se sont prononoées l’une pour
la négative et l’autre pour l’affirmative.
Voila pour le fiait
Sur la queetion de principe, le tribunal
déclare que le, droit incontestable et le
premier devoir de l’autorité judiciaire d’un .
pays est d'assurer avant tout 1a plaine et
entière exécution -de ses propres décisions et
partant de refuse» toute exécution bu décl-
f gions émanées do juridictions étrangères qui
1 seraient en contradiction aveo les sienne* ;
1 en cas de contradiction, lo‘principe de sou-
' veraineté exige qae la décision étrangère
' soit sacrifiée à oellequi émane de la juridio-
. t ion do nevs. .	.	’
Une pareille décision sorait d’ailleurs appli-
quée en Italie, ai le oai.se présentait U suffit.
de citer b ce sujet un arrêt do la Cour d’Appel
de Milan en date dn 4 novembre 1873 et on
arrêt de la Cour de Cassation de Turin en
date du 18 juillet 1877 qui arguent du même
principe. Comme la réciprocité eet de règle en
la matière, on ne saurait, s'étonner que la
jaridiotion mixte dont la mission est de rendre
justice en Egypte, au nom. du souverain de oe (,
pays, se refuse b accorder l'exequatur. b une
décision rendue par la juridiction italienne et
qui est en contradiction formelle ave» ses
propres décisions.	'
Ce point une fois acquis et la Cour d Anoône
écartée,en ne oomprend plus la force oxéoutoiw
du jogement du tribunal oonsulaire d’Italie,
puisque oe jugement n’aurait auonn effet
la confirmation do l’arrêt de la1 Cour
d’Àncône; en sorte que ri oelui-ci ne pçut être
exécuté, le jugement ne peut l’être d'atantage.
Du reste, les motifs d'ordre supérieur qui
s'opposent è l’exécution de l’arrêt, s'opposent
tout aussi bien b celle du jugement ; en vain
ün argumente du principe admis que le» juge-
ments de» tribunaux consulaires peuvent être
directement revêtua de la formule exécutoire
mixte, Bans besoin d'ordhnnanoe d'exeqnatur j
il n'en résulte nullement que U juridiction
mixte soit tenue.de leur assurer l’exécution an
>'»«•*• i* —i—
elle-rntme et d# jwrtw U «mot# à
r.ntoritidont«kütïaMrtifc
reprab» »	4. mtomlB,
i I-uWiU 4» 11™“ ooo»1mi»
np'alk û'MUnd pM
« ««>
Uirei. mi. « «• »«~l «■~4“‘
ser b le juridiction mixte en exigeantAsile
qu'elle contribue b lourexécution. En l’abeenoe
de toute juridiction supérieure, compétente b
réroudro un oonflit de oette nature, le refus
d'exécution «t non seulement un droit pour
le» tribunaux mixte» mei» (me le seul moyen
d'éviter dan» 1a mesure du poariblp Ip qonsé-
quenoes pratiquei de paierie OOn&ifo etd’w
</p></div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
