<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Thomas Corzo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-08">October 8, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-17">June 17, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JUNE 17, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PEACE PROSPECTS.</head>
                    <p>PROGRESS MADE. RUSSIAN ARROGANCE.</p>
                    <p>Washington, June‘16. M; Takahira notified President Roosovelt the refusal of
                        Japan to send plenipotentiaries to Europe. Russia accepted, and joined
                        Japan, in asking that the meeting should take place here. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>LondoN June 16. The announcement of the selection of Washington as the
                        meeting place of the plenipotentiaries seems to imply that progress is being
                        made in the direction of peace, otherwise nothing whatever is known.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, Juuo16. The press continues to comment arrogantly upon the
                        peace suggestions, declaring that Japan needs peace more than Russia:
                        (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TSAR AND THE ZEMSTVOS. THE COMING RECEPTION.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 16. The Tsar having announced that he would receive some
                        of the delegates of the Moscow Congress of Zemstvos, but not all, the
                        delegates have decided to decline the audience (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 16. The Tsar’s final decision regarding the audience to
                        the Zemstvos will be communicated to them on Monday. It has boon determined
                        that this audience must bear a political character, and the question of its
                        reception eclipses that of peace in the public mind. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>RUSSIAN RAILWAY STRIKE.</p>
                    <p>A PAR-REACHING THREAT.</p>
                    <p>Moscow, Juno 16. A meeting of railway engineers held here has decided that
                        its members will join a general political strike upon the first signal, for
                        tho purpose of entirely stopping the economical life of the country.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>RUSSIAN MARINE MINISTER - RESIGNS.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 16. Admiral T. C. Avellan has resigned the Ministry of
                        Marine. (Reuter )</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE GRAND DUKE ALEXIS.</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, June 16. The Tsar has accepted the resignation by the Grand
                        Duke Alexis of the supremo command of the fleet and Navy Department, but he
                        retains the dignities of Grand Admiral and Aide de camp to the Tsar.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</p>
                    <p>THE POWERS AND A CONFERENCE.</p>
                    <p>London, June 16. Austria; Italy, and America have intimated that they are
                        prepared to join in a conference on the subject of Morocco, provided always
                        that the Powers chiefly concerned accept; the invitation. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>M. ROUVIER'S SUCCESSOR.</p>
                    <p>paris, Jane 16. M. Merlon, Deputy, succeeds M. Rouvier at the Finance
                        Ministry. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, June 16. M. Ronvier abandons the Ministry of Finance and takes that of
                        Foreign Affairs only. The German Ambassador, Prince de Radolin, is
                        conducting important discussions with M. Rouvier. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>DEATH OF MAJOR WISSMANN.</p>
                    <p>ACCIDENTALLY SHOOT’S HIMSELF.</p>
                    <p>Berlin, June 16. Major Wissmann, ex-Governor of East Africa, has accidentally
                        shot himself, and is dead. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE LATE M. DELYANNIS.</p>
                    <p>DIED IN ABSOLUTE POVERTY.</p>
                    <p>Athens, June 16. M. Delyannis died in absolute poverty. Two nieces with whom
                        he lived will receive a pension from the State. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>ATHENS, June 16. Great Britain, France, and Italy have sent the wannest
                        condolences to Greece on acconnt of the assassination of M. Delyannis. The
                        body lay in state on a catafalque in the Chamber yesterday. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CHOLERA IN RUSSIA. St. Petersburg, June 16. Cholera has appeared at Tomsk,
                        and on the Siberian railway. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>PLAGUE CASE AT MANCHESTER.</p>
                    <p>Manchester, June 16. There has been a death from plague on board the SS.
                        Seacok” which has arrived from Buenos Ayres via Hamburg. (Reuter )</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>HONORS FOR LOCAL OFFICIALS.</p>
                    <p>London, June 16. The King has appointed H. E. Boutros Pasha Ghali, Grand
                        Cross, and Mr. E. H. Vin-oent Corbett, Knight Commander, of the Vio-torian
                        Order. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mah. will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a.m. on
                            Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The National Bank or Egypt</head>
                        <p>announces that letters of allotment and regret for the issue of 50,000
                            new shares have been posted.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Pont de Koubheh quarter of Cairo
                            during to morrow night and at daylight on Sunday will be poisoned by the
                            police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Red Sea Lights</head>
                        <p>We are requested by the Ports and Lighthouses Administration to
                            acknowledge -the gift of books and periodicals from Milbnrn Bey for the
                            Red Sea lightkeepers.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Drowning Fatality at Ciiatby</head>
                        <p>While a native youth was giving a horse a bath yesterday in the sea off
                            Chatby the animal took fright and throw his rider off. The youth was
                            drowned.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Ostrich Feathers</head>
                        <p>The total number of cases of Egyptian ostrich feathers put up to auction
                            in London last week was 123, of which 81 cases were sold. Full details
                            of the sales will be found on page 5 of to day’s issue.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hypnotism</head>
                        <p>M. do Lafontaine, the well-known'hypnotist, will begin a series of
                            seances at the Edlen Theatre on Thursday evening next. He will be
                            assisted by his Creole mediums, Mmes. Nadia, Blanet do l’lsle, and
                            Myralda.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Circus</head>
                        <p>The stay of Gatti’s cirons troupe at the Theatre des J’yran ides is
                            drawing to a close, as the company is leaving for Italy in a few days.
                            Two performances will be given to-morrow, a mantinee (which will be the
                            last) and an evening one.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>14 vessels passed through the Canal on the 14th inst, of which 10 were
                            British, 1 Italian, 1 Gorman, 1 French, 1 Dutch. Tho receipts tor the
                            day were frs. 328,118.31 making tho total from the 1st inst. frs.
                            3,821,664.31.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>// Giro del Hondo in 80 fiiorni (Round the World in 80 Days) drew a large
                            and delighted audience to the Alhambra last night. The play was a great
                            success. It will bo reproduced to-night and twice tomorrow, in the
                            afternoon and evening.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Accident in Harbour</head>
                        <p>On Wednesday, on the departure of the Khedivial mail steamer "Ismailia,"
                            and just after the ship had left the quay, a sailor of the crew was
                            knocked off the ship into a lighter while some merchandise was being
                            slung into it, and was seriously injured. He was removed to the
                            Government Hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mr. Jones and Mr. Brown</head>
                        <p>A native contemporary announces that the Cairo Gon-vernorat has received
                            news from Maghaga markaz that the police there have arrested two
                            Englishmen, named Mr. Jones and Mr. Brown. Each of these persons were
                            found in possession of a donkey, which had been stolen from the
                            Bab-el-Louk stand at Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alexandria Tramway Co</head>
                        <p>The rumours as to the approaching extension of the Alexandria tramway
                            system to Montazah are without foundation, and have apparently only been
                            set on foot for the purpose of encouraging speculation in land in the
                            eastern district of Alexandria. The company will come to a decision as
                            to the extension of the Ramleh lino to Mohamed Aly-squaro on Tuesday
                            week.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Passengers from Zeitoun and other stations along the Pont LIMONI-Barg
                            railway lino much shocked a day or two ago to find one of their pastimes
                            ruined. A small spur of the Mokattam range which had been thrown up by
                            workmen patting in the water conduit, over which they had been merrily
                            climbing every time they arrived in or left Cairo for the last month,
                            was suddenly heaved over into the trench, and nothing now remains but a
                            bit of rocky desert in front of the entrance to the Pont Limoun
                            station.Passengers from Zeitoun and other stations along the Pont
                            LIMONI-Barg railway lino much shocked a day or two ago to find one of
                            their pastimes ruined. A small spur of the Mokattam range which had been
                            thrown up by workmen patting in the water conduit, over which they had
                            been merrily climbing every time they arrived in or left Cairo for the
                            last month, was suddenly heaved over into the trench, and nothing now
                            remains but a bit of rocky desert in front of the entrance to the Pont
                            Limoun station.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egypt’s G.P.O. in 1400 B.C</head>
                        <p>Professor Sayce, lecturing in London last, week, said the civilised
                            Oriental world of the Mosaic Age was us highly civilised as our own of
                            the present day. Correspondence from the Egyptian Foreign Office of 1400
                            B.Ci was contained in the cuneiform tablets discovered at Tel-el-Armana
                            nearly twenty years ago. Well-organised postal services, high roads,
                            colleges, and libraries existed, and there was “ample evidence that
                            monarchs were as anxious to protect the trade of the country as Mr.
                            Chamberlain today.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>North German Lloyd</head>
                        <p>The S.S. “Schleswig,” of the Norddeutscher Lloyd, left on the 14th inst
                            with a total of 220 passengers for Naples , and Marseilles. It may
                            interest our readers to know that in order to meet the wishes of many
                            Egyptian residents, the directors of this company have ordered the
                            steamer to leave Naples during Saturday night or quite early on Sunday,
                            so that passengers for Marseilles will be able to land there by Monday
                            afternoon, instead of Tuesday as hitherto. The next departure of the
                            “Schleswig" will be on the 5th July, and we hear that the bookings for
                            this fine ship are coming in rapidly.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT. DISCOVERY OF THIEVES. BOOTY TRACED.</head>
                    <p>XWith reference to the recent theft from the Mahmal caravan, the Cairo
                        Gonvcrnorat reports that it appears from the investigations made that the
                        thieves ore Amdrous Melnka, Said Hannalla, a money changer, Ibrahim Ashour,
                        a labourer, and Mankarins, a barber. These men divided the money among
                        themselves, bought a house at Haret el Nasarn, 1,500 metres of land at
                        Shoubra, and were negotiating for the purchase of a honse at Eagallab for
                        £3,000, but they did conclude the bargain for fear of attracting attention.
                        Amdrons also bought jewels for his wife. The box which contained the stolen
                        money remained buried for several weeks in an unknown place and it was then
                        brought to Said Hannalla’s house and burnt there. The houses of the accused
                        have been searched by the police. £2,723 was found in tin box built in the
                        wall in Amdrous’s house and£400 and a quantity of jewels and valuable papers
                        were found in Said Hannals's house. The accused deny the charge of theft,
                        but they are being retained in prison during the enquiry.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE STRANDED RICE BOAT.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent ).</byline>
                    <p>Suez, Friday I wired yon this morning that the German (not British) steamer
                        “Helen Rickmers" was aground near Ras Garib lighthouse in the Suez Gulf.
                        This steamer has a full cargo of rice from Bangkok, and grounded apparently
                        last Thursday night She was reported here yesterday by the Dutch mail boat,
                        whioh brought her chief officer to Suez. According to the latter’s
                        statement, the vessel is not in a bad position, and it is expected that she
                        will come off after discharging 400/500 tons of cargo, and for this purpose
                        several lighters and labourers are about to sail from Suez this afternoon.
                        The Khedivial mail liner “Rahmanieh'' is also leaving Suez to-night to
                        assist the steamer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>SUEZ CANAL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>With reference to the report of the annual general meeting of the above
                        company, held in Paris on the 6th inst., at which the British Government was
                        represented by the Hon. Reginald Lister, of the British Embassy, it will
                        interest our readers to learn that there are nine English members on tho
                        board of administration, all of whom wore present, viz., Sir H. Austin Leo,
                        Mr. H. T. Anstruther, Mr. R. Alexander, Sir Thomas Sutherland, Mr. R. S.
                        Donkin, Sir John Ardagh, R.E., Lord Rath-more, Mr. F. Green, and Mr. T. W.
                        Hughes, whose election to the board in place of Mr J. B. Westray, resigned,
                        we lately announced in these columns. It is reported in Cairo that amongst
                        the principal improvements in contemplation is the further deepening of the
                        Canal so as to admit of the passage of vessels of the largest draught, which
                        at present have to coal at Suez instead of Port-Said.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>ST. MARK’S CHURCH, ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>SERVICES FOR TRINITY SUNDAY.</p>
                    <p>8. am. Holy Communion. 11. am. Matins and Sermon. To Denm (B. Tours). Anthem,
                        solo and choral Sanctus from Gaul’s “Holy City.” “A new Heaven and a new
                        Earth.” Noon. Holy Communion. 6:15 pm. Evensong and Sermon. Magnificat and
                        Nune Dimitris (Bunnett). Anthem, solo and choral Sanctus from “Holy City.”
                        Preacher at morning and evening services, the chaplain. Collections for
                        church exponses.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>SAN STEFANO CA8INO.</p>
                    <p>The following is the programme of music to be performed to-morrow morning,
                        commencing at 10 a.m. :— 1. Marche—Tho Liberty Bell- The following programme
                        will be executed in the afternoon, at 5 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Roman Prinoe,” from Antwerp and London, left Malta on Friday and is
                        due here on Tuesday next, with passengers and general cargo. The Kbedivial
                        Mail S.S. ‘Prince Abbas’ will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for Piraens,
                        Smyrna, Mitylene and Constantinople.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ECLIPSE IN EGYPT. SCIENTIFIC EXPEDITION.</head>
                    <p>An important American expedition is to be despatched to Upper Egypt to
                        observe the eclipse of the sun, which will occur on August 30. The
                        expedition will be organised and despatched under the auspices of the Lick
                        Observatory. Mr. W.W. Campbell, director of the Lick Observatory, recently
                        sent a communication to Secretary Shaw asking that permission bo given to
                        the collector of the port of Now York to examine a number of scientific
                        apparatus to be used in observing the eclipse. Included in the apparatus to
                        be brought out are lenses, prisms, mirrors, telescopes, clocks, photograph
                        apparatus and materials, tents, mechanics’ tools and other minor
                        necessaries. Some of this apparatus is to bo taken from the United States
                        Naval Observatory at Washington, from Harvard University, and from
                        Princeton. The director stated that be would ship some of this late in May.
                        The expeditions will start July 6 from New York. He asked also that on the
                        return of the expeditions the instruments might be shipped in bond direct
                        various destinations, because an examination in Now York involved danger to
                        them on account of the unpacking and repacking. The Secretary of the
                        American Treasury has instructed the collector to make the requested
                        examination so that the instruments may be taken back without payment of
                        duty. Inasmuch as the expeditions are for advancing knowledge the department
                        makes this special ruling.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN IMPROVEMENTS CORPORATION.</head>
                    <p>The above company has purchased the pro perty of Prince Mohamed Aly, brother
                        of the Khodive, situated opposite the Savoy Hotel at Cairo, from the local
                        syndicate that bought it lately from the Prince for L.E. 52,000. The palace
                        and the adjoining buildings are be pulled down, the contract for their
                        demolition having been given to Mr. Pietro Fonti, the Cairo contractor, who
                        pays £1,500, and in return gets all tho stone and other material, the work
                        having to be completed in five mouths. The palace, with its annexes, cost
                        £32,000 to build eight years ago, and it stands on 1,000 square metres of
                        ground, the total area of the property being about 7,300 square metres. On
                        the vacant plot six large residential houses in flats will be erected.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW BUILDINGS IN CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>The erection of the now palatial pile, the largest of its kind in Cairo,
                        situated opposite the Savoy Hotel, is making rapid progress, and the
                        building will bo completed and ready for occupation by the end of the year.
                        Including the ground floor there will be no loss than five stories, besides
                        the basement, and the whole cost will be about £40,000, not including the
                        site of 1,810 square metres. The masonry work was given to Messrs. Guetin
                        and Charvand, the architect being Fabricius Pasha, who designed the handsome
                        National Bank buildings, whilst Mr. A. St John Dia-mant is the surveyor on
                        behalf of the Standard Life Assurance Company, for whom the new premises are
                        being constructed. The ground floor will be partly occupied by tho oompany
                        and partly let out as offices, and on the remaining four floors there will
                        be eighteen residential flats on the latest and most approved principles,
                        especially as regards the sanitary arrangements, which have been devised by
                        Dr. II. Nolan of Cairo, and are the most perfect and scientific in the
                        Capital. The rents of these apartments will range from £90 to £850 per
                        annum. Throe of the larger rooms of every flat will have English fireplaces,
                        whilst all the locks and grates as well as the lifts are being brought out
                        from England. We understand that most of the apartments have already been
                        let.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHOUBRA PRIVATE HOSPITAL.</head>
                    <p>The now private Sanatorium opened at Shoubra last November by Dr. S.
                        Voronoff, consulting physician to H.H. the Khedive, has proved a great
                        success, judging by the large number of patients that have been admitted. Id
                        fact for several weeks during the winter many pressing cases had to be
                        refused admittance for want of accommodation. Miss Glewitt, the matron,
                        formerly lady doctor at the Suez Quarantine Office, and Miss Mac-phereon,
                        her assistant, have been kept busy since the opening. The latter has now
                        left for England owing to ill-health, but her place will be filled later by
                        another English nurse. The buildiug grounds surrounding were leased for four
                        years, with option of purchase, from Mohamed Boy Abdel Wahid, a wealthy
                        landlord of the Capital, and the gardenis 4,000 square metres in extent The
                        mansion contains over 20 rooms, but it is intended during the summer to make
                        several improvements and alterations which will increase the accommodation
                        for patients. Since the opening ho less than 106 cases have been treated in
                        the hospital, all ot which, with the exception of twelve, were surgical.
                        Besides paying patients there are also free beds for persons of
                        respectability who are unable from want of means to pay the fees. Dr. S.
                        Voronoff has left for Europe on a short and much-needed holiday and until
                        his return his duties will bo performed by Dr. G. Voronoff.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO AUTO EXCURSIONS. AN AMERICAN INNOVATION.</head>
                    <p>Plans and contracts have been completed for four electric automobiles, each
                        to carry forty passengers at a trip, and an American youth as conductor, who
                        will explain through a megaphone bis unlimited stock of information about
                        the sights between Cairo and the Sphinx. The cars cost £1,000 each and will
                        start running on the first of January next, from Shepheard’s, stopping at
                        the Continental, Angleterre, National, and Savoy Hotels to pick up
                        passengers. The head porters in all those hotels are financially interested
                        in the scheme. Two trips per day, 9 a.m. and 3 p.m., are scheduled. About an
                        hour will be spent on the road and two hours at the Pyramids. About March,
                        the machines will bo shipped to Paris, where they will be used during the
                        summer in seeing the sights, both day and night, much as they are now used
                        in New York. Mr. Frank Whitcomb, the originator of these public sight-seeing
                        autos, has carried through the deal, and will also send over to Cairo two
                        big naphtha launches to be used as “Seeing the Nile" at ten piastres a
                        head.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRATRICIDE IN MENOUFIEH</head>
                    <p>A shocking crime is reported from the village of Miniat El Kobra, in the
                        Menoofieh maiksz, Menoofieh province. A fellah, who had a grudge against his
                        brother, attacked him from behind while he was engaged in threshing his
                        wheat crop, and foiled the unfortunate man with several heavy blows of a
                        about. Unfastening his turban, the murderer coolly strangled his victim, and
                        having satisfied himself of his death, dragged the body to a neighbouring
                        canal and threw it into the water. The body was found floating in a partly
                        decomposed state, but the marks of the injuries sustained by the murdered
                        man persisted and the inquiry which was held established the brother’s
                        guilt. The murderer, who was arrested, has confessed to having committed the
                        crime.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN CIVIL SERVICE.</head>
                    <p>Class list of probationers in Arabic test examination (arranged in
                        alphabetical order within each class). First class.—Jelf, MacMichaol,
                        Willis. Seoond class.—Barton, Johnson, Loyd, Mao-Donnoll, Matthew. Third
                        olass.—Bentley, Blomfield, Gye, Osborne. Fourth class. - Bond, Evans,
                        Pennefatbor. Edward G. Browne, D. S. MarGoliouth, A. Shaweesh, Mohamed A
                        sal.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The D. C. L. degree will be conferred on Sirdar at the Enciouia to be held in
                        the Sheldonian Theatre on the 28th inst.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death of Ferik Racliid Husni Pasha, which occurred
                        at Cairo on Thursday. The deceased took part in the Russo-Tnrkish war and
                        also saw service in the Sudan and Abyssinia. He was 70 years of age.</p>
                    <p>Sir William Garstin and Mr. Webb, Undersecretary of State, Public Works
                        Department, returned to Cairo yesterday morning.</p>
                    <p>Lienti-Colonel (Brevet Major) J.J. Asser, Dorsetshire Regimeht, who has been
                        serving with the Egyptian Army since January, 1897, and has lately been
                        employed as Financial Secretary to the Sudan Government, has been appointed
                        Station Commandant at Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to learn that Mr. Clowes, the Inspector General of Irrigation for
                        Upper Egypt, has quite recovered from tho shock he received in the recent
                        accident on the Fayoum Light Railway.</p>
                    <p>Mr. John Herbert Landon, the newly appointed inspector of irrigation, has
                        arrived from India and taken over his official duties.</p>
                    <p>We regret to - hear that Mr. Richards, II. B. M.'s Consul at Damascus, has
                        been compelled by ill health to leave Syria for Vienna, where he will
                        probably have t dergo an operation. We are sure that Mr. Richards’ many
                        friends in the Near East will join ns in wishing him a rapid and complete
                        recovery.</p>
                    <p>The following officers have been granted leave of absence, on private affairs
                        : Lieut Colonel W. M. Duckett District Paymaster in Egypt Major H. C.
                        Petrie, Lieut J. H. 8tarkey, Lieut J. P. Crosbie and Lieut, A. A. Tod, 2nd
                        Rifle Brigado.</p>
                    <p>Rev. E. Ryan, Senior Chaplain to the Forces (R. C.) has been granted leave of
                        absence the recommendation of a medical board, from June 20 to October
                        19.</p>
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer, SC HOTEL COMPANY. RIVER Transport OF Goods
                        Between Alexandria A Cario Three Sellings a-Weak.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                        <byline>(From Our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <p>Port Said, Thursday. The official return for the pilgrim season of the
                            numbers of the different classes which passed through the Canal homeward
                            bound, show that 37 ships of different nationalities carried 33,036
                            pilgrims,which number includes 3,268 and Russians, 400 “varions,” the
                            balance, 29,368, being natives of these coasts. The total loss at Tor
                            through death is 161. 181 still remain there under treatment.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>RETURN OF BRITISH BATTLESHIPS.</p>
                        <p>Apropos of the recall of the entire fleet of British battleships on the
                            China Station, I learn that the “Canopns” and "Goliath,” whioh vessels
                            only recently passed through the Canal, are included in the list. The
                            others which have already received orders to return are the “Albion,’’
                            "Centurion," “Glory,” "Ocean," and “Vengeance.” They are to arrive here
                            on the 14th July.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>THE RECENT RIOT.</p>
                        <p>The water police officer who was badly hurt in the recent riot is now
                            convalescent and is again on partial duty. An enquiry is in progress at
                            the Gouvemorat into the case. Mr. Philippidis, secret service, Major
                            Bonelli, and Schalck Bey, of the Police, have been busily engaged. The
                            injured Arabs and police are all doing well. No farther trouble has
                            ensued and the lesson has undoubtedly had its effect, for more Arabs are
                            to be seen dredging for coal.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>HARBOUR IMPROVEMENTS.</p>
                        <p>The back of the “Chantier des Blocs" is now being cut away and will serve
                            as a dredger dock for the Canal Company. The heel of the new East
                            breakwater is also under process of continuation, it being intended to
                            form a protected bay for the floating dock there.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>HASHISH SEIZURE.</p>
                        <p>A seizure of 12 demijohns of what were described on the ship's manifest
                            and Customs declaration as mineral water took place at the custom house
                            to-day, through the intrepidity and zeal of the teftiche officer, Ali
                            Effendi 8abib, who called the attention of the local director (Mr. A. G.
                            Tarroll) to the matter. Although not this officer’s special work he had
                            his doubts, and on one being unpacked in presence of the director at the
                            bottom hashish was found in cakes. Duty had already been paid on the
                            “mineral water," but the director felt it his duty to retain the
                            consignment for instruction from the Direction-General.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>PERSONAL</p>
                        <p>Mr. Felix Powell, inspector in the Sanitary Administration, is due at
                            Port Said from Cairo to-morrow night. He will stay at the Eastern
                            Exchange.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>CANAL TRAFFIC INTERRUPTED.</p>
                        <p>Port Said, Friday. At 10 a-m. to-day all canal traffic was stopped north
                            and south of Kil. 18. It appears that one of the “Couloir” dredgers,
                            which has been working in that locality for some weeks, had an accident
                            to her machinery, which has resulted in the breaking of the bucket wheel
                            and chain. These have fallen into the canal quite close to the axial
                            line and in consequence ships are tied up north and south ot the point
                            By sundown six will be tied up to the south and five or six from the
                            north. Several vessels are at 8uez. Shear legs and divers have been
                            despatched to the scene under command of the port captain. </p>
                        <p>Port Said, Saturday. The Canal was clear again for traffio at 9 o'clock
                            last night The work of pumping and refloating the S S."Congai" will be
                            taken in hand at daylight on Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                        <p>London, Juno 16. England. First innings 282, second 151 runs for 5
                            wickets. MacLaron 70. Australia 181 runs, Darling 41. Derbyshire beat
                            Yorkshire by 9 wickets. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>London, Jane 16. Manchester Cup. 1, Airship; 2, Whistling Crow ; 3,
                            Thunderboltt (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>At last night's lotteries in connection with this afternoon’s racing the
                            following were the prices realised in Egyptian shillings Maiden Pont
                            Plate. —Fantaiia and 8t Frnrqnin 100, Suleik and Loulou 460, Siham 15,
                            A'mory 30, Aeolus 30, Gameohioken 40, Viking 100. Annual
                            Handicap.—Florenoe 60, Moofid 80, Brennus 100, Mashkonr 110, Fahd 400,
                            Mizzaud 85. Pony Handicap.—Roland 320, Spectre 50, Sirur 45, St Frnsqnin
                            55, Oyama 30, Agib and Aeolus 90, An Revoir and Sadik 500, Viking 200,
                            8hahronr 240. Champion Scurry.—KJondyke 85, Farhan H. 80, Rachid 840,
                            The Clown 20, Mizzaud 100, Kendal and Sattam 20, Roi de l’Air and
                            Veniotus 490, Tamerlan 150, Gameohiokeq 65, London 25, Sweetie 180</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD. ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh. ALEXANDRIA PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED BECK and CO’S PILSENER
                        BEER In Cario, Alexandria THE SUDAN. U, Bar we**, Alexandria </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
