<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-03"></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, MAY 16,1905</head>
<head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
AGAIN IN FRENCH WATERS.
M. ROUVIER’S EXPLANATIONS
Tokio, May 15.
It is positively affirmed that the BaltiC Fleet
left Honkohe temporarily under French pres-
sure, but it has since returned and remains
there.
Japan has prohibited the export of coal to
Saigon as long as the Russians remain in Indo-
Chinese waters.	(Reuter.)
Paris, May 15.
Replying to M. de Pressense in the French
Chamber, M. Rouvier declared that he had
nothing to add to the previous explanations;
he could only repeat that he had ordered the
authorities in the Far East to see that neu-
trality was strictly observed.	(Havas.)
<head>BRITISH STEAMER CONFISCATED.</head>
Tokio, May 15.
The Prize Court at Sasebo has confiscated
the British S.S. "Silvania," which was captured
on the 20th February near Vladivostok.	(R )
ANOTHER JAP TRANSPORT SUNK.
Chifu, May 15.
A steamer arrived here reports that another
Japanese transport was sunk by a mine in the
Gulf of Pechili almost simultaneously to the
time of the loss of the “Sheyuthu Maru.” (R.)
<head>STATE OF RUSSIA.</head>
DISORDERS IN ST. PETERSBURG.
St. Petersburg, May 15.
Slight disorders took place in the Vassily
Ostraff and Schlusselbourg quarters in the
afternoon and evening. The officers who were
ordering the holiday makers to disperse were
jeered and hustled towards the artificial lake,
where they stood knee deep and threatened the
crowd with their revolvers. The Cossacks
arrived and speedily dispersed the crowd. 50
arrests have been made.
The day passed quietly at Moscow, Warsaw,
Lodz, and most of the large towns of Russia.
(Reuter.)
<head>RUSSIA AND AFGHANISTAN.</head>
COMMENTS ON Mr. BALFOUR'S SPEECH.
St. Petersburg, May 15.
The "Bourse Gazette,” commenting on Mr.
Balfour’s speech, says that Russia has no time
at present for Central Asian affairs, but when
she emerges from the present crisis the efforts
of her enemies will be fruitless.
The "Novosti” sees no objection to Afghan-
istan serving as a rampart for India. The
“Petersbourg Listok” says that Russia has no
pretensions in Afghanistan.	(Reuter.)
<head>ALGIERS-TOULON AUTO-BOAT RACE.</head>
BOATS ABANDONED AT SEA.
Algiers, May 15.
The motor boats contesting in the race from
Algiers to Toulon left Port Mahon in a very
rough sea escorted by cruisers and destroyers.
The weather quickly got worse and developed
into a severe storm. The motor-boats were
taken in tow, but they had to be abandoned.
The crews were rescued. Even the destroyers
weathered the gale with great difficulty. (R.)
'	Port Mahon, May 15.
Out of seven motor-boats of the Algiers
foulon race six were lost. All the crews were
saved.	(Reuter.)
Toulon, May 15.
In the Algiers-Tonlon race, in consequenoe
of a storm, all the auto-boats sunk, except the
F.I.A.T., which was picked np. The crews were
saved.	(Hamas.)
<head>CELLULOID EXPLOSION IN VIENNA</head>
Vienna, May 15.
A fire which broke out in a store of- the
Kornblued factory caused an explosion of
celluloid. 58 people were injured.	(Havas.)
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
Sanitary Dept.—Drs. N. Iliakim Waizbard
and Isaac David have been authorised to
practise in Egypt
Holiday.—All the Ministries and Govern-
ment offices will be closed to-morrow on the
occasion of the Mouled en-Nebi.
The Plague.—No further cases of plague
are reported, and the measures taken on the
departure of vessels have been suppressed.
Popular University.—M. Alex. Max de
Zogheb will give a lecture at the university
to-morrow at 9.15 p.m. on "The History of
Alexandria.”
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
Esbekieh quarter of Cairo during the night of
Wednesday and at dawn on Thursday will be
poisoned by the police.
Anglo-American Nile.—The annual general
meeting of the Anglo-American Nile Steamer
and Hotel Company has been fixed to take
place on the 30th inst.
Suez Canal.—14 vessels passed through
the Canal on the 12th inst, 8 of which were
British, 1 Austrian, 2 German, 2 Turkish, 1
French. The day’s receipts were frs.;373,977.71,
making the total from the 1st inst francs
3,711,391.44.
<head>The "Mahroussa."</head>
—Work on the Khedive's
yacht, the “Mahroussa," still goes on at
Messrs. Inglis’s yard, Glasgow. The wood bul-
warks for the entire length have disappeared,
giving the ship a most woebegone appearance.
A good deal of the interior is still to come out.
<head>Egyptian Mining.</head> — 
Mr. B. 0. Ahlere,
A.M.I.C.E. (late chief engineer of the Coro-
mandel Gold Mines), has left England to con-
duct a preliminary expedition to the concession
of the North-Western Exploration Company,
Limited, in the district of Assiout.
<head>Irish Linens</head>.
—We do not know if the
fame of linens manufactured in Ireland has
spread throughout Egypt, but it should be
good news to British residents in this country
that they are obtainable in Cairo. Mr. Plan-
kett, of "Au De Rouge,” has just received his
summer supply.
<head>A Cool Fellah.</head>
—The following story told
about a railway signal-man is contained in
Dr. George Vincent’s new book, "Sunny
Egypt.” "About the most remarkable speci-
men of humanity we saw in Suez,” says Dr.
Vincent, "was a signal-man at a level cros-
sing, who, having fixed the gates so that trains
could pass and vehicles cross, had covered
up his head with his flags and gone to sleep
half in and half out of his signal box.”
Presentation of Medals. — On the occa-
sion of the recent visit of Brigadier-General
G. M. Bollock, C.B., commanding British troops
in Egypt, to Alexandria, on church parade at
Mustapha Pasha he presented Long Service
and Good Conduct Medals to Sergeant Major
Firth, 2nd Royal Berkshire Regiment, Garrison
Sergeant Major ; and staff Sergeant Major
Armstrong, Army Service Corps, Chief Clerk,
Caracol Attarin. The General, in presenting
the medals, alluded in a very appropriate
speech to the meritorious service of each
warrant officer, and wished them both long life
to wear their decorations. The qualifications
for the Long Service and Good Conduct Medal
are 18 years’ service and an exemplary cha-
racter.
<head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
TURKISH TROOPS FOR YEMEN.
(From our Correspondent).
Port Said, Monday.
The Transports Maritimes S.S. "Les Andes”
arrived here yesterday from Smyrna. She had
on board 2,540 Turkish soldiers and is to
be followed by another large vessel, flying
the same flag, to arrive in the course of the
next 24 hours. This last has some 3,000 more
Turkish troops, also bound for Hodeidah.
These two vessels make a total of nine
since the beginning of the month, and they
have taken in all a little over 17,000 troops
to various Red Sea ports, from whence they
will proceed to the seat of the trouble in
the Yemen.
<head>SEVERE WEATHER.</head>
The SR. "Stanley Hall,’’ which arrived
from England last night, reports haring en-
countered exceedingly heavy weather in the
Channel. It appears that off the Isle of Wight
the weather on the 1st and 2nd inst was
so bad as to oblige a largo number of ships
to anchor close to the Nab lightship. Several
vessels have been badly damaged and many
of the tramp class are much overdue.
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
The Ellerman S.S. "Athenian" arrived this
morning from Liverpool, Swanses, and Malta
with cargo.
The Papayanni liner "Flavian” left Malta
yesterday evening and is expected to arrive at
this port on Thursday afternoon with mails
and passengers.
<head>REAPPEARANCE OF LOCUSTS. IMPORTANT NEW FLOTATION.
CAREFUL WATCH ORDERED.</head>
Locusts having appeared in the Moudiriehs
of Minieh, Assiout, and Beni Souef, instructions
have been sent by the Ministry of the Interior
for a careful watch to he exercised and every
spot marked at which the locusts have settled'
in order that the eggs may at once be searched
for and also in due course necessary measures
may be taken to destroy any which are not
discovered and which hatch out
These locusts are the Acridium perigrinum,
the same as last year, and are reported to
have arrived from the S. E. So far they are
in much smaller flights than were observed
previously, and it is noticeable that they are
more than a month later.
The locusts have chiefly descended in the
Kurtun cultivation on their appearance.
<head>RED SEA-SUDAN RAILWAY</head>
The Red Sea terminus of the new line to
the Nile valley is eventually to be at Port
Sudan,but at present it is atSuakin. The line is
being pushed on with great rapidity, but
Opinion of many competent 'critics, celerity of
construction is sacrificing the efficiency of the
line for the following reason. The Sudan
Government, in its eagerness to complete
railway, is avoiding all difficult gradients
and costly tunnelling, with the result that,
while the present caravan route from Suakin
to Berber is about 250 miles, the distance By
rail will be over 300 miles. As speed and
shortness of time in transit are the essentials
of all modem railways, this policy may be
considered very false economy.
<head>Port Sudan</head>
The Sudan Government has adopted a very
wise system in the ease of Port Sudan, in
order to prevent the over-speculation in land
which is becoming a dangerous symptom in
Egyptian development. Instead of selling the
land outright at what is to be the great port
of the Sudan, the Government has decided
to only grant leases for a long term of
years. This is the policy we advocated in
our leading article in our issue of Friday
last in regard to the new quay estate at
Alexandria. Why does not the Egyptian Govern-
ment follow the precedent of the Sudan and
adopt our advice ?
<head>BRITISH .GARRISON.</head>
The command of the troops at Alexandria
will in future devolve upon the senior officer
at the station. It is not thought necessary to
appoint an officer specially to the charge, hav-
ing regard to the steps which have lately been
taken to reduce the strength and expenses of
the Army of Occupation in Egypt.
Col. L.B. Friend, R.E., commanding R.E. of
the British forces in Egypt, vacates that ap-
pointment on transfer to the home establish-
ment, and is succeeded by Lient-CoL A.M.
Mantel, who has been doing duty at Alexan-
dria, which will cease to be a lieutenant-colo
nel's charge under the reduction scheme.
Colonel J. Magill, M.D., C.B., P.M.O. in
Egypt, accompanied by Major F.W. Hardy,
M.B., R.A.M.C., will proceed from Cairo on the
24th inst. to Cyprus, on inspection duty, re
turning to Cairo on completion.
<head>NEW THEATRE FOR CAIRO</head>
The open theatre on the banks of the Nile
at Ghezireh has been leased by Messrs. A.
Royet and Co. and was opened on Friday night
as a place of variety entertainment under the
name of "Theatre des .Ambassadeure.” A
more delightful situation for a summer theatre
could not have been chosen, and should the
management keep the entertainment np to
the same standard as that which we witnessed
tho other night they are sure to meet with suc-
cess. A restaurant is attached to tho theatre
where dinners are served before the per-
formance and suppers during and after it A
third of Friday’s proceeds arc to be devoted
to the various charitable institution^' of the
oity, and as the theatre was crowded' a con-
siderable sum should be distributed amongst
them.
At the commencement of the entertainment
the band played the Austrian, Russian, Italian,
French, English, and Khedivial National
Anthems in the order named and this was
followed by a prologue of welcome to the
audience spoken by Mmo. Royot. Wo than
settled ourselves down to enjoy what proved
to be one of the best programmes which Cairo
audiences have ever had presented to them.
Unfortunately, shortly after the performance
had begun, the electric light, which is supplied
by a special dynamo, went out, and the
audience and stage were left in total darkness
for tho space of a quarter of an hour, bat on
the light being restored the entertainment
rolled merrily on without farther interruption.
It would be invidious to individualise from
amongst the various artistes, as each one was
good in his or her particular line, and want of
space prevents us from giving a detailed ac-
count. The names of the artistes are: —Miles
Carmen 8t. John, Arlette, Daulnoy, Liane
Brionhe, Lietto Linda, Dolly, Demezin, De
Coral, Solea la Morena, Luce Marsay, MM.
Cooper, Nerly, Perrand, Lea Real Roseltys and
les Renards.
The performance, however, would not suffer
by being made somewhat shorter as it was 1 a.m.
before the entertainment was concluded. We
would also suggest to the management that
some arrangement should be made by which
the seats could be placed in raised tiers and
that give the whole audience an equal chance
of seeing the artiste on the stage.
<head>LARGE LAND COMPANY.</head>
On the 18th inst we will publish the 
announcement and abridged prospectus of a
very important new estate company.  It is
called the North Egypt Land Company and it
is offering to the public 100,000 shares at £1
each. The issue is being made simultaneously
in Egypt and in England. 40,000 shares of
this issue are reserved for subscription in
Egypt and it is gratifying to learn that the
share warrants for this number of shares are
now ready for delivery.
The board is a very strong one, and the
chairman is the Earl of Galloway, who. proved
his business ability when he was commissioned
by the British Government to rearrange the
Ottoman Debt when be was at Constantinople.
The subscriptions will be received at the
Anglo-Egyptian Bank at Cairo and at the
Banque d’Athfines at Alexandria, from which
banks prospectuses can be obtained. We are
advised that the lists will close on or before
Friday next at 4 p.m.
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
The Khedive will leave for Cairo this after-
noon, accompanied by HE the Governor, in
order to attend the Monied eni-Nebi celebra-
tions 
We understand that, the Khedive’s has ante-
dated his .departure for Europe. His Highess
now intends, leaving Alexandria on the 25th
inst on a specially chartered steamer.
In consequenoe of the Khedive’s change of
plans, the State Ball, which the "Journal Offi-
ciel” yesterday announced would take place on
the 5th Jane, has had to be postponed.
One of the great attractions for visitors to
London from Egypt this season will be the
beautiful portrait of the Khedive exhibited at
the Royal Academy this year. The artist is
Mr. J. Watson Nicol and the portrait is an
effective fall-length of the Khedive in uniform
of blue and gold.
<head>COTTON COMPANIES’ PROFITS.</head>
Mr.W. Tattersall in the "Financier” (May 8)
—Cotton companies have declared very large
dividends this week on recent stock-takings. It
is said that at the end of May and Jane still
larger gains will be announced. There has been
a good deal of talk about these results! It is
contended by some that such large figures
should not have been published, but directors
are supposed to know their business. One thing
is pretty sure—that the Egyptian spinningtrade
is very poor indeed compared with American
counts. Bolton spinners, it is said, especially
those who spin the superior marks, are losing
money, but in Lancashire, where rather com-
moner yarns ate produced, it is reported that
there is a slight profit This is confirmed by
the result declared by a company in the town
of Rochdale.
<head>A SOLDIER'S FROLIO</head>
This was the phrase with which an English-
speaking Egyptian youth described a scene in
the Sharia Mohamed Aly in Cairo yesterday
evening. It was, however, a frolic that might
possibly have led to very serious consequences.
At about a quarter to seven o’clock two Eng-
lish soldiers, one of whom was very much' the
worse for drink, attempted to enter a tram car
just as it had turned out of the Atabah el
Khadra, with the idea that it was going to the
Citadel. The conductor and others tried to
make the men understand that the oar was not
going in the direction in which they wished,
bnt the man who was intoxicated persisted in
trying to enter it. Naturally a crowd collected
and when at length' the would-be passenger
was persuaded to await another car and
abandoned his effort to force himself into the
wrong one, a number of the young roughs who
had assembled began boo-ing and shouting.
Thereupon the wrathful Tommy, a fine strap-
ping fellow, charged the mob, which promptly
scattered to a safe distance, froth which it re-
sumed its boo-ing. Again the offended man
made a reckless charge, and this time arming
himself with his belt, laid it with good will
upon all he could get within reach of. For-
tunately, all of these were in full flight and
received the blows upon the less vulnerable
parts of their persons. Thenceforth for folly
a quarter of an hour the mob kept alternately
returning to their boo-ing and flying from the
soldier, whose companion was entirely unable'
to restrain him. In this way the contending
parties, if we may so term them, carried on
their warfare until they had reached the house
formerly occupied by Dr. Milton’s establish-
ment Here an Egyptian from one of the shops
flung a chair at the soldier, which glanced off
his back and fell,—with such violence that fine
of the legs was broken. Eventually the
drunken man’s companion managed to get
him into a tramcar going to the Citadel,
and the affair came to a happy end.
That it did so was, however, entirely due to
the fortunate chance that the drunken man
failed to inflict any injury upon any of those
whom he attacked, and that although many
stones and other missiles were thrown at him,
they likewise toiled in their aim. As it was,
the affray was a "soldier’s frolio” and on both
sides a good-humoured skirmish rather than
anything else, bat it might very easily have
developed into a serious matter, and it is
therefore desirable to speak a word of censure
for four other English soldiers who, coming on
the scene, almost in the thick of the battle,
made haste to leave it without the least at-
tempt to carry off their drunken companion.
We need not say that we have no desire to
make a mountain out of a molehill, but when
we remember how important it is that every
Englishman in the country should do his best
to prevent any friction between , any of his 
countrymen and the natives,we cannot but
think that these men were very seriously want-
ing in their duty in acting as they did.
<head>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY
TELEGRAM FROM KHEDIVE</head>
Pressure on our space yesterday prevented
us from giving the. text of the telegram ad-
dressed to H.H. the Khedive by Yehia Bey.
The following is a translation
Monseigneur,—Les fetes officielles du cen-
tenaire de votre illustre aieul, le Grand Mehe-
met Aly, viennent par la grace de Dieu de
prendre fin entourees de toute la pompe et de
tout l’eclat dont elles sont dignes et an milieu
de la joie unanime de la population. Mon
devoir, en cette circonstance, est d’exprimer
respectueusement a V.A. tant en mon nom 
qn'en celui des habitants de cette ville et de
ceux des antres porta d’Egypte, tons sujets ,
fidles de V.A nos vives sinceres felicita- ,
tions pour l’elan de loyalisme et de devouement
au Trone de V.A. dont les fetes de ce jour ont
revele la sincerite. Animes de ces sentiments
nous prions le tout Puissant d’acoorder a V.A.
et k vos Augustes enfants longue vie et
prosperite. 
The following gracious reply was reoeived
from his Highness :—
"Nous avons recu avec une grande satisfac-
tion et une profonde gratitude votre telegram-
me qui temoigue des sentiments eleyes dont
sont animes, & quelque nationalite qu’ils
appartiennent, lee habitants de oette villa,
sentiments dont nons avions la certitude. Nous
vous inviterons ainsi que MM. les membres du
Comite des fetes a venir au Palais de Ras-el-
Tin afin de vous exprimer a vous et a eux, nos,
vifs remerciements pour tout ce que vous avez
fait a l’occasion du centanaire de notre grand
aieul—Abbas Hilmy.
<head>MASONIC MEETING.</head>
The special meeting of Masons held at
Alexandria to commemorate the centenary of
Mohamed Aly was a very impressive one,
representing as it did every nationality .to
Egypt united under one great bond of brother-
hood. Representatives were present from.
English, Scotch, Egyptian, Italian, German,
Greek, and French lodges.
The president, after opening the meeting,
addressed a few words to French, drawing
attention to the debt civilisation to Egypt
owed to Mohamed Aly. The grand secretary
then added a few remarks in English, and be-
fore the meeting closed the following tele-
gram was sent from the united brethren to
H. H. the Khedive.
Je prie Votre Excellence de vonloir bien
transmettre k Son Altesse le Khfidive l’ordre
da jour suivant:
Les masons des Loges Egyptiennes, Alle-
mandes, Anglaisee, Ecossaises, Hellenes et
Italiennes tennis en seance solennelle sous les
auspices du Supreme Conseil Ecossais federal
du 33e degre commemorant le centenaire de
votre aieul vénère, héros de l’humanité, qui fit
luire le flambeau de la civilisation en Orient,
Forment des voeux pour la conservation de
Votre Altesse et de votre auguste dynastie et
prient Votre Altesse d’agreer l’expression de
leur dévouement.
Felix de Menasce.
His Highness replied as follows:—
Je suis profondedment. reconnaissant aux
Macons des Loges Egyptiennes, Allemandes,
Anglaises, Ecossaises, Hellenes et Italiennes,
qui reunis en seance solennelle sons les ans-
pices du supreme Conseil Ecossais federal du
33e degre ont vote un ordre du jour comme-
morant d’une facon si touchante le centenaire
de mon Aieul.
En vons remerciant, Monsieur le Baron, ainsi
que les freres macons, de cette eclatante mani-
festation d'attachement a la dynastie, je tien os
k vons faire parvenir egalement ma gratitude
pour les voeux que vous m'adressez vous tous
en ce jour memorable.
Abbas Hilmi.
<head>DATE OF CENTENARY.</head>
To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir, It would be interesting to know at
whose instigation and from what motives the
date May 14th was selected for the celebretion
of the centenary of Mohamed Aly. The firman
appointing Mohamed Aly to be "Governor of
Egypt” was signed, according to El-Gabbarti,
on June 18th, 1805. The Saltan’s envoy,
Saleh Agha, landed at Alexandria with the
firman on June 26th and arrived at Cairo on
July 9th, at which date Felix Mengin, tee
contemporary French historian, tells us the
investiture took place. May 14th was not
accordingly the date on which Mohamed Aly
became the rightful Governor of Egypt but
was in fact the date on which the preliminary
insurrectionary movement against Khorshid
Pasha was inaugurated.
Mengin narrates the the incident as follows:
Le 14 mai, les mecontents se porterent en
foule dans la grande cour du Mehkemeh. Le
Cadi, redoutant une revolution populairo, fit
fermer les portes de son tribunal. Seyd-Agha,
et plusieurs d’entre les principaux cheikhs,
qui se trouvaient depuis le matin chez ce
magistrat se rendirent chez Mohamed-Aly, et
lui d’clarerent qu’ils ne voulaient plus être
gouvernes par Khourohyd-Pacha; que ce chef
s’etait rendu odieux par ses persecutions;
qu’il avait encouru l'indignation publique, et
qu’il meritait que la justice de Dieu s’appe-
santit sur lui : "II faot le deposer,” ajouta
Seyd-Omar Makram."Quel est celui que nous
vonlez toveatir de son antorite 1" demanda
Mohamod-Aly a ces representants. — "Vous-
meme. Nous vunlons que vous soyez notre
gouverneur suivant les lois, parce que nous
savons que vous aimez le bien.” Mohammed-
Aly, qui ne voulait point laisser croire qu il
etait l’instigatenr de ces menées, refusa* d'a-
bord ces propositions; mais les cheikhs syant
renouvale leurs instances, il se rendit a leurs 
vceux.
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
Mr-.Douglas Dunlop, Secretary general of
the Ministry of Public Instruction, is leaving
for England on leave at the end of the
month.
Mr. and Mrs. A. G. M. Dickson were among
the pasaengers who left by tee Austrian Lloyd
steamer for Europe on Saturday.
A marriage has been arranged, and will
take place early to August, between Major
Francis J. L. Howard, A. 8. C., attached
Egyptian Army, third sou of Lieutenant-
Colonel Howard, late R.R., of Kensington
Park-gardens, and Maria, Ethel, widow of
Captain Alexander Campbell,the Black Watch,
and elder daughter of the late Rear Admiral
George Hancock, of Berwick Lodge, Ryde,
Isle of Wight, and Mrs. Hancock, of The
Cottage, Bampton, Oxfordshire.
In our issue of the 12th inst. we omitted to
say that Archdeacon Gwynne was first sent np
to Khartoum about a year after the battle of
Omdurman by the Church Missionary Society,
to order to hold himself to readiness for any
work that the Government might permit him
to undertake there on behalf of his society. In
addition to what he has been able .to do to this
direction, he has acted as chaplain to charge of
the troops, and has given his services also as
chaplain to the residents to Khartoum, besides
paying periodical visits to, Wady Halfa for the
same purpose. Before going to the Sudan, Mr.
Gwynne had been for some years vicar of a
church to Nottingham.
<head>PEMJME AND SOCIAL</head>
The following visitors have put up, most
of them for a long stay, at the Bean-Rivage
Hotel, Ramleh : Mr. and Mme Jules May,
Mr. and Mrs. L. Davies, Mr. and Mrs. H.
Tilseau, Dr. and Mme Amb. S. Ralli, Mi—
E. Cornwell, Miss A.. Drusham, Capt and
Mrs. W. H. Rotheram, Miss M. Soulic, Mr.
J. W. Dart, Mrs. F, IL Farrar and oonrier,
the Misses. Farrar, Miss M. Young, Min
Lewis Stewart, Min C. Wormer, Mr. and
Mrs. H. Linaut, Min L. Clarke, Mr. R.
Ahrale and Mr. J. W. Foxwoft
Alors Seyd-Omar Makram et le cheikh Ab-
dallah-Cherkaouy se leverent, revetirent d'una
pelisse le gouvernenr qu’ils venaient d’elire, et
le firent proclamer do suite dans toute la ville.
Une deputation so rendit aupres de Khour
chyd-Pacha, pour lui donner connaissance de
ce qui venait de se passer: “Je suis vice-roi de
l'Egypte," repondit ce prince, "en vertu des
litres que m’a conferes le sultan ;je ne con
sentirai point a etre destitue par des fellahs j
je declare que je ne descendrai de la citadelle
que d’apres les ordres da la Sublime Porta.’’.
Toute la wille etait dans une violente agita-
tion ; les cheikhs se réunirent a la place de
l'Ezbekieh avec une partie du peuple en armes.
Khourchyd-Pachs fit monter a la citadelle da
ble, da biscuit, et toutes les provisions qu'il
put.rassembler………Les cheikhs se reunirent
an Mehkhemeh, ou ils dresserent un acte dans
lequel ils déclaraient les motifs qui les avaient
guides dans les circonstances qui venaient de
se passer..... La conseil des cheikhs expédia
de suite un courrier a Constantinople, pour in
former la Porte des mesures qu’il avait prises
d'apres le voeu des habitants, pour assurer la
tranquillite de l’Egypte.'........Khourchyd oc-
cupait toujours la citadelle......Le 19 mai
Mohamed-Aly fit placer des troupes a l’entour
de la citadelle pour en former le blocus....
Le 23, la garnison de la citadelle fit une sortie
dans l'intention de surprendre les gardes pos-
tdes aux retranchements sur la place de Ron-
meyleh ;…….Le 29 la citadelle fut tout-a-fait
cernee, et on transporta sur le Mokattam deux'
mortiers pour la bombarder……Le 19 et 20
juin, Khourchyd Pacha fit bombarder la ville
.......Le 88,un courrier dromadaire apporta
la nouvelle du debarquement a Alexandrie de
Saleh Agha,avec des depeches de Constantino-
ple.......Le 9 juillet, le Capidjy fit son entree
au Caire…….Oh donna lecture deja de la volon-
te des ulemas et du peuple……
Is it possible that the date May 14th was
selected by some of our "Young Egyptians” to
contempt for the Sultan's authority and to
glorification of the “divine right” of rebellion?
And how came the members of the Committee
to acquiesce in the selection ofthis date?
Yours &c, etc.
Historicus.
WINDSOR HOTEL.
Largest 1st class and most comfortable 
Hotel in Alexandria.  Facing the sea 
central position. Under English management.
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
