<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brayan Barbosa</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-12-07</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-07-25</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

                <div type="section">
                    <head>TSAR AND KAISER. THE MONARCHS’ INTERVIEW. CONJECTURES AS TO OBJECT</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, July 24. The Tsar was accompanied by his brother only ;
                        neither the Court nor the Ministry of - Foreign Affairs being represented.
                        The fact is perhaps to be explained by consideration for French feeling.
                        There will be a second meeting on board the Standart to-day, and the Tsar
                        will return to Peterhoff in the evening. It is authoritatively stated that
                        the meeting took place at the request of the Emperor William, who informed
                        the Tsar, from Sweden, that he was desirous of seeing him, in order to
                        convince him of the sincerity of the German policy towards Russia.</p>
                    <p>Probably he was anxious to counteract the effect produced by the cordial
                        reception of Prince Arisugawa in Germany and the German participation in the
                        Japanese loan. The real significance of the meeting, however, can only be
                        surmised. M. Witte knew nothing of it before his departure.</p>
                    <p>It is pointed out in official circles that the exchange of views between the
                        Emperors is calculated to assist the labours of the Russian
                        plenipotentiaries, by promoting a general entente on the affairs of the Far
                        East (R.) Berlin, July 24.</p>
                    <p>The German papers suggest that the inter- view emanated from the Tsar. The
                        motives and objects of the meeting are being anxiously discussed throughout
                        Europe, especially in France, where M. Witte is at present discuss- ing
                        future policies, notably the possibility of a loan.</p>
                    <p>The Emperors' yachts only met at 10 o'clock last night but visits were
                        immediately ex- changed. The Monarchs separated at 1.30 this morning
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Borgo, July 24. After having exchanged repasts on board the Hohenzollern and
                        the Polar Star, the Tsar and the Emperor William conferred for two hours.
                        The Tsar afterwards returned to St. Petersburg. (Havas.)</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>REPORTED JAPANESE REPULSE. FIGHT FOR POSSESSION OF TIUMEN PASS.</head>
                        <p><placeName>Vladivostok,</placeName> July 24. in a battle fought for the
                            possession of the Tinmen pass, 30,000 Japanese were repulsed.
                            (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIAN UNREST. OUTBREAK OF MOB VIOLENCE</head>
                        <p><placeName>Nijni Novgorod,</placeName> July 24. There has been a terrible
                            outbreak of mob violence here against all well-dressed people, who were
                            pursued into the houses. Many were killed and wounded. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW GOVERNOR OF GIBRALTAR. GEN. FORESTIER WALKER APPOINTED.</head>
                        <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 24. ” General Forestier Walker has
                            been appoint- ed Governor of Gibraltar. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <p>Major-General Sir Francis R. Wingate had an audience of the King at
                            Buckingham Palace on Tuesday week.</p>
                        <p>The Bey of Tunis has conferred the 2nd Class of the Order of the Iftikhar
                            upon Sheikh Ali Youssef, Editor of "A1 Moayad.” M. S. Doliwa, Austro
                            Hungarian Consul at Port Said, left for Europe yesterday. His functions
                            will be performed during his absence by M. S. C. Wellunschek.</p>
                        <p>M. Falqui-Cao left Alexandria for Cairo on Sunday evening.</p>
                        <p>Birch Pasha leavesenxt Saturday by the Austrian Lloyd boat.</p>
                        <p>We are informed that Saghcolagassi Lynn has resigned his functions and
                            that his resigna- tion has been accepted, to date from Monday. July
                            24.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                        <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</p>
                        <p>REGATTA.</p>
                        <p>The handicap for to-morrow’s racing is the same as last week.</p>
                        <p>Class I. Course F. Class II. Course N. A. S. C.</p>
                        <p>Polo will be played on Friday instead of Thursday this week, the
                            regimental sports of the 2nd Royal Berkshires being held on Thursday
                            (Maiwand Day).</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>GOVERNMENT CRISIS.</head>
                    <p>MR. BALFOUR’S ATTITUDE.</p>
                    <p>OPPOSITION PROTESTS.</p>

                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 24. House of Commons.—Mr. Balfour has an-
                        nounced that the Government will not resign, In the House of Commons Sir
                        Henry Camp- bell-Bannerman condemned Mr. Balfour’s atti- tude as utterly
                        unconstitutional. Mr. Redmond said that the Liberals and Irish will unite to
                        make the position unendurable by contesting everything. Mr. Winston
                        Churchill accused the Government of (touting the traditions of Parliament,
                        and dishonoring the service of the Crown.</p>
                    <p>There were several heated scenes and speeches, but the Opposition, for
                        tactical reasons, deciding to abstain from a division, the debate
                        unexpectedly terminated. The Government motion for adjournment was carried
                        without division, amid derisive Government laughter and cheers.</p>
                    <p>The Government supporters had been most effectively whipped, and the
                        Opposition was anxious to avoid any heavily unfavorable divisions, which
                        would counteract the effect of Thursday’s defeat.</p>
                    <p>House of Lords.—Lord Lansdowne an- nounced the decision of the Government.
                        Lord Rosebery said that Mr. Balfour is strain- ing the principles of the
                        Constitution to their very foundation. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> July 21. The papers are full of surmises and
                        conjes- tures as to the date of dissolution, but nothing is certain, and
                        there are no further develop- ments of the crisis. The Liberal papers
                        vehemently protest, against the argument that foreign politics make the
                        resignation of the Government un- advisable. (Reuter.)</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                        <p>THE PLAGUE.—Yesterday’s bulletin records one case at Dekerness only.</p>
                        <p>HASHISH SEIZED.-The Customs Guards yes- terday seized 236 torbas of
                            hashish on the S.S. Singapore and Enna now in port.</p>
                        <p>MINISTRY OF THE INTERIOR —Mr. Burnett Stewart will inspect Behera and
                            Gharbieh provinces till further notice.</p>
                        <p>SAILOR HURT.—An English sailor named Dunphy fell into the hold of the
                            S.S. Northam yesterday after lunching, and had to be removed to the
                            German Hospital,</p>
                        <p>FALL FORM A TRAM.—A Greek maid has been sent to hospital suffering from
                            injuries sustained through falling from a tram between San Stefano and
                            Schutz.</p>
                        <p>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS found in the Darb el Ahmar district of Cairo
                            during the night of Wednesday and at daylight on Thursday will be
                            poisoned by the police.</p>
                        <p>AFFRAY IN HAMAMIL-STREET.—A Greek attacked one of his countrymen in
                            Hamamil- street yesterday and stabbed him, inflicting injuries that
                            necessitated his removal to hospital. The criminal has been
                            arrested.</p>
                        <p>NATIONAL BANK.—The committee of the London Stock Exchange have appointed
                            August 3 a special settling day in National Bank of Egypt—Scrip
                            certificates for a further issue of 19,622 shares to bearer of £10 each
                            (issued at £10 premium), £5 paid (all of which i is premium).</p>
                        <p>SAINT CATHERINE’S COLLEGE, ALEXANDRIA. —The annual distribution of prizes
                            at this institution will take place at 4 o’clock to- morrow afternoon,
                            under the presidency of M. Maurice Campana, acting French Consul. An
                            attractive programme has been arranged, which includes the performance
                            of the operetta in 2 acts, Riquet a la Houppe.</p>
                        <p>A MEMORIAL SERVICE for the late M. De- lyannis, Prime Minister of Greece,
                            was held at n the Greek Orthodox Church of St. Nicolas, Cairo,
                            yesterday. M. Gennadis, M. Rikakis, and most of the principal members of
                            the Hellenic Colony of Cairo were present at the impressive ceremony
                            over which Mgr. Photius, the Greek Orthodox Patriarch, presided.</p>
                        <p>A RARE KORAN.—“Al Mokattam" states that Mansfield Pasha, Commandant of
                            the Cairo Police, is taking a copy of the Koran with him to England.
                            This copy has a most curious history, having been made by the secretary
                            of the false Khalifa, Abdallah el Tasishi, who presented it to Emir
                            Ahmed Wad Medani. Manfield Pasha will present the copy to the library of
                            Beaumont College, where his son is being educated.</p>
                        <p>ALHAMBRA THEATER. OwtsjM. George Ralli well-known Author of local
                            reviews, has handed to M. Gonnet-Levy, whose comedy company occupies the
                            boards of the Alhambra the manuscript of a comedy in 3 acts entitled Les
                            Surprises de l’Heritage. This evening, the company produces Les Deux
                            Gosses(“The Two Vagabonds”), and to-morrow Mysotte, Lave- dan’s 3-act
                            omen, which is new to Alexandria, will be staged.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>PROPOSED PROMENADE PIER.</head>
                    <p>EAST HARBOUR PIER SCHEME.</p>
                    <p>We have previously made reference to this scheme, and are now able to give
                        our readers further information upon the subject. We understand that the
                        promoters made their application to tho Alexandria Municipality in December,
                        1903, for the necessary concession, and by November, 1904, the final plans
                        had been submitted. All points of discussion had been amicably settled
                        between the Municipality and the promoters about three months ago ; and one
                        would have therefore naturally con- cluded that the issue of the concession
                        would have been only a question of a few days. But alas we understand the
                        whole question has been shelved pro tem, as most of the Municipal- ity
                        officials are away on leave and the matter cannot be decided in their
                        absence. If it were only the members of the Municipal- ity who would be
                        affected we should have nothing more to say in the matter; but such is not
                        the case: the whole population of Alex- andria and its neighbourhood is
                        interested in this scheme, inasmuch as when the pier is built it will fill a
                        much-felt want and will be the happy means to help them to pleasantly while
                        away the long Bummer evenings, away from the noise and heat of the busy
                        city, yet so to speak within easy distance of their very doors.</p>
                    <p>The length of the pier, we are given to understand, will be over 1,000 feet,
                        and in appearance will resemble the very handsome one erected at Brighton.
                        The skeleton work will be all of iron and supported on cast-iron columns,
                        while the decking will be of wood, and several ornamental structures will be
                        erected upon it, such as a very handsome pavilion, refreshment rooms, shops,
                        and other necessary accommodation suitable to the country. There will also
                        be the usual band- stand and promenade, and first-class swimming baths.</p>
                    <p>Not only will a pier of this kind supply a much-felt want, but it will add
                        considerably towards embellishing the appearance and ge- neral effect of the
                        new quay wall and eastern harbour. We therefore hope that the Municipa- lity
                        will do their utmost in getting through with the necessary formalities as
                        soon as pos- sible, and place the promoters in a position to start the work
                        with as little delay as possible, for the sooner this is done the sooner
                        will the pie be built and placed at the disposal of the general public. As
                        the cost of the proposed pier will be very considerable, we think the
                        authorities should in the interest of the general public give the promoters
                        every assistance to enable them to guarantee the enterprise prov- ing a
                        success, whilst at the same time safe- guarding other public interests.</p>
                    <p>When completed, the new quay will un- doubtedly be the fashionable promenade
                        of Alexandria, and we think the authorities would be well advised to take
                        every precaution to avoid the collection of unlicensed touts and
                        loafers.</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA’S DRAINAGE.</head>
                        <p>Considerable, if unwilling, attention has been paid by the public to the
                            unpleasant smells arising from the drains daring the last two or three
                            weeks. The present season is the most favorable for the outbreak of
                            epidemics, and we should like to point out to the Municipal authorities
                            that the least negligence may lead to sanitary complications, the
                            prevention of which will be more easy than the pure. The public would be
                            glad to know whether the linking of the subsidiary drains with the main
                            drain of the city has been completed or not, and we are of opinion that
                            the Municipality would do well to reassure us on these points. If the
                            drainage system is not properly at work yet we hope that the necessary
                            measures of disjunction and clearing of the drains not yet linked with
                            the main collector are being taken with a view to minimise the evil
                            results of the non completion of the system.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ENTERTAINMENT AT SUEZ</head>
                        <p>Last Saturday evening a most enjoyable entertainment was given at the
                            Cercle Inter- national at Port Tewfik by Mr. O. D. Harris, who produced
                            an original play in one act entitled “Pierrot et Pierrette," a pretty
                            little sketch in which Mr. Heale made an admirable Pierrot and Miss
                            Glennie a most charming Pierrette, At the conclusion both actors and
                            author were called before the curtain and greeted with much applause.
                            Mr. Harris may be remembered as the author of “The Mummy and the
                            Munmmer," a topical farce performed at Suez last year.</p>
                        <p>The remainder of the programme consisted of several well-selected items,
                            among which mention should be made of Mile'. Deperais's singing of
                            Raynals' “Valse Chantee,” end Mrs. Hugues’ excellent tendering ol
                            Tosti’s “Chanson de Fortuno.” Both ladies received enthusiastic encores.
                            Mr. Dogmore scored a “hit" in his amusing song, “The Stammering
                            Sweethearts.” Mr. Rittuck showed himself an able banjoist in the solo
                            “Bonnie Scotland." ‘Ailsa Mine," song by Mr. Heale, was very much
                            appreciated, as it fully deserved to be. Instrumental selections were
                            rendered by an orchestra consisting of banjos (Messrs. G. W. Hancock and
                            E. J. Pittuck), violin (Mr. H. F. Healy), and piano (Mr. H. T. Healy)
                            The entertainment concluded with a very amusing and original “torn" by
                            Mr. O. D. Harris, "In the Twilight," with imitation violoncello obbli-
                            gato, which was continually interrupted by rounds of applause. His
                            ventriloquial sketch, in which he introduced to the audience his two
                            figures "Joey” and "Eliza," caused great amusement. Great credit is due
                            to Mr. O. D. Harris for his unflagging energy in arranging the
                            entertainment, and he is to be congratu- lated on being able to secure
                            the services of so many talented amateur.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>EGYPT AND MONTENEGRO.</head>
                    <p>COMMERCIAL AGREEMENT</p>
                    <p>CONCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday's "Official Journal” contains cor- respondence relating to the
                        conclusion of a commercial agreement between Egypt and Montenegro. In a
                        letter dated March 30,1905, M. V. G. Voucovitch, Montenegrin Minister for
                        Foreign Affairs, informs the Egyptian Mi- nister for Foreign Affairs that
                        the Montenegrin Government is anxious to give the necessary stability to the
                        commercial transactions be- tween the two countries by the conclusion of a
                        treaty of commerce and navigation. While the terms of such a treaty were
                        being studied the Egyptian Government would perhaps agree with the
                        Montenegrin in considering that a provisional arrangement on the basis of
                        the most-favoured nation clause would be of great advantage to both
                        countries.</p>
                    <p>In a letter dated May 3, 1905, H. E. Mostasha Pasha Fehmy suggests that the
                        object of both governments would be best obtained not by the conclusion of a
                        treaty, but by an agreement finder which each country in their mutual
                        commerce is to enjoy the same privi- leges as those possessed by nations
                        which have concluded commercial treaties with Egypt.This provisional
                        arrangement is to remain in vigour until denounced by one or other of the
                        contrac- ting parties, who are bound to give 12 months’ notice of their
                        intention.</p>
                    <p>The remainder of the correspondence is confined to the formal acceptance by
                        both Governments of the proposal.</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE COTTON WORM</head>
                        <p>The weekly official report issued by the Ministry of the Interior on the
                            work which is being done for the destruction of the cotton worm shows
                            for the week ending 22nd inst. not only a general and distinct decrease
                            in the number of areas which have been attacked,but also that the cotton
                            cultivations of three provinces, namely, Fayoum, Minieh, and Beni-
                            Souef, which had suffered previously, have during the last week remained
                            entirely free of the worm, During the preceding week 27,026 feddans were
                            in all attacked in these provinces, so that the non-appearance of the
                            worm through- out last week may be taken as an indication that these
                            provinces have been entirely cleared of it, and its re-appearance is
                            regarded as im- probable.</p>
                        <p>The reports from other provinces are as follows:-</p>
                        <p>Ghizeh :—880 feddans, belonging to 379 pro- prietors, have been attacked
                            by the worm and have all been cleared from it</p>
                        <p>Kalioubieh :—318. feddans, belonging to 174 proprietors, have been
                            attacked, and 407 feddans here been cleared by 2,608 children,</p>
                        <p>Menoufieh : -1,106 feddans, belonging to 492 proprietors, have been
                            attacked and 1,335 feddans have been cleared by 7,260 children.</p>
                        <p>Gharbieh :—1,968 feddans, belonging to 254 proprietors, have been
                            attacked and 1,898 feddans have been cleared by 3,665 children.</p>
                        <p>Sharkieh :—122 feddans, belonging to 55 proprietors, have been attacked
                            and have all been cleared by 520 children.</p>
                        <p>Behara :-31,035 feddans, belonging to 1,743 proprietors, have been
                            attacked and 26,005 feddans have been cleared by 73,555 children.</p>
                        <p>Pakahlieh :—4,336 feddans, belonging to 1,015 proprietors, have been
                            attacked and 3,995 feddans have been cleared by 15,174 children.</p>
                        <p>Damietts :-159 feddans, belonging to 72 proprietors, have been attacked
                            and have all been cleared by 1,025 children.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEDWET EL ASSAL</head>
                        <p>The Nedwet el Assal has appeared in various cotton cultivations but
                            active steps are being taken for its destruction.</p>
                        <p>Many of oar readers will doubtless re member that in a note which was
                            published by the Ministry of the Interior the Nedwet el Assal was
                            described as a certain sooty fungus which are attracted by a sticky kind
                            of honey- dew deposited on the cotton leaves by small green midges,
                            known as Aphis, which attack the cotton plant at this time of year. It
                            will be useful to recall the method by which the Aphis may be
                            killed.</p>
                        <p>The plants are sprayed with a very fine spraying machine, with an
                            emulsion made of 1/2 rotl soap, 1 gallon water, 2 gallons kerosene, and
                            to this is added 25 times the bulk of water. The 1/2 rotl soap is cut up
                            and boiled in the one gallon of water, until completely dissolved, it is
                            then taken off the fire, the two gallons of kerosene are added, the
                            whole is vigorously stirred, and upon the addition of 25 times the built
                            of water it is ready for spraying on the leaves of the plant. Special
                            attention should be paid to the under surface of the leaves, which is
                            usually attacked by the insect. It is important to note that the Aphis
                            usually appears on the borders of the cotton fields near drains and
                            water courses, and also that spraying should be done early in the
                            morning or in the evening.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>QUARANTINE IN GREECE</head>
                        <p>A telegram from the British Legation at Athens states that two days’
                            quarantine is imposed in Greece on arrivals from Alexandria and
                            Adalia.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BECK CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
                        <p>BREMEN.</p>
                        <p>fears no honest competition for quality.</p>
                        <p>N.B.—Inferior Brands now being offered to Mao. ages of certain good.</p>
                        <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very supreme
                            brand of beers</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>A DANGER TO EGYPT GERMANY AND TURKEY VERSUS ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST </head>
                    <p>BY WILHELM MEISTER.</p>
                    <p>(Translated).</p>
                    <p>II.—THE REMEDY. </p>
                    <p>A glance at a map of the Near Bast and the plan of the Turko-German General
                        Staff suggests the remedy. Since Egypt most be defended at all costs, and
                        since armed resist- ance in Egypt will not avail, when the Turkish
                        preparations are complete, the only effective guard against the blow is to
                        check the mobili- sation scheme that aims at using Syria as a bridge between
                        Egypt and Asia Minor. I have pointed out in my first article that the
                        Anatolian grand trunk line that is now in course of construction bifurcates
                        at the longi- tude of Diarbekir. Its western branch will link with the
                        Syrian system at Biredjik, on the Euphrates, passing through Siverek and
                        Orfa, while the Eastern branch will be carried through the plains of
                        Mesopotamia and the Tigris-Nahrwan valley towards Mosul, Bagdad, Bassorah,
                        and Koweit.</p>
                    <p>The Syrian branch, in itself a grand trunk line, will run from north to
                        south, throwing out branches towards the Mediterranean destined to carry the
                        troops from each of the segments into which they divide the country to the
                        main line, as the tributaries of a river basin carry their waters to the
                        main stream. These branches link or will link the grand trunk line with the
                        ports of Alexandretta, Latakia, Tripoli, Beyrout, Haifa, Jaffa, and Gaza to
                        the very frontiers of Egypt. Between Sunamein and the Jordan about 120 miles
                        S. of Damasous a cross country line of about 100 kilometres in length will
                        be pushed to Jerusalem, thence to Hebron (ElKhalil), which will be itself
                        linked with Gaza.</p>
                    <p>All along the course of the line and its branches garrisons are distributed,
                        whose strength varies according to the strategical importance of the
                        localities and which all gravitate around the military centres of the two
                        commands into which the Army Corps District of Syria is divided, the
                        commands of Aleppo and Damascus.</p>
                    <p>Covered and bound by these links of steel Syria will present the aspect of a
                        moving chess- board, an ideal field for the military policy and hold designs
                        of the Seraskierat. In case of a mobilisation not only will the powerful
                        corps posted in the regions that I have indicated be called to the front,
                        but in each of the six segments between Aleppo and Gaza into which Syria is
                        divided, the Redifs (Reserve) and Mustafiz (Landsturm) will be called to the
                        colours.</p>
                    <p>The region between the western loop of the Euphrates and the Golf of Akaba
                        contains 2,500,000 Moslems, and at the lowest com- putation sixty thousand
                        soldiers, once trained in the Nizam (first line) and sprung from a proud and
                        warlike race that has distinguished itself in all ages by courage on the
                        field of battle. With the divisions of Aleppo and Damasons and
                        reinforcements from Anatolia a force of 150,OOO men could be massed in
                        Syria— a force composed of excellent material,fanatical, brave, and well
                        disciplined, which would like nothing better than a campaign against
                        England* in Egypt, and the reconquest, from the infidel whom they hate, of
                        the ancient province which they have lost but still regard as the rampart to
                        the Holy Cities of the Moslem world. It may be urged that in the recent
                        campaign against the Imam Yehia several regiments deserted to the rebel
                        side, but it must not be forgotten that they were fighting Moslem foes,
                        their brothers in race and religion, and that face to face with the
                        extraordinary difficulties of the country they may well have despaired of
                        the success of a campaign of repression undertaken with Bach a lack of
                        military essentials. But if these very troops were fighting an infidel army
                        with the valley of the Nile as their prize, might not the fervour of their
                        faith and the artful appeals of the Pan-Islamic party drive them on.
                        fanatical and irresistible, as one man to the divinely ordained conquest of
                        the City of Victory</p>
                    <p>It follows from all this that the invading army must be prevented from ever
                        starting on its march to Egypt. If it can once be con- centrated and
                        supplied with ammunition and provisions, then, in my opinion, Egypt is lost.
                        The principle enounced in the opening para- graph of this study leaps into
                        light again. To prevent an invasion mobilisation in Syria must be rendered
                        impossible. There are two rotations of the problem and each will serve as
                        the Remedy- the neutralisation—or the annexation-of Syria. At first sight
                        they may appear difficult, well-nigh impossible, but though they seem big
                        with consequences in the near or the more distant future, though they
                        promise to perturb the political atmosphere of the world, yet we may boldly
                        affirm that either is possible and that the clouds which, through their
                        employment, may darken the sky will pass away without storm or danger.
                        Translator’s Note-The Turks and their panislamic sup- porters regard England
                        with increasing distrust and fear. Recent incidents at koweit and on the
                        Aden frontier have intensified these emotions.</p>
                    <p>(To be continued)</p>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                        <p>GUARANTEED DISTILLED.</p>
                        <p>ALEXANDRIA: CAIRO!</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,</head>
                        <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                        <p>$5. PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED</p>
                    </div>
                </div>


                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARRIVAL OF PRINCE ARISUGAWA.</head>
                        <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                        <p><placeName>Port Said,</placeName> Monday. T.I.H. Prince and Princess
                            Arisugawa and a numerous suite arrived to-day at 1p.m. in the N.D.L.
                            S.S. Preussen, which vessel ap- pears to have had a very fine voyage. It
                            will be remembered that the Prince passed through here in the Print
                            Heinrich on the 4th May on his way to attend the wedding of the Crown
                            Prince of Germany as representative of the Mikado. His Highness
                            disembarked im- mediately on arrival to-day,making several calls on the
                            Agent for Japan and others. He looks exceedingly well and as I write is
                            driving about the town seeing the few sights Port Said has to offer. The
                            Preussen is to enter the canal at 7 p.m.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GOVERNOR OF INDO-CHINA</head>
                        <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. Caledonian, which left here in the very
                            early hours of last Saturday, had on board, among her abnor- mally large
                            complement of passengers, M. Beau, the Governor-General of Indo-China,
                            who had, I understand, left the ship at Suez and pro- ceeded to Cairo.
                            This gentlemen on his de- parture was accompanied to the ship by M.
                            Bonin, the French Charge d’Affaires, and many other gentlemen, including
                            the French Consul, M. Laffont. M. Bonin left here for Cairo in a
                            specially reserved compartment by last even- ing’s train.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRIZE DISTRIBUTION.</head>
                        <p>The annnal prize distribution and speech- day of the Ecole dee Freres was
                            held on Satur- day afternoon at 4 o’clock. The function proved a great
                            success, and the children and parents with their numerous friends, were
                            kept amused and entertained till after 7 p.m., when the proceedings
                            terminated.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY.</head>
                        <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                        <p><placeName>Medinet-el-Fayoum,</placeName> Monday. A Belgian company,
                            which has been consi- dering the question of purchasing the above-
                            mentioned railway, has sent two delegates to FayoUm to go through the
                            company’s books, etc. Any intending purchasers of the line will do well
                            to make a thorough investigation not only of the books but of the
                            condition of the line, stations, and rolling stock, before dosing the
                            bargain.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ST. HILDA</head>
                        <p>The crew' of the St. Hilda, the steamer which was captured last month and
                            sunk by the Russians, reached Plymouth last Monday. They appeared highly
                            amused at the report that a display of force by British warships was
                            necessary at Port Said to secure their release from the Dnieper, on
                            board which they were kindly treated.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The S.S. "Scottish Prince,” with passengers and general cargo, left
                            Manchester on Sunday, and is due here,via Malta,on or about August
                            7.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR</head>
                        <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                            correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit
                            - within certain necessary limits - free discussion.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“HONOR TO WHOM, ETC."</head>
                        <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. Sir,—It is much to be regretted
                            that some of your contemporaries, instead of following the example of
                            the "Gazette” and confining themselves to a bare account of the incident
                            that took place at the Eden Music-Hall on the night of the French fete,
                            have indulged in attacks on Fire Brigade Superintendent Lynn, while bis
                            conduct on the occasion is still under investigation. With regard to
                            what took place on the night of the 14th inst., I will only say that one
                            account of the assault made upon Captain Lynn is confirmed by the
                            testimony of an eye-witness, and the enquiry into the affair will, it is
                            to be hoped, disclose the truth.</p>
                        <p>But even supposing that the worst alleged against Superintendent Lynn is
                            tully proved, and that his conduct was altogether unjustifi- able, I
                            would ask. Is the mistake of a single night to be allowed to outweigh
                            the many years of valuable service, both military and civil, rendered to
                            this country by the gallant captain On the field of battle he has over
                            and over again proved himself to be a brave and efficient officer; in
                            his many contests with the fiery element be has shown himself equally
                            fearless and skilful, and many an owner of property in Alexandria has
                            gratefully acknow- ledged the value of his services. In the United
                            States also they were also greatly appreciated, and Capt. Lynn possesses
                            a medal bestowed upon him by the late Pope for saving the lib of an
                            American Cardinal at a fire in Boston. I trust that no remissness on the
                            part of his many friends will allow these facts to be ignored by the
                            authorities, and that the great services rendered in the past will not
                            be permitted to escape their attention. It is indeed surprising to find
                            such a dead- set made against a man occupying such a position and
                            holding such a record as Mr. Lynn-I am, Sir, etc., THOS ATWOOD
                            Alexandria, July 94-</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
