<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Charlie Rymer</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-03</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">Thursday, August 24, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="item" n="1">
                    <h1>CHANCES OF PEACE</h1>
                    <h2>PRESS RUMOURS RIFE.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE PRESIDENTS PROPOSALS.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 23.</h3>
                        <p>The “Times” is a telegram from Portsmouth
                            quotes a high Japanese authority as saying
                            yesterday that it Was more than possible that
                            {bat the plenipotentiaries would come to terms
                            on the subject of the indemnity and Saghalien
                            ijlaml.. Tift '•Times” adds that there is no
                            doubt that the Japanese want peaoe, and are
                            trying to make peace easy for Russia. (Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 23.</h3>
                        <p>Well informed circles consider that final
                            ruptures to day are impossible. It is known
                            that President Roosevelt’s proposal oonsists in
                            Russia repurchasing all or part of the 8aghalien
                            Island for a sum to be determined hereafter, if
                            the belligerents disagree in future.This amount,
                            together with a Chinese payment for the oes-
                            sion of the railway and a Russian payment for
                            the maintenance of prisoners, is equal to
                            Japan's total war costs.
                            [Later). The Conference met to-day, but
                            nothing has yet been disclosed.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 23.</h3>
                        <p>The next sitting offhe peace conference has
                            been adjourned till Saturday.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE IMPERIAL MANIFESTO.</h2>
                        <h2>GREETED WITH THE MARSH</h2>
                        <h3>Moscow, August 23.</h3>
                        <p>Extraordinary scenes took place here yester-
                            day when the Mayor proclaimed the Tsar’s
                            manifesto. The crowd greeted it with uproar,
                            aud sang the "Marseillaise.” Fierce speeches
                            were made expressing contempt for the mani-
                            festo. The Municipality moved a resolution
                            accepting the Constitution merely as a prelim-
                            inary step, and demanding freedom of speech,
                            for press and meeting.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <h2>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>GERMANY TO ANSWER THIS WEEK.</h2>
                        <h3>Paris, August 23.</h3>
                        <p>Prince von Radolin will forward Germany’s
                            answer on the subject of the programme of the
                            Moroccan Conference at the end of the week.
                            (Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>EAST AFRICAN RISING.</h2>
                        <h2>DISAFFECTION SPREADING.</h2>
                        <h3>Berlin, August 23.</h3>
                        <p>The rising is spreading in German Bast
                            Africa. The natives attacked the German camp
                            for two successive days but were repulsed.
                            (Reuter).</p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>HOME CRICKET.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 13.</h3>
                        <p>Notts beat Derbyshire by 6 wickets. Glou-
                            cestershire best Surrey by 8 wickets. Sussex
                            beat Kent by 10 wickets. Woroestsrshire beat
                            Leicestershire by 110 runs. The other matches
                            were drawn.		(Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PASSENGER LIST.</h2>
                        <h3>ARRIVALS.</h3>
                        <p>Per P. & 0. 8.8. Caledonia arrived at Port
                            Said from London, on the 22nd inst.
                            Mr. J. Wheeler, Mr. J. Carr, Mr. and Mrs.
                            Fielden, Mr. A. P. Hirsch, Mr. C. Beckett, Mr.
                            A. Silvers, C. Adib Bey.
                            Per P. & 0. Isis arrived at Port Said from
                            Brindisi on the 23rd inst
                            Mr. P. Vuyk, Mr. G. Gifford, Mr. Pali-
                            canaky, Mr. D. Carrie, Mr. E. T. Richmond, Mr.
                            C. 0. Gok.</p>
                        <h3>DEPARTURES.</h3>
                        <p>Le paqoebot "Prince Abbas” de lstKhedrrisf
                            Mail parti hier.poor le Pir<e. Snjyrne, hfetalin,
                                Dardanelles et Constantinople sfoit k hfita:
                                LL EE. Mobamed Bey Abou phade, Moba-
                                mcdSadik Bey Ab*ta, F*kh*y Bey. Abate,
                                M •burned Bey Cherea et sa dame, Ahmed Bey
                                Chawky. Ahmed Bey Emm, Hassan Bey Cho-
                                rea, Mohamed Bey Rismie, Hamdi Bey Ieuuil,
                                Tewfick Bey Ypsri, Mme Alex. Benachi, WM,
                                noqrrioe et gonvernjrote, ColOoeJ Mitford, W.
                                Webb, Atbanaae Boiesoglo, Platon Papozi, M,
                                et Mme Spiro Antippa et f&milla, D. Kapadjis,
                                H. Ghessarian, SpiroJA. Cavadias, 8tavro Tbeo-
                                doridis, Ahmed Hamdi, Ant Mevros, Geo.
                                F-igs, Minas. Constantjnon, Athanase Xaris,
                                AnastsM Mardngoe, G. Pappadfkis, N. Mau-
                                gelos, Mme Athina Capaitsis et faailte, T,
                                Varonxis, C. Pepedflpoolos, -Ernest Grill, Mmes
                                A. Caradia, Pranghiades, Miles Caridas, aiof
                                qne 178 passegen de pont.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="2">
                    <h1>LOCAL AND GENERAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <p>The Plague,—Yesterday's plague bulletin
                            reports one death at Alexandria, and one
                            death at Port Said.</p>
                            
                        <p>Suez Canal —9 vessels passed through tbe
                            Canal ci&he 21st inst, 5 of wb&h were British,
                            3 German, 1 French. Tbe day’s reoeipts were
                            fra 279,745. making the total from the 1st
                            inst. frs. 6,209,725.81.</p>
                            
                        <p>Cart Accident.—Yesterday a cart ran over
                            a native woman and a man in Sisters' street
                            As usual, the unfortunate woman came worst
                            out ol the accident, sustaining injuries that
                            require about ten days’ medical treatment.</p>
                            
                        <p>Sudan Storm.—Heavy rain storms are re-
                            ported from the 8udsn. Two miles of the
                            permanent way on the Sudan line were washed
                            away on the 12th inst and the Kartonm-Wadi-
                            Halfa express did not arrive til the 14th inst.</p>
                            
                        <p>Interesting Discovery - We hear that
                            fragments of columns and monoliths have been
                            discovered on the lands belonging to Skandar
                            Pasha Fehmi at Sirfi MasaoLd in the Marioot
                            district These antiquities are believed to be
                            Of Ptolemaic origin.</p>
                            
                        <p>A Child Killed.—A little boy of four years
                            of age was playing in a large wheelbarrow in
                            the Labhan quarter yeaterdiy, when it over-
                            balanced and fell. The child was caught nnder
                            the barrow and receive 1 internal injuries which
                            proved fatal.</p>
                            
                        <p>Zaoazio to Zifxa.—The oonstrqotion of a
                            line between Zagazig and Zifta will probably
                            be oomuienoed this winter; and the Ministry of
                            Pnblio Works is preparing a decree, which will
                            be submitted to the Council of Ministers re
                            the necessary expropriations.</p>
                            
                        <p>Killed by a Tram —A collision ooourred
                            on-the Shocbra road on Tuesday between a
                            tram car and a cart. The foroo of the collision
                            threw a young girl to the ground and the
                            wheels of the tram passed over her and killed
                            her. The two other oooupants of the cart, a
                            blind man and his wife, were not injured.</p>
                            
                        <p>London Stock Exchange. — Applications
                            have been made to the London Stook Ex-
                            further issue of 6,000 shares of £1 each, fully
                            paid, Nos. 30,601 to 36,000 ; and to allow the
                            following seourity to be quoted in the Official
                            List—Egyptian Estates, Ltd.—250,006 ordi-
                            nary shares of £1 each, Nos. 1 to 250,006.</p>
                            
                        <p>Grand Crown Casino.—The management
                            of the'Crosrn Casigo at Ibrahimieh is present-
                            ing an excellent variety entertainment to its
                            patrons. To-night Mile. Nina de Pervenche,
                            an Italian artiste with a well-trained and
                            pure mezzo-soprano voioe, will appear for the
                            lint time at this theatre, and Mile Mary
                            Flenr, to whom the mnsio-hall youth (and
                            would-ba youth) of Cairo have without ex-
                            ception lost their hearts, will ask and obtain
                            the applause of the Crown Theatre audienoee.
                            The dnettist? Colibris are as lively and at-
                            tractive a couple as one oould wish to see,
                            and Mile Lyda Osman, a favorite in Egypt
                            ever sinoe the day of her arrival, is miking a
                            great hit with the song ‘Oil fa!” sang k
                            l'Egyptienne.</p>
                            
                        <p>The Turkish Police. — News comes from
                            Coastantippple of the discovery by the Turkish
                            Police ol a perfect magazine of bombs in an
                            Armenian house at Smyrna. The polioe have
                            made numerous arrests, and the rospeotable
                            majority of the Armenian community is re-
                            ported to be greatly perturbed. Meantime the
                            searoh for the authors of the Constantinople
                            outrage continues, though we understand that
                            the real'culprit is known to have been killed
                            by the bomb, and a "Young Turkish" proclam-
                            ation attacking the Sultan, whioh was posted
                            up on some mosques lately, has caused the
                            police to redouble their vigilance. One of the
                            results of this renewal of activity has been the
                            arrest of a Frenchman who bora the same
                            Christian name as the fabulous Italian anarch-
                            ist who is the "official” author of the crime.</p>
                            
                            <p>Crime at Kapr el Zayat. - Kafr el Zayat
                            and tbe sorronnding districts are notorious for
                            the prevalence of crime. Mnrders and other
                            serious (jffefioes oertainly seem more frequent
                            in these districts than in any others. Tho
                            Ministry of ^he Interior have just dompleted
                            tax inquiry into the base of a certain Mahmoud
                            el Arebi who fired a gun in dose proximity to,
                            if not actually at, two Englishman residing in
                            the village, and who gave at his excuse that
                            he was “frightened of the ghaffirt" which were
                            about A report now readies as that tbe body
                            of a man, named Jkfnstapha Omar, was -found
                            in the street at ge& el Z*yat two nights ago.
                            He had been shot twioe, there being two bullet
                            wounds, and than were alsotwo knife thrusts
                            :0 bis body, either of whieh would1' doubtless
                            have proved fetal. Tbe. attack, thereto^
                            and brought to justice.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="3">
                    <h1>SYRIA’S TRADE IN 1904.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>DAMASCUS</h2>
                        <p>Mr. Richards, H.B.M.'s Consul at Damasons,
                            wiuts out in his report on the trade of the
                            Syrian oapital in 1904, that absolutely, or
                            even, in some oases, relatively* accurate data ;
                            are unattainable. owing to the absenoe of any !
                            official figures of the amount and value of the -
                            exports and imports Of the vilayet In 1901 ,
                            trade seems to have been normal, though a ,
                            bad harvest had, of ooune, considerable .
                            influence on the purchasing powers of the ,
                            peasantry. Sogar appears to have risen enorm-
                            ously in prioe owing,' it is said, to the .
                            withdrawal of the Austro-Hungarian Govern- ,
                            ment bounty hitherto granted to Bogar
                            exporters, and tbe failure of the beetroot .
                            crop in'Austria and Rustia. Another oause -
                            was the oessation of the cholera epidemic ;
                            whioh had raged for nearly a year inthe
                            oountry, The oonnectioD does not seem ob- ‘
                            vions at first sight but is easy enough to
                            realise, when the foot is grasped that the
                            onsumption of tea, and consequently of ,
                            sugar, rises abnormally during an epidemo ;
                            whioh makes evta the waters of Abana and j
                            Pharphar suspect	,
                            Egyptian rice completely ousted the Genoa
                            artiole in the vilayet, and appears to be the ;
                            best obtainable, the Rangoon produot coming ,
                            second. No loss than 70 % of the whole ,
                            import of rioe came from Egypt and Egyptian
                            sugar was also more freely imported than
                            before. Tbe export of native silk and ootton
                            fabrics to Egypt increased, and Cairo took
                            nearly all the handsome silver girdles, which
                            every tourist knows, amounting to some £7,000
                            in value. These girdles, Mr. Richards states
                            are made as a rule, oat of melted Maria-
                            Teresa dollars imported from Aden and the
                            Straits Settlements, and are sold at about two
                            shillings each.
                            To tarn to the trade with the United
                            Kingdom and with India, British imports con-
                            sist mainly of cotton goods, ootton and woollen
                            yams, doth, hardware and metals. The slight
                            decline reoorded is easily explained by the bad
                            harvest, and it is satistaotory to note that
                            despite dismal forecasts of the ousting of British
                            ootton goods and yarn by Italian and German
                            product i, these dangerous competitors are
                            losiog ground. British ootton yarn advanoed
                            from 41 to 60 % of the whole trade in this
                            artiole and the United Kingdom is responsible
                            for 82 % of the whole import of ootton goods.
                            Hardware fell off owing to the faot that one
                            throwing machine only was imported in the
                            oourae of tha year. Mr. Richards remarks that
                            Syria is extraordinarily backward in this
                            respeot,even for an Oriental country,land^notas
                            the conservatism of the few large land owners
                            who oould afford- to purchase up-to-date agri-
                            cultural machinery. On the other hand a con-
                            siderable number of stocking-knitting maohinee
                            are yearly imported, selling for £9 12s. eaoh,
                            and there is some demand for sewing machines
                            Bioyoles— mirabiU dicta I — have also bdffli
                            sent to Syria, bat as the author of the report
                            justly remarks, "the execrable state of the
                            roads makes the demand for this means of looo-
                            mation less and less every year.” It is perhaps
                            a sign of'the times that while the lawful im-
                            portation of cheap andinferior sporting smooth-
                            bores fell off in 1904,the illicit import trade in
                            serviceable rifles showed an inoreaae. The
                            Martini-Henry was the favorite pattern, but
                            Mansers and Miionliohera found their way into
                            the oountry. This year the trade is said to be
                            prospering, and quite a number of Mausers
                            have found their way to the Hauran, while
                            Martinis, with eaoh of whioh fifty rounds of
                            ammunition are given away, are as popular as
                            ever.	►
                            The report throws some interesting side-
                            lights on the eoonomic condition of the oountry,
                            and on the changes that, even in the East,
                            affect the demand for oertain goods. Marble
                            is no longer so freely used in domestio arehi-
                            teotare. The Damascenes 'are nowadays more
                            economically inclined than they used to be in
                            the matter of the adornment of the oonrtyards,
                            and still more of the interiors of their houses,
                            into ^rhich marble^)lain and riohly sculptured,
                            entered largely and lavishly to the extent of
                            many thousands of pounds. All this extra-
                            vaganoe is how a thing of the past, to the I
                            great' loss of Italian importers Who have a
                            monopoly of the article.’
                            We have not ^he spaoe for farther dis-
                            oussion of the leading fodtureeiri these
                            interesting reports, but would like to point
                            out to British merchants in the Near East
                            that there are plenty of openings for trade in
                            Syria and Palestine, and that, thanks to the
                            high rapntation of British goods, and, we may
                            add, of British traders,energy oombined with a
                            readiness to attend to the eoonomio needs of
                            the people, will meet with their reward. The
                            town population shows a wish to better itself
                            that may be manifested in strange ways—eg. in
                            an increasing demand for ready-made sails of
                            exceptional atrocity—bnt should none the less
                            be olosely studied by British firms and their
                            agents of travellers.</p>
                    </div>
                    
                </div>
         
                    
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>