<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-10"> February 10, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, FEBRUARY 10, 1905
<div type="item">
<head>CONDITION OF RUSSIA</head>
<head>WARSAW HOSPITALS FULL</head>
<head>PROBABLE RESUMPTION OF STRIKE</head>
<p>Warsaw, February 9.
The hospitals are full and refuse to admit
more persons.	(Reuter.)</p>
<p>Sr. Petersburg, February 9
It is officially announced that the killed at
warsaw, petrokoff, and radom do not exceed
100 altogether.  Nine policement were wounded
in warsaw alone.
Despite the official announcement, romors
are rife here to the effect that a general
resumption of the strike will take place on
sunday.   The railway construction works are
already out on strike, and there has, undoubtedly,
been further trouble at the putiloff
works.  The whole situation is full of uncertainty. (Reuter.)</p>
<p>Sr. Petersburg, February 9
The strikes University professors and
students are becoming general throughout
Russia.	(Reuter.)</p>
</div>               
<div type="item">
<head>GENERAL KUROPATKIN.</head>
    <head>TO BE REPLACED BY GRAND DUKE</head>
<p>St. PETERSBURG, February 9
The newspapers publish the rumour that
Grand Duke Nicholas is to replace General
Kuropatkin.	 (Havas.)</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>NEW JAPANESE FOREIGN LOAN</head>
<p>London, February 9
Router's Agency learns from Tokio that M.
Takahashi, the Vice President of the bank of
Japan, sails on the 17th inst. for America and
England. This step is regarded here as an
indication of a now foreign loan. (Reuter.)
</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
    <head>GERMAN STRIKE COLLAPSES</head>
    <head>MINERS RESUME WORK</head>
    <p>Cologne, february 9
    In view of the governments promises regarding
    the ripining labour legislation, and the
    hopelessness of breaking down the mine-owners
    resistance in the near future, the german
    miners will resume work tomorrow.  (Reuter.)</p>
    <p>Essen, February 9
    The delegates of the miners have declared to resume
    work. (havas.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWEDEN AND NORWAY</head>
                    <head>KING OSCAR TRANSFERS FUNCTIONS</head>
                    <p>Stockholm, February 9.
                    King oscar is in indifferent health.  He has
                    transferred sundry functions to the crown 
                    prince.  (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Stockholm, February 9.
                    King oscar has transferred his functions
                    because he is not robust enough to deal with
                    the new crisis arising from the final disagreement
                    between sweden and norway concerning
                    the seperate consular services.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHURCH AND STATE IN FRANCE</head>
                    <p>Paris, February 9.
                    M. Bienvenu Marin, minister of instruction
                    and of the cults, has laid the bill for the
                    seperation of the church from the state
                    before the house.  (havas.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, February 9.
                    Chamber of deputies- the government 
                    bill for the seperation of the church from the
                    state has been introduced today.  It has been 
                    referred to a committee.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STRANDING OF A CRUISER</head>
                    <p>Saigon, February 9.
                    The cruiser sully has run aground and is
                    in a critical situation.  The crew has been saved.  
                    (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>Hanoi, February 9.
                    The french cruiser sully is ashore in a 
                    bad position along the bay.  The crew has been
                    taken off.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHINESE 5% LOAN</head>
                    <p>The chinese 5% loan of $1,000,000 will be
                    issued on friday here and in Berlin at 97. (R.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STAMBOUL GUN DIFFICULTY</head>
                    <head>ARRANGEMENT ARRIVED AT.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, February 9.
                    The difficulty regarding the guns has been 
                    compramised.  France has recieved a portion 
                    of the order.  The guns will be paid for out of
                    the loan from the Ottoman Bank, with which 
                    negotiations have been reopened.  German
                    financiers will find the money to pay for the 
                    Krupp guns.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH ANTARCTIC EXPEDITION</head>
                    <head>HOPE ABANDONED</head>
                    <p>Buenos Ayres, February 9
                    The argentine man of war uruguay has
                    returned here after a prolonged and fruitless
                    search for the french antarctic expedition
                    under dr. charcot.  It is feared that all the members 
                    of the expedition perished during the great
                    storm in april 1904.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICA AND CHINA</head>
                    <p>New york, february 9
                    According to the new york world, the government
                    practically decided to return to china after the
                    war is over 22,000,000 dollars of teh indemnity 
                    remaining after the settlement of the american 
                    claims.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The brindish mail will close at the G.P.O., 
                    alexandrai, on sunday at 8.30 a.m.</p>
                    <p>The plague- yesterdays bulletin records
                    two fresh cases and a recovery at suez.</p>
                    <p>The New Orthodox Church at medinet
                    el-fayoum will be consecrated tomorrow by
                    the patriarch photius.</p>
                    <p>Cathedral for cairo- a movement is on
                    foot among the maronite community to build
                    a maronite cathedral at cairo.</p>
                    <p>The margherita societys masked ball,
                    we are asked to remind our readers, will take
                    place at the eden theatre tomorrow night.</p>
                    <p>Gymehana- the next mena house gymkhana
                    will take place on thursday, 16th inst.
                    and not on friday, 17th, as originally arranged.</p>
                    <p>The french ball, which is to be held in
                    the esbekieh gardens on the 24th inst., 
                    promises to be a great success.  The proceeds
                    will be devoted to the cairo poor.</p>
                    <p>Alhambra theatre- a grand high life
                    performance is to be given at this theatre
                    tonight in honor of mue. Annita Mannvernt, 
                    the danseuse etoile of the ballet company.</p>
                    <p>The outrage committed on monday last
                    by some unknown person, who fired at the
                    dining car train between Damanhour and
                    antah, is the subject of an official enquiry.</p>
                    <p>Jewish pilgrimage- about 150 jews
                    infuding about 80 chief rabbis, from austria, 
                    germany, switzerland, and russia will arrive
                    at alexandria about the 7th proxo.  on a 
                    pilgrimage to Jerusalem.</p>
                    <p>Suez canal.- 11 vessels passed through 
                    the canal on the 7th inst., of which 6 were
                    british, 1 dutch, 1 german, 2 norwegian, 1
                    italian.   The receipts for the day were frs.
                    238,360.25 making the total from 1st  inst. fre. 
                    2,563,692.07</p>
                    <p>Alexandrias drainage- the tenders for
                    the construction of the eastern collector from
                    rosetta gate to chatby-bridge are as follows:
                    Messrs. Almagia, l.e. 10,000; Messrs. Degiarde
                    brothers, l.e. 8,071; Mr. yerakis, l.e. 7,600;
                    Mr. minas, l.e. 6,480</p>
                    <p>Presses Libres egyptiennes- during the
                    12 months ending on august 31 last, this
                    company pressed 174,010 bales, as against
                    172,385 bales for the previous yers pressing.
                    The net profits for the year amounted to P.T.
                    624,954 8/10 as against p.t. 473,452 3/10 in
                    the preceding twelve months.  This surplus was
                    chiefly due to storage and assurance, owing to
                    the length of time that the cotton remains in
                    the companys depots</p>
                    <p>Ghezireh casino- The first big ball of 
                    the ghezireh palace hotel this season will be
                    given at the casino on thursday, 23rd inst.
                    over 500 visitors and prominent residents have
                    been invited, and the ball promises to be, as
                    usual, a great success.  Many dinner parties
                    have already been ordered in the restaurant,
                    and visitors are requested to give orders for
                    tables as early as possible to the manager
                    of ghezireh palace hotel.</p>
                    <p>Cheap houses- the statutes of the company
                    to be formed for the construction of
                    cheap dwellings at alexandria have been laid
                    before the egyptian government.  The capital
                    will consist of 50,000 shares of L.E. 4 each, 
                    with a guarenteed interest of 4 per cent.  It is
                    proposed to construct seven great block of
                    flats, each containing 96 residences.  The official
                    tital of the company is Societa anonima
                    delle case economiche</p>
                    <p>Fancy dress ball- Mr. chas. Baehler
                    informs us that the invitations to the fancy
                    dress ball at ghezireh on shrove tuesday are
                    issued thus early in order to afford ladies and
                    gentlemen attending the ball ample time to
                    prepare their costumes.  Guests presenting
                    themselves in ordinary evening dress will be
                    called upon, on entrance to the ball, to pay
                    the sum of P.T. 40, and all such fines will be
                    handed over to the society for the prevention of 
                    cruelty to animals</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHIPS COLLIDE AT PORT SAID</head>
                    <head>NORGWEGIAN COLLIER SUNK</head>
                    <p>from our correspondent
                    Port said, thursday.
                    a serious collision occured in the harbour
                    this afternoon between the harrison liner
                    craftsman and the norwegian collier congal.
                    The latter was sunk</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                    <p>The khedive, who has been spending the 
                    last few days between edfina and mariout
                    will attend the zizinia theatre this evening
                    On monday morning his highness will go to
                    avdeen palace, and at 2 p.m. will drive to
                    ghezireh to open the agricultural show, 
                    returning afterwards to the palace to recieve
                    those gentlemen who have recently had decorations
                    bestowed on them.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KINGS CRUISE</head>
                    <p>Nothing is known officially as to the truth
                    of a statement in a london paper to the 
                    effect that the king is about to pay a visit to
                    egypt.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT AND THE RUSSIAN FLEET</head>
                    <p>A correspondent writes expressing his agreement
                    with the view of the judicial adviser
                    that the engagement of england as regards 
                    the suez canal convention of 1888 requires to be
                    regarded as seperate and distinct from that
                    of egypt.  But, he adds, if that view be correct, 
                    how does the case stand great bririan was a party
                    to the convention with a certain reservaation which,
                    she maintained, absolved her from complaince with its
                    stupulations in 1898.  By the anglo-french agreement
                    of april 8 1904, she declared her adherence to
                    the stipulations of the suez canal treat, but
                    that- i am quoting from the anglo french
                    agreement itself- the last sentence of paragraph
                    1 and that of paragraph 2 of article
                    VIII. of this treaty will remain suspended.
                    Is not this another reservation which, unimportant 
                    though it be, may enable her, at any 
                    time, to take up the position which she assumed
                    in 1898, or, by parity of reasoning, enable
                    other powers to maintain that the suez canal
                    convention is inoperative. I confess that i do
                    not consider the situation as entirely satisfactory.
                    </p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MIXED COURTS</head>
                    <p>No judgements were given in the mixed
                    appeal court on wednesday owing to the
                    somewhat serious indisposition of judge de
                    korizuniez.  The judgements will probably be
                    given on the 22nd inst.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE</head>
                    <p>The annual general meeting of the british
                    chamber of commerce of egypt was held on
                    tuesday last in alexandria at the offices of 
                    Messrs. Carver Bros and Co., Ltd., when the
                    balance sheet and accounts for teh year 1904
                    were presented and passed.  The four retiring
                    members of teh committee, Messrs. S.H. Carver,
                    G.A. Williams, K.P. Birley, and A.R. 
                    Brown, were unanimously reelected.  The 
                    report of the committee on the past years work
                    was reviewed by the president, Mr. R.C.
                    abdy, and he announced that it would be 
                    published in the monthly journal.
                    The following resolution, signed by 11 of
                    the cairo members, had been recieved-
                    Article 7 of the statutes to be extended as follows-
                    That a committee of 12 be elected by the 
                    cairo members to sit in cairo subject to the 
                    rules that govern the alexandria committees
                    to be exchanged and the alexandria committee
                    remaining the executive.
                    On the motion of the president, this resolution
                    was unanimously adopted.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BALL AT LUXOR</head>
                    <p>From our correspondent
                    Luxor, February 8.
                    A very successful fancy dress ball was given
                    yesterday evening at the luxor hotel in aid of the
                    luxor native hospital, under the auspices 
                    of teh luxor sporting club.  About
                    200 guests attended from the Nile Steamers
                    and different hotels.  Dancing was kept up with
                    animation until a late hour, to the strains of 
                    the De Stefano band, which came specially
                    from the cataract hotel, assouan, for the
                    purpose and was much appreciated.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The messageries maritimes S.S. Congo
                    arrived at Marseilles from alexandria at 4 a.m.
                    yesterday.
                    The cunnard S.S. Cypria sailed yesterday 
                    afternoon for liverpool, and the S.S. Veria
                    arrived yesterday at liverpool.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Representative required by large
                    dundee house manufacturing water
                    proof canvas covers, sacks, and all kinds of 
                    jute and linen gods.  Apply, linen, the
                    egyptian gazette, 36, new broad street, 
                    london</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh
                    Ten minutes from alexandria.  First class in every respect
                    very moderate charges.  Bulkely is the fashionable english
                    place.  Visitors from cairo alight as sidi gaher station.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD</head>
                    <p>Alexandria
                    8s. per day, wine included.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH GARRISON</head>
                    <head>DEPARTURE OF ARTILLERY</head>
                    <p>No. 4 mountain battery, royal garrison
                    artillery, has recieved orders to hold itself in
                    readiness to embark for england in transport
                    soudan, sailing from port said on 
                    march 12.
                    No. 5 Company, royal malta artillery, has
                    likewise recieved orders to hold itself in 
                    readiness to embark for malta on the transport
                    dilwara, sailing from alexandria on march 4.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL OPERA HOUSE</head>
                    <head>FEDORA</head>
                    <p>The performance of fedora at the khedivial
                    opera house last night, thanks to signa
                    pandolfini, was a great success.  Signa 
                    pandolfini is a thorough artiste adn an actress
                    of a very high order.  Her rendering of fedora
                    was, if possible, better than her tosca.  Signor
                    Giraud was variable, though undoubtedly good
                    in the last act; his singing in the second act
                    was not at all that we should have wished:
                    he sang more than once sharp (one natural
                    was turned into sharp) and did not always
                    seem to have hold of his note.  Inaccuracies
                    were numerous and hardly justified, and he 
                    seems to have a difficulty in taking really
                    high notes.  We may mention a most admirable
                    high C by signa pandolfini.  Signor rubini
                    delivered his solo very effectively in act
                    1. Signor Polese was good and sang well, but
                    he has not the sme chance as in la tosca; he 
                    is a real chef de police, and as such probably
                    finds diplomacy too tame an occupation.  The 
                    chorus is unusually good, and the khedivial
                    theatre heave-in that branch-spent their
                    money to real advantage.  Indeed, in theatrical
                    accessories cairo need not fear competition, 
                    so long as the present conditions are in force.
                    Rigoletto is to be given tonight.  We hope
                    that some improvement will be effected therein.
                    In this connection it is interesting to note that 
                    in alexandria-as in cairo-signor tomisani
                    seems to have scored a brilliant success in that
                    opera.  Though our fellow critics may take
                    exception to his methods, a glance at the scores
                    of the operas in which he sings will show that
                    he handles his high notes with an ease and
                    dexterity apparently foreign to his better
                    known rivals of the state theatre. Whatever
                    his compatriots may think of his tone, it
                    undoubtedly pleases the anglo-saxon in general;
                    and we could wish that-but we are
                    criticising the khedivial theatre, and it is as
                    well to remind our readers that siberia, also
                    by giordano (whose compositions seem to be
                    above the average) will be given on saturday.
                    Let us mention, before we close, that signora
                    tromben really showed to advantage in her part.  
                    As long as great and startling efforts are
                    not required of her, she is quite pleasing.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABBAS HELMY THEATRE</head>
                    <head>I PURITANI</head>
                    <p>The performance of I Puritani yesterday
                    evening served once more to show the incomparable
                    talent of signora isabella svicher.
                    this gifted ladys vocal organs are very extended;
                    she possesses more than three octaves, 
                    which is phenomenal.  She recieved a perfect
                    ovation at the end of the 2nd act, and was
                    repeatedly called before the curtain.  Sig
                    tomisani, in the difficult role of lord arthur,
                    also obtained a great success, and sig. baldelli,
                    as sir george, distinguished himself.
                    We were more than surprised to find a sparsely
                    filled house last night.  It is astonishing that, 
                    when such a rare opportunity of hearing one of
                    the bright particular lights of the operatic world
                    is afforded alexandrians, they do not flock to the
                    theatre.  A more fickle public than is that of
                    alexandria it would be impossible to find.  Has a 
                    soiree noire, with all its debasing suggestiveness,
                    been announced, it would be safe to say that the 
                    playhouse, which is now adorned by such brilliant
                    artistes, would have been filled to overflowing.
                    Tomorrow evening, carmen will be given, with signa 
                    bellincioni in the leading role, and we hope to see
                    a bumper house.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS</head>
                    <p>departures.
                        Le paquebot "Cairo" de la Cie Plorio Ru-
                        battino parti hier pour Genes avait a bord:
                        MM. Fra Bernardo, Dr. Gurgsn, M. et Mme 
                        beebing, M. et Mme N. Hoig.Plarman, Brown
                        et enfant, M. et MUe Rol, chev. Mosterto, 
                        bruto Qhelli, U. Brundschunk, U. Nacamuli,
                        enirichetta Ri«petti, Alwin Ruf, Catello Espo
                        sito, Reja Michele, M. et Mme Plokea, Av. Si- 
                        gnorini et sa dame, Vitt FraDgini.Gangbinelli, 
                        pio-Balilansi, Roberto	Giovanni, Righetti,	
                        guido Pistoleei, Guido Bichielli, A. Giglioli, et ^
                        20 passagers de 3e classe.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The meterological report for the year
                    1902 has just been issued by the survey
                    department of the public works ministry.  It 
                    is replete with interesting statistics, and 
                    includes a large number of plans and diagrams
                    all carefully compiled.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A BEDOUIN OUTRAGE</head>
                    <head>EUROPEAN ATTACKED NEAR SUEZ</head>
                    <p>From our correspondent
                    Suez, February 9
                    A european named gilbert, who had failed
                    to find employment at suez, decided to go to
                    suakin, and not having money to pay his passage,
                    set out on the 25th ganuary last en route
                    for suakin on foot.  His belongings he carried
                    on his back in a bag which contained papers
                    of identity, certificates, a knife, paper, pen and
                    pencils, the sum of P.T. 9.5, a pair of boots,
                    and some clothes.  For provisions he had only a
                    bag of sea biscuits and he carried two empty
                    water bottles.  On the morning of the 27th
                    January, after having passed the attaka
                    mountains, he encountered near the shore
                    about half a dozen native fishermen, who
                    recieved him cordially and gave him fish and
                    bread to eat.  After a good rest, gilbert
                    proceeded in the direction of the mountains,
                    where he took shelter for the night.
                    Early on the following day, he descended
                    the mountains and went on his way, meeting with
                    no untoward incident, but next day, at about 
                    noon, he encountered two bedouins, whom he
                    asked for water.  The latter gave him to understand
                    that if he followed them they would 
                    take him to some wells, which the traveller
                    did without the slightest suspicion.  On the 
                    way he made them aware of the fact that he 
                    was a poor man, and that on account of this
                    he was obliged to walk to suakin in order
                    to find employment.
                    After several hours walk, seeing no trace of
                    water, and being exhausted, he proposed that
                    they should all have a rest, and accordingly sat
                    down on a rock.  Suddenly the younger of the 
                    bedouins, who was at a distance of about 50 
                    yards from gilbert, began to swear at him, and
                    raising his gun, fired.  Gilvert was slightly wounded
                    in the back, but his bag prevented a serious
                    wound.  The bedouin afterwards reloaded his
                    gun and asked gilbert to place all his belongings
                    at a certain spot.  This was done without 
                    hesitation.  While the bedouin was occupied 
                    with his gun, gilbert managed to creep from
                    rock to rock, and, favored by the darkness, 
                    succeeded in eluding the bedouins.  After a long 
                    march the whole of the night he arrived at
                    daybreak at a small coast guard station, where
                    he was well recieved.  Here he remained till the
                    1st inst., when he was offered a camel, and, in 
                    company of a coast guard named mahmoud, 
                    he reached the attaks mountains, where there
                    is a coast guard station.  The governor of Suez
                    was at once advised of the matter, and,
                    accompanied by the chief of the police, a doctor, 
                    and several gendarmes, proceeded to the spot
                    to hold an enquiry.  Finally, gilvert was
                    conveyed to the french hospital at suez, where
                    he still remains, on account of his wounds.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY</head>
                    <head>CAIRO SOLDIERS CLUB</head>
                    <p>Billiard handicap (250 points up)
                    A large number of members assembled on
                    wednesday evening to witness the final heat in
                    the ablove handicap, when a most enjoyable and
                    exciting game was played between sergy.
                    white, rifle brigade (owing 40) and Mr. 
                    adams, garrison institute, citadel (owing 70).
                    The back-mark man commenced well, and
                    quickly rubbed off his points, but after this
                    was unable to get going agin for some time.
                    his opponent meanwhile, by breaks of 20,12, 
                    and 15, was forging ahead steadily and at one
                    time held the lead by 62 points and appeared
                    to have the game well in hand, but the back
                    mark man, nothing daunted, played a most
                    plucky game, and ultimately won, amidst
                    great applause, by the narrow margin of
                    one point.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>The grand duke nicholas nicholaivitch,
                    who, it is rumoured, is to succeed general
                    kuropatkin in manchuris, is least known to
                    the world of all his kindred, having kept
                    himself aloof from the world of politics.</p>
                    <p>Prince Karl and princess edina von
                    khevenhuller are staying at the grand hotel,
                    helouan</p>
                    <p>The prince is the head of teh khevenhuller-
                    metsch family and belongs to one of the oldest
                    princely families in austria.  He is also prince
                    of aichelberg, count of hohen-ostrowitz and
                    annabuchl, baron of landscron and wernberg,
                    etc., etc. He is the hereditary grand master
                    of ceremonies in the austrian court.</p>
                    <p>Lady bisset and her daughter, countess
                    bernadorff, lady lucy mariott, and a large 
                    number of other distinguished visitors are also
                    staying at the grand hotel, helouan.</p>
                    <p>Princess said toussoun and mr. waldorf
                    astor were among those who arrived at assiout,
                    where they were recieved by fakry pasha, the
                    sub-moudir, the commandant of police, and
                    the principal functionaries of the moudirieh.</p>
                    <p>On tuesday, M. de la bouliniere arrived at
                    minieh, where he was recieved by the moudir,
                    sub-moudir, the french consular agent, and
                    the police commandant and mamour el markar.
                    M. and Mme. de la bouliniere return to cairo
                    on saturday.</p>
                    <p>Major-general sir ronald lane, late G.O.C.
                    at alexandria, is arriving at port said on the
                    15th inst. by the bibby liner Staffordshire,
                    and will proceed direct to cairo.  Sir ronald
                    will afterwards pay a visit to alexandria,
                    where he made so many friends during his
                    tenuer of office here.</p>
                    <p>Lord and lady dalhousie gave a dinner at
                    the savoy hotel on wednesday; among their
                    guests were general and mrs. slade, mr. 
                    vincent corbet, and the countess of londesborough</p>
                    <p>On wednesday nigh sir E. Cassel gave a
                    dinner party at the savoy hotel.  Among his
                    guests were sir william and lady willcocks, 
                    harari pasha and mrs harari, sir edward and
                    lady colebrooke, the hon. sidney peel, capt.
                    and mrs. westropp, and mr. john ward.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the savoy we
                    notice sir benhamin baker, mr. w. waldorf
                    astor, col and mrs planta, the non. sidney
                    peel, mr and mrs hames givvs, and mr 
                    john aird.</p>
                    <p>among the fifty-nine passengers for egypt,
                    who landed at port said yesterday from the 
                    orient pacific liner, orontes (commander J.F.
                    Ruthven), were the Rt. Hon. J.W.
                    Mellor, Mrs. Rowley Hill, Mr. J.S. and
                    lady jane trotter, lady and miss brocklehurst,
                    general and miss davidson-smith, and 
                    prince cantecusena.</p>
                    <p>The king of portugal has conferred the
                    order of out lady of the conception on
                    nungovich bey, in recognition of his attentions to
                    the queen of portugal during her majestys
                    visit to egypt.</p>
                    <p>The latest arrivals at shepheards include
                        baron,Baroness and Miss Pycke de Peteghem,
                        prince zu Lichtenstein and Comte Traotmanns-
                        dorf, Mr. Pembroke Jones and party of 8,
                        baroness von Adelsheim, excellenoe and Mrs.
                        von Diest Baron and Barooess von Vassilko,
                        ritter von Phi, Ritter too Schreiner. Dr. Seidl
                        and family, Baron and Barooees von Tiedemann-
                        seeheim and party, Forstemeister von Ulerici,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Thos. B. Lyon, of Chicago, and
                        family, Baron von Walzdori, Mr. von der
                        planitz and family, Mr.S.Crozerandparty, Mr.
                        burrmeister and party, Mr. Lovallol and
                        party, etc</p>
                    <p>Mr. Geo. W. C. Drexel, the well-known
                        american millionaire, and family, who are cruis-
                        ing their private yacht “Alcedo" in the
                        mediterranean, are expected today at Shep-
                        heards, where a large suite has been reserved
                        for them</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. thos walsh and miss walsh,
                    of washington, are returning today from
                    assouan and will stay at shepheards</p>
                    <p>Mrs. barlett, of boston, comes back from
                    assouan today and has reserved an apartment
                    at shepheards.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the savoy hotel,
                        port said, we notice Rev. J. T. Parfit
                        mr. and Mrs. J. A. Hurst, Mr. Philipp von
                        schoelber, Mr. Frigell and fomily.Mr.and Mrs.
                        shannon, Mr. Lauts, Mr. Dohme, Mr. Cowan,
                        Mr. Carl Baubinscb, Mr. and James Mrs. Ness,
                        Mr. and Mrs. J. S. Perry, Mr. Huettner, Mr.
                        Zeidler, Mr. and Mrs. Bridgewater, Dr. Schlossingk. </p></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
