<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Melizza Black</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-08-09</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY,  AUGUST 9, 1905.</head>
                
                
                <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Royal Insurance Coy</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>
                    <p>Largest Fire Office in the World.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782); </p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria. </p>
                    <p>31-3-906 FRED. OTT &amp; CO., Sub-Agents, Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                
                
                GWYNNES, LIMITED.
                (J. & H. GWYNNE, LTD., A GWYNNE 4 Co., UNITED.)
                Lo	»-
                .(WTNNS. lo	* h J, Mh *.■,■• i*h Baubm*. XI.	US	UASK.
                M0UX1> ■ * NXAJ/H.
                Trade MtirU- INVINCIBLE."
                kaiiivaoti'hcks or rna i-mnaer **d most arriciaxv
                Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
                in lb* world coltabl* far *11 yuryc***, including
                RKCLAIATIOK, DRAIHASB, IRBIGATIOM, SBWAGE WORKS, GRAVTMG
                S FLOATING DOCKS, MINKS, S ALL SANOFACTUKIHG PURPOSES.
                b**o Pome* out bs drlvsa by ij»o»ca. On*. 03 Wnti Kiseiriehv, os otb*r utu, lor Lift* Ol from 1 !Y 10 Kxm.. aud from I to *00,000 Udloni * Minot*. Maker* ol lb* M*z Pomp*. Raault* Qjarantaed.	Ovar	60	Yaara'Fredttoel Cxparlanoa.
                All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Maohinery specially designed to meet Egyptian requirements.
                London Offices -	Work*—
                81, Oannon Street, London, S.O.	Hammersmith,	London,	W
                The British Engineering Company of Kgypt, Ltd:
                Rne do la Qaro du Oalro, Alexandria.	sniex-ll.13-90*
                
                
                N. SPATHIS
                NB.—This Whisky ia the same i m supplied to the Bed Cross Society, Loudon, for use by the invalided troops and hospitals in South Africa, to the House of lords and House of Commons.
                
                
                <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> CIGARES de la HAVANE</p>
                    <p>de provenance directe et de toutes les meilleures marques</p>
                    <p>Nicolas G Sabbag</p>
                    <p>IMPORTATEUR GENERAL</p>
                    <p>FOURNISSIUR DE S A LE KHEDIVE et de tous les grands Clubs et Hôtels
                        d'Egypte.</p>
                    <p>2—Rue de la Gare du Caire—2 ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p> Adresse Télégraphique : SABBAG Alexandrie</p>
                    <p> Té1éphone No 559.</p>
                    <p> 246081-26-904</p>
                </div>
                <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</p>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>NICOLA G. SABBAG</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, 2, Rue de la Gare du Caire</p>
                    <p>Telephone; No. 559.</p>
                    <p>24528-15-3-905 </p>
                </div>
                <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>“AU DE ROUGE."</p>
                    <p>GENERAL DRAPERY ETABLISHMENT.</p>
                    <p>(Central Tramway Station), CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>P. PLUNKETT, PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>LADIES’ SUMMER STOCKINGS.</p>
                    <p> IN SPUN SILK at P.T. 20 per pair.</p>
                    <p>LISLE THREAD, in plain and lace open-work, in black, white,
                        tan and usual shades, to suit boots worn in Egypt, frpm P.T. 5 per
                        pair.</p>
                    <p>Every pair is marked “Au De Rouge" which is a guarantee that the
                        Color is absolutely fast and stainless.</p>
                    <p>24916-15-11-905</p>
                </div>
                <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>IMPORTANT NOTICE.</p>
                    <p>MARTELL COGNAC.</p>
                    <p>M. H. DEMIRGIAN BEY, General Agent for this important House, warns the
                        public to beware of Imitations, and to examine the labels, corks, and
                        capsules.</p>
                    <p>The principal importers of this well-known Brand are </p>
                    <p>At Alexandria: MM. G. Attard &amp; Co. Christo C. Solea, Costi H.
                        Georgiou, N. Pappa, A. &amp; G. Monferato, John B. Caffari, Frangini
                        Mitzos &amp; Co. Cokinos Freres, P, J. Zombos.</p>
                    <p>At Cairo: MM. S. di M. Riso, A. Jeronymidis &amp; John B.Caffari.</p>
                    <p>Where customers will find the genuine MARTELLI, which cannot be sold
                        below the minimum price given below for each quality: </p>
                    <p>* 35/- per case or P.T. 170.5.</p>
                    <p>** 40/6 " " " 197.5.</p>
                    <p>*** 47/- " " " 229</p>
                    <p>VO 53/- per case or P.T. 256.</p>
                    <p>VSO 60/- " " " 292.</p>
                    <p>VSOP 80/- " " " 390.</p>
                    <p>All so-called MARTELL Cognacs sold below these prices cannot be
                        genuine.</p>
                    <p>25912.7-8-9)</p>
                </div>
                
                
                SPATHIS’S GRILL ROOM.
                •an uitiMT., ALsxAiaaiA. Cb^Ti^ **1TTi>	»~ca«a
                
                
                IND, COOPE & Co., Ltd.
                IBJbdEU V\7”_tU JtGS,
                BURTON-ON-TRENT AND ROMFORD.
                PALE ALE Sr DOUBLE STOUT.
                SPECIALLY BREWED FOR EXPORT.
                A-grents:
                MESSRS. JOHN ROSS & Co.,
                now	ALEXANDRIA	*	CAIRO:	«•»-*■«
                
                
                THE PERFECTION OF QUALITY UNO VALUS. —«
                In Sterling Silver,
                “ iVdlbadk" ft 3ilver Plated Goods
                Provisions, Wines, Oigars,
                Orookery, Bras'ae3,	^**^*Yu	J*
                &o., &o.	^
                “ECONOMICAL STORES’'
                CAIRO AND ALEXANDRIA
                PRICE LIST ON AJPPXjIOATION. i*-u.dos
                
                
                THE ARTESIAN BORING
                AND
                PROSPECTING COMPANY.
                (SOCIETY ANONYMK)
                C A I It U, £8, SHARI A- EL - MAN AKH,
                (OPFOHITB IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK).
                I.	—Installation of complota Watar supplies for drinking, agricultural, anr
                Industrial purposas by means of artesian wells.
                II.	- Deep borings for prospecting purposes in all conditions of soil by means of tho
                "Express Boring System."	34,487 19	i-90i
                
                
                Siemens SchuckertWerke
                CAIRO BRANCH
                General Agent: Gustav Grob,E.E.
                85840—15-1 906
                ELECTRICAL MACHINBS & MATERIALS.
                KABB-KL-HIL HTREKT,
                80ARE8 BUILDINO, OppofiM lb* BANK OP BOTPT.
                F O B. 866	Tetofboo- 811
                
                
                H. D. RAWLINGS, LIMITED.
                SODA WATER, LEMONADE, St GINGER ALE.
                A* liirruu r» Kara a*» lions furls r
                Agent : — JOHN B. CAFFARI.
                
                
                Hotel Beau-Rivage. +
                11 Kinot*. bT 0»rr-Mt. nr -Palat.- tram tram Sldi (War Dbun.  Wlbw< -W-a*	m~U~~ - «nT*.
                DnJqoo Situation an Lb* BwolL
                Urralr u*rd*r. Lairs Ttnni*. - lars* Terraco. • IWetrlc U*l,k • 6m Hatha • Own eprlno- ■ P.:{«t aenilarr arran**tu<nu. IHabU* brbumiuf
                    Moderate Cbarfoa. - Kp*c!»l urx* lor (krr<nm..nt OSctai* and Oman of tb* Stray of Occupation.
                        3*117.1.900	o.	RUNOKEWTTZ,	Proprietor
                        
                        
                        THE NATIONAL HOTEL, Cairo
                        OPENS 1st NOVEMBER, 1905,
                        One of lho finest and most up-to-date Hotels in the Metropolis. Situated in Sharia So liman Paaba, the very centre of the healthiest and moat fashionable quarter. Stands in its own grounds with garden and lawn tonnis grounds at back. Over 350 rooms and 5 saloons. Magnificent salle a manger. Handsome covered promenade verandah, 8 ) yards long. Highest class cuisine, electric light throughout, and lifts.
                        English comforts. Rooms and apartments at prioee to suit every one.
                        For further particulars apply to
                        GENERAL MANAGER, Cairo.
                        
                        
                        <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>HOTEL-CASINO SAN STEFANO IS NOW OPEN</p>
                            <p>26045-80-9-5</p>
                        </div>
                        
                        
                        ASK FOR
                        AND IP NOT SUPPLIED
                        APPLY TO
                        JOHN B. CAFFARI
                        AUXANDRIA ft CAIRO *•’<»
                        
                        
                        FOR THE VOYACE TO EUROPE
                        TRAVELLERS generally, but especially Invalids and Children, thonid not be without HOWIE-8 STBRIL1ZE1) MILK OR CREAM. It is invaluable. Address Howix & Co., Hygie-aio Dairy, Shonbra Road, Cairo.
                        36039-98-5-906
                        
                        
                        <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>MAGASINS VICTORIA.</p>
                            <p>ECCLESTONE AND KEILL ENGLISH DRAPERY. </p>
                            <p>Opposite Austrian Consulate, near the Zizinia Theatre. Catalogue on
                                application.</p>
                        </div>
                        <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</p>
                            <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO. </p>
                            <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                            <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order. </p>
                            <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                            <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                            <p>7-8-90</p>
                        </div>
                        
                        
                        DAILY WEATHER REPORT
                        IIMQY ATIOH* »T «T3RVfv AK	A.
                        '«■* at Bm ---------------------   MUf	tit
                        0(SUuTxziv.	 »J
                        4becm j	Ac*	do* .......... fl^J
                        A freat N.W. mod Le blowing and tbo wontbor 10 allgbilj OTHER STATIONS.
                        SK 1	ffS	■	S	ffB
                        •bhl*. :	»ri:.	,	ar-aai*.	*h*dA
                        WWi------	»	»	JUrow. '	ti	»
                        W.__________M	M	B*rb*r ;	M	M
                        prBWooui. •» m moaWo ...	*»	»>
                        HebJMb.--	*»	*0	Xh.-WruB....j	SI	V
                        'liml ______ S*	II	j WaS KrluL	»	®
                        w*Sr H*KA.i	u I M	j
                        TOaEOM STATIONS.
                        Bunn..	Bwus.! Wind. | Twbp. Mm •
                        turn,___________ H* T Almort It OWm
                        <«■-------------- ;	^	»	“5
                        --------------1“^* "
                        —-----------------1™-4 Iks	°	,U*M
                        FUAsaa or tub moon.	thi	sow.
                        Sag. 1	IUw Km	• t *.ok	All	At*
                        „	•	IM Qoarwr	01* * a.	All	Att
                        _	u	rail lfoon	All *.m.	All	AM
                        „	*1	Lam Qmnar	All A-n.	AM	SM
                        ..	M	New Muon	AU p.m.	AM	AM
                        
                        
                        THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.
                        SUBSCRIPTIONS.—Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including delivery in Alexandria or postage to subscriber’s address) P.T. 231 1/2 per annum, P.T. 116 for (six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries in the Postal Union P.T. 273 (£2.16s.) per annum. Six months P.T. 136k (£1.8s.), three months P.T. 92 (£0.19s.)
                        N.B.—Subscriptions commance from the 1st or 16th of any month
                        ADVERTISEMENTS.- P.T. 4 per line Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages, or Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20. Every additional line P.T. 10. Notices In news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for standing advertisements. SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS are due in advance. P.O. Orders and Cheques to be made payable to the Editor and Manager, Rowland Snelling, Alexandria. London Offices : 36, New Broad-street. B.C. THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE can be obtained in London at our office, 36, New Broad Street, E.C., and also at Mesars. May & Williams, 160, Piccadilly, W.
                        
                        
                        
                        THE “EGYPTIAN GAZETTE” IS PRINTED IN PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE LONDON PAPER MILLS Co. LIMITED (SALES OFFICE : 27, CANNON STREET, E.C.)
                        
                        
                        The Egyptian Gazette
                        An English Daily Newspaper, Established in 1880
                        Editor & Manager : R. Snelling 
                        Price: One Plastre Tariff.
                        
                        
                        WEDNESDAY, AUGUST 9, 1905.
                        
                        
                        COLES PASHA'S REPORT FOB 1904.
                        Coles Pasha’s Report is as interesting as ever,
                        'as well arranged, and, happily, as outspoken, and as suggestive The author’s optimism never blinds him to the defects that are still to be found b the prison system, bat while he is thoroughly determined to point out its weaknesses, and shows a courageous readiness to confess that he has at times made too roseate forecasts of the results of legal reforms, he is no pessimist, and his annual reports have a special attraction to all who prefer ‘human documents,’ which reveal the personality of their author, to mere catalogues of statistics sandwiched between the dry crusts of unilluminating comment, with which the Egyptian public is sometimes regaled. After pointing oat that the large increase b the prison population for 1904 is doe to the working of the revised code, under which there is practically no delay when onoe sentence is passed. Coles Pasha notes that,b spite of legal obanges and the establishment of Markaz magistrates, there are still too many prisoners awaiting triaL In his opinion the procedure followed by the police in sending on arrested persons to the Parquet without the neceasary witnesses, is largely responsible for this excessive ratio of unsentenced  prisoners. The petty thief taken flagrante delicto, instead of going before the police magistrate and getting his sentence asia England, is first sent before the Parquet, which has to consult the Casier Jadioiaire, summon the witnesses, and name* day for the trial. The ’dossier” system may be sure and safeguard persons who are innocent of the crime imputed to them, but it is an open question at to whether its slowness does not nullify the effect of its sureness. The certainty of acquittal is said by some to make prison life comparatively blithe end cheerful, but we should imagine that it must be most exasperating to be dismissed 'without a stain on your character' after awaiting trial in the most palatial gaol for six weeks or so. On the other, hand the number of prisoners appealing showed a decided diminution, thanks to the recent establishment of Assise Courts, which was doe to the recognition of the fact that the power of appeal had been grossly abased in the past. As regards the periods of imprisonment and the claasification of offences, it is interesting to note that while the number of prisoned who were confined for contraventions was reduced by over 50 %, there was a large increase of persons imprisoned for delits (misdemeanours). The increase of the prison population in 1904 is doe to the increase ot persons sentenood to terms of from one week to three months, imprisonment, and not, as was imagined, to any increase in the number of persons sentenced to longer periods. Indeed, the number of those sentenced to periods of 6 months or a year’s imprisonment, snd over, bears exactly the same proportion to the prison population as in 1903, and is only 1 % lower than in 1909.
                        The passages in the report which deal with juvenile offenders are of such importance that they must be dealt with separately, and we pass on to the conduct of the prisoned. A marked increase of minor prison offences is noted for 1904, bat major offences can hardly be said to have increased, and the acts of violence and murderous assaults on police officials at Tourah, which at one time threatened to become unpleasantly numerous, shows at most gratifying diminution, which is ascribed by Coles Pasha to the establishment of the discipline gang, and to the fact that the convicts are now well aware that certain selected officials carry revolved and are ready to use them if necessary. Of the 67 prisoned who escaped, 19 are still at large. The prison punishments list shows a most satisfactory and continued decrease in the sentences of corporal punishment, which have fallen from 9i3 in 1903 to 70 during the pest year. Tho passages of this report and the report of Dr. Kirton, Principal Medical Officer to the Prisons Administration, which deal with the health of the prisoners, demand separate notice in our colunmns. We are glad to note that Coles Pasha pays a well-deserved tribute to the clerical staff of the administration for the care and thoroughness with which the tables acompanying the report have been prepared, and to read that the information famished in the Egyptian Prisons' Report does not now fall far short of the statistics published annually by European and Indian prison
                        
                        
                        ESPIONAGE ON THE FRENCH
                        FRONTIER.
                        Inhabitants in the country parts of Prance have remarked the presence of Urge numbed of vendors of images and of itinerant merchants generally. Three persons visit the villages in detail, and show marked predilection for local gossip. Such a phenomenon was observed on the eve of the war of 1870-71, and its reappearance at this moment is significant of the resumed activities of Germany. The pedlars are no doubt spies in the pay of the German Intelligence Department. Their business is to find out the local resources of the country, and to take note of the state of feeling of the inhabitants. Daring the great struggle of thirty years ago the spy, primed with local knowledge, played a large part in the military operations. A be lame of the village would often be sainted by name by a soldier wearing the Prussian uniform, who had perhaps occupied some position in the country before the outbreak of the war, and utilised his opportunities of seeing and hearing to the advantage of the conquerors. In view of this fact, it is, perhaps, not surprising that the peasants should be convinced that Germany contemplates some new mischief.
                        On the other hand, the French are also preparing for the day of an heroic straggle whose proximity rests on the knees of the gods. It appears to be established that the Military Intelligence Department is, however, a very ineffective arm of the French But-major. It received its death-blow at the Dreyfus trial — that singular and disquieting symptom of official rottenness. The country, disgusted at the revelations of the uses made of the secret side of the service,practically acquiesced in its abolition. Its power and duties were generally transferred to the polios, who naturally are more occupied with ordinary affaire of criminality than with matters of political and military espionage. Moreover, the repression of spying and informing, when carried out under the organised system of Germany, is a difficult and almost impossible operation. A pedlar upon whose person is found a notebook containing general particular* about the country-side can hardly be held in prison as a spy dangerous to the national interests.
                        
                        
                        CALENDAR OF THE WEEK.
                        (Coptic and Mohamedan.)
                        Sun. 6 Avoid female society. Opening of reservoirs (Upper Egypt)
                        Mon. 7 Evening rising of Sirius.
                        Toes. 8 Avoid eating onions and garlic.
                        Wed. 9
                        Thurs. 10 Drink cold water before breakfast. 
                        Fri. 11 Great abundance of water melons, 
                        Sat. 19 Ripening of pisteodo (Syria). </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

