<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Cassandra Frederick</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-24">October 24, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-11">May 11, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7195] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, MAY 11, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN FLEET. JUNCTION OF THE SQUADRONS</head>
                    <p>Nha-Trano, May 9. Admiral Rodjestvensky, who has been cruis ing off Vamfong
                        Bay for several days, left to day with the whole fleet. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>SaiGon, May 10. Two cruisers of Rodjestvensky's squadron came to Cape Saint
                        Jacques and brought instructions for Admiral Nobogatoff. The latter took to
                        the high seas again and effected his junction with Admiral Rodjestvensky.
                        (R.)</p>
                    <p>Saigon, May 10. Admirals Nebogatoff aud Rodjestvensky have effected a
                        junction in neutral waters. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MANCHURIA. ANTICIPATED EVACUATION OF HARBIN.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 10. The Russians are preparing to move their base
                        hospital from Harnin to Transbaikalia, anticipating the necessity of
                        evacuating Harbin in the near future. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CIRCUM BAIKAL RAILWAY BLOCKED.</head>
                    <p>Moscow, May 10. The Circum-Baikal railway is blocked owing to an avalanche.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ZEMSTVOS CONGRESS.</head>
                    <p>Moscow, May 10. The congress of Zemstvos is closed. It adopted a programme
                        providing for the crea- tion of two assemblies, the first chosen by
                        universal suffrage, the second consisting of delegates from autonomous
                        institutions. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARREST OF SPIES IN TOKIO.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, May 10. A leading French resident, M. Bougouin, bis step son, and an
                        unknown Englishman have been arrested here. They are charged with being
                        spies. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN DIPLOMATIC CHANGES</head>
                    <p>Washington, May 10. Count Cassini, Russian Ambassador here, has been
                        transferred to Madrid. Baron do Rosen, formerly at Tokio, will succeed him.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ITALY IN THE MEDITERRANEAN. HER INTERESTS IN TRIPOLI.</head>
                    <p>Rome, May 10. Signor Tittoni, speaking in the Senate, said that the Navy Bill
                        will be submitted to that Parliament with the object of safeguarding Italian
                        interests in the Mediterranean. He denied that Italy intended to occupy
                        Tripoli but said that Italy had an economic preference there, and was
                        entitled to take the steps neces sary for the industrial and economic
                        develop ment of the country. He could not tolerate the distrust shown by the
                        Turkish officials. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EARTHQUAKE AT BANDAR ABBAS INHABITANTS PANIC STRICKEN.</head>
                    <p>Aden, May 10. An earthquake at Bandar Abbas on the 25t April caused a
                        mountain behind the town t partly collapse, burying fifty persons. Severn
                        houses fell and there have been shocks ever day since. The inhabitants are
                        panic-stricken (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TURKISH MISSION TO FEZ.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, May 10. The Porte intends to send a mission to Fez
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RACING.</head>
                    <p>London, May 10. Chester Cup. 1, Imari; 2, Mark Time ; Throwaway. 10 ran.
                        Betting: 100 to 8 against Imari; 4 to 1 against Mark Time; 6 to 1 again
                        Throwaway. Won by three-quarters of length. 2nd and 3rd same. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>22855-16.7</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Fayoum Brigands</head>
                        <p>Abbass Ezoomor, the leader of the Fayomn brigands, has been arrested.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Quarantine restrictions as against plague are now applied to arrivals in
                            Egyptian ports from Porbandar.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>General Holiday</head>
                        <p>All the Ministries, Government offices, and banks will be closed on
                            Saturday next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Cotton Worm</head>
                        <p>The Ministry, of the Interior has ceased granting leave of absence to the
                            Mondirs owing to the prevalence of cotton worm.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Public Works Department</head>
                        <p>During the absence on leave of Mohamed Anis Pasho, Mr. Crawley, director
                            of works, will act as head of the technical department.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Gordon Memorial College at Khartoum has been bequeathed £500 by the
                            will of the late Mr. Horace Downey Harrel, of Chobham Cottage, Chobham,
                            who died on January 3.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Killed, by his Father</head>
                        <p>A report has been received from Boni Souef stating that Said Ibrahim, a
                            native of Berber Murkaz, has killed his son with tho blow of an axe. On
                            arrest the man pleaded guilty.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Land and General Trust</head>
                        <p>Application has been made to the Stock Exchange Com- mittee to appoint a
                            special settling day in and to grant a quotation to : Egyptian Land and
                            General Trust, 200,000 shares of £1 each, 5s. paid.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>On the 8th inst 12 vessels passed through the Canal, 8 of which were
                            British, 1 French, 1 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Aus- trian. The day's receipts
                            were frs. 251,231.84, making the total from the 1st 'inst. frs. 2,62!,
                            910.84.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>State Domains</head>
                        <p>Messrs. N. M. Rothschild and Sons announce that a drawing of Egyptian
                            State Domain mortgage bonds, amounting to 185,220 nominal capital, will
                            take place this month. The bonds so drawn will cease to bear interest
                            from June 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Relics</head>
                        <p>General Lord Greufell, who is this year president of the Royal Insti-
                            tution of South Wales, at Swansea, has just forwarded some additional
                            Egyptian relics to the museum of the institution. Among those already
                            given by Lord Grenfell is a mummy.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Corporation or Western Egypt, Ltd</head>
                        <p>Mr. Edward J. Scott, late District Commissioner and Political Officer in
                            Nigeria, has been appointed Secretary to the Egyptian Board of the
                            Corporation in Egypt. Mr. Scott has arriv- ed in Cairo, and has entered
                            upon his duties.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>By general request, Primavera Scapigliata will be repeated at tho
                            Alhambra this evening. To-morrow, the first performance will be given of
                            I Viaggi di Satur- nino Faradola. On Saturday, on the occasion Ot tho
                            Mohamed Aly centenary, a gala perform- ance will be given, and the
                            theatre will be illuminated.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Pharmacy Closed</head>
                        <p>The Sanitary Depart- ment has ordered tho cloring of the Mousky pharmacy
                            and drug-stores,in Sharia el Chaouaz- iia, belonging to Messrs.
                            Zilbermann&amp;Co., for an infringement of the new pharmacy
                            regulations,the proprietor not being a qualified chemist himself and not
                            having a qualified man as manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cairo and Alexandria Cold Storage Com- pany, Limited.</head>
                        <p>Registered April 29. Capital, £7 in £1 shares. Object, to carry on in
                            Egypt or elsewhere the business of proprietors of cold- air stores and
                            receiving depots for meat and other produce, &amp;c. No initial public
                            issue. Registered without articles of association.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>An Island in the Nile</head>
                        <p>A London finan- cial contemporary states that an island in the Nile was
                            offered in London a few months ago for £6,000. It was subsequently sold
                            at public auction for £120,000. Negotiations are now pending for it to
                            change bands agai. this time on the basis of £1,000,000. After that, J
                            who will say there is no corn in Egypt </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>P.W.D. Contracts.</head>
                        <p>The Public Works Department has given the contract for building the road
                            bridges over the Ibrabimieh Canal, between the Guenidi regulator and
                            Zeitoun (Projects Circle) to M. C. Gandolfi; for the Esbet Cherif Pasha
                            and Mangoriche bridges to z. M. L. Santrapfrze ; for the Bouche and
                            Zeitonn bridges and the supply of 700 tons of ooal for the Ghizeh
                            pumping service to M. Soussa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Hero of El Teb</head>
                        <p>Major W. T. Marshall, V.C., 19th Hussars, has been selected to fill the
                            appointment of Camp Quarter-master, Aldershot Army Corps, in succession
                            to Major J. Poole, 10th Hussars, who is shortly vacating the post. Major
                            Marshall, as a non-commission- ed officer, won his V.C. at the battle of
                            El Teb, during the Sudan expedition of 1884. Ho took part in the cavalry
                            charge, during which Lieut- Colonel Borrow was severely wounded, and his
                            horse killed. The colonel was on the ground surrounded by the enemy,
                            when Quartermaster sergeant Marshall, who stayed behind with him, seized
                            his band and dragged him through the enemy back to the regiment.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PIGMIES AT CAIRO DATE OF DEPARTURE.</head>
                    <p>Col. Harrison’s pigmies will leave Cairo direct for London in via Port Said
                        on the 18th inst. They are exceedingly well in health and have gained
                        considerably in weight. It is worthy of note that when Stanley first carme
                        upon the pigmies he was struck in quite an unwonted way. The first of them
                        that he beheld was a captive, some four feet high, “but more venerable than
                        the Memnonium of Thebes." Here was the oldest type of primeval man. Forty
                        centuries ago, the famous battle between these pigmies and the storks was
                        put into song. Think of it ’ he is fain to ejaculate.</p>
                    <p>"Oil every map since Hekataeus’ time 500 years before Christ, they have been
                        located in the Mountains of tho Moon, and there they are yet, while all the
                        dynasties of Egypt, and Syria, and Persia, and Rome have flourished, and
                        expired." Well, yes. And if these little people, who run from three feet to
                        four feet six inches, and whose average weight is 9O lb., and whose most
                        marked talent, at any rate in Stanley’s time, was tho poisoning of arrows,
                        represent a survival of the fittest, the, Darwinian theory gets a knock.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RETURN OF THE MAHMAL.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Wednesday. </dateline>
                    <p>The escort of the Mahmal, viz., cavalry, infantry, and artillery, showed
                        signs of great fatigue. The horses especially were completely exhausted.</p>
                    <p>It appears that they all suffered consider- ably this year, and tho fighting
                        with the- Bedouins was serious. However, tho latter were repulsed with heavy
                        losses, while the escort of dthe Mahmal lost one officer and four men
                        killed, and about 22 wounded.</p>
                    <p>The special train convoying the Holy Carpet to Cairo left Suez at 1 o'clock
                        this morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MECCA RAILWAY.</head>
                    <p>The “Kiiluische Zoitung,” of Berlin, learns from Constantinople that an
                        interruption has occurred in the execution of tho great under- taking which
                        is intended to connect by rail the Mohauiodan places of pilgrimage with the
                        Mediterranean. The extension of the projocted railway bejond Maau, an
                        Arabian town- 84 miles south coast of Jerusalem, is being carried out only
                        very slowly, while the important section of the line between Demand Haifa,
                        which is the real line of exit leading to the Mediterranean, has suffered
                        severely from inundations, and cannot be built as it was intended; while,
                        lastly, tho plan of laying down a branch line to Akaba, on the Red Sea, has
                        been giving up, greatly to the keen regret of a number of young and serious
                        officers in tho Turkish Army. The disorders in Yemon havo shown clearly the
                        great value of. such a linc/of railway leading southwards from Damascus\to
                        the Rod Sea, for it would facilitate the trans- port of troops of the Syrian
                        Army Corps into Arabia, and there would not be the dreary march across the
                        desert. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MARIOUT DISTURBANCES.</head>
                    <p>We have received tho following official statement as to. the recent
                        disturbances at Mariout on Sunday last.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of Finance despatched last week a sarraf, Ghirghis Effendi by
                        name, to Mariout in order to draw up a report ou the ownership of some laud
                        and crops in the Amrieh district. On Sunday last tho sarraf was in that
                        neighbourhood when he saw a number of fellaheen attesting to get to some
                        land belonging to Bedouins. The latter barred their way and told them that
                        if they persisted they would fight The fellaheen replied that the laud
                        belonged to them, and a discussion ensued which led to blows.</p>
                    <p>The sarraf was merely a witness of the fight and was not hurt at all. The
                        omdeh and sheikh and one mounted police man were with the sarraf, and this
                        escort was sufficient to protect that official.</p>
                    <p>The policeman belonging to the escort, on witnessing the disturbance, redo
                        off to the markaz to inform tho mamour, who at once saddled and bridled and
                        galloped off to the scene of the trouble. Ho arrived on the spot scarcely an
                        hour after the beginning of the engagement. When he arrived on the scene of
                        action he found three fellaheen slightly wounded with bows from nabouts.
                        About 12 of the combatants were then arrested and charged with riotous
                        conduct. They have been sent to Alexandria for trial.</p>
                    <p>There are now 30 police officers and men in the Mariout district Eighteen
                        months age there was a total of only seven police officers and men there.
                        Patrols are mode daily, and the Bedouins are gradually getting to reaped law
                        and order.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="navalNotes">
                    <head>NAVAL NOTES.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Wednesday.</dateline>
                    <p>The six British torpedo-destroyers “Dee,” “Erne," "Ettrick,” “Arun,”
                        “Exe,”and "Itchen sailed from Suez yesterday afternoon bound t
                        Singapore.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good
                        circles.</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very Superior Brand
                        of Beer</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x xx</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY. CELEBRATIONS AT CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>The following is- the general programme of die festivities to be held on
                        Saturday next at Cairo : 7.30 p.m., procession of school children through
                        Mohamed Aly-square, Ataba el Kha- dra, Post Office-street, Abdeen-square.
                        8.30 p.m., night fete on the Nile ; illumination of die east quay, Kasr
                        el-Nil Bridge, and the small promenade; illumination of boats anchor- ed on
                        both banks ; military and native bands; longs by Sheikh Salama, etc.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has sent a letter to Chawarbi Pasha, president of tho Cairo
                        committee, ex- pressing his regret at not being able to wit- ness tho fetes
                        in Cairo on Saturday. His High- ness desires the president to convey to the
                        members of the committee and all the subscri- bers, the satisfaction and
                        pleasure be has in Acknowledging the spontaneous manifestation of sympathy
                        with himself and the Khedivial family.</p>
                    <p>AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>The following police measures for regulating traffic have been, ordered, for
                        the occasion of the illuminations celebrating the centenary of Mohamed: Aly
                        Pasha on .the 13th inst. All empty carriages and other vehicles will be
                        forbidden to enter Mohamed Aly-square. The following streets only will be
                        open for entrance thereto and exit therefrom for wheeled traffic.</p>
                    <p>ENTRANCE</p>
                    <p>EXIT.</p>
                    <p>Cherif Pasha-street Tewfik Pasha-street Frauk-street Anastassi-street
                        Sister-street Gama El-Sheikh-street</p>
                    <p>All other streets will be blocked except for foot passengers.</p>
                    <p>The open space in the centre of the square, on both sides of the statue, is
                        likewise blocked for carriages.</p>
                    <p>Carriages will only be allowed to circulate in the square at a slow pace and
                        in single file, commencing from the entrance of Cherif Pasha- street down to
                        the Cafe d’Europe and from thence in the direction of Tewfik Pasha-street It
                        is expected that the cafe at Alexandria Bourse will be Crowded on the night
                        of the fete. On this occasion a charge of F.T. 5 per head, which will
                        include a seat and refresh- ment will be made. It is understood that the
                        proceeds will be divided among various local charities.</p>
                    <p>On the occasion of the Mohamed Aly cen- tenary, prayers will be said in tho
                        different mosques, and alms will be distributed to the poor.</p>
                    <p>THE MADHOUSE MEMORIAL.</p>
                    <p>The scheme for erecting a madhouse to the memory of Mohamed Aly is meeting
                        with some criticism. In the first place, the idea of a madhouse as a
                        memorial is some- what bizarre, and it may well be doubted whether this
                        project, however useful it may be, is suited to the dignity of the occasion.
                        Moreover, in view of the fact that the Government intend building a large
                        lunatic asylum in Lower Egypt between Alexandria and Tantah, as is announced
                        in Lord Cromer's last Report, subscribers are hesitating, as they ask
                        themselves what is tho utility of giving donations towards building an
                        asylum when the Government has already decided to build one. Supporters of
                        the scheme may reply that the madhouse which is to be built by the
                        Government will not be actually situated in Alexandria itself. But as this
                        asylum is to be built on the "Villa Colony" pattern, it is far bettor to
                        construct it in a rural district. We may quote the actual words of Lord
                        Cromer on tho subject :—</p>
                    <p>"I am glad to be able to report that there seems at last to be a fair
                        prospect of providing adequate accommodation for lunatics in this country.
                        In the first place, LE. 21,000 is to be spent during tho current year and in
                        1906, on inclosing 75 acres of desert land adjoining the present asylum, and
                        on adapting and enlarging an existing building, now used as an army hospital
                        for the use of lunatics. Thus the number of bods will be increased from 500
                        te 820. In the second place, the construction ol another large lunatic
                        asylum is under conside- ration. Plans are being prepared, but the site has
                        not yet been chosen. It will probably be situated somewhere between Tantah
                        and Alexandra. The type of the new asylum will be that known as the "Villa
                        Colony.” Ian informed that this system has been tried with great success in
                        Germany, and that it is eminently suited to the Egyptian climate."</p>
                    <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman SS. "Anatolia" arrived ai Liverpool on Wednesday morning.</p>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Portugal,1 from Alexandria, arrived at
                        Marseilles at 5 a.m yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The Canard S.S. "Pavia" will arrive hero of Saturday from Volo, and will
                        immediately commence loading cargo for Liverpool am American porta. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INNSBRUCK-TYROL.</head>
                    <p>Ideal Spring and Sampler Resort. Beautiful promenades and mountain
                        excursions.</p>
                    <p>HOTEL TYROL.</p>
                    <p>1st Claes Hotel, enlarged, lately with an ex tensive palatial addition with
                        every modern comfort</p>
                    <p>Fireproof System Hennebique. Illustrated pamphlet on Innsbruck free from
                        proprietor: CARL LANDSEE.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aan02">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Goods Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>1.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>( From Our Correspondant ).</p>
                    <p>MORE RUSSIAN REFUGEES.</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Wednesday. To-day at 8 a.m., the Messageries Maritimes S.S.
                        “Tonkin" arrived from Yokokama, having on board 24 Russian sailors, 4
                        military officers, and 84 refugees. The ship is to sail this after- noon for
                        Marseilles direct.</p>
                    <p>I learn on good authority that those amongst the number who are wounded are
                        to go to a sanatorium which has been specially prepared for them at Nice.
                        The building, which from all accounts is magnificently situated, is rented
                        by the Russian Government, and has a large medical and surgical staff,
                        principally of French nationality.</p>
                    <p>P. &amp; O. PASSENGERS.</p>
                    <p>For some time past the Suez Canal Com- pany have employed a large number
                        (some 800) of Arabs on the now dockyard and workshops which are in coarse of
                        construc- tion so the Asian shore of the harbour. Arab town being on the
                        west shore, these work- men are brought over by boat every evening about 6
                        o’clock I frequently see this horde of somewhat unruly characters, in bands
                        of 50 to 100, land at tho main passenger jetty. Last evening they landed at
                        the Custom House as usual and went up the main street (Rue de Commerce)
                        shouting and laughing, much to the alarm of many lady passengers who had
                        come ashore from the P. &amp;0. "Mongolia," and who, fearing some sort of
                        riot, took refuge in shops and hotels. -Seeing that coal coolies are not on
                        any pretext allowed to traverse main thoroughfares, it is generally thought
                        that the police might well include these frequently equally dirty crowds in
                        the regulations, and so avoid such scenes. The name of Port Said is none so
                        good, though much improved, that this state of things can be allowed to
                        continue.</p>
                    <p>CONFLICT OF JURISDICTIONS. STRANGE CASE.</p>
                    <p>The Appeal Court of the Mixed Tribunals gave judgment in tho case of Stagni
                        v. Selinas on the 3rd inst, and as our readers are aware, the text of this
                        judgment appeared in foil in our columns a few days ago. Mr. Salinm, the
                        well-known Alexandria stockbroker, won the case both in the Mixed Court of
                        1st Instance and in the Appeal Court But both Mr. Luigi Stagni and Mr.
                        Salinas are Italian subjects, and tho same case has also pi-.es before the
                        Italian Consular Courts and to the Appeal Court at Ancona, where judgment
                        was given in favor of Mr. Luigi Stagni. This gentleman has naturally decided
                        to abide by the decision of the court which gave judgment in his favor, and
                        two days ago levied an execution on the furniture of Mr. Salinas, although
                        the latter is the successful suitor according to the Mixed Courts. Wo do not
                        call to mind a more striking instance of the conflict of jurisdictions pre-
                        vailing in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>A COTTON CORNER.</p>
                    <p>"A Native Landowner" (Helouan) writes:— Some merchants at Alexandria have
                        arranged a “corner” in May cotton and have artificially raised the price by
                        two dollars within the last three days. The price of May cotton is now 15
                        3/4 dollars, while last Saturday it was only 13 3/4 dollars. What is very
                        strange is that while cotton is abundant in Alexandria, and there is one
                        hundred thousand cantars more than last year at this time, still cotton at
                        Alexandria is four dollars dearer than at Liverpool. Is not such a comer
                        illegal and prohibited by the law? And will the Tribunals allow people to be
                        robbed by such corners ?</p>
                    <p>PORT SAID SALT ASSOCIATION.</p>
                    <p>Owing to Saturday next being a Bank Holi- day, the subscription list of the
                        Egyptian Salt Association will close on Friday evening instead of
                        Saturday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Among the passengers for Constantinople by the S.S. "Prince Abbas,” which
                        left Alexandria yesterday, wore Princesses Said Pasah Halim, Abbas Pasha
                        Halim, Judge Piggott, Count Etienne Zizinia, etc.</p>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Cromer are expected back from their excursion in Upper Egypt on
                        the 17th inst.</p>
                    <p>Col. D. F. Lewis, C.B., A.D.C., who has been unemployed since he retired from
                        the Egyptian Army in September, 1900, arrived at Port Said yesterday on his
                        way from England to Manchuria, having been selected by the War Office to do
                        duty with the Japanese army in the field as a Military Attache CoL Lewis
                        will be remembered for the services he rendered under Lord Kitchener in the
                        Sudan, especially in connexion with the pursuit and ultimate defeat and
                        death of the Khalifa.</p>
                    <p>Captain Blomfield, of the Warwickshire Regiment, son of Sir Massie and Lady
                        Blom- field, arrived at Port-Said by the P. &amp;0. "Mongolia" on Tuesday.
                        He has come to join the Egyptian Army.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Sir Massie and Lady Blomfield leave Alexandria for the Austrian Tyrol
                        on the 27th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN SHAKE KARKET. (FROM OUR CORRESPONDANT).</head>
                    <p>London May 5 Awaiting the events ! The very largeness of the impending
                        struggle belittles all else. Mean time, rumors of peace negotiations are
                        persist- ent but no one knows through what channel they come. Hope is
                        perhaps “father to, the thought" that the Tsar may still have a grain of
                        sense left, and may use the factor of doubt yet remaining to obtain some
                        kind of terms. As yet there is no sign of activity in stock markets, and
                        moreover, there is little induce- ment to lead to an increase of public
                        business the position in the Far East being no clearer than it was a week
                        ago, though the somewhat strained feeling in European diplomatic circles as
                        reflected in financial circles seems to have almost passed away.</p>
                    <p>Japanese stocks have hardened a little, especially the new 4 1/2 per cent
                        issue, the special settlement in which took place today, Consols are dull,
                        and dealers in all quarters seem anxious to avoid having any position open,
                        until the horizon is clearer.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian stocks are steady, but inactive. Daira Sanieh shares are a trifle
                        lower at 285/8, ex a dividend of 3s.; and Bank shares are unchanged. In the
                        mining section the tone is dull. The market at the moment is a neglected
                        one, and suffers, in company with Booth Africans, from sheer want of
                        business. Specu- latively—i.e. for any intermediate improvement -there is
                        nothing tempting about this market, but, to take op and put away, prices are
                        near, if they have not already reached, a cheap leveL</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB. REGATTA.</head>
                        <p>The following is the result of yesterday's regatta Class I. Boat. Start
                            Finish Sailed by 1 Banshee 3.07.05 4.40.26 S. Dorling 2 Tier-el-Mina
                            2.56.33 4.41.20 Capt. Borg 3 Leman 3.05.08 4.43.15 F. de Planta Minnie
                            2.55.22 4.45.00 N. W. de Conroy Celtic 3.03.18 4.47.45 Capt. P. Evans
                            Jenny 2.57.55 4.49.59 T. McClure May 2.55.45 5.01.42 Sag. Herbert /?/
                            Disqualified Mr Blagden Class II. 1 Laura 3.37.58 5.00.47 Prince Aziz 2
                            Calypso 3.26.13 5.05.41 Dr. Rudolph 3 Shamrock 3.24.30 5.10.15 Mr. E.
                            Gentilli St. George 3.29.04 5.11.32 Maj. Feetham Masr 3.27.05 5.13.03 Mr
                            Fransis Akraba 3.20.24 5.14.53 Sag. Phillips Ironie 3.20.48 5.15.52 Mr.
                            Girard Cattelaya 3.20.34 gave up P.C.Barnard The wind was flesh from the
                            N. The “Coot" was disqualified for knocking over the starting flag with
                            her main boom. The prize in Class I. for the four races was won by the
                            “Tier-el-Mina” and in Class II. by the "Laurea." Next week there will be
                            a new handicap.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                        <p>E. T. C. v. KOM EL-DIK. The E.T.C. commenced a match on Tuesday against a
                            ‘Kom-el-Dik’ XI. For the E.T.C., Messrs. Stacey and Cheesman put on 73
                            before being separated. The last wicket also pat on 48 runs. In bowling
                            Mr. Henley took 8 wickets for 68. For ‘Kom-el-Dik’ Mr. Dawson played a
                            good innings of 54. Scores E. T. C. Mr. Stacey, l.b.w., b. Slade… … … 50
                            „ Cheesman, c. Hall, b. Burke… … 29 „ Blythman, c. Dawson, b. Davis … 14
                            „ Hanley, run out… … … … 0 „ R. B. McLean, a Davis, b. Slade … 13 „
                            Byrne, b. Davis… … … … … 5 „ Henley, b. Murray… … … … 4 „ Lees, c.
                            Slade, b. Davis… … … 0 „ Scarth, c. Burke, b. Davis… … … 0 „ Thurston,
                            l.b.w. b. Dawson … … 20 „ Millar, not out… … … … … 32 Extras. … … … … …
                            … … 25 Total … … … 192 Kom-el-Dik. Cpl. New, c. Blythman, b. Henley ....
                            1 Sgt. Fuller, c. Millar, b. Henley ... ... 4 Cpl. Murray, o. Thurston,
                            b. Henley... 11 Sgt. Borke, c. Hanley, b. Henley.. ... 88 S. J. Dawson,
                            b. Stacey ... ........... 58 Gr. Hall, b. Hanley... ................ 0
                            Gr. Davies, ran,out... ... 7 Gr. Slade, st Hanley, b. Henley........ 3
                            Cpl. Maher, not out.. ,.. ........... 0 Br. Wilde, st Hanley, b. Henley
                            ... 0 Hassan, c. Scarth, b. Henley............ 1 Extras.
                            .......................... 11 Total ... ... …. 124</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo
                        alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aaw01">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p>Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
