<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Emma Taylor</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-13">November 13, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
           
<div type="item"><head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS. 

REVOLT OF PRISONERS.

HOLY SYNOD'S APPEAL.</head>

<p>St. Petersburg, November 11.	</p>
<p>Martial law has been proclaimed at Kronstadt.
The corps of Marine Cadets here is in a state of extreme excitement. The cadets insist upon the band playing ‘ the "Marseillaise" on every opportunity, singing to the music ribald words insulting the Tsar.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p> 

<p>Kishineff,	November 11.</p>	
<p>Yesterday evening the prisoners in the gaol revolted en masse and set fire to the prison. The troops arrived and fired, killing 22 and wounding many.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p> 

<p>St.	Petersburg,	November 12. </p>	
<p>The last of the Kronstadt mutineers have surrendered.	
The Holy Synod has issued an address to the people begging them to cease attacking and murdering landed proprietors and Jews, and to avoid 	civil war. It further urges them	
to inaugurate an era of peace and tranquillity.

Martial law has been proclaimed throughout Poland, where the authorities fear that an insurrection is being organised.

M. Witte has received telegrams from various parts of Poland demanding full autonomy, including a Diet at Warsaw, elected by universal suffrage. M. Witte informed a Polish deputation that he is in favor of autonomous administration, but opposed to political autonomy.</p>	
<p>(Reuter)</p> 

<div type="item"><head> THE NEW CABINET </head>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 11. </p>
<p>The Minister of Justice remains in office, and the Cabinet is therefore complete except the Ministers of the Interior and Public Instruction, seeing that the Ministers of War
Marine, Foreign  Affairs, and the Court do not form part of the Cabinet according to the plan of re-organisation of 26th October.</p></div>


<div type="item"><head>POWERS’ NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.

ITALY AND TURKEY.</head> <p>Rome, November 12.</p>

<p>It is semi-officially explained that Italy’s cooperation with the Powers in the naval demonstration is not inspired by any ill-feeling towards Turkey, but by a belief in the necessity of financial control in Macedonia. The squadrons will probably meet at Piraeus.</p> <p>(R.) </p>
</div>
<div type="item"><head>RELIEF OF UNEMPLOYED. QUEEN’S CONTRIBUTION TO FUND.</head>

<p>London, November 11.</p>

<p>The Queen has given £2,000 to the unemployed fund, and appeals to all charitable persons in the Empire to relieve the starving daring the winter.</p>	  <p>(Reuter)</p> </div>

<div type="item"><head>THE CAIRO FRERES CASE.

FORMER FINDING REVERSED.</head>	

<p>Paris November ll.</p>	

<p>The Court of Cassation has reversed the finding of the Aix Court, similar to that of the Cairo Consular Court, in the libel suit brought by the director of the Christian Schools in Cairo, admitting the action of the local director and not that of the General Superior of the Congregation.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p></div>

	

<div type="item"><head>DR NANSEN.

NORWEGIAN MINISTER IN LONDON.</head>

<p>London, November 11.</p>

<p>The explorer Dr. Nansen has been appointed Norwegian Minister here.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BRITISH SQUADRON’S VISIT TO

NEW YORK.</head>

<p>New YORK November 11.</p>

<p>The visit of the British Squadron to New York is affording an occasion for every kind of international courtesy. Prince Louis of Battenberg is producing an excellent impression by his unaffected geniality.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
</div>
<div type="item"><head>french ministry.</head>

<p> Paris, November 11.</p>
<p>M. Etienne has  succeeded M. Berteaux as Minister of War.</p>	
<p>(Reuter)</p>

<p>Paris November 12.</p>

<p>M. Efienne has been appointed Minister of War, M. Dubief of the Interior, and M. Trouillet of Commerce. The other Ministers retain their portfolios.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>KING ALFONSO IN VIENNA.</head>

<p>Berlin, November 12.</p>

<p>King Alfonso has left for Vienna.</p> <p>(Havas)</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>

<p>Harmonia Club.</p>

<p>A successful afternoon dance was given at the Harmonia Club, Cairo, on Saturday afternoon.</p>

<p>Khedive's Accession Fete.</p>

<p>The first list of subscriptions towards the celebration of the anniversary of the Khedive's accession amounts to L.E. 133.</p>

<p>Dragoman Tariff.</p>

<p>The Governor of Suez has issued a new tariff for dragomans and public guides, which comes into force in a week.</p>

<p>Land and Mortgage Co. of Egypt (Ltd.)</p>

<p>The directors have declared an interim dividend at the rate of 10 p.c. for the six months ended Sept. 30 last.</p>

<p>Killed by a Buffalo.</p>

<p>A native boy was tending a buffalo near El Fashn Markaz on Saturday, when the animal turned upon the lad and gored him to death.</p>

<p>Egyptian Estates, Limited.</p>

<p>Messrs. Walker and Meimarachi have purchased a fine block of land in an excellent position in Cairo from the Egyptian Estates, Limited.</p>

<p>Suez Canal.</p>

<p>From the 7th to the 9th inst 24 vessels passed through the Canal, of which 17 were British,

1 German, 2 French, 2 Dutch, 1 Austrian, 1 Greek. The total amount received in dues from the 1st to the 9th inst was frs. 2,965,670.93.</p>

<p>Nile Valley Operations.</p>

<p>October crushing:—The 5-stamp battery ran 21.5 days, crushing 410 tons of ore, yielding 198 ozs of gold over the plates, valued at £720 sterling. The total footage development was 208 ft.</p>

<p>Ministry of The Interior.</p>

<p>Mr. J. de M. Johnson and Mr. Arthur Thomas Lloyd have been appointed by special decision to be sub-inspectors of the Ministry of the Interior, with pay at the rate of L.E. 240 per annum. These appointments are probationary.</p>

<p>Gaolbird Captured.</p> 

<p>Hussein el Sayid, who was condemned in 1893 to 15 years' imprisonment with hard labour, for the murder of Sheikh Abdel Ghani Osman, omdeh of Sheikh Fadl, and had escaped from prison, living for several years in the country unknown to the police, has been recaptured and put in prison again.</p>

<p>Village Murder.</p>

<p>A native named Ali Abon Shahbeh of Mahallat Manouf, was found murdered on the 8th inst. in that village. An enquiry into the circumstances of the crime has led the Tantah authorities to suspect the omdeh’s cousin and the latter's servant of the murder. The men’s clothes were found to be stained with blood.</p>

<p>Royal Anniversary.</p>

<p>Saturday being the birthday of H.M. King Victor Emmanuel III., the Gouvernorat, Consulates, and Agency flaw their national flags and the Italian dolours were much in evidence in the streets of Cairo. Visits were exchanged between Count A. Gonzaga and H.E. Boutros Pasha Ghali, Minister for Foreign Affairs, and a reception was held at the Italian Agency, which was largely attended.</p>

<p>Credit Franco-Egyptien.</p>

<p>Mr. Petcovich, sub-manager of the Credit Lyonnais at Alexandria, has been appointed manager of the Credit Franco-Egyptien at a salary of £3,000 a year. We congratulate the Credit Franco-Egyptien on the appointment, for the business capabilities of Mr. Petcovich are well known, and the acquisition of this gentleman as director of the Credit augurs well for the sound financial lines on which it will be run. Restoration of Convent

Nungovich Bey has handed to Mgr. Photina, Patriarch of Alexandria, the sum of £100 as a contribution towards the reconstruction of St George’s convent, which was burnt some time ago. He has also opened a credit of £500 at the Patriarchate for the same purpose. It is stated that M. Karam, of Alexandria, has generously offered to supply all the timber necessary for the reconstruction of the convten.</p> 
<p>Khedivial Geographical Society</p>

<p>Two new bulletins have just been issued by the Khedivial Geographical Society, numbers 7 and 8 of the sixth series of these publications. The most interesting article is a study of the physical geography of the cataract at Assouan by Mr. Fourtan. It is enriched by some remarkable photographic reproductions of the rooks at Salouganarte. Dr. Bonola Bey contributes a note on Egypt and Nubia from the memoirs of Santoni and there are articles on Moslem explorers by Mahmoud Salem Bey, Feudal and Patriarchal customs in Abyssinia by Dr. Lincoln de Castro, and some impressions of a trip in German East Africa by Dr. Jaeger.</p></div>


<div type="item" scope="advertisement">
    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
    <p>BREMEN.</p>
    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
        Sudan.</p>
    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
</div>



<div type="item" scope="advertisement"><p>JOSEPH COMAS.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>NIAM NIAM EXPEDITION.

GOOD SERVICE LIST.</head>

	

<p>His Excellency the Sirdar has just published \ list of officers, N.C.O’s, and men whose names had been brought to the notion of he Khedive for their good services in the recent operations against the Niam-Niams. The list includes the names of the late Miralai Boulnois Bey, commanding the expedition, the late Kaimakam Fell Bey, Intelligence officer, Bimbashi Rawson, Kaimakam Sutherland Bey, and one native officer, all of the Staff, Bimbashi Bethell, one native officer, and one soldier of the Artillery, Bimbashi Percival Bey, D.S.O., one native officer, and one soldier of the Camel Corps, Kaimakam Carter Bey, three native officers, and five N.C.O’s. and men of the 9th Sudanese, Kaimakam Gordon Bey, two native officers, and two N.C.O's and men of the 10th Sudanese, Bimbashi Ryan, D.S.O., one native officer, and two men of the 15th Sudanese, Kaimakam Bray Bey, Kaimakam Riven Bey, and Bimcbashi Brakemridge, and two native officers of the Medical Corps, and Bimbashi Flint and three native officers of the Transport.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>

<p>Ibrahim Pasha Fathi, Director of the Recruiting Department, has been appointed Emir El Hag, and Mohamed Bey Wahbi, an official in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, treasurer, for the present year’s pilgrimage.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>TWO MOROCCAN VISITORS.</head>

<p>Sid Mohamed El Mackry, son of the Moroccan Finance Minister, and Sid Mohamed El-Benani, engineer in the Moroccan Government, have recently arrived in Cairo. After spending several days in the Capital they will proceed to the Hedjaz, on the pilgrimage.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>

<p>The Council of Ministers will meet next Saturday morning, at Abdeen Palace, under the presidency of the Khedive.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>FINANCE MINISTRY.</head>

<p>The drawing up of the new project elaborated by the Ministry of Finance relative to the classification by degree of Government fficials, will be finished by the end of March, and it will come into force as from the 1st January next.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>

<p>H. H. the Khedive is expected to pass five or six days at Montazah and during his stay to inspect his properties at Mariout.</p></div>

 <div type="item"><head>THE LATE ME. MOLTENI.</head>

<p>The body of the late Me. Molteni has been successfully embalmed and will be conveyed to Cairo station on Monday afternoon, the family of the deceased having decided that the burial should take place in Italy.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>CAIRO TRAMWAYS.</head>

<p>There is no truth in the statement of a contemporary that a misunderstanding has occurred between the Cairo Tramway Company and the Ministry of Public Works oh the subject of the new carriages, with first-class compartments, which it is intended to place very shortly on all the lines. There has been some delay in their delivery, but it is expected that they will be running by the new year, These carriages, which have a compartment for first-class passengers in front, another for ladies at the end, and accommodation for the second class in the centre, should prove a great boon to those residents who are compelled to use the tramcars several times daily between their homes and offices, and we congratulate M. Dessalles, the energetic manager, on this innovation.

The company will in a short time begin the laying of the now extension from the present terminus at Boulac to the Boole des Arts et Metiers. Some delay has occurred in beginning the work on account of the difficulties the company has encountered from the owners of the properties to be expropriated for this purpose.</p></div>		

<div type="item"><head>SAVOY HOTEL, PORT SAID.</head>

<p>This well-known hostelry has been sold by Mr. Klingler, the proprietor and manager of the Continental Hotel in Cairo, to Mr. Henri Chamoulleau, former proprietor of the Khedivial Hotel at Alexandria, who will enter into possession on the 15th November. During the four years that the hotel has been in possession of the former gentleman he has succeeded in forming a high-class clientele, which no doubt Mr. Chamoulleau will not only retain but increase, since his reputation as an hotelier has long been established.

Daring the summer a large sum of money has been spent on alterations and improvements at the Savoy Hotel, which will add greatly to the comfort of visitors. The whole of the shops facing the quay have been removed and replaced by a fine dining saloon and bar opening on the sea front and supported by massive marble columns. The additions include 32 newly-built bedrooms, which bring up the total to 74. Mr. Klingler lately obtained an extension of the lease from the Messageries Maritimes, who are the owners of the whole large block of buildings in which the hotel is situated.</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>PIRACY IN THE RED SEA.

H.M.S. FOX’S MISSION.</head>

<p>Details of the fighting which occurred at Hodeida, in the Yemen, when the British cruiser Fox was at that place a few weeks ago in connection with the pursuit and punishment of the pirates who bad attacked British dhows, have just been received. Claims were lodged with the Porte in regard to these outrages, and the Pox was despatched to the Yemen coast in order to see that the local authorities carried out the British demands, arrested and punished the guilty persons, and destroyed the pirate dhows.	

The British cruiser co-operated with the local Turkish authorities in the accomplishment of these objects. It was found that the pirates bad moored their dhows at a place called Khor Gbu’eifaka, which was not easy for the Turks to attack and that the former had mounted guns round the cove where the pirate chips were lying. A stiff fight occurred, in which the pirates lost twenty-five killed and a large number of wounded. A launch belonging to the Fox went aground and was lost, and one British sailor was slightly wounded.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>BAGOURIAH canal.</head>

<p>In consequence of the low level of the Nile it has been derided not to close the Bagourish Canal during December and January, as previously notified.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>LAUNCHES FOR THE NILE.</head>

<p>Four car-loads of power launches were shipped  from St. Joseph, Mich., on the 20th ult. to the order of the Egyptian Government for use on the River Nile.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>SUEZ CANAL COMMISSION.</head>

<p>Sir Charles Hartley and Sir John Wolfe Barry have left London for Paris to attend the annual meeting of, the International Technical Commission of the Suez Canal, on which they are the British representatives.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>SUEZ CANAL COUPONS.</head>

<p>The board of directors of the Suez Canal have fixed the rate of the coupons due on January 1 next, at follows :

Actions de Capital, gross 35 fr.

Actions de Capital, net 50.408 fr.

Actions de Jouissance, gross 42.50 fr.

Actions de Jouissance, net 88.782 fr.

Pounders' Shares, grots 23.943 fr.

Founders' Shares, net 29.005 frs.

Coupons can now be presented.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>

<p>M.M. Fourneron and Sampaolo have returned from their inspection of the Matana, Arment, and Nag Hamadi factories with a very large collection of documents for their next report, which, however, can hardly be completed in time for Thursday's hearing. The report promisee to be the most important and interesting of the series and will doubtless give rise to vigorous discussion.	

At the request of the Hon. A. J.Davey, the bearing of the action brought by M. Poutrel has been fixed for Tuesday, 14th inst.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN SALT AND SODA CO.</head>

<p>On Saturday last, the first consignment of oilcake made at the Kafr Zayat factory since the establishment of the new regime of the Salt and Soda Company was shipped from Alexandria for England by the S.S. Mariner, chartered by Messrs. Barber and Son.

A large quantity of machinery, plant for the manufacture of caustic sods, has been dispatch ed from Alexandria to the Wady Natron.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>

<p>A Cairo correspondent writes to ask how it is that we published an authorised denial of the rumour that Mr. A. Hooker had retiree from the Egyptian Land and General Trust Limited, when in a letter from Crooksbank Pasha, addressed to the Editor of the “Egyptian Gazette,” the Pasha alluded to Mr. Hooker as ex-managing director. The reply to this question is that Mr. Hooker has resigned the post of managing director of the company, but he has not resigned his position on the board, and is therefore still a director.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>

<p>Daring the absence on leave of El Lewa St. George C.Henry Pasha,c B., Adjutant General. El Miralai Asser Bey, Commandant, Khartoum Station, has taken over the duties of Acting Adjutant General.	

El Bimbashi Moore,Junior Inspector, Kaseala province, has been granted leave of absence till December 31.</p></div>

 <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

<p>The S.S. Carib Prince, with passengers and general cargo, left London on Saturday, 11th inst, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on or about the 97th inst

The Messageries Maritimes S.S. Congo from Marseilles, passed the Straits of Messina on Saturday and is due here tomorrow.

The S.S. Sailor Prince, from Alexandria arrived at Manchester on Saturday last.</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>ALEXANDRIA WATER SUPPLY

REPLY TO “ALEXANDRIAN. ’’

To THE Editor of the Egyptian Gazette</head> <p>Sir,—In your paper of yesterday you publish a letter under the above heading signed "Alexandrian,” containing certain malicious statements, which, if true, would not only reflect very seriously on me and my colleagues, past and present, on the board of the Alexandria Water Company, Ltd., but also on the character of many high officials of the Egyptian Government, who, during a long series of years, have represented the Government on the board of that company.

Your correspondent says  "it was discovered " that the company were charging the double of what they were legally entitled to for a " girbeh of water.” This statement is absolutely false ; the Water Company never has sold water at any higher price than they were legally entitled to. 

In the autumn of 1878 the waterworks of Alexandria were offered for sale in London, by a man of the highest integrity, then Minister of Finance to the Egyptian Government, under certain conditions, and one of the most attractive of these conditions was, that a certain branch of the service known as the Sakkas, or water carriers, service, brought in a net revenue of £12,000 a year ; this was not an estimated revenue, but one which had been realised for many years by the Egyptian Government itself, at the price at which it had sold the water, and proposed to transfer and did subsequently transfer, to its purchaser, the Water Company, by contract of sale, the right to continue the sale of water on the same condition, and at the same tariff as that in use by the Government during the many years it had worked the undertaking. Not only is this confirmed by contract, but the gentleman to whom I above refer, is still living, and not only can, but would contradict me, if anything I say in this matter is not strictly true, The Water Company rotated this right until 1894, when it gave it up not as your correspondent says, because it was an extortion, but as the result of an agreement with the Municipality of Alexandria, who offered in exchange for it a new system of filtration subject only to a contribution of L.E. 10,000 by the Water Company, and not only this, but they gave the company the right to sell water by meter, a right which led to complications, reference to which would tale up too much of your space.

Not only was it the first duty of the Government representatives on our board to assure themselves that the Water Company was acting in accordance with its legal rights, bat I am in a position to say, without fear of contradiction, that one and all of these gentlemen conscientiously did their duty in this respect	

There are several other inaccuracies in the letter under notice, which I could easily refute, but will not weary your readers by doing so at present.	

I write only in my own name, and without prejudice to any action in the matter which my colleagues may decide to take ; they are men as well known as any in Alexandria, and it requires no testimony of mine to defend them ; but in memory of those with whom I formerly had the honor of being associated, and who have gone from this world and are no longer able to defend themselves, I will, say, that it is a disgraceful action to endeavor to sully their names by such false insinuations; for they were honorable men, who,under trying circumstances, did the best which could be expected of them for the general good.

I do not know who your correspondent "Alexandrian” may be, nor have I the slightest wish to make his acquaintance, for, in my opinion, a man who would publish the malicious statements he has made, on a subject oh which be shows that he is profoundly ignorant, is beneath contempt.—I remain, etc., E. Cornish,

A director of the Alexandria Water;

Company, Limited. Alexandria, 12th November.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>I. O. G. T.

 BLUE CAPS' PRIDE LODGE M107.</head>

 <p>The above lodge held its opening session list week under favorable circumstances at Mustapha Pasha barracks, Alexandria, Bro. Charles Neill, V. T., presiding. After the transaction of the ordinary business of the lodge four initiations took place. Another friend was put on proposition. The lodge deputy urged the officers to do their utmost to keep the members together, and try and introduce new members to the Order. He hoped members would use their influence In the several departmental corps in Alexandria and swell the lodge. Work is required and not

words,  and he had not the least doubt that if brothers and sisters put their shoulders to the wheel, success would assuredly follow. The programme for the evening was the reading of “Temperance Cuttings.” Several members contributed. A debate followed in which Bros. Will, Ireland, Gervine, and Miller took part The meeting was duly closed by Bro. Neill, V.T, at 9 p.m.

A regular session will be held on Tuesday next at 7 o'clock. Friends are cordially invited on the "good of order” programme.</p></div>


<div type="item"><head>A FRENCHMAN IN THESUDAN.

HIS IMPRESSIONS.</head>

<p>M. E. Sulesses, director of the railway in French Guinea, has just returned to Paris from an official visit to Africa, during which be inspected all the railways now working on this continent, and saw a good deal of the Sudan and Egypt

It is satisfactory to note for the future good relations of France and England in Africa that M. Salesses is an Anglophila He was presented to all the British officials in the course of his itinerary, and received the greatest assistance from their hands. His speaks particularly well of Sir Reginald Wingate— as, indeed, do all his compatriots. The Sirdar has known how to make himself extremely liked by the French because of his tact and consideration. M. Salesses exchanged a few words with Lord Cromer, and was impressed with the power of the man, even in so short an interview.	

As to the treatment of the natives by the British Administration, M. Salessies regards it somewhat in the light of mistaken kindness. The native is a child, and must be treated as such. Occasionally it is necessary to show firmness. You cannot apply all the ideas of Western justice to him. The judicial branch must not bo separated from the political and executive. There is no division of, labour amongst the native Africans. The potter digs his own clay ; the bootmaker is a tanner. And so the Commissioner in charge of a district should himself bo able to apply the law. Justice must be swift The native does not understand being punished three months after the commission of a crime. Three months is too long for his memory— he has forgotten all about the offence.”

M. Salesses shares the view of Lord Cromer that the Cape-to-Cairo railway can very properly utilise a steamboat service on the lakes and the White Nile to connect its sections. He thinks that Germany should strike a bargain with England over the lease of a atrip of land between Tanganyika and Victoria Nyanza. Such a cession of territory would work no prejudice to German interests; on the contrary, the communication afforded by the railway would be highly profitable to the colony.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>THE NEW SUDAN RAILWAY.</head>

<p>The railway line in the neighbourhood of Suakin has been washed away on two occasions lately in several places. It has now been repaired.

Macaulay Bey and Drury Bey are expected at Suakin this week from Cairo.</p></div>

<div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>

<p>We see by the "Morning Post” of the. 4th just that a marriage has been arranged between Lord George Seymour, R.N., youngest son of the Marquis and Marchioness of Hertford, and Miss Norah Skipwith, only daughter of the late Mr. Archibald Peyton-Skiptwith and of Mrs. It. Curtis Toogood, 87, Cadogan-gardens, and niece of Admiral Sir Massie BlomfieldtK.C.M.G. Lord George Saymour is first cousin of Count Gleichen, formerly of the Military Intelligence Department, Egyptian Army.</p>

<p>Mr. Somera Clarke, the architect to St Paul’s Cathedra], is at present engaged in a study of the proposed restoration of St Mark’s Church, Alexandria. He is the guest of Admiral Sir Massie and Lady Blomfield.</p>

<p>We are sorry to hear that Lady Blomfield has been suffering from a sharp attack of influenza, and is still very weak.</p>

<p>Hopkinson Bey, Commandant of Alexandria City Police, was among the passengers who arrived by the  Austrian mail this morning.</p>

<p>Chitty Bey returned from Cairo yesterday evening.</p>	

<p>Mohamed Mahmoud Suleiman Effendi, sub-inspector to the Ministry of the Interior, has been appointed private secretary to the Adviser of the Ministry.</p> 

<p>The well-known post and dramatist Sharkri Ghanem is expected to arrive at Cairo on the 27th inst.</p>

<p>Mr. J. Pearce-Hill, of the ET.C„Alexandria, is due to arrive at Port Said by the S.S. Pegn on Wednesday, on his return from leave Mr. Pearce Hill's reputation as an amateur entertainer is well-known, and his many friends here will be glad to bear that he has made arrangements for the production of a comic opera which has proved a great success both  in America and England, and the "plot" of which is laid in Egypt To his popular ventriloquial show Mr. Pearce Hill has made several additions, and has also perfected a little invention of his own, whereby be is enabled not only to sing a duet with the assistance of "Mr,. and Mrs. Sawdust,” but play the accompaniment on the piano at the same time.</p></div>

<div type="item" scope="advertisement"> 
     <p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. </p> 
     <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p> 
     <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p> 
     <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p> 
 </div></div> 


<div type="item" scope="advertisement"> 
    <p>CARLTON HOTEL</p> 
    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p> 
    <p>Ten miniutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate 
         charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron 
        Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p> 
   <p>xxxxx-xx-x-905</p> 
     <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p> 
 </div> 




            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
  </div> </body>
    </text>
</TEI>


