<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Charlie Rymer</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-03</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">Wednesday, August 23, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="item" n="1">
                    <h1>PEACE OR WAR?</h1>
                    <h2>CONFERENCE POSTPONED</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PEACE RUMOURS
                            IN BRITISH PRESS.</h2>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 22.</h3>
                        <p>The Plenipotentiaries yesterday were await-
                            ing instructions from their home Governments.
                            Pending to-day’a resumption of work, their
                            attitude is pessimistic but not hopeless.
                            The Conference has been postponed until
                            to-morrow. The non-completion of the proto-
                            cols is the assigned reason.
                            It is believed that the real reason of the
                            postponement of the Conference is that M.
                            Witte is waiting for final instructions from
                            St. Petersburg.
                            A representative from Mr. Roosevelt con-
                            ferred with M. Witte and Baron de Rosen
                            today.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 22.</h3>
                        <p>A summary of the peace protocols, which
                            were submitted to the Conference today, has
                            been published. It shows that both sides adhere
                            to their positions regarding the indemnity and
                            the island of Saghalien.	(Rader)</p>
                        <h3>London, August 23.</h3>
                        <p>The "Morning Post" learns from Portsmouth
                            (N.H.) that a treaty of peace will be signed
                            shortly. It provides for Russia paying to Japan
                            a sum, which is not large, for the keep of pri-
                            soners and wounded, and stipulates for the
                            ceding of the southern half of Saghalien. Japan
                            abandons her claim on the interned warships
                            and the question of the limitation of Russia's
                            naval power in the Far Bast.-	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CONSTITUTIONAL CONCESSIONS</h2>
                        <h2>REFORMERS DISSATISFIED.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 22.</h3>
                        <p>There are symptoms of a general indignation
                            throughout Russia on acount of the meagre
                            character of the Constitutional concessions.
                            The widespread dissatisfaction is aggravated by
                            the unsatisfactory economic conditions of the
                            country.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <h2>FRANCE AND MOROCCO.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>FRANCE CONTEMPLATES
                            A DEMONSTRATION.</h2>
                        <h3>Paris, August 22.</h3>
                        <p>The French Minister at Fez has presented a
                            vigorous demand for the release of the Algerian
                            chief and the payment of an indemnity. It is
                            understood that France contemplates a demon-
                            stration either on the Algerian frontier or in a
                            Moorish port, as a lesson to the Sultan. (R.)
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>SCANDINAVIAN SEPARATION.</h2>
                        <h2>SWEDEN REQUESTED TO CONCUR</h2>
                        <h3>Christiania, August 22.</h3>
                        <p>The Norwegian Storthing has resolved by
                            104 votes to 11 to request Sweden to concur
                            in the dissolution of the Union. (Reuter)</p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE FAMINE IN RUSSIA.</h2>
                        <h3>Moscow, August 22.</h3>
                        <p>The peasant masses are arriving in a state
                            of destitution from the places where the famine
                            exists.	(Haeat)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>HOME CRICKET.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 22.</h3>
                        <p>Australians beat Lancashire by an innings
                            and 67 runs.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>OBITUARY.</h2>
                        <h2>SAID BEY NASR</h2>
                        <p>We deeply regret to record the death of Said
                            Bey Nasr, Honorary President of the Mixed
                            Court of Appeal, which occurred at 10 a.m.
                            yesterday in the Italian hospital at Abbassieh.
                            Educated in France, Said Bey took an honora-
                            ble part in the war of 1870-71, as lieutenant of
                            a crack batallion of chasseure-a-pied and won
                            the military medal. Returning to Egypt in
                            1872 he filled several administrative posts with
                            distinction, and was appointed Honorary Pre-
                            sident of the Mixed Court of Appeal in 1895.
                            He was admired and respected by his European
                            and native colleagues, and his funeral, which
                            took place at 10 a.m. this morning was largely
                            attended by the European and native members
                            of the judiciary and the Cairo Bar. H.H. the
                            Khedive was represented by Ahmed Bey Yawer,
                            and the Alexandrian Court of Appeal and
                            Mixed Tribunal ware represented by M.
                            Paolucci. Judge Took, the acting President of
                            the Cairo Mixed Court, was also present at the
                            sad ceremony.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="2">
                    <h1>LOCAL AND GENERAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <p>The Brindish Mail arrived at Port Said at
                        6 o'clock this morning, and will be distributed
                        at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 9.30 to-night.</p>
                        
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
                        Abdeen district of Cairo during to-morrow
                        night, and at dawn of the 25th inst. will be
                        poisoned by the police.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Plague.—One new case was admitted
                        into hospital at Alexandria yesterday, and
                        one recovery was reported from the same town.
                        The new case is that of a Sudanese policeman,
                        residing in the Karmooz quarter.</p>
                        
                        <p>Fayoum Normal School.—The Ministry
                        of Public Instruction has decided to open a
                        normal school for teachers in the kuttabs at
                        Medinet-el-Fayoum. An examination of can-
                        didates for admission will he held towards the
                        end of next month.</p>
                        
                        <p>Cotton-Worm Duty.—Mr. J. Sarle Peacock
                        and Mr. G. Bonaparte, who have been tempor-
                        arily attached to the Ministry of the Interior
                        as sub-inspeotors for cotton-worm duty, have
                        been struck off the lists, their service being
                        no longer required.</p>
                        
                        <p>Suez Canal.—On the 19th and 20th inst,
                        14 vessels passed through the Canal, of whioh
                        8 were British, 4 German, 1 French, 1 Ameri-
                        can. The receipts for the two days were
                        trs. 349,216.20, making the total from the
                        1st inst frs. 5,929,980.81.</p>
                        
                        <p>Accident to a, Sais.—Ali El Ammari Om-
                        man, a sais, was riding over the Menasce
                        Bridge over the canal in Moharrem Bey
                        quarter yesterday, when his horse slipped and
                        rolled on his rider, breaking one of his legs
                        and inflicting other injuries.</p>
                        
                        <p>Suicide in the Labban Quarter. — On
                        Taesday night a Maltese woman, who had
                        seffered for seme years from an incurable di-
                        sease, committed suicide by hanging herself to
                        the post of her bed. Her body was renoved
                        to the Deacounesses’ hospital yesterday.</p>
                        
                        <p>Attacked by Bedouins.—Two fellaheen
                        while leading a camel near Marg were fired at
                        on Monday evening by a couple of bedouins,
                        and one named Mohamed el Uamal was wound-
                        ed. The Mamonr of the Waili kism of Cairo
                        has proceeded to the spot and opened an
                        enquiry.</p>
                        
                        <p>Sudden Death.—A store moawen of the
                        Ccstoms Administration Darned Ali Bffendi
                        Hasson suddenly fell yesterday and was carried
                        insensible to the Custom’s Porters' Pharmacy.
                        He was found to be suffering from oerebral
                        haemorrhage and died while beiDg carried to
                        hospital on stretcher.</p>
                        
                        <p>Theft by a Servant—A native notable oi
                        Cairo named Abd-el-Megid Boy Hafiz has ac-
                        cused his servant of the theft of £150. The
                        latter, on being arrested and questioned,
                        stated that he only took £100, whioh he gave
                        to an Armenian money changer to take charge
                        of The Armenian has also been arrested.</p>
                        
                        <p>San Stepano Casino.—The vocal and in-
                        tromental concerts, with which the manage-
                        mint of the 8an Stefano Casino delight their
                        patrons, have met with such suooess that it has
                        been deoided to retain the artistes until 15th
                        September. We would remind oar readers that
                        the snbeoribera' cotillon ball will take place
                        on Saturday evening.</p>
                        
                        <p>Technical Schools. — The Ministry of
                        Pnblio Works has received a notioe from the
                        Railway Administration intimating tbat it
                        be neoessary for the Boole dee Arts et Metiers
                        to remove from their present site in conto
                        quenoe of the projected enlargement of the
                        Boolao workshops, which was advised by the
                        recent Commission. We understand that the
                        new site of the sohool will be at Ghezireh, near
                        the bnildiDga of the Polyteohnio Sohool.</p>
                        
                        <p>Egypt and the Sudan Parcel Post. —
                        An excellent innovation by whioh parcels can
                        be sent between Egypt and the 8 a dan, and
                        between post offioes in the Sudan, and their
                        value pud to the postal authorities on delivery,
                        will be inaugurated on September 1. No parcel
                        sent in this way mnst haves greater value than
                        L.E. 20, and an extra charge of five millibmes
                        must be paid on each parcel by the sender.
                        The postal authorities forward the amount
                        collected to the sender of the parcel, after
                        deducting a sum similar to that payable on a
                        money-order. The offices which are open to
                        suoh service will be notified from time to time
                        by the director of posts and telegraphs.</p>
                        
                        <p>Licensing op Advocates.—In oonseqoence
                        of it having been brought to the notice of the
                        Sudan Government that oertain persons have
                        been acting as pleaders, or making a praotioe
                        of appearing as agents in cases before the
                        Sudan Civil Courts without legal qualification,
                        a notioe has been published in the "Sudan
                        Gazette” to the effect that no person is allow-
                        ed to praotioe as an advocate or professional
                        agent before the Sudan Civil Courts without
                        the oonsent of the Legal Secretary to the
                        8udan Government Suoh oonsent will only be
                        given to those who hold a diploma of the Cairo
                        Iaw Sohool, or some other approved legal
                        qualification. It is also neoessary to prodnoe
                        evidence of character, In order to praotioe
                        before the Sudan Mohamedan Religious Coorta
                        it is necessary to obtain the oon*ent of both
                        the Lejal Secretary and tb« High Mpfakanja.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="3">
                    <h1>SYRIA'S TRADE IN 1901</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE COAST.</h2>
                        <p>The two Consular reports reoently published
                            by the Foreign Office on the trade of Damascus
                            and of Beyrout and the Syrian Coast in 1904,
                            are very interesting reading, and it ia highly
                            satisfactory to note that British trade and
                            shipping are holding their own. The return of
                            the year’s shipping putting in at Beyront
                            shows a total tonnage of 1,940,259 tons,
                            British vessels being foremost with 316,458
                            tons, as against 268,848 tons in the previous
                            year. The totals fur the shipping of other
                            European natious shows an increase in 1904
                            except in the oase of Franoe, where the pro-
                            longed strike at Marseillee serioasly affeoted
                            intercourse with the Levant
                            British imports are now reckoned at abont
                            two-thirds of the whole Syrian trade. They
                            oonsist principally of Manchester ootton goods,
                            and patent fuel, copper, galvanised sheets, lin-
                            seed oil, oaustio soda, and various kinds of
                            provisions, and though Austria and Germany
                            are endeavouring to oompete in prints and
                            woollen staffs, Italy and America in T-oloths,
                            and the Netherlands in	their
                            endeavours have so far met with little suooees.
                            Belgian patent foel, being unencumbered by an
                            oxpert duty has lately found a market in Syria,
                            but British ooal imports still form over 80% of
                            the total. Egyptian imports to the Syrian
                            ooast oonsist almost entirely of flour, with
                            small quantities of high quality rioe, dates and
                            sugar. The exoprta to Egypt oonsist mainly of
                            dried fruits, sesame, and silk stuffs, the excel-
                            lent Syrian silk thread going to Franoe alone.
                            The United Kingdom takes the greater part of
                            the barley and wheat exported, the best qual-
                            ities of wool, and a good deal of tobacco, and
                            while the bailey export fell off in 1904 owing
                            to a very poor harvest we may say that, from
                            onr own observation, the present year’s crop
                            premirod vary well, exoept in the higher parts
                            of the Lebanon, in May and Jane, and nothing
                            has been heard in Egypt of any failure of the
                            harvest owing to disease or drought.
                            Taking the ooast ports one by one, we note
                            that Beyront’s commerce has suffered and
                            continues to suffer from the heavy quay
                            dues levied by the company and the insuffi-
                            cient supply of porters for the removal of
                            goods from the lighters to the custom house.
                            The spvo in the warehouses of the latter
                            is also very limited and goods remain ex-
                            posed in lighten in all weathers, though in
                            winter and spring it can rain as heavily at
                            Beyrout as anywhere, until their tarn oomee
                            to bo taken to the warehouses of the Douane.
                            The Homs-Hama broad gauge line from Rsyak
                            has unquestionably increased Beyrout's ex-
                            port trade, while Trablous (Tripoli in Syria)
                            has lest ground. The reason for this is ob-
                            vious enough, So long as the fertile region
                            of the B'kaa and the important towns of
                            Homs and Hama were unconnected by railway
                            with the ooast, it was obviously better polioy
                            to send goods on mule-baok straight over
                            the hills to Tripoli than to oonvey them
                            twice the distance to Reyak or Zahleh sta-
                            tions, and send them on by train to the ooast
                            Now that Hama is within fifteen hoars of
                            Beyront by rail it is natural that the ex-
                            port trade of the northern port should de-
                            cline very considerably.
                            The shipping of Haifa increased conside-
                            rably in 1904 owing to the frequent calls
                            of steamers carrying railway material for the
                            Haifa-Dera’a branch of the Hedjsz line, and the
                            fact that quarantine against Egypt was less
                            oontinnonB than in former yean. Neither Mr.
                            Drummond Hay nor Mr. Riohards make any
                            oommenta on the strange frequency with
                            whioh quarantine restrictions are imposed on
                            arrivals from Egypt in the summer months
                            of each year but we have a suspicion that
                            the Ottoman authorities are influenced by
                            other than sanitary considerations.
                            (To be continued.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                            <h2>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</h2>
                            <p>The Hon. L. Morris Iddings, new diplo-
                            matic agent and oonsol general for Amerioa,
                            will leave for the United Statee shortly, and
                            return to Egypt in November.</p>
                            <p>Leave of absenoe has been granted to Mr.
                            A. W. Hazel, inspector in the Ministry of the
                            Interior, from September 1 to November 5.</p>
                            <p>Sadik Bey Abaza, the well-known notable
                            of the Sharkieh province is leaving for Con-
                            stantinople to-day by the Khedivial mail boat.</p>
                            <p>"Theengagement is announced" writes M.A.P.
                            "of Miss Grace Blyth, daughter of Sir James
                            Blytb, and Captain Rome, of the 11th Hnssara.
                            The bride-eleot ia a pretty girl, rather small
                            aud dark, and has been seen abont with her
                            father at some of the smartest parties. It will
                            be remembered that her married sister, Mrs.
                            Alan Gardner, is among oor most noted So-
                            ciety sportswomen, and has gone after big
                            game in distant parts of the world. Her father,
                            Sir James Blyth, is one of onr riohest widowers.
                            He has a place in Essex, and a fine house in
                            Portland Place, where he gives dinners and
                            some beantifol oonoerts. He holds t£e Imperial
                            Order of Leopold from the Ring of the Bel-
                            gians, and the Order of the Medjidieh from the
                            Khedive, both oonfenred for his servioee to
                            agriculture. He is also deeply interested in
                            viticulture and dairy-farming, and has an eleo-
                            trio modal dairy at Blyth wood, his plaoe in
                            Braex. He writes and reads and is one of thoee
                            who oaks th« belt of life in town and country,"</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="4">
                    <h1>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>LANDING OF PASSENGERS.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)
                            Port Said, Tueeday.
                            Intending passengers to and from Egypt will
                            have pleasure in learning that today saw the
                            recommencement of the embarking and dis-
                            embarking servioe by the Canal Cos SB. Ibis,
                            whioh has been repaired and overhauled ready
                            for the ootniDg tourist season. She disembarked
                            today the passengers from the Caledonia, whioh
                            arrived from England and Marseille* at 4 p.m.</p>
                        <h2>THE AUSTRIAN MINISTER</h2>
                        <p>By the kind permission of thaCanal Company,
                            the Austrian Minister and his staff made an
                            interesting trip yesterday as far as lima ilia in
                            the.Company's steam launches. The Albatross
                            left, the Qoai Baganie jetty at 8 p m. and was
                            relieved by the Gotland at Kan tan, I believe,
                            to-whioh vessel the party there transferred.</p>
                        <h2>SUSPECTED INFANTICIDE.</h2>
                        <p>An Arab baby girl aged 18 months was
                            found drowned this morning, in the Freeh
                            Water Canal oloee to Kan tan station. Althoogh
                            there are no marks of violence on the body,
                            many things point to deliberate infanticide,and
                            I understand the polioe and sanitary authori-
                            ties are making an exhaustive enquiry.</p>
                        <h2>A NOTABLE PASSENGER</h2>
                        <p>The M.M. Yam whioh left here last night
                            had on board the Governor General of Reunion.</p>
                        <h2>FEVER AND SANITATION.</h2>
                        <p>The past few months have been somewhat
                            remarkable for the very large number of om
                            ot what is variously known as Malta fever,
                            Mediterranean fever, or dengue. The disease
                            has been of an almost epidemic character, and
                            bearing in mind its very weakening, not to my
                            dangerous, effects, should be oarefally consider-
                            ed by onr sanitary authorities. There have'
                            been several oaaee of late, many of whioh have
                            not recovered, even after two and three months
                            treatment The town itself is really in a very
                            filthy condition, and though I am aware of
                            the difficulties whioh the sanitary authorities
                            have to oontond with, I am of the opinion
                            that much might be done to improve the
                            present system of transport of sewage and the
                            like. I may add that these are also the
                            opinions of an eminent surgeon here, who, in
                            oonvenation, reoently remarked upon the larger
                            numbers than usual of Anopheles mosqaitie-
                            to be seen daily around Port Said, whioh he
                            says are very probably the’ means by whioh
                            the disease is propogatod.</p>
                        <h2>S.S. GIBRALTAR.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent).
                            Suez, Taesday.
                            After the reappearance of fire in the oargo
                            of sugar on board the SB. Gibraltar, No. 1
                            and 2 holds were flooded with water and the
                            vessel was-beached on the sand in abont 17
                            feet of water. The water is now being pumped
                            out Much of the cargo in the foreholdv is
                            destroyed by either the fire or water.</p>
                        <h2>NEW RED SEA LIGHTHOUSE.</h2>
                        <p>The new lighthouse on the island'of Diferein
                            (Italian territory in the Red Sea) will be
                            lighted for the first time on the 95th inst The
                            light will be visible at a distance of 18 miles.</p>
                        <h2>POUM BL KHALIG FESTIVAL.</h2>
                        <p>The annual oeremony of the catting of the
                            Khalig in celebration of the rise of the Nile
                            will, as previously announced, be held on
                            Saturday, whioh will be observed as a general
                            holiday, and will be presided over by H.E. the
                            aoting Regent, on whose arrival at Foam el
                            Khalig a salute of twenty-one guns will be fired,
                            and again on his departure. The oavalry baud
                            will be in attendance and will prooeed to the
                            soene of festivities by the dahafaeah Akafaa,
                            starting from the Bonlao Government Arsenal
                            at 8 p.m. The Altaba will be gaily dooo rated
                            for the occasion and will be illuminated at
                            night The festivities will ohiefly oonsist of
                            songs by leading Dative artistes, fireworks, and
                            military marie. A well supplied baffet will
                            be provided for the gneate of the Governor.</p>
                        <h2>HASHISH SEIZURE.</h2>
                        <p>In onr issue of yesterday we mentioned
                            that six tarbas of hashish had been found 1
                            in a sack of floor at the Costoms. A oarofol1
                            search waa made in the remaining floor sacks 1
                            stored, by Mohamed Effendi Bl Ghoriani, of
                            the Customs Administration who discovered 1
                            that no less than forty of tho saoks oon-1
                            tained from one to six tarbas of the drug, j
                            The consignment of flour has been seised
                            pending inquiries. It weiged 8,410 kilog. and :
                            oon tain od 116 tarbas of hashish weighing 1
                            149 J kilogrammes.</p>
                        <h2>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</h2>
                        <p>The Moss liner Men os arrived at Iiverpool
                            yesterday morning.
                            Thu Moss liner Seti sailed from Malta
                            yesterday afternoon, and is due here on Friday
                            tfternoon with passengers, mails, and general
                            oa%o.
                            The BA Oarib Prinoe left Miaratah yester-
                            day end is das to arrive at Alexandria on
                            Friday.</p>
                    </div>
                    

                </div>
                <div type="item" n="5">
                    <h1>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>AUSTRIAN COMMERCIAL ACTIVITY</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent).
                            Constantinople, August 16.
                            Austria-Hungary is at present making gnat
                            efforts to maintain her oommtroial position
                            sgainst the growing German competition in
                            the Near East, and to increase her trade,
                            mors especially in Turkey and the Balkan
                            states. The Salonika Bank toe ether with the
                            Linder Bank is about to create a new finan-
                            cial establishment, The Anstro-Bolgarian
                            Bank—with nnmeroos branches in the Beat
                            The Bankverein also proposes to open bran oh
                            establishments at Constantinople, Sofia, Alex-
                            andria and Salonika. The Creditanstalt of
                            Vienna also proposes to found establishments
                            for the sale of Austro-Hasgarian products,
                            under the title of the "Anstro-Oriental Com-
                            mercial Company” whioh will be managed by
                            M.M. Otto Horral and Wilhem Stem. Finally
                            we hear of an effort made by several Vien-
                            nese banks acting in combination to found a
                            new financial establishment destined to bring
                            Austria into closer economic relations with
                            Macedonia, Greeoe and Egypt</p>
                        <h2>THE ABYSSINIAN MISSIONS.</h2>
                        <p>General Mesheshia Warlrie, the ohief of the
                            Abyssinian mission, who is expected here in
                            a few days, visited the Armenian Patriarch
                            at Jerusalem, and presented him with an an-
                            tograph letter from the Negus Menriik, and
                            Austrian Emperor in the name of the Negni
                            a collection of very fine elephants tusks, whioh
                            are of great value. Hadji Abdallah has been1
                            deoorated fay the Bmperor-King with the
                            Cross of Commander of the Francis-Joseph
                            Order.</p>
                        <h2>TURKEY AND EGYPT.</h2>
                        <p>Preparations are already being made for
                            the visit of H.H. the Khedive, who is ex-
                            pected to arrive in the near futon. On the
                            other hand it is stated here, and I give the
                            statement for what it is worth, that the Valis
                            of the various Syrian ports have reoeived
                            secret instructions to prevent or hamper the
                            lauding of any of the numerous Egyptian
                            officials, who pass their holiday every year
                            in the Lebanon or near Damascus.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>M. JALUZOT’S RECENT LOSSES.</h2>
                        <p>The recent sensational crash in the French
                            o mmercial world brought about by the oolos-
                            sal losses of M. Jaluiot, the managing director
                            of the well-known Magasina du Prin temps of
                            Paris, by speculations in sugar, has been
                            causing some anxiety and much talk both in
                            Cairo and Alexandria. A large basineas is
                            done by the two branches established in Egypt,
                            amounting to several millions annually, the
                            profits from whioh are said to be no less than
                            £I0,0~0 a year. The Cairo branch only quite
                            recently moved into larger premises situated
                            in the Sharia Kasr-el-Nil, whioh have been
                            taken on lease for 12 years. We learn on
                            reliable authority that the failure of M. Jalnsot'
                            is not likely to affeot in any way the business
                            e ther in this ooontry or in Franoe, as his
                            private property is more than sufficient to
                            meet his loss of £600,000, caused by attempt-1
                            ing to oorner the sogar market, whioh, oontrary
                            t> all expectations, has been lately a falling
                            instead of a rising one, despite the shortage
                            in the beet crop on the Continent last season.</p>
                        <h2>DECOUVERTE ARCHEOLOGIQUE.</h2>
                        <p>A la dernikre sdanoe de l’aoad&nie frau;«iie
                            dee inscriptions et belles-lettres, M. la dootesr
                            Capitan a pr^entd en son nom et en oelni de
                            son oollaboreteor l’abbd Arnsnld d'Agnel, deux
                            oirtona de fort beaux ailex taillfe, identiquee
                            sur lee deox oartona.
                            Lea ailex d'un. dee oartona montrd k titre de
                            oomparaisqn sortent d’Bgypte et out lea formes
                            oaraoteristiqoes des si lex taillde Egyptians de
                            l’dpoque ntfolithique. Ceux de l'autre carton
                            out ritri tronvds, bien en plaoedans la sable, sor
                            lea llanos d’nn vallon, dans one petite He de la
                            Mlditerrande, 4 parrois abroptes, l'lle Rioo, 5
                            treize kilometres de Marseille et 4 trois kilo-
                            metres de la cflte de Proveooe. •	1
                            Ia superposition dee debris des diverse*
                            civilisations qui se sont aaoo6d6es en oe point
                            est la anivante. A la surface da so), poteriee
                            romaines abondantes ; an-deseons fragments
                            1 varide de oeramiqoee greeqaes; plus bos,
                            poteries figures; au-deesous, si!ex dgyptiens,
                            et plus has encore, amas de ocquilles marines
                            comestibles, debris de poteries neofithiques,
                            petits ailex trfcs different* des precedents et
                            deox petitea haohea polies das types Iooanx ;
                            ee sont dee "debris de outline” de Fhoorne
                            ndofithiqne.
                            On pent dooo dedoire de oes observations
                            que des populations aborigines miaerables de I
                            lYpoque neolithiqoe out, il y a oertainement t
                            plus da oinq mille ana, veou 4 Riou. Un pen .
                            plus tard, des Egyptians prehiatoriqnes aont I,
                            venus dans l'lle oh ils out laissd quelqoes-nns
                            delean beaux si lex tallies oaracteristiqase-Des
                            Ligures ont ensaite sejourne en oe point, pais
                            des Greos y sont venue, laissant ohaoun dee
                            debris de lenr oeramique ; enfin dee Remains
                            y sont rest4e asses longtampe, abandoonaat de
                            trie nombreux fragments du potarias. Eosuite
                            iln’ya plus, en oe point, aaoune trace de
                            l’homme anx dpoques ultdrieufs.
                            Cert la premiers fois qn’on signals la cfcoou-
                            verte bien en plaoe de iQsx tallies dmtteial
                            suteWndsleorpayd'origiDe.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="6">
                    <h1>SPORT AND PLAY.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CRICKET</h2>
                        <p>B. T. C. v. SERGEANT hURKJTS XL
                            This match waa played on the A.C.C. ground
                            yesterday and resulted in a win for Sgt.
                            Burke’s teams by five runs. The latter battel
                            first, and were all out for 97, Graves being
                            highest aoorar with 42. The RT.C.'s fielding
                            was not good, runs being thrown away oarw
                            lemly, and oatohes bring dropped. For the
                            B.T.C. Byrne played wrii for 22 (top soon),
                            G. MoLean being the only other batsman
                            t) reach double figures. For the winners
                            Gunner Davis bowled well, and Dawson be-
                            hind the stumps was very good, stamping two
                            Mr. Thurston	7	2	21
                            „ Byrne	13	8	45
                            „ R. MoLean	8	2	20
                            „ Blythman __	8.1 JL1	0 P.C.	4
                            
                            
                            Sergeant Fuller, b. MoLeen... '... ...
                            Gonnsr Davis, & and b. Byrne.
                            Mr. P. P. Graves, b. McLean ________
                            „ R J. Dawson, b. Byrne— ...........
                            Corporal Burgess, o. and b. McLean...
                            8ergeant Burke, o. Blythman. b. Byrne
                            Corporal New, b. Thunton............
                            Private Swan, a Lees, b. Thurston...
                            n Slade, b. Blythman............
                            Corporal Weaver, a Byrne, b. Blythman
                            Gnoner Pryar, not out...............
                            Total...
                            B.T. C. Bowling.
                            Oven Maidens Rons Wiokets
                            Mr.	Chessman, Lb.w., b. Burke...	2
                            ,,	Byrne, b. Davis.............. 22
                            „	Harrison, b. Davis........... 8
                            „	R. MoLean, et Dawson, b.	Davis	5
                            „	G. MoLean, o. Dawson, b. Davit...	14
                            „	Blythman, b. Graves.......... 8
                            „	Henley, o. and b. Davis...... 2
                            „	Millar, si Dawson, b. Davis	...	5
                            „	Collier, not ont ... — ............. 8
                            „	Thurston, o. Burke, b. Davis..	8
                            „	Lees, b. Graves ... ................ 5
                            Total......... 92
                            Sbroiaht Burin's XL Bowling.
                            Overs Maidens Rons Wiokets
                            Mr. Graves	13.8	5	20	2
                            Bgt Burke	8	0	19	1
                            Gnr. Davis	10	0	44	7</p>
                        
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>LETTER TO THE EDITOR.</h2>
                        <h2>BATHING FATALITIES.</h2>
                        <p>To The Editor or the Egyptian Gazette.
                            Sir,—It is distressing to know that anothe
                            death by drowning took plaoe yesterday after
                            noon at Ramleh.
                            The victim in this oase was a young nativi
                            who had gone to bathe at the Ibrahimis!
                            baths. He had gone for a swim and ventured
                            farther oat than he should have done, when
                            the strong undercurrent prevented him
                            from getting book, and he was drowned.
                            Notwithstanding his struggle* and arise fin
                            help, no one, I am informed, attempted to ran
                            him although there were many persons in the
                            baths and on the beach at the time.
                            No doubt had the proprietor of the baths i
                            boat, life buoy, or fine in stook (whioh in mj
                            opinion should bo made compulsory for them
                            to have, when they reoeive their license) the
                            poor fellow might have probably been raved.
                            May I ask whether it oouldnot beporai
                            ble for a policeman to patrol the beaoh, and
                            prevent people bathing in dangerous pkras.
                            Con Id not a life baoy and line be placed
                            in charge ol the pofioeman, so that it oould
                            be easily got at, and thereby render imme-
                            diate oasis tanoe possible I
                            I may also mention that hundreds of people
                            bathe on the beach at Ibmhimieh. mostly
                            women and children,	«uA annoyenoe is
                            given to bathers, at tubes, by young Natives
                            and others, and there ia not a single policeman
                            there to keep order, or prevent a breach of the
                            peTtirust you will kindly find space in the
                            columns of your wall-oiroulated paper far thi*
                            appeal to theauthorities, in order that measures
                            may be taken to prevent as for as possible
                            suoh a lamentable toes of fife, and to ensure the
                            public security in the future. I am. Sir, etc.,
                            OBSERVER.
                            Alexandria, August 28.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advertisement"></div>
                    <div type="advertisement"></div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>