<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, MAY 17, 1905.</head>
<div type="item"><p>AMERICAN TRADE IN EGYPT.
VICE-CONSUL MORGAN’S REPORT.
( Continued from Saturday.)
In compliance with the Department circular,
I sent out a series of questions to those dealing
in American goods, and interviewed many,
and I give herewith a summary ot reports
received and results of inquiries made verbally
on the commercial relations between the
United States and Egypt:
(t) Are American manufacturers amenable to
suggestions made from Egypt 1
The general experience is that they are not,
and that they rather resent suggestions. This
applies especially to the machinery trade.Uulike
British manufacturers, the Americans refuse
to guarantee their goods, contenting themselves
by saying “the machines do the work we claim
for them in this country (the United States),”
and then proceed to put idiomatic expressions
into their letters which are, in many cases,
beyond the linguistic attainments of the in-
tending agent or purchaser. One manufacturer
lost a market for his "cultivators” owing to
the springs carrying the body of the machine
not being strong enough to properly support
the machine when crossing the irrigation
channels, with which all fields in Egypt are
intersected. In reply to the suggestion made
to strengthen the springs, he said that the
machines were not made to “jump ditches.”
'These ditches are rillets of but 3 or 3 inches
deep. Suggestions as to "finish” of certain
wearing parts are as regularly scouted as they
are made, as are also suggestions about modi-
fications to make the machines more adaptable
to the peculiar agricultural conditions of the
country, the nature of the soil, etc. British
manufacturers have long had the reputation
ot acting in precisely a similar manner as that
now attributed to Americans, but I have it
from a gentleman returned from the United
States, which he visited for the sole purpose
of inducing manufacturers to introduce certain
modifications in their agricultural machinery
which were essential to their efficient working
in Egypt, that he simply lost his time and
money, and returning east he offered his sug-
gestions to a British manufacturer, who at
once took up the business. The purchaser is
paying 30 per cent, more for his machines, but
he gets what he requires,and also the guarantee
for working efficiency, which the American
manufacturers refuse. The coming market in
Egypt is that for machinery, and it is needless
to point out that all descriptions of machinery
are referred to.</p>
<p>(2) Are orders sent direct to the manu-
facturers or through European agents 1
It is seldom that any one repeats the ex-
periment of sending a direct order to the ;
United States. The invariable rule is "cash 1
with order,"and the general impression here is,
that once he has the cash, the American manu-
facturer troubles himself little as to when or '
in what condition the goods reach their destin-
ation. Even where credit is given the bills ]
mature long before the arrival of the goods
and the purchaser has practically no remedy
for loss owing to delays, broaching of cargo in ‘
transhipment, deterioration on voyage, and loss '
of a market demand, which, meanwhile, has ‘
been satisfied from elsewhere. Fifty-two days 1
would, as a rule, appear to be the quickest (
time in which a direct order from the United 1
States might be completed by the arrival of \
the goods here. In the case of perishable goods '
it would be safe to say that a second direct 1
order is never sent—as the buyer must risk 1
total loss—for it has happened that consign-
ments of an alimentary nature have arrived '
from the United States in such condition that '
they have had to be destroyed by the health
authorities, and although the instances may be '
few, their effect is very widespread.
Id some instances orders sent direct to '
manufacturers in the United States are sent by 1
the manufacturers to agents in Europe for
execution as a consequence of some arrange-
ment for exclusive agencies being granted for
particular zones. The system gives rise to
dissatisfaction here, but the consequences to
American trade are far more serious than
would at first appear. It is with no little
trepidation that I transmit for the information
of American manufacturers the following, as,
from my personal knowledge, I cannot vouch
for what is related to me as fact, but it is for <
those directly interested to make the necessary i
inquiries into the subject and see about setting |
their houses in order:	
“'The system of filling orders through Con- <
tinental agencies is a gratuitous indication as i
to where a new market is springing up, and no j
sooner has an American article made its way |
and created a demand than a cheap imitation i
produced elsewhere is thrown on the market,
the cards and packing being so gotten up that i
the inexpert buyer sees no difference.”
The person from whom I obtained this in- i
formation made no complaint about the
system. He really seemed to be amused at the
idea that the Yankees, considering themselves
to "cute,” should not have detected what was
going on. It was a matter of indifference to
him where the goods were produoed; he
supplied a demand and made his profits in
doing so, and it was not his afiair to suggest
any change in the existing order of things.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>MAGASINS VICTORIA.
ECCLESTONE AND KEILL
ENGLISH DRAPERY.
NOTES FROM ASS10UT.
ADVOCATE STRUCK OFF THE ROLL
(From oob Correspondent).
Assiout, May 13.
The council of discipline for advocates gave
judgment this week striking the name of
Mikhail Eff. Hanna Sarabanah off the roll of
advocates practising in the Native Tribunals.
He was accused of having spent £2 (which had
been given to him by one of his clients for
Court fees) for his own purposes. He denied
that be had received the money, but the fact
was proved by his own handwriting. He has
appealed against the judgment</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>A BRIDGE WANTED.
In a few days we shall have the new build-
ing for the Moudirieh ready. It is a very large
edifioe situated on the Nile S.E, of Assiout
Consequently, all Government offioes will be
situated in El Hamra, on the Nile bank. El
Hamra is a small village separated from
Assiout by the railway lino. At present we have
the Court, the TanzimOffice,theSurveyDepart-
ment, the Irrigation Department, the Reservoir
offices, and in a short time we shall have the
Moudirieh, the GovernmentSchool, the Techni-
cal School, etc., all situated in H amra. Therefore
traffic between Assiout to Hamra will increase.
As it is, a good many people have to cross the
railway line, and very oiten the station gates
are closed owing to trains passing. Frequently
people have to wait half an hour for the opening
of the gates, notwithstanding that they may
have urgent business.</p>
<p>A petition has now been sent to the Railway
Administration asking for a bridge to be
constructed in the Hamra road over the railway
line to enable foot passengers to cross at any
LETTERS to the editor.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>INFANT MORTALITY IN EGYPT.
To ins Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir,—The recent correspondence in your
columns must have led many persons to believe
that Egypt was the only country in which
infants were sacrificed to maternal ignorance or
negligence, and that if Egyptian mothers could
be trained or coerced to bring up their off-
spring in the enlightened methods prevalent
in other countries a vast wastage of infant
lives would be saved. As an Egyptian I had
my doubts whether things were really much
worse in this respect in Egypt than in other
countries, but as our mentors were so positive
in their statements, I hesitated to intervene in
the discussion. From the “Graphic” of April
15th I, however, cull the following paragraph,
which will I think show that there is room for
missionary work among mothers even in Eng-
land. Perhaps it would be advisable to print
the paragraph in very small type, as I should
be sorry to shook any susceptibilities :—
"Would that the mothers of the lower
classes could learn a little about the moral and
physical natures of their unfortunate little
ones ! With all the boasted spread of educa-
tion, the mothers still feed their poor children
on the most unsuitable food, still forget that
milk,and milk only, is the natural nourishment
for babies, and ic consequence, infant mortal-
ity continues to increase in frightful propor-
tions. At an inquest held last week it was
proved that a woman had fed her baby on
•boiley,' or ground biscuits, a food which the
doctor declared could not be digested by any
child under twelve months old. Think of the
waste of life, the suffering, the expense entail-
ed by this crass ignorance of the most common
maternal duty, and let us not brag or pride
ourselves on our system of education until the
mothers of England have ceased to murder
their children by slow and deliberate starva-
tion.”
Yours, etc.,
An Egyptian.
Cairo, May 14.</p></div>
<div type="item">PUMPS IN EGYPT.
To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir,—Any discussion as to the relative merits
of pumps is perfectly useless when based on
mere assertions. The sole test is ooal consump-
tion and water lifted. Unfortunately, reliable
figures do not exist, and to obtain them
quite a staff of trained men is needed to
measure coal and water used by boilers, read
gauges, and take discharges and lift for water
pumped ; all of Which must be done simul-
taneously and for a period of six hours on end.
The Government returns for Mex pumping
station give the general results for the year,
but there are no figures which would be
accepted by technical men as conclusively
establishing the relative efficiency of Farcot
and Gwynne. Till these figures can be pro-
duced the pumps, in golfer’s phrase, are "Like
as they lie” and their respective advocates
may lie as they like.—I am, eto.,
An Apprentice.
Alexandria, May 14.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SPORT AND PLAY.
FOOTBALL.
M. M. F. v. Inniskilling Corporals.
For the fourth time this season the above
teams met at Abbassieh in a friendly enoounter
on Friday last. The match drew a large crowd
of spectators. The police set the ball in
motion. For a time the exchanges were very
eveD, each side attacking in turn. Russell took
a corner, the first of the match, but sent
behind. A second followed, but like the
previous one, it went behind. This half was
greatly in favor of the boys, and they time
after t:we pressed the police custodian, but all
to no avail as Broadhurst was in good form.
A neat centre by Russell looked well and
Rafferty just missed the goal by inches. Oh
the kick-off the police attacked and good play
by Carter ended in Hopkins drawing first
blood. Rafferty resumed operations and David-
son had a run all to himself and centred well.
Rafferty had a pot at goal, the custodian
conceding a corner. In saving this was well
taken, the goal being cleared for a moment,
but R&fferty found the ball at his feet a few
yards out and with an unsavable grounder
made the scores equal Play after this became
even. The police now took play in hand and
the outside left getting a timely pass added
number two. Excitement was at a great height
just now. Rafieuy, getting on a single-handed
run, ran through all opposition and passed
to Davidson, who equalised the game
onoe more. Aiken amused the spectators by
some fancy work. Edgar was now playing a
good game and checked the left wing time
after time, play being somewhat exciting until
Russell broke away, but Wingate returned in
grand style. From this until half-time play
was of a very even nature. Shortly after half-
time was announced with the soore:
Corporals Inniskillings Abbassieh oontingent
2 goals.</p>
<p>Military Mounted Police 2 goals.
After the usual interval both teams re-
sumed. The police at once assumed the
aggressive. For sometime play was within
goal's range but Carter shot wide. On the
cick-off Ciee got possession and dodged a
couple of opponents and gave to Russell,
who sent a smart grasshopper in to the cus-
todian, who fell on the ball, but Wingate
managed to dear. Hopkins now showed to
advantage and after dribbling the ball well
up he gave to Field, who was ruled off-
side. Tho representatives of Ireland now
forced several corners, all to no purpose. The
polioe attacked the right wing. They however
wore scut back by Behan, who was in good
form. The service oompauies now asserted
themselves and Rafferty came through all
by himself, but he shot against the custodian
and immediatdy afterwards the ball hit the
upright The police attacked in strong foroe
but Murray was not called upon. The Ab-
bassieh contingent pulled themselves together
and forced two comers in quick succession,
and although pressing strongly they were
unable to penetrate the M. M. P.’s defense.
Broadwood was asked after this to save
from Davidson, which he did well Ireland
now had a spell of attacking, Rafferty
putting in several nice cross-shots, each of
which the custodian saved in good style. The
Inniskillings played the better football, but
there was little to chose between them in points
of attack. Cree and Russell were continually
aggressive and forced another comer, which
came to nothing. The Inniskillings still pressed
and another comer fell to them, but to no
purpose. The police now had an innings but
did not stop loDg, as Behan and Supple were
playing a cool and steady game and returned,
lafferty who was playing a splendid game, got
possession and led his forwards away. Cree
raced up the field and gave to Russell, who
with a rapid shot put his side ahead. Nothing
further of any importance occurred up to full
time, the score being:
Corporals Inniskillings Abbassieh Contin-
gent 2 goals.
Military Mounted Polioe 2 goals.
M. A. Lyons officiated as referroe.</p>
<div type="item"><p>ARMY AND NAYY.
(From odb Correspondent).
London, May 8.
On the 14th of July next Colonel and Chief
Paymaster T. 8. Coppinger, A. P. D., Distriot
Paymaster in Egypt, will go on retired pay
under the age rules. Colonel Coppinger, who
is one of the few purchase officers now serving,
joined the army nearly 40 years ago, and was
transferred to the A. P. D. in 1876. Whilst
paymaster of the 24th Regiment he saw servioe
m the Zulu War of 1879 (medal with clasp).
His impending retirement will be learned with
regret by his many friends in the land of the
Pharaohs.</p>
<p>Captain C. Pierce, Royal Berkshire Regi-
ment, on promotion, has been re-appointed to
the 1st Battalion at Dublin.
Lieutenant Charles Howard, 1st Battalion
RoyaUBerkahire Regiment, who was returned
for trial to Dublin City Sessions for an alleged
assatm on the polioe, failed to turn up at the
Sessions last Saturday. His bail bonds were
ordered to be estreated and a warrant was
issued for his arrest It was stated in court
that Mr. Howard, who had sent in his papers
some time ago, had gone abroad, to Canada it
Intelligence from Eequimalt, B.C., states
that at the recent sale of Admiralty stores,
consequent on the reduction of the Pacific
Squadron, very low prices were realised. For
instance, 102 torpedo nets, which ooet £40
each, were sold for £2 ; 1,500 ooaling baskets
only realised £1 4s., 176 zino-lined oordite
boxes went for £5, and other stores realised
comparative trifles. The Admiralty set a
reserve price on the large store of anchors and
chains, to purchase which a Yankee ring came
all the way from San Francisco.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>Calendar of Coming Events
ALEXANDRIA.
May.
Wed 17 Alhambra. Italian operetta com-
pany. 9 p.m.
Fri. 18 A. S. C. grounds. Tennis match.
K. S. C. V. A. a c.
Sat 20 Race from Sidi Gaber to Alexandria
by pupils ot Scotch SchooL 6a.m.
A. C. C. grounds. Crioket Gar-
rison XI t>. A C. C. 1.30 p.m.
Mustapha Rifle Range. Practice
by B. R. C. 2.30 p.m.
San Stefano Casino. Opening Ball
of Season. 10 p.m.
Sun. 21 San Stefano Casino. Concert 10 a.m.
Gabbari. Pigeon Shooting. 2.30 p.m.
Tubs. 23 San Stefano Casino. A. L. M. &
D. S. Conoert 9.15 p.m.
Thurs. 25 A. S. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting.
Sat 27	A. S. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting.
OAI RO.
May.
Fri. 19 Zoological Gardens. Performance by
Ghixeh Boys’ Band in afternoon.
Shepheard’s Hotel. Meeting of
K. G. 8. 5 p.m.
Esbekieh Gardens. Performance
by British Military Band. 9 to
11 p.m.
Tues. 23 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
British Military Band. 9 to 11
p.m.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ALDERSON’S CARDER, BULKELEY.
In oonsequence of extensive alterations to the
theatre in Aldereon’s Garden, the theatre will be
dosed all this month.	25696-81-3-906
Opposite Aostrian Oon>nlate, near the
piiitii Theatre. Catalogue on applied ion
British Chamber of Commerce.—We would
call the attention of persons interested in J
Egyptian trade to the work of the British
Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, whose office
in Alexandria gives information asto standings '
trade, &a, to its members, and whose monthly1
publication reviews our commeroe. The annual
subscription is £1 and all British traders should
become members. Our London office, 86, New
Broad- street RO., sots as London agency to
Um Canto.</p></div>	
<div type="item"><p>HALLS
Sanitary
• Washable
THIS OILS SRATEO
WATCH PA RT
IS MADE IN TWO
QUALITIES FOR
INSIDE AND
OUTSIDE WORK.
DISTEMPER
HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER
is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70
artistic tints, and only requires the addition
of water to make It ready for use. It Is
quickly and easily applied with a whitewash
brush, with half the labour and at one third
the cost of paint. HALL’S DISTEMPER
ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing^ to the
eye. It appeals alike to artistic and praotical
house decoration.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>HALL'S DI8TEMPER I* of apodal value In hot
climates. Owing to Its cool, pleasing colours,
great weather-reacting and germ-destroying
vTBr properties. It lends Itself to every kind of
wall, wood, brlok or stone coating, pot-
^	seising all the advantages of paint, oolour-
wash, and disinfectant at one third the cost
of oil paint It never blisters In the hottest
iJmlF- sun. and the fact that It oan be washed
add* greatly to Its sanitary advantages.
supplied m rima add mom kcob.
sttBC,	tel* Manufacturer*-
SISSONS BROTHERS It C0„ LTD., HULL
wtiwCL :	Bioc)LB an bald In- Oalra br Frank RatelUte, BanlMrr
Contractor a EngUMar, Shari* HapUoh.
iraSeP® In Alexandria by Knnaadaa Tl—eaf, Sanitary
=“=*	ganNalArffn.oV^MerrUMQn,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>HOSPITAL SECRETS
A Nurse Says! "Pe-ru-na 1$ i
Tonic of Efficiency.”
Mrs. Kata Taylor, a graduated
nurse ot prominence, gives bar ex-
perience with Peruna In an open
letter. Her position In society and
professional standing combine to
give special prominence to bet
utterances.</p></div>
<div type="item">CHICAGO, ILL, VO Monroe Street,—
“A* far as I have observed, Peruna
la the nnest tonic any man or woman
ran ua* who is weak from the after
effects of any serious Illness.
“Peruna seems to restore vitality.
Increase bodily vigor and renew health
and strength In a wonderfully short
time."—MRS. KATE TAYLOR.
Address The Poruns Medicine Co,
Colnmhua, Oh lo, if you desire free liter*
ture oircatarrh.</p>
<p>For special directions everyone
should read “The Ills of Life," a oopy
of whioh surrounds eaoh bottle. Peru-
na is for sale by all chemista and
druggists at five shillings per bo ties
or sue bottles for twenty-five shillingt
Those wishing direct correspond-
ence with Dr. Hartman and can wait
the necessary delay in requiring a
reply should address Dr. 8. B. Hart
man, Columbus, Ohio, U.8.A.
The following wholesale druggist
will supply the retail drug trade in
Alexandria, Egypt</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>MAX FISCHER,
Cairo and Alexandria, Egypt.
CHAMPAGNE
GEORGE GOULET.
BT SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO
HIS MAJESTY THE KING.
REIMS.
SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,
NICOLA G. SABBAG
ALEXANDRIA,
a, Rue de la Oars du Cairo'
Telephone No. 0S9.
Societe Internationale des Employes
D’ALEXANDRIE
SiioE Social : Roe MoequfiE Attarinb No. 21
BUREAU DE PLACEMENT
Offrbs d’emplois
BONNE MAISON d’Alexandrie domande :
1.	on employd oonnaisaant bien 1* Mercerie.
2.	an jeune homme eide-vendear.
Demand es
Comptable pr. Le Cairo saobant bien la Comp-
tabilitd et oonnaisaant l’Anglais.
Comptable pr. Le Cairo aveo connaissanoes en
langues.
Comptable pr. Fort-Said aveo oonnaissanoes en
N.B.—Ponr tons renseignementa s’adresser
soit dirootement, soit par lettre au Siftge Social
de la Sooidtd, Rue Mosqude Attarine No.21.
Le Secretariat eetouvert les Lundi, Meroredi
et Vendredi de 7 h. 1/2 k 8 h. 1/2 du soir.
Les insertions oi-dessns soot (kites gratoite-
ment par les soins de la Socidtd et seals, lee</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>INNSBRUCK-TYROL.
Ideal Spring and Summer Resort. Beautiful
promenades and mountain excursions.
HOTEL TYROL.
1st Class Hotel, enlarged lately with an ex-
tensive palatial addition with every modern
oomfort.
pampSet on Innsbruok/rs* from proprietor i l
I OARL LAND8EE.
1	85609 40-19</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>DAVIES
BRYAN
& Co.
Continental Hotel Buildings.
CAIRO,
St. David's Buildings,
ALEXANDRIA,
and 35 - 37 Noble Street
LONDON, B.O.
English Tailors
Drapers
and Outfitters.
Beg respectfully ;to an-
nounce that they have
received their various
stocks in the latest
styles suitable for the
present Season.
A large assortment of
Blacks, Blues, Scotch,
Irish & Harris Tweeds.
All garments cut by ex-
perienced English Cut-
ters, fit and style gua-
ranteed.
A varied stock of
Ladies’ Blonses, Boas,
Skirts, Belts, &e.
Careful attention is
paid to Ladies’outfits
the Nile.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>GENTS’
OUTFITTING:
Collars, Shirts, Gloves, &o.
Hosiery in all the newest
makes, (Camel Heir brand
a speciality).
We are making a special display
in the Drapery Department, con-
sisting of Household Linen, Blan-
kets, Calicoes, Eider-down Quilts,
Cushions, Ao.,Ao., which are mark-
ed at such figures aa to command
attention.
Boots & Shoes in the latest
shapes, Bags, Trunks <& all
Leather goods in great va-
riety.
A] bo a large assorted supply of the
following articlee:—
HATS, CAPS, UMBRELLA8,
WALKING-STICKS, RUGS. 9
STUDS, BRUSHES AND ALL
TOILET REQUI8ITE8, AC.
Davies Bryan & Co.
Cairo & Aleandrii</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

