<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Riley Ouellette</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-18">April 18, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. PREPARING FOR FIGHT JAPS CAPTURE COLLIERS.</head>
                    <p>Hanoi, April 17. </p>
                    <p>The Baltic Fleet in Kninaranh Bay included battleships and 6
                        cruisers.{Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Saigon, April 17.</p>
                    <p>Admiral De Jotiquier, on board the cruiser “Descartes," has gone to Kamaranh.
                        A French steamer steamer also left with a cargo of provisions for tho Baltic
                        Fleet. - {Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>St.Petersberg, April 17.</p>
                    <p>The Russians are elated at the daring and skill of Rodjestvensky, and state
                        that he is coaling and clearing his fleet at Kamaranh prior to engaging the
                        Japanese ( Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>Tokio, April 17.</p>
                    <p>The Japanese have captured a large number of celliers off the coast of
                        Vladivostok, which is now free from ice. (Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>Saigon, April 17. </p>
                    <p>The Japanese have captured some colliers. {Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN NAVY.</head>
                    <p>Isabuan (Borneo), April 17. The American' destroyers “Barry” and “Chauncey”
                        have arrived here and are proceeding to join the cruiser "Raleigh” (Reuter))
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN REFORM. CONFERENCE TO BE HELD.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 17. The Constitutional Conservative Party, which is now
                        being termed in Russia, includes 7 members of the Council of the Empire
                        besides Senators and prominent Government officials. The party is
                        countenanced by M. Bnliguine and is issuing several thousand invitations
                        throughout Russia for a Conference to be held in St. Petersburg on tho
                        subject of reform. A scheme for the composition of a representative Assembly
                        has already boon drawn up. (R) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL CRUISE. ARRIVAL AT ALGIERS.</head>
                    <p>Algiers, April 17:</p>
                    <p>The King and Queen on of England have landed. The town was lavishly decorated
                        with French and British flags. Their Majesties have paid a visit to the
                        Governor General and will remain here till Wednesday. They are motoring in
                        the neighbourhood. (Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>Algiers, April 17. </p>
                    <p>The English Sovereigns lunched with the Governor.<persName>
                            ref="refhttps://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_VII">King Edward</persName>
                        has conferred the Grand Cross of the Victorian Order on M. Jonnart. (Hamas)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MACEDONIA. A STATE OF ANARCHY.</head>
                    <p>Sofia, April 17.</p>
                    <p>The following is evidence of the condition of tilings in Macedonia. A Greek
                        band attacked and destroyed the Bulgarian village of Zagoritchani, killing
                        most of the inhabitants and carrying off the remainder into the mountains.
                        The Bulgarians in revenge attacked a monastery near Klissurs. The Greeks
                        arrived and a fight ensued. 15 Bulgarians were killed, (R.) </p>
                    <p>Prisrend, April 17. </p>
                    <p>The Turks killed 30 Albanians in a fight near the town.(Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ITALIAN RAILWAY STRIKE. </head>
                    <p>Troops working traffic. Rome, April 17. A general strike has begun on the
                        Italian railways. The men object to disciplinary measures, tending to
                        curtail their rights to strike, being inserted in the Government Bill by
                        which the State will take over the railways Troops are working the traffic.
                        (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH STRIKE DISTURBANCES.</head>
                    <p>Limoges, April 17.</p>
                    <p>In a conflict between the strikers and the troops two workmen wore killed.
                        (Hamas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Eastern Telegraph Coy. Ltd </p>
                    <p>AVERAGE TIME occupied in transmission of Egyptian telegrams from England to
                        Alexandria on Monday, 17th April, 1905. outwards. Between hours of 10 a.m
                        and 6 p.m. (Cairo time)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>FROM London……………. 18 41 Liverpool…………… 15 27 Manchester……………. 20 1.12
                        Glasgow……………… — — Other provincial offices — 88 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WAR. JAPANESE ATTACKED. FLANKS ENVELOPED</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 17.</p>
                    <p>Linievitch reports that the Russian left, on tho 11th inst. attacked the
                        village of Pon-houl, 5 miles to the east of Meian. They enveloped tho flanks
                        of the Japanese, who retired to Meian, from which they had advanced to a
                        post on the Kirin road. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The New Station at Benha was opened for traffic on Saturday last at 6 a m.
                        The Plague .—During last week, only one case of plague was reported
                        throughout Egypt this occurred in the Toukh district. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The River Club Dinner will bè held tonight at Shepheard’s at 8 o’clock, to be
                        followed by a general meeting of the club. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Exiles.—Two Europeans wore expelled the country to day by the Alexandria
                        Goavernorat, agreement with their consular authorities. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fatal Accident. — A native boy of 16. employed in a paper mill on tho
                        Mahmoudieh Canal, got his arms entangled in the machinery yesterday and was
                        killed on the spot. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Port Arthur Garrison.—A number of Russian officers and men arrived at
                        Alexandria, yesterday from Far East, via Port Said, and will leave on Friday
                        for Odessa by the S.S. "Impeiator Nicholas II." </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The New Station at Benha was opened for traffic on Saturday last at 6 a m.
                        The Plague .—During last week, only one case of plague was reported
                        throughout Egypt this occurred in the Toukh district. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The River Club Dinnthrough the Canal on the 14th inst. 7 of which were
                        British, 1 French, 1 Spanish, 1 Egyptian. The receipts for the day wore frs.
                        299,996.86, making a total from the 1st inst. of frs. 4,478,554.54. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Saida Zeynab quarter of Cairo during
                        the night of Wednesday and dawn of Thursday, and in the Boulac district
                        during tho night of Thursday and dawn of Friday, will be poisoned by the
                        police. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>England in Egypt.—England is doing great things for Egypt, and its work
                        promises to make the Nile valley the seat of a new civilization which, if
                        less picturesque than the old one, will contribute vastly more to human
                        well-being and happiness.—"New York Times”. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Garrison Church of St. George,Mustapha Pasha. — To-morrow ( Wednesday ) and
                        on Good Friday there will be a picture service, illustrating the Passion and
                        Crucifixion of Jesus Christ, together with prayers and hymns, at 6 p.m. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>White Slave Traffic.—The recently appointed committee formed for the purpose
                        of repressing the “white slave traffic” in Egypt will meet at the Alexandria
                        Gouvomorat tomorrow at 5 p.m. in order to discuss certain proposals, and to
                        elect an executive committee from their number. H.E. the Governor will
                        preside. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Police and Dogs.—A correspondent writes: The following incident took at
                        Ibrahimieh on Friday last, on which day the police cart was there both
                        morning and afternoon. An Englishman was driving with an Arab by his side
                        while two other men, one a Greek, the other an Arab, were in the cart An
                        invalid German lady resident was standing at the door of her house watching
                        her little dog, who was being given a short run and within call, when the
                        dog was lassoed by the two men and put in tho cart. The lady cried out, and
                        although unable to do much, tried to stop the cart and recover her pet. The
                        driver whipped up his horses and she was thrown the ground. However, she got
                        up and bold the bridle of one horse. Again the driver used his whip and the
                        plucky lady was hit across the hands. Ultimately she succeeded in recovering
                        the dog. The animal had been fully under her control, and the action of the
                        police was quite unjustifiable." </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GOLDENCROSS LINE. FOR CARDIFF AND BRISTOL DIRECT.</head>
                    <p>The fast steamer “Venedotian" will arrive on or about the 17th April and will
                        have room for about 1,400 tons of cargo. - For Freight and references,
                        please apply to Alice Nimnim , Marina, Alexandria. 26780-3-8</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TYROL ..Weissenstein Castle 3410 ft. First-class private hotel near
                        windisch-Matrei ; Station, loans (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                        mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September.
                        Prospectuses and Photographs, " Egyptian Gazette " office, Cairo. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>
                        LORD
                        CROMER’S REPORT. PUBLISHED IN LONDON. THE CAPITULATIONS. ATTITUDE OF KHEDIVE</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London, April 17,</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer’s annual Report on Egypt and the Sudan, which has been published,
                        is of great' interest. He dwells on the necessity of modifying the regime of
                        the Capitulations, more especially in the direction of devising an improved
                        scheme for legislation where Europeans are concerned. </p>
                    <p>He alludes to the rapid growth of the Sudan revenue, and points out that,
                        exclusive of capital expenditure, the cost of the Sudan to Egypt in 1904
                        only amounted to LE. 27,000. He states that the attitude of the Khedive has
                        contributed to establish the most friendly relations between tho British and
                        Egyptian portions of the Administration, and speaks in complimentary terms
                        of tho action of the Legislative Council and Assembly. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLISH IN THE COURTS.</head>
                    <p>The following is the text of the decree issued recognizing English as one of
                        the official languages of the Mixed Courts :— Vu le Règlement d’organisation
                        judiciaire pour les procès mixtes en Egypte ; Après accord intervenu entre
                        Notre Gouvernement et les Puissances qui ont adhéré à-la Réforme Judiciaire
                        ; Sur la proposition de Notre Ministre de la Justice et l’avis conforme db
                        Notre Conseil des Ministres ; * </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DECRETONS</head>
                    <p>Article Premier.</p>
                    <p>L’artic’e 16, titre I, du’ Règlement d’organisation judiciaire est modifié
                        oomme suit : ‘Article 16 —Les langues judiciaires employées devant le»
                        Tribunaux pour les plaidoiries et la rédaction des actes et sentences sontj
                        l’arabe, l’anglais, le français et l’italien.’’ Art. 2. Cotte disposition
                        entrera en vigueur un ois après la publication qai en tera faite dans les
                        formes prévues par varticle 35, titre I, du Règlement d’organisation
                        judioiaire. Art. 3. Notre Ministre de la Justice est chargé de l'exécution
                        du présent décret.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MINISTRY OF JUSTICE</head>
                    <p>Ibrahim Pasha Fuad, Minister of Justice, will leave in a few days for
                        Carlsbad. The Minister will take three months' leave in Europe this year.
                        His functions will be performed during his absence by Boutros Pasha Ghali.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WAKFS ADMINISTRATION.</head>
                    <p>We hear that H. H. tho Khedive has not yet accepted the resignation of Abd el
                        Halim .Pasha Assem, Director General of tho Wakfs Administration, and that
                        the Pasha will probably retain his post till the end of the year. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspohdert).</p>
                    <p>Suez Monday.</p>
                    <p>Up to date over half of the Egyptian pilgrims have returned to their homes
                        from the Holy Places, and the remainder are expected to arrive shortly at
                        Suez from Tor. Out of 14,340, which was the total number of Egyptian
                        pilgrims who left, this year, over 8,300 have already returned, and their
                        health is very satisfactory. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH CRUISER AT SUEZ.</head>
                    <p>Suez, Monday.</p>
                    <p>The relief crew for the French cruiser “En-fernet” arrived at Suet yesterday
                        from Marseilles by the M. M. steamer "Melbourne. The homeward-bound officers
                        and men will return to Marseilles shortly, by the first French mail steamer.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Ramesos” sailed yesterday afternoon for Liverpool viA Malta,
                        with passengers, mails, and general cargo, including 2,144 bales cotton. The
                        “City of Cambridge,” of the Papayanni Line, left Malta on the 17th inst and
                        is due here on the morning of tho 21st The Ellerman S.S. ''Alexandria" is
                        expected here from FiumThe Moss liner “Ramesos” sailed yesterday afternoon
                        for Liverpool viA Malta, with passengers, mails, and general cargo,
                        including 2,144 bales cotton. The “City of Cambridge,” of the Papayanni
                        Line, left Malta on the 17th inst and is due here on the morning of tho 21st
                        The Ellerman e on the 24th inst. to load for Liverpool</p>
                    <p>The S.S. “Creole Prince” arrived in Manchester from Alexandria on Monday. </p>
                    <p>The Khédivial Mail S.&amp; "Dakahlieh” will leave Alexandria on Saturday and
                        Port Said on Sunday for Jaffa, Caiffa, Beyrout, Tripoli, Metsina, and
                        Aloxandretta. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate charges.
                        Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi
                        Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL GERMAN ENTERPRISE </head>
                    <p>HAMBURO-AMERIKA LINE’S DEVELOPMENTS.</p>
                    <p>Next season the Hamburg-Amerika Line intend developing their Mediterranean
                        system by running regular steamers between Naples and Alexandria. The same
                        company is building a magnificent sanatorium-yacht at Hamburg. The boat is
                        to be called the ‘‘Furst Bismarck,” the liner of that name having been sold
                        to the Russians. The steamer will visit Alexandria several times daring the
                        coarse of the season. She will carry a staff of ten or twelve physicians,
                        under the direction of Prof. Schweninger, medical adviser and confidante of
                        Prince Bismarck. The company may open some hotels in Egypt, but on this
                        point nothing has yet been decided. It is however certain that their offices
                        near the Grand Continental Hotel, Cairo, will be greatly enlarged, and that
                        new offices will be established at Alexandria and Port Said. Mr. Ernest
                        Stangen, general manager of the tourist department of the Hamburg-Amerika
                        Line, is expected to arrive shortly. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LAND BANK OF EGYPT. </head>
                    <p>The Land Bank of Egypt proposes, in the course of the month of April, to
                        issue on the Paris market debentures to the amount of £2,500,000. This bank
                        was founded at the beginning of the year by a syndicate which included
                        Messrs. Zenrudachi, Aghion and Salvage, of Alexandria ; Messrs. Rodocanachi,
                        and the Anglo-Foreign Banking Company, of London ; besides Messrs.
                        Zafiropoulo and Za-rifi, and la Société Marseillaise, of Marseilles, with
                        the object of advancing loans on mortgage to Egyptian agriculturists. Its
                        capital consists of £500,000 in 95,000 £5 ordinary shares. The Land Bank is
                        said to be interested in the BeheraSyndicate ("Financial Nows”). </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST AND INVESTMENT </head>
                    <p>A London contemporary, speaking of the issue, says : The Egyptian Trust and
                        Investment Company (Limited) appears to us to be one of the most hopeful
                        Egyptian enterprises introduced on this side as yet The character of the
                        enterprise is fairly well indicated by its title, and there is -little doubt
                        that under expert local management the company ought to do very well and get
                        its fair share of the profitable business which is sure to arise in
                        connection with the commercial development of the country. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER’S REPORT.</head>
                    <p>A statement has been issued to the effect that owing to the energy of the
                        commission, composed of Abid Bey, Mr. L. G. Boossin, and Mr. Siennes, the
                        French translation of Lord Cromer’s Report will probably be ready on
                        Wednesday night, on the same day that the English version arrives in Cairo.
                        We understand that Mr. A. Komeid is largely responsible for the actual
                        translation of the report, the revision and correction of this translation
                        having been given to the commission above-mentioned, who have been working
                        very hard to bring tho translation out in timeCopies will be obtainable ai
                        Barbiers Booktall, price P.T. 10 each. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MURDER IN CAIRO. </head>
                    <p>A cold-blooded murder was committed in Cairo on Sunday morning. About 8.30
                        a.m., as M. Egidio Gerosa, aged about 25, was on the point of entering the
                        Catholic Church it the Mousky, ho received two shots in the back from the
                        gun. He was immediately removed to the caracol in Ataba Khadra square, but
                        shortly afterwards expired from the wounds he had received. </p>
                    <p>The murderer was arrested by the police men on duty outside the church, and
                        was conveyed without showing any resistance to the samo caracol. The man’s
                        name is Fabio Ninci, and, like his victim, is of Italian nationality. It
                        appears that he had some time ago been discharged from the service of tho
                        Telephone Company, where he was employed as a wires-man. This discharge ho
                        attributed toM.Gerosa, who was an electrician of the company, and it was to
                        avenge himself that he had committed the deed. An enquiry has been opened by
                        the Italian consular authorities in Cairo ; meantime, the murderer has been
                        incarcerated in the central native prison. He will be sent to Ancona for
                        trial Yesterday afternoon, at 4 o'olock, the funeral of the victim took
                        place from the Italian Hospital At Abbassieh. The Italian Consul and
                        Vicennial, Mr. StevensoD, manager, and the rest of the personnel of the
                        Telephone Company were amongst the five hundred persons who formed tho
                        funeral cortege. Great sympathy was evinced for the unfortunate engineer,
                        and the funeral service at 8t Joseph's Church,Ismailia,was largely attended.
                        The interment took place at the Catbolic Cemetery. It is rumoured that M.
                        Gerosa's death the result of a plot among the workmen discharged by the
                        Telephone Company, some of whom are said to be Anarchists,but- this rumour
                        lacks confirmation at present </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good -----</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very ---- Brand of
                        Beer</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x xx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="councilMinisters"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS. REPORT OF PROCEEDINGS</head>
                   <p>Part of the business transacted at the Council of Ministers yesterday was the
                        approval of the foundation and statutes of the Upper Egypt Hotels Company.
                        Besides the appointments which we mentioned in yesterday’s issue, the.
                        following promotions were approved ; Youssef Bey Fahmy to be Chef dn Parquet
                        at- Tantah. El Said Bey Mohamed to be substitut da Parquet at Chibin el
                        Korn. Moh. Bey Ibrahim to be 3nd class substitut du Parquet Moh. Ibrahim
                        Effendi to be 2nd class substitut to the Procu rear-General. Moh. GafFor
                        Effendi to he 4th class judge at Tantah. Youssef Fahmy Effeudi to be 5th
                        class substitut Dr. Borchard and Baron Biasing were appointed members of the
                        EgyptologiafJ oom-mittee. ( X--- Mr. Little wood was appointed delegate of
                        the Egyptian Government at the Veterinary Congress which is to be held at
                        Buda Pest in September next. A credit of L E 5,000 was opened for lighting
                        Damanhour with gas. </p>
                    <p>Authorisation was given to form a joint stock company to be termed the
                        Sooiété Egyptienne do Daim Sanieh. Authorisation was granted to part with
                        Government land gratuitously, such land to he used for the construction of
                        kuttabs. A general prison is to be built at Chibin el Kom and a reformatory
                        school for minors at Cairo. The Archives Dept was detached from the Ministry
                        of the Interior and will be henceforth attached to the Ministry of Financé.
                        Decrees were signed a) for the construction of a prolongation of the Mellawi
                        branch of the Derwah Canal ; (b) for further work to be done on the Behout
                        Canal (Gbarbieh) ; (c) for the enlargement of the Minieh railway station ;
                        {d) for the construction west of the Khandi-bah Canal, Assouan, of a branch
                        to improve the supply of the Edfou and Kelh hods ; (e) for the construction
                        of an offioe for the 5th Circle at Gexireh el Hemodat(Keneh). </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA ARCHÆOLOGICAL SOCIETY. EXCURSION TO ABOUKIR.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday, a large number of the members of Alexandria Archeological Society,
                        accompanied by their families and a few invited friends, in all numbering
                        probably over 150, took part in the first exouraion of the season arranged
                        by the committee of the society. Alonkir was the chosen destination, and an
                        inspection of the tesselated pavements of the supposed temple of Canopis,
                        prior to their removal to the Alexandria Museum, the object of the visit.
                        Special arrangements were made for the conveyance of the party by the 4.10
                        afternoon train from Sidi Gaber, and on the completion of the journey the
                        train drew up on the line at the spot nearest to the Hike. This was a little
                        awkward for the ladies and children, who found some difficulty in alighting
                        from the carriages, but it was soon overcome by the help of their male
                        companions. The afternoon was fine, and the heat was tempered by a cool
                        breeze, rendering the walk through the fields of barley—which was in process
                        of harvesting—a pleasant one. Arrived at the site of the temple, the company
                        grouped themselves around a stone from which Dt,_ Breccia gave a short
                        lectors descriptive of the history of the rains as far as it is known or can
                        be conjectured. A great deal on this subject has already appeared in our
                        columns, and only in the early part of this year we called attention to the
                        necessity of steps being taken for the preservation of these interesting
                        tessalated pavements. After the lecture and an inspection of the pavements
                        and the The few granite columns visible, the company wended their way to
                        Kharabia, where Prince Omar Toussonn had very kindly erected a tent, in
                        which refresh meats were served, and greatly appreciated after the long and
                        tiring walk. Before leaving the tent Mr. Ralli, as president of the
                        Archeological Society, thanked Prince Omar Toussoun for his kindness in
                        affording the party the facilities he had given, and Dr. Schiesa, on the
                        part of the Alexandria Musuem, thanked Dr. Breooia for his interesting
                        speech. A number of very interesting ratios were on view in some
                        outbuildings of Prince Toussoun, and after inspecting these the company
                        proceeded to Khabara station, whére they entrained at 7.30 for Alexandria.
                        We may mention, as being in the party, Yacoub Pasha Artin, Sir Gerald
                        Pitigerald, Judge Batcheller, Mr. and Mrs. Gould, Admiral Sir Massie and
                        Lady Blomfield, Hon. Mrs. Hcpkinaon, Boron Alfred de Menasoe, Mr. Ssndara,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Maoanlay, Mr. and Mme Girard, Baron von Humboldt Dtcbroe-der,
                        Mme Constantine Sinadino, Mr. Ambroise Ralli, Mr. and Mrs. 8idney Oarver,
                        Mrs. Borchgrevfak, Mr. and Mrs. Bourgeois. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aaw01">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p>Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aan02">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Goods Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>1.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAVY.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>London, April 11. </dateline>
                    <p>Lieutenant Charles L Rome, 11th (<persName
                            ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert,_Prince_Consort">Prince
                            Albert’s</persName> Own) Hussars, attached to the Egyptian Army, has
                        just been promoted captain after six and a-half years’ subaltern service.
                        Captain Borne joined the Khedives army over two years ago, the gallant
                        “Cherry-Pickers” being then stationed at Cairo. His brother, lientenant
                        Claude S. Rome, who is adjutant of the 11th at the Curragh, and lieutenant
                        R. M. Yorke, side-de-camp to Lord Granfall, have also been promoted to the
                        rank of captain </p>
                    <p>Second Lieutenant the Hon. C. J. Lyttletou, Rifle Brigade, has been formally
                        appointed aide de-camp to Lord Selborna, High Commissioner for the Transvaal
                        and Orange River Colony.</p>
                    <p>The home battalions of the Royal Innis-killing Fusiliers and Royal Berks
                        Regiment will send shortly some details to their foreign battalions in
                        Egypt. Captain A. G. Macdonald, 1st Battalion Royal Berks Regiment, has
                        pawed the examination for promotion to the rank of major. The landing of the
                        Kaiser at Gibraltar gave rise to several questions fa the House. Mr.
                        Arnold-Forster, however, was of opinion that such matters were safe in the
                        discretion of Sir George S. White, V.C the commander of "The Rock”, I should
                        think so. The man who "kept the flag flying” is not the one to give anything
                        away even to Kaisers. At the same time it is questionable taste even in
                        great personages to visit such places. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Ghazi Makhtar Pasha, Imperial Ottoman High Commissioner, will leave Cairo by
                        special train on Thursday next at 9.45 a.m. tor Alexandria, where be will
                        arrive (Hadra station) at 1.20 p.m. His excellency will be accompanied by
                        his military and civil household. Prince Mirski, Russian Minister of the
                        Interior, was among the passengers who arrived from Marseilles yesterday by
                        the S.S. “Hohenzollern.’’ Lady Cromer went to Port Said in company with her
                        sister, Lady Beatrice Thyme, who left for England with Lady Cromer’s young
                        She has since returned to Cairo. Mr. C. Belinfante-ostberg,
                        Swedish-Norwegian Diplomatic Agent, arrived from Cairo yesterday. Herr von
                        Hoeltz, German Representative at Adis Abeba, is staying at the Hotel da Nil,
                        Cairo. He is on his way to Europe on leave from his diplomatic duties at the
                        Court of the Emperor Menelik </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA CONSERVATOIRE.</head>
                    <p>A very interesting concert was given by the Conservatoire of the People’s
                        University last night, and if such excellent programs are provided from time
                        to time the subscribers will be doubled and trebled soon and a larger
                        concert hall will have to be provided. We hear, however, that the new hall
                        kindly provided by M. Aghion behind the French Consulate, is much more
                        spacious than the University's lecture hall and also better ventilated. For
                        want of space the choruses sung by the pupils were given in a room behind
                        tho platform, the door between being left open. The effect was a very
                        pleasing one and the choruses (a) Serenata Napoli tana, (b) Barcarole, by
                        Dénia, were sung with ‘‘attack’’ and precision, the lights and.shades being
                        well attended to. A young tenor, M. Papanti, sang, “Aprite,” by Toeti, with
                        expression and great tunefulness, and his voice has a future fa store tor
                        him. The two pianoforte pupils were quite Aon de ligne. Miss Giglio’s
                        classical appreciation of her part in the Beethoven Quartott, fa which the
                        was supported by the profwsors of the Conservatoire, Messrs. Lama, Cuirlo
                        and Romeo, being remarkable for its thoughtfulness and good taste. Mile.
                        Levi, too, absolutely astonished her audience by her brilliant passage
                        playing in Lizst’s Rhapsodie No. XIa. Mlle. Vente kindly took port in the
                        programme and delighted everyone by the tinging of two songs, “Le Saüs," by
                        Olagnier, and a charming romance written by the director artistique of the
                        Conservatoire Professor Colella. Both songs were sung with great expression,
                        and Mile. Verita's voice has in our opinion greatly improved in timbre and
                        reserve since we have had the pleasure of hearing her. Last, but very far
                        from least, came Mendelssohn’s splendid Serenata, played famously well by
                        Professor Colella, and he was accompanied by a small orchestra under the
                        baton of Mr. Gianni Galletti, who also accompanied all the songs. We were
                        glad to hear that during the concert the vice president, Lady Blomfield1 was
                        promised £25 by a generous music-lover, who heard she was in need of funds
                        to purchase a few instruments necessary for the orchestra now being formed.
                        The organizers of the “ Pavane, ” i.e, the representation given for the
                        Enfants trouvés at the Zizinia, have kindly promised to repeat their
                        performance at popular prices in aid of the funds of the University and the
                        Conseratoire </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
