<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Gwen Lofman</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-10-07">October 7, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Saturday, October 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, OCTOBER 7 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CANAL TRAFFIC, SHIPS ENTER TODAY.<head>
                    <dateline>Port Said, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The mail boats will enter the Canal to-morrow and pass the Chatham on Sunday. The cargo boats will follow.</p>
                    <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN INSURANCE COMPANIES.</head>
                    <head type="sub">IRREGULARITIES AND WASTE OF FUNDS.</head>
                    <dateline>New York, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The investigation which is being made into the management of the Insurance Companies is leading every day to the discovery of fresh irregularities and waste of funds.</p>
                    <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be made up at the G.P.O., Alexandria, on Tuesday at 8.30 a.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Kobessi district during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 9th inst. will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Bank of Abyssinia</head>
                        <p>The first meeting of the directors of the above banks will be hold at Cairo next week. As has been expected Mr. McGillivray is to be appointed governor of the Bank of Abyssinia, and will proceed to Adis Ababba to take up his now duties in about two months’ time.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MR. TAFT IN JAPAN.</head>
                        <head type="sub">IMPORTANT UNDERSTANDING WITH U S. A.</head>
                        <dateline>Tokio. <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>The semi official ‘Kokoumin" says that the occasion of Mr. Taft’s voyage to Japan the latter concluded an important understanding with the United States, ‘ in consequence of Japan's explicit disavowal of any designs whatever upon the Phillipines.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIAN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>. The Minister of the Interior has ordered the local authorities to abstain from interference with the forthcoming elections to the National Assembly.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head type="sub">THE REICHSRATH.</head>
                        <head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE.</head>
                        <dateline>Vienna. <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>The Rechsrath has rejected the resolutions for universal suffrage.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH SQUADRON AT KOBE.</head>
                        <dateline>Kobe, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>The British China Squadron has arrived here.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STRIKES IN LIVONIA.</head>
                        <p>St Petersburg, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>. Strikes and pillaging continue in the Livonia province.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head type="sub">HAMBURG-AMERIKA LINE</head>
                        <head>NEW STEAMER PURCHASED.</head>
                        <dateline>Berlin, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>The Hamburg-Amerika Line has purchased the Union Castle steamship Scot, which has been re named the Ocean. This steamer will make one of an express service between Naples and Alexandria, in connection with the Berlin express.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ROMAN ATHLETIC MEETING.</head>
                        <dateline>Rome, <date value="1905-10-06">October 6</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>A great athletic meeting is taking place in the Vatican gardens under the patronage of the Pope, who warmly approves of sports.</p>
                        <byline>(R.)</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sir Vincent Corbett, the Financial Adviser, will arrive at Alexandria on Monday from Marseilles by the North German Lloyd S.S. Schleswig.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lord Hindlip is shortly expected in Cairo on his way to British East Africa. His lordship is going on a six months’ visit to that country in connection with the farming scheme which he started in the Protectorate last year. Lord Hindlip is accompanied by Lady Hindlip.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Harrison, general manager of Messrs, Thos. Cook and Sons, is expected to strive in Egypt towards the end of this month.</p>
                    </dvi>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Baehler is expected back in Cairo with his family, on Monday.</p>
                    </dvi>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. David Longworth left Cairo for Nairobi yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    </div type="item">
                        <head>ST ANDREWS CHURCH.<head>
                        <head type="sub">CAIRO</head>
                        <p>Services — 10:30 a.m.</p>
                        <p>6 p.m.</p>
                        <p>Beginning Sunday, <date value="1905-10-08">8th October</date>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports</head>
                        <p>From the 1st of January to the 5th of October, 824,306 tons of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 443,720, Newcastle 194,487, Scotland 99,112, Yorkshire 56,574, and other places 31.503 tons. During the corresponding period of 1904, 797,262 tons were received.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Found drowned</head>
                        <p>A corpse of a native lad aged 12, which was not identified, was found floating in the Mahmudieh canal yesterday, and on being taken out of the water was removed to the hospital for medical examination. Inquiries are being made in the hopes of identifying the body.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Ottoman Medal</head>
                        <p>In accordance with the Sultan's desire the Ottoman Government will strike a new medal, which will be called the "Yemen Medal." The new medal is to be confered upon the soldiers who distinguished themselvcs in suppressing the Yemen rebellion.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Burnt to Death</head>
                        <p>A woman of the name of Maria Rato, 25 years of age, was boiling a kettle on a gas stove on the 5th inst. when the flame caught her clothes. The flimsy material immediately flared up and the unfortunate woman received terrible burns from which she died very shortly after.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>The Della Guardia Dramatic company will stage Maison de Poupée at this evening's performance and a matinée will bo given to-morrow, commenting at 4 p.m., for which l Fourchambault is billed. To-morrow evening there will no performance, it being the eve of tbe Jewish Day of Atonement.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Affray at Menshieh</head>
                        <p>A quarrel took place yesterday at Menshieh between Alexandre Khalikopolo a Greek carpenter aged 30, and Said Imam, a native cabdriver aged 20, in which the former stabbed the latter with a knife the right hand. The man's hand was badly wounded and he was taken to the hospital, where he will be detained until recovered.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino</head>
                        <p>The demonstration of telepathy, thought-reading, and autosuggestion by Professor Bellini will take the place of the usual small dance at the San Stefano Casino this evening. Subscribers will be admitted free, non-subsribers will be charged P.T. 10. The Bracale orchestra will play as usual tomorrow at 10.30 a.m. and 5 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Painful Death</head>
                        <p>A London contemporary announces that a cow in Sullivan County, U.S.A., has just joined the majority in painful circumstances. Wandering into a kitchen, the peckish cudster found an old umbrella and several cakes of yeast, all of which it proceeded to swallow. The subsequent fermenting of the yeast opened the umbrella, and the beast died in great agony.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Rumoured Hotel Amalgamation</head>
                        <p>A rumour is current that on the return of Mr. Nungovich Bey a proposal will be submitted the shareholders of the Nungovich Hotels Co., and the Upper Egypt Hotels, for the amalgamation of the two companies under one directorate. It is reported on the Cairo bonne that the recent appreciation in the shares of there companies is due to this reason.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Selection of a Grand Mufti</head>
                        <p>We learn that the Council of Ministers at their meeting on Monday will select two sheikhs, shore names will be submitted to H. H. the Khedive fur the post of Grand Mufti of Egypt. There is much speculation as to who will be appointed to that important position in the Mohamedan world, but, our native readers have not to wait much longer now know whether their own choice has been selected.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring information on trade matters generally, including the question of appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for snob advice, it is obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain farther particulars from our London office, 86, New Broad-street, which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CAIRO “ZOO.”</head>
                        <head>REPORT FOR 1904.</head>
                        <p>The sixth annual report by the director of the Ghizeh Zoological Gardens affords most interesting reading. It seems to be complete in every detail, even to the noting that "one Egyptian pound (L.E. 1) equals ₤l.0s.61/4d. or 25 francs and 92 centimes.” We may be sure that after the precision shown in this matter we may rely upon the other statements in the report being equally exact</p>
                        <p>Passing over the details as to the staff, which seems to he selected with a view to complete efficiency, not only as regard the animals, but also for the upkeep of the ornamental grounds, we notice that the number of visitors shows a steady increase year after year. There was a slight falling off in 1902 in consequence, no doubt, of the bad season that year, but with this exception the increase has been steady, and whereas in 1899 the number of visitors was 43,567, in 1904 it reached 64,711, the gate receipts amounting to LE. 1,388.150. December, February,and March wore the months that brought in</p>
                        <p>most visitors and gate money, June and August being those in which the gardens were least frequented. The accounts for the year showed a useful credit balance of L.E. 189.848, an increase of L.E. 80.288 on the previous year's figures, although rather considerable new building, joining and repairing work had to be undertaken. The result shows clearly enoug that the present director's abilities are not by any means confined to administration and natural history.</p>
                        <p>Deaths among the animals, birds and reptiles—not including in the casualty list the results of the raids of foxes, wild cats, etc. or purely accidental fatalities—totalled 267 against 235 in the previous year; the winter mouths November and December, which were marked by outbreaks of influenza and dengue among human beings at Cairo, being exceptionally severe. There were some important departures and deaths to chronicle, Lord Kitchener’s giraffe dying, and the two Indian elephants being sent off to Europe; while the champauzee presented by the Sirdar, which has since unfortunately died, the pair of zebras, the sacred shrew and sacred ibis, and the giraffe and other animals from the Sudan all deserve mention among the numerous new arrivals. The note on the aquarium is most interesting, containing, as it does, evidence of close personal observation of the various species of Nile fish kept in captivity there, and Dr. Franz Werner of the University of Vienna has sent a list of the grasshoppers and kindred insects to be found in the Gardens which, should interest entomologists.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>H.H. the Khedive has graciously consented to open the Mansourah Agricultural show on Friday, the 20th inst., and daring his stay will be the guest of the Municipality.<p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head>
                        <head>RECEPTION OF BUELOW'S STATEMENTS</head>
                        <byline>(From our London Correspondent).</byline>
                        <byline>(By Telegraph).</byline>
                        <dateline>London, <date value="1905-10-06">Friday</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>The Paris Press shows a bitter unanimity in its reception of the proposals of Prince von Buelow as to a Franco-German alliance. Even a rapprochement between France and Germany would, it is declared, be highly distasteful to the French people, which has not forgotten the loss of Alsace and Lorraine. Any attempt to reduce France to the position of a submissive ally of the German Empire is certainly doomed to failure, whether brute force or diplomatic persuasion be employed. Prince. von Buelow's suggestions, in whatever spirit they may have been concived, are roundly declared to be as tactless as they are provocative. "They add insult to injury.” — Such is the opinion of the general French public.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
                        <p>Sir William Willcocks leaves to-day for Upper Egypt, where he will visit the Sucreries Company's factories and will be followed later by MM. Fourneron and Sampaulo, whose report will be given to the public on the 18th inst. On their return from Upper Egypt they will draw up a report in combination with Sir William Willcocks, which will state the exact condition and value of the factories.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CREDIT FONCIER EGYPTIEN.</head>
                        <p>Nothing is known at the offices of the Credit Foncier in Cairo regarding the rumor published by some of the local papers of the retirement of Mr. Beyerle, the managing director. On the contrary in the last letters received from this gentleman, who is now in Paris, he mentions his intention of returning at the end of this month to resume his post.</p>
                        <p>We may add that on the death of his wife a few months back Mr. Beyerle wished to resign but was requested to reconsider his decision, at d, on the solicitaiton of his colleagues on the board, be decided to retan his appointment.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>
                        <p>There will be an extra regatta held on Friday in honor of the visit of H. H. the Khedive to the yacht club. The weekly regatta will be held on Wednesday as usual.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Moss liner Rameses sailed from. Malta yesterday afternoon and is due at Alexandria on Tuesday with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SHIPS ENTER THE CANAL.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <datelnie>Suez, <date value="1905-10-06">Friday</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>Till this morning at 8 o’clock, 42 vessels were anchored in the Suez roads, and the first steamer to enter the Canal was the S.S. Clan Ogilvy, which proceeded at 10 am., and was subsequently followed by 10 more vessels. Some of the remaining steamers will enter tomorrow morning, and the next divisions on Sunday and Monday. The S.S. Durham Castle will enter the canal with the fourth division of steamers, and some of the members of the British Association have returned to Suez from Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE S.S. NUBIA.</head>
                        <p>The Anchor liner Nubia, which is ashore at Ras Shouhair in the Suez Gulf, is expected to to be refloated shortly. The Khedivial mail liners Fayoum and Calioubieh are taking in cargo from the stranded vessel, and up to now over 1,200 tons have been discharged. The coustguard cruiser Noor el Bahr is standing by the Nubia guarding the coast for fear of the Bedouins pillaging the cargo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BRITISH ASSOCIATION.</head>
                        <byline>(From Another Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <datelnie>Port Tewfik, <date value="1905-10-05">Thursday</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>As I telegraphed yon yesterday the Durham Castle, one of the famous Castle liners, arrived here with the members of the British Association on board, in all about 200 persons. Many of the members ware visiting Egypt for the first time and were very eager to have a few days stay but several of the Professors have to be home by the 18th inst. as they have engagements to fulfil at Oxford and Cambridge, the term commencing soon, and should the canal remain blocked they intend going via Marseilles by the M.M. mail boat from Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BLOCK AT SUEZ.</head>
                        <p>The block in the canal traffic is beginning to show at this end. There are now over 40 large steamers in the hay including several liners, notably the P. & 0., Carman mail, Dutch mail, Spanish mail from Manilla, Bibby liner, three Clan liners, Durham Castle and many other regular traders, but there is still plenty of room, as the magnificent bay could easily accomodate 200 or upward. Strangers arriving at night generally anchor far off as they are unable to find their way to a good anchorage before daylight The bay has a very fine appearance at night when all the ships are lit up and many residents take a trip round the ships in a steam launch in the cool of the</p>
                        <p>Officizl notice was given yesterday that traffic was to be resumed but was cancelled late in the evening, and it is now rumoured that no movement will take place here till Sunday as the ships in Port Said will come through first so as avoid too much crossing in the canal and consequent danger of colliding.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HARBOUR NOTES</head>
                        <byline>( From our Correspondent. )</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, <date value="1905-10-05">Thursday</date>.</dateline>
                        <p>In continuation of my notes sent yon yesterday, I have thought it might be interesting to your readers to see a list of the numerous vessels which are at present lying at Port Said and Suez awaiting more or less impatiently the restarting of traffic, which I hear now (2 p.m.) may occur on Sunday :—</p>
                        <q>Arrived at Port Said, 27th ult Ping Suey; 28th ult Rugia, Menelaus, Avooa, Mahratta, Merton Hall; 29th ult. Staads Kratke, Persia (Anchor), Weissenfels, Langdale; 80th ult Statesman, Oxus; 1st inst Ataka, Buda, Sicilia (transport), Dunolly; 2nd inst Yana, Siam, Palermo, Sachsen, Arabistan ; 3rd inst Goentor, Flores, Africa, Nubia, Persia; 4th inst Wartenfels, Arracan, Hector, City of Athens, Nippoon, City of Madras; 5th inst Bohemia, Atholl, Engineer Civdakoff; Omrah, Assouan: Arrived at Suez Roads 27th ult City of Manchester, Clan Campbell, Oriel, Orselo, Irrawaddi; 28th alt Clan Ogilvie, Aberlour, Forestdale, Langoe ; 29th ult Coquet, Clan Mackinnon, Isla de Panay ; 80th ult Trentham Hall, Ras Elba, Acacia, Tebe, Vindobona, Malaoca, Alladin, Fulwell; 1st inst. Emile; 2nd inst. Matiana, Adm. L. Treville, Victoria, Britannia, Rocklight; 3rd inst. Umbilo, Warwickshire, Turkistan, Korena ; 4th inst City of Karachi, Durham Castle, City of Benares, Kanzler, Kybfels, Yeddo; 5th inst Prinz Hendrik, Sumatra, Ixion, Avals. That is to say, that exclusive of the nine colliers discharging here now, and the</q>
                        <!-- TODO find the truncated part of this note -->
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ENGLISH CHURCH IN KHARTOUM.</head>
                        <p>The "Standard” has received the following letter from Sir Reginald Wingate Pasha appealing for funds for the construction an English Church at Khartoum :—</p>
                        <quotedLetter>
                            <opener>
                                <salute>Sir,</salute>
                            </opener>
                            <p>I should esteem it a great favour to be allowed to make an appeal to the readers of your valuable paper on behalf of an English Church in Khartoum. Designs and plans for the building are under the consideration of the Church Committee, and is hoped the work of construction will be commenced in the autumn of this year. The estimated cost is £7000, and towards this amount £3000 have already been raised, almost entirely by local subscriptions. The Government has provided an excellent site, close to the Gordon Statue, where the foundation stone of the chuchh was laid by Prinoess Henry of Battenberg on her visit last year.</p>
                            <p>The Rev. L. Gwynne has been appointed Archdeacon of the Sudan by the Bishop in Jerusalem, and he is now organising our church work with a view to providing service for our rapidly increasing population, not only at Khartoum, but also in the outlying station, such as Suakin, Wady Haifa, and Shendi.</p>
                            <p>The generosity of the British officials and residents in the Sudan will be taxed to the utmost to provide chaplains, and to build churches necessary for these far-scattered stations. Therefore, in order to rect a building at Kharatoum worthy of our Church and nation, we are forced to ask help from those at home.</p>
                            <p>Other communions are making progress with their churches. The aged Patriarch of the Coptic Church in Egypt set a noble example by undertaking a prolonged and arduous journey up the Nile, daring which he collected some £1000 for the building of a chuch in Khartoum, the foundation stone of which he laid on his arrival, and now the edifice is approaching completion. The Roman Church has already a suffient sum for its proposed cathedral, whilst a very handsome mosque has been constructed at a cost of over £13,000.</p>
                            <p>We, therefore, more earnestly ask for the generosity and sympathy of our people at home to enable us to complete the building of our church in Khartonm,</p>
                            <p>Subscriptions will be recieved and acknowledged by A. Dyke Acland, Eq., 186 Strand, W.C. Cheques should be crossed Bank of Egypt, and made payable to the "Khartonm English Church Fund."</p>
                            <closer>
                                <salute>I am, Sir, your obedient servant</salute>
                                <signed>(Signed) REGINALD WINGATE</signed>
                            </closer>
                        </quotedLetter>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Less regularly, we have now 37 steamers in the harbour of Port Said and 40 at anchor in Suez Roads.</p>
                        <p>Roughly speaking there are 1,700 passengers delayed either here or at Suez, and at tie lowest computation some 231,000 tons of cargo and one of the large British India turret ships having 12,500 tons of cargo on board, is expected to-day. A fair estimate of probable arrivals between now and Sunday will be five ships at each end per day, say at least 25 mail vessels by Sunday morning, which will bring up the number of waiting ships to about a hundred and five. In Port Said harbour practically every possible good berth is occupied and in many oases, on the main buoys, there are two ships lying. The Dutch Basin which so far has been used solely for men-of-war has five ships in it The berth "No. 6 Black" has five ships at anchor where one usually lies. The Yam and Oxus lie side by side, as do also the Melenaus and hector; in fact, ships are everywhere, and I think I may safely say, never before has Port Said seen such a sight</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CANAL TRAFFIC RESUMED.</head>
                        <byline>(By Telegraph)</byline>
                        <p>Port Said, Saturday, 6.16 a.m. The mail steamers Tourane, Nippon, Omrah, Wartenfele, Africa, Goentor, Oxus, Sachsen. Yarra, Staads-Kratka, and Persia will enter the canal at eight o'clock this morning, and will tie up north of Ras el Esh, and fifteen more will follow this afternoon. Eleven steamers have entered from Suez and anchored at Ismailia, and fourteen more will go as far the Bitter Lakes to-day. Full traffic There are forty-six vessels here and the number at Suez.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AT KILOMETRE 18.4 Work goes on in the chiefs and everyone are more than hard at work, pieces of plate and frame are coutinually being found and recovered and several have been broken up by small mines under the supervision of the engineers’ staff assistants advised by Mr. Harris. Bands of Arabs busy collecting and transporting the smaller pieces in lighters to Port Said while the dredgers are cutting out the main channel in the wake of crane". M. Schmitt has been down to the spot examining the bank and channel, which, I believe, will have a temporary width of 30 yards and a depth of 27 feet</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DEPARTURE OP M. COULLANT.</head>
                        <p>M. Conllant, the Canal Company's chief agent at Port Said, (who by the way succeeds M. Tillier as chef de service in the coming year) left last night for France in the M.M. Senegal. M- Coallant arrived hare by the Brindisi mail in company with Mr. Harris and bis two assistants in order to form the commission which eventually decided the fate of the unfortunate Chatham.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><!-- TODO Replace with ad boilerplate -->
                    <head>BECK & GO'S PILSENER BEER</head>
                    <p><unclear>OMalaakla frum *r*nr R*M*itatl* fIra</unclear> In Cairo, Alexandria, & the Sudan. Otherwise apply too <unclear>. j ntwnn. r. wcauii</unclear></p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Anglo American Nile Steamers & hotel company.</head>
                    <p>Three Saillage a-Week</p>
                    <ad/>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CURONIQUE FINANCIERE</head>
                    <dateline>Vendredi <date value="1905-10-06">6 Octobre</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Il y a Peru de choses à ajouter à ce que none avons dit dans notre dernière chronique concernant la pénurie de numéaire, l'élévation du taux d’escompte, les veraement à opérer t' es liquidations de fin du mois, sinou que l'effet déprimant de ces divers facteurs semble dev i subsister quelques jours encore sur notre marché.</p>
                    <p>Durant la semaine qui vient de s'écouler la cots a subi une baisse presque générale, bien qu'une certaine animation n'ait cassé de prévaloir. Dés lundi las cours fléchissent et aprés un semblant de reprise mercredi la réaction ne fait que s'accentuer jusqu'à la clôture d'ajour-d'hui.</p>
                    <p>Quant aux transactions, alias n'ont au de réelle importance qu'en National Bank, au Agricole et en Nungovich.</p>
                    <p>Le Consiel d’Administration de la D ïra Sa nieh s'est réuni jeudi à la National Bank et a décidé le paiement à la date du 16 courant de £10 par action et de £78 par part de fondateur. Quelques jours aprés, le 30 courant, auront lieu les plaidoireries de l'affaire, des princes de la famille Khédiviale. Bn attendant le cours de la Dura perd 1/8 comme résumé de la semaine et clôture à 28.</p>
                    <p>Le capital de £500.000 de 1’Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Co., (dont Sir W. Wilcocks est le président) a été plus que couvert. Un tiers des actions sera néanmoins offert en souscription publique afin d'obtenir la cotation officielle. Les promoteurs de l’affaire n'ayont pas touché da rénumération pécuniaire, il a été créé poor let dédommagsr, an certain, nombre de ports de fondateurs. Les actions auront droit à un dividende cumulatif de 4 % et le surplus des bénéfices sera divité entre les parts de fondateurs 30 pour cent et les actions 70 pour cent.</p>
                    <p>Aux Sucreries la situation ne s’est pas améliorée: le cours a meme fléchi d'une façon sensible mais purs reprendre en clôture à 43. Le rapport des experts qui a paru le 4 courant n'est pas pour rassurer let actionnaires: on y voit, en effet, que les exercise éjaulés ce soldent tous par das pertes croisssantes variant de 2000 à 120000 Livres; ces pertes étaient combléas par an compte annuel d'arbitrages envoyé de Paris par Crouier et dounant un bénéfice suffisant pour distribuer un dividende et laisser un reliquat.</p>
                    <p>Le prolongement à bréva échéance du Nubarieh dont on a beaucoup parlé deraiérement vient d’etre officiallement démenti, Ce travail a été renvoyé à une date indéterminée et le Gouvernement a suspendu la vents de ses terrains dans la région intéressée attendant d'étre fixé sur ce point</p>
                    <p>Une nouvelle banque va incessamment etre laucée ici sous le nom de Egyptian Bank of Commerce. Son capital est firé à £500000 et conseil d'administration figurent les noms de plusieurs grands financiers londonians.</p>
                    <p>Asset mouvementés au début, les Estates</p>
                    <p>terminent avec une reaction totals de 1/32 à 1 7/32 acheteurs. Cette valeur sera désormais inscrite au Stock Exchange de Londres,</p>
                    <p>L’Agrioole qui a été en grande faveur durant toute la semaine finit à 9 5/8, en gain de 3/16 sur le cours de vendredi dernier.</p>
                    <p>Toot aussi animée, quo que en snes contraire, 1a National Bank clôture à 27 3/16, en parts de 5/16.</p>
                    <p>C'est la Nungovich qui a eu les honneurs de la semaine et le record de la bausse ces joursci; elle monte de 10 3/8 à 10 15/16. Le prix de 11 a meme été pratiqué pour le 15 courant.</p>
                    <p>Ea hausse également les Tramways d'Alexandrie de 159 à 169 la Privilégiée et de 320 à 328 la Dividende, les Eaux du Caire de 1155 à 1160, la Béhéra de 42 1/2 à 43, la Land Bank de 9 3/4 à 9 7/8, les Markets de 23 à 25/ 3, et la Banque d'Athènes de 188 8/4 à 135.</p>
                    <p>La Delta Light fléchit de 18 1/4 à 13 1/16, sans beaucoup d_ff ires.</p>
                    <p>Contraiment aux Tramways, la Ramleh Railway tombe de 7 5/16 à 7 1/8.</p>
                    <p>La Crown Brewery accuse une baisse de 5 francs sur la Privilégiés à 202 et de 11 francs la Dividende à 1_0. Quant à la Brasserie des Pyramides, elle perd 1 frano sur la Dividende et gagne 50 centimes sur la Privilégiée au cours respectifs de 62 et 125.</p>
                    <p>Les Cotton Mills fléchissant de 6 à 5/9 et la Salt & Soda de 33/9 à 33/6.</p>
                    <p>De 5 5/8 l'Anglo-American Nile recule à 5 9/16, la Delta Land de 2 9/16 à 2 1/2, le Treat de 1 5/16 à 1 9/32 et l'Urbaine de 5 1/2 à 5 3/8.</p>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demis)</p>
                    <p>Comme d’ordinaire le samedi, notre marché a éte à peu prés nul ce matin, soit comme variations dans la cote, soit comme transactions. Cependant, on constate une inclinasion vers la baisse, ce qui est du en partie aux motifs déjà exposes dans notre chronique, en partie à 1a fermeture de la corbeille lundi prochain, à l'occasion du Grand Jeûne Israélite.</p>
                    <p>La National Bank est offerte au prix de 27 3/16, tandis que l'Agricole est demandés à 9 11/16.</p>
                    <p>De 2 9/16 la Delta Land fléchit à 2 1/2 acheteurs et Daïra Sanieh de 28 à 27 15/16 vendeurs. La Part de Fondateurs Daïra tombe également de 180 à 178.</p>
                    <p>Par conre, la Filature estun pen plus ferms</p>
                    <p>Les Estates se font remarquer par leur formeté</p>
                    <p>Tandis que la Privilégiée Tramways d'Alexandrie est offerts à 162, la Dividende est demandée à 332, au hausse de 4 francs sur le cours d'hier.</p>
                    <p><unclear/>gouverment a une reprise vere le<unclear/></p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
