<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Charlie Rymer</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-03</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">Monday, August 21, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="item" n="1">
                    <h1>PEACE PROPOSALS.</h1>
                    <h2>IN THE HANDS OF THE TSAR.</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CONTRADICTORY RUMOURS.</h2>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 24.</h3>
                        <p>An authoritative Russian statement says
                            that the proposal to purchase Northern
                            Saghalien, although a new. form, is identical
                            with the proposal already rejected, and merely
                            amounts to insistence for the reimbursement
                            of war costs under the name of purchase.
                            Russia cannot pay an indemnity, by what-
                            ever name it may be called, and peace cannot
                            bo assured unless Japan withdraws the demand
                            for the repayment of war costs. (Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>(Jo.nnt Lamsdorff has authorised Rooter's
                            Agency to declare that Russia will pay no
                            direct or indirect contribution, nor will she
                            mako any cession of territory.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Portsmouth (N.H.), August 24.</h3>
                        <p>The Conference has adjourned until Satur-
                            day. M. Witte is desirous of referring to. St.
                            Petersburg the Japanese compromise under
                            which Russia is asked to repurchase half of
                            the Saghalien Island for 1,200,000,000 yen.
                            (Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>London, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>It appoare that the peace negotiations are
                            no longor in the hands of the delegates, and
                            that the issno now rests with - the Tsar, who
                            had threo hours' conference with the American
                            Ambai sudor yesterday.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE IMPERIAL MANIFESTO.</h2>
                        <h2>GREATER FREEDOM DEMANDED.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>The Municipality has passed a resolution
                            similar to that of Moscow, formally thanking
                            the Tsar, but demanding freedom of speech,
                            meeting, and the press.	( Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>RUSSIA'S INTERNAL LOAN.</h2>
                        <h2>A FEEBLE RESPONSE.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 24</h3>
                        <p>The Russian internal lean bos been so far a
                            failure. Only 7,000,000 of roubles have been
                            taken up.	(Reuter)
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>MARTIAL LAW AT WARSAW.</h2>
                        <h2>RAILWAY BRIDGE DYNAMITED.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>The railway bridge over the Vistula near
                            Radom has been blown up. Martial law has
                            been declared throughout the government of
                            Warsaw.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>The R&iom railway bridge has been blown
                            up. A state of siege has been proclaimed at
                            Warsaw and Odessa.
                            (Havas)</p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>AGRARIAN TROUBLES.</h2>
                        <h2>THE PEASANTRY DESPERATE.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>Fresh agrarian disturbances have taken
                            place in the south of Russia. The peasants,
                            driven to despair by the bod-harvest and the
                            prospect of famine, have begun to attack the
                            landowners’ estates.	(Renter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>FRANCE AND MOROCCO.</h2>
                        <h2>FRENCH GOVERNMENT DETERMINED.</h2>
                        <h3>Paris, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>Tho French Government has definitely de
                            cided to make a military demonstration, unless
                            tho Fronoh Algerian subject, who was taken
                            as a prisoner to Per, be immediately released.
                            (Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>Paris, August 24.</h3>
                        <p>M. Rouvier has demanded the release of the
                            Frenchmen arrested at Tangiers. (Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</h2>
                        <p>We are glad to learn that Mr. R. Suelling,
                        editor of the “Egyptian Gazette,” is making
                        good progress towards recovery.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Prime Minister, Mustapha PJaha
                        Pebmy, will meet H.H. the Khedive at Vienna
                        to-morrow.</p>
                        
                        <p>Mr. G'onrtenay Clifton who is acting in Mr.
                        Perry’s abeOBoe aa Under Secretary rf State
                        for towns and buildings to the Ministry of
                        Publio Work*, leaves for a ten days’ tour of
                        inspection in Upper- Egypt to-morrow.</p>
                        
                        <p>Rajah Brooke of Sarawak with hia suite is a
                        passenger for home by the P. &-0. 8.8. China,
                        which passed through the Canal on Tuesday.</p>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="2">
                    <h1>LOCAL AND GENERAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <p>The Cairo Teleoraph Office will in future
                        be cloapd from midnight till 6 am., as from
                        to-day.</p>
                        
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in tho
                        Qheziroh distriot of Cairo daring to night and
                        and at dawn of tho 26th inst will be poisoned
                        by the police.</p>
                        
                        <p>Undesirables Expelled.—Two Europeans
                        who have “left their oonntry for their country's
                        good” have been arrested hereby the Grover-
                        non.t and will be deported.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Plague.—Yesterday's plague bulletin
                        reports two new admissions to hospital at
                        Alexandria, the cases being brothers who live
                        together in the Karmooz quarter.</p>
                        
                        <p>Accident on a Building —Ali Ghonaim, a
                        workman omphyed ou tho Orwa el Woska
                        school building at El Azarito, fell from the
                        roof yesterday and sustained severe injorios.</p>
                        
                        <p>Smugglers Arrested —Two Italians were
                        arrested by the quay police yesterday while
                        attempting to emugglo tobacco. They have
                        been handed over to the Italian Consulate.</p>
                        
                        <p>Suez Canal.—10 vessels passed through
                        the Canal on tho 22nd inst, of which 5 were
                        British, 1 German. 1 Russian, 2 Austrian, 1
                        Italian. The day's receipts were frs. 259.636 76,
                        making the total from the 1st inst fra.
                        6,469,462.57.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Lighting of Cairo.—The Ministry of
                        Public Works has authorised the Cairo Gas
                        and BlectricLight Company to lay underground
                        wires in Mohamed Ali street for the snpply of
                        eleotrio light to tho bnildings between Bub el
                        Khalik aud Menahieh</p>
                        
                        <p>Army of Occupation.—Tho troopship Dun-
                        era which will arrim at Alexandria frim
                        Malta on October 9 gjll laud two hundred
                        non-commissioned officers and men .with their
                        familioa, and a sufficient proportion of officer*,
                        who will quartered at Alexandria.</p>
                        
                        <p>Robbed in the Train.— Mr. Peter, platform
                        inspector of Cairo station, fell asleep whilst tra-
                        velling from Alexandria to Cairo, and on wak-
                        ing up at Bonha station discovered tint his
                        gold watch and chain were missing. The police
                        wore immediately informed of thethefc, bat no
                        arrest has, as yet, been made.</p>
                        
                        <p>Human Bones Discovered.—The workmen,
                        employed on tho foundations of the new
                        Wakfs building at Ataba el Khadra at Cairo
                        have unearthed a number of bones, apparently
                        those of persons' buriod in a cemetery that
                        formorly existed on the same spot The Gou-
                        vernorat has informed the Sanitary Adminis-
                        tration of the disoovery.</p>
                        
                        <p>Nouveautes Theatere.— A performance was
                        given at the Nouveautds Theatre, Cairo, tho
                        ovoning before last for the benefit of the mneh-
                        applauded Mile Marie Flenr, a vivacious and
                        pretty Italian artiste. The hall was orowdod
                        by her numerous supporters and she excelled
                        herself in her efforts to delight and amnse.
                        Alexandrians will have the, opportunity of
                        welcoming this artiste very shortly.</p>
                        
                        <p>San Stefano Casino;—We would remind
                        our readers that the subscribers' grand ootillon
                        ball at San Stelano Casino will take place to-
                        morrow. Subscribers must not neglect'to take
                        their tickets with them, aa no invitations have
                        been issued. A grand oouoert will be given on
                        the last day of the. month at 9.30 p.m. for the
                        benefit of M. Braoal'e.rWe will publish the
                        programme at a later date.</p>
                        
                        <p>First aid to the Injured.—The Egyptian
                        State Railways Administration has rooently
                        issned a circular to the station-masters giving
                        the sections of the polioe regulations which
                        relate to the assistance to be rendered to the
                        injored with- the following additional note.
                        ‘ Station-toasters are reminded that it is their
                        daty to render immediate assistanoe by all
                        means in their power to persons accidentally
                        injured. Employes or others injured must be
                        taken to the nearest plaoe where they oan
                        receive medical attention. Station-masters who
                        have ambulances at their disposal are remind-
                        ed that their nso is not limited to stations,
                        bat that they mast be employed in all oases
                        of severe injnry on the line, to enable tho
                        victims to be transported to the nearest station
                        or pharmacy."</p>
                        
                        <p>The Cutting of the Khalig . — To mor-
                        row is the festival of Foam el Khalig
                        -when a large number of tbe native world
                        of Cairo and many visitors from other
                        towns will betake themselves to that village
                        to participate in the festivities oelebrating
                        What is_coifed the cutting of the Khalig. In
                        those'days when the land was not mitered by
                        the present system of irrigation, the cutting of
                        the dam nsed to take place atFoom el Khalig
                        when the water had reached its normal boight
                        of sixteen ells, and it waa the signal for tho
                        ontting of the embankments of all the irriga-
                        tion canals. Now the aotual dotting does not,
                        of course, take plaoe but the ceremony is kept
                        op with the same religion* rites and is attend-
                        attended by the same form of rejoicings. The
                        day is known amongst the ‘ natives - aa the
                        “Yom rfdba el bthr” and always fall* between
                        the first' and fourteenth day of the Coptic
                        A oath of Mian. In ancient times the ikte
                        of taxation used to be dettifmined in accor-
                        dance *&4e height of (he inundation,</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="3">
                    <h1>AN IMPORTANT LAWSUIT.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CLAIM BY MEMBERS OF THE
                            KHBDIVIAL FAMILY.</h2>
                        <p>An important and sensational lawsuit, in-
                            volving many millions. of francs, will oome
                            before the Mfked_TribanaI of Cairo on the
                            ro-opening of the Coarts in October. It is a
                            claim brought by the Prinoeasee Djenaniar
                            and Tchorn Afet Hanem, widows of the late
                            Khedive Ismail, and Princea Hassein Kamel,
                            Ibrahim Hilmy, Mahmoud Hamdi and Fouad,
                            his sons, against the Daira Sanieh Co., tho
                            Daira Sinieh Administration, v the Egyptian
                            Government and the Credit Fonmer Egyptian.
                            Thom have beon cited to appear on the 80th
                            Ootober and the citation, which emanates
                            from the office of Maitre E. Mannsardi was
                            s rved by the hnssiers of the above Tri-
                            bunal on Tuesday last The suit is brought
                            in virtue of artiole 40 of the Law of Liqui-
                            dation of the 17th Jaly, 1880, by which the
                            late Khedive Ismail handed over certain estates
                            known os the Daira Sanieh to safisfy. dome
                            of his European creditors. In 1898 the Egypt-
                            ian Government oeded to . a company that
                            was formed under the title of the Daira
                            Sanieh Co. Limited, all the estates belonging
                            to the D»ira Sanieh Administration, on the
                            condition shat the former should engage to
                            pay all outstanding claims on thp latter’s
                            dissolution, ou the 15*h October, , 1905.
                            These rights were rooently transferred to
                            the Credit Foncier Egyptian upon certain
                            conditions that were previously _ stipulated
                            between tho two parties oonoerned.' The'claim
                            of the above Prinoesae* and Princes, the
                            plaintiffs in the aotion,resta upon the interpret-
                            ation of the artiole in question of the Law of
                            Liquidation. Acoording to the plaintiffs they
                            are entitled to all tho remaining surplus of the
                            Daira Sanieh, after the satisfaction of all the
                            creditors of the said administration, as the
                            heirs of the foimer owner, the Iato Khedive
                            l tutY Should this thesis be upheld by the
                            Tribunals, the shareholders of the New Daira
                            will find themselves deprived of tho benefit of
                            their option or right to the purchase of the
                            properties of the Daira 8anieh Administration
                            on the 15th Ootober, bat, m that event, they
                            will have a claim against tki Government for
                            reimbursement of the snms paid by them. In
                            tho citation served on the Credit Foncier that
                            institution is prohibited from handing over to
                            tho Now Daira the sum agreed upon for the
                            parobase of its lands.
                            The case is exciting great interest in looal
                            finsnoinl circles, and seems at present almost
                            tho solo topio of conversation on the Cairo
                            Bourse and amongst business men in general.
                            What makes it still more interesting is that it
                            is stated thst the plaintiffs consulted so mo
                            two years ago the late Monsieur Waldeck-
                            Rousseau, the celebrated French lawyer and
                            Prithe Minister of Franoe, and that it was
                            upon his favorable advice that the present
                            lawsnit has been brought. Maitre Carton de
                            Wiart of Cairo is the legal adviser of the Dslra
                            Sanieh, and would bo the oounsel tor these
                            defendants should the care oome on for hearing;
                            of which, we may add, there seems to be some
                            donbt.</p>
                        <h2>THE ECLIPSE.</h2>
                        <p>The eminent astronomer M. Buscaloni has
                            recently published diagrams of the soLr eclipse
                            as seen from Cairo, Alexandria and Port Said.
                            At Cairo the area of the eclipsed portion
                            of the sun' will be 9047 m. -The eclipse
                            will begin at eight urinates and fifty-two
                            seoonds past 8 p.m., will reach its maximum
                            phase at eighteen minutes and five seoonds
                            past 4 p.m. and terminate at twenty min-
                            utes and seven seoonds past 5 p.m. At
                            Alexandria the eolipsed area will measure
                            {8 m. The eclipse will begin at fifty-nine
                            ruinates and fortune seconds past 2 p.m.,
                            roach its climax atnine minutes and thirty-bine
                            seconds past 4 p.m. and end at twelve minutes
                            twenty two seconds past 5 p.m.
                            At Port Said the eclipsed area will measure
                            -87 m., and the eolipee, after starting to darken
                            the son at twelve minutes thirty-five seoonds
                            past 8 p.m., will be most intense at twenty
                            minutes fifty seoonds past 4 p.m., and end at
                            twenty two minutes twenty-six seoonds past
                            5 p.m.</p>
                        <h2>SMYRNA BOMB DISCOVERY.</h2>
                        <h2>ARMENIANS ARRESTED.</h2>
                        <p>In oonsequence of the disoovery of a large
                            number of bomba in Smyrna nnmerons arrests
                            of Armenians have taken plaoe, and many
                            -if the ohief members of the Armenian com-
                            munity are olosely watched by the Khafieh.
                            The arrests of Armenians in Constantinople
                            continue, among those arrested being the
                            Mother Superior of the Hasskeni Armenian
                            Orphanage in the suburbs. It is not known
                            whotber these arrests are in oomieotion with
                            the discovery at Smyrna or the attempt against
                            the life of the Saltan on July 21st.</p>
                        <h2>THE MAHMAL THEFT.</h2>
                        <p>The Saperior Coonoil of War that sat for
                            several days at tho War Office in Cairo for the
                            trial of Mirilkl Mohamed Rabat, on the
                            ohaVge of gross negligent* in connection with
                            tho theft of pert of the treasure from the
                            Mabmal, has, we are informed, found this
                            offioer, who was in charge of the military
                            ‘■wort, guilty; bat ■ the finding of tbe eoort-
                            roartia! will not be made publio-until it has
                            received the affirmation of Lewa Henry
                            Pasha, O.B., ’Adiotant-Genefl and soting
                            Sirdar, who is at ‘present at Kfcsfcotun,</p>
                    </div>
                    
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="4">
                    <h1>NOTES FROM SUEZ</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>MAN-EATING SHARK CAUGHT.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent).
                            Suer, Thursday.
                            Two days ago, an enormous shark was
                            caught in the Suez roads, and on being out
                            open the head and two hands of a mao were
                            found in tbe abdomen. The unfortunate man
                            could not be identified, but it is presumed that
                            bf was a lasear who must have jumped over-
                            board from some steamer.</p>
                        <h2>THE GOODS TRAIN ACCIDENT.</h2>
                        <p>All day yesterday and ttpday, railway engin
                            eers, who came to Sue* from Cairo and
                            Port Said on special duty, were busily occupied
                            with workmen in pulling away the damaged
                            tijuok* and looOmotiveof the goods train which
                            through the stationon Taesday and caused
                            £fi£aoh damage. Twolooomotives were attaohed
                            to the broken truoks and set in motion in
                            order to poll them on to the railroad, bat it
                            was some time before this could be effected
                            with the aid of a powerful railway crane whioh
                            was especially brought down from Cairo. The
                            engine was also raised by means of the orano
                            and the railroad is now dear again for traffic.</p>          
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>MARIOUT LANDS.</h2>
                        <p>We are informed that in oonseqnenoe of ah'
                            approaching visit of officials who intend to
                            map and survey certain outlying distripts in
                            the Dokhleh and Mariout country, great pre-
                            parations are being made for their reception
                            by numerous individuals who have phrohAsed
                            government lands from the ingenious Bedouin,
                            and have as yet made no attempt to back
                            their title’ by produdfeg any evidence of
                            permanent occupation. Numbers of ne’erdo-
                            wells have been hired to pose as Wakils,
                            ghaffirs and what not, masrafr are being
                            dug with frantio haste, boundary marks
                            are Springing up everywhere and cibehs are
                            being built with great energy, though the
                            Majority of these "soi-disant" proprietors prefer
                            to have wooden “kiosques’’ made for them in
                            from four to eight pieoes at Alexandria,
                            whioh are then transported on oarts or camels
                            from Kafr Dawar or Max, and can be ‘pat
                            together and erected in an hour's timo. We
                            befieve that the Survey party has no intention
                            whatever of examining the boanifaries' of
                            different properties or ‘olaimi’ on the surveyed
                            portion of the Mariont oonntry, but a guilty
                            oooBcienoe appears to breed fears.
                        </p>
                        <h2>OUR SILVER CURRENCY.</h2>
                        <p>The Ministry of Finance has resolved upon
                            increasing the minimum of the silver and sub-
                            sidiary coin held in reserve in the Government
                            Treasury from LB. 400,000 to L.R 600,000,
                            and has first ordered a farther L.B. 100,000
                            from Eagland. Daring August the demand
                            is at its loweet, but it increases considerably in
                            Ootober and November, when it reaches its
                            maximum, on aooonnt of tho needs of mer-
                            chants for the new cotton crop. lost November
                            tbe amount in circulation had reached
                            L K 860,000, and it is to guard against an-
                            other silver famine, suoh as was expdrienoed
                            two years ago, that the Finance Ministry
                            decided lately upon augmenting its reserve.</p>
                        <h2>SAN STEFANO"CASINO.</h2>
                        <p>Tho following is the menu of the dinner to
                            be given on the oooasion of the Subscribers
                            grand ootillon ball-to-morrow :— ,</p>
                        <h2>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</h2>
                        <p>TheS.S. Roman Prinoe left Malta yesterday
                            with passengers and general cargo, add is. dne
                            to arrive at Alexandria on Monday next.</p>
                        <div type="section">
                            <h2>LETTER TO THE EDITOR.</h2>
                            <h2>EGYPTIANS IN SYRIA
                                AND THE TURKISH POLIOE.</h2>
                            <p>To the Editor or the Egyptian Gaeeite.
                                Hear Sir,—I took an absence leave this year
                                and thought of passing it in Syria and Motrnt
                                Lebanon, and on my way lack to Egypt, I
                                thought of passing by Haifa to See a friend of
                                mino there, fo I got my passport marked and
                                itearoer’s ticket ready and sailed to there.
                                On the steamer’a arrival I took a boat and
                                landed at the passport office, 'and as usual
                                handed my passport to three officers there,
                                who, after underitanding that I am an Egypt-
                                ian refused to let me land, protending they ,
                                have orders not to let Egyptians enter Haifa,
                                as they are interfering in political questions
                                against the Tarkish Government.
                                I have made ovory effort possible, to make
                                these people undorttand that I haVe nothing ,
                                | to do whatsoever with politico, and that I am ,
                                going (here to see a friend only, bnt all was in
                                1 vain and they added if I did tnisa the bo&t <
                                they would throw me into the sea.	i
                                So I thought of returoing to thehoat, arit
                                anchored there for two hours duly, and I really
                                had hardly time to get book to it.
                                My friend MM to get an order <rtn» the
                                    won id break Orders, ana insist on refusing me.
                                    Will you kindly note thh 'above 1 Youfs
                                    faithfully,	MB. Famt.
                                    Alexandria, August 25,</p>
                            
                        </div>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="5">
                    <h1>THE NILE FLOOD</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>NOTE BY MB. WEBB.</h2>
                        <h2>METEROLOGICAL CONDITIONS</h2>
                        <p>Since "knitting my-Wet NwteronsMtebfa
                            information hAI been socelved nfcmdkg the
                            meteorological conditions affectin' the Nile
                            flood. A telegram from Adia-Ahabo, storing
                            that the rains daring July in the 8hae district
                            of Abyssinia had been a complete failure, aid
                            shjortin the eastern Gogim distriot, explains
                            Ufa deficiency in thoBiee Nile flood.
                            Captain Lyons efeo reports that “Except for
                            tbe short tune at trie end of July a»d the
                            beginning of August unfavorable ootdftfoti
                            have heeb oontinaoos ud Mfaient taint hum
                            been the Order : now the fonder seem to domi-
                            nate all Abyssinia and most probably raint MH'
                            again be much below average."
                            _ All the meteorological conditions, therefore
                            indioate a low flood.</p>
                        <h2>LEVELS OF THE RIVER</h2>
                        <p>Owing to a substantial rite on tfie Blue Nile
                            add the Atbera on the 10th, there has been a
                            very sensible improvement 4a the river levels
                            south of Assouan, this improvement is working
                            northwards, and though very late in coming, if
                            will considerably assist tfie flood irrigation in
                            Upper Bgypf.
                            A farther rise has occurred ih both rivbrt on
                            the 20th whioh will be mpfct nsefal for main-
                            taining the river levels dfayin^ September.</p>
                        <h2>AT KHARTOUM</h2>
                        <p>The following table shows the levels of the
                            river at Khartoum, compared with last year
                            and the very low yeere bf 18W end 1902.
                            feaYPTtog SEAR&MAB&CT.
                            vFrom our Financial Corrisp-ndent).
                            Date	1889	1902	1904	1905
                            10th.	. 4.08	4i88	5.58	4.06
                            16ti>.	4.45	4.60/	5:44	4.68
                            20th.	5.07	4.61	6.22	6.02
                            Maximc	im 6.37	5.50	6.64	
                            As the gaage is now falling, and will only
                            riiffirA wa
                            maximum will exoeed tifab bf M02.</p>
                        <h2>AT ASSOUAN.</h2>
                        <p>The following table shots the levels of the
                            river at Assouan, oompared -with last year, the
                            very low years of 1899 and 1901, and the am-
                            agb of 20 years.</p>
                        <p>The geqge ,js exceedingly low, beu£ 2.30
                            metres below the average ofthe.past 30 years.
                            It is, however, now rising, and will rapialy
                            improve, bat it is too late to suppose that it
                            Mil ever be more than low.</p>
                        <h2>SADDS IN THE DELTA BRANCHES.</h2>
                        <p>The sadd in the Romttahrwch of the
                            Mob allot el Amir was cat on the 11th instant
                            and that in the Damietta branch at Faraskonr
                            on the 16th, these dates show bow poor the
                            levels in Egypt proper have been, and how well
                            tbe barrages have done their work.</p>
                        <h2>THE BARRAGES.</h2>
                        <p>The Askiont bariege was qomplstely closed
                            on 12th instant, and the flood is now passing
                            over the tope of the gates : the head on the
                            barrage ia 1.60 metres.
                            The Delta barrages are being oontinnonsly
                            regnlatea\opan.
                            The	barrage waa opened on 14th
                            instant and is still being regelated upon.
                            It is impossibl^fo exaggerate the enormous
                            benefit* resulting from these barrages in a year
                            of very low levels like the present.</p>
                        <h2>PERENNIAL IRRIGATION.</h2>
                        <p>The unavoidable delay in irrigating some of
                            but the straw is now over, and exoept that the
                            d rah crop briu be late in so** diatrieta, Sedi-
                            tions are very favorable.</p>
                        <h2>BASIN IRRIGATION.</h2>
                        <p>Practically no basin irrightfonbnbttneAM-
                            •i np to the present, as tbe flood canals are
                            rosy low. A rapid improvement however, will
                            position of affaire oh* the i
                            yiboe onrM YroMfy M
                            ohtw^itao.dioK there mi
                            sssaf</p>
                    </div>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>