<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Riley Ouellette</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-30">November 30, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-20">April 20, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, APRIL 20, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RIVAL FLEETS JAPANESE CRUISERS SIGHTED. RUSSIANS CUT CABLE.</head>
                    <p>Singapore, April 19.</p>
                    <p>The mail boat "Manila" yesterday sighted 16 Japanese cruisers and destroyers
                        scouting oil Sampalok Point (Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>London, April 19.</p>
                    <p>The "Daily Mail” learns from Singapore that Russian agents have cut the cable
                        between Foochow and Formosa. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH NEUTRALITY. STATEMENT BY M. BOUVIER.</head>
                    <p>Paris, April 19.</p>
                    <p>Chamber of Deputies.—M. Ronvier, being questioned, said that France would do
                        everything necessary to assure French neutrality in the Far East (Reuter.)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO. PRINCIPLE OF FRENCH PROPOSALS ACCEPTED. </head>
                    <p>Paris, April 19.</p>
                    <p>M. Delcasse, speaking in the Chamber, said that Morocco had accepted! the
                        principle of the French' proposals, and that negotiations were now
                        proceeding on that basis. If Germany considered his explanations regarding
                        Morocco were insufficient, he was prepared to complete them, and to reassure
                        all interests, and so remove any misunderstanding. {Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCO-SIAMESE DELIMITATION, OCCURRENCE OF HITCH.</head>
                    <p>Paris, April 19.</p>
                    <p>A hitch has arisen in the Franco-Siamese delimitation under the last
                        convention owing to the French commissioners declaring they have discovered
                        some errors in the geographical data supplied by Siam. (Reuter ) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ITALIAN STRIKE RIOTS. TROOPS FIRE ON MEN.</head>
                    <p>Rome, April 19. </p>
                    <p>The railway strike led to a riot at Foggia between the troops and the mob.
                        Both parties fired. Three men were killed and 10 wounded. The
                        latter,included several soldiers. (Reuter.) </p>
                    <p>Foggia, April 19. The strikers, having' attempted to invade the station, came
                        into collision with the troops. Three of the men were killed. (Hanoi.) </p>
                    <p>Rome, April 19.</p>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies has passed the Bill for the working of the railways
                        by the State. (Havas.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LIMOGES RIOTING. EXCITEMENT IN FRANCE</head>
                    <p>Paris April 19.</p>
                    <p>The Limoges rioting on the 17th inst has created much excitement in France.
                        The Socialists have vehemently attacked the Government for utilizing the
                        troops, but the Chamber has largely supported the Ministry. It appears that
                        nearly two hundred officersand soldiers have been wounded. The town is now
                        quiet' (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PARLIAMENTARY RECESS. ADJOURNED TO 2nd MAY.</head>
                    <p>London, April 19. </p>
                    <p>The House of Commons has adjourned to the 2nd of May. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EXCHEQUER BONDS.</head>
                    <p>London, April 19.</p>
                    <p>The average price obtained for the Exchequer Bonds on the 12th inst. was £98
                        13.10. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE TO OUR READERS.</head>
                    <p>The “Egyptian Gazette" will not be published tomorrow (Good Friday.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aaw01">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p>Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; HOTEL COMPANY RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS
                        BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO Three sallings a week</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>A case of plague is reported from Toukh today.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Mahmal</head>
                        <p>is expected at Tor from Yambo on the 24th inst </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Pilgrimage</head>
                        <p>Up to the present about 8,300 pilgrims have returned to Egypt from the
                            Hag. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Quarantine restrictions</head>
                        <p>as against plague are now applied to arrivals in Egyptian ports from
                            Jamnagar. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Next Archealogical Congress</head>
                        <p>is to be bold in Cairo in 1907- This year’s Congress closed at Athens
                            last Thursday. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The “Cairo.”</head>
                        <p>—Messrs. Almagia have not yet succeeded in moving the wreck of the S.S.
                            ‘Cairo" from the Againe Shoal. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Death Sentence.</head>
                        <p>— The Tantah Tribunal has sentenced Mohamed el Guiudi to death, and
                            Abdul Aziz Hussein to hard labour for life, on a charge of homicide.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>St. Mark's Church.</head>
                        <p>—The preacher &amp; the 11 a.m. service tomorrow (Good Friday) will be
                            the Rev. F.L Denman, M.A, secretary of the London Jews’ Society. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AL Azhar.</head>
                        <p>—Sheikh Mohamed el Gaziri and Sheikh Mohamed Ashurol el Sydfi have been
                            appointed members of the board of administraion of the Al Azhar
                            University. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Native Tribunal</head>
                        <p>at Alexandria has sentenced a native to death for the murder of the
                            omdeh of the village of El Kadr (Behera). His accomplice was sentenced
                            to hard labour for life.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in the Shoubra district of Cairo during the night of Friday and
                            dawn of Saturday, and in the Waily district during the night of Saturday
                            and dawn of Sunday, will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>—16 vessels passed through tho Canal on the 17th inst., 8 of which wore
                            British, 1 French, 1 German, 1 Danish, 1 Norwegian, 1 Dutch. The lay’s
                            receipts were frs. 424,012, making the' total from the 1st inst fro.
                            5,566,032.62. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mohamed Aly Centenary.</head>
                        <p>— This after noon there will be a meeting of Native and European
                            notables at the house of Chawarbi Pasha in Cairo to consider the best
                            means of celebrating tho centenary of the dynasty of Mohamed Aly. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Agricultural Bank.</head>
                        <p>—The Committee of the London Stock Exchange has ordered the
                            undermentioned security to be quoted in the Official List : Agricultural
                            Rank of Egypt,further issue of 62,500 4 per Cent. Cumulative Preferred
                            shares of £10 each, fully paid. Nos. 312,501 to 875,000 (bearer
                            warrants). </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Prisce’s Palace Sold.</head>
                        <p>—“Al Moayad” announces that the palace of Prince Mohamed Aly Pasha has
                            been sold for £250,000. According to our contemporary, the superficies
                            embraces 7,000 square metres, which gives an average of £35 per metre.
                            The sale of the same palace for the sum of £60,000 was announced a few
                            months ago. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Œuvre des Enfants Abandonnes.</head>
                        <p>—We have received the following from the Sister Superior of the Asile St
                            Joseph, Moharrem Bey : “ Très touchées des nombreux témoignages de
                            sympathie prodigués récemment à nos chers enfants, j’ai recours à votre
                            obligeance pour exprimer à tous nos bienfaiteurs notre profonde et
                            sincère gratitude.” </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Ghazi Mukhtar Pasha, Imperial Ottoman High Commissioner, arrived from Cairo
                        at 1.20 p.m. to-day, by special train which drew up at Hadra station. His
                        Excellency, who was met by H. R the Governor, the Sub Governor, and a number
                        of native notables, proceeded with his family to No. 8 Palace. Gbazi Mukhtar
                        Pasha will' leave for Austria by the S.S. "Habsburg” on the 29th inst Signor
                        Martini, Civil Governor of Erythrea, will not arrive at Alexandria on
                        Sunday, as has been stated, having embarked at Naples direct for Massowah.
                        Marquis Salvago Raggi, Italian Diplomatic Agent, has left Cairo for Luxor,
                        where Proffesor Schiaparelli is at present engaged on archeological mission.
                        Dr. Spyridion C. Tracadas has been authorized to follow bis profession in
                        Egypt. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TYROL</head>
                    <p>Weissenstain Castle 8410 hotel near Windiaeh-Matrei ; Station, Liens (reached
                        from Venice or Trieste). Good mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best
                        June and September. Prospectuses and Photographs, "Egyptian Gazette" office,
                        Cairo. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WHITE SLAVE TRAFFIC. MEETING AT GOUVERNORAT.</head>
                    <p>A meeting was held yesterday afternoon at the Alexandria Gouvernorat of the
                        members of the organizing committee for the suppression of the white slave
                        traffic. Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of Alexandria, was in the chair, and
                        those present were M. Girard, doyen of the Consular Corps, Mr. Gould, M.
                        Sootidis, Count Lavison, M. Stechelkounow, M. Szarvasy, Mr.'Preeman, M.
                        Ravelli, Baron Jacques do Meoasco, M. Hamaoui, Baron Felix de Mensace, Mr.
                        Bindernagel, Mr. Chataway, Mr. Atwood, M. Alexandre Padoa, Mr. Rudolph, Mr.
                        laurens, M. George Zervudaohi, M.. Kreutfchner. Messrs. Girard and Gould
                        brought forward a draft of the statutes, which was approved with some slight
                        changes. According to these statutes an International Society is constituted
                        at Alexandria for the suppression of the white slave traffic, in order to
                        put a stop by all due methods to this scandal. The society’s governing body
                        consists of a general committee, of which tho Governor is chairman. This
                        committee selects nine persons as.an executive' committee, which for the
                        first year will consist of Barons. Jacques and Felix de Meuascc, Mr.
                        Hamaoui, Kreutschner, Alexandre Padoa, F. de Planta, Rudolph, D.
                        Tambacopoulo, and George Zen udischi. The organizing committee was then
                        dissolved. We may mention that among the powers of the executive committee
                        is that of forming a committee of ladies to assist them in their work.
                        Subscriptions to this society consist of three categories, i.e.from donors
                        of not leas than £50, annual subscribers of E1, and life members of £20.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PIGMIES IN CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Liuet-Col Harrison recently arrived at Cairo from the Semlihi Valley and
                        Khartoum, bringing with him six pigmies from the Semlihi Forest, four men
                        and two women, whom he was intending to-take to England. The eldest of the
                        women, aged 32 years, was suffering from the effects of an old spear wound
                        in the knee, and we understand that there is no likelihood of the pigmies
                        leaving for England in the near future, if at all, for tie state of their
                        health has given cause for some anxiety, and they are all inmates in the
                        Kasr el-Aini Hospital for the present. Liout-CoL Harrison states that he
                        pursued the Okapi in the Semlihi, but owing to the impenetrable character of
                        tho forest valley, obtained no specimens, though be brought back two damaged
                        skins which he obtained from the natives. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>A meeting was held yesterday afternoon at the Alexandria Gouvernorat of the
                        members of the organizing committee for the suppression of the white slave
                        traffic. Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of Alexandria, was in the chair, and
                        those present were M. Girard, doyen of the Consular Corps, Mr. Gould, M.
                        Sootidis, Count Lavison, M. Stechelkounow, M. Szarvasy, Mr.'Preeman, M.
                        Ravelli, Baron Jacques do Meoasco, M. Hamaoui, Baron Felix de Mensace, Mr.
                        Bindernagel, Mr. Chataway, Mr. Atwood, M. Alexandre Padoa, Mr. Rudolph, Mr.
                        laurens, M. George Zervudaohi, M.. Kreutfchner. Messrs. Girard and Gould
                        brought forward a draft of the statutes, which was approved with some slight
                        changes. According to these statutes an International Society is constituted
                        at Alexandria for the suppression of the white slave traffic, in order to
                        put a stop by all due methods to this scandal. The society’s governing body
                        consists of a general committee, of which tho Governor is chairman. This
                        committee selects nine persons as.an executive' committee, which for the
                        first year will consist of Barons. Jacques and Felix de Meuascc, Mr.
                        Hamaoui, Kreutschner, Alexandre Padoa, F. de Planta, Rudolph, D.
                        Tambacopoulo, and George Zen udischi. The organizing committee was then
                        dissolved. We may mention that among the powers of the executive committee
                        is that of forming a committee of ladies to assist them in their work.
                        Subscriptions to this society consist of three categories, i.e.from donors
                        of not leas than £50, annual subscribers of E1, and life members of £20. </p>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive arrived at Abdeen this morning and presided over a meeting
                        of the Ministères His Highness afterwards gave audience to Lord Cromer, Rev.
                        Father Godefray, the curate of St Joeeph’s Church, Ismailia, and Scnor De
                        Lari os, who presented M. Camalada, Judge of the Mixed Tribunal at
                        Mansourah. This afternoon, his Highness gave audience to M. de la
                        Boulinière, who presented M. Bonin, second secretary of the Preach Agency,
                        and M. Bretschneider. Tomorrow his Highness will pray at Koub-beh mosque. At
                        10.30 Am. on Saturday his Highness will receive Count Boleita Kodziobrodaki,
                        the new Austro-Hungarian Diplomatic Agent, who will present his letters of
                        credence. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>P. W. D. CONTRATS.</head>
                    <p>The contract for the construction of annexes to the Tewfikieh School at Kasr
                        el Nooiha, Cairo, has been given to Messrs. Guétin and Charvant, the price
                        being L.E 10,022. The contract for the extension of the Zagh-lonla Canal
                        from KiL 11 to KiL 21 has been given M.P Marsili, the price being L.E2,439.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXECUTIONS IN CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>On Monday, Issa Diab Ramadan, who murdered one Mabmond Ahmed Gabr at Tabbar,
                        in the Fayoum, was executed at Cairo. The murderer, who showed no signs of
                        fear, confessed his crime, stating that be had discovered the existence of
                        improper relations between his wife and the murdered man, and avenged his
                        honor by a blow of a hammer. On Tuesday,- the ghaffir Abd el Mangud Ahmed
                        Rizak, of Kafr el Gbananieh, was also executed in the prison of the Native
                        Court of Appeal at Cairo. The ghaffir murdered and robbed a Greek merchant
                        named Kiroa Nicholas on Docember 20, 1904. This is tho fourth execution that
                        has taken place in four successive days. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate charges.
                        Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi
                        Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good -----</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very ---- Brand of
                        Beer</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x xx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOCIETE EGYPTIENNE DE LA DAIRA SANIEH.</head>
                    <p>The decree was signed by the Khedive on Monday authorizing the Daira Saniah
                        Company, Limited, represented by Sir El win Palmer, Sir Ernest Cassel, Sir
                        El win Palmer, M. Raphal Suarès, Harari Pasha, M. Simon Rolo and Mr. Léon
                        Carton da Wiart, at their risk and peril, and without any responsibility on
                        the part of the Government, to form a limited liability company in Egypt
                        under the style of the "Société Egyptienne de la Daira Sanieh.” The object
                        of the company is to take over all the assets and liabilities of the Daira
                        Sanieh Company, Limited. This company will have a capital of £600,030;
                        divided into 118,006 shares of £5 each and 10,000 deferred shares of Xl
                        each. The board of the company will consist of Sir Elwin Palmer, Sirv
                        Vincent Gaillard, Aly Bey Charaoui, Orookahank Pasha, M. François
                        Dusseiguour, Viscount Esher, M. J.vay Lus-sac, Mr. Carl Meyer, Mr. Robert
                        Miller, Sir John G. Rogers, M. Simon Rolo Sir Edward A. Sassoon, M. Raphael
                        Suarès, and Sir William AWard. 118,000 ordinary fully paid up shares and thé
                        10,000 deferred shares are defrred to remunerate the "apport” made by the
                        Daira Sanieh Company, Limited, and to be allotted share for share among the
                        holders of shares and of deferred shares of this company. The surplus of the
                        shares, six ordinary, have been subscribed and fully paid np by Sir Ernest
                        Cassel, Sir Elwin Palmer, M. Raphael Suarès, Harari Pasha, M. Simon Rolo,
                        and M. Léon Carton da Wiart, each one share. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IMPORTANT PROPERTY SALE</head>
                    <p>Hassan Pasha Mohsen and Mr. William B. Rees have purchased tho Gorbal estate
                        of 400,000 square pics situated between the Attarin quarter of Alexandria
                        and the Mahmoudi eh Canal. This fine building estate is to be greatly
                        developed and should fond a salubrious suburb of Alexandria. There is no
                        truth in the report, published in a local newspaper yesterday, to the effect
                        that Mr. Hooker had made offers to these gentlemen to purchase the estate at
                        an enhanced price. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>In the prospectus of Messrs. G. M. Callender &amp; Co, limited, who have just
                        made an issue of 25,000 preference shares, >e note that tho formation of a
                        company to manufacture the materials necessary for their business, in Egypt,
                        where the company has carried out important works, has been decided upon by
                        the directors. From a report made to the board by the managing director
                        relative to the negotiations and interviews which he has conducted in Egypt,
                        the directors believe that the whole of the requisite working capital for
                        such a company can be found locally in Egypt by gentlemen who are well
                        acquainted with the merits of the compony's materials and whose connection
                        with the company here should prove invaluable. Under the contemplated
                        arrangements the company will be entitled to one-half of the profits of the
                        Egyptian company, the basis of such arrangements being that it is to receive
                        an amount in fully-paid shares of such company equivalent to the cash
                        capital Messrs. G. M. Callender &amp; Co., Limited, are the sole suppliers
                        of Callender's pure bitumen dam-course, Callender's pure bitnmen sheeting
                        and Callender’s damp resisting solution. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN LAND INVESTMENT CO.</head>
                    <p>A meeting of the board of directors of the Egyptian Land Investment Company,
                        Limited, was held at the Bank of Egypt at Alexandria yesterday afternoon.
                        Mr. Edward Poliak, the secretary of the Austro-Hungarian Chamber of Commerce
                        and the agent of the Rinnione Adriatica Fire and Life Insurance Company, was
                        appointed as manager of the company. Mr. Poliak is an old resident at
                        Alexandria, having had a considerable experience of business in Egypt,and we
                        congratulate the company on its selection. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DISPUTE OVER EGYPTIAN MINING CONCESSIONS. </head>
                    <p>Mr. Justice Kekewich, in the Chancery Division last week, had before him the
                        matter of Brown v. Haig and Oxley, arising out of a pending action by Mr.
                        Archibald Knox Brown, a mining engineer, against the defendants with regard
                        to a disputed partnership in some mining concessions in Egypt and the Sudan.
                        Mr. P. Ogden Lawrence, K.C., for Mr. Haig, said the application against the
                        plaintiff was that he should be ordered to give security for costs in a
                        pending action, and he would also submit that the notice of trial was
                        irregular. After hearing Mr. Terrell for the plaintiff, his lordship ordered
                        the plaintiff to give security for £100 to each of the defendants. As to the
                        notice of trial his lordship found that the rules had not been observed, and
                        he therefore set aside the notice of trial on this, plaintiff's counsel at
                        once gave fresh notice of trial </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lake of Como - Como. "PLINIUS” GRAND HOTEL</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="shareMarket"><head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
                    <p>(From OUR Financial Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>London, April 14.</p>
                    <p>While in matters financial the same conditions on the Stock Markets have
                        ruled as were ruling last week the issue of the South African Trust, and the
                        most recent Egyptian companies have thrown extraordinary light upon the
                        amount of capital ready for investment The applications in England and
                        France for that company are stated to have amounted to £20,000,000, showing
                        there are still in these two countries investors with sufficient confidence
                        in the future of “Kaffirs" to put in as much again as has been invested up
                        to the present This, taken in conjunction with what we call attention to
                        below, would seem unmistakably to point to ranch enlarged markets in the
                        future, and considerably higher prices for investments, even in the mining
                        class The future of cheap money seeming to be assured, it would look as if a
                        return to these conditions most lead to an altogether higher level of
                        prices, especially when considered in conjunction with the Government plans
                        of not making any further issue of Consols this year. As soon as the new
                        issue of £10,000.000 Exchequer Bonds, which has been greatly sought after,
                        is out of the way, a considerable rise in Consols would appear to be
                        inevitable if the political barometer is undisturbed. There is much leeway
                        yet to be made up by first-class investment securities, and as soon as these
                        have appreciated, the demand for more speculative stocks is sore to follow.
                        The accounts of the Easter holidays will no doubt delay events for a short
                        time. </p>
                    <p>Quite the feature of the past week, in spite of the fact that the Egyptian
                        market has been dull and quiet, has been the phenomenal securities that has
                        attended the flotation of the Egyptian Trust and Investment, Ltd. Although
                        the promoters were only asking for £200,000, the following figures, we are
                        informed, represent the amounts applied for :— In London—£1,012,037 In
                        Egypt— £9,759,429 or a grand total of £10,771,466. In other words, over
                        £1,000,000 was put down in application money alone. The number of applicants
                        exceeded 5,000,. The allotment of the shares will be made to-day. It will
                        take place simultaneously in London and Egypt and each distribution is
                        independent of the other. The price of the shares is nominally 5/8 premium,
                        although we doubt if they could be bought even at 3/4 premium. We understand
                        the rush for the prospectus was so great that, although the London Bank
                        applied for more copies a day or two before the issue was made, the company
                        were unable to famish them Cut enough, to-keep pace with the demand. The
                        Egyptian market, with the exception of the mining section, which is weak,
                        keeps fairly firm. Dairas hold their price well at 27 1/8, and both National
                        and Agricultural Banks keep strong, though both these prices really look
                        quite high enough at 27 1/8 and 13 3/8. Egyptian Markets have come in for
                        some attention this week, and have hardened to 1 3/8, and look good for a
                        further improvement The issue of shares at 2 has not affected the price of
                        Delta Lands. </p>
                    <p>The remarkable success of the last new issue, the Egyptian Trust and
                        Investment, Ltd., has been referred to above. The Egyptian Laid and General
                        Trusty issued two days previously, iras also largely oversubscribed, and the
                        shares stand at 1/2premium. This company. is in good hands as far as the
                        market is concentrated, and should do well. </p>
                    <p>In the mining section the North Nile Company's report was a weak point, and
                        upset what was already a dull market, so that prices have given way
                        considerably. Fresh capital requirements are spoken of in several cases.
                        What business there is is of a very professional nature. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. MARK’S CHURCH,. JUBILEE OP CONSECRATION.</head>
                    <p>April 25, 1905, is the 50th anniversary of the consecration of St. Mark’s
                        Church, by Samuel Gobât D.D., Anglican Bishop in Jerusalem and the East. To
                        commemorate the jubilee of consecration it is proposed to unveil and
                        dedicate on the festival of St Mark, a brass tablet mounted on marble,
                        erected in the south porch of the church. This tablet will record with dates
                        the chief points in the history of the church, and will give a list with
                        date of consecration, of Anglican Bishops in Jerusalem and the Bast and also
                        a list of the chaplains of St Mark's. The winged lion of St Mark, with
                        opened book of the Gospels, the Arms of the Bishopric, and the Jerusalem
                        Cross will also appear on the tablet </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Windsor Pharmacy</head>
                    <p>Kasr-el-Nil Square, CAIRO. BEIT CHEMICAL PRODUCTS, English and Foreign
                        Prescriptions carefully prepared by Certified Chemists ALWAYS IN STOCK
                        LARGEVASSORTMENT OF ENGLISH PROPRIETARY ARTICLES &amp; SPECIALTIES </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDEN PLACE HOTEL</head>
                    <p>CAIRO Open All Year Round</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGAL NOTES. MIXED COURT OF APPEAL</head>
                    <p>At yesterdays sitting of the Court of Appeal, presided over by M. de Konmu,
                        several interesting cases were beard. One concerned the question as to
                        whether, in consequence of the decree of November, 1904 (following the
                        Anglo-French Agreement), the Egyptian State, Railways, in relation to
                        treaties, were still under the jurisdiction of the Mixed Tribunals. The
                        point was a purely legal one, and the arguments were a ably put forward by
                        Counsel for the appellants, and Sciarahati Bey for the Government. A claim
                        for damages amounting to £7,500 against the International 'Sleeping Car
                        Company was disposed of A waiter in the service of the company was injured
                        in accident which occurred in 1908. The patient was doing well under the.
                        treatment of the company's doctors, Dr. Madden and Dr. Phillips, but he
                        developed “railway spine” after the unusual period of nine months after
                        abandoning the company’s doctors. The Cairo Tribunal granted him £1,400
                        instead of £600 which the oompany offered as equivalent to his net salary of
                        £4 a month for his lifetime. Both parties appealed The claimant set forward
                        his points through Me. Volpini, replacing Me. Ballis of Cairo. Me. Carton de
                        Wiart appeared for the company and forcibly pat forward its position,
                        maintaining the offer in spite of the curious circumstances of the case.
                        There was also an action for the illegitimate use of tobacco packing cases,
                        in which Me. Manusardianly defended the Salomon Cigarette Company, whilst
                        Me. Carton de Wiart strongly advocated the appeal of Messrs. Sabi Bros., the
                        Cairo merchants. The case of Boustros Bros. v. the Alexandria Stockbrokers’
                        Association will be heard on the 26th inst </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES, Le paquebot poste "Ismailia" de là compagnie Khédiviale parti
                        hier pour Pirés, Smyrna, Metelin, Dardanelles et Constantinople, avait à
                        bord : Mr. and Mme Jean SevastopooloJE. et Mme H. Hermanoviu, M. et Mme
                        ÊW.Boyse, M. st Mme W. Speokmann, Honorable et Mme A Davey, M. et Mme J. H.
                        Von Egben, M. st Mme Geo. Zaldari, M. et Mme N. Rmalhnan et famille, M. et
                        Mme CL Nioolaoo, M. et Mme De Bÿ-Verhagen, M. et Mme Ulysse Couelelis, M ait
                        Mme Antoine Bpigliatoponlo et famille, M. et Mme W. Peacock et fomilla, M.
                        K. P. Birley, Comte Nicolas M croate, Comte de Karff, A. Umarovich, Mr. et
                        Mlle F. Lark-worthy Bvagelo Alexandre ù, J. M. Harley, R Felowiclri, M.
                        Tottenham, Geo. Milonas, H. Christodulides, M. Weckaelbaum, Ernst Dsut-sch,
                        Mlles Mary Marrogordato st Q. Gordon, Baron W. de Giel-Giealingen, R
                        Drinkwatar, P. J. Blwes, Mmes N. Twoney, EUy 0'Brien, A et N. Heywood,
                        Carazxia et 8 enfants, Constantinidas, Willy Schwarts, N. Georgantas, A.
                        Mittaraochi, Mlle Zellender, M. Const Gianellis, Geo. Nakkas, 0. Lewis,
                        Gaston Riche Const Benderly, W. Assmann, Mme Aspaxia Triandafilidi st son
                        fils, Mlles Areky de Carpuri, Philo Zohrah, Disc. Vassiliou, Mary Way 1er,
                        Mme P. Paraake-vaa, Despina Mavroudia, D. Q. Umhados, Bonne Mme Towney, Mme
                        Sakellaridi, et 2 fils, F. Printed. N. Apostilidi, R Zixxio, Geo. Coas tan
                        tinou, Geo. Naoomidea, P. Zachariadis, Aug. Mihailou, Fandeli Mihailon,
                        Andrea Triandafilidia, S. Caloyers, Q. Trin-gopoulo, Hans Konnan, Geo.
                        Droseoponlo, Const Miltiadis, Laden Sciuto, D. Garminiao, Behaldik Rahmy
                        Zade, Geo. Papadopoulos, Const Coumonlas, D. Theologhides, Ant Stamouli,
                        Mihran Da vidian, Theodore Aposto-lidi, Michel Prinio, Nicolas Cantraa,
                        Dimitri Mihailidia, Hassan Effendi Amer, Mustapha dJrfi, M. Cladois, Aly Bey
                        Moubarak, et 850 passagers de pont </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Salarie,” from Alexandria, arrived at
                        Marseilles yesterday morning. The Moss liner ’Tabor" sailed from Malta
                        yèsterday afternoon, and is due here on Saturday afternoon* with passengers,
                        mails, and general cargo. The Papayanni liner "Belgravian ’ sailed yesterday
                        for Liverpool with oargo. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="legal">
                    <head>CHRONIQUE JUDICIAIRE </head>
                    <div type="item"><head>TRIBUNAL MIXTE DU CAIRE</head>
                    <p>Uh village dost lb haut axis boit IXFULSÉ8 Lundi a été appelée par devant U
                        Tribunal mixte do Caire an prooès appelé à avoir un grand retentissement
                        Tous les habitant* da village de la fabrique de la Daira Sanieh à Armant au
                        nombre de 4,000 personnes qui avaient conrtruit ledit village se sont vu»
                        sur le point d’être expulsés par des acquéreurs auxquels la Daira Sanieh a
                        vendu le village tout entier. Toutes les démarchas auprès des autorités
                        n’ayant pas réussi à réparer ostto injustice, dit le Journal du Caire,
                        lssdita habitants du village se sont vus obligés de s’idresrer à L justioe
                        pour obtenir satisfaction contre Iss prétention» exorbitantes de la Daira et
                        ont oonflé te soin de leur défonce à Maître Ayrat hey, l'avocat W» tous du
                        barreau égyptien, </p>
                </div></div>

            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
