<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Emma Taylor</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-19"> October 19, 2016></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-16">November 16, 1905></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- 7,347, 1905-11-16, 6 -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS. ANOTHER GENERAL STRIKE. CRITICAL SITUATION. BOTH
                        CAPITALS CUT OFF. FOREIGN RESIDENTS LEAVING.</head>

                    <p>( Gazette's Special Service ).</p>

                    <p>London, November 16.</p>

                    <p>Private advices received from St Petersburg portray a gloomier position than
                        is shown by the press reports. 90,000 workmen are already on strike. British
                        and other foreign residents are leaving the Capital.</p>

                    <p>A private telegram received at Alexandria this morning announces that the
                        Russian Government has notified the Powers that all foreigners should be
                        withdrawn,as the Russian authorities are powerless to protect them.</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The council of workmen’s delegates has decided upon another general strike to
                        day, owing to the employers having refused the eight-hoars’ work proposal,
                        but it is intimated that the real object of the strike is largely political.
                        The situation is critical. (Reuter.)</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 15.</p>

                    <p>M. Witte’s Polish proclamation is almost universally condemned throughout
                        Russia. It is pointed out that a timely concession in Finland appeased that
                        country.</p>

                    <p>The council of workmen’s delegates declared a general strike, beginning at
                        noon, in sympathy with the revolutionists at Kronstadt and in Poland. The
                        strike began punctually in all the great works, and on all the railways
                        radiating from this city, except the line to Moscow. Both capitals are cot
                        off from the rest of Europe. The strike is rapidly becoming general. Fifteen
                        high officials met at M. Witte’s to discuss the proclamation of martial law
                        here.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Warsaw, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The police has begun to arrest the prominent Polish leaders.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The strike has been resumed in many of the works.</p>
                    <p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUTINY AT VLADIVOSTOK. TOWN IN FLAMES.</head>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 15.</p>

                    <p>It is reported here that a mutiny has broken out at Vladivostok. Fierce
                        fighting has taken place between the rioters and the loyalists, soldiers and
                        sailors taking part on either side. A great part of the town is in flames.
                        The mutiny was finally suppressed after a state of war had been
                        declared.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Vladivostok, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The mutiny here was due to the discontent of soldiers not sent home.</p>

                    <p>300 rioters, principally soldiers and sailors, were killed or wounded during
                        the first day of the outbreak.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Vladivostok, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The Reservists, who are demanding disbandment, have pillaged the town.</p>
                    <p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREAT BRITAIN AND GREECE. THE KING’S TOAST.</head>

                    <p>London, November 15.</p>

                    <p>At a banquet at Windsor King Edward, in proposing the toast of his health,
                        said that he was glad to receive King George, who had ruled so successfully
                        that Greece was now in a most flourishing condition. The study of the
                        glorious language and history of Ancient Greece in no wise diminishes our
                        sympathy and friendship with the Greece of to-day.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>London, November 15.</p>

                    <p>The visit of the King of Greece to the City and the lunch at the Guildhall
                        were marked by a hearty popular welcome to the Queen’s brother.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER BOMB EXPLOSION IN STAMBOUL.</head>

                    <p>Constantinople, November 15.</p>

                    <p>A bomb was thrown at Pera into the carriage of Fehmy Pasha, Chief of the
                        Palace Police, who was unhurt The damage is slight Three Armenians have been
                        arrested on suspicion.</p>

                    <p>(Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Constantinople, November 15.</p>

                    <p>A bomb exploded in the main street of Pera behind the carriage of Fehmy
                        Pasha, but did not injure anybody.</p>
                    <p>(Havas</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>INVENTOR OF TORPEDO DEAD.</head>

                    <p>London, November 15.</p>

                    <p> Mr. J. Whitehead, the torpedo inventor, is dead.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>H M.S. ASSISTANCE REFLOATED</head>

                    <p>Tangier, November 15.</p>

                    <p>H.M.S. Assistance has been refloated. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

                    <p>Beau Rivage.</p>

                    <p>The Beau-Rivage Hotel, Ramleh, closed its doors for the season yesterday.</p>

                    <p>Stray Dogs.</p>

                    <p>Stray and ownerless dogs found in the Khalifa district of Cairo daring the
                        night of Friday will be poisoned by the police.</p>

                    <p>The Pilgrimage.</p>

                    <p>Up to date 23,977 pilgrims have asked for passports for the pilgrimage to the
                        Holy Places.</p>

                    <p>Slave Emancipation.</p>

                    <p>The Repression of the Slave Trade Department during the last month gave
                        manumission papers to fourteen Sudanese slaves.</p>

                    <p>Aboukir Company.</p>

                    <p>Mr. S. Gurney Sheppard has been elected a director of the Aboukir Co. (Ltd.),
                        in place of Mr. Samuel G. Sheppard, deceased.</p>

                    <p>Egyptian Army.</p>

                    <p>The competition for H.E. the Sirdar’s Prize will take place on Tuesday. 5th
                        December, 1905, on the Abbassieh Rifle Range.</p>

                    <p>A Change of Religion.</p>

                    <p>A great sensation has been aroused at Mellawi by the conversion of the
                        headmaster of the Coptic School there to Islam.</p>

                    <p>Ports and Lighthouses Administration.</p>

                    <p>The tender submitted by Messrs. Suzzarini and Stienon on the 31st October.
                        1905; has been accepted for the supply of 3,000 sq. m. of paving stones.</p>

                    <p>Mixed Appeal Court.</p>

                    <p>Basili Pasha Tadros has been appointed honorary president of the Mixed Appeal
                        Court. The appointment will be officially confirmed at the next Council of
                        Minister.</p>

                    <p>Suez Canal.</p>

                    <p>On the 12th inst. 13 vessels passed through the Canal, 8 of which were
                        British, 9 German, 2 Austrian, 1 Turkish. The total receipts from the 1st to
                        the 12th inst. were frs. 4,045,331.80,</p>

                    <p>Rosetta Municipality.</p>

                    <p>It is announced that the Finance Ministry will contribute L.E. 300 per annum
                        to the expenses of the Municipality which is to be instituted at
                        Rosetta.</p>

                    <p>German Excavations.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Rubinson, the well known German Egyptologist, who vi. its Egypt every
                        winter, will conduct some excavations this winter at Ashmouneen and
                        Elephantine on behalf of the Berlin Museum.</p>

                    <p>Sudan Mines.</p>

                    <p>Application has been made to the Stock Exchange committee to appoint a
                        special settling day in Sudan Mines, Limited - 40 000 Vendors’ shares of £1
                        each, folly paid (Nos. 20,001 to 60,000).</p>

                    <p>Cairo Tramways.</p>

                    <p>As the Public Works Department has decided to asphalt Fagallah street, the
                        Abbassieh trams will follow the route Ataba el Khadra, Mohamed Ali street,
                        Mousky, and Daher from January 1, 1906, till the completion of the
                        asphalting of the above-mentioned street.</p>

                    <p>Electric Wire Falls.</p>

                    <p>A Syrian, while crossing Fagallah-street, Cairo, at 7.15 p.m., on Tuesday,
                        was struck bv a falling overhead wire and tell insensible. Immediate aid was
                        rendered and it is hoped that he will be saved. Is it quite impossible for
                        guard wires to be provided ?</p>
                    <p>Kuttabs.</p>

                    <p>The native notables throughout the provinces are showing a praiseworthy
                        keenness in the foundation of new kuttabs. At a meeting of the notables of
                        Shebrakhit it was decided to found 21 kuttabs. At a meeting of the Menoufieh
                        notables it was agreed to make a bequest of 200 feddans for the upkeep of
                        the kuttabs recently created.</p>

                    <p>Coastguard Administration,</p>

                    <p>Mr. Pascal Bavastro, of the Coastguards Central Bureau, has retired from the
                        service of the Egyptian Government, which he entered in May, 1888. Since
                        then he has been chief cashier, private secretary, and chief of the European
                        Bureau, and his valuable services will be greatly missed. He received the
                        Medjidieh in 1901.</p>

                    <p>A Sad Case.</p>

                    <p> A young woman of the name of Lettohorn was tried at the Native Assize Court,
                        Cairo, on Tuesday last for having caused the death of her new-born child.
                        The young woman was seduced by her lover, who, on learning that she was
                        about to become a mother, abandoned her. The Court, in considering the
                        extenuating circumstances of the cases, sentenced her to two years’
                        imprisonment.</p>

                    <p>Amateur Theatricals in Cairo.</p>

                    <p>Our readers will remember the success that the amateur performance of The
                        Pirates of Penzance met with last season at the Khedivial Opera House,
                        Cairo. We are now informed that a committee is about to be formed to take up
                        the question of staging some comic opera in Cairo for the coming season, the
                        proceeds of which will be distributed among the chief English and American
                        charities.</p>

                    <p>A. L. M. &amp; D. S.</p>

                    <p>The Alexandria Literary, Musical and Dramatic Society’s season will commence
                        on Monday, December 4, when a lecture will be given on “The Desert of 8inai”
                        by Dr. Marc Armand Ruffer, M.A., M D., C.M.G., president of the Quarantine
                        Board. The lecture will be illustrated by some 50 or 60 lantern slides. It
                        will be remembered that Dr. Ruffer visited the Sinaitio Desert last spring,
                        spending some time in studying the country and taking photographs.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES AFFAIR. PROPOSED ARRANGEMENT.</head>

                    <p>The following proposals will be submitted to the creditors of the Sucreries
                        Company at the meeting to be held at 3 p.m. to-day.</p>

                    <p>1. All creditors other than employes, depositors, purveyors, and holders of
                        obligations and Cronier bills are to abandon 20 per oent of their credit and
                        accept in lieu thereof privileged shares bearing 5 per cent interest.</p>

                    <p>2. That 800,000 bands are to be issued on mortgage and are to be employed to
                        buy out the shares of the Daira Sugar Corporation, the surplus to form a
                        working fund for the company.</p>

                    <p>3. The Daira Sugar Corporation renounces 1 per cent, of the annual interest,
                        being the difference between the interest on the present shares and that on
                        the shares to be issued to them on payment.</p>

                    <p>4. As tor the shareholders, they are to receive one new share for each three
                        original shares which they hold.</p>

                    <p>Further details as to the arrangement should be made public this
                        afternoon.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT’S TRADE. OCTOBER RETURNS.</head>

                    <p>The Customs returns for last month are very satisfactory, and both the
                        imports and exports show satisfactory increases on the returns for the
                        previous October. The imports amounted to L.E. 2,504,550 and the exports to
                        LB 1,939,074, being increases respectively of L.E. 381,221 and LE. 128,508
                        on the returns for the corresponding month last year. The imports for the
                        ten months op to the 31st alt were L.E. 17 221,409, a surplus of LE
                        1,527,700 on the figures for the same period in 19 4,and the exports
                        amounted to LE. 14,817.247, a decrease of L.E. 717,738 on the figures for
                        1904.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN EGYPTIAN PRINCESS’S FLIGHT.</head>

                    <p>According to news just received from Constantinople an Egyptian Princess who
                        used to reside every summer in one of the Prince’s Islands in the sea of
                        Marmara, has suddenly disappeared without a word of warning. It is stated
                        that matrimonial troubles are at the bottom of the matter and that a divorce
                        wilt ensue.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROBBERY AT MENOUF.</head>

                    <p>The Ministry of the Interior reports that M. Carthalis, a Greek merchant of
                        Alexandria, recently complained that his agent, who bad taken from the post
                        office at Menouf the sum of LE. 1,000 destined for the Ghamamieh ginning
                        factory, was attacked on the way to the factory by Arabs who robbed him of
                        all the money.</p>

                    <p>The enquiries made by the moudirieh authorities resulted in the discovery of
                        the bag which had contained the LB 1,000, and still contained L.E 893, under
                        the threshold of the sister of one of the members of the gang. During the
                        enquiry the brother, who had been arrested, admitted his participation in
                        the theft and revealed the place where he had bidden L E. 77. The remaining
                        L E. 30 had been spent by the culprits, all of whom have been arrested. They
                        are six in number ; four have confessed and denounced the other two. We
                        wonder how ?</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FATAL PIT.</head>

                    <p>A native of Karnak, near Luxor, had reason to believe that his house was
                        built over an ancient tomb or some old building, wherein a great treasure
                        was awaiting discovery. He dug a huge pit and succeeded in coming upon an
                        old door, which after some trouble he managed to get open. He entered, but
                        never came out alive. His wife became alarmed at her husband's long absence
                        and at last took a lamp and made her way down the excavation to the dorr.
                        She likewise did not come back. The son and daughter then went in search of
                        their father and mother* and they also disappeared. A native of the same
                        village, finding the house deserted, determined also to go down, and on
                        getting to the door became asphyxiated. The omdeh got to hear of this fatal
                        pit and informed the markez authorities. The bodies of the man and his wife
                        and two children were discovered just inside the door, they evidently having
                        been suffocated by the foul air. The story is told by our vernacular
                        contemporary “A1 Moayad ”</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BOURSE LANE</head>

                    <p>To The Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>

                    <p>Sir,—Tho block in Bourae-lane is increasing, and every day this convenient
                        and moat central thoroughfare is becoming more and more eneumbered. The
                        latest addition to the lane is an elaborate bar for the sale of syrups, etc,
                        which takes op a great deal of room. Has the Municipality any right to grant
                        reksas for the occupation of the thoroughfare, to the great inconvenience of
                        the public ?—I am, etc</p>

                    <p>In A. Hurry.</p>

                    <p>Alexandria, Nov. 16.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

                    <p>The Moss liner Menes sailed from Malta yesterday afternoon and is due here on
                        Saturday next with passengers, mails and general cargo.</p>

                    <p>The S.S. Orestes (Westcott and Laurence Lire) left Malta to day and is doe
                        here on the 19th inst, with general cargo from Antwerp and London,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALT AND SODA CO. THE MONOPOLY—A DIVIDEND.</head>

                    <p>It is stated that the directors of the Salt and Soda Company have come to an
                        arrangement with the Government The company, as a solatium for the abolition
                        of the monopoly. will be granted the concession for six years of all the
                        salt-pits in Egypt.</p>

                    <p>The board of directors of the company has decided to distribute a dividend at
                        the rate of 4 per cent. for all shares.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DESERT CAMP, HELOUAN.</head>

                    <p>Our readers are doubtless aware of the existence of the many open-air
                        institutions in England and on the Continent, it being claimed, with no
                        small degree of reason, that living and Bleeping in the open air is
                        conducive to regaining and maintaining the best conditions of health.
                        Believing, as we do,the correctness of these principles, we are pleased to
                        bo able to announce that an open-air camp on the most up-to-date lines has
                        been erected in the desert at Helouan. The camp has been pitched to the
                        north of the town, adjoining the golf links and race-course, and forms from
                        its delightfully open position and structure an ideal spot for those who may
                        come to Egypt for health sake daring the present winter.</p>

                    <p>The camp consists of single rooms and a sitting-room combined with sheltered
                        verandahs, eta, comfortably furnished, open at the same time on all Bides to
                        the desert and fitted with every convenience. The whole is lighted by
                        electric light and the hygienic arrangements are on English lines.</p>

                    <p>There are two golf links (10 and 12 holes), tennis courts, cricket-ground,
                        the miniature rifle range of the H S.C., eta, all within a stone’s throw of
                        the camp. The camp is under the immediate personal supervision and direction
                        of Dr. A. J. M. Bentley, and as only about 15 patients are received, special
                        individual attention, which is so necessary to a successful result, is
                        assured.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>HONOR TO WHOM, &amp;c.</head>

                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>

                    <p>Dear Sir.—Will yon allow me a little space for a word of praise for the
                        prompt and energetic action of Yousbashi Waller and bis staff of firemen, in
                        coping with a fire at Ibrahimieh yesterday ? At about 10.30 a.m. my wife
                        telephoned to me in town that a fire had broken out, as I understood, at
                        home, advising the fire station at the same time. My son and I drove
                        straight out at once and found the house of Mr. Sabatelli, a building partly
                        of lath and plaster and partly of wood, situated about eight yards from
                        ours, in flames, and the Fire Brigade already at work. Not withstanding the
                        light and inflammable nature of the building, after some two hoars of work
                        the fire was extinguished, part of the house and of its contents being
                        saved, and the fire prevented from spreading to the adjoining
                        buildings.—Yours faithfully,</p>

                    <p>P. Schilizzi.</p>

                    <p>Ibrahimieh, Nov. 15.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COTTON MARKET. Kearslby and Cunningham's Weekly Report.</head>

                    <p>Liverpool, November 9.</p>

                    <p>Egyptian Cotton has been in more extensive demand at advanced prices, the
                        quotation of Brown being raised 1/4 per lb, except Fine, which is 3/15d. In
                        Upper the supply is limited, Good Fair being 2/15d and Fully Good Fair 1/2d
                        dearer; the higher qualities are unchanged.</p>

                    <p>In Futures a good business has been done, and the following are the closing
                        values :</p>

                    <p>Nov. 8.19 Jan. 8.8 Mar. 8.6 May. 8,6 Dec. 7.12 Feb. 8.7 Apr. 8.6 June 8.7
                        July. &amp;7</p>

                    <p>AMERICAN FUTURES. - The Market this week has displayed great activity, and
                        prices have experienced a considerable advance, being at one time as much as
                        33 @ 35 points higher than those of last Thursday. This induced free
                        liquidation, and prices had a sharp reaction, but to-day’s dosing values are
                        only 3@ 5 points below the extreme rates touched. Bad Crop reports, with
                        greatly reduced estimates of the yield, coupled with heavy purchases to
                        cover by the “Bears,’’ and well maintained manipulation by the “Bulls” and
                        the withholding of the actual cotton in the South, are amongst the principal
                        causes of this rapid advance, amounting to nearly Id per lb in the last
                        three weeks. The Ginners’ report indicates. a far as one can judge, a yield
                        of about 10 1/2 millions, but the Bureau Report of the Crop, i.e., the
                        condition of the Crop which is to be issued to-morrow, is regarded with
                        greater interest, and will have a very important and immediate effect upon
                        the course of prices. It is impossible to forecast it, but general sentiment
                        is looking for higher prices. We are inclined to think that the serious
                        condition of the Crop is being exaggerated, and that present values discount
                        a great deal.</p>

                    <p>The following are the closing quotations:— Nov. 6.01 Feb./Mar. 6.12 Jnne/July
                        6.17</p>

                    <p>Nov./Dec. 6.01 Mar./Apr. 6.14 July/Ang. 6.19 Dec./Jan. 6.05 Apr./May 6.15
                        Aug/Sept. — Jan./Feb. 6.09 May/June 6.16</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN COTTON.</head>

                    <p>Messrs. Collinge Brothers, Liverpool, cable as follows Price hammering New
                        York on increased crop estimates. Advise friends to have no interest for the
                        moment.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Warton Collinge cables from New York as follows Market weak on increased
                        crop estimates. Price cabling over the South. Expect serious break in cotton
                        market-Personally I think liquidation over.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW BRITISH CLUB. LAST NIGHTS MEETING.</head>

                    <p>A sufficient number of replies having been received to the provisional
                        committee’s circular , to warrant the formation of the proposed new British
                        Club at Alexandria, a general meeting of those who had signified their
                        intention of joining was held at the Eastern Telegraph Company’s
                        headquarters last night. About sixty gentlemen responded. Admiral Sir Massie
                        Blomfield, R.N..K.C.M.G.,was voted to the chair, and addressed the meeting
                        as fellows:</p>

                    <p>“The printed circulars sent to yon by the provisional committee will have
                        sufficiently explained the object of our meeting this evening, and the
                        response to these circulars assures ns that oar view as to the demand for a
                        local British club at a low rate of annual subscription was not mistaken.
                        Before proceeding to the business on the agenda, I should like to explain
                        that the subscription was fixed at £ .10 0 per annum, because the committee
                        understood that that is the highest rate within the means of all the members
                        for whose benefit it is proposed to establish the club. This rate of
                        subscription having been made the basis of our appeal to you for the
                        formation of the club, cannot be increased except by a practical unanimous
                        vote of those who have responded in the affirmative, until the club is
                        properly constituted with a committee of management and established rules.
                        As the present number of members at £1.10 per annum is not likely to produce
                        a greater annual revenue than £300 per annum, whilst the annual donations
                        cannot be counted on for more than £100 per annum —making £400 in all—the
                        provisional committee can only recommend for your selection premises whose
                        annual rental will not exceed £200. As regards the furnishing expenses
                        guaranteed by us, the funds at present at the disposal of the committee, or
                        promised,amount to £500. It is obvious that, under such conditions, the club
                        most be started on an economical basis with modest pretensions ; but this
                        need not discourage us in our belief and hope that the club will progress
                        and prove a great boon to those for whose nee it is intended, by enabling
                        them to enjoy one another's society, and become better acquainted, in a home
                        of their own conducted by themselves on strict principles.’’</p>

                    <p>"We now come” (added the chairman)"to the first item of the agenda, the
                        election of a committee of management, and we have great pleasure in telling
                        you that the Earl of Cromer has done us the honor to accept the presidency
                        of the olnb.” This announcement was received with applause. The meeting then
                        proceeded to the election of two vice-presidents, and unanimously voted in
                        favor of Sir Massie Blomfield and Mr. E. B. Gould, 1.S.0.</p>

                    <p>A discussion subsequently took place as to the name which the club should
                        bear, and it was found to be the general feeling of the meeting that the
                        club should be known simply as the British Club. This led to some talk
                        regarding the definition of British, much of which was irrelevant, and
                        finally it was agreed to leave the question as to the class of British
                        subjects to be admitted to membership for the committee to decide.</p>

                    <p>Voting then took place for the members of the committee, the following eleven
                        gentlemen being elected : Messrs. J. Hughes, J. McGregor, W. J. B. Webb, G.
                        Morris, T. F. Donovan, W. P. Hughes, J E. Hewett, P. Leveaux, P. Corfield,
                        J. Davies Bryan and Waddington.</p>

                    <p>This committee of eleven will, daring the first three years’ existence of the
                        club, act in conjunction with the provisional committee, which has row
                        formed itself into a finance committee. It was felt that this was necessary,
                        on account of the latter's responsibility for the proper expenditure of the
                        donation fund.</p>

                    <p>Plans and estimates were submitted of various premises in the town suitable
                        for the headquarters of the club. It was stated that the club could not be
                        properly housed at a less rental than £250 per annum, and the committee
                        therefore suggested that the annual subscription should be raised from P T.
                        150 to P.T. 250, as the former subscription was not considered sufficient to
                        cover the estimated expenditure. A good deal of opposition was shown to this
                        proposal, and it was therefore rejected in favor of a proposal of Mr.
                        Chataway that the smaller sub cription should be given a trial for a year or
                        two, when it would be seen whether it could be continued or other wise. As
                        regards the club premises, the committee were asked to come to an
                        arrangement concerning suitable quarters in the centre of the city.</p>

                    <p>A vote of thanks to the chairman, and to Mr. Giles and the mess president of
                        the ETC. for the use of the room, brought the proceedings to a close.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>

                    <p>By kind permission of Lient. Col. R. C. C. Cox, commanding, and officers 2nd
                        Batt. Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will perform the following
                        selection of music on the Terrace, Shepheard’s Hotel, on Saturday next from
                        4 to 6 p.m. March- entry of the Gladiators- Overture - juanita- suppe
                        Rojaiaa MMwrk»-L» Ocarina-G*»a* fUlcctioo—Talk of tha Town-air. Batfonl
                        Va'aa - Bjmpathl# Tima—Gong'I Bon*-Tha Children'* Home-Ocwen
                        8#'a«k>o—Verooiqoa ¥•»*•*« Hun tartan renew—Noa. I and s- Brahma RsctmseM
                        March, KfcedMal Arnhem, Ood Sara the Kin*. It Warn* Bunn,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ CANAL DETENTION. LARGE COMPENSATION CLAIM.</head>

                    <p>The recent block in the Suez Canal caused by the sinking of the steamer
                        ‘Chatham,” resulting in considerable delay to vessels using the waterway, is
                        at present creating much controversy in shipping circles.</p>

                    <p>At the instigation of the Leith Shipowners’ Society, the different steamship
                        associations throughout England have been circularised with a view to joint
                        action against the canal company for detention damage, variously estimated
                        at £80.000 to £100,000 What steps will finally be taken depends, of course,
                        upon the nature of the replies received. The opinion is, however, general
                        that compensation should be paid, although there is a disposition to regard
                        the claims as among those which should first be referred to the protecting
                        and indemnity associations, which, if necessary, could open op negotiations
                        with the company. It is also thought by some that, whilst the agitation may
                        possibly not result in redress for the recent detention, an arrangement
                        might be arrived at in the event of future delay.</p>

                    <p>This is the first time since the canal was opened that it has been found
                        necessary to blow up a wreck in the fairway, and it may easily be that
                        another thirty-six years will elapse before a second disaster of the kind
                        occurs ; but in the opinion of prominent shipowners, the company can hardly
                        wait till then to apply the lesson. Seeing that over 18,000,0 0 tons gross
                        of shipping pass through the canal every year, they think the time has
                        arrived when the construction of an alternative channel should be seriously
                        entertained.</p>

                    <p>Meanwhile it is interesting to note that, owing to the obstruction , the
                        traffic receipts of the company for October show an appreciable diminution
                        on the same month in 1904 and 1903, reducing the surplus acquired at the end
                        of September by over a million and a quarter francs. Three hundred and three
                        vessels passed through the canal in October this year as compared with 880
                        in the corresponding month 1904, and 336 in October 1908, the receipts being
                        8,900,00fr., 10,270,000fr.t and 9,440,000fr. respectively.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

                    <p>Lord and Lady Waterford have been spending a few days in London at Claridge's
                        Hotel preparing for their winter tour, and have now left London for Cairo.
                        They will go on very shortly to British Bast Africa.</p>

                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Henry Bacon have left for Egypt and are arriving by P. &amp; O.
                        steam at Port Said for Cairo in the early days of December. They will take
                        op their residence as usual at Shepheard's Hotel.</p>

                    <p>Shepheard’s Hotel is filling op rapidly. Already 200 guests are staying
                        there. Last night several dinner parties were given there, among them a
                        banquet of the officers of the Rifle Brigade, covers being laid for 22. The
                        band of the regiment played during dinner.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Morgan had 11 guests, including Major and Mrs. Spong, Crookshank Pasha
                        and Mrs. Crookshsank, Captain and Mrs. McLean, Mr. and Mrs. Hayter, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Stout, Major Davidson.</p>

                    <p>Mr. E.V. Bird’s dahabieh Zemet el-Nil left Kasr-el-Nil for Luxor yesterday
                        for a long trip up the Nile.</p>

                    <p>Count Ma z .i.i has returned to Cairo.</p>

                    <p>M. Thelier and a party of friends are leaving Cairo shortly for a trip on
                        Messrs. Cook’s private steam dahabieb Oonas.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Leigh Canney has arrived in Cairo from England and is staying at the
                        Continental Hotel.</p>

                    <p>The branch of the Credit Lyonnais at Alexandria has lost another high employe
                        in the person of M. Beghian, a funde de ponvoirs of the bank.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Naguib Khuri has been authorised to follow his profession in Egypt.</p>
                </div>




                <div type="item">
                    <head>Carlton Hotel</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Joseph Comas</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck and Co's</head>
                </div>



            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
