<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Justin Esteve</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-28">September 28, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-12-15">December 15, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> <div type="item">
                <head>﻿THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY DECEMBER 15 1905:</head>
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLAND AND GERMANY</head>
                    <head>DISTRUST OF THE TEUTON.</head>
                    <head>SPEECH BY BULOW</head>
                    <p>Berlin, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Replying to Herr Babel in the Reichstag, Prince von Bulow accused the democratic Socialists of stirring up English distrust. He denied that Germany had resolved in 1905 to declare war against England. Germany only wants the same rights of commerce and of navigation as other nations.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</head>
                    <head>ISSUE OF YELLOW BOOK.</head>
                    <p>Paris, December 14.</p>
                    <p>The Yellow Book referring to Morocco bears out the critical position which existed last June when France was hesitating to agree to the Conference. Count von Bulow, speaking to the French Ambassador, deprecated delay, urging him not to linger on the brink of a precipice, if not an abyss. The remainder of the Yellow Book records difficult negotiations culminating in the formation of the programme for the Conference.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Paris, December 14.</p>
                    <p>A Yellow Book on Morocco has been issued The "Temps” says that it proves that France did all she could to come to an understanding with Germany.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INSECURITY IN THE CAUCASUS.</head>
                    <head>FLIGHT OF MOSLEMS.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, December 14.</p>
                    <p>5,000 Mussulmans have arrived here from the Caucasus, fleeing from the insecurity in that province. The Porte is arranging to distribute them in the Empire.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SITUATION IN BALTIC PROVINCES.</head>
                    <head>GOVERNOR-GENERAL APPOINTED</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, December 14.</p>
                    <p>In view of the serious situation in the Baltic provinces, the Tsar has appointed a special Governor-General, and has directed that a commission shall be elected by the nobility, municipalities, and peasants to assist him in introducing reforms. As, however, the revolutionary congress is arranging for the removal of officials and the establishment of an elective administration. 12,000 Cossacks have also been sent.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUTINY OF RUSSIAN SAILORS.</head>
                    <p>Colombo, December 14</p>
                    <p>100 Russian sailors on board the battleship Tsarevitch mutinied in the harbour here. Military assistance was asked for and sent. 50 mutineers were landed and the Tsarevitch sailed.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWISS CONFEDERATION.</head>
                    <p>Berne, December 14.</p>
                    <p>M. Forrer has been elected President of the
                        Confederation.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WELL-KNOWN AUTHOR DEAD.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>William Edward Thompson Sharpe is dead. His identity as the author of the works written under the name of Miss Fiona Macleod has been revealed.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>The late William Edward Thompson Sharpe, who was born in 1831 and was the son of the late Christopher Sharpe, Birr, King's County, Ireland, had been Conservative M.P. for Kensington since 1895. In 1873 he married Frances, daughter of the late Rev. Mr Guilleband,of Clifton. He was educated at Trinity College, Dublin, and in 1857 entered the Ceylon Civil Service, becoming Chief Commissioner of the N. W. Province of that island, and retiring in 1889. The works he wrote under the nom de plume of Miss Fiona Macleod, whose identity had hitherto remained secret, were the following : — Pharais ; a Romance of the Isles, 1894 ; The Mountain Lovers, 1895 ; The Sin Eater, 1895 ; The Washer of the Ford, 1896 ; Green Fire 1896; and (in verse) From the Hills of Dream, 1896. The Laughter of Peterkin, Old Celtic Tales Retold, 1897, Collective edition of the Celtic Tales from The Sin-Eater and The Washer of the Ford. with others added, in 3 vols., Spiritual Tales, Barbaric Tales and Tragic Romances, 1897 ; The Dominion of Dreams, 1899; The Divine Ad venture ; Iona; and other Studies in Spiritnal History, 1900 ; Revised and Augmented Re-prints by Mr. Mosher of Portland, Maine. 1902, and three in 1903 ; also Tauchnitz Selected Tales; The Immortal Hour and other Poems ; The Winged Destiny; The Magic Kingdoms ; and French Trans. Selection by Mr. Davray, and German Trans. Selection by Herr W. Mey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME RULE FOR IRELAND.</head>
                    <head>MR. REDMONDS APPEAL.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Speaking at Belfast, Mr. John Redmond appealed to the whole of Ireland to rend a united party to Parliament. Protestants might dismiss the fear that they would be subjected to religious disabilities if Home Rule were granted. The Nationalists were willing to agree to any safeguard that Protestants might demand regarding this matter.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FREE-FOODERS AND LIBERALS.</head>
                    <head>NO ALLIANCE.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>The members of the Unionist Free Food group have refused an alliance with the Liberals.</p>		<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIRST MEETING OF CABINET.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>The first meeting of the Cabinet took place to-day. It is understood that the Ministers discussed dissolution.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNEMPLOYED DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                    <head>THE PREMIER INTERVIEWED.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Some thousands of unemployed gathered on the Embankment and marched in procession to Hyde Park, passing Sir Henry Campbell-Bannerman's house. They stopped to interview the Premier, who said that be keenly sympathised with them, but was unable to give any reply until he had consulted his colleagues. Mr. John Burns concurred.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MIXED TRIBUNALS.</head>
                    <p>Rome, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Sig. Tittoni has laid before the Chamber the bill for the prorogation of the Mixed Courts of Egypt.</p>	<p>(Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EARL COWLEY MARRIED.</head>
                    <head>TO LADY HARTOPP.</head>
                    <p>London, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Earl Cowley has married Lady Hartopp by special licence at Colombo.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Lord Cowley, who was known as Viscount Dangan before his father’s death, was divorced in 1897 from his wife, nee Lady Violet Neville, daughter of the Marquis of Abergavenny. Lady Hartopp is the daughter of Mr. Charles Wilson, the shipowner, and brother of the Wilson of Tranby Croft. Lady Hartopp was the wife of Sir Charles Cradock-Hartopp and was recently divorced from her husband.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MISS ROOSEVELT'S MARRIAGE.</head>
                    <p>Washington, December 14.</p>
                    <p>Miss Alice Roosevelt will marry Mr. Longworth, a member of Congress, in February.</p>
                    <p>(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>M. LOREDAN'S PIANO RECITAL</head>
                    <p>A Cairo correspondent writes : — M. Pierre Loredan is, on the whole, to be congratulated on the success of his recital, for the odds were against him. He was provided with an exceedingly bad piano, the treble of which had no tone at all, and the attendance was sparse, and inclined to be talkative. I may mention as glaring examples of this vice three ladies in the sixth, row on the right and two ladies in the third row on the left (neither group English or French). who, by incessant conversation, did their best to draw public attention from the pianist to themselves. They could not have achieved this result by other means. I hope they will read these lines. The upper half of the programme was, as will be seen, of a very high standard ; but, like Nebuchadnezzar's  image, it degenerated into brass, iron, and common clay. M. Loredan has a fine technique, and shows to most advantage in the more complicated and difficult passages ; his touch is at times a little unsympathetic, but much may be excused one whose instrument is inexcusable. While his rendering of Beethoven left me cold, I cannot but admire most heartily 8carlatti’s Pastoral, as treated by him and the three choices from Chopin, though well worn, were hardly less enjoyable. The Sinding Printemps, a piece which should be reserved for great growing girls, was a failure, La Filense, pretty and delicately rendered. Il Tremolo is nothing more or leas than a cake-walk time, technically difficult but musically impossible; it is a pity that such fire works should be included in any programme. I trust M. Pierre Loredan will see his way to giving another recital under less adverse circumstances: so accomplished a pianist deserves more encouragement than he has, so far, met with.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Brindisi Mail.</p>
                    <p>The mail will close at the G. P. 0., Alexandria, on Sunday at 3.10 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Assouan Dam.</p>
                    <p>The appointment of Mr. Lewis as assistant engineer at the Assouan Dam has been announced. The salary is L.E. 360 per annum.</p>
                    <p>New Maronite Cathedral.</p>
                    <p>The purchase of a site for the new Maronite Cathedral at Cairo has been made and all the necessary legal formalities have been arranged.</p>
                    <p>Calisthenics.</p>
                    <p>Professor Conegliano has resumed bis dancing lessons at his dancing-hall and at pupils’ residences. Full particulars on application  at the Alhambra.</p>
                    <p>Fayoum Water Power.</p>
                    <p>An Anglo-Swiss company has applied to the Public Works Department for a licence to use the Fayoum waterfall for the production of electricity and for lighting the town of Fayoum.</p>
                    <p>New Sudd.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has given the contract for the construction of a sudd across the Nile at Mehallet El Amir, near Rosetta, to M. F. Baldi whose tender amounted to L.E. 8,800.</p>
                    <p>Agency.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Walker and Meimarachi inform their numerous clients, friends, and the public in general that they are now the sole agents in Alexandria also for Messrs. Mappin and Webb. Ltd, of London and Sheffield. A large and rich assortment of ’Xmas presents has just been received.</p>
                    <p>European Robbed.</p>
                    <p>An elderly French gentleman, M. Justin Peril. was the victim yesterday of a cowardly attack by three natives, who relieved him of his watch and chain and other trinkets, and made off. The assault took place in broad daylight, near Rosetta-road, and in the presence of some other natives, who were passive spectators.</p>
                    <p>Sale of Work.</p>
                    <p>We remind our readers of the sale of work to-morrow under the auspices of the 8cots Schools Fellow Worker’s Union in St Andrew’s High School. Major Allan, of Glasgow, a generous friend of the schools, has kindly consented to come from Cairo to open the sale at 3 p.m. Visitors will not only have the opportunity of buying suitable Christmas gifts at reasonable prices, but also of helping a very desirable object.</p>
                    <p>The New British Club.</p>
                    <p>A circular has been issued by the chairman and hon. secretary of the new British Club at Alexandria stating that the committee. having carefully examined the estimates for fitting up the club, finds the funds now available are not sufficient to furnish the place as comfortably as could be desired. In fact, unless more money is forthcoming (they say) two nr three rooms must be left unfurnished. A further sum of £250 is required, and the oommittee feels justified, in view of the low figure at which the annual subscription has been fixed, in appealing to members for donations to the capital fund, and is confident that this appeal will meet with a generous response. Donations can be sent to the hon. sec., to tbe hon. treas., Mr. P. W. Carver, or to any member of the committee.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord Cromer has been obliged to forego the transaction of any important business during the last two or three days owing to a slight attack of dengue fever, but is now in a fair way to complete recovery.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stanley Fisher, President of the District Court, Kyrenia, Cyprus, is going to England on leave of absence. during which his duties will be performed by Mr. J. C. Makaskie, President of the Famagusta District Court. Mr. Fisher entered the service in 1902, and has acted as King’s Advocate.</p>
                    <p>M. Quinsac, the well-known French portrait painter, is staying at Cairo for a few days.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Ernest Hills and Miss Wynne Roberts have left Redleaf, Penshurst, for Egypt, and will not return till after Easter.</p>
                    <p>Abd El Halim Pasha Assem, president of the Wakfa Administration, came down from Cairo yesterday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left for Upper Egypt by the train de luxe on the 11th Inst Mr. Vtrans and Mme Vtrans, Mr. Langsdorff and party of five, Mr. Beauge, Mr. J. P. Wells, Mr. Spathis, Mr.Tomme, Mr. Western, Rev. And Mrs. Ward, Mr. Gordon and Mr. Hadston.</p>
                    <p>The following left by the train de luxe on the 13th inst:— Miss Mosler, Mr. Mosler, Mr. Daven and party of four, Mr. Fraser, Mr Harrison, Mr. Pattani and secretary, Mr. Makran, Mr. Langier, Mr. Mansfield, Mr, Gunther Mr. Raouse, Mlle Klaudman, Mr. Bittar, Mr. Otto Sterzing, Col. and Mrs.
                        Muller</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RECENT DISTURBANCES.</head>
                    <head>ATTITUDE OF NATIVES.</head>
                    <p>Alexandria has not been troubled by any fresh disorders, and the attitude of the native population is officially declared to be very tranquil.</p>
                    <p>The upper-class natives have expressed a keen desire to assist the authorities in preventing an outbreak on the part of the populace. Many of them have been voluntarily enrolled as special constables, and have under-taken that, if any outburst of disorder should break out in' their quarters of the city, they will exert themselves to the utmost to check it.</p>
                    <p>The Alexandria City Police have not discovered that the riot on Sunday is in any way to be attributed to premeditation. It is considered that had not the Greek shot the Arab no disturbance would have broken out on that day.</p>
                    <p>Every precaution has been taken by the authorities in case of a future outbreak.</p>
                    <p>All the gunsmith's shops still remain closed.</p>
                    <p>The Greeks who have been arrested in connection with the riot are local subjects and will therefore be dealt with by the Egyptian authorities.</p>
                    <p>The general opinion in official circles is that the Capitulations ware a powerful contributory cause, for  the natives recognise that there is one law for the Europeans and another for the Egyptians, and so wherever a native is injured there is always a predisposition for his compatriots to taka up his cause on the spot. Egyptians generally appear to regard the special privileges accorded to Europeans with a growing disfavor, which is often justifiable.</p>
                    <p>It is pointed out that the ferocity of the mob on Sunday has been much exaggerated by timorous Europeans, for, if the crowd had been as evilly disposed as has been made out, how is it that not a single European was killed outright during the disturbance?.</p>
                    <p>COMPENSATION CLAIMS.</p>
                    <p>The estimate of the damage done to the property of Hellenic subjects during the disturbance has been sent in to the authorities of the Alexandria Gouvernorat by M. Scotidis, the Hellenic Consul General. It amounts to £2,000.</p>
                    <p>The official valuation of the damages, which was undertaken by an engineer of the Alexandria Gouvernorat by order of the Parquet, amounts to the total sum of £50. The discrepancy is significant.</p>
                    <p>DEMONSTRATION STOPPED.</p>
                    <p>A number of Europeans had intended to organise a procession through the city on Sunday next, headed by a band, as a demonstration against the natives. As this would have been a most likely way to provoke another outburst the police authorities wisely decided not to allow such a foolish proceeding, and strict orders have been issued that no such procession is to take place. Any similar demonstration will also be prevented by the police in the interest of public security.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive attended prayers at Montazah Mosque this morning.</p>
                    <p>His Highness will probably return to Cairo on Sunday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GRAND CADI.</head>
                    <p>Sheikh Djemal El Din, the new Grand Cadi of Egypt, arrived at Alexandria yesterday evening from Mecca. He is accompanied by his family and is proceeding to Constantinople, where he will receive his investiture of the Cadiship of Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
                    <p>We understand that no definite arrangement has yet been arrived at with regard to the future of the Sucreries, and it is not expected that matters will finally be settled till early next week.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JUDICIAL REFORM.</head>
                    <p>The International Commission for the reform of the Mixed Legislation has ordered its committee to draw up a draft law regulating marches a terme on the basis already adopted. The draft will be submitted to the representatives of the Powers at its next meeting, which will take place next month before Lord Cromer’s departure for the Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL.</head>
                    <p>The Legislative Council met on Thursday morning and after approving the draft Budget for 1906 decided to present its thanks to the Government for the reduction or the suppression of the taxes on Salt fisheries and boats, ferries, etc., and for the improvement in the pay of State employes. The Council also respectfully begged the Government to improve the condition of the employes of the Mehkemeh Sharieh and to suppress the tax on data palms. It also transmitted to the Government the demand of Mahmoud Pasha Suleiman, member for Assiout, for the Creation of a Municipality at Assiout. The Legislature Council finished by appointing four new members to the Commission appointed to study the rrgulations for the ghaffirs in place of four members whose period of service as members of the Legislative Council has expired. These members are Taman Bey Habarin, Mob. Bey Meligni, Issa Bey Nawar, and Mahmoud Bey Abdel Gaffar</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>‘‘TOSCA” AT THE ZIZINIA</head>
                    <head>A SPLENDID PERFORMANCE.</head>
                    <p>In pronouncing last night’s performance of La Tosca as one of the best productions ever staged at this theatre, we believe we are
                        voicing the unanimous verdict of a warm and crowded house. The intense and harrowing pathos which pervades Sardon's drama and,
                        in sparcely less degree, Puccini's opera, was carried home to yesterday’s audience in a combination of rapturous music and tragic. acting, rising at its climax in the second act to heart-rending and tear-starting emotion. The first act was very well executed so far as the leading parts were concerned. Signa.Bellincioni, in the title ro1e. was in her best voice. The first solo of Sig. José Palest, as the artist Cava-radossi, and his subsequent duet with the diva, were cordially received, and with good reason. Sig. Giovanni Polese made at once a telling impression in his impersonation of Scarpia, the gentlemanly villain par excellence. Sig. G. E. Gianoli put in useful work as the Sagrestano. The boys’ chorus was too hurried and confused, but Sig. Zuccani eventually brought them well together.</p>
                    <p>To Act II. enough admiration cannot be given; suffice it to say that from beginning to end it was perfect Sig. Polese’s 8carpia was as active as it was dignified ; he used his voice with much fluency, keeping well within its limitations. Sig. Palet’s small share in this act was skilfully and fervently executed. But the honours, of course, go to Signa. Bellincioni, who, has seldom displayed the wealth of her resources to better advantage. Hsr sweet, flex-ible voice, her gracefulness. her striking beauty, and her magnificent dramatic powers must have stamped an indelible image on the memories of her many admirers, who were roused to tumultuous enthusiasm. The sustained and powerful passages with Scarpia. the charmingly plaintive solo, and the tragic finale were truly great moments than which we do not wish to see anything finer. 8mall wonder that the house rose at her and demanded calls innumerable, both of her, Sig. Polese, and Maestro Zuccani. Signa. Bellincioni followed up her triumph throughout Act III., and Sig. Palet's rendering of the famous aria marked a culminating point of excellence. Moreover, the orchestre in this, as in the preceding sets, showed a fine feeling of ensemble, so that the whole performance leaves ns in a spirit of gratitude with a "lively sense of pleasures to come."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THEATRE REGULATIONS.</head>
                    <p>The draft theatre regulations were submitted to the Legislative Committee at its. last meeting. Certain clauses are to be altered and the task has been confided to the Contentieux to the Ministry of the Interior, who will make the necessary changes in concert with the Contentieux to the Ministry of Justice. It is expected that the new regulations will be promulgated in the course of the winter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PENNY POSTAGE.</head>
                    <p>We may remind our readers that the new postal arrangements whereby letters weighing under 15 grammes may be sent to England for 5 milliemes, comes into force to-day.</p>
                    <p>New Zealand has followed the lead of England in regard to penny postage. Letters to that country may now be sent for 5 milliemes.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MEMORIAL TO THE LATE M. TESTOUD.</head>
                    <p>It is a pleasure to us to record the kindly act of appreciative remembrance by which the old pupils of the School of Law have just sought to perpetuate the memory of their old Principal, M. Testoud. It appears that in response to a general feeling among the old students that some permanent memorial of the late Principal was desirable, a committee was formed and subscriptions were collected. It was decided that the memorial should take the form of a life-sized photograph, handsomely framed, to be offered to the Ministry for exhibition in the school. Tbe work hss been executed and was handed over to his Excellency , the Minister, yesterday by Omar Bey Lutfi, Abd El-Khalek Bey Sarwat, and Mo-hamed Bey Delavor, as delegates of the old scholars. His Excellency the Minister, in accepting the gift, expressed high appreciation of the motives which had prompted it, and has given orders for the portrait to be placed in the salle de reunion of the School.</p>
                    <p>The portrait is about life size and is a good likeness of the deceased jurist. It is mounted in a massive and handsome mahogany frame, fixed on an easel, the design and workmanship being extremely artistic and very creditable to its executant, Mohamed Saleh Suleiman. The frame and easel are mounted with arabesques in silver, and on the ledge of the easel is inscribed in silver fret-work the quotation from the Koran "Iuna hâzihi tazkirah” (this is a remembrance), together with the following verse of much merit specially composed for the purpose by Ahmed Bey Shanki, the Poet to his Highness the Khedive: -</p>
                    <p>Ashari antum,</p>
                    <p>Wa fadll ladelkum,</p>
                    <p>Wa ulumi ukurn,</p>
                    <p>The verse may be translated as follows:</p>
                    <p>You are my monument,</p>
                    <p>My virtues are with you,</p>
                    <p>My learning is in you,</p>
                    <p>So how can I die?</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA RACING SEASON.</head>
                    <head>NOMINATIONS FOR BIG RACES.</head>
                    <p>The following are the nominations received by the A. S. C. for the big races of 1906:-—</p>
                    <p>Club Stakes.—Prince Omar Pasha Tous-soun’s Kohalian and Hadban. Khalil Pasha Khayat's Suleik and Suheil, Moharrem Pasha Chehin's Chutney, Baron J. E. de Menasce’s Radium, Ishak Bey Hussein's Kamboula II. and Nessim, Ibrahim Bey Cherif's Sudan and Terel Hamam, Ibrahim Bey Cherif and Elie Bey Sursock's Mikado, Hussein Bey. Sioufi's Abou Nadara and Katcout, Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakri’s Kohilan Talr, Mr, A. J. Sursock's: The Bard and Royal Oak, Saleh Bey Yaghen's Abou Arkoub, Bid, and Bulkeley, Hassan Bey Kheir el Din's Louhan, Mr. E. Bustros’ Tamsah, Mr. R Karam’s Nimrod and Val d’Or, Mr. Tueni's Viking.</p>
                    <p>National Stakes. — Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun’s Mouftakhar and Jourham, Khalil Pasha ; Khayat’s Hedieh, Baron J. E. de Me-nasce’s Chance, Hussein Bey Sioufi’s Mabrouka, Mr. A J. Sursock's Venicius, Mr. A. J. Miohas-lides’ Monarch, Hassan Pasha Mohsen’s Chay-lak and Karaguioz, Hussein Bey Sioufi's Aida.</p>
                    <p>Grand Prize of Alexandria. — Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun's Nadir and Kohailan, Khalil Pasha Khayat’s horses, Moharrem Pasha Chebin’s Chutney, Ishack Bey Hussein's El Tahawi and Fadghan, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs El Darwish and Shendi, Ibrahim Bey Cherif and Elie Bey Sursock's Mikado, Hussein Bey Sioufi’s Metwalli and Abou Nadara, Omar Bey Saltan and Ahmed Bey Bakry’s Eclair, Mr.. A J. Sursock's Boule de Neige and -Alarm, Saleh Bey Yaghen’s Mabaout, Mansour, and Tamerlan, Hassan Bey Keir el Din's Mackboul, Mr. Ed Bustros' Roland, Mr. E. Karam’s Hector and Douglas, Messrs. Branch and Mason’s Starboard Light, Mr, Tueni'a Caprice and Faineant, Mr. Emile Tharson's Cyrano.</p>
                    <p>Continental Stakes.—Prinoe Omar Pasha Toussoun's Gratitude and Quick Returns, Prince Mohamed Ibrahim’s. Gribiche and Ulema, The Angels’ Eglantine and Ajax II. Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Ketch-up and Aurelius, Omar Bey Sultan and Bakry Bey’s Bonus, Moharrem Pasha Chehim's Mabrook, Hassan Pasha Moh-sen’s Riado.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Derby.—Prince Omar Pasha Tossoun's Nadir and Kohailan, Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Malgré Tout and Crillon, Moharrem Pasha Chehim’s Waziz, Ishack Bey Hussein's El Tahawi and Kismat, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs El Derwish, Ibrahim Bey Cherif and Elie Bey Sursock's Mikado, Hussein Bey. 8ioufi's Metwalli, Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmet Bey Bakry’s Eclair, Mr. A. J. Sursock's Boule de Neige and Alarm, Saleh Bey Yaghen's Tokar, Mabsout and India, Mr. Ed Bustro's Roland, Mr. Karam’s Hector and Douglas, M Tueni's Caprice and Fainéant, Mr. E. Pharaon's Cyrano.</p>
                    <p>Lord of Rosna Stakes — Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun's Gratitude and Quick Returns, Prince Mohamed Ibrahim’s Theodore, Brown Boy and Ulema, The Angels' Eglantine and Ajax II., Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Ketch-up and Aurelias, Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Baby’s Florence and Bonus, Moharrem Pasha Chehin’s Mabrook,
                        Hassan Pasha Mohsen’s Merry Rustic and Riado.</p>
                    <p>St. Leger Stakes-Prince Omar Pasha Toussoun's Nadir and Kohailan, Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Trenton and Au Revoir, Moharrem Pasha Ohehim's Chutney, Ishack Bey Hussein's El Tahawi and Fadghan, Ibrahim Bey Cherif's St. Frusquin and El Derwish, Hussein Bey Sioufi's Metwalli, Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakry's Eclair, Mr.
                        A. J. 8ursock’s Boole de Neige and Sans Pareil, Mr. A J. Michaelides’ Jupiter, Saleh Bey Yaghen’s Mansonr, Bid and Mabeout, Mr. E Bustros' Roland, Mr. E Karam’s Tamerlan and Finasseur, Mr. Tusni's Caprice and Fainéant.</p>
                    <p>Ibrahimieh Stakes.—Prinoe Omar Pasha Toussoun's Hadban and Beylan, Khall Pasha Khayat's Suleik and Loulon, Moharrem Pasha Chehin's Acelus, Isbak Bey Hussein's Kam-boula II. and Nadim, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs Sudan and St. Frusquin, Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakry’s Kohilan Taier, Mr.
                        A J. Sursock's The Bard and Royal Oak, Saleh Bey Yaghen’s Moyasser, Abou Arkoub and Rubis. Mr. E Bustros’ Temsah, Mr. E Karam’s Kaimakam and Fakir, Hussein Bey Sioufi's Abou Nadara and Katcout, Mr. Tueni's Viking.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</p>
                    <p> Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste. </p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
                    <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>x.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>NOTED FOR ITS EXCELLENT CUISINE</p>
                    <p>Electric Light. Lift.</p>
                    <p>Special terms for officers of the Army of Occupation and Government officials.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>MOERIS HOTEL,</p>
                    <p>First Class Encampment,</p>
                    <p>On Lake Moeris</p>
                    <p>In connection with the Kardon Hotel, Fayoum.</p>
                    <p>For particulars apply Mr. TASCO, Fayoum.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx.x.xxx</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
