<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02"></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>1905-05-15
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE|M, MONDAY, MAY 15, 1905.</head>
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in Old
Cairo during the night of Tuesday and dawn
on Wednesday will be poisoned by the police.
Murder with Robbery.— Our Keneh Cor-
respondent telegraphs that a murder, accom-
panied by robbery, took place at Dahasa
village, Nag Hamadi, to day.
Suez Canal.—10 vessels passed through
the Canal on the 11th inst., 8 of which wore
British, 1 Norwegian, 1 Spanish. The day’s
receipts were frs. 263,738.54, making the total
from the 1st inst frs. 3,337,413.73.
Cattle Plague.—During the week ending
13th iust, 18 deaths from cattle plague were
notified. These cases occurred in the following
districts: 6 at Hehia, 2 at Mina el Kamh, 1 at
Zagazig, 1 at Simbellawein, 6 at Mit Ghamr,
and 2 at Embabeh. The number of deaths no-
tified during the corresponding period last
year was 5,995. The number of animals ino-
culated between the 7th and 12th May was 606.
Since the commencement of the plague the
total number of the deaths has been 147,199.
Panic at the Arsenal.—An extraordinary
scene occurred at the Alexandria Arsenal on
Saturday afternoon, but fortunately it was
not attended by any loss of life and only a
few people were injured. A fine bull managed
to escape from a steamer belonging to the
Khedivial Line in the harbour and swam
ashore. The bull was an exceptionally power-
ful brute and became very excited and nervous
on getting ashore owing to the attempts made
to capture it. He landed at the Arsenal and a
chase at once began. The animal was followed
by a crowd of pursuers who scampered after
the brute in a vain attempt to corner him.
Again and again the bull, who became more
and more infuriated, turned upon the crowd
of hunters and at least six hapless Arabs were
tossed into the air by the maddened animal.
The chase lasted an hour and a half and was
attended by numerous exciting incidents and
hair-breadth’s escapes. All attempts to lasso
the bull were quite ineffectual, and his in-
domitable energy spread terror among all his
pursuers. Finally it was determined to shoot
him, and after some unsuccessful aims, poor
“toro" was pierced by a deadly bullet, and the
exciting episode was brought to a conclusion.
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
Herr von Mohl, German member of the
Public Debt Commission, accompanied by Mrs.
von Mohl and Miss von Mohl, left by the
Austrian steamer on Saturday. He will return
to Alexandria on the 15th July.
Captain T. E. Bayley. Staff Captain, Cairo,
and Captain W. H. Rotheram, R.E., have been
granted leave of absenoe.
Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern
Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. and Mrs.
J. Van den Berg, Mr. and Mrs. A. S. Leary,
Mrs. E. A. Chaplin, Mr. P. E. Hergel, Mr.
G. B. Kerr, Mr. L. Stienon, Dr. Muir, Miss
Townsend, Miss Patton, Mr. E. A. H. James,
Mr. Frank Jacques, Mr. G. Clay, Cav. Cesare
Pini, Count and Comtesse C. Maucinelli Scotti,
Mr. G. Sarros, Mr. A. H. King, Kamal Bey,
Mr. Carnielli, Mr. W. T. Me Queen, Mr. M.
Pinto, Mr. E. Bajocohi, Mr. and Mrs. P. Remy,
Mr. L. Rossetto.
<head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
H.H. the Khedive will leave Alexandria
to-morrow in order to attend the celebration of
the Monied en-Nebi, which takes place on
Wednesday next.
H.H. Prince Mohamed Ibrahim and the
Emir el Hag, Mahmoud Housni Pasha, were
received yesterday by the Khedive at Ras-el-
Tin Palace.
This afternoon his Highness will hold a
reception of the members of the Cairo and
Alexandria committees of organisation of the
Mohamed Aly Centenary celebrations.
It is said that his Highness will give his
annual State Ball at Ras-el-Tin Palace on
the 5th June.
<head>EGYPTIAN ARMY</head>
H.H. the Khedive has been most graciously
pleased to approve of the following promo-
tions :—
Local Miralai G. K. Watson Boy, C. M. G.,
D. S. O., to be Miralai and temporary Lewa
whilst holding the appointment of Aide-de
Camp to his Highness, from the 3rd May 1905.
El Bimbashi H. D. E. O'Sullivan, Sudan Go-
vernment, to be Kaimakaro from the 19th
April 1905.
Lieutenant D. S. B. Thompson, M.B., Royal
Army Medical Corps, having reported his
arrival in Egypt from England, is taken on the
strength of the Egyptian Army, with the rank
of Bimbashi. He is posted to the Medical
Corps.
<head>HOME CRICKET</head>
. London, May 18.
Yorkshire beat Worcestershire by 65 runs.
Surrey v. Australians and Sussex v. Notts
drawn.	(Roster.)
<head>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY</head>
CELEBRATIONS AT ALEXANDRIA.
The official celebration of the centenary of
Mohamed Aly Pasha, founder of the Khedivial
Dynasty, began on Saturday at 4 p.ra., when
the representatives of H. H. the Khedive,
T. H. Prinoe Aziz Bey Hassan, Prince Moha-
med Ibrahim, and Prinoe Omar Toossoun
arrived, accompanied by Said Bey Zulficar,
Grand Master of Ceremonies, at the reserved
enolosure opposite the statue of the great
Pasha, where a large company had gathered
at tho invitation of the Governor of Alex-
andria, and wore awaiting their arrival in
the large tout erected on tho Place des
Consuls. By the time the Princes arrived Moha-
med Aly-square was one mass of humanity,
thousands of people thronging every available
space and every point of vantage being
occupied. Although the space in front of the
statue was ostensibly reserved for the invited
guests, and although we found it a matter of
difficulty to pass through the cordon of police
at the end of the square, we were disagreeably
surprised to find on entering the enclosure
that the approaches to the tent and the statue
were occupied by a rabble through which it
was difficult to make one’s way. In this respect ■
we think the organising committee had not 
taken sufficient precautions.
The Princes were accommodated on a raised 
dais under the triumphal arch which had been
erected. Here several speeches were delivered, 
the first by H.E. the Governor, who spoke in 
the name of Alexandria. His Excellency said:— 
<head>ALTESSES, MESDAMES ET MESSIEURS</head>
II appartenait a la villa d’Alexandrie qui 
fut le sejour prefere de Mohammed Aly de 
celebrer avec pompe l’anniversaire de l’Avene- 
ment du Grand Homme au Gouvernement de 
l’Egypte. Aussi la Commission Municipal 
a-t-elle saisi avec empressement-l'occasion qui ,
lui etait offerte de montrer, par des rejouis-
sances dignes de son antique et glorieuse re-
nommee, la reconnaissance qu’elle porte au *
fondateur de l'Egypte moderne et son atta-
chemeut a Sa Dynastie.	'
C'est pour moi ua grand honneur, le plus 
grand de ma carriere deja longue, de prendre
la parole en cette occasion.
Je ne voua parlerai pas de la vie et des 
ceuvres de Mohamed Aly. Vous connaissaez
tout ce quo j’en pourrais dire, mais je tiens 
seulement a constater l’accord unanime de la
population d’Alexaudrie, indigene et euro- 
peenne dans cette circonstance.
L’elan populaire est reellement touchant; 
il a été aussi irresistible que spontané, je 
le remarque avec orgueil
La foule qui m’entoure, composee des invi-
tes de la Commission Municipale, hauts fonc-
tionnaires et notables est l’image du pays
tout entier, c’est en raccourci toute l’Egypte 
actuelle qui fete Mohammed Aly, tandis 
que l’Egypte de demain representee par les
delegations des ecoles de toutes les natio-
nalites vient prendre une veritable lecon de
large tolerance' et d'humanite. Ces entants
qui sont l’avenir viennent saluer le passe et
en acclamant Mostre Ai'eul de S. A. le
Khedive, ils apportent k mon gracieux Maltre
l’hommage de la generation nouvelle. Dans
cette journee dont le souvenir restera grave
dana tons les wears, les homines de nos joars .
se sentent revivre dans l’ame de tons ces j
jeunes egyptiens d’origine et d’adoption qui
comma leurs alnes travailleront a la prospe- '
rite, au progres et a la gloire ininterrompue '
de l’Egypte, dans la voie ouverte par Moham- 1
med Aly.
Je salue au nom do la Municipalite les re-
presentants des Puissances, les notables de
toutes les colonies et leurs families ; je salue '
les enfants des ecoles et leurs maltres et je les
remercie. *
J’adresse aux dignes representanta de S. A.
le Khedive, L.L. A.A. les Princes Omar Pacha '
Toussoun et Aziz Pacha Hassan, au nom de '
tons, l’expression de nos sentiments do grati- 
tude pour avoir honore de leur presence la J
ceremonie.
A S. A. le Khedive Abbas Hilmy, le bien- 
aime Souverain de l’Egypte, qui a donne
tant de preuves de sa paternelle affection 
pour notre ville, j’apporte un nouvel hommage
de notre profond et respectueux attachement 
a Son Auguste Personne et l’assurance des 
sentiments de pur loyalisme qui nous animent. '
Tout a l’heure je deposerai, aux pieds de 
la statue de Mohammed Aly, une palme,
symbole de gloire et de paix. A ce moment 
tous les cceure battront a l’unisson et dans une 
acclamation unanime et enthousiaste nous
unirons dans nos acclamations Mohamed Aly
et S. A. le Khedive Abbas Hilmy.
An nom de la Commission Municipale et de
la Ville d’Alexandrie je vous invite a vous 
joindre a moi pour crier:
Vive Mohammed Aly dans la memoire des 
generations.
Vive S. A. le Khedive Abbas Hilmy.
The next speaker was Mr. Ambroise Ralli,
vice-president of the Alexandria Municipality,
who made the following oration :—
L’histoire a demontre a maintes reprises, 
qu'aox moments critiques de la vie d'une na- 
tion, l’homme, le genie necessaire pour sa re- 
generation parait. Tel fut le cas pour l'Egypte. .
Au debut du 19eme siecle, ce pays etait de-
shire par des oonflits internes, il etait devaste,
la population oroupissait dana la misere. Mais 1
l’homme destine a la sauver etait la, le grand
Mohamed AIL
Le 18 mai 1805 les Ulemas allerent le trou-
ver et lui direst "C’est toi que nous voulons
“ pour nous gouvener, car sur ton visage nous
“ voyons la probite et la justice ”.
Je passe outre les premieres annees pendant
lesquellee il eut a lutter pour affermir son
pouvoir, car cela ne rentre pas dans le cadre de
mon discours.
Mohamed Aly est l’auteur de l’Egypte mo-
derns. Une fois femement établi, il applique
toute son attention k ameiiorer la condition de
l'Egypte. Son esprit penetrant lui fit voir im-
mediatement que sa grande force reposait
dans l’intrduction de la civilisation europe-
enne et il en profita avec une habilete con-
sommee. Il invita les Europeens a venir en
egypte y etablir des ceuvres d’utilite publique
et par son ferme gonvemement, il rendait
l’Egypte si tranquille et si sure qu’un voyageur
de u'importe quelle nationalite on religion
pouvait la traverser toute entiere avec une
seourite que nuls antres pays civilises pou-
vaient lui rivaliser. L'entifere constitution gou-
vernementale de l'Egypte fut son oeuvre, mo-
deiee en grande partie snr les systemes en-
ropeens. Il n’epargna pas ses efforts pour
ameliorer le commerce, les industries et les
manufactures d’Egypte. Les colleges des lan-
gues et de medecine, l’imprimerie de Boulak
sont parmi les institutions de grande utilite
etablies par lui. Le canal qui alors reliait Alex-
andrie au Nil etait dans un tres mauvais etat.
Mohamed Aly fit creuser le Mahmoudieh
actuel, si indispensable au commerce d'aujour-
d’hui. Sous sa direction le Barrage au Caire
fut commence pour ettre termine recemment,
et qui a augments a on si haut degre la ri-
chesse du pays.
Par ses louables efforts dans la direction
vraie pour la feiicite de son pays, Mohamed
Ali s’est montre de beaucoup en avance sur ses
contemporains. Son caraotere moral, son esprit
eclaire et son habilete le placent au premier
rang des hommes d’eiite des temps modernes.
Aujourd’hui que nous pouvons mesurer son
ceuvre, en constater les resultats, en prevoir
consequences, o’est avec raison que nous ap-
pelons Mohamed Ali, le Grand Mohamed Ali.
Et dans la ceremonie de ce jour a laquelle
assistant les representants de toutes les co-
lonies europdennes, je me fids un devoir, en
leur nom, d'apportor mon hommage respec-
tueux et reconnaissant k l’homme-de genie
dont l'image ici voisine nous rend presente
l'ceuvre gigantesque a laquelle son nom est
desormais indissolublement lie.
Mr. Ralli was followed by Yehia Bey, who
gave the following speech in Arabic :—
A pareil jour, il y a centans, le Grand Hom-
me auqnel l'Egypte doit sa prosperite, fut revetu
de la pilisse et du Caffetan ; les notables, les
ulemas et l’armee l'ont, en ce jour, investi du
pouvoir et ont' sollicite du Grand Khalife, le
Sultan Selim III, la sanction de leur voen ; le
firman d’investiture ne se fit attendre que
cinquante sept jours.
Ce jour fut pour l’Egypte 1’inauguration
d’une ere nonvelle,car les evenementaauxquels
il a donne lieu ont en pour objet de substitner
a l’anarcliie et aux exactions qui devastaient
le pays et troublaient la sécurité des habitants,
pendant près de trois siecles, un gonvemement
regulier et une administration sage.
Les paroles suivantes que le Grand monarque
prononca un jour, donnent une idee de ses as-
pirations élevées et de la règle de conduite
qu'il s'dtait traede: "Ce que je sfeme aujonrd'hni,
" dit-il, ne sera pas récolté avant que naissent
" mes petits enfants.—Dans un pays ou l’anar-
“ chie regne aussi profondement qu’elle regnait
“ ici, on la dissolution atteint les saines tradi-
“ tion8 de l’Etat, oil un peuple, tel qne oe peu-
“ ple, etait retourne al’etat sauvage, a l’igno-
" ranee et h une profonde incapacity de tout
" travail salutaire, la civilisation ne peut re-
“ prendre et se rdpandre que tres lentement”
Et, en cultivateur sage et prudent, le Grand
Pacha u’a voulu confier les semences de la civi-
lisation qu’a un terrain bien prepare; il a com-
mence par le purger des mauvaises herbes et
des germes malfaisanta, puis il a'est mis a re-
pandre poor chaque vie ses semences.
Pour la vie intellectuelle, il a fonde de nom-
breuses écoles, tant pour les sciences que pour
les arts ; il a eu egalement soin d’envoyer des
missions sucessives dans les pays civilises.
Pour la vie economique, il règle le partage
des terres, la repartition des impôts; il a ame-
liore l'irrigation, construit des ponts, creuse
des canaux et des drains, entretenu les digues,
amende 1’agriculture, introduit des methodes
nouvelles de culture et importe des plantes
jusque-la inconnues, qui donnent au pays la
richesse et le bien-etre, il a encourage le com-
merce, en donnant lui-meme le bon exemple;
il a couvert l’Egypte de manufactures et d’usi-
nes ; il a formd des artisans indigfenes dans
toutes les branches de l'industrie; il a recher-
che partout les mines; en unmot, ila tollement
change la face de l’Egypte, que partont sont
revenus le mouvement et la vie.
Pour la vie politique, il a pu donner a
l’Egypte une position marquante qui lui a per-
mia de jouer on role .dans la politique euro-
peenne.
Et ses semences de civilisation etaient si
vivaces que, oontrairement a ses previsions, il
a pu en recolyrt lui-meme les fruits, ainsi que
ses enfants et ses petits enfanta, et que les
quelques semences dont la récolte est en retard,
ne tarderont pas k fendre la terre et a garmer,
le jour ou les conditions du sol seront plus
favorables.
Tout lo bien-etre dont nous jouissons et
dont none jouirons, c’est a Mohamed Aly que
nous le devons.
Sois donc beni, o bercean d'Alexandre, tu
nons as fourni, apres le Creatour d’Alexandrie,
celuj qui a restaure le royaume d’Egypte et qui
a choisi notre ville pour en faire le port de son
grand royaume, apres lui avoir restitue son
ancienne splendeur.
Quels bienfaits les Alexandrins ne doivent-
ils pas a Mohamed Aly  Ne nous a-t-il pas
conduit les eaux du Nil, dont nous etions pri-
ves?  N’a-t-il pas relie notre ville, qui etait
isolee, a l'interieur, a l’Egypte et, a l’exterieur,
au Monde, de sorte qu’elle est devenue un
trait d’union entre la terre et la mar N'a-t-il
pas rendu le port plus sur, permettant aux
marchands d’y affluer de tons les points de la
terre ? N’a-t-il pas construit des forta et des
fregates pour sa defense et la marine mar-
chande pour son commerce? N’a-t-il pas re-
leve l’honnenr du drapeau Egyptien sur toutes
1es mers?  N’a-t-il pas construit, sur nos bords,
un arsenal resonnant de coupe de marteaux et
du sifflet de la vapeur ? N'dtions-nous pas une
petite population ne depassant pas 8,000, en
nombre, et voila que nous débordons des fau-
bourgs et que nous nous trouvons a l’dtroit
dans nos quartiers, malgre le grand develop-
pement des constructions.
Et cette union que nous voyons aujourd’hui
entre les enfants du pays et les differentes
colonies, dans cette ville commercials, n’est-
elle pas le résultat qu’il visait des lors, en
convoitant une Alexandria florissanto et po-
puleuse 
Nous considerons comme un don du Ciel, la
faveur qu’a eu la ville d’Alexandrie, de posse-
der sa statue, qui est parmi nous l’embleme
vivant de ses bienfaits, afin que nous puissions
nous les rappeler nuit et jour.
O Mohamed Aly, -aujourd’hui, Alexandria
joyeuse te salue.
Ton peuple qui t’a aime parce que tu lui as
voue une affection profonde, qui t’a venere
parce que tu l’as releve, s’efforce de marcher
vers la realisation de tes voeux et saisit cette
occasion pour manifester tout ce qu’il ressent
pour toi de profonde gratitude. Aussi dois-je
declarer au nom de tous les citoyens tant de
cette ville que des autres ports de l’Egypte,
que c’est pour nous un devoir sacre que de
professer la plus sincere affection a l’egard de
celui qui nous a prodigue tant de bienfaits.
Que ta memoire se perpetue, o Mohamed
Aly; que ta posterity se succède sur le trône,
suivant ton example, et que Vive ton digne
arriere-petit-fils, notre Souverain bien-aime et
Khedive Abbas Hilmi II et ses augustes
enfants.
Afterwards H.H. Prince Omar Toussoun
rose and, on behalf of the Khedive, thanked
the committee for the excellent arrangements
which they had made to celebrate the centenary
of the founder of the Khedivial dynasty, and
expressed his gratitude for the many kind
things which had been said by the speakers.
His Highness ended by promising to convey to
the Khedive the many expressions of loyalty
and affection which had been made.
At the end of Prince Omar's speech a move
was made to tho statue of Mohamed Aly, on
the pedestal of which a wreath of silver laurel
leaves was placed.The Princes and the members
of the committee then took up their stand at
the base of the statue and a defile of nearly the
whole of the school boys of Alexandria, with
bands and banners flying, took place, the
Princes receiving the salutes of all, and each
band striking up the Khedivial Anthem as it
passed. The march-past would have been
more effective had it been carried out under
less cramped conditions. At its conclusion, the
Khedivial Princes, again accompanied by Said
Bey Zulficar, entered their State carriage and
drove off, to the strains of the National Anthem
played by the band of the 7th Egyptian Batta-
lion. Thus ended the official celebration of the
centenary at Alexandria.
<head>AN INCIDENT</head>
An incident, which at one time threatened
to mar the whole proceedings, occurred while
the school children were defiling past the
members of the Khedivial Family. Several fire
balloons were in the course of the afternoon
sent up from the open space familiarly known
as the “French gardens,” and where the tent
had been erected for the accommodation of the
afternoon's guests. One of these, of most
fantastic shape, got caught during its ascent
in the star and crescent which formed the
pinnacle of tho triumphal arch. At first it was
thought that it would disentangle itself, but
the wind was against it and in a short time
the paper of which it was formed caught fire.
At that time the excitement of the thousands
who were watching it from underneath began.
In a few seconds the fire would spread to the
triumphal arch and then—well the possibilities
were immense. With a promptitude which
deserves the highest praise one or two of the
spectators, notably M. Gillot of the Gas
Company, and one of the firemen on the spot
scaled the tent. One man scrambled up
the arch and tore the fiery balloon away just in
the nick of time, amidst the cheers of the
spectators. It was a daring act because the
aroh was of the most fragile character. In
throwing down the burning paper, however, he
set fire to the tenting below, and when the
latter began to blaze, the excitement reached
its height. There was nothing for it now but
to cut down the burning portion of the tooting
and this was quickly done, about twenty fire-
men seizing hold of it below and stamping out
the flames. The fire engine was on the spot in
two minutes, but its services were not required.
<head>THE ILLUMINATIONS</head>
Undoubtedly the best part of the celebra-
tion, however, took place in the evening.
The Municipal buildings were the chief
centre of the illuminations in Rosetta Gate-
street. The entire facade was picked out with
red eleotric lamps. The windows were blocked
with a white escutcheon on red cloth. One line
of brilliantly white gas lamps ran along the first
story and the whole length of the terrace was
surmounted by flags at short intervals. The
steps leading to the main entrance were picked
out in red and white eleotric lights. Another
charming feature was the display of Bengal
lights in the front garden, which shed a lurid
red and white light at frequent intervals.
The Mohamed Aly Club was very pretty
and a feature of the decoration was the huge
escutoheon with the initials "M. A." Tho
Greek Club was illuminated with blue and
white lights and presented a splendid spectacle.
The Italian Club also had some artistic decora-
tions.
The Khedivial Club was splendidly illumi-
nated and formed one of the most prominent
features in the square. The dub was thronged
with guest* and 800 dinners were served in
the evening. Among those present were Prince
Asis Pasha Hassan, tho Governor of Alexandria,
a number of Municipal Councillors, officers of
the Army of Occupation, and the elite of
Alexandria and R«yl«h
The preparation* that had been made during
the past week gave a very clear idea as to
what might be expected when darkness
enabled the full effort of the delicate tra-
cery of the festoons in the Mohamed Aly-
square to he seen and appreciated. Apart
from the illumination of the square, the
Municipality, and the Clubs, little was
to be seen, excepting in Cherit Pasha-
street, worthy of the name, although there
were of course numerous solitary examples
in other streets, where the displays of bunting
were in some instances supplemented by
illuminated devices in the way of coloured
lamps, Chinese lanterns, etc., while in a few
instances, the Rudolph Home for example,
the absence of flags by day was compensated
for by a display of lamps in the night
Cherif Pasha-street, however, made up for
any shortcomings in other districts by the
luxuriance of its colour, both in flags and in
illuminated devices, in its plethora of coloured
lamps and decorated balconies. The excellent
police arrangements permitted both foot pas-
sengers and carriage occupants to take a
leisurely and comprehensive view of all there
was to be seen, and one cannot too highly
commend the way in which both the mounted
and foot police on duty managed the multi-
tude that thronged the street
Debouching from Cherif Pasha-street on
to the Mohamed Aly-square in the earlier
hours of the night the paucity of colour was
very noticeable, and as it was 9 o’clock before
the illuminations were to be seen in all their
beauty, those who visited the square before
that hour mast have been somewhat disap-
pointed by the meagre show, after the brilliant
scene they had just left However, shortly
after half-past eight the various sections of
the vast space were one after another lit up,
commencing with the statue in the centre, the
illumination of the canopy, suspended grace-
fully from four poles which were surmounted
with transparent white crescents and stars,
being greeted with a roar of applause from the
crowd below. By nine o’clock—the appointed
hour—the whole square was lit up and present-
ed a truly magnificent sight From Venetian
masts placed at short intervals along the whole
pavement skirting the square were suspended
a double festoon formed of incandescent eleo-
trio lamps, the masts being draped in red and
white, and having bannerets depending from
each. Similar festoons encircled the gardens
and outdoor cafes in the centre, as well as the
statue.
At the south corner of the Bourse terrace the
band of the Customs House Porters School was
stationed, the strains of which contributed
greatly to enliven the proceedings, and com-
pensated somewhat for the absence of a public
band in the centre of the square. Viewed from
the top of the Ottoman Bank buildings the
scene was a most striking one, the brilliancy
of the ladies toilettes’ on the terrace of the
Khedivial Club showing up very conspicuously
by the light of the pink-shaded gas standards
which helped to give them effect. Want of
space compels us to curtail our account of a
scene of which we have given after all a very
inadequate description.
<head>THE PLAGUE</head>
A fresh case of plague is reported at Alexan-
dria, the victim being a Greek grocer'a boy
who arrived here from Zifta on the 9th inat
In consequenoe of this case departures from
Alexandria are subjected to quarantine re-
<head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCES</head>
A Cairo correspondent writes The nerve-
breaking noises in some of the Cairo streets at
night-time arid in the early morning are simply
appalling. Not far from the Savoy Hotel, for
instanoe, Berbereen, mostly under the influence
of drink, are to be heard long after midnight
shouting or rather howling like savages. The
rattling of water-carts in the early part of the
morning, too, makes sleep impossible; but
then from five to seven a.m. come the prin-
cipal miseries,—for two weary hours one’s rest
is disturbed by a never-ending stream of vege-
table hawkers, eta, howling oat their goods
from the pavement with the most hideous
ories, rendering the place a perfect pandemo-
nium. It is, I think, small wonder that many
Cairo residents, after a few years in the country,
develop nervous breakdown, especially daring
the summer, through want of rest and quiet-
ness. Could not the Commandant of the Cairo
City Police issue orders against these annoy-
ances?
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
The Moss liner "Pharos” sailed yesterday
afternoon for Liverpool via Malta, with passen-
gers, mails, and general cargo.
The Messageries Maritimes SE. “Congo,’’
from Marseilles, passed the Strait* of Messina
on Saturday and is due here to-morrow.
ARISTON AERATED WATERS
Guaranteed Distilled.
ALEXANDRIA:7, Ene de la Poste
CAIRO:
GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,
AlEXANDRIA.
PER DAY, WINE INCLUDED
NOTES FROM PORT SAID.
M. TILLIER'S RETIREMENT.
(From our Correspondent).
  <head>Port-Said, Saturday</head>
In yesterday’s Cairo papers I read that
“M. Tillier, Chief of Service of.the Suez Canal
“Company, is to retire in the coming month,
“and the Comte de Serionne, l’agent supe-
“rienre’ at Cairo, has appointed one of the
“Canal pilots to replace him. ” I fancy the
article is written in all seriousness, for, to
make matters worse, it has been copied by
local journals as news. Even if humour were
intended it would hardly take this form. I
might mention that M. Tillier is the virtual
chief of the Canal Company in Egypt, and he
it is who draws the larget salary. It is any-
thing but absurd to suppose that such a
change would take place, especially when the
principal agent, M. Coullant, has already been
appointed?
<head>THE S.S. “CANDLESHOE."</head>
The “Candleshoe” is nearly ready for sea.
The ship has sold by private contract some
10,000 bags of more or less ruined rice.
<head>THE SUNKEN DREDGER.</head>
The sunken dredger "Pharson II.,” which
has been quietly resting at the bottom of the
harbour for a month, seems likely to go
through similar stages as the famous “Congal,”
which, by the way, is at last nearly ready for
lifting. The dredger, on sinking, was at once
railed in, but since then absolutely nothing
has been done.
<head>THE COMING ECLIPSE.</head>
A certain amount of preparation seems
likely to be made here for the forthcoming
solar eclipse, which, in Egypt generally, given
dear weather, should be somewhat remarkable.
Absolute totality will occur on a line passing
in a N.N. direction, some 180 mils* south of
Cairo, and it will there occur in the afternoon
of the 80th August. It will be almost complete
totality over all Egypt As we are now dose
to the epoch of maximum sun spots, the
protruberences should be very brilliant and
numerous.
<head>EGYPTIAN IMPROVEMENTS</head>
CORPORATION.
The subscription for shares in the Egyptian
Improvements Corporation was opened at the
Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Cairo and Alexandria,
this morning and will dose to-morrow at 5 p,m.
We have already drawn the attention of out
readers to this new company, which seems to
he founded on a serious basis. It has also*
plan of action dearly defined, and appear* to
have several important affairs in hand and in
course of realisation under specially advan-
tageous conditions. The board is composed of
well-known men who have had a great deal of
experience in the business for which the com-
pany is formed. Two of the members of the
board are specialists, M. C. J. Nicole, who is
at the head of one of the biggest real estate
houses in Europe, and M. Charvant, of Messrs.
Guetin and Charvant, of Cairo. M. C. J. Nicole
has been appointed administrateur-delegue,and
the management will probably also be confided
to a Swiss who is acquainted with every branch
of the business.
<head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
DEPARTURES
Le paquebot “Cleopatra” du Lloyd Autri-
chien, parti samedi poor Trieste avait k bold t
S.E. le Baron et la Baronne de Biegeleben,
M. Bertel et Mme A G. M. Dickson, M. K.
Dittmer, M. et Mme A. Prang), M. et Mme
N.Gandour et gouvernante, M. A Kaiser,
Mme Klinger et enfant, Mlle Lindenau, M. et
Mme Lee, Mr. M. E. Metatia, M. et Mme 0.
de Mohl et 2 filler, M. Muller, M. A. Petrof et
8 de famille, M. G. K. Rouschias, Mr. L Selig-
sohn, M. Schaetzle, Mlle Sacks, M. Springer,
M. le Dr. Sassi, Mme Thoma et fille, M. V.
Vedl, M. C. H. Vogel, 48 Pelerins Bresiliens,
M. Vogel, 48 Pelerins Bresiliens, M. Francois
Abram, M. J. N. Asilouopulos, Mlle Martina
Arbeiter, Mile Bice Baitz, Rev. Bruno, M. E.
Bayer, M. Alex. Contaboni, M. Max Hokap-
fel, Mme Klaxer, Mme Mayard, M. Macri et
2 de famille, M. Meisser, Mlle Neherbauer,
Mme Popp, Mme Smidt et fils, Mme J. Sam eh
et 2 enfants, Rev. Walter, M. Zembruski, M.
Ziokermann, 8 femmes de chambre.
BECK & CO'S PILSENER BEER
Obtainable from every Respectable Firm
In Cairo, Alexandria & Ten Sudan
Otherwise apply to
E.J. Fleurent, 
Anglo-American Nile Steamer,
m HOTEL COMPANY.
RIVER TRANSPORT BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO
CARLTON HOTEL
Bulkily, Ramleh
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
