<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Logan Wills</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 1905</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-26">September 26, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 26 1905</head>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND VENEZUELA ATTEMPTED NEGOTIATIONS. STRAINED RELATIONS</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 25. The relations between France and Venezuela are becoming
                        acuta President Castro recently closed the French cable alleging a breach of
                        contract. M. Taigny. the French charge d’af- faires, is endeavouring to
                        negotiate, but Presi- dent Castro is adopting au arrogant attitude.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS. EMPEROR AND OPPOSITION.</head>

                    <p>Budapest, September 25. Intense anger prevails here at the way in which the
                        leaders of the Opposition were received by the Emperor, who received them
                        standing, did not shake hands, and addressed them curtly in German, without
                        giving them an opportunity to speak. He dismissed them in four minutes. </p>
                    <p>The leaders informed Count Cziraki yester- day morning that they declined to
                        form a Government on the Emperor’s conditions, Count Czraki promised to
                        bring the Emperor’s reply at 2.30 p.m., but when he arrived at the hotel at
                        3.15 he found that they had already returned to Budapest. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>Budapest, September 25. The Hungarian Opposition leaders received great
                        ovation when they returned here. (R.)</p>

                    <p>Budapest, September 25. Thw disagreement between the Hungarian cabinet and
                        the Emperor is becoming grave. (Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH COTTON GROWING. ASSOCIATION CEASES EXPENDITURE.</head>

                    <p>London, September 25. The "Westminster Gazette" is informed that the British
                        Cotton Growing Association has been compelled to cease expenditure on new
                        developments and to curtail its expend- ture generally, owing to lack of
                        financial support {Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>EAST AFRICAN REBELLION. ATTACK ON MAHENGE.</head>

                    <p>Berlin, September 25. 350 rebels in German East Africa have been killed in an
                        unsuccessful attack on Mahenge. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREECE AND ROUMANIA. THE PRESS INDIGNANT.</head>

                    <p>Bukarest. September 25. The newspapers protest against the expulsion of
                        Roumanians from Greece, and threaten to retaliate. The situation is
                        strained. (Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>TARTARS AND ARMENIANS. CONCLUSION OF PEACE.</head>

                    <p>Baku. September 25. A conference of the leading Tartars and Armenians has
                        concluded peace. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>JAPS SEIZE MERCHANT SHIP.</head>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 25. Intelligence has been received that the
                        Japanese have seized a steamer of the Kamt- chatka Trading Company near
                        Behring island, which they occupied afterwards. The name of the Japanese
                        commander and the date of the affair are not stated. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITAIN AND JAPAN. MEETING OP FLEETS. </head>

                    <p>Tokio. September 25. As soon as the treaty of peace is ratified the British
                        Squadron and the Japanese fleet will meet in Tokio Bay. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONGRESS OF POLAR EXPLORERS.</head>

                    <p>Brussels, September 25. The King has initiated a Congress of Polar Explorers
                        to organize international expeditions to both poles. All the leading
                        explorers have given their support to this Congress. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>M. WITTE'S MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, Septombar 25. M. Witte has had an interview with M. de Richthofen. He
                        will be received by the Empe- ror at the Castle of Rominten on Tuesday. R.)
                        Berlin, September 25. M. Witte visited Prince Von Bulow and then left for
                        Rominten. (Havas)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE COUNT BRAZZA</head>

                    <p>PariS, September 25. The explorer Brazza was returning to France with the
                        most scathing indictment against M. Gentil, the administrator of the French
                        Congo, for incapacity and maladministration, aS well as for encouraging
                        gross cruelties. (Reuter</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF M. CAVAIGNAC.</head>

                    <p>Paris, September 95. The ex-minister Cavaignao is deed. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>A Smuggler Arrested.—An Arab named Mohamad Abdullah was arrested last Sunday
                        for attempting to pass the customs officers with a quantity of tobacco in
                        his possession without declaring it.</p>

                    <p>The Bank ok Athens.—We understand that the cashier of the Bank of Athens who
                        was arrester I yesterday on a charge of embez- zlement had misappropriated
                        £1,000 and not £2,000 as was generally reported at the time.</p>

                    <p>Suez Canal.—10 vessels pa sod through the Canal on the 22nd inst, 8 of which
                        were British, 1 German, 1 French. The day’s receipts were frs. 295,1-82.40,
                        making the total from the 1st inst frs. 6,133,032.65.</p>

                    <p>Child Burnt to Death —A little boy of five years of age was playing with a
                        lighted candle in his father's house on Saturday even- ing, when his clothes
                        caught fire. The lad received severe burns, from which he died very shortly
                        after. </p>

                    <p>A Gambler’s End. - A Copt named Rusdi Morcos, 33 years of ago, who had
                        misappro- priated gums of money entrustod to his charge and had lost them by
                        gambling, committed suicide on Saturday evening by drinking a quantity of
                        phenic acid.</p>

                    <p>Cholera in Russia.—The president of the quarantine board has received
                        information from the Russian sanitary delegate of a fatal case of cholera at
                        Vlatslovosk, Varsovia. The precautionary measures of disinfection and
                        isolation have been taken.</p>

                    <p>Fatal Bathing Accident. -A native, Gad Ahmed Ibrahim by name, twenty years of
                        age, was bathing yesterday at El Nafrouzeh, when he suddenly disappeared
                        under water and did not come up again. The body of the un- fortunate youth,
                        was, however, recovered later and taken to the hospital, where an inquest
                        was held previous to interment.</p>

                    <p>Army Arabic Examination. —The follow- ing officers of the Egyptian Army have
                        passed the Preliminary Arabic Examination held on the 1st August:—El
                        Bimbashi Hawksley, Artii- ery, El Bimbashi Dyer, D.S.O., Camel Corps, El
                        Bimbashi Lucas, 1st Battalion, El Bimbashi Percival, 11th Sadanase, El
                        Bimbashi Beamish, 12th Sudanese, El Bimbashi Rugg. Medical Corps, El
                        Bimbashi Foster, Medical Corps.</p>

                    <p>Fall from a Roof.—A sad accident oc- curred yesterday in the Attarin quarter
                        to a native woman of forty years of age, named Mahbouba bint Ahmed. The un-
                        fortunate woman was at work on the roof of her house, and at the time was
                        occupied in shaking a mat, when she overbalanced herself and fell from the
                        roof to the ground. Her ankle was fractured and it is believed that death
                        must have been almost instantaneous.</p>

                    <p>Troops for Egypt.—The transport Duners, which leaves Southampton to morrow,
                        will bring out a large number of troops for Egypt, includ- ing 7 officers
                        and 153 non-commissioned officers and men for the Royal Berkshire Regiment ;
                        1 officer and 152 noncommissioned officers and men for the Royal
                        Inniskilling Fusiliers, 1 officer and 56 non commissioned officers and men
                        for the King's Royal Rifles ; 41 men of the Royal Garrison Artill-.ry,
                        besides several details for other corps. The vessel is due at Alexandria on
                        the 8th October.</p>

                    <p>For the Calabrian Victims.—We are once more asked to appeal to our readers to
                        support an entertainment for the relief of the victims of the Calabrian
                        earthquake. The committee of the San Stefano Club and H.E. Khalil Pasha
                        Hamada are organising a benefit entertainment, which is to take place on
                        Friday, under the patronage of Baron Acton, diplomatic agent and consul
                        general for Italy, when the children of tbe members of the committee will
                        perform a ballet "en miniature” on the terrace of the casino. The Bracale
                        orchestra will give a concert, the items of which will be composed entirely
                        of Verdi’s works and the band of the customs porters’ children will also
                        play selections. At the conclusion of the enter- tainment a number of
                        presents will be dis- tributed to the cbildren. Subscribers will not be
                        admitted except on payment of the entrance fee of P.T. 5, and the whole of
                        the receipts will be devoted to the benefit fund. The entertainment will
                        commence at 5 p.m.</p>

                    <p>Esbekieh Gardens Theatre. -Judging by the large audience that nightly attend
                        this theatre, the French Operetta company now performing there seem to have
                        become great favorites with the Cairene playgoing public. On Saturday the
                        three act comedy Monsieur le Directeur was played before a crowded and
                        enthusiastic house. Between the second and third acts Mlle Symiane-Val
                        entertained the audience with some songs from her extensive repertoire which
                        elicited hearty applause. Last night the Gardet company gave a special
                        benefit performance for the thousands I who have been rendered destitute by
                        the terrible earthquake in Calabria and the house was crowded in every part.
                        The artistes appear- ed to excel themselves for the occasion and their
                        efforts met with most hearly and well deserved applause. The piece staged
                        was La Marraine de Charley, which evoked much laughter. Daring the third act
                        Madame Bra- cale sang Giordano's "Andre Chenier" and Bizet's "Pecheur dee
                        Perles” in excellent strain, and the ever popular Mile Symiane-Val sang
                        "Sous les Bamboos," "Daos l’Oasis," and "Messanda” with her accustomed
                        vivacity.</p>
                </div>



                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE RAILWAYS REPORT. REPLY TO THE COMMISSION.</head>

                    <p>The report of the Board of Administration of the State Railways and
                        Telegraphs and the Port of Alexandria is of special interest, appear- ing as
                        it does a few months after the report of the railway commission presided
                        over by Lord Farrar. The chairman and the directors of the board were
                        evidently by no means insensible to the criticisms of Lord Farrar, Mr. Bury
                        and Major Le Breton, and at the conclusion of the report under the heading
                        "General” the reader will find their answer to the commis- sion. So
                        interesting is this reply that we felt that no apology is needed for the
                        reproduction of the more interesting passages of the direc- tors reply in
                        full.</p>
                    <p>“During the last four months of the year, a rapid and exceptional increase of
                        imports pro- duced an acute crisis in traffic at Alexandria and gave rise to
                        well-founded complaints. We had forseen the possibility of such a crisis,
                        though we had not anticipated so sudden an increase in trade, but we had
                        been unable to obtain funds in sufficient time to prepare for it. Since it
                        occurred, funds have keen placed at our disposal, which are, we believe,
                        sufficient to provide against so serious a crisis in future.</p>
                    <p>The commission presided over by Lord Far- rer, to which we have alluded, was
                        in Egypt when these difficulties were at their worst, and it was far from
                        easy for our officials to deal with the exceptional stress of traffic and at
                        the same time furnish the commission with the information they desired in a
                        complete and convenient form.</p>
                    <p>The commission criticised severely our sys- tem of signals. When the present
                        Board took office, they were at once struck by the defects of this system,
                        but owing to the many other works which urgently required attention, and the
                        enquiries and experiments which we con- sidered necessary before embarking
                        on a large expenditure, we did not seriously commence signalling work until
                        1903, in which year we gave large orders for appliances of the latest types.
                        The erection of these appliances only commenced in 1904, and the commission
                        seems to have based its opinion on installations which were unfinished, or
                        even—as at Kantara, which is cited by them as an example — which had not
                        been commenced.</p>
                    <p>The reasons which led us to adopt the electro pneumatic system for Cairo
                        station do not appear to have been fully explained to the commission.</p>
                    <p>The technical member of the commission expressed to us verbally a high
                        opinion of our signal engineer, Naghib Bey Shakour, which we share. We note
                        with pleasure the remarks of the commission on the ability and skill of Mr.
                        Husson, deputy chief engineer, who is entrusted with the difficult task of
                        strengthen- ing the railway bridges.</p>
                    <p>Finally, we cannot refrain from commenting on the remarks made both in the
                        report of the commission and in the press on the subject of the Permanent
                        Way Department. It is extremely easy to criticise this Department, it is
                        most difficult for any person not intimately concerned in the work to
                        realise the difficulties which have baset Mr. Cotterill's efforts to make
                        good the defects both of organisation and of maintenance which had resulted
                        partly from a long period of insufficient expenditure, partly from other
                        causes which we need not here discuss. Mr. Cotterill has ungrudgingly
                        devoted all his time and energy to the work ; he has done his utmost to
                        ensure economy, to defend the interests of the administration, and to
                        improve the position of his staff, espe- cially of the labouring class. No
                        one acquaint- ed with the alterations made daring his term of office, can
                        fail to recognize the improve- ments effected under his direction.</p>
                    <p>Much remains to be done, and we have been obliged to consider the
                        desirability of appoint- ing a succesor to him, whose powers have not been
                        affected by so long a period of work under trying conditions; but we feel
                        certain that if he leaves our service, his own staff and many in this
                        country who have been brought into contact with him, will join in our
                        sincere regret at his departure."</p>
                    <p>Whatever view be taken of the defence as a whole, (and it is certain to give
                        rise to some discussion) we feel sure that the references to Mr. Cotterill
                        contained in the last two para- graphs will be thoroughly appreciated by all
                        who have had an opportunity of watching Mr. Cotterill's work or of studing
                        his schemes for the benefit of the lower ranks of his staff and their
                        children.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB. REGATTA.</head>

                    <p>The handicap for to-morrow's race is the the same as last week.— Class I.
                        Coarse B. Class II. Course N.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB, (ALEX )</head>

                    <p>Owing to the annual acquatic sports of the Alexandria Swimming Club taking
                        place on Saturday, 7th October, there will be no shoot- ing on that day, the
                        B.R C. Cup competition being postponed until Saturday. 14th October
                        next.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA CRICKET CLUB.</head>

                    <p>The season of the Alexandria Cricket Club will he closed on Satarday by a
                        match between earns composed of members who are over and those who are under
                        29 years of age.</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHATHAM EXPLOSION. TRANSPORT OF BLASTING MATERIAL.</head>

                    <p>A special train arrived at Alexandria from Aboukir shortly after 1 am.
                        yesterday. The train which had been specially chartered by Messrs. Thos Cook
                        and Sons was in charge of Hr. Harold Harris, P.C.S., the well-known expert
                        employed by Messrs. Nobel, and con- tained twenty-two cases of blasting
                        gelatine with other accessories which are to be employ- ed in the blowing np
                        of the SS. Chatham which will take place on Thursday. These cases, which had
                        been stored at Aboukir, were naturally handled with great care by all who
                        were responsible for their conveyance to the train and officials of the
                        Railway Admi- nistration were also on board the "special" to supervise the
                        operation and the transport of the cases to Alexandria. In the evening the
                        train left Alexandria station with Mr. Harris on board for Ras-el-Esh,a
                        station fourteen kilo metres south of Port Said, near which the electric
                        batteries which will ignite the charges that are to explode the Chatham are
                        to be put into place. Special precautions have been taken against any
                        accident happening to the train which conveys the explosive charges.</p>
                    <p>We hear that no great danger is apprehended by the most competent judges from
                        the wave that will follow the explosion. They hold that, the banks of the
                        canal near the scene of the explosion being low, a great quantity of the
                        water displaced will sweep, over them and dissipate its force instead of
                        rushing violently up and down the canal as it would do were the banks high
                        and solid.</p>
                    <p>A certain amount of inconvenience will be caused to the public by the rupture
                        of tele- graphic communication between Port Said and the rest of Egypt, and
                        we wonder whether it would be possible for the Government and the Eastern
                        Telegraph Company to come to an ar- rangement by which the submarine cable
                        from Port Said to Alexandria could be used for messages to other parts of
                        Egypt during the interval between the explosion and the restor- ation of
                        telegraphic communication.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHIP ASHORE IN SUEZ GULF. ( From our Correspondent ).</head>
                    <p>Suez, Monday. The Anchor liner Nubia from Liverpool bound to Calcutta with
                        general cargo ran ashore yesterday in the Suez gulf at Ras Shukhair, fifteen
                        miles south of Ras Garib lighthouse.</p>
                    <p>It is however expected she will come off after discharging cargo from the
                        forehold, and for this purpose assistance will be sent from Suez to
                        night.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE MR. HANSARD.</head>

                    <p>The late Mr. R. M. Hansard's funeral which took place at the Cairo cemetery
                        on Sunday at 4.30 p.m. was attended by Col. Atkin- son, Capt. Lidlow, Capt.
                        Pearson, Messrs. E. M. Dowson, W. B. Trelawoy, J. Craig, L. B. Weldon, G. R.
                        Smith, Robert Bey, Dr J. Ball, II. J. Boadnell, J. Kearney, B. F. Keeling,
                        A. Lucas, Ch. Seiuerth, S. H. Trim an, F. Wilshire, T. D. Scott, Grahame,
                        Harle, Man-field, Da Cosson, Dr J. Garner, Tatton Brown, Muntz etc. etc, and
                        all the Survey staff (including many native employes).</p>
                    <p>The funeral service was conducted by the Very Rev. Dean Butcher.</p>
                    <p>Wreaths were sent by Capt. and Mrs. Lyons, Lieat. Col. and Mrs. Atkinson,
                        Capt. H. D. Pear sou, Mr. and Mrs. J. F. G. Hopkins, Mr. E. M. Dowson and
                        Mr, W. B. Trelawny, Mr. and Mrs. L. B. Weldon. Mr. and Mrs. Craig, the
                        printing office, Survey Dept., the topographical 'office and„"His colleagues
                        in Upper Egypt."</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOTORS FOR THE SUDAN.</head>

                    <p>The Sirdar has been for some time trying to solve the problem of desert
                        locomotion by the introduction of a quicker mode of transport than the camel
                        in those, districts which are not served by the railway. The motor-car which
                        has been constructed specially for Sir Reginald Wingate for the purposes of
                        desert travel was finally tested before the departure of the Sirdar for
                        Egypt last week on the sands at Dunbar. While the car came well out of the
                        trials it is doubtful whether a motor can be constructed that would be
                        powerful enough to drag the 1 1/2 ton dead weight of the trailer, as the
                        sandbanks of the Sudan would place a heavy strain on the machinery. The car
                        when last tried ploughed through the soft sand at the rate of three miles an
                        hour; on the harder aand seven miles was the average, and when relieved of
                        the trailer excellent progress was made.</p>
                    <p>It will be interesting to know at what rate of progression the same car can
                        be propelled over the loose sandy soil of the greater part of the desert,
                        and whether this specially built motor will turn out a success, for, if so,
                        the problem will have been solved.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advertisement">
                    <head>BECK and CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
                    <p>Bremen Obtainable from every respectable firm In Cairo, Alexandria, and the
                        Sudan Otherwise apply to, E.J Fleurent F. Micallif</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTABLE DENOUNCED. BASELESS ACCUSATION.</head>

                    <p>A certain Abdallah Sadik recently informed the Slave Trade Department that
                        Lamloum Bey El Saadi, a notable of Maghagha, who rendered considerable
                        services of a quasi-di- plomatic nature to the Government this year, had
                        brought four black slaves with him from the frontier of Tripoli, which he
                        visited in March.</p>
                    <p>On receiving this denunciation the Depart- ment sent an inspector to visit
                        the Bey's ezbeh at Maghagha. The black slaves proved to be free laborers
                        working for a daily wage, abso- lutely without complaint and, in fine,
                        enjoying what Mr. Edward Lear describes as "truly abject and rustic
                        happiness.” The Bey, who was justly indignant at the accusation stated that
                        he bad been sent on a mission to the frontier of Tripoli and had there
                        settled a number of questions that had arisen from Bedouin quarrels, and
                        finding Sudanese slaves there had persuaded them to accompany him to Egypt,
                        after obtaining manumission documents from the Ottoman Government which were
                        countersigned by the British Con- sul. The Bey having thus emerged from the
                        enquiry without a stain on his character Abd- allah Sadik remains to be
                        dealt with. We hope to hear of his appearance in the dock one of these
                        days.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MENZALEH CANAL CO.</head>

                    <p>It is now expected that the channel across the lake will be completed by the
                        end of next month,and it is proposed that Sir John Rogers, the chairman of
                        the company, who returns to Cairo in about a month’s time, will inaugurate
                        the new passengers and goods service between Port Said and Matarieh in the
                        first week of November. The Matarieh and Damietta section will then be taken
                        in hand and it is hoped that the dredging operations of the whole distance
                        of about 30 kilometres will be finished in six months. When this has been
                        accomplish- ed the company will then undertake the widening of the Ananieh
                        canal near Damietta, which is 6 1/4 kilometres long, and by means of a lock
                        gate, make it navigable for small steamers, which will then be able to go
                        through from Port Said to Mansourah by the Nile. This work will also greatly
                        facilitate the transport of coal from the former port to all the places on
                        the river.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HAMBURG-AMERIKA LINE.</head>

                    <p>We learn on good authority that a meeting of the directors of the
                        Hambarg-Amerika and Anglo-American Companies will be held in London in the
                        course of next week when it is expected that a decision will be arrived at
                        between the two companies with regard to a joint tourist service on the
                        Nile. As we have already informed our readers the German com- pany intended
                        starting a rival line of river steamers to run in opposition to the two ser-
                        vice already long established but, from what we hear the negotiations that
                        have been going on through the summer are likely to be brought soon to a
                        satisfactory conclusion.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>

                    <p>The above company has just concluded the sale of the estate purchased from
                        the Daira Sanieh about a year and a half ago at Mataana in Upper Egypt; the
                        price at which it has been sold will leave a net profit of £50,000 to the
                        company. The estate consists of some 3,450 feddans, the greater part of
                        which is under cultivation, and gives a revenue of nearly £9,000 per annum,
                        which represents about 6% on the purchase price.</p>
                    <p>The board of directors in London have decided upon paying a dividend of ten
                        per cent on the called up capital at the end of next month. This is the
                        first distribution to be made since the formation of the company in
                        1899.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STOCK EXCHANGE SETTLEMENTS</head>

                    <p>The London Stock Exchange Committee has appointed Wednesday, September 27, a
                        special settling day in— Egyptian Gold and Gam Syndicate, Limited — 6,623
                        Vendors’ Shares of £l each fully paid, Nos 28,371 to 34,993. Sudan
                        Goldfield, Limited - 145,000 Vendors’ Shares of £1 each fully paid, Nos. 1
                        to 145,000.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>COAL ASSOCIATION.</head>

                    <p> We understand that the majority of the members of the Coal Association of
                        Alexandria favor a stoppage on the same lines as that which recently
                        disturbed the Genoa market and was caused by the dilatoriness of the Italian
                        Government in remedying the deficiency of the State Railways in waggon
                        supplies.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL AGRICULTURAL SOCIETY.</head>

                    <p>At its meeting of last Saturday the execu- time committee of the Khedivial
                        Agricultural Society decided to establishing seven large depots of chemical
                        manures in the principal centres of Lower Egypt and appoint store keepers to
                        have the charge of these depots. It was also derided to hold the usual
                        agriculture show at Cairo in the first fortnight of February. The Mansourah
                        show was put off a week to avoid dashing with the Leilat-al-Mirag feast in
                        the middle of the Moslem month of Shaaban.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

                    <p>H. H. the Khedive left Constantinople yesterday and will arrive at Alexandria
                        on Thursday.</p>

                    <p>Boutros Pasha Ghali arrived at Alexandria this morning by the Messagaries
                        Maritime until boat.</p>

                    <p>Mrs. and Miss Bullock are returning to Egypt by the troopship Donera, leaving
                        Southampton to-morrow.</p>

                    <p>El Kaimakam D. K. E. Hall Bey, Government, and El Bimbashi H. M Travers, 10th
                        Sudanese, have resigned their commis- sions in the Egyptian Army.</p>

                    <p>Captain C. K. Morgan, R.A.M.C., has been granted leave of abscooe until
                        December 21.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Warnock, resident medical superinten- dent of the Abbasieh Lunatic
                        Asylum, is expected to return to Cairo from England at the end of this
                        month.</p>

                    <p>H. I. M. the Shah of Persia has been gra- ciously pleased to bestow the order
                        of com- mander of the 3rd Class of the Lion and Sun upon Mr. C. Meimarachi,
                        managing direotor of Messrs. Walker and Meimarachi, Ltd.</p>

                    <p> We are pleased to announce that Dr. Charles Faber, American Dentist of
                        Cairo, will shortly open an office in Davies Bryan’s new building for the
                        practice of his profession.</p>

                    <p>The news comes from Vienna that Mr. Bea- man, correspondent of the "Standard”
                        at the Austrian capital has met with a slight accident Mrs. Beaman, who has
                        been staying at Ther- pia, has left for Vienna with Mile Sophie Corpi.</p>

                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice:—Capt
                        Ladmouth, Mr. and Mrs. W. W. D. Tweddie, Miralai O’Connell Bey, Kaimakam
                        Percival Bey, Vi- comte and Vicomtease de Fontarce, M. Atorff, Mr. A. Baker,
                        Ayruth Bey and family, Miss Miller, Miss Reimer, Mr. Walther, Mi. B. Joseph,
                        Hogg Bey, Rev. and Mrs. Cooke Collie Smith, M. Siess, M. Histhemann.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head> LETTER TO THE EDITOR. We do not hold ourselves responsible for the
                        opinions expressed by our correspondents, but we wish, in spirit of fair
                        play to all, to permit - within certain necessary limits- free discussion.
                        APPEAL TO THE SOCIETE ARTISTIQUE.</head>

                    <p>To the Editor or the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—As the open season draws near I
                        allow myself to ask the Societe Artistique if this year we will again be
                        bereft of one of the finest modern operas, and only for a political
                        difference. Yes political!! strange as it seems. But what have politics to
                        do with art,. and pa- triotism with music?</p>
                    <p>It is Germania that I mean, that splendid opera that we had the happy chance
                        of seeing staged two years ago, interpreted by cele- brated artists such as
                        Anoona, Garbin, and Santerelli, not forgetting Walter Carlo and Emma
                        Trentini.</p>
                    <p>The piece was new, the music rather diffi- cult, worthy of Wagner himself,
                        but little by little the artistic ear of the Egyptian public relished the
                        masterful and harmonious "airs” of Germania and the eye became more and more
                        interested in its everchanging scenes.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria especially was enthusiastic. In every corner one spoke but of
                        Germania and the "Gaudeamus igitur" was whistled by young and old. But then
                        came the reaction.</p>
                    <p>Some found themselves piqued in their patriotism, especially by the last
                        scene in which Napoleon’s army is seen retreating before the Germans, and
                        loud was their outcry, that such a piece could be played in a land like
                        ours. I say "some" and happily there were not many.</p>
                    <p>This year La Belliucioni will once more favor us with her presence! What a
                        splendid "Ricke” she would be, and we all hope to see her in this part.</p>
                    <p>Let politics be politics and art remain art. One has nothing to do with the
                        other.—I am, Sir, etc.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advertisement">
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL RESTAURANT TABE D’HATE LUNCHEONSS and DINNERS SERVED ON THE
                        TERRACE ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M. DELIGHTFUL SITUATION SEA BREEZES</p>
                </div>

                <div type="advertisement">
                    <p>CARLTON HOTEL Ramble’s Fashionable Hotel Patronized by the Elite</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
