<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Emma Taylor</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-03">October 3, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-15">November 15,1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item"><head>ENGLAND AND RUSSIA.
                A POLITICAL ENTENTE PAVING THE WAY.</head>
               <p> London, November 14.</p>
                <p>Renter’s  Agency is authoritatively informed that the friendliest discussions are going on between Great Britain and Russia, with a  view to eliminating the obstacles in the way of negotiations for a political entente, when the time is ripe for the latter ; but definite political steps are inopportune while the present | disturbed state of Russia continues. It is felt, however, that it is already possible to pave the way, by the revision  of the commercial treaty, in view of closer commercial relations. (Reuter) </p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>FRENCH DOCKYARD STRIKE. ATTITUDE OF GOVERNMENT.</head>
                <p>PARIS, November 14.</p>
                <p>The dockyard employés at Toulon, Brest, Rochefort, and Cherbourg will strike to-day.</p> <p>(Reuter)</p>
                <p>PARIS, November 14.</p>
                <p>The strike in the French dockyards has begun without disorder.
                Except at Toulon arsenal, the strike is only partial.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p>
                <p>PARIS, November 14.</p>
                <p>The strike is general at Toulon and partial at Brest and Cherbourg.</p>
                <p>A circular issued by M. Thomson, Minister, assimilates the strike to desertion. The strikers will be struck off the lists.</p>
                <p>M. Reuvier stated in the Senate that the Government would resist the strike. This statement was received with applause.	</p><p>(Havas)</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE POWERS AND THE PORTE.
                THE NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                <p>CONSTANTINOPLE, November 14.</p>
                <p>It is understood that before making a naval demonstration the Powers will notify the Sol- tan of their preparations, in the hope that he may listen to reason at the last moment. (R.)</p> </div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS.
                RESTORING ORDER.</head>
                <p>ST. PETERSBURG. November 14.</p>	
                <p>The Governors of Odessa, Esthonia, Perm, Tomsk, and Kezan have been dismissed for not having prevented the massacres. (Reuter)</p>  <p>ST. PETERSBURG, November 14.</p>
                <p>The Tsar is sending aides-de-camps armed with dictatorial powers to restore order in the governments of Tehermigoff, Saratoff, and Tamboff, where disorders between the town and rural populations still continue.</p>
                <p>There were a hundred killed in a small town in the government of Ekaterinoslav. (Reuter)</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>TO PROTECT AMERICAN CITIZENS.</head>
                <p>LISBON, November 14.</p>
                <p>It is stated that the American cruiser Minneapolis, now here, has received urgent orders to proceed to Kronstadt to protect American citizens. Marines will be disembarked if necessary.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>MASS MEETING IN LONDON.</head>
                <p>LONDON, November 14.</p>
                <p>A mass meeting has been held at the Memorial Hall to protest against the Russian atrocities A telegram was read from Mr. Balfoar stating that the Government had beard with pity and horror of the massacres of Jews, and bad already taken every step that seems possible to mitigate the calamity. Lord Rose¬bery, Mr. Chamberlain, Mr. Asquith, Lord Rothschild, the Archbishops of Canterbury and Westminster, and other prominent men sent similar telegrams.</p>	<p>(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE ENTENTE MUNICIPAL.
                FRENCH INVITATION TO L.C.C.</head>
                <p>LONDON, November 14.</p>
                <p>The County Council has received the most cordial invitation from the Paris Municipal Council to visit Paris in January. (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES
                235 BRANCHES.
                French, German, Italian, Greek, Arabic, etc. Private Lessons, Residence Lessons, taught by Native Masters.
                ALEXANDRIA : 26 Rue de l'Eglise Copte.
                CAIRO :	1 Sharia Kamel.
                TRIAL LESSON FREE.</p></div>
              
                        <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                            
                            <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>
                            
                            <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                            
                            <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
                            
                            <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
                            
                        </div>
                        
                  </div>  </body>
                    
                </text>
    <title>ARISTON AERATED WATERS advertisement</title>
    
   </bibl>
    
    </sourceDesc>
    
    </fileDesc>
    
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        
        <body>
            
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                
                <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                
                <p> Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                
                <p> ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste. </p>
                
                <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                
            </div>
            
        </body>
        
    </text>
               <div type="item">  LOCAL AND GENERAL
               <p>The Brindisi Mail.</p> 
                <p>The Brindisi mail will arrive at Alexandria this afternoon and be distributed at the G.P.O. at 5 p.m.</p>
                <p>Stray Dogs.</p>
                <p>Stray and ownerless dogs found in the Sayeda Zenab quarter of Cairo during the night of the 16th inst will be poisoned by the police.</p> 
                   <p>Asphalting in Cairo.</p>
                <p>Fagalish street, Cairo, is to be asphalted next year. During the progress of the work the trams will run by a new route for the time being.</p>
                <p>Fatal Tram Accident</p>
                <p>An Arab boy six or seven years old was ran over by a tramcar this morning near the corner of Sisters street and Mohamed Aly square. The child was killed on the spot.</p>
                <p>British Manufacturers’ Exhibition.</p>
                <p>A general meeting in connection with the proposed exhibition of British manufactures will be held at H.B.M.’s Consulate, Alexandria, on Tuesday, 21st inst., at 4.30 p.m.</p>
                <p>Fire on Ship.</p>
                <p>The S.S. Westburn, which arrived at Alexandria on Monday with a fire on board, has begun discharging her cargo of coal The fire in the hold has been almost extinguished.</p> 
                   <p>Murder st Tantah.</p>
                <p>While George Avrinos and Yanui Konatns, two residents of Tantah, were drinking together in a bar on Sunday, a dispute arose between them which ended in the former stabbing his companion fatally.</p>
                <p>Suez Canal.</p>
                <p>16 vessels passed through the Canal on the 10th and 14th inst., 18 of which were British, 4 German, 2 French, 1 Austrian, 1 Portuguese. The total receipts from the 1st to the 11th inst were frs. 3,683,898.06.</p>
                <p>Fikis at Alexandria.</p>
                <p>The Khedive has given orders for the creation of three committees cf fikis for reading the Koran in the mosques of Alexandria. The incomes of these three committees have been fixed at LE. 700 a year.</p>
                <p>Journalists Imprisoned.</p> 
                <p>The Court of Sayeda Zenab, Cairo, has sen¬tenced Ahmed Eff. Abbas and Reghib Eff. Hassad, editors of "El Khalan," and Abd-El- Medjid Eff. Kamel, editor of the Egyptian "Papagallo,” to six months' imprisonment for libelling Ibrahim Eff. Shaker, an advocate of Cairo.</p>
                <p>El Dorado.</p>
                <p>Alexandrians will be glad to hear that M. Conegliano has transformed the summer garden bordering on his new establishment in Cairo Station street into a winter garden. Mr. Conegliano neglects nothing to satisfy the desires of his patrons, and the El Dorado should soon become the most frequented rendezvous in the city.</p>
                <p>Scorpions at Keneh.</p>
                <p>Owing to the many deaths from scorpions in Keneh and its neighborhood, a society was formed some time ago for the purpose of putting an end to the pest, and a reward of two milliemes for each scorpion killed was offered. From the end of May to the end of October last 4,990 scorpions had been destroy¬ed at Keneh.</p>
                <p>Shepheard's Hotel.</p>
                <p>From to-day a general booking office will be open at Shepheard’s Hotel for the issue of 1st and 2nd class railway passenger tickets and forwarding of luggage by passenger trains to the destination of Alexandria, Ismailia, Port Said, and Luxor during the tourist season. In addition to the general tariff rates, an extra charge of 5 milliemes on every passenger ticket and on every 100 kilos of luggage, or fraction of same, will be made on all bookings from this office.</p>
                <p>Relieving his Conscience.</p>
                <p>Elias el Absi, an inmate of Tantah prison, has written to the Parquet stating that, being desirous of relieving his conscience, he wishes to confess the following crimes, which have hitherto been unknown to the authorities. He murdered, he says, a sheikh el Arab, by name Lemboon el Saadi, near Magbaghs, in the Minieh moudirieh, and sold a plot of land belonging to the Government, in the Sharkieh moudirieb, to a native, pretending that he was a delegate of the Ministry of Finance. An enquiry has been opened by the authorities.</p>
                <p>Nile Trip.</p>
                <p>The Anglo American Nile Steamer and Hotel Co. announce that their first departure from Cairo to Assouan, for the twenty days' trip, will take place on the 8th December next, by the first-class tourist steamer Mayflower. Though the company's lowest rate for tourists is £49, yet residents will be afforded a special opportunity to travel by the Mayflower at the exceptionally reduced rate of watch will include a first-class table, all sight-seeing expenses, excursions, dragoman,&c.Tbe Government permit of £1.4 8. is not included in the above fare.</p>
                <p>Burnt to Death.</p>
                <p>A Berberin, employed as a servant in one of the flats attached to the National Hotel, Cairo, went to sleep on Monday night and awoke to find his clothes on fire. Seized with panic the wretched man ran op and down the stain calling for help. Mr. Rozensweig, of the Minis try of Public Works, extinguished the flames, and the man, who did not receive any useful assistance from his fellow servants,was conveyed to hospital in a carriage which had been sent for by a British resident. The shock from his injuries bad been too great, however and he succumbed yesterday morning.</p></div>
                <div type="item"> <head>SALT AND SODA.
                QUESTION OF THE CONCESSION. EXCITEMENT ON BOURSES.</head>
                <p>The great excitement which was display¬ed on the Alexandria and Cairo Bourses yesterday, in the rash to dispose of Salt and Soda shares, was renewed this morning, when a further fall took place and lens of thousands of shares were disposed of. At midday some strong buyers appeared on the market and a slight recovery took place. The shares closed when we went to press at 24s. 6d.</p>
               <p>It is stated that the Egyptian Government has withdrawn the salt concession, but that there are grounds for believing that an arrangement will be arrived at between the company and the Government, so that a modus vivendi may be established. This news is, however, not official, but merely the substance of what is alleged on the Alexandria Bourse.</p>
                <p>Lord Cromer’s remarks on the subject in his last Report are worthy of quotation at the present juncture. His lordship says "I regard this (the salt monopoly) as one of the greatest of the remaining blots on the existing fiscal system. A country lest adapted for a monopoly of salt than Upper Egypt can hardly be imagined. The desert is full of salt, which can be had for the trouble of taking it away. In the long narrow strip of inhabited land, there are but few villages which are far from some salt deposit Smuggling, of course, takes place and it is practically impossible to stop it. In 1904, 1,716 cases of contraband occurred; the number of persons fined or imprisoned was 1,223. In the remaining cases, the salt was seized, and the animals used in smuggling were confiscated. The number of animals thus confiscated was 489. The offenders rarely, if ever pay the fines imposed, and, I conceive, do not much mind being imprisoned for a short t mo. Confiscation of the animals is probably a more severe punishment, as it must often reduce the culprits, who are all very poor, to a state of indigence. Although no domiciliary visits are ever made to search for salt, it cannot be doubted that the measures taken to repress the contraband trade axe rightly regarded by the population as oppressive. I hope, therefore, that the financial situation will, at tome future time, permit of a Urge reduction in the royalty now paid on salt A small reduction would merely involve a loss of revenue, and would not lead to any considerable increase of consumption.”</p>
                <p>The revenue derived from the salt monopoly in 1904 was L.E. 182,000 as compared to L.E. 169,000 in 1903 ; 60,000 tons of salt were consumed. This is at about the rate of 5.4 kilos, per head of population. The normal consumption in most European countries is considerably higher than this figure.</p>
                <p>Prior to 1892, all salt was sold direct by the Government at a price of P.T. 800 a ton. It is now sold by the company at P.T. 500 a ton. The Government receive a royalty out of this sum of no less than P.T. 310 a ton.</p> </div>
                <div type="item"> <head>EGYPTIAN ESTATES.</head>
                <p>The Egyptian Estates, Limited, have made a moat successful deal in the disposal of a fine block of land of 4,950 square metres with a frontage of 150 metres, to Messrs Walker and Meimarachi,Limited, in the Ismailia quarter of Cairo, near the Credit Ponder and the E.T.C. The Egyptian Estates bought the land at LE. 10 per square metre and sold it at L E. 15. Immediately after the purchase Messrs. Walker and Meimarachi were offered LE. 20, but refused to entertain this. The profit in the transaction realised by the Egyptian Estates accounts to close on £25,000.</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>NEW BANKS IN EGYPT.</head>
                <p>The Wiener Bank Verein intends to commence backing operations in Egypt shortly. This bank’s two new branches at Gatala and Stamboul will be opened on January 1. As soon as these branches have been opened and are in working order, the direction of the bank will busy itself with the foundation of its new branches at Alexandria and Cairo.</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>PRO BONO PUBLICO ?</head>
                <p>A Cairo French contemporary announces that Mr. Terah Hooley and Mr. Horatio Bottomley are coming to Egypt this season. Oar contemporary adds : Nos hôtes, qui comp- tent parmi les rois de la finance anglaise, »e proposent d''étudier l'opportunité de contribuer au mouvement industriel du pays.’’</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>STOCK EXCHANGE SETTLING DAYS.</head>
                <p>The Committee of the London Stock Exchange has fixed settling days as under: Nov. 14.- Central Egypt Exploration Com¬pany, limited—7 shares of £1 each, fully paid
                (Nos. ICO,001 to 100,007);and 99,993 Vendor’s shares of £1 each, fully paid(Nos. 8 to 100.000)
                Nov. 22. - Eridea (Egypt) Exploring Company, Limited—10,007 shares of £1 each, fully paid (Nos. 1 to 8 and 65,008 to 75,007)</p>
                </div> <div type="item"
                    ><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                <p>The S.S. Roman Prince, from Manchester, with passengers and general cargo, left Malta on Tuesday, and is doe to arrive at Alexandria on the 18th inst.</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>THE SUCRERIES.
                THE POUTREL-DAVEY ACTION.</head>
                <p>At 10 a.m. yesterday the 2nd Chambre Civile of the Cairo Mixed Court was asleep, or st least nodding : oases of small importance Ironed along— some of the members of the Bench were obviously drowsy and the audience bored. At last Judge Herzbruch called the Poutrel Davey case,—No. 50 on the roll sod the audience and Bench awoke in earnest Me. Guilhanmon opened the case for his client shortly before 11 a.m. and for the next forty minutes kept the Court interested, for his speech contained some most interesting passages described in piteons terms the plight of M. Poutrel, summoned from Europe by an urgent wire and dismissed within three hours of bis arrival at Cairo, and then discussed the reasons of his dismissal. Obviously, the Hon. A. J. Davey and others bad sought a scapegoat and M. Poutrel had been selected for this office : the whole beard had done its utmost to escape from the incubus of their responsibility for the crash, some had failed, and the Hon. A J. Davey's attempts could impose on no one. How could he explain sway the letter that ha had written to his colleagues on the board ? -the letter containment  the statement of Mr. X, who informed the Hon. A. J. Davey in the Turf Club that Sir Ernest Cassel had told him in the presence of Birch Pasha many things, and this among others, that if he did not take the Sucreries in hand a smash was inevitable, and that he did not know how they got their dividends and meant to go into the question.”</p>
                <p>Counsel for the defence suggested that the letter might as well be produced. Mr. Guilhaumon declined, but stated that he believed in its existence and contained to take its most interesting passages as his text All, be said. pointed to the fact that the Hon. A. J. Davey knew all and had known all along before the crash, nor did he fail to avail himself of other arguments. Defendant had signed the balance-  sheets, could he have possibly been ignorant of their true meaning? And much more to that effect. Then back to the famous  letter : it existed, so he believed, but he would not produce it, and so saying he sat down at 11.35 a.m and Mo. Carton de Wiart took up the defence.</p>
                <p>Then came the first sensation Counsel for the defence would like to know whether plaintiff’s counsel had seen the original or  the copy of the letter. A brief verbal skirmish  followed, and then Me. Carton de Wiart startled the Court and the audience by the statement that the letter had been stolen "with effraction” from the Sugar Company’s safe, to which Me. Guilhaumon retorted that be was not the Public Prosecutor.</p>
                <p>Then came the defence. M Poutrel was bringing a personal action, but the Hon. A J. Davey had acted as he had done in his official capacity of administrator delegate, acting manager, in fact, of the whole business. On September 2l, he had written officially to the board concerning M. Poutrel, and the board had given him carte blanche to dismiss M. Poutrel or accept his resignation. The letter was there, and what evidence could be clearer? Then came another incident Me. Guilhaumon claimed that the letter had not been communicated to him. “No," replied Me. Carton de Wiart, "it was communicated to you last night,” and added that he had himself written to the papers on the subject stating that the Hon. A. J. Davey's conduct bad been approved by the hoard, and that Me. Guilhaumon bad replied also in the columns of the Press. Counsel for the plaintiff argued that tie Press was not the proper medium for the communication of documents. Counsel for defendant replied briskly and then Me Guilhaumon, on the ground that he had not studied or seen the document, asked for the postponement of the hearing. It was granted, and shortly before midday a most interesting trial was over—for the time.</p>
                <p>We regret that owing to an error in the telephonic transmission of yesterday's account of the proceedings, Me. Guilhaumon's name appeared as Me. Pangalo</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>CAIRO IMPROVEMENTS.</head>
                <p>According to a native contemporary the Finance Ministry has transmitted to the Public Works Ministry the application of a group of European financiers for the lotting of the lands lying to the west of the Pyramids of Ghizeh, with a view to forming a new suburb.</p>
                <p>It is ????  a? that an Anglo-Egyptian company is negotiating for the purchase of the tumble-down dwellings in Boulao, which they would demolish and in their place build houses replete with every modern  comfort.</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>DRAGOMANS AT SUEZ.</head>
                <p>The new tariff for dragomans at Suez is to be as follows :—
                Milliemes 60 per hour for first three hours. Milliemes 30 for every supplemetary hour after the first three hours.
                Milliemes 250 for a whole day in the town and milliemes 300 for a whole day outside the town.</p>
                </div> <div type="item"><head>HASHISH SMOKING.</head>
                <p>The Ministry of the Interior has sent a circular to the governors and moudirs throughout Egypt enjoining them to send every year on the 1st January to the Ministry of the In¬terior, reports on cases of hashish intoxication. Hitherto their reports have been sent on
                18th February of every year.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>RUN TO FARTH.
                SMART CAPTURE OF BRIGAND.</head>
                <p>About eight yean ego a case of highway robbery and murder occurred in the Mariont district, which at that time was in the Kafr Dawar marker. A Bedouin, of the name of
                Abou Shalot, belonging to a family notorious for its lawlessness, was accused of the crime. He could not be found, so he was sentenced in his absence to penal servitude for life.</p>
                <p>The police have been persistently looking for him ever since, and about three years ago a rumour was brought to their ears that this man was lurking in the neighbourhood. The police officer in charge of the district, Abdul Axim Wahbi Effendi, went out into the desert on the criminal’s trail, but Abou Shalot laid an ambush for him and badly wounded the officer and placed a shawish and a naffir hors de combat, while he succeeded in making good his escape.</p>
                <p>For the last two years, since the Alexandria police have taken over the Mariont district, they have never ceased to look out for Shalot and on Monday morning, owing to secret in-formation, the mamour of the district, with an armed patrol of smart Sudanese policemen, went off eastwards from Amrieh and found Shalot in a home, waiting for them with a gun in his hand He was disarmed before he could do any damage, and was brought into Alexandria Yesterday in irons by an armed escort.</p>
                <p>The mamour and police of the Mariont district are to be congratulated on having so successfully run to earth such a dangerous criminal after so many years of search.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS.</head>
                <p>All the stories about the departure or changes of functions on the part of prominent English officials,which have appeared in the columns of our contemporaries, are devoid of foundation in fact.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>HELLENIC NATIONALITY.</head>
                <p>It is reported that some discoveries have been made of a remarkable series of frauds for famishing Greek rayahs. domiciled in Egypt, with papers purporting to prove their Hellenic nationality.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>THE NEW ASYLUM.</head>
                <p>A site covering about 120,000 square metres has been chosen for the new asylum and its grounds in the desert near Khanke. Some 600 patients will bo accomodated in the new building, and the pressure on the Abbassieh , Asylum will he greatly relieved by its erection.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>RUSSIAN CONSULAR CHANGES.</head> 
                <p>Our Constantinople Correspondent informs us that M. Tobirkoff, secretary to the Russian | Consulate at Alexandria, has been appointed to a poet at Mitrovitza, to replace M. Kohmansky, himself transferred to the consulate- general at Salonica in place of M. Basilewaky, who has been appointed Russian Consul at Rio de Janeiro</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>PASTEUR INSTITUTE.</head>
                <p>The selection of the new director of the Pasteur Institute at Cairo has been made by the Public Health Department, and is now awaiting the approval of the Government</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>NEW BRITISH CLUB.</head>
                <p>It is expected there will be a large gathering of members of the British community in Alexandria at the meeting  in the ETC. quarters this evening of those interested in the formation of the proposed British Club. It is unfortunate that this meeting and the meeting of the, A L M & D. S. should have been arranged for the same evening, but members of the latter society will have finished their business in ample time to attend the dub meeting which takes place at 9.15 p.m.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>NEW CAIRO HOTEL</head>
                <p>The Swiss Hotels Company has just registered at the Cairo Mixed Tribunal the deed of purchase of the lands situated on the Kaer-el- Nil esplanade at the price of LE 10 per square metre. The work of building the new hotel to be constructed there will be begun before the new year.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR</head>
                <p>This first-class hotel, which has been thoroughly renovated, will open for the reason on the 20th inst. It is now under the management of Mersre. G. and M Runkewits. proprietors of the Beau-Rivage Hotel at Ramleh. This fact is a guarantee that at the Savoy Hotel. Luxor, visitors will find every comfort conducive to a pleasant stay. The hotel is near to a11 places of interest,  with their many ruins and temples. The situation of the hotel on the river bank, with a view of the Nile traffic and beautiful surroundings, also adds to the charm of the hostelry. Special care has been taken to provide an excellent cuisine and cellar, the services of a well known chef have been secured, and a reliable service throughout has been instituted by the management. A number of applications have already been received from visitors who will pot up at the Savoy for some weeks.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>THE CATTLE PLAGUE.
                NO EXTENSION IN THE SUDAN.</head>
                <p>We are officially informed that the statement as to the increase of cattle plague in the Eastern Sudan is without foundation. Bovine typhus at present is confined to the Ashram district, on the borders of Erythrea, a remote and thinly populated region, and it is hoped that police measures will soon bring t he epidemic under. In any case, so far from there being an increase of cattle plague, the latest returns show a marked diminution in the number of cases.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>THE CATTLE MARKETS.</head>
               <p>On the 22nd inst., the cattle markets in Upper and Lower Egypt will he opened again, and for this purpose the country has been divided into four veterinary divisions,
                as follows :</p> 
                <p>1.	Moudiriehs: Assouan, Keneh, Ghirgah, and Assiont; inspector, Mr. Trydell, at Assiout.</p>
                <p>2.	Moudiriehs: Mirieb, Benj-Souef, Fayoum and Ghizah ; inspector, Mr. Milner, at Cairo.</p>
                <p>3.	Mondiriehs : Galionbieh, Charkieh, Dakahlieh, Talkha marker, Cherbin, Suez Canal and Damietta ; inspector, Mr. Cooper, at Mansourah.</p>
                <p>4.	Moudiriehs : Menoufieb, B hera and the marker of Tanta, Zifta, Mehella, Santa, Kafr e1 Sheikh, Dessouk, Kafr el Zayat and Alexandria ; inspector, Mr. Herbert Mason, at Tantah.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                <p>We understand that the escort of the Holy Carpet will this year be composed of half a battalion of regular Egyptian troops, instead of a provisional force of Reservists, as was the case last year. We need not dilate on the obvious advantages of this arrangement, and hope to be in a position to furnish our readers with details of the composition of the force in  the near future.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>EXCAVATIONS NEAR ABOUKIR</head>
                <p>Professor Fliuders Petrie is shortly expected to arrive at Alexandria, in order to undertake some excavations in the vicinity of Aboukir.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>DELEGATION MUNICIPALE.</head>
                <p>( Communication Officielle)</p>
                <p>Le Délégation Munierinsie s'est réunie le 14 novembre 1905 h 9 h. du soir sous la présidence de Mr. Amb Ralli.</p>
                <p>Présents : MM. P. Fenderl, Mansour Bey Youssef. Soliman Bey Abani, E Stross, G. Zervudachi, membres, W. P. Chataway, administrateur , A. Willner, secrétaire p.i.</p>
                <p>Eu raison de Il'encombrement de la voie publique à  Minet-el-Bassal, et déférant au désir exprimé à ce sujet par 1'Alexandria Produce Association, la Délégation décide d’interdire toute occupation dans ce quartier at de neplus délivrer de roksas à cet égard.</p>
                <p>La Délégation proposera a la Commission l’ouverture d’un crédit supplémentaire de LE 200 pour le service du balayage, en raison des déspenses imprévues nécessites par le nettoyage des maisons infectées par la peste.</p>
                <p>Elle adjuge à Mr.V. di Bari, plus has offrant, au prix de LB. 824,les travaux d’empierrement de la rue de la Promenade, depuis la route de Siouf jusqu'à la rue Scambali, à Ramleh.</p>
                <p>La Délégation examieners, à l'occasion de la discussion du budget de 1906, une demands de la Société Artistique tendant à accorder une allocation au Théâtra Zizinis pour la saison prochaine et à porter cette allocation à LE 1,000.</p>
                <p>La Délégation décide de communiquer au Gouvernorat, sv. re avis favorable, sauf pour la durée demandée, one requéte de M. Santi Boni tendant à l'installation d’un bain à proximité des terrains dits “Bains Cléopatra,” à
                Ramleh.</p>
                <p>La Délégation ajourne, comms prématurés, une demande tends tfa la location do terrain occupé par le Port Kail Bey, à l’effiet d’y errer et exploiter no grand hotel-restaurant, aveu établissements baluéaire, café et concert.</p>
                <p>L’Adminisitrateur déposa sou rapport sur le budget de 1906.</p>
                <p>Ce rapport sera distribué à tout les membres, en vue de sou examan à une prochaine sésnce.</p>
                <p>La séance est levée â 11 h. 1/2 p-m.</p>
                </div><div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                <p>The Grand Cadi is expected to arrive at Alexandria from Constantinople on Saturday.</p>
                <p>The Marquis de Marescot and Mme de Marescot are expected to arrive by the Lloyd boat to day from Syria.</p>
                <p>Baron von Trauttenberg has arrived from
                Europe.</p>
                <p>An "at home" was given by Gallini Pasha at his Ghesirah villa on Monday. Among those present were Princes Agis Pasha Hassan and Djemil Toussohn, Mukhtar, Parhs, Omir Bey Sultan, Mustrapha Pasha Kamel, Messrs. A. Cattaoni, de Vries, Vernon, L. and A. Suares, and many others.</p> 
                <p>The following are among the latest arrivals at the Carlton Hotel: Dr. C. Goodman and Mrs. Goodman, and Mr. B. Pereival.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
