<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Kedric Heyward</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-30">November 30, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-24">June 24, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7223] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JUNE 24, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</head>
                        <head>M. ROUVIER’S NOTE.</head>
                        <head>GERMANY CONSIDERS IT UNSATISFACTORY.</head>
                        <p>Berlin, Jane 23. It is intimated here that M. Rouvier’s note regarding
                            Morocco is not regarded as satisfactory. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>Paris, June 23. M. Rouvier announced to the Council of Ministers that the
                            negotiations with Germany are progressing normally. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RIOTING AT LODZ.</head>
                        <head>FIFTY PEOPLE KILLED.</head>
                        <p>Lodz, June 23. Fifty persons have been killed and 200 wounded in a riot.
                            (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TSAR AND ZEMSTVOS.</head>
                        <head>MISCONSTRUCTION OF SPEECH.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, June 23. The Russian Government has issued a circular
                            rebuking the newspapers for construing the Tsar’s speech to the
                            delegates of the Congress of Zemstvos as promising the establishment of
                            a National Assembly on a constitutional basis. The Tsar simply meant a
                            convocation strictly in accordance with the fundamental laws of the
                            Empire.</p>
                        <p>The journal “Russ” has been suspended for publishing the Zemstvosist's
                            petition mentioned oh the 9th inst. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW SPANISH CABINET.</head>
                        <p>Madrid, June 23. A Liberal Cabinet has been formed under the presidency
                            of Senor Mantero Rios. (H.)</p>
                        <p>HOME CRICKET:</p>
                        <p>London, June 23. Middlesex beat Kent by 4 wickets. York-hire beat
                            Warwickshire by 66 runs. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" element="comingEvents">
                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>
                    <table cols="2" xml:id="deg-ta-coce01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="2">ALEXANDRIA.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>June.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fri. 22</cell>
                            <cell>Windsor Hotel Orchestra 6 to 11 pm.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Mex Prinea's Restaraunt des Bains. Roumattian orchesta, every
                                afternoon. Sundays morning.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Alhambra. Italian operetta company in <hi rend="italic">La
                                    Principessa di Trebisonda</hi>. 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Pyramids Theatre. Gatti's Circus Troupe. 9.15 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sat. 24</cell>
                            <cell>A.C.C. Grounds. Cricket "Alexandria" "Cairo" 1.30 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Mustafa Rifle Range. Practice by B.R.C. 3p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>A.S.C Gymkhana 3.30 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Marina Alexandria Swimming Club members meet 4 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>San Stefano Venetian fete 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sun. 25</cell>
                            <cell>San Stefano Cassino Concert at 10 a.m. and 5 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Eden Theatre Prof de Lafountaine Hypnotist 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wed. 28</cell>
                            <cell>Khedieval Yatch Club Regatta</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>July Sat. 15</cell>
                            <cell>A.S.C Skye Meeting</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="2">CAIRO</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>June.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sat. 24</cell>
                            <cell>Theatre des Ambassadeurs. 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Theatre des Nouveautés. 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Esbekieh Theatre. Italian Comedy Company. 9 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tues. 27</cell>
                            <cell>Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                                p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fri. 30</cell>
                            <cell>Zoological Gardens. Performance by Ghizeh Boys’ Band in
                                afternoon.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                                p.m</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>July.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sat. 8</cell>
                            <cell>Credit Foncier Eygiptian Extroidinary meeting 4 p.m.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a.m. on
                            Monday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Police Station.</head>
                        <p>The Ministry of Finance has opened a credit of L.E. 1,110 for the
                            construction of a police station at El Sarabi, Abou Tig Markaz.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hashish Seizure</head>
                        <p>A native named Oth-man Ahmed Othman was arrested yesterday with 9 torbas
                            of hashish while trying to pass though the railway stores at
                            Gabbari.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Camilleri Case.</head>
                        <p>The preliminary examination of witnesses in this case was concluded at
                            H.B.M.’s Consulate, Alexandria, this morning, accused being committed
                            for trial.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Ghirgeh Scandal</head>
                        <p>We hear that Mr. Corbett, the Procureur General, has submitted his report
                            on the Rifaa affair to H.E. Musta-pha Pasha Fehmy and to the Judicial
                            Adviser.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Union Artistique Francaise</head>
                        <p>A general meeting of the members is to be held this evening for the
                            election of a president in place of M. A. Nicolas, who has resigned.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hypnotism</head>
                        <p>In response to a general request Prof. de Lafontaine has agreed to give
                            another seance of hypnotism and thoughtreading at the Eden Theatre to
                            morrow, commencing at 9 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Abdeen district of Cairo to-morrow
                            night and at daylight on Monday, and in Zeitoun during Monday night and
                            at daylight on Tuesday, will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>La Principessa di Trebizonda is a delightful 3-act operetta by Offembach,
                            which was produced at the Alhambra last night with great success. It
                            will be repeated this evening, and at a matinee tomorrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 21st inst., 4 of which were
                            British, 1 German, 2 French, 2 Turkish, 1 Danish. The receipts for the
                            day were frs. 278,969.60, making the total from the 1st inst. frs.
                            5,685,665.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records two fatal cases at Alexandria, the victims
                            being a native girl at Haggari and a native boy at Bab Sidra, who were
                            both found dead at their homes. A fatal case is reported from Zifta and
                            a death in hospital from Damanhour.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casino.</head>
                        <p>We remind our readers of the night fete to be given at the Casino this
                            evening. To-morrow (Sunday) besides the popular concert which commences
                            at 5 p.m., Professor and Mme. Fedik will give a conjuring entertainment
                            in the club’s big saloon, at 6.30 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports</head>
                        <p>From the 1st January to the 22nd June, 434,077 tons of coal were imported
                            into Egypt. Wales sent 246,835 tons, Newcastle 82,473, Scotland 64,134,
                            Yorkshire 23,723, and other districts 16,932 tons. The quantity received
                            during the corresponding period of 1904 was 467,579 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Opening Ceremony</head>
                        <p>We may remind our readers that the formal opening of Messrs. Walker and
                            Meimarachi’s stores in Old Bourse-street will take place this afternoon
                            at 6 o'clock, when customers and friends are cordially invited. A
                            well-stocked buffet will be placed at the disposal of visitors.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A New Theatre</head>
                        <p>has been built in what is known as the Ciccolani Gardens, now the
                            property of Mr. G.B. Alderson, adjacent to the Blind School. The
                            establishment will be opened to-night by an Italian operetta company,
                            cinder the management of Sig. G. Castagnetta, the piece selected for the
                            inauguration being Varney’s popular Fanfan la Tulipe. The curtain will
                            rise at 9 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mnemonics</head>
                        <p>Mnemonics certainly help one greatly, but this is only an artificial art.
                            The Berlitz method, on the contrary, employs natural means ; it strikes
                            the imagination. Its results are always magnificent, be the pupil old or
                            young, or even a child. For the latter there is a special method which
                            develops their intellectual powers by accustoming them to arrange their
                            ideas. But its greatest recommendation in that they learn a foreign
                            language unconsciously ; instead of their lesson being wearisome they
                            look forward to it as a distraction. [Advt.]</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Bandman Opera Company have been playing successfully at Colombo,
                            whence they proceed to India. Says the “Indian Planters’ Gazette”</head>
                        <p>An advertisement in the daily press announces the proposed visit to
                            Calcut ta of Mr. Maurice Bandmann and his company.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>By the way the split between Messrs. Bandmann and Dallas is now complete,
                            and the festive Henry is cavorting in America, whither he proceeded from
                            Shanghai via Honolulu. Mr. Dallas is clever behind the footlights, but
                            like many other geniuses he has no head for accounts. He can play the
                            man about town to perfection, even to the extent of outrunning the
                            constable. He found congenial company off the stage in Calcutta last
                            cold season ; but, though the Press patted him on the back as a rare
                            good sort, his festiveness did not conduce to the profits of the
                            partnership which is off, just as he is.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CREDIT FONCIER EGYPTIAN. INTERESTING DETAILS.</head>
                    <p>In view of the recent suppression of public lotteries we have gathered
                        together some particulars regarding the obligations a lots, or lottery
                        bonds, of the above institution which should prove of interest to our
                        readers. These lottery bonds differ from other lotteries inasmuch as whereas
                        the money paid for the former remains invested at an annual interest of
                        three per cent until the bond is drawn for redemption, that paid for the
                        latter class of paper is lost if the number does not gain a prize at the
                        drawing.</p>
                    <p>Several of the principal towns of France and other parts of Europe have
                        raised money on this description of securities, and they are a very favorite
                        form of investment with the class of email capitalists. The cessation of the
                        sale publicly of lottery tickets has naturally, greatly enhanced the price
                        of the obligations a lots of the local Credit Foncier, which are nominally
                        for 250 francs, but have been quoted at as high as 350 francs and are now
                        worth about 314. These prices are for the first emission. Those of the
                        second emission are now worth 272 francs, whereas they have been sold at 280
                        francs. Although there are monthly drawings with similar amounts of prizes
                        for both series the difference in price is accounted for by the fact that
                        there are far less of the first category of bonds than of those of the
                        second. The first series of 400,000 obligations of 250 francs each nominal
                        were issued in 1886 and the second for the same Dumber of bonds, and at 250
                        franca also, were issued in 1903.</p>
                    <p>There is a drawing for each series on the 15th of every month, i.e., 24
                        drawings per annum in all. The “gros lot,’’ or first prize, amounts to
                        100,000 francs and 50,000 francs on alternative months so that for the two
                        series there are 12 drawings for the larger sum and 12 others for the
                        smaller. At each drawing there are, besides, 25 prizes of 1,000 francs each.
                        When bonds gain any of these prizes they are considered as drawn for
                        redemption and have to be surrendered on the amount of the prizes being
                        paid. There is besides an annual amortisation at par of several hundreds of
                        bonds on the 1st March. To guard against loss between the price of purchase
                        and that of redemption many investors insure their bonds before this latter
                        date. Of the former series of obligations there are 355,000 bonds still
                        remaining unredeemed out of the original total of 400,000 whilst of the
                        latter category here are 395,000 out of the same total issued.</p>
                    <p>The former series were issued at 230 francs in 1886 and fell in the same year
                        to 210 francs, which was the lowest figure they ever touched.</p>
                    <p>Although some few thousands are held abroad, he bulk of the bonds of both
                        series are in he possession of persons in this country, and many well known
                        residents of Cairo and Alex-andria have been fortunate enough to draw the
                        "gros lot.”</p>
                    <p>The Credit Foncier, the oldest and one of the most prosperous land banks in
                        Egypt, was constituted about 25 years ago with a capital of 40 million
                        francs, and at the general meeting held on the 30th November, 1881, this was
                        augmented to 80 millions of francs, divided into 160,000 shares of 500
                        francs each. This capital was again raised in January of last year to 100
                        nillions and it is intended to still further ncrease it next month.</p>
                    <p>The interest charged on loans, always made at half the estimated cost of the
                        land mortgaged, was formerly from 7 % to 9 % per annum, but this rate is now
                        reduced to 6 % for large sums and between 6% and 7% for smaller. The loans
                        made last year were 729 in number for a total sum of L.E. 2,679,883, or
                        nearly 69 1/2 million francs, and the profits for the same period enabled
                        the directors to pay a dividend to the shareholders of 12 1/2 francs on each
                        share of 500 francs or 10 per cent per annnm on the total capital of 100
                        million francs.</p>
                    <p>The splendid new buildings of the Credit Foncier, one of the finest of the
                        Metropolis, which were completed in December last, cost £40,000, besides the
                        value of the 2,000 square metres of land they occupy, and which is valued at
                        the minimum of £20 per square metre. The total area of buildings and ground
                        around is 2,700 square metres. For the whole plot the Bank was offered £15 a
                        square metre a few years ago, since which time sites in this part of the
                        Capital have enormously increased in price.</p>
                    <p>In consequence of the enormous increase of late in the business the staff of
                        the Credit Foncier now numbers in Cairo about 125 persons.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Tabor” sailed from Malta yesterday evening and is due here on
                        Tuesday morning with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Menes” arrived in England yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Britannia” sailed on Friday from Liverpool for Gibraltar,
                        Malta, and Alexandria with general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The SS. “Kaffir Prince” left London on Thursday with passengers and general
                        cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. “Tuscan Prinoe” left Manchester on Friday, with passengers and
                        general cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. “Avon” sails hence today for Liverpool direct with a
                        general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail S.S. “Ismailia” will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for
                        Piraes, Smyrna, Mitylene and Constantinople.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>REFLOATING OF S.S. “CONGAL.”</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline><dateline>Port Said, Friday.</dateline><p> The S.S. “Congal,” which was
                            refloated on Monday, was to have at once gone into the floating dock,
                            but her draught of water necessitated the discharge of 700 tons of coal.
                            This was completed to-day and the vessel is now dry. The appearance of
                            her side is most extraordinary : she is apparently much less damaged
                            than was expected ; masses of seaweed and barnacles are to be seen
                            everywhere, and her engines and cabins are naturally completely rained.
                            It is anticipated that she will be sold, and probably towed to an
                            Austrian port for breaking up, as the expense of putting her in working
                            order will be too heavy.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>VISIT OF BRITISH CRUISERS.</head>
                        <p>The two first-class cruisers which I noted yesterday as coming into the
                            harbour from sea, are to stay here for an indefinite period. It is said
                            they will remain until the battleship squadron, due here from China in
                            the middle of July, has arrived. I learn that the “Lancas-ter,” while in
                            Malta, was in practically constant wireless telegraphic communication
                            with Poldhu, the Marconi Company’s largest station in England ; she is
                            fitted with an especially powerful set of instruments.</p>
                        <p>Tonight, H.B.M's Consul is giving a dinner party in honor of the captains
                            and officers of the “Lancaster” and “Suffolk” at the Eastern Exchange. A
                            large number of residents have been invited, I believe.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HAMADA BEY’S ARREST.</head>
                    <p>Sheikh Mohi el Din Bey Hamada, father-in-law of the Grand Mufti of Egypt, who
                        was arrested on returning to Beyrout from Cairo some three weeks ago, has
                        been released.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that the venerable sheikh was believed to be in possession of
                        compromising documents. Certain papers were seized and examined by the
                        police, who were obliged to admit that they referred only to the
                        organisation of aid for destitute Hadjis returning from the Holy Places. On
                        this being reported to Constantinople H.I.M. the Sultan gave orders for the
                        immediate release of the sheikh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHEPHEARD’S HOTEL IMPROVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The management of Shepheard’s Hotel intend to pull down the row of ten
                        offices and shops that face Kamel-street, and in which are included the
                        Cairo offices of the Messageries Maritimes Company and Caffari’s forwarding
                        branch, and to erect in their place better and large premises. The work will
                        be begun on the 1st proximo and completed in about two months from that
                        date. In all probability the number of the buildings will be reduced by one
                        or two, and likewise the facade of the premises will be advanced 3 metres
                        forward in the present broad pavement and made to run parallel to about the
                        middle of the street verandah. The roofs of the new row will serve as
                        balconies or promenade to the occupants of the rooms above them.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGINEERING UNDER THE PHARAOHS.</head>
                    <p>Among the great engineering problems before the world at the present time,
                        there is none, perhaps, that arouses greater interest than the control of
                        the waters of the Nile for the use of Egypt The ancient Egyptians attacked
                        the problem with such success that 4,000 years ago the valley of the Nile
                        supported a dense population, whose monuments stand to the present day among
                        the wonders of the world. A civilisation capable of erecting the Pyramids
                        would be equally able to conceive and carry out the more important works for
                        controlling the irrigation of the country, though it is only during the last
                        two decades that the magnitude and character of these works have been
                        realised by the modern world. Diodorus, Strabo, and Herodotus have
                        independently borne witness to a vast artificial lake or reservoir, which
                        was constructed to receive the superfluous water from the Nile at flood
                        time, and to distribute it when and where required by means of canals. This
                        lake— Moeris—was dug by the orders of King Amen-emhat III., who lived about
                        2000 b.c. It had a superficial area of 950 square miles, about the size of
                        an average English county, with a depth in places of 300 ft, and its contour
                        measured 450 miles. It was connected with the Nile by a canal 10 miles long
                        and 300 ft. wide, controlled by means of sluices, which served to draw off
                        the surplus water from the river, and return it at periods of low water. In
                        spite of the claims of Herodotus, Diodorus, and others to have actually seen
                        this magnificent engineering work, until comparatively recent years its
                        existence was either denied, or its dimensions were reduced to those of a
                        shallow pool or broad canal. The exact description of the early travellers
                        was discredited, and their accounts classed with the famous discoveries of
                        Sir John Mandeville. As all who have followed the recent history of Egypt
                        will know, the site of the ancient lake has been identified beyond doubt
                        with the present province known as the Fayoum, by Mr. Cope Whitehouse, whose
                        researches have not only abundantly justified the classical historians, but
                        have had a most direct bearing upon the problem of the irrigation of Egypt
                        at the present day. The canal to the Nile had become silted up during
                        centuries of neglect, and the lake had vanished, but the depression
                        remained, as a fertile valley in the desert. ("Engineering.")</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HINTS FOR A. S. C. GYMKHANA</head>
                        <p>Now that the Alexandria gymkhana season is on it may be well to review
                            the new features to be introduced this summer in gymkhanas at home.</p>
                        <p>One of the contests which will be most popular this summer is the animal
                            race. Any four-footed beast or feathered fowl is eligible for
                            competition, the only rule to be observed in making the selection is
                            that combatants should not be wholly antagonistic to each other.</p>
                        <p>No limit is placed on the mode of progression ; the animals may fly, hop,
                            skip, or run in their efforts to advance towards the winning post, and
                            walking backwards is not considered a disqualification. Judicious
                            goading is allowable ; in fact, the fair owners are granted a free hand
                            in this respect, and no limit is placed on the extent to which the art
                            of gentle coaxing may be employed. A lady whispering counsel into the
                            receptive ear of her tame goose, is well within the strictest rules.</p>
                        <p>Before the tournament the days are taken up with much serious training.
                            The capabilities of each animal are put to severe tests, and by lavish
                            bribing the ethics of the game are instilled into the various
                            contestants. A dame in charge of a prize porker has hit on a novel
                            substitute for the barbarities of the whip in the shape of a soda-water
                            syphon, the gaseous drink being presumably not destined for piggy’s
                            delectation. Usually the competitors show natural unwillingness to start
                            when the signal is given, but once under way excitement waxes fast and
                            furious, and all the skill of the drivers is brought into requisition to
                            keep the combatants in the direction in which they should go.</p>
                        <p>The motor race is a new development of the gymkhana, and is a severe test
                            of the steering capabilities of the driver. The competitor has to cover
                            a certain course, the lady beside him clasping a glass of water filled
                            to the brim. A steady hand and a smooth course, rather than a high
                            speed, are required in order to achieve success, one overflowing drop
                            disqualifying the competing car.</p>
                        <p>The doll perambulator race competition is not so easy a one as at first
                            sight it might appear to be. To those who have tried to wheel a toy
                            vehicle of this description in a straight line the difficulties of
                            arriving at the goal will be at once apparent, the diminutive wheels in
                            a distracting manner preferring to adopt the most circuitous route.</p>
                        <p>As the dolls are not fastened into their carriages, the least jolt
                            suffices to land them on the course. If the perambulator is overturned
                            or its occupant tipped out, the amateur nursemaid returns vanquished
                            from the field, the winner, of course, being the competitor who first
                            reaches the winning post All the competitors in the race are attired as
                            modem nursemaids.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good
                        -----</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very ---- Brand of
                        Beer</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-xx-x xx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                        English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern
                        sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-whr01">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>
                    <p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                    <p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M</p>
                    <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
