<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-11-26">November 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-12">12 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="r">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JULY 12, 1905.</head>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>EGYPT EXPLORATION FUND.</head>
                    <p>Few things are more remarkable in the intellectual development of the last
                        quarter of a century than the growth of archæology as a serious study, no
                        longer to be regarded, like Latin verses, as an elegance or added charm to
                        scholarship. It has altered the whole attitude of men’s minds towards
                        antiquity, and, to seek an analogy in a widely different quarter, may be
                        compared to the substitution of oral evidence for affidavits in the Court of
                        Chancery. The ancient tomb or inscription, statue or remains of a temple,
                        like the living word of the witness, are more likely to tell the truth than
                        any writing. In no department has the progress been more striking than in
                        Egyptology. A few years ago there was at most one exhibition in the year for
                        showing the work done ; now there are always two or three, and the progress
                        has been so great as to make necessary a division of labour. Thus there is
                        now open, for a month, in the library of the Society of Biblical Arcbæology,
                        37, Great Russell street, London, a most interesting display of antiquities,
                        mainly from the eleventh dynasty temple at Deire, Bahari, found daring last
                        season’s work by Dr. Edouard Naville and Mr. Hall. This funerary temple of
                        King Neb-hapet-Ra Meutuhetep (ILL) was discovered in the preceding season,
                        1903 4, and lies to the south of the great temple built by Queen Hatshepsu.
                        Two thirds of it have now been cleared away, and it is hoped that further
                        search may disclose the pyramid tomb of the King himself, which was called
                        Akh-asset, “Glorious are its seats.” From the site the explorers have been
                        allowed to bring home— for distribution among various museums — many
                        valuable, though fragmentary, remains. Had they been more perfect they would
                        perforce have been retained m Egypt. They are of exceptional interest as
                        including specimens of high relief work of which no other examples appear to
                        be extant, and they belong to tho eleventh dynasty, of which we had very
                        little knowledge. These remains have, in fact, opened a new chapter of
                        Egyptian art. The craftsmen of Egypt, like the architects of medieval
                        Cathedrals, are usually unknown by name ; but in this instance the name of
                        the chief artist has come down to us. He was Mertisen, who describes himself
                        on his tombstone as a master of artistic skill which he handed down to his
                        son. It is thought that he was the inaugurator of a new birth of Egyptian
                        art, just as his master, Neb-hap8t-Ra Mentuhetep, was the refounder of the
                        Egyptian kingdom under the headship of the Thebans. Of another King,
                        Usertsen III., three massive statues of black granite—mutilated, it is true,
                        but not to such an extent as to conceal the character of the face—are shown.
                        They represent him at different periods of his life, with a face rather of a
                        European than of an Egyptian or Semitic type. 'The mouth is large, but the
                        lips are thin and firm, and the nose would appear to have been somewhat
                        aquiline. The ears are of enormous size. What appears to be the earliest
                        instance of the newly-discovered eleventh dynasty style of high coloured
                        relief is the seated portrait figure of a Queen or priestess named Nefer
                        shushusa. There are also other similar figures—one with a flower in the left
                        hand, and another smelling a flower. A relief of a King holding the hand of
                        a Queen seems to commemorate a chief of the hunters of the desert by its
                        peculiarly cut inscription. From the shrine of the priestesses comes another
                        high relief sculpture of a man who is represented with the person below him
                        as walking in the temple. The remarkable feature of this fragment is a
                        “proto-Doric” octagonal column, and the whole affords interesting evidence
                        of the actual appearance of the columns of the ambulatory surrounding the
                        pyramid» To the left are two fragments showing the hinder parts of a dog and
                        of a man binding a bull for sacrifice, and above is one of the sacred cows
                        of Hathor licking her calf. Pieces of purely Theban work are two fragments
                        from scenes representing King Mentuhetep and his wife. On the right-hand one
                        is seen the upper part of tho Royal crown, and the beautifully carved
                        hieroglyphs and the wonderful prdservation of colour give singular interest
                        and charm to these remains. The inscriptions refer to the Qneen (Aashait). A
                        complete slab of this type is kept back in the Cairo Museum. A variety of
                        other objects assignable to this period are also shown—the King overthrowing
                        an Aamn, warriors armed with axes, boatmen, and reliefs of animals. The
                        drawing of the latter, notably a flamingo, is marvellously free and
                        accurate. </p>
                    <p>The specimens of later dynasties are of no inferior value and interest. The
                        most beautiful, perhaps, of the objects displayed is an alabaster head of a
                        cow, ascribed to the eighteenth dynasty. The sculpture is wonderfully true
                        to life. The eyes were inlaid with lapis, of which traces remain, and the
                        ears and horns were probably of silver. The cow was probably from a figure
                        of the goddess Hathor, dedicated in the Hathor shrine of the Great Temple. A
                        portion of a large funerary stela commemorates Userhat, priest of the
                        deceased Kings Amen-hotep III. and Tut-ankh-amen, and his wife, the singer
                        of Amen, Nefretari. These are ascribed to the early nineteenth dynasty.There
                        is also a great number of smaller objects— beads,blue-glazed faience, vases,
                        hieratic ostraka containing lists of names, accounts, letters, a literary
                        text, and a list of hieroglyphs which may have been school exercises. It
                        remains to b3 said that Dr. Borchardt contributes a series of very beautiful
                        photographs of the temple, and that Mme. Naville has made some admirable
                        coloured drawings of cows from the eleventh dynasty sarcophagi. It is
                        somewhat curious that the draghtsmanship displayed in work presumably of the
                        same age is very unequal. Some of the cows are freely and nataralistically
                        drawn, whilst others are conventional to the degree of being almost wooden.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>MATTERS OF MOMENT.</head>
                    <head type="sub">THE PITH OF THE HOME PRESS COMMENTS.</head>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>TO EXCLUDE UNDESIRABLES.</head>
                        <byline>“Times.”</byline>
                        <p>The House of Commons was again occupied yesterday with the debate upon
                            the Aliens Bill. That is the third full Parliamentary day devoted to the
                            Committee on this measure, and the House has not reached the middle of
                            the first clause. The amendments have been uniformly directed to making
                            the Bill unworkable, or intolerably cumbrous. It is merely a measure of
                            police for the protection of ratepayers from burdens which ought not to
                            be placed upon them, of English workmen from being crowded out of home
                            and employment by some of the lowest populations of Europe, and of
                            society at large from persons incapable of making good citizens. It is
                            constantly treated by the Opposition as if it were an invasion of the
                            rights of man and an attack upon the privileges of persons more worthy
                            of our care than the subjects of the King. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>ELECTORAL REDISTRIBUTION.</head>
                        <byline>“Telegraph.”</byline>
                        <p>The Radicals find themselves in a dilemma, which, as usual, they have
                            made for them selves ; as a witty lady said at the beginning of the last
                            century, “I’ve often heard of people running their heads against stone
                            walls, but I never knew of any but the Whigs who built stone walls to
                            run their heads against” No Radical supports. in ' theory the strange
                            anomaly by which one Member of Parliament represents what may be called
                            a, one-vote power, while another, with only the same privileges in the
                            House of Commons, stands for a ten-vote power. Radicals are mostly
                            ideologues, and equal electoral districts would best coincide with their
                            absurd theories about the literal equality of men, and for that matter
                            of women and men. Why not of men, women, and children Î Therefore, they
                            cannot conscientiously oppose the principle of redistribution. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>TOO MANY OFFICERS.</head>
                        <byline>“Morning Post.”</byline>
                        <p>If Parliament took a real interest in economy and efficiency for the Army
                            some member would ask for a return showing the number of officers
                            attached to the headquarters of a command and the number of regular
                            troops in the command, on the one hand, in each British command, and, on
                            the other hand, in a normal French or German division and Army Corps.
                            That return, we suspect, would astonish the House of Commons even more
                            than the report of Sir William Butler’s committee. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>WAR STORES SCANDAL.</head>
                        <byline>“Evening Standard.”</byline>
                        <p> The suggestion which has been made—it may almost be called a threat—that
                            certain highly placed officials should be impeached, under certain
                            circumstances, in connection with the War Stores scandal, at once takes
                            us back to the days of an earlier generation. One had imagined that
                            Warren Hastings was the last great example of a great impeachment. To
                            day he affair would be less picturesque and dramatic, if not essentially
                            less tragic. Tho galaxy of oratorical talent that made that protracted
                            trial so astounding has passed with the classics from the House of
                            Commons, and oratory as an art is on the down grade. There is, of
                            course, the possibility that an impeachment might serve to revive this
                            lost art, though the possibility lends no sufficient attracting* to the
                            prospect. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>THE VICEROY AND LORD KITCHENER</head>
                        <byline>“Standard.”</byline>
                        <p> A practical and satisfactory solution of the difficulty arising out of
                            the original difference of opinion between Lord Curzon and Lord
                            Kitchener is not likely to be facilitated by endeavouring to make it a
                            purely personal question. Far greater issues are at stake than the
                            prestige and reputation of any of the exalted persons who are involved
                            in the controversy. It is one that most be settled on its merits ; and,
                            however interesting it may be to hear that the Viceroy will resign or
                            that the civilian members of his Council would rather perish than
                            survive a military dictatorship, such contingencies, not obscurely
                            hinted at by the Anglo-Indian journals, do not touoh the main point.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>REVOLT IN RUSSIA</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <byline>“Standard.”</byline>
                            <p> What Marseilles has been to France, Odessa is to Russia, and there
                                is hardly a centre at which the contagion of military revolt would
                                not have been at work. We must remember not merely that the more
                                lawful forms of propagandist Liberalism have leavened ordinary
                                society, but that, in the army not less than in the workshops,
                                subterranean conspiracy has prepared the labouring population of the
                                towns for desperate courses. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <byline>“Daily News.”</byline>
                            <p> Meanwhile no action has followed the fair words of the Tsar. The
                                promise of a Constitution was hardly made before it was explained
                                away, and it would seem now that the report which the Minister of
                                the Interior was commissioned to draw up with a view to creating a
                                way oat of the impasse has been postponed. This means that the
                                bureaucrats have checked the reformers at every point.......... </p>
                            <p> They overthrew Prince Mirsky, whom history may come to regard as the
                                last hope of the Royalists, much as it regards Necker as the last
                                hope of the Bourbons. And it would seem that Yermaloff, the Minister
                                of Agriculture, who dared to tell the Tsar that he was faced I with
                                a revolution, has disappeared also from effective service. The Tsar,
                                in fact, is clearly in the hands of the Grand Dukes, who seems
                                destined to furnish one more example to the <cb n="3"/> Royal Houses
                                which have, fallen because they “learn nothing, and forget nothing.”
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <byline>“Manchester Guardian.”</byline>
                            <p>The mob which went looting in Odessa under the shelter of the
                                Potemkin’s guns was doubtless yielding to the imperious temptation
                                of hunger. In such conditions there seems every reason to fear that
                                the struggle for liberty must come to wear more and more the aspect
                                of a class war and a battle for bread, unless the Liberals can find
                                the courage and the means to impose both peace and a Constitution
                                upon the Tsar. </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>THE MOROCCAN CRISIS.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <byline>“Echo de Paris.” </byline>
                            <p>Another important article by M. Jules Delafosse, which has made a
                                deep impression in Paris, has appeared in the “Echo de Paris.” He
                                says that France is willing to conclude an understanding with
                                Germany, because that implies a régime of peace, but she will not
                                conclude an alliance with her, because that involves chances of war
                                contrary to the interests of France. M. Delafosse then inquires what
                                the German Emperor had to reproach France with as regards Morocco.
                                His answer is, absolutely nothing. The German Emperor demanded in
                                haughty terms the territorial integrity of Morocco, the independence
                                of the Sultan, and the open door. But those three points were
                                distinctly accepted in the text of the Franco English Agreement.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <byline>“Cologne Gazette.”</byline>
                            <p>The “Cologne Gazette” declares that in view of the reservations with
                                which M. Ronvier has doubtless accompanied his consent, in this
                                question it is impossible to speak of victor or vanquished. The
                                lesson of the “Franco-German incident” is described as being that
                                “reforms in Morocco can only be achieved by means of an
                                international understanding aid not by the initiative of a single
                                Power.” </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>BEAUTIFUL ENGLISH PEERESS PRAISES DR. WILLIAMS’ PINK PILLS FOR PALE
                        PEOPLE.</head>
                    <p>Though sharing the traditional reluctance of our old nobility to emerge from
                        aristocratic privacy and come before the public-as the subject of a
                        newspaper article, the Right Hon. Lady Haldon has expressly permitted the
                        publication of a statement recently made to a representative of the Press
                        regarding her wonderful cure by Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills. </p>
                    <p>Recognising that the words of a titled lady in her position must necessarily
                        bear great' weight with the public, and earnestly <figure>
                            <head>The Lady Haldon.</head>
                            <p>From photograph by Johnston and Hoffmann.</p>
                        </figure> desiring that the benefits she had derived from Dr. Williams’ Pink
                        Pills should be publicly acknowledged. Lady Haldon waived all personal
                        reluctance and told a story which cannot but impress every reader.</p>
                    <p>‘For the sake of all sufferers,” said her ladyship, “I want to tell you what
                        Dr. Williams* Pink "Pills for Pale People did for me when I had given up all
                        hope, after tho best professional treatment. </p>
                    <p>‘I have been a great traveller. Five years ago, when residing Tn Australia,
                        my heart became seriously affected. Symptoms of advanced Anaemia showed
                        themselves. One of the results was most acute Indigestion. I suffered
                        severely in the back and under the shoulder blades, including an especially
                        severe oppression of the chest. The most careful diet brought no relief.
                        Even after a glass of water my discomfort was almost unbearable. Food of any
                        kind caused me snob misery that I ate less and less, till I was practically
                        starving myself. In walking the shortest distance palpitations of the heart
                        would make me feel as though I were suffocating. </p>
                    <p>“As anæmia developed I grew alarmingly ill ; I could not sleep at night ; my
                        whole system was deranged. My nerves broke down, my bead ached constantly,
                        until my eyesight became affected. </p>
                    <p> “My illness seemed so deeply rooted that I determined to go to the Clinique
                        de la Caroline, in Switzerland, where I was attended by eminent physicians. </p>
                    <p>“But about August, 1903, while I was travelling by train and nearly prostrate
                        with one <cb n="4"/> of my attacks, I casually picked up a small pamphlet
                        referring to Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills for Pale People. I became so
                        interested in some cures mentioned therein that I determined to give a trial
                        to this medicine.</p>
                    <p>“Within three days I was astonished at the marvelous improvement. I procured
                        further boxes of the pills, and very soon I was delighted to find that all
                        traces of my complaint had practically vanished. </p>
                    <p> “I could now walk long distances with an entire freedom from pain. My
                        appetite had returned with a heartiness that surprised me, and my general
                        health was suoh as I had not enjoyed for many years.” </p>
                    <p>In every class of society the curative powers of Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills
                        have been proved repeatedly in diseases arising from too little or
                        impoverished blood. For men as well as women they are invaluable in Anæmia,
                        Indigestion, excessive weakness, Decline, Consumption, Rheumatism, Sciatica,
                        Paralysis, Locomotor Ataxy, Nervous Disorders. Dr. Williams’ Medicine Co.,
                        Holborn-viaduct, London, send a box post free for 2s. 9d., six boxes for
                        13s. 9d. ; uat they can be had at all medicine shops. </p>
                    <p>Sold in Egypt by all chemists at P.T. 13 per box or P.T. 70 per 6 boxes. Can
                        be bought at the general depôt : Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel du Nil St. (1st
                        floor), and Alexandria, Rue Stamboul, No. 8. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>AGRICULTURAL BANK OF EGYPT</head>
                    <head type="sub"> New Issue of Shares for Increase of Capital.</head>
                    <p>IN PURSUANCE of an Extraordinary General Meeting held on the 18th May 1905.
                        the Board of Directors of the Agricultural Bank of Egypt offer 243,000 new
                        shares of the said Bank of Five pounds sterling each. These shares will
                        constitute an increase of the Capital of the Bank, and are issued in
                        conformity with the Statutes at the price of Five Pounds sterling per share,
                        payable on application. </p>
                    <p>Application should be made </p>
                    <p>in EGYPT to the Head Office of the National Bank of Egypt at Cairo and to the
                        Branch at Alexandria, </p>
                    <p>in LONDON to the London Agency of the National Bank of Egypt, 4 &amp; 5, King
                        William Street, E.C. </p>
                    <p>The new shares will rank for dividend from the 1st January 1906, that is to
                        say from the beginning of next year. Every shareholder has the right on
                        application to an allotment of one new share in respect of every old share
                        held. </p>
                    <p>All shareholders who wish to exercise their rights must, under pain of
                        forfeiture of those rights, lodge their applications at one of the places
                        named above on or before the 2nd October 1905 depositing their Share
                        Warrants together with the total amount payable, viz : £5 per share. </p>
                    <p>The President of the Board of Directors, (signed) Elwin Palmer. </p>
                    <p>Cairo, the 8th July 1905.</p>
                    <p>26218-4</p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>NOTICE</head>
                    <p>Is hereby given to all persons having claims against the estate of the late
                        Miralai Boulnois Bey, Officer Commanding the Bahr el Ghazal district (Major,
                        Royal Artillery) that such claims must be forwarded endorsed such to the
                        Assistant Adjutant General, War Office, Cairo, to arrive on or before the
                        7th August, 1905, after which date they will not be taken into
                        consideration. </p>
                    <p>26212-A-5 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>NOTICE. </head>
                    <p>NOTICE is hereby given to all persons having claims against the estate of the
                        late Kaimakam Fell Bey, Inspector, Bahr-el Ghazal Province (Royal NaVy) that
                        such claims must be forwarded endorsed as such to the Assistant Adjutant
                        General, War Office, Cairo, to arrive on or before the 7th August, 1905,
                        after which date they will not be taken into consideration. </p>
                    <p> 26221*63 </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>Municipalité d’Alexandrie</head>
                    <head type="sub">AVIS.</head>
                    <p>Il est porté à la connaissance des propriétaires de chiens qu’il pourront
                        retirer ou faire retirer au bureau Sanitaire de la Municipalité, à partir da
                        12 Juillet courant de 8 h. 1/2 a.m. à midi, le dimanche et jours fériés
                        exceptés, la médaille que doit porter tout chien circulant sur la voie
                        publique. </p>
                    <p>Les propriétaires seront tenue d’indiquer très exactement leurs nom, prénoms,
                        nationalité, adresse (rue, propriété, cheikh el Hara, Kism, etc.) ainsi que
                        la race et la couleur du chien si celui-ci n’est pas présenté à la
                        Municipalité. </p>
                    <p>La médaille est délivrée gratuitement. </p>
                    <p>Passé le 10 Août tout chien qui n’en sera pas porteur et qui sera trouvé
                        errant sera saisi et conduit à la fourrière du Mex. </p>
                    <p>Alexandrie le 8 Juillet 1905. </p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur (signé) W. P. Chataway.</p>
                    <p>26225 3 2</p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>Administration des Chemins de Fer et des Télégraphes </head>
                    <head type="sub">AVIS</head>
                    <p>Le Conseil d’Administration a l'honneur d’informer le public que le bureau
                        télégraphique de Wardan acceptera des dépêches en langues européennes à
                        partir du 10 juillet 1905. </p>
                    <p>Le Conseil d’Administration </p>
                    <p>Le Caire le 10 juillet 1906.</p>
                    <p>26228-1</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>Société Internationale des Employes</head>
                    <head type="sub">Siège Social : Rue Mosquée Attarine No. 21</head>
                    <head type="sub">BUREAU DE PLACEMENT</head>
                    <p>Demandes </p>
                    <p>Un bon comptable en partie-double cherche à tenir la comptabilité d’une
                        Agence de Bourse ou d’une Maison de Commerce dans ses heures libres ; il
                        connais le français et l’italien et parle l’arabe. </p>
                    <p>Un bon comptable, français, très sérieux ayant déjà un emploi, désire entrer
                        dans an bureau d’agent de change, de commissionnaire ou de banque : Peut
                        offrir une caution ou garantie. </p>
                    <p>Offres </p>
                    <p>2 Places de commis ans écritures sont offertes dans une maison de Nouveautés
                        (très importante) de la ville. </p>
                    <p>N.B.— Pour tous renseignements s'adresser soit directement, soit par lettre
                        au Siège Social de la Société, Rue Mosquée Attarine No. 21. </p>
                    <p>Le Secrétariat est ouvert les Lundi, Mercredi et Vendredi de 7 h. 1/2 à 8 h.
                        1/2 du soir. </p>
                    <p>Les insertions ci-dessus sont faites gratuitement par les soins de la Société
                        et seuls le sociétaires peuvent en bénéficier. </p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui font des offres ou des demandes sont priées de joindre un
                        timbre à leur lettre, sinon il ne leur sera fait aucune réponse. </p>
                    <p>25735-7 4-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>BECK* CO’S PILSNEfl BEER fEAR8 WO -EORiBT 1 COMPETITION JF0 QUALITY. N
                        .B.—Inferior Brand* now being offered to Mu* Rgortf tenais good cento. Be
                        ward ot evilly dietseed «oinyeitoif fanning down Ntta very Ba*** *r V)6e
                        ïBest Çùrink for Jiot (Countries is BARLEY WATER. The Best Way to make
                        Barley Water ia to use It can be obtained in One Pound Tins at the Local
                        Store. Manufacturers : KEEN, ROBINSON S’ Co., Ltd., LONDON, ENGLAND. M*kara
                        of ROBINSON’S PATENT OROATS. McLAREttS STEAM PLOUGHS SUITABLE FOR EVERY
                        DESCRIPTION OF SOIL AND QROP. ESTABLISHED 1876. IMPROVE ipCOI PODS D
                        ENGINES.: Balance Ploughs turning* CULTIVATORS. Harrows. . Water”cart8.
                        8TECL BOMBSU of very best quality QATkLOGTtS oi POST FRKK ON APPLICATION 1.
                        &amp; W: MCLAREN, MIDLAND ENGINE WORKS. 1 Code» usfcct: A.B.C. 4thfand
                        5thedition».it-1EBE!*S. LEEDS. ENGLAND. ENGLISH MADE PLOUGHS FOR ALL
                        COUNTRIES AND ALL PURPOSES. J. &amp; F. HOWARD, Enarlamd.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>NILE GAUGE READINGS</head>
                </div>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
