<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-11"> February 11, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
              <div type="item">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY. FEBBUABY 11, 1D05.</head>
<head>Til 11 IlUSSl AN STRIKES.</head>
<head>I - I'SI IU <>N \Yt»l:KM:S</head>
<head>11:: sil SliSOUhJ KSPKtKEI).</head>
<p>duo lli'iiMUi-1, live limu'ln-d Mrik.-rs i
iiatcl, thought sliAi work w.-i> vn»cclit.;
They stern il ton ir!- the l.iiii-ling, vvlion il
soldier* tired from the windows, liiiliiig umn
of the striker*.	< H'ut-r</p>
<p>St. IVniiiMittRO, February Ml.
The me. of tin- l’.uil..il mi.i Fram n ltns i.
works hole have stalled an eight-hours day
their own Recount As the employers It ■>
retu.-cd to countenance the fimvement, -I
oat. 'ihetr.V'Jsiw in reading t.. ,.reve.
the si i ike spreading.</p>
<p>Five thousand striker* have |>amdcd he
today. They induced four" other factories
join tl.eui, bat dis|rersed •quietly on encuuntc
At the instance of the governors, the umn
taeturci sol Warsaw aid i he mine owners-
So-iiowice are conferring will, a view to tuakii</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>i; 'CAL AND GENERAL.</head>
<p>Tiib Legislative Council met at Cairo
to dry.
nlE Plague.—Yesterday'* bulletin record*
a r -overy at Suez.
ttfUARANTIKE restrictions on arrivals in Egyp-
. (Huts from 1’orhuniUr and Yodia (India)
Council ok .Mt.M.sfKiis. The next meeting
of tho Council ol .Ministers will probably take
The Steam Yacht "Argonaut" arrived at
Alexandria from Jail* yesterday with a large
uuiuour ot touiisis, who proceeded to Cairo.
Eoyptlvn Salt and Soda Company. — The
monthly return ot sales of salt during Jauuary
hows a tolar of 1/.E. 33,301.698, as against
Ut. J4.b0ii.USt iu Jauuary 1003.
Very Severe Weather is reported betwoeu
C.cio and Aioxainiim. The S. S. "1'riuee
•AOOas," wluek amveu dim uiuruing from Cou-
siaiuinup.e, burn traces ui having wcalheied a
stunn.</p>
<p>Warsaw. February 10.
niglil" with'die u.^' Tne laMer fi^lM th
m./na. li.o sinkers were extinguishing (h
killed >r woundeii.	(lUut".</p>
<p>St. pKTBHtfDlIRO, February 10.
A striko lias W n declared iu tbe I’utilo
works. l're>h disorders ore feared.
</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>MANCHURIA.</head>
<head>JAPANESE ATTACK REPULSED.</head>
<p>St. Pi.TEiL'Bt'Ko, February 10.
his'left think on ‘the u’lli' ,L‘t ' J//•»«*<</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GENERAL ELECTION PROSPECTS.</head>
<head>LIBERALS GETTING.HEADY.</head>
<p>London, February lt
.Mr. llyrncit ........, the chief Libe.al
Whip, lias warned die Liberal agents to
general ebvim.- lie ■•spec's the dissolution
hq/uf Put!i..Ui.:nl -n the l id. inst. ( itrulr..^</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>A LIBERAL MANIFESTO. ■ i</head>
<head>ISSUED BY LORD SPENCER.</head>
<p>I/ISUOH. February 10.
Ippnae* oi'tbc ...Mliu'i.r. trciu-. lie ailvo
r! . i,, l..i	....g. Isj-nd lie
.•‘•b-- •" •» •	...« 6w.iinets.aty -y»U-i
ballet is to bo produced at a matimfo perfonn-
anco to-morrow. Four porformancos are shortly
tohegivon by tho old ohansohuiera. of tho
famous "Chat Noir.” The company,- wbioh is
being brought hero by M. C. iBarot, has the
celebrated Jules Moy at its head.
Hblouan Spohtino Club.—A very success-
ful |iertormauca was giveu yesterday afternoon
ny the hoys' band of Tourah Prison, which is
composed of tho sous' of negro warders. The
boys who were voiy smartly uniformed in
blue ami white, played fr 'in 3 to 5 p.m. in tho
eiielosuro of tho lloluuaii Sporting Club, next
to tho Tewfik Palnca Hotel, aud also igavo a
display of physical drill, which waa-greatly
appreciated.
Still Tuey Comb !— Next week largo num-
bere of tourists are duo at Alexandria, oilAo
13th inst. by the North Gerhian v.Lloyda o.S.
"liohenzotluru'' and on the 15di"m/*;-by the
White Star liner "Romanic.',' ^Phroedmadred
,.ud iifty tourists are duo' here On qls 37th
inst by tbo lluiuburg-Amurijfari S.S. “Moltke."
Tho passougura will roui*ui,m Egypt fo^6j or
12 J days, as tboy may desire. ’ The "Moltko"
leaves Alexandria ou March 5 for Beyruutaud
returns boro ou March II, leavlug shortly
alter tor JulTu.
( The Fbkres Case.—tho Court ol Appeal at
A LX ou IhutMlay eoulirmed iu its entirety toe
juilgmeut ui the FreueU tuusular Court giveu
against M. L. Yayuu lor libel against tbo
, Ghnstlall Brothers.
' The Cairo Tradesmen 's Ball is to bo given
ou lliu 1! to lust, al tue Verdi 1 lie. t ru. 1 hm U
.lie eccuuu annual lull ol turn etiaraeler, UUU
,i suuuid Uceumo a regular yearly nxture. inu
1 uail was a gieat success last year.
Sue? Canal. —10 vessels passed through
' me canal uu Use Bill llisL, ol winch 'J were
onUsU, 1 Dutcii, 3 German, 1 Austrian, 3
Italian. TUe day’s leccipla werolrs. 4'J4,34b.03,
uiaaing tuotolatsiueo 1st mat. fro. 3,l)Ai,'J4U.dy.
j •The Pirates or Penzance."—Wo loam
Lint the pcriuiuiauce in Cano ot Gilbert and
auiiivau s opera lias been antedated to the
lJlU inst. as li-R.il. tuo DuKC of Colinauglil
iios sign Hied bis lulelitlou ol bouuriug the
puriuruiauee Willi urn presence.
White Nile Exploration.—Oneoi thochiei
ton ti ion Lulls tome "Gcograpmcal. Journal,'
vol. XXIV., containing the proceedings ol
Lie Royal Geograplneal Soeioiy duiiug tbo
asl ball .) oar, is au ibteresling article by
Captain Liddell on bis exploration ol the
IV bile Nile.
' Coal Imports.- From 1st January to Uih
inst. tuo quantity oi Coal impoiled was 5U.66Z
ton.*. Dui mg lue eoircspomliug period of lost
jear To,SIS tons wore received. This year
,• .Newcastle sent j,SJ3 loos, Welsh districts
jj,Mil. .-Scutch uistriula o.-sj 1. Yorltsbire
-. 4,6s7, and otner disliiets 637 tuns.
auras Helmy Theatre.— This evening,
.- Sig. ora Bciiintiuui will appear in Mauent-t’s
,	Mu.,... I umu.ro-a mal.me |a-.lormu.ao ol
	ke given, and n. the oe.ing
I..	u to bo pluuuccvl uU Jlunua), -bcD
n. .sign. i.v Ucbutciuui -ill iigaiu appear.
Cheap Hocses at Alexanuklc—A meeting
'1 he iNNlsKU-LiNO l* isiLlEUo uuia tueir regi-
mental spurts at -Mena House ycstuiduy. Some
ol the eveuts were held beloro aud some alter
much. Iu spite ol tbe cold Weather, lira spurts
went oil web, there buuig a very Urge number
I ,,l events. About lit) to 3W guests bad been
muted by tlie ullicurs.
1 The ElelTiiii'katiuR of tho Ramleh Rail-
' way bas luspHoi imitators in Cairo, and it is
, ue-u.laling vvilb tbe Railway Administration
i .„ u„ eltedie tram service ou the .Matunch
b..,e. Tho eompuiiy proposes to run one</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>i III t;< II AMI STATE IN FRANCE.
<head>SEI'ARATION To BE VOTED.</head>
Paris. February 10.</head>
<p>vi.li-'dm	of lln- rlnin-l.es fr.ni the
Sra-L- ...i-i V. li.ig the B nlgct ..ml the military
law.	z//«.»»</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>11..M.S. “I'YLAUES" AGROUND.</head>
<head>SliiNKY, Fehrimry 10.</head>
<p>II.M S. ■‘I’vluilc*" i* aground on the Feel
lle-f 'Thiir.-dsv 1-laiul) but isimt serioiiilj
dainsgi-d.	(Ur-'t-
Mr. Goo. B. Atdo\on has resigned his position
on tho Alexandria Municipality, and we havo
boon roquosted by him to publish tho following
copy of a communication addressed by him to-
day to Mr. Chataway
To tho Administrator of Alexandria Muni-
cipality.</p>
<p>Dear Sir,—I havo now boon ono year a
mornbor. of your honorable assembly aud feel
that, not having boon invited to sit on tbe
Delegation, l am useless for the pnblio good,
and beg to offer yon my resignation.—Yonrs
obediently,	Gko, B. Aldkrson.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>Bulkeloy, February lltb.</head>
<head>THE PORT SAID COLLISION.</head>
<p>Retail Trade Combination. — Wo have
received a c-.py ot the publication, entitled
••The Retail .Merchants' Journal of Cauada,"
which sceius to ho a first-rate medium for
uriugmg together manufacturer and retailer.
Like our American cousins, Canadian traders
have an excellent idea ol looking alter tho
main chance, and are wou aware of tho advan-
lagesof eombi-iatiou for tbo advaboemeut ol
their mercabUio interests. The secretary and
editor is E. M. Troworn, 31, Riohmund-stnset,
West, Toronto, mid too siibscriptiou $3 per
lviiEbiviAL Club.—The auuualgeneral meot
ling of llio Kbedivial Glub, Alexandria, was
held this week, when tho following gentlemen
were elected us ollieers of the club lor tbo
current veur : president, Robert J. Moss;
vieo-prosidents, Mr. Adv. R. Giro aud llassan
Tasini Muhsen ; auditor, Mr. A. Bimseusteiu ;
members, Messrs. J. U. Aghiou, U. R. C. Blog-
uou, Av. Clemeuto Castro, P. Cavafy, A.
Ccsauo, Av. M. Colucoi, E. Friudhoim, IL
U. Grenthead, F. C. Haseldeu, Lt. Col. Lucas,
C.B..R.A.M.C., W. B. Rees, J. R. Roovos, Av.
.M.Romano, Dr. M. A. Ruflor, A. Sorokine, Em.
Stros.-, mid Av. Alfred Tilche. Tho tollowing
members of the uutgomg house committee
were ro-electcd unanimously: Mr. Adv. R. Giro,
Mr. P. Cavaly, llassan Pasha Mohsen, Mr.
A. Cesana, aud Mr. A. Sorokine.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ULUA.U. AND riUCl.Vl.
m •, UiUiSfD</head>
<p>OalalwaUI*	«.«*»	r »«•
OthsrvK'.apply la
f. I. f* fWIHT. T. Wt"trs -I'l* Awe
in r l r. r r\ r» i • r\ T r i</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>VviKDSCR i-.OTEL</head>
<p>Urged 1st class and most ocmfortabl.
Br.iel ir. AleXyDdria. Faring the mi
i>i capitalists iiiierested iu tbe ijnesiiou Ol
cheap houses ut Alexandria lor the Working
classes, will be held shortly, wheu tho statules
of the EoeieuY Aiiuiiima di Cose Euoiiouiichc
ml, ho considered. Il the statutes are appruved
me company will be deluutely luimed.
11.M. Transport "Soudan" (CapL S. de
B. Luekyerj reached Port Said on Thurs«la)
night, outward .hound from Southampton,
and entered ihe Canal * yesterday morning en
route for Bombuy. The troops ou hoard num-
bered 1,313 of all rauks. Tho officer com-
manding is Lt.-Col. M.G. Jackson, 1st Devon-
shire lU'ginieut,
Lord and Lady. Cromer aud Lady Beatrice
Tbyime are expected to arrive at Assouan ou
Tuesday.</p>
<p>Tho following passengers left Cairo yesterday
by l ho I’.S. “ TJatasoo" for tho Nile trip:
Geneial and Mrs. Lance, Mr. Gilbert Elliot,
lie.. S. .rad Mrs. Campbell, Mr. aud Mrs. A.
Baillierc, Capt. and Mrs. Ueopcke, Mr. Josel
Hicbaum, Lt. aud Mrs. von Meyer iu Kuouow,
.Mr. J. Buckley Jonas, Mr. E. Hughes Jones,
Mr. E. C. Morris, Mr. Otto Kohou, Miss L. D.
Shephard, Miss Sara Nicholson, Mrs. Hogg,
.\IiM .v. G. Morris, Mr. J. P. Brady, Mr. W. J.
Biaily, Judge lloyle, Mr. Geo. Hoyle, Mr. S. H.
buerley, Mr. E. Foster Bruok, Mrs. Brierley,
Miss A. W. Shaw, Admiral aud Miss Dale,
Mis. Uundiu, Mr. Heibert Wallis, Miss A. B.
Hyde, Mias M. E. Crouse, Mr. E. Sas.
No ollicial statement has yet been made
confirming tho rumour that Mr. Russell is to
be appointed director of the Treasury.
The marriage arranged between Mr. Charles
O. B.nuan and Emmeliue Beatrice Hewgill,
'youngest iluughter ol Mr. John Hewgill, id
Mex, will rake place at St. Mark's Church on
Tuesday next, 1-ltli inst.
The marriage ummgod betwoeu Mr. Alex-
ander M. lleid, of the Eastern Telegraph
Co., and Ada Elvira, daughter of Mr. and
Airs. John Augel, will take place at St.
Andrew's Uhureh, Alexandria, on Tuesday,
38th inst., at 2.30 p.m. A reception will
alter wards be held at the Hotel Abbot.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY.</head>
<head>RESIGN^flON' iOF MR. ALDEllSON.</head>
<head>KBEDIVIAL LBVBE.</head>
<head>ORDER OF RECEPTION.</head>
<p>On tho oocasion of tho feast of Konrban
Boy rmu, the Khedive will hold a reception at
Abdecn Palaoo on Tuesday next, when visitor*
will be received in the following ordor:—
At 8 a.m. The Ulema; the General As-
sembly and Legislative Council; the Governor
of Cairo and the Mtludir of Ghiieh.-the officers
of the Army and Navy, from the rank of
Bimbashi upwards.
At 8.80 a.m. The officials of tho following
administrations : Council of Ministers, Minis-
try of the Interior, Board of Health, Prisons
Inspectorate, 81ave Trade Repression Depart-
ment, Cairo Gouvernorat, Ghiich Moodirieb,
Finanoo Ministry, Postal Administration, the
C6ast Guards, Publio Debt Commission, Daira
Sanieh, State Domains Administration, Admi-
nistration of Railways, Telegraphs and the
Port of Alexandria, Publio Works Ministry,
Ministry of Justioe, Ministry of Publio Instruc-
tion, Ministry of War, Foreign Offioo, Watfa
Administration.
At It a.m. Tho Prinoee of the Kbedivial
Family; tho President of tbe Council of
Mioistere and the Ministers ; the Financial
Adviier, the Judicial Adviser, and tho Advirer
at tho Ministry of the Iuterior and of Pn
blio Works; the Under Secretaries of State.
At 0.30 a.m. The former Presidents of the
Council of Ministers, the former Ministers,
Presidents of the Legislative Council, Sirdars,
Grand Masters of Ceremonies, beads of the
Khedivial Cabinet, ohief aides-de-camp, Di-
rectors of tho Khedivial KLasso, Directors
General of Walds, Under Secretaries of State;
dircctora-general of the Daira Sanieh, ad-
ministrators of the State. Domains and ad-
ministrators of the Railways, Telegraphs, and
Port of Alexandria; unofficial military and
civil personages having the rank of Lows or
Oula Sinf Sani and upwards, the officers of
tho Army aud Navy unattached and on the
retired list having the rank of Kaimakam or
Miralai; the unofficial civil Beys, having the
rank of Moutemaiz or Sanieh and upwards.
At 10 a.m. The Diplomatic and Consular
Corps. ,
At 10.16 a.m. The Directors-Commissioners
of the Publio Debt Commission ; the Director
Gcnoral and tho Controllers of tho Daira
Sanieh; tho State -Domains administrators ;
tho administrators of Railways, Telegraphs,
and the Port of Alexandria.
At 10.46 ajn. The field offioers of theArmy
of Occupation ; the clergy ; the Mixed Magis-
tracy ; the Native Magistracy.
At 11.16 a.m. Tho Khedivial Counsellors ;
native notables ; European notables ; the
officials of the military and civil households
of H.H. tbe Khedive and those of the Khe-
divial Kbassa.
The Kbedivab will also hold a reoeption on
Tuesday at Abdecn Palace. The Prinoeases ot
tbs Kbedivial Family and native ladies will be
received from 3 to 3.30 p.m., European ladies
from 3.40 to 4.40 p.m., and the wives of mem-
bers of the Diplomatic Corps at 4.45 p.m.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>FULLER DETAILS.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent.)
Port Said, Friday.
As already reportod, a serious collision
occurred in Port Said harbour on Thursday
afternoon between the Harrison liner, "Crafts-
man," of Liverpool, a vessel of some 8,000
tons, and the Norwegian collier, "Congal,” of
Saudofjord, bound for Hong Kong with ooal.
Tho "Congal,” ready to enter tho Canal, was
moored fore-and-aft at her bertb, but having
no breast line out aft,jhad drifted slightly into
tbe fairway. Tbe “Craftsman," from the Canal,
in proceeding to her allotted bertb, abreast of
tho Suez Canal Company's offioes—which was
directly astern of that of the "Congal,"—passed
toonear, with the result that a side collision
was inevitable, the smaller vessel's msin
rigging being touched by the high oountor of
the "Craftsman,” and tbo stanchions on tbo
poop bont. The main damage, however, was
caused by tho propeller blades (three of whioh
arc reported to be broken) ripping the plates on
the port side of tho “Cougal" below the water
lino, and causing tho vessol to begin to settle
down.
Tbo Canal authorities, realizing the situa-
tion, at once sent tugs to tow the "Congal”
in-shore if possible, but the operations were
only half completed when she sank at the stem,
and tho water rushing in, one bulkhead after
another gave way till the wholo hull was
submerged. She now lies in the Bassin Cherif
with bridge aud boats amidships, a small part
of the forecastle deck, and the mast and
funnel visible. The crow were able to save most
of their effects.</p>
<p>Khedivial Geoukapiiical Society.—Dr. L.
de Cuxiro, who is the doctor attaciiol to tho
lluliau Legation in Abyssinia, will read a paper
belore the Khedivial Geographical Society,
entitled Le l’atnarchisme el le Fouilalisiuo eu
Ahyesmie," ou Momlay.Dr. de Castro has spent
three years iu Meuelik's country, and his
paper should be ot great interest.
Alhambra Thkatkb.—A ball will bo given
at this theatre this evening and to morrow
evening, alter the usual variety performance,
which is still as attractive as ever. A new
Amongst the latest arrivals at the Eastern
Exchange Hotel, Port Said, aro Mr. J. A.
Kuutli, Capt. P. W. North, Mrs. B. H. Jossen,
Mr. B. Mansfield, Mr. and Mrs. B. Firth, Mr.
Alex. Firth, Miss Wrightiuan, Mr. E Edwards,
Alj. and Mrs. R. Walker, Mr. and Mrs. Craw-
shay, Mr. P. R. Box well, Mr. E. L. Botham,
Mr. F. G. Davidson, Dr. W. M. Aden, Mr.
and Mrs. 0. B. Butler, Mr. and Mrs. Wykoff,
Ur. and Mrs. Dunlop, Mr. and Mrs. MacNutt,
Mrs. J. Grundy, Mrs. M. Lucas, and Kauial
B«y.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>FAShENBER GISTS.</head>
<head>DEPARTURES.</head>
<p>1/9 paquobot “Niger" des Mo«a;crics Mari-
tiuies parti,bier pour Marseille avaithbord :—
Provenance du Cairo: M. Pointel, Mmo
ot Milo West, M. Walter Mansfield, M.
M. Yungtlcsoh ot son (ID, M, 1. Pierrori’t,
M. Cbeueval.
Provenance d'Alexandrie: M. Primi, M.
Katfaian (consul do Perse), M. Emile Mercier,
M. Mary, M. FiSlix Lebon, et 13 passagers de
3ino et 4me clusse.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>SAVOY llUTEL, LUXUll.</head>
<p>Best and must cninli rtahle, unique for it*
position on Niielsmk. l i.ilet Girnian Manage
merit Moderated,*rg«	1 Mn.ui.-ed l«y iffieei
of Army of Occupoiiur.. Concert* twice daily
MM041-1I	rtomatoi*, Moroni * MoauwRL
Having ancooodod Mr. J. 8. Pritchard, or tho
••CAIKO BODEGA' (Royal Hotel nidus.). I beg to
lalorni the publio that It la my Intention to main-
tain tho reputation vihlch thU cataoUshmont baa
been* Voorganlood!0 In "addition to tbo flrat-clooo
dr.nks already served, many coo loo brands will bo
I added, and tbo oxporlenoo acquired of several
' years' sSrvlcowUl o on bio mo to fully satisfy my
I clients.</p>
<p>-JOSEPH.- Managing Proprietor.
I Macdonald and null's V.OJ-. Llqusur, now tho
Premier Whisky of Egypt.	WW-frl
Anglo-American Milo Steamer,
A ItOTW.l. COMPANY.
RlYtH IHIISPUBT Of CnojraFTiRl UfHIOWA 4 CAIRf
Throe Salllngt o-Wook.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>SIR W. WILLCOCKS’ EXPEDITION.</head>
<p>As wo announoed a few day* ago, Sir Wil- 0f
Ham Willoocka has returned to Cairo from bis 0|
important expedition to the Euphrates and the ( jj
Tigris. He has' kindly given ns tho following |
statement of the conclusions ho has arrived: ’p
at	tl
The Tigri* and Euphrates havo apparently n
enough water to allow of tho perennial irriga- fr
tion of 5 million acres and of keeping naviga- j*
tion open to the sea. The hydranlio problems
are not so hard as those on tho Nile ; but
comprehensive projects must be taken op to G
secure the canals against obliteration by silt,
which has often ruined Babylonia. I saw the di
Tigris in places only 740 feet wide and 6 feet fr
deep,mid the Euphrates 40 feet wide and 3 feet
deep, though I measured the water ontering
Babylonia and found it 50,000 cubic feet per
second for tho Tigris, and 25,000 cubic feet per
second for tho Euphrates. All the existing C
canals in the Bagdad Pasbalio were ditcharg- tl
ing 500 cubic feet per second between them. C
The first work needed would be an irrigation F
and navigation canal some 150 foot wide, join-
ing the Tigris and Euphrates at Bagdad. This
would be easy, as tbo Euphrates is about 15
foot higher than tho Tigris.
The Hindia Barrage on the Euphrates has 'I
so far been a failure, because they have made b
the same mistake as was made on the Cairo t
Barrage. 1 tried to persuade tho engineer (a *
-on of Mougel Bey, who built the Cairo Bar- r
race) to act a* I acted in Egypt, but he con- 1
si lured the risk too great.	c
Some 100 specimens of soils and building ?
mitorials and water have been collected by me. ']
When tho agricultural experts and chemists t
havo -ent in their reports I shall bo in a posi- ,
tion to frame estimate*.	1</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE PRICE OF MEAT.	j</head>
<p>A* some misapprehension appoars to prevail 1
in regard to tbo subject of the price of meat 1
nnd thocold storage system, vre may state that i
in spito of the extra freight for meat landed 1
, at Port Said (it actually oostsless to send I
-	frozen meat from Australia to London than 1
, from Australia to Port Said) and for railway ear- 1
. riago by fast trains, which is absolutely ;
, necessary unless tho meat is to deteriorate,
, also for duties, tho Nile Cold Storage Com-
1 pany’s prices average only Id. per lb. more
than those given in the. London Army ai d
Navy Stores' catalogue for 1904. And this
though tho chargos mentioned make the
cost of transport nearly 1 Jd. per lb. higher,
tho additional freight charge coming to about
-	a halfpenny per lb. more, while railway
-	charges add an extra Jd. in the lb. and
e Customs about Jd. As for the retail prioes of
. tho batchers in Cairo, they average 12% dearer
, than those quoted by tho Nile Cold Storago
Company. Here is an example—for lamb
[. (18 months old as a rule) four Cairo retailers
r, charge P.T. 14, 14, 13, and 11 peroke respect-
|e ively, while the oompany charges for genuine
lamb P.T. 12 for legs or loins, and P.T. 11 for
_ other parts. In beef, motton, and hams tho
difference is evon more marked.
Tho Khedivo is leaving Montazah for
Cairo this afternoon.
The motor car which his Highness bought
during his recent visit to Paris has arrived ^
from Europe this week.	;</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE ROYAL VISIT.	“</head>
<p>Sir William Garstin, Mr. Webb, and Mr. ^
Clowes left Cairo last night for Assouan, where I ^
thoy will meot the Duke and Duchess of ^
Connaught ou tho oocasion of their Royal I QI
Highness's visit to the Assouan Reservoir.
I i/enh at Alexandria :</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. Ll.
11.10 804</head>
<head>’	STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
<p>r The Moos liner'‘Tabor” wiled from Liver-
pool yesterday afternoon and is due here about
the 24th inst., with passenger*, mail*, and
general cargo,</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>^ ARMY ANTI NAVY.</head>
<p>(From our CoaRzsroronrr.)
London, February 8.
The appointment of P. M. 0- in Egypt will
be filled by the porting of 8urgeon-Iisutenant-
Colonel James Magill, C. B., senior
offioeroftho Coldstream Guards. lieutenant-
Colonel Magill entered the medical depart,
rnent in 1885, and reached hi* present rank
in May, 1896. He is no strangar in Egypt, for
ha accompanied the Guards Camel Corps in
tho Nile Expedition 1884-85 and was severely
wounded in the fierce action at Abou Klea,
near where Colonel Fred Burnaby fell fighting.
Ho was mentioned in despatches, received tbe
medal with two clasps and bronze star. He
was with the Coldstreams in tbe Boer War,
and was proetot at tbe actions of Belmont,
Eoslin, Modder River, Magenfontein, Poplar
Grove, Driefontein, Vet River, Zand River,
Johannesburg, Pretoria, Diamond Hill, Belfast,
and Komati Poort, and the succeeding cam-
paign. For his servioet he was mentioned in
doaDctohas, awaxdod the C. B., medal with six
clasps, and King’s medal with two olasps.
The Army Council, despite muoh hostile
oritioism, has determined to withdraw the 56th
Battery R. P. A. a-^i No. 4 Mountain Battery
from Egypt The field battery will return homo
in March. The Army Connoil is pushing ,
retrenchment to the very verge of safety.
We have the authority of Mr. Arnold-
Forster for stating that 120 of the new 18J-
pounder field guns—just soffioient to arm 20.
batteries—are now ready and that 600 more
will be delivered in -1906. That is a great
hiatus. If 120 guns can be produced for India
in a few weeks, why wait newly two year* for
tbe balance 1 The haste in providing guns for
India is based on Mr. Balfour's now historic
statement that "tho problem of tho British
Army is the problem of tbe defenoe oi
Afghanistan."
The battleship “Illustrious" has arrived at
Portsmouth to hare one of her 12-inch bar-
bette guns replaoed by a new One.
One of tbe objection^ to the late distribu-
tion of tbe fleet was that in a great number ot
foreign oountrie* tbe tremendous naval power
of Great Britain was not fully enough realised.
On many shores a small cruiser or obsolete
gunboat represented —or rather .misrepresented
—tbe premier naval power. That will now bo
all changed. Tbe second cruiser squadron, -
which consists of eight powerful 24-knot ar-
moured cruiser* under tbe oommand of Rear-
Admiral Prince Louie of Battenberg—who has
just hoisted bis flag on tbe swiftest cruiser
afloat, tbe “Drake”—has been detailed for a
seven months’ cruise along tbe coast line of
North and 8outh America. Every port of
importance will be visited, and tbe naval migbt
of tbe Empire practically demonstrated. The
selection of tho “Drake” as flagship was a
happy one, perpetuating as it does the name
of that grim old sea dog who was the terror ol
our enemies on the "Spanish main."</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ZIZINIA THEATRE.	^</head>
<p>Lost night’s performance at the Zizinia !'
Theatre in aid of the El Orwa El-Woska ^
benevolent society waa a brilliant snocess. H.H. j
tho Khedive arrived punctually at 9 p.m. and
was received by.H. E. the Governor and the F
members of the oommittee of the society. His .
Highness oocupiod Baron de Monasoe’s box in
company with the Governor, Baron Alfred de
Menascc, and several members of tho oommittee. D
The appearanoe of the theatre waa magnificent, I
tbo whole of fashionable Alexandria being pro- {
.-out,and the aspect waa illrther onli' enedhy the *
band of the society in their brilliant and beoom- 1
ing uniforms. The Khedive on several oocaaiona a
applauded the playingof the youngbandsmen. ]
During the intervals his Highness received ]
many European and native notabilities and (
also all the French comedy artists, who |
kindly lent their sorvicee in aid of the society’s (
funds. The play, Lt mondt oi) ton tennuit, 1
a sparkling comedy by Pailleron, waa very (
ably rendered and fa certainly one of the beet ,
performances of the company this season. Mme.
Pamy, l’atry, Lily and M1 le.Georgo t to Loyer were 1
particularly good. The latter, in the amusing ,
part of Suzanne do Villiers, was much ap 1
predated, and was applauded more than onoe I
by H. IL the Khedive. Messrs. Cooper and ,
Laurent also deserve special mention.
The net receipts amount to about £300, ,
end we Biuoeroly hope that it will help to
enhanoe the good this sodety fa doing .in
the education and moral improvement of tbe
' poorer classes of native boys. At present more
than 2,000 boys reoeive instruction at its
1 hands. ^</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ROYAL MALTA ARTILLERY.</head>
<p>Tho news that the oompany at Alexaxdria
and the detachment at Cairo of the Royal
Malta Artillery aro leaving Egypt for their
native isle has been received with much
regret, as during tbe five year* tbe
R.»M. A bare been in Egypt they have
made themselves very popular. They came
hero in January, 1900, two companies having
been raised in Malta for service abroad, and
one was sent to Egypt
Nothing fa known as to tbe future of tbe
oompany now in Egypt, and it fa doubtful
whether they are to be stationed permanently
in Malta, or to be posted to some foreign
station. Since tbo IL M. A. oamo to Egjqit
they have been under tbe oommand of Major
Balbi. The troeps are leaving on the 4th
proxo. by the “Di wara.”</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN HOTELS, LIMITED.</head>
<p>A great many people appear to be quite
naware of the position of the Egyptian Hotrls,
imited, which oompany owns tbe Qherireh
’alaoe and Sbepheard’s Hotel We are
mthoriaed to state that this oompany, as
it present constituted, fa an English company
md fa registered under tbe Companies Aeta.
its board fa composed as follows. Chairman :
[/>rd Claude Hamilton, tbe Chairman of the
Treat Eastern Railway Company ; members of
die board: Sir Robert Herbert, Mr. Emmanuel
J. Zervudacchi, Mr. E. A. Harrison (general
manager of Messrs. Thos. Cook and 800, Limit-
9d), and Mr. J. J. Hug, of Cairo. The London
offices of the oompany are at 8, Lothbnry, RC.
Up to last spring the Compagnie Interna-
tionale do*' Grands Hotels was tbe largest
fiaroholder in the Egyptian Hotels Company.
The former company was bought ont entirely
by .Mr. Charles Baehler, who fa backed by a
powerful financial syndicate. He therefore fa
now in oontrol of the deetimee of tbe company,
and with the assistance of his board, some ot
he should make the oompany, under its* new
conditions, even more snoceerfnl than it was
before.</p>
<p>Oirtng to tbe rise in the price of land,
especially for building purpose* in the neigh-
bourhood of Cairo, tbe property belonging to
thfa oompany at Qherireh has become a very
valuable asset Tbe oompany intend to develop
the Qherireh estate into one of tbe finest
residential quarter* of Cairo. Already thirty-
two villas have been bnilt and some very high
offers have been reoently made for rites at
Qherireh.</p>
<p>Tbe fashionable neighbourhood of thfa Mtoto,
and its proximity to tbe Qherireh Palace
Hotel, with it* beautiful park and tbe Kbedi-
vial Spotting Club, already oombino to make
It a anqh loughUfter »pot for rerideoee*.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>BULLETIN pE LA BOUB8E tl</head>
<p>tA UfOmrttAni d midi it demit)	tl
Notre marohi! devient de jour en jour plus n
forme et la tender)oe est pour la hausse.	t'
La Banque Nationale atteint96 7/16, l’Agri- 0
oole 11 8/8, l'lnveetment 1 25/32, la Delta G
Light 14 5/16, TAnglo-American Nile 5 8/8 it
les E*ux d’Alexandrie 16 3/8.	•
Par contra il y a une Ugtre "faction en I
Banque d'Athtaes, on Salt and Soda *t «o 1
Tramway* d’Aleiandri*,</p>	</div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
