<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-11-07</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-05-16</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, MAY 16, 1905.</head>
<div type="item"><p>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.
(From ocr Corhbspondkiit).
Constantinople, May 9.
The Roumanian Maritime Service has ordered
from the Chantiera de la Loire, in France, a
steamer, to be called “Imperatnl Troian,” for
the line to be established between Constanza
and Alexandria. This steamer will afford every
comfort for passengers, and will havo ample
cargo space.</p>
<p>The Tsar has been graciously pleased to
confer on M. Maximoff, formerly Russian
Diplomatic Agent in Cairo and now Minister
at Cettignd, the grand cordon of the Order of
St. Anne.</p>
<p>The Court of Appeal has passed sentence of
imprisonment for life in a fortress upon the
agitator Eshref, who fled to Egypt and has
been publishing seditious literature in Cairo.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CORPORATION OF WESTERN
EGYPT.
An exploring party has discovered a consider-
able tract of land with remains of ancient
buildings to the north-west of Um el Dabadib,
in Khargeh. This tract is about six miles
square, level, and the soil appears to be oi
good quality. It should form an important
addition to the cultivable area of the oasis.
Cultivation is proceeding both at No. 1
borehole and on the land watered by the well
within the Deir. The ancient conduit from
this well could not be traced throughout its
length and as it is situated at a somewhat in-
convenient depth below the present door of the
Deir, the soil of which is loose filling danger-
ous to excavate, a four-inch pipe has been
laid down and is now discharging about 100
gallons a minute from a point considerably
above the level of the ancient conduit. A
fresh conduit can be constructed when a
favorable opportunity oooura which will allow
of taking a considerably greater discharge from
a lower level.</p>
<p>It should be remembered that another well
giving a considerable supply of water exists at
a distance of less than 26O metres outside the
Deir. This well has not been at all allocated to
opening the well within the Deir, and indica-
tions of other ancient springs or wells exist in
the immediate vicinity.</p>
<p>The present conditions should go far to
refute suggestions of a tall in the water level
since Roinau times, and of necessary injury to
one well by opening another in the immediate
vicinity, also the laud surrounding the Deu
should prove a most valuable asset to the
corporation.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ECLIPSE STATION IN EGYPT.
Professor Turner and Mrs. Bellamy have
been appointed by the British Government to
form a station in Egypt for the observation of
the coming eclipse.</p>
<p>Professor Turner, D.S.C., F.R.S., is a distin-
guished astronomer and was appointed Saviliau
Professor of Astronomy at Oxford in 1893 and
fellow of New College in the same year. He is
a member ot the Senate of Cambridge Univer-
sity and was formerly fellow ot Trinity College,
Cambridge, and chief assistant at the Royal
Observatory at Greenwioh.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>Calendar of Coming Events
ALEXANDRIA.
May.
Tues. 16 Behera Co.’s Offices. Extraordinary
General Meeting. 8.30 p.m.
Alhambra. Italian operetta com-
pany. 9 p.m.
Fri. 18 A S. C. grounds. Tennis match.
K. S. C. v. A. 8. C.
8at 20 A. C. C. grounds. Cricket Gar-
rison XI t>. A C. C. 1.30 p.m.
Race from Sidi Gaber to Alexandria
by pupils ol Scotoh SohooL 6 a.m.
San Stefono Casino. Opening Ball
of Season.
Son. 21 San Stefano Casino. Concert 10 a.m.
Gabbari. Pigeon 8hooting. 2.30 p.m.
Tues. 23 San Stefano Casino. A L. M. &
D. 8. Concert 9.15 p.m.
Thurs. 25 A. S. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting.
Sat. 27 A. S. C. grounds. 2nd Summer
Meeting.
OAI RO.
May.
Tues. 16 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
British Military Band. 9 to 11
p.m.
Fri. 19 Zoological Gardena Performance by
Ghixeh Boys' Band in afternoon
Esbekieh Gardens. Performance
by British Military Band. 9 to
11 p.m.</p>
<p>British Chamber ofCommerce.—We would
call the attention of persons interested in
Egyptian trade to the work of the British
Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, whose office
in Alexandria gives information as to standings
trade, Ac., to its members, and whose monthly
publication reviews our commeroe. The annual
subscription is £1 and all British traders should
become members. Our London office, 86, New
Broad- street EC., acts as London agency to
pM Chanter.</p></div>
<div type="item"<p>AN ANGLO-EGYPTIAN
COMPANY.
IN THE BANKRUPTCY COURT.
A sitting of the London Bankruptcy Court
was held last week, before Mr. Registrar Hood,
to inquire into the promotion, history, and
failure of the Anglo Egyptian Automatic Tra-
ding Company, Limited, which was formed in
November, 1901, with a capital of £15,000, to
manufacture, buy, and use automatic machines
for the sale of goods. The accounts filed under
the liquidation show liabilities £7,462, against
assets £80,500, and an estimated surplus of
£9,885 as regards contributories. The com-
pany's assets consist of 25,500 £1 shares in
the British and Colonial Automatic Trading
Company, Limited, valued at par, and a book
debt of £12,000, due from the same company
and valued at £5,000. The witnesses called
were Mr. Stuart Dixon Ross, Mr. George Ross,
and Mr. John Tweedy Scott
Mr. H. Brougham (Senior Official Receiver)
first examined Mr. Stuart Dixon Ross, who
stated that ho was the promoter of the com-
pany, and, in oonjunction with his brother
(George Ross) and his cousin (J. T. Soott), he
acted as director throughout About tho end
of 1901 or the beginning of 1902 witness
bought between 100 and 200 tons of castings
for the construction of automatic machines, at
the price of about £150. Messrs. Crooke and
Co., the sellers, had purchased the castings at
iron price from the liquidator of the
Automatic Supply Company, Limited. Witness
agreed to sell them to the Anglo-Egyptian
Company for £12,500 in cash, and he was,
further, to have an option to purchase the
whole or part of the share capital at par. No
trading business was ever done by the Anglo
Egyptian Company, witness’s idea being to
obtain large contracts on its behalf, and then
sell the whole undertaking to a larger
company. In June, 1903, the British
and Colonial Automatic Trading Company,
Limited, was registered, with a nominal
capital of £150,000, to acquire this Anglo-
Egyptian company, the Automatic General
Stores, Limited, and the Automatic Telegram
and Letter Delivery Company, Limited. The
consideration payable to the Anglo-Egyptian
Company was £37,500, divided into £12,000
cash and £25,500 shares. The cash had not
been paid, and although the shares were
allotted, the certificate had not been handed
over to the Anglo-Egyptian Company, the
reason being that witness was advised that
they could not deal with the shares until their
debts had been liquidated. The British and
Colonial Company was now in voluntary liqui-
dation, and witness was a bankrupt In October,
1903, he was given a charge for £7,500 over
the whole of that company’s assets, and as
they were being realised the proceeds were
being paid over to the trustee under his bank-
ruptcy.</p>
<p>So that thd goods qf the Anglo-Egyptian
Company which;, were sold to the British and
Colonial Company, are finding their way back
to your possession 1 — The proceeds—yes.
The witness was examined regarding the
returns filed at Somerset House, and showing
that the shares had been issued for cash. He
admitted that instead of the £12,500 which
was to be paid him in cash, he accepted shares
at par, and they were included in the returns
as having been issued for cash. In all, 12,346
shares were allotted to witness or his nominees,
and 10,339 of the number had been transferred
to other people. Some were given away for
services rendered; but about 8,000 were taken
up by the public (chiefly in Scotland), at
premiums ranging up to £2 5s.
Reexamined by Mr. Barnard Lailey, who
was briefed for the three directors, witness said
the machinery for which he paid about £150
had originally cost from £12,000 to £15,000;
so that the price he paid for it was no criterion
of its value. The £12,315 shares allotted to him
in consideration of the purchase were issued in
payment of the machinery, but also under his
option to take the company's share capital at
par.</p>
<p>Mr. George Ross and Mr. John Tweedy Scott
were also examined by the Senior Official Re-
ceivor, and the inquiry was closed.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>YEMEN.
Yemen, which is now in revolt against the
Sultan of Turkey, has always exercised a sin-
gular fascination over Oriental scholars and ex-
plorers, for whom it has been the true “Araby
the Blest,” has long had relations with Europe,
and it was known when the rest of the penin-
sula was for the most part a land of mystery.
The first European traveller wholeftan account
of it was Ludovico di Varthema, a Bolognese,
who published his description at Rome in 1510.
He reached Sana, and was astonished by the
fine buildings of the place and the high fertility,
"the fair orchards and fountains,” of the
country, which had not yet been occupied by
the Turks.</p>
<p>Yemen suddenly, in modern times, be-
came an important land when the coffee berry
was "discovered” at the end of the sixteenth
century. The East India Company sent many
expeditions there. Probably the first English
men who ever reached Sana were the members
of one of the earliest of these expeditions, led
by Henry Middleton. Middleton and his party
were taken there as prisoners by the Turks.
He described it as "somewhat larger than
Bristol, well built of stone and lime.” In 1761
the famous Danish expedition of which Carsten
Niebuhr, the first great name in modern
Arabian exploration, was a member set out.
8ince Niebuhr’s time there has been no longer
any mystery about it In the ancient world the
country was of course the neat emporium of
the produce of Africa and the East, and it wa-
the object of the famous ill-fated Arabian
invasion of Augustus: It was no doubt a part
of the Egyptian "Land of Punt," and some
scholars have identified it indeed, as the land
of Ophir. But just now the African Zimbabwe
KW to be the most generally accepted Ophir</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE SUEZ CANAL SHARES.
Lieut-Colonel Stanton writes to the "Times”
oonfmnii g what was stated concerning his
father, General S r B. Stanton, by a correspon-
dent in our columns on the 24th ulto. He
says</p>
<p>In you* issue of April 10 there appeared
the report of a speech made by Mr. Greenwood
at a complimentary dinner given in his
honour, in which he made certain statements
in connexion with the purchase of the Suoz
Canal shares, referring in a most unwarrant-
able manner to my father, General Sir E.
Stanton, who was at that time H.M.’s Agent
and Consul-General in Egypt</p>
<p>In your issue of April 15 Mr. Greenwood
partially withdrew these statements and quoted
part of a letter ho received from my father on
the subject, but omitted to insert the whole
of it</p>
<p>As the latter is convalescent, after a serious
operation, and not in a fit state of health to
challenge Mr. Greenwood on the subject, I
venture to do so on his behalf.
Sir E. Stanton does not for a moment deny
that he was not aware of the Khedive’s in-
tention of parting with the Canal shares till
his attention was called to the matter by
Lord Derby; but Mr. Greenwood’s statement
that as a consequence Colonel Stanton was
sent into forced retirement to a minor post
on tho Black Sea, which he afterwards cor-
rected by saying he would withdraw the word
"retirement,” is so far from the truth and
facts of the case as to require a further
disclaimer.</p>
<p>After 11 years’ service in Egypt Sir Edward
Stanton, for purely private reasons and on the
store of health, asked for a change. He was
offered Chile, which he declined, and later
was offered promotion as Charge d’Affaires at
Munich in 1876, which he accepted. I do not
see how Mr. Greenwood can reconcile this fact
with even his amended statement</p>
<p>It is unfortunate that the principals in this
historical event—viz., the Khedive Ismail,
his Foreign Minister Nubar Pasha, Lord
Derby, and his Under-Seoretary for State—are
all dead and cannot therefore testify, on Sir K
Stanton's behalf. I may mention, however,
that the official correspondence (Bgypt No. 1,
1876), which can be seen by any one who
wishes to do so, absolutely disproves the truth
of Mr. Greenwood’s statement, and makes it
clear that the Government were satisfied with
Sir Edward Stanton’s aotion in the matter.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>LAND & MORTGAGE COMPANY.
The following is the report of the directors to
be presented at the twenty-fifth annual general
meeting of the company, at Cannon-Street
Station Hotel, London, E.C., on Friday-next, 19ih
inst : —In presenting the twenty fifth annual
report of the oompany, together with the
balance sheet and accounts for the year ended
31st March, 1905, the directors are gratified at
being able to state that the result of the year’s
operations justifies them in recommending
payment of a dividend for the whole year at
tho rate of 10 per cent., being an increase of
one per cent, as compared with the year ended
31st March, 1904. In making this announce-
ment the directors are carrying out the policy
they explained to shareholders last year, viz.,
that the reserve account having been brought
up to £50,000 (exclusive of the reserve capital
of £25,180) it was their intention to distribute
the bulk of the year’s earnings among the
shareholders. The gross earnings for the past
year amount to £44,291 9s. 8d., as against
£43,426 13s. 2d. for the preceding year, and
the net earnings to £17,039 7s. 5d., as against
£17,062 la 7d. The gross earnings for the
year amount to£44,291 9s. 8d. Deducting total
expenditure, including interest on debenture
bonds, £27,202 2s. 3d., the net earnings for
the year are £17,089 7s. Od., to which add
balance brought forward from last year’s ac-
count, £2,400 8s. 2d., making £19,48915s. 7d.
Deducting amount of interim dividend paid
on the 12th Nov., 1904, £6,750 Os. 8d., the
balance to credit of profit and loss is
£12,739 15a 7<L The directors have placed
£2,000 to reserve for contingencies, and
granted £350 to the staff’s provident fund,
leaving available a balance of £10,389 16a 7d.
Out of this they recommend that a dividend
of Per cent for the past six months
be declared, which with the 47 per cent paid
in November will make a dividend of 10 per
cent for the year. This will absorb £8,250,
leaving the sum of £2,189 15a 7<L to be
carried forward.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>A RELIC OF GORDON.
Addressing the Royal Geographical Society
last week on "The Nile Provinoe of Western
Uganda," Lieut Colonel C. Delme-Radcliffe
said when he took over the oivil and military
charge of the Nile District from Colonel Martyr
he found the parapet and ditches of Emin
Pasha's old station at Wadelai on the left
bank, in a foir state of preservation, though
the buildings had disappeared. The natives
remembered Emin well. Of Gordon only a few
natives seemed to know anything, though most
of those living near the river had heard of
“Godun,” as he was called, and an interesting
relic had been secured in the shape of an
Austrian bentwood chair, which Gordon had
given to the chief Gimorro. The chair was to
be seen in a room adjoining the lecture
theatre.</p>
<p>Tie American Manufacturers Agency
wishes to advise having received a fresh ass-
-ignment ot Roll-top Desks, Morris Chain,
Sewing Machines, cartridges, Typewriters and
various other American goods. Rue da l’An-
cienne Boon®.	25878-8-5-806</p>
<p>The Standard Life Assurance Company.
B8TABI.I8 HKD 1886,
ACCUMULATED FUNDS £11,300,000
BONUS YEAR, 1005.
THX NEXT DIVISION OF PROFITS wUl be made eUKmjtt 'penldpeCg Polkdee In	UllUi November ISO*
JU TFUk PrejU F'lieiM i/tUd n #r k^fkrt lk*t miU *, ntuUd U -1— tm Ue ritiiiln
SEVEN MILLIONS STERLING.
Hoad Office lor Egypt: Hharla Hnnr-el-Nll, Cairo.
B. NATHAN A Oo.,	A. V. THOMSON
for Aleztmdria,	Secretory for z’rypt.
S. & H. HARRIS’
HARNESS composition
(Waterproof).
SADDLE PASTE
(WnUrpjocI) |W Saddle., Irew. Hu.
nem, and nil Brows Leather Artiale*.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>JET BLACK OIL
HARNESS COMPOSITION	BLACK DYE
SADDLE PASTE	“•
(Waterproof). Fer Saddle., Brown Ear.	SADDLE SOAP
Bern, and all Brows Leather Article..	For Gleaning Saddle^ Brown Haroeau
JET BLACK OIL	l^W boou, *».
Tor Hunan.	0 EBONITE BLACKING
H	(Waterproof).
HARNESS LIQUID.	|] CURRIER'S DUBBING.
The "RAVEN" HARNESS COMPOSITION (Waterproof).
Specially adapted for Warm Climates.
Manufactory. lnONPON, E. (engl*kno.)
SPORT AND PLAY.
KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.
REGATTA.
The following is to-morrow’s handicap
Class I.
Boat	Time of Star
Minnie .................... 2.50
Jennie .................... 2.53
May ....................... 2.55
Celtio ................... 2.56
Coot ..................... 2.57
Tier el Mina ............. 2.58
Time of Start.
2.50
2.53
2.55
2.56
2.57
Leman \
Agamy/
Banshee
Class II.
3.02
3.06
3.07
Cheap Prepaid Advertisements
A DVKRTI8ING AGENTS.—The best publio
Advertising sitae in Alexandria belong to
G. Vestri & Co., Advt Agents, St Cathenne’s
Sinara. Special rates for permanent clients
oderate terms. Prompt despatch.
25642-31-12-905
ARABIC LB8S0NSgiven by on I
^ tntor to Europeans. Apply M.
‘ ‘Egyptian Gazette’ offices.
8.19
326
3.49
Derphil/ ............... AU7
Rosamund................ 3.14
Jessica ................ 8.16
asm .................... 818
Ironic ................. 8.19
Tantah j
Shamrock [.............. 8.24
Gum rook j
8UJt»>g.}	........ 385
Oalypso ................ 3.34
Laurea ................. 3.49
Class I. Coarse E.
Class II. Course A.
The attention of members sailing in Class I
is particularly called to Course E, which is
a new course and totally different to last
year.</p>
<p>Owing to his Highness the Khedive leaving
for Europe earlier than was at first intended,
viz., on the 25th inst, the regatta to be given
in his honor has been postponed until his re-
turn to Alexandria.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>TENNIS MATCH.
A tennis match will take place between
the Khedivial Sporting Club and the Alex-
andria Sporting Club at the AS. C. grounds
on Friday, 18th inst.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CRICKET.
A cricket match will be played on Saturday
next, 20th inst, between a Garrison XL and
the Alexandria Cricket Club, on the ground
of the latter, commencing at 1.30 p.m. sharp.</p></div>
<p>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB (ALEX.)
The2nd spoon competition of the season
was shot off on Saturday last under fairly
favorable weather conditions. The following
are some of the qualifying boo res :—
1st Class.
Mjh. »♦ j*. MOjk Mil
Dickson H. P.	33 + 33 +	80 = 91
Waddington H.	31 + 89 +	80 = 93t
	2hd Class.	
Allen D.	99 + 24 +	23 = 76t
Smith G.	26 + 90 +	29 = 76
	3rd Class.	
lias A. G.	96 + 30 +	24 = 80t
Radoliffe L. E.	82 + 91 +	22 = 75
Millar F. G.	99 + 20 +	23 = 72
Lovell G. D.	18 + 28 +	18 = 64
Robertson C.	21 + 34 +	17 = 62
Broomfield J.	19 + 18 +	16 = 58
• Penalised 5	t Winners.
Mr. H. Waddington won the N. R. A.
bronze badge, also the Milton gold badge.
Others fired for the silver and bronze badges,
but did not qualify.</p>
<p>Mr. H. F. Dickson, having previously won
the N. R. A bronze badge, was not able to
again compete. He was also penalised 5 points
in the spoon competition, having won the
first of the season.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SCHOOLBOYS’ RACE.
A race from Sidi Gaber to Alexandria, by
pupils of the Sootoh School, will take place
on Saturday next commencing at 6 a.m.
The first prize is to be a silver medal, and
there will be two other prizes. There are
nine entries so for. The youngest boy is
about 11 and the oldest 17 or 18. They
have been training for about three months,
and can do the distance easily in twenty
minutes. They will start from the railway
crossing at Sidi Gaber and finish at the
sobool doot in rue Pereyra (Mleeall*),
A FPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German,
to the Berlitz Schools, Alexandria (26,
Rue de l’Egliae Copte); Cairo Sharia Kamel),
Most rapid method Trial lesson free. Evening
olasses at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per mbnth.
23069-30-9A-905</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9, No. 7
A* £ll. W.T. Kmmens, 99 Rue Attarine,
Alexandria, Address, Poet Office Box 85.
30-6-905a</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EXPERIENCED NURSE would take charge
J-i of infant for free passage to England
June, July. Apply, No. 25,949, "Egyptian
Gazette” Office.	26949-6-3
R SALK—Cart, Donkey, and Harness.
£25. Apply, No. 26,952, "Egyptian
tte” Offioe.	25962-6-3
GENUINE PANAMA HATS for sales, very
good quality, very cheap. At Mal-
luk’s, Mouoky, Cairo.	26969-12-2
MOUNTAIN CAMP, for boys during sum-
Hl- mer holidays. Apply, Percival Mayall,
B.A, Headmaster, English School, Cyprus.
25921-48-8
TUTOR WANTED for two English children.
A" £24. Apply, No. 25,972, " Egyptian
Gazette” offices.	25792-6-1
SINGING LESSONS recommended by the
famous tenor Jean db Res zee given by
Herr B. Woe haler of Heidelberg University.
Voice production systematic. Apply for trial
lesson, press extracts, Herr B. Wechsler, Post
Office, Cairo.	25929-12-7
CELL CHEAP.— Engine Press, etc.; best
kJ condition ; presses hundred bales daily
easily. No. 25,939 “Egyptian Gazette” offices. I
25939-6-5 I
[’0 LET.—Furnished house with five rooms, I
1- situated in the best quarter of Alexandria, {
T°j
rLET, on very moderate terms, a Stable
at Bulkeley. Apply, Manager, Carlton
Hotel.	2597U-S-1
A Electric light; bath. Independent en-
trance. English, Poste Res tan te, Cairo. 26965-6-1
rLET at Alexandria, off Rosette-road, for
the summer, a large, airy, roomy, Fur-
nished House ; eight rooms ; garden ; terms
moderate. For particulars apply, Magaains
Victoria, Alexandria.	269b3-6-l</p></body>
<div type="item"><p>TTNEDAME ANGLAISE offre ses services
pour le massage tant recomand par beau-1
ooup de dootears, massage de figure bgalemeht j
pour en effaoer las rides et rendre an corps et
a figure la fraloheur et la santd de la jeuueese ;
striotement secret; prix mod^rds. S’adresser j
No 26,962 “Egyptian Gazette.” 26962-8-2 .
TIT ANTED at Port Sudan, for Government
TI Works, a typewriting English Clerk, I
salary L.E. 16 per menaum. Applications in I
writing to Asst. Director of Works, War'
Office, Cairo.	25966-1
ANTED at Port Sudan, for Government
»» Works, an estimating Draughtsman,
salary L.E. 18 per menaum. Applications in '
writing to Asst Direotor of Works, War;
Office, Cairo.	96967-1</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>YOUNG ENGLISH LADY desires situation
A Resident Governess, in Alexandria or
Ramleh j oan teach musio. Apply, No. 96,978
,‘Egyptian Quetta" offices.	958784-1
DAVIES
BRYAN
& Co.
CAIRO,
St. David’s Buildings,
ALEXANDRIA,
and 35 - 37 Noble Street
LONDON, E.O.</p>
<p>English Tailors
Drapers
and Outfitters.
Beg respectedly;to an-
nounce that they have
received their various
stocks in the latest
styles suitable for the
present Season.
e&OTBt:
A large assortment of
Blacks, Blues, Scotch,
Irish & Harris Tweeds.
All garments cut by ex-
perienced English Cut-
ters, fit and style gua-
ranteed.
A varied stock of
Ladies’ Blouses, Boas,
Skirts, Belts, &c.
Careful attention is
suitable for Tours up
the Nile.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>GENTS’
OUTFITTING:
Thelatest novelties inTies,
Collars, Shirts, Gloves, &c.
Hosiery in all the newest
makes, (Camel Hair brand
a speciality).
We are also making a special display
in the Drapery Department, con-
sisting of Household Linen, Blan-
kets, Caliooes, Eider-dovrn Quilts,
Cushions,&o.,&o., which are mark-
ed at such figures as to command
attention.
Boots & Shoes in the latest
shapes, Bags, Trunks & all
Leather goods in great va-
riety. __
Also a large assorted supply"of the
following articles.’—
HATS, CAPS, UMBRELLAS,
WALK!NO-STICKS, RUQ8,
STUDS, BRUSHES AMD ALL
TOILET REQUI8ITE8. AC.
Davies Bryan & Co.
Cairo & Alexandria.</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

