<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>John White</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-01">October 1, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-06-01">June 1, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7203] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JUNE 1 [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, JUNE 1, 1905.</head></div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE NAVAL BATTLE.
                FURTHER DETAILS.
                THE RUSSIAN LOSSES.
                RODJESTVENSKY WOUNDED.</head>
          
                <p>St. Petersburg, May 31.</p>
                <p>General Linievitch forwarded on the 29th inst. a report of the commander of the
                    cruiser "Almaz" which was only published yesterday evening. It says that the
                    battleships “Knyaz Suvaroff," "Borodino,” “Osliabia," and the cruiser "Ural”
                    were sunk during Saturday’s fighting. After the "Almaz" had left the fleet, the
                    battle was resumed in the darkness and the "Almaz,’’ being unable to rejoin the
                    squadron, proceeded to Vladivostok. The details of subsequent fighting are
                    unknown.</p>
                <p>The “Almaz" had 5 killed and 10 wounded.</p>
                <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                <p>Shanghai, May 31.</p>
                <p>The transport “Korea" arrived at Wusung pierced by several projectiles, and all
                    her boats were shot away. She escaped directly the Japanese appeared, but was
                    struck by several shells before she got out of range. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>London, May 31.</p>
                <p>The "Daily Express" learns from Tokio that the Russian cruiser "Gromoboi,” in
                    leaving Vladivostok, apparently hoping to join Admiral Rodjestvensky’s fleet,
                    struck a Japanese mine and foundered with all hands.</p>
                <p>The “Daily Mail" learns from Tokio that when the "Kniaz Suvaroff" sank, Admiral
                    Rodjestvensky went on board another vessel, but was captured off Fumi yesterday,
                    severely wounded in the arm. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>Tokio, May 31.</p>
                <p>Admiral Togo’s report confirms the capture of a Russian torpedo-boat on the 27th
                    inst., with Rodjestvensky and another Admiral seriously wounded on board.</p>
                <p>The total Russian losses amount to twenty-two ships. The Japanese losses are
                    unknown.</p>
                <p>(Havas.)</p>
                <p>Tokio, May 31.</p>
                <p>(Official). Admiral Rodjestvensky and another Admiral, both severely wounded, and
                    numerous Staff officers were captured on board the destroyer "Boevoi." The
                    Japanese losses are not yet determined but it is believed that no ship has been
                    seriously damaged. The first division lost about 400 men and Admiral Misu is
                    wounded. The Russians lost altogether 22 ships with an aggregate tonnage of
                    153,411 tons. The battle and pursuit lasted from Saturday morning until Monday
                    morning. The Japanese were unrelaxing in their efforts until they had gathered
                    in the whole prey.</p>
                <p>Admiral Rodjestvensky has arrived at the Sasebo hospital.</p>
                <p>The Japanese loss during the battle was only three torpedo-boats. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>St. Petersburg, May 31.</p>
                <p>The torpedo-boat "Bravi" arrived at Vladivostok with 200 survivors from the
                    "Osliaba."</p>
                <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                <p>St. Petersburg, June 1.</p>
                <p>The destroyer "Razyashtchi" has arrived at Vladivostok.</p>
                <p>The Admiralty denies the news that the cruiser "Gromoboi” foundered in
                    quitting</p>
                <p>Vladivostok. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>Tokio, June 1.</p>
                <p>Two hospital-ships have been seized and taken to Sasebo on the suspicion that
                    they took a strategic part in the battle. (Reuter )</p>
                <p>Tokio, June 1.</p>
                <p>Admiral Rodjestvensky's forehead is fractured, necessitating an operation, but he
                    is expected to recover. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>RUSSIAN PRESS AND THE DEFEAT.</head>
            
                <p>IN FAVOUR OF PEACE.</p>
                <p>St. Petersburg, May 31.</p>
                <p>The defeat of the Baltic fleet has given a fresh impetus to the clamour of the
                    Russian newspapers fur representative institutions. The liberal organs are not
                    hesitating to attack the Government, declaring that the bureaucracy has crowned
                    the work of national dishonor.</p>
                <p>The "Sviet” is the only paper which is in favor of continuing the war. The
                    “Novoye Vreyrna" declares that the situation demands 'the immediate convocation
                    of a representative assembly.</p>
                <p>Admiral Alexeieff conferred with the Tsar to-day regarding the situation.
                    (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>St. Petersburg, May 31</p>
                <p>The Press is unanimous in showing up the mistakes committed in the conduct of the
                    war, and calls for the immediate convocation of a representative national
                    assembly. (Havas.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>NEW LIBERAL ORGAN</head>
                <p>LONDON, May 31.</p>
                <p>A company has been formed with a capital of 300,000 pounds to start a penny
                    morning paper here It will be an official Liberal organ and will be named "The
                    Tribune". (Reuter. )</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>ATLANTIC YACHT RACE</head>
                <p>London, May 31</p>
                <p>In the Atlantic yacht race the German yacht 'Hamburg" arrived second and the
                    British "Valhalla" third. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PARIS BOMB OUTRAGE.ATTEMPT  ON KING ALFONSO'S LIFE</head>
            
                <p>Paris, May 31.</p>
                <p>A detonation was heard at midnight just as King Alfonso was leaving the Opera
                    House. Neither the King nor M. Loubet was hurt.</p>
                <p>(Havas.)</p>
                <p>Paris, June 1.</p>
                <p>As King Alfonso and M. Loubet were returning from the Opera last night a man
                    dressed like a workman threw a bomb. The cuirassier officers riding on both
                    sides of the carriage were thrown from their horses and bruised. One horse was
                    killed and 6 were injured. Three policemen, a woman, and a child were wound-, ed
                    and taken to the hospital.</p>
                <p>The King and President Loubet were unhurt.</p>
                <p>The thrower of the bomb was arrested. (R.)</p>
                <p>An attempt on King Alfonso's life had been expected by the Parisian police.
                    Yesterday-week they arrested seven Anarchists, two of whom had been entrusted
                    with the carrying out of an attempt against the life of King Alfonso during his
                    stay in Paris. The men were lodged in prison. Five of them refused to give any
                    account of themselves, but the other two asserted that they bad arrived with the
                    intention of assassinating the King of Spain.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>DERBY</head>
            
                <p>WON IN RECORD TIME.</p>
                <p>London, May 31.</p>
                <p>1, Cicero ; 2, Jardv ; 3, Signorino.</p>
                <p> Betting. 4 to 11 against Cicero : -4 to 1 .Jardy ; 50 to 1 Signorino ; 33 to 1
                    Blue Streak. Cicero Won by 3/4 of a length. One head between 2nd and 3rd. Time 2
                    minutes 29 2/5. This is a record. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>HOME CRICKET</head>
                <p>London, May 31.</p>
                <p>Australians all out for 221 runs. Cotter 45. England 318 runs for 5 wickets.
                    Tyldesley 61. MacLaren 140. (Reuter.)</p>
                <p>London, May 31.</p>
                <p>England 426 runs for 5 wickets. The innings was declared closed. Jackson 82 runs
                    not out.</p>
                <p>Australian’s second innings 188. Gregory 51. Analysis, Bosanquet 8 wickets for
                    105 runs. England beat Australia by 213 runs.</p>
                <p>Oxford University beat Kent by 51 runs. Leicestershire beat M.C.C. by 202 runs.
                    Sussex beat Northamptonshire by 8 wickets.</p>
                <p>Yorkshire beat Worcestershire by 203 runs. The match between Cambridge University
                    and Surrey has been drawn. (Reuter.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Khalifa district of Cairo during the night
                    of Saturday and at daylight on Sunday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                <p>Lots Turcs.—The Imperial Ottoman Bank informs us that the gros lot at yesterday’s
                    drawing of the Ottoman Railway Lottery-bonds was won by the holder of bond No.
                    120,289.</p>
                <p>Hellenic Fleet. — The sum of £8,000, which had been collected in Egypt towards
                    the funds for the increase of the Hellenic Fleet, has been sent to Athens
                    through the Greek Diplomatic Agency.</p>
                <p>New Maltese Band.—The first meeting of the promoters of the “New National Maltese
                    Band" will take place on Sunday next in the hall of the Maltese Benevolent
                    Society, 4, Trieste street, when the band will be definitely formed and a
                    committee appointed.</p>
                <p>H.M.S. “Juno," Captain Christian, R.N., convoying the Admiralty dredger “St.
                    Lawrence," arrived at Alexandria to-day from Malta. Mr. E. B. Gould, I.S.O.,
                    H.B.M.’s Consul-General, introduced Captain Christian to H;E. the Governor of
                    Alexandria this morning.</p>
                <p>Suez Canal. — 18 vessels passed through the Canal on the 27th and 28th May, of
                    which 8 were British 1 Norwegian, 4 German, 1 Italian, 2 French, 1 Dutch, 1
                    Turkish. The receipts for the two days were frs. 575,525:94, making the total
                    from 1stMay frs. 8,491,069.55,</p>
                <p>Attempted Suicide.—Yesterday an old native, 60 years of ago, tried to commit
                    suicide by throwing himself into Alexandria harbour. He was rescued before life
                    was extinct and on being questioned declared "that he wanted to make away with
                    himself to escape a load of debt.</p>
                <p>Fight on the Bourse.—Shortly after midday to-day the Alexandria Bourse was the
                    scene of a serious encounter with fisticuffs between two well known young
                    Greeks. One of them was much injured about the face and blood flowed freely. The
                    encounter caused considerable excitement. </p>
                <p>Fire at Zagazig.- On Tuesday night, at 11 o'clock, a fire broke out in the bullet
                    at Zagazig station. The Moudir, Schalch Bey, Commandant of the Port-Said Police,
                    and Mr. Langley, of the Irrigation Department, directed the efforts of the fire
                    brigade and the fire was extinguished after some trouble.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE COTTON CUT WORM</head>
                <p>INTERESTING EXPERIMENTS.</p>
                <p>Some interesting and successful experiments in trying to combat the cotton cut
                    worm (Agro tis Ypsilan) have been carried out at Kharaba, on the lands of the
                    Aboukir Company. The Khedivial Agricultural Society sent their entomologist, Mr.
                    Willcocks, to examine a method of dealing with the pest proposed by Mr.
                    Richmond, and we understand that Mr. Willcocks was to impressed with the system
                    employed that he strongly urged the society to arrange for experiments to be
                    carried out in the Behera province, where this particular pest causes so much
                    damage to the young cotton. The same worm has this year also cleared off a great
                    part of the berseem which was left to seed. Unfortunately the society have
                    postponed putting the method to further practical tests till next year, although
                    there was plenty of time to act on their entomologist’s advice.</p>
                <p>Mr. Richmond’s method of dealing with the pest is based on making the cotton
                    fields distasteful to the female moth, so as to prevent her laying her eggs on
                    the cotton fields or at the roots of the young plants. To do this he advises
                    that with the first watering which is given to the fields after sowing the seed,
                    two to three gallons of petroleum should be applied for each feddan.</p>
                <p>The simplest method of applying the petroleum is to bore a tiny hole in the
                    bottom of a full 33 lb. tin containing 4 gallons and place the tin on a board at
                    the point where the water is being run on to the field. The petroleum falls in a
                    tiny stream or almost in drops on to the running water and is quite sufficient
                    to make the necessary film.</p>
                <p>As the irrigation water sinks into the soil it leaves behind it a very fine film
                    of petroleum, which is most distasteful to the moth, whilst it does no harm to
                    the germinating cotton. This is prevention of attack and for that reason a very
                    valuable precaution.</p>
                <p>The greatest damage is done a few days after the plant makes its appearance above
                    ground, when the stem is very thin and easily gnawed through by the caterpillar.
                    With the second watering the petroleum should be applied in the same quantity
                    and manner as previously. After the second watering the plants quickly become
                    strong enough to withstand stem attacks, which are the most fatal.</p>
                <p>The petroleum film on the fields should kill any eggs and newly hatched
                    caterpillars with which it comes in contact. This may be called cure, of a value
                    only second to prevention. The method is a very simple one, very cheap, and can
                    be applied by any cultivator. Petroleum can be obtained in any village in Egypt
                    at about P.T. 10 per tin. Half a tin will do a feddan, and the sole instructions
                    to the fellah are to make a very small hole with a pin. The experiments are to
                    be continued in the autumn on the young berseem crop, which is generally badly
                    attacked by Agrotis at Aboukir if the berseem is sown early.</p>
                <p>From caterpillars collected at Kharaba Mr. Richmond finds that the chrysalis
                    stage is 14 days and the presumption is that there are a succession of broods
                    during the summer.</p>
                <p>It is interesting to note that two of the caterpillars which were being watched
                    were badly attacked by parasites which appeared to bo the larva of an Ichneumon
                    fly. Those larva bored their way out of the bodies of the two caterpillars and
                    spun small yellowish white cocoons for themselves. Both caterpillars attacked by
                    the parasites died, being unable to turn themselves into pupae. The cocoons of
                    Ichneumon flys should on no account be destroyed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE NUBARIEH CANAL</head>
                <p>The Ministry of Public Works has issued the following notice in regard to the
                    prolongation of the Nubarieh Canal :—</p>
                <p>“In order to put the public on their guard against certain statements to the
                    effect that the Government had the intention of shortly prolonging the Nubarieh
                    Canal, the Ministry of Public Works hereby declares that any undertaking for the
                    extension of the canal, if t is executed, will only bo carried into effect in
                    any case in the distant future.”</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE UPPER NILE</head>
                <p>Major P. Powell Cotton, late 5th Batn. Northumberland Fusiliers, the African ex plorer, who is on an expedition from the Nile to the Zambesi, has been heard of again. Ho left the Lado Enclave for the Congo Forest at the end of February, and arrived on the 29th April at Wadelai— allwell. Major Powell-Cotton is travelling all alone, having only a bodyguard of natives, who will follow him anywhere, such is their admiration for the "kind white chief." The gallant explorer's methods are always those of peace and goodwill.</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                <p>The Ellerman S. S. “Bulgarian” sailed from Liverpool on Tuesday for Gibraltar,
                    Malta, and Alexandria.</p>
                <p>The Moss liner "Seti" arrived in England yesterday.</p>
                <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Congo” arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria
                    yester-1 day morning.</p>
                <p>The Moss liner "Rameses” sailed from Malta yesterday and is due here on Sunday
                    morning with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                <p>The S. S. "Royal Prinoe,” from Manchester, left Malta this morning and is due
                    here on Sunday evening next, with passengers and general cargo.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>THE SUEZ CANAL</head>
                <p>DIVIDEND AND DISSATISFACTION.</p>
                <p>A London correspondent writes:—</p>
                <p>Considerable dissatisfaction is expressed in shipping circles at the decision of
                    the directors of the Suez Canal Company to pay a dividend of 28 per cent. on
                    account of 1904, as against 26 per cent. for the previous year. It had been
                    hoped that the increase in net profits during the past twelve months would have
                    been devoted entirely to the reduction of the dues charged on vessels using the
                    Canal. The addition of 2 per cent. to the shareholders’ dividend knocks this
                    idea on the head, and if the present charge of 8.50 francs per ton is reduced to
                    7.75 francs shipowners will think themselves lucky, for the generosity of the
                    company may even fall short of this small concession. Indeed, I should not be
                    surprised if the reduction is only to 8 francs per ton. Such a decision might be
                    regarded with favor by some of the shareholders, but I fancy that in the end the
                    directors would regret their niggardliness.</p>
                <p>As to whether the redaction is likely to be maintained, a high authority in the
                    shipping world said to a Press representative last week: —-"In 1906 the Canal
                    Company are going to lose 10,000,000fr. in consequence of this reduction , and
                    it is a question whether or not such a loss can be continued. The company are
                    taking considerable risk in the interests of the shipping trade—certainly not in
                    the interest of their own shareholders.</p>
                <p>The proposed redaction is 75o. per ton, which is equal to a reduction of
                    10,000,000fr. or £400,000. The arrangement is just part and parcel of the London
                    programme, and is by no means in consequence of the agitation which was set on
                    foot a short time ago."</p>
                <p>On the other hand there are shipping authorities who hold the view that the 75c.
                    reduction is distinctly the outcome of the recent agitation.</p>
                <p>“At first," said one of these gentlemen to the representative, "they only talked
                    of a 25c. reduction, but, ultimately, a little sop of 75c. was suggested.</p>
                <p>"The company are paying 28 per cent dividend on the shares, which is a breach of
                    the London agreement All profit over 25 per cent., according to the terms of
                    that arrangement, ought to go to a reduction of the tonnage dues, and if that
                    were adhered to in all probability the rates would be brought down 2fr. or
                    3fr.</p>
                <p>"The agreement to which I refer was between M. de Lesseps on the one hand, and
                    the London Committee of Shipowners on the other. This is a clean, logical
                    agreement, and would, nodoubt, hold good at law. It is a great deal more than an
                    'honorable understanding.’</p>
                <p>"I learnt the other day from a gentleman of exceptionally high authority on these
                    matters that the only explanation which can be given for men like those at the
                    head of the Canal Company's affairs—including representatives of the British
                    Government—practically breaking their word, lies in the fact that they have
                    discovered that the London agreement, if adhered to, would place them in the
                    position of fiduciary legatees. Still, the code of honor that regulates private
                    firms should apply in the case of great companies.</p>
                <p>“The company might have come to the shipowners and said, ‘We are in a mess—we
                    must have this agreement altered.’ The shipowners, who have shown every
                    disposition to be reasonable, would, no doubt, have consented to discuss the
                    matter. Instead of that they have ridden rough-shod over everyone.</p>
                <p>“As to the enforcement of the agreement, where is the court to enforce it ? The
                    shipowners would have to go to France, and in an international affair of this
                    kind they ought to have their own Government with them. The Government, however,
                    at this time are sitting on the fence.”</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA</head>
                <p>The preliminary articles of association of the Bank of Abyssinia wore signed by Sir Elwin Palmer, Messrs. F. T. Rowlatt, D. McGillivray, Bohor Naggar, Raphael Finzi, Humbert Ebano, and Alfred Vulliet. The bank will concern itself with banking, commercial, industrial, and financial business specially in Abyssinia, and with the consent of the Government will be able to issue notes and coin money. The capital is 100,000 shares of £5 each all of which has been fully subscribed. The chief office of the bank will bo at Adis Abeba, but its "siege social" will be at Cairo.</p></div>
            <div type="item"><head>NEW NILE NAVIGATION CO.</head>
                <p>The Delta and Upper Egypt Nile Naviga-Company has been formed with a capital of 10,000 shares of £4 each, all fully subscribed by the following Messrs. Ph. Th. Fotia-dis &amp; Co., 3,125; Ph. Th. Fotiadis, 1,225; Ant. E. Benachi, 1,250 ; Const J. Choremi, 1,375; Etienne Delta, 1,250; Const A. Pringos, 1,025; Michel Mavrogordatos, 750. The seat of the company will bo at Alexandria. Its objects are evident from its title.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>MORE NEW COMPANIES.</head>
                <p>Two new companies are announced with a capital of one million pounds sterling apiece. "London Opinion,” of May  24, says :—There is a crop of new Egyptian land, industrial, And mining ventures coming along. Two of them are to have a capital of a million each ; one to act as a kind of General Mining and Finance Corporation for Egypt, and the other as a Land, Agricultural, and Trading concern.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>NEW ROUTE TO EGYPT</head>
                <p>ROUMANIAN STEAMSHIP COMPANY</p>
                <p>The Roumanian Steamship Company has ordered a new steamer for the
                    Constanza-Alex-andria line at the Chantiers de La Loire at Saint Nazaire. The
                    vessel, which is to cost frs. 2,340,000, will be the finest in the company’s
                    fleet. She is to be named the "Emperor Trajan."</p>
                <p>The new line to Alexandria is an extension of the Constanza-Constantinople-Athens
                    service. This route has lately been brought into prominence owing to the new
                    Constanza-Constantinople cable, which is of great economio importance. By this
                    means, telegraphic correspondence will be increased both between Berlin and Constantinople, on the one hand, and between Scutari,
                    Angora, Mossul, Baghdad, Basra, and Fao on the other.</p>
                <p>As regards mails, if the Constanza rente is adopted instead of the Brindisi line,
                    the distance will be considerably shortened between Europe and Asia Minor,
                    especially when the Baghdad railway is completed. There is now a rapid line of
                    steamers between Constanza and Constantinople, and the Roumanian Government
                    intends to extend the Athens line to Alexandria.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS</head>
                <p>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</p>
                <p>By kind permission of Major C. J. L. Davidson, D.S.O., commanding, and officers
                    2nd Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers the Band will perform the following selection
                    of music Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Friday) at 9 p.m. :—</p>
                <p>1 March--Greetings to Egypt-Tobisch.</p>
                <p>2 Air de Ballet-Les toiles- Eaton.</p>
                <p>3 Overture-Masaniello—Auber.</p>
                <p>4 Song-Still wie die Nacht--Bohm.</p>
                <p>5 Selection- Reminiscence of All Nations—A. Godfrey.</p>
                <p>9 Valse-Amoretten Tanze—Gung'l</p>
                <p>7 Musical Idyl—The Smithy in the Wood—Michaelis.</p>
                <p>8 Polka-Toujours Galant Fahrbach.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
          
                <p>H.H. Prince Abbas Halim Pasha and suite left for Constantinople yesterday by
                    the</p>
                <p>Lord Dormer arrived at Port Said from England yesterday by the Brindisi mail.</p>
                <p>Hassan Mohsen Pasha and the Princess Mohsen and daughter are leaving by Austrian
                    Lloyd’s S.S. “Cleopatra” on Saturday next for Trieste en route to the Tyrol.
                    They rill return to Alexandria in October.</p>
                <p>M. Jacques Lebaudy, the “Emperor of the Sahara," is said to have been camping in
                    the desert at Helouan.</p>
                <p>Captain the Hon. C. James, Assistant Financial Secretary, Egyptian Army, has been
                    transferred to the Ministry of the Interior, with pay at the rate of L.E 450 per
                    annum, from the 6th Jane.</p>
                <p>H.H. the Khedive has been most graciously pleased to confer the grade of Sanieh
                    on Mohamed Labib Bey, formerly Mamour, Kous Markaz, Keneh, now on pension.</p>
                <p>H.H. the Khedive has been graciously pleased to confer the rank of Commander (3rd
                    class) of the Order of the Medjidieh on Langlois Bey, late of the Railway
                    Administration.</p>
                <p>Mr. Boyd Carpenter, first inspector of the Ministry of Public Instruction, is
                    acting as Secretary-General of the Ministry during the absence of Mr. Douglas
                    Dunlop.</p>
                <p>Bimbashi C. Cobbe, Assistant-Commandant of Police, Alexandria City, has been
                    granted the local rank of Kaimakam.</p>
                <p>Mr. M. Moberly, Inspector in the Ministry of the Interior, has been appointed
                    Assistant Commandant of Police, Cairo City, and has been granted the local rank
                    of Kaimakam. The appointment dates from the 21st March.</p>
                <p>Dr. Elie Vassilavo has been authorised to practise in Egypt.</p>
                <p>Mr. Paul Cavafy, who has been very greatly indisposed for some time past, is, we
                    are glad to bear, now convalescent, and has resumed his official duties at the
                    Alexandria Municipality.</p>
                <p>The Malta correspondent of the "New York Herald," writing on Saturday week, says
                    :— A gloom has been cast over the island to-day by the death of Mrs. Balbi, wife
                    of Major Balbi, of the Royal Malta Artillery. Though she had only recently
                    arrived from Egypt, she had already become one of the best liked women in Malta.
                    Mrs. Balbi died of Mediterranean fever, after a very short illness.”</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item">
                <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
                <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                <p>x.10.904</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item"><head>SPORT AND PLAY</head>
                <p>PORT AND PLAY.</p>
                <p>ALEXANDRIA CRICKET CLUB.</p>
                <p>MATCH WITH LONDON COUNTY </p>
                <p>Members are informed that a match has been arranged between the London County and
                    Egypt, at the Crystal Palace, on the 9th and 10th of August. Any members of the
                    club who will be in England at that time, and are anxious to play, are requested
                    to send their names and home addresses, as soon as possible, to Mr. G.
                    Scott-Dalgleish, for selection.</p>
                <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</p>
                <p>REGATTA.</p>
                <p>The following is the result of yesterday’s regatta.</p>
                <p>Class I.</p>
                <p>Boat Start Finish. Sailed by</p>
                <p>1 Minnie 2.50.40 4.20.40 N.W.deCourcy</p>
                <p>2 Celtic 2.56.12 4.21.17 Mr. Blagden</p>
                <p>3 Banshee 3.06.18 4.24.53 T. McClure</p>
                <p>Agamy 3.09.25 4.26.46 Mr. Ravalli</p>
                <p>Tier el Mina 2.58.07 4.27.00 Capt. Borg </p>
                <p>Leman 3.02.10 4.27.35 M. de Planta</p>
                <p>Jenny 2.53.20 gave up S. Dorling</p>
                <p>The result therefore of the points scored during the last three races was as
                    follows: </p>
                <p>Coot 1 + 1 + 0 = 2</p>
                <p>Leman 4 + 1 + 1 = 6</p>
                <p>Celtic 3 + 0 + 3 = 6</p>
                <p>Banshee 1 + 8 + 2 = 6</p>
                <p>Minnie 1 + 1+ 4 = 6</p>
                <p>Jenny 1 + 4 + 0 = 5</p>
                <p>Agamy 0 + 2 + 1 = 8</p>
                <p>Tier el Mina 1+0+1 2</p>
                <p>Coot 1 +1 +0 </p>
                <p>As the first four of the above boats had scored exactly the same number of
                    points, a special race was run to decide the winner, particulars of which are
                    given herewith Start. Finish.</p>
                <p>Banshee 5.20.20 6.02.00</p>
                <p>Leman 5.20.37 6.05.16</p>
                <p>Minnie 5.20.32 6.07.06</p>
                <p>Celtic 5.20.55 6.07.17</p>
                <p>The "Minnie” won on her time allowance</p>
                <p>from the “Banshee.” The course sailed was one round of Course A, the time
                    allowance being therefore halved.</p>
                <p>Class II</p>
                <p>Boat Start. Finish. Sailed by</p>
                <p>1 Gumrook 3.24.44 5.43.18 Mr. Macauley</p>
                <p>2 Masr 3.26.56 5.45.10 „ Francis 3 Shamrock 3.24.28 5.46.25 E. Gentilli</p>
                <p>St George 3.27.30 5.47.40 </p>
                <p>Calypso 3.34.17 5.49.06 0. Werner Akraba 3.18.30 5.50.25 Sagh. Phillips Jessica
                    3.18.25 5.56.23 Grafton Bey As the “Masr” on the three races had</p>
                <p>scored 11 points against the next boat’s 8 she therefore won the prize.</p>
                <p>Next week in Class I. the cup of Chitty Bey will be raced for; in Class II.
                    points will</p>
                <p>be scored as usual.</p>
                <p>The handicap also has been revised. Yesterday there was a moderate breeze
                    from</p>
                <p>the N. N. W.</p>
                <p>DONKEY GYMKHANA.</p>
                <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                <p>Port Said, Wednesday,</p>
                <p>A very successful donkey gymkhana was held at Port Said on Saturday last, under
                    the patronage of H.E. the Governor-General of the Canal, Mustapha Ibady Pasha,
                    and was well attended, there being numerous entries for the various events.
                    Results were as follow:—</p>
                <p>I. Driving race between bottles.—1st, Miss M. Guy and Mr. C. Broatch; 2nd, Mrs.
                    Brown and Mr. Greaves.</p>
                <p>II. Tandem race.—1st, Mr. Guy; 2nd, Dr. Meade ; 3rd, Mr. Norman.</p>
                <p>III. Egg and spoon race.—1st, Mr. Brown , 2nd, Miss Hoole; 3rd, Miss Strange.</p>
                <p>IV. Tie race.—1st, A. Tweedie and Mrs, Stapledon; 2nd, A. V. Wallis and Miss N.
                    Guy.</p>
                <p>V. Face to tail race.—1st, Mr. Guy;2nd, Mr. Parnis; 3rd, Mr. Tunstall.</p>
                <p>VI. Hand in hand race.—1st, A, V. Wallis and Miss M. Guy ; 2nd, J. Norman
                    Yearsley.</p>
                <p>VII. Mathematical race.—1st, J. Thornton and Miss Hoole; 2nd, J. Norman and Mrs.
                    Tweedie ; 3rd, A. Ingram and Mr. Swallow. Mr. Hasse came in an easy first but
                    the addition by Mrs. Stapledon was wrong.</p>
                <p>VIII. Tug-of-war on donkeys.—A.V. Wallis’ team, which won twice against J.
                    Chesman’s team, included Messrs. Tweedie, Tunstall, Warner, Norman, Parnis,
                    Rodger, and Newton.</p>
                <p>IX Extra tug-of-war— Shore team, composed of Messrs. Wallis, Tweedie, Norman and
                    Tunstall, pulled over "Osiris” team after 17 minutes’ hard pull.</p>
                <p>Capt. Hide, R. N. R., of the "Osiris,” acted as judge, Mr. F. Guy as starter, and
                    Mrs. A. J. Tweedie very kindly distributed the prizes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                <p>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</p>
                <p> Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                <p> ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste. </p>
                <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</p>
                <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA. </p>
                <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                    English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern
                    sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens. </p>
                <p>1-48-31</p>
                <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
            </div>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                    Sudan.</p>
                <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>