<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-09">November 9, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-01">July 1, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. ] ALEXANDRIA, MONDAY, JULY 1, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN DISORDERS. </head>
                    <head>MUTINY SPREADING</head>
                    <head>ODESSA BOMBARDED. </head>
                    <head>THE POTEMKIN SURRENDERS </head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Sevastopol, June 30. </dateline>
                        <p>Four battleships, one cruiser and several torpedo boats left here
                            yesterday evening under the command of Admiral Kruger, with orders to
                            sink the “Potemkin” if she refuses to surrender, and then assist in
                            restoring order in town. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Odessa, June 30. </dateline>
                        <p>The "Potemkin” began to bombard the town at 11.30 yesterday evening. The
                            transport "Vecha” has joined the mutineers.</p>
                        <p>The central railway station has been burnt. The funeral of the sailor who
                            was shot for presenting the petition for better food, was a great
                            popular demonstration. There was no disorder. Neither police nor troops
                            were on the route.</p>
                        <p>The burnt ships include the “Saratow” of the Volunteer Fleet.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Libau, June 30. </dateline>
                        <p>The seamen here have mutinied and wrecked the barracks. The Cossacks and
                            artillery have been called out and fighting has ensued, but there are no
                            details. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>ODESSA, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Nine vessels have been burned, but it is believed that none of them were
                            British. Machine guns were used to clear the streets. Two more regiments
                            have arrived. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>St. Petersburg, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>It is reported that a mutiny has broken out at Cronstadt, and that the
                            sailors have stoned a number of officers. The troops at Peterhof, where
                            the Tsar is, have been reinforced. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Washington, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>The American Consul at Odessa telegraphs that the fleet arrived at noon,
                            and that the "Potemkin” surrendered without firing a shot. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Odessa, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Martial law has been proclaimed.</p>
                        <p>The funeral of the sailor, whose death was the cause of the mutiny, took
                            place yesterday. The police did not make an appearance.</p>
                        <p>Owing to the arrest of the sailors, the "Potemkin” bombarded the town.
                            The sailors were released. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE “PERESVIET” REFLOATED.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Port Arthur, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>The battleship “Peresviet” has been refloated here. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head>
                    <head>EARLY SETTLEMENT EXPECTED.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Paris, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>It is announced that M. Rouvier will hand a note to Prince Radolin to-day
                            accepting the conference regarding Morocco. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Paris, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>It is expected that the Franco-German incident will be settled next week.
                            (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT’S JUDICIAL REFORM.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>Paris, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>The Chamber of Deputies has agreed to the prolongation of the judicial
                            reform in Egypt. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EAST FINSBURY ELECTION.</head>
                    <head>LIBERAL GAIN.</head>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <dateline>London, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Mr. Baker, Liberal, 2,320, Mr. Cohen, Conservative, 1,552; in succession
                            to Mr. Richards, deceased. This is a Liberal gain. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="wireReport">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET</head>
                    <dateline>London, June 30.</dateline>
                    <p>Kent beat Yorkshire by six wickets. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p> 2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>22855-16.7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement" xml:id="deg-ad-aan02">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>1.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                        English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern
                        sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>-Yesterday’s bulletin records a fatal case at Port Said and another at
                            Ashmoun. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Foundling.</head>
                        <p>.—A living new-born child was found yesterday in the Haret el Balkatria,
                            and was sent to the hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Public Instruction.</head>
                        <p>—Mr. Dunlop will select 25 gentlemen whilst he is in England to add to
                            the staff of Government school instructors.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Course of the Nile.</head>
                        <p>- -A credit of L.E. 6,350 has been opened for an examination of the
                            course of the Nile near the Upper Cataracts. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Crown Casino.</head>
                        <p>—A variety company makes its debut this evening at the new theatre which
                            has been built at the Crown Casino, Ibrahimieh.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p> found in the Esbekieh district of Cairo during the night of Monday and
                            at daylight on Tuesday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>French Comedy.</head>
                        <p>— The Gonnet Levy-French comedy company arrived at Alexandria this
                            morning and opens this evening at the Eden Theatre with the 3-act comedy
                                <hi rend="italic">Mme Mongodin</hi>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>— 9 vessels passed through the Canal on the 28th ulto., 4 of which were
                            British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Turkish. The day’s receipts were frs.
                            207,947.32, making the total from 1st June frs. 7,714,139.54. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Accident.</head>
                        <p>— An Italian named Gaetano Flatino, aged 65 years, was run down by a cab
                            in the Attarin quarter yesterday. His skull was fractured and he expired
                            within a few minutes after being conveyed to the French Hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"Under the Mosquito Net.”</head>
                        <p>—The notes under this title which we usually publish in our Saturday’s
                            issue will not appear during the next few weeks. The concluding portion
                            of the article entitled "The Principles of Heredity" is also similarly
                            postponed. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports.</head>
                        <p> — From 1st January to 29th June, 458,233 tons of coal were imported into
                            Egypt. Wales sent 260,729 tons, Newcastle 87,864, Scotland 65,132,
                            Yorkshire 26,876 and other places 17,632 tons. During the same period of
                            last year the imports amounted to 482,943 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Shepheard’s Buildings.</head>
                        <p>—A short while ago we informed the public that the shops which form part
                            of the buildings of Shepheard’s Hotel were to be pulled down and larger
                            ones erected in their place. The work of destruction has already been
                            commenced and four of the shops are being rapidly demolished.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sudan Mines.</head>
                        <p>—Application has been made to the committee of the London Stock Exchange
                            to appoint a special settling day in Sudan Mines, Limited—Further issue
                            of 400 shares of £1 each, 2s 6d paid (Nos. 1 to 200 and 401 to 600); and
                            3,896 shares of £1 each, fully paid (Nos. 7,605 to 11,500).</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre.</head>
                        <p>—The excellent Italian operetta company which is holding the boards of
                            this playhouse continues to attract large audiences. This evening, the
                            company will stage Suppé’s popular operetta <hi rend="italic">Donna
                                Juanita</hi>. To-morrow alternoon <hi rend="italic">La Gran Via</hi>
                            will be given with the first and second acts of <hi rend="italic">I
                                Grandtieri</hi>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Seizure of Hashish.</head>
                        <p>—On Wednesday and Thursday last the Coastguards made seizures of no less
                            than 500 and 200 okes of hashish on the small islands off Agamé. It had
                            been deposited on the islands by the smugglers while awaiting an
                            opportunity to pass it to the shore, which is so well guarded that it is
                            now a matter of extreme difficulty to land hashish. Before the transfer
                            of the above large quantities could be managed the Coast-guards got wind
                            of its concealment and seized it.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Kanaan Affair.</head>
                        <p>— The Native Parquet of the Minet-el-Bassal Kism has presented its report
                            to the Gouvernorat on the Kanaan affair. We are glad to hear that an
                            enquiry has been opened on the subject, and hope that it will be
                            possible to discover who was responsible for the extraordinary mistake
                            made by some one in the Native Hospital who ordered the burial of the
                            corpse without a proper inquest, and noted the discovery of the body of
                            a Sudanese ! Why not a Japanese or an Eskimo ?</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"King’s English.”</head>
                        <p>—A very interesting article appeared a short time ago, showing the great
                            differences in the language, add especially of pronunciation, in
                            different parts of England, and a witty allusion was also made to
                            “American English.” It admitted, however, that many modern Americanisms
                            were in use in the time of Shakespeare, but the universal opinion is
                            that there is only one English worthy of the name, which is “King’s
                            English,” and special care is taken to keep only to the form throughout
                            all the Berlitz Schools, [p. 2vt] .</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPEECH BY LORD CROMER.</head>
                    <head>THE CONDITIONS OF EGYPT'S PROGRESS.</head>
                    <head type="sub">(Special Cable to the Gazette. )</head>
                    <dateline>London, June 30.</dateline>
                    <p>The Earl of Cromer has received the honorary freedom of the Skinners’
                        Company. His lordship, in replying to the toast of his health, declared that
                        the Anglo French Agreement had been of unmixed benefit to all who had to
                        deal with the local affairs of Egypt and were now relieved from the constant
                        friction and annoyance that had marked the past. The story circulated in the
                        Press to the effect that representations had been made to H.H. the Khedive
                        as to the presence of British troops in Egypt was purely mythical. Four
                        conditions were necessary to secure the uniform progress of Egypt : first,
                        no hurry; second, that Egyptian affairs should be kept outside the domain of
                        British party politics ; third, that the utmost care should be taken not to
                        force Western ideas and exotic institutions upon the Egyptian people before
                        the country was ripe for their assimilation; fourth, that Egypt should
                        continue in the future as in the past to be governed in the interests of the
                        Egyptians themselves.</p>
                    <div type="wireReport">
                        <head>(Reuter’s Telegram)</head>
                        <dateline>London, June 30.</dateline>
                        <p>The Earl of Cromer, speaking at the banquet of the Skinners’ Company,
                            dwelt upon the benefit to Egypt caused by the Anglo-French entente, and
                            the valuable co-operation of the Egyptian Government. His relations with
                            the Khedive were most satisfactory.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL.</head>
                    <p>At Thursday’s meeting of the Legislative Council, Ibrahim Effendi Abd el Al,
                        the new Fayoum delegate, was presented to the members, and the proposal for
                        the formation of an Armenian Catholic community discussed. It was finally
                        decided to have these proposals printed and distributed among the members of
                        the Council.</p>
                    <p>The Council meets again on August 1.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PUBLIC WORKS. </head>
                    <p>Among various credits that have been opened by the Ministry of Finance we
                        note the sum of LE. 11,000 for the neceesary repairs to the Tewfikieh
                        School, LE. 4,750 for the construction of new agricultural roads in Ghizeh
                        Provinoe, L.E. 1,500 for repairs to the Alexandria Mixed Court of Appeal,
                        L.E 950 for the improvement of the harbour lights at the entrance to the
                        port of Alexandria, and smaller credits for the purchase of the necessary
                        material for the sinking of artesian wells in the mining districts, for the
                        purchase of pomps, and for the purchase of dog muzzles rendered necessary by
                        the new law relating to rabies.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DANGEROUS GAMINS.</head>
                    <p>We wish to call the attention of the authorities to the dangerous use of
                        catapults in the streets by European and Arab boys. These gamins appear to
                        be supplied with up-to-date weapons, and samples of their ammunition which
                        we have seen look most formidable, small bolt heads and chopped iron bars
                        being the pattern most in favour. Every evening parties of boys may be seen
                        in the quieter streets, especially in the Moharrem Bey quarter, shooting at
                        the small birds which settle on the tamarisks planted by the road. We
                        imagine that the use of catapults on the public roads is forbidden, and
                        there can be no doubt about the illegality of their use when missiles are
                        fired into gardens with disastrous consequences to windows and grave risk to
                        the eyesight of those who happen to be in the line of fire.</p>
                    <p>Even the Mohamed Aly-square is rendered unsafe : the windows of St Mark’s
                        Church have repeatedly been broken by stones and lumps of iron. Mr.
                        Casimatis, of the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, who is also in charge of part of the
                        business administration of the church, has made an interesting collection of
                        ammunition fired into the windows and has captured two of the culprits, whom
                        he handed over to the police—without any obvious result. This morning the
                        bowab of the church was struck on the left side of the face by a stone from
                        a catapult which inflioted a very nasty wound. Had the missile struck the
                        unfortunate man an inch higher he would probably have lost the sight of one
                        eye. We hope that the authorities will take steps to render the repetition
                        of the offence highly dangerous to the offenders.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The following is the programme of the Wagner oonoert to be given to-morrow,
                        commencing at 10.30 a.m. :—</p>
                    <list>
                        <item>1 Huldingungs Marsch.</item>
                        <item>2 Ouverture do Rienzi,</item>
                        <item>3 Prelude Lohengrin.</item>
                        <item>4 Entrée des dieux dans le Walhall de “l’or du Rhin.”</item>
                        <item>5 Ouverture des Maîtres-Chanteurs.</item>
                    </list>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Raineses” sailed yesterday afternoon for Liverpool, via
                        Malta, with passengers, mails, and general cargo, including 4,247 bales
                        cotton.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>THE S.S. “ST. KILDA.”</head>
                    <head>CREW LANDING AT PORT SAID</head>
                    <head>INTERVIEW WITH CAPTAIN.</head>
                    <head>HOW THE VESSEL WAS SUNK.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From our own Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Suez, Friday.</dateline>
                        <p>As I advised yon this morning by wire, I proceeded on board the Russian
                            cruiser “Dnieper” (ex “St. Petersburg”) in order to interview the crew
                            of the sunken British steamer “St. Kilda,” but the officer on duty
                            absolutely refused to allow me to see any of the British offioers,
                            saying that it was strictly forbidden. He added at the same time that
                            they would probably be landed at Fort Said.</p>
                        <p>I understand, however, that the S.S. “St. Kilda” left Hongkong for
                            Yokohama on the 4th June, with a cargo of rice, cotton, and hemp, and
                            when 40 miles out she met the Russian cruiser "Dnieper,” which signalled
                            to her to stop. A prize crew was subsequently put on board, and next
                            day, when the orew had been removed, the cruiser sank the “St. Kilda”
                            after firing ten shots. All the personal effeots belonging to the orew
                            were lost. 41 of the Chinese crew belonging to the “St Kilda” were
                            transferred to the Dutoh steamer “Flores” and landed at Singapore, while
                            the British officers were retained and brought here.</p>
                        <p>It is remarkable that the “Dnieper,’’ in spite of the long voyage and the
                            heavy seas she encountered, has the appearance of having been recently
                            drydocked. She is heavily armed with large and small machine guns, and
                            fitted with wireless apparatus. She is also flying the naval flag.</p>
                        <p>At about 9.30 a.m. to-day the Russian commander paid an official call on
                            the commander of the British battleship "Canopus,” which was duly
                            returned. The same official calls were exchanged later on between the
                            battleship “Goliath,” which arrived at 10.30 a.m., and the
                            “Dnieper.”</p>
                        <p>The battleship “Goliath” was reported by the “Canopus” as approaching
                            Suez at 7 a.m., being in wireless communication with her.</p>
                        <p>Finally the battleship “Canopus” entered the Canal at 11.15 this
                            morning.</p>
                        <p>The "Goliath” left at 1.40 this afternoon, and the “Dnieper” at 1.55 for
                            Port Said, where, I understand, she will take in abonu 300 tons of coal,
                            not having taken anything at this port.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From our own Correspondent.) </byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Saturday.</dateline>
                        <p>After considerable difficulties had been put in my way I at last obtained
                            an interview with Captain Jones, of the S.S. “St. Kilda.” Captain Jones
                            states that the “St. Kilda” left Hongkong on June 2 last. The European
                            crew refused to proceed to Japan and were landed at Hongkong on June 3
                            and imprisoned. A Chinese crew was shipped and the "St. Kilda” sailed
                            for Yokohama on the same day.</p>
                        <p>On June 4 the Russian erniper “Dnieper” stopped and captured the “St.
                            Kilda,” putting a prize crew on board. The ships proceeded at a speed of
                            nine knots in company into deep water and at 6 a.m. on the 5th June an
                            unsuccessful attempt was made to sink the “St. Kilda” by means of
                            dynamite, after the crew had been taken off. The Russians then opened
                            fire with their quick-firers and sank the captured vessel with 16 4.7
                            inch projectiles at 10 a.m.</p>
                        <p>The “St.-Kilda” was bound from Rangoon to Yokohama with a cargo of rice,
                            cotton, and sugar. The “Dnieper” had been warned of her departure by
                            Russian agents at Hongkong. After the vessel had been sunk the Chinese
                            crew were put on board the S.S. “Flores,” bound for Singapore.</p>
                        <p>The prisoners, who were thirteen in number, were well treated on the
                            “Dnieper,” being each allowed a cabin and having perfect freedom of
                            movement abont the decks.</p>
                        <p>The commander of the “Dnieper”' refused to receive the visit of the
                            captain of H.M.S. "Lancaster” this morning. The Russian cruiser carries
                            eight 4.7q.f. guns and 27 pieces of smaller calibre ; she is bound for
                            Libau and the prisoners have received orders to disembark at Port Said
                            to-night.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALVAGE OF “FOYLE” PROBABLE.</head>
                    <byline>( From our Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Friday,</dateline>
                    <p>The S.S. “Foyle” is now slightly making water in No. 2 hold, and about 70
                        tons of rice has been thrown overboard.</p>
                    <p>Owing to the fine weather, discharge is continuing satisfactorily, and up to
                        the 24th inst., over 800 tons of dry rice, and 500 tons of damaged rice, had
                        been discharged into lighters and landed at Perim.</p>
                    <p>It is now expected that the “Foyle” will be shortly refloated if the weather
                        continues favorable.</p>
                    <p>The divers report that little damage is visible but fear it is considerable
                        underneath the forepeak.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MISSING SUEZ TUG.</head>
                    <byline>( From our Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Friday.</dateline>
                    <p>The lighters laden with rice belonging to the German steamer “Helene
                        Rickmers” have been seen lying at anchor 20 miles south of Ras Gharib
                        lighthouses, but nothing has been heard of the tug. Strong northerly winds
                        prevail and a heavy sea is running in the Suez Gulf, so it is expected that
                        the tug has taken shelter.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>CAIRO TO PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MENZALEH CANAL AND NAVIGATION CO.</head>
                        <p>This new company, founded last year, hopes to inaugurate the Port Said to
                            Matarieh branch of its service across Lake Menzaleh about the middle of
                            October. The Matarieh to Damietta section will also be completed soon
                            after, dredging operations being now hastened for that purpose. The
                            distance between the former two places is some 28 kilometres, and the
                            same distance separates Damietta from Matarieh, where the lake service
                            works in conneotion with the passenger trains of the Compagnie des
                            Chemins de fer de la Basse Egypte to Mansourah and at the latter town in
                            coincidence with those of the State Railways.</p>
                        <p>In October therefore there will be a through service between Cairo and
                            Port Said by railway and passenger steamer. For the latter traffic there
                            are two stern-wheelers for passengers besides two tugs and six lighters
                            for the freight traffic. All these were constracted in England, brought
                            out in sections, and put together at Karputi, near Port Said, by the
                            Anglo-American Nile Steamer Co., who have entered into a contract to
                            work the lines of the Menzaleh Canal and Navigation Company for two
                            years from the date of inauguration. The steamers have good
                            accommodation each for a certain number of first and second class
                            passengers, besides 150 of the third class.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY CO.</head>
                        <p>A correspondent writes:—Apropos of accidents on this railway, they are of
                            almost daily occurrence now. On Friday last the Nesleh engine broke down
                            as it was about to leave for Fayoum ; another engine was sent, but never
                            reached its destination, and as no other was available passengers and
                            train had necessarily to wait until one of the other branch trains
                            arrived at Fayoum, when that engine was sent and succeeded in returning
                            home with its unfortunate companions “hours late.”</p>
                        <p>The Shawashna train on the same day was never seen at Fayoum. A few days
                            ago a funeral party ordered a "special” for 3 p.m. for Daire el Azab;
                            they arrived and had to sit in the train in the broiling afternoon sun
                            until 5.30 p.m., when the engine from Lahoon took the train. No other
                            was available.</p>
                        <p>Last year the traffic receipts were published pretty regularly and always
                            showed an increase. It would interest many to know why they are now
                            suppressed, as LE. 300 a month will not cover the decrease of receipts,
                            and from what can be gathered it is likely to be still more. It really
                            is time the public were better served and these directors were stopped
                            "playing at railways,” for I am told that the native who is “running the
                            show” at the moment, seizing the moment of chaos, actually threatened to
                            resign “playing at puff puffs” unless he got more pay, and, in the face
                            of this large and continued decrease of receipts, I hear he is to have
                            an increase of P.T. 200, so that the farce may continue— “Great Scot
                            !”</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="sporting">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“TROTTER EGYPTIEN.”</head>
                        <p>The following is the programme of the fourth day’s racing at the
                            Hippodrome, Round Point, which takes place on the 22nd inst:—</p>
                        <p>Prix de Hadra.—P.T. 700 (400 200 100). Pour chevaux ambleurs (Rahouan)
                            attelés ou montés. Epreuve unique—4 tours de piste 2364 métres—Entree
                            P.T. 50.</p>
                        <p>Egyptian Maiden.—P.T. 6.000 (3.000-1.500- 1.000-500—Pour chevaux arabes
                            et indigenes maiden (qui n’ont jamais gagné de premier prix)—En deux
                            épreuvee 3 tours de piste 1784 metres. Entree P.T. 500—(Cette course
                            aura lieu s’il y a au moins 6 engagements).</p>
                        <p>Prix de la Promenade.—P.T. 300 de Sweepstakes. Pour chevaux de la même
                            écurie attelés en paire à des voitures américaines à quatre roues
                            caoutchoutées. Pour chevaux de tous pays. Seront exclus les trotteurs de
                            course. Le 1er recevra un objet d’art et le 65% sur les entries. Le 2me
                            le 35%— Epreuve unique.—Distance 4 tours de piste 2364 métres.</p>
                        <p>Grand Handicap International. — P.T. 5.000 (3.000 1.000 700 300) En 2
                            épreuves— Pour tous chevaux de 1re, 2me, 3me, 4rme classe avec
                            rendements de distance suivant la vitesse constatée en Egypte. Les
                            chevanx qui n’ont pas de vitesse constatée partiront scratch. Distance 3
                            tours de piste 1.780 m. minimum. Entrée P.T. 300.</p>
                        <p>Conditions Générales.—Les courses sont soumises aux réglements du Trotter
                            Egyptien. Les inscriptions seront closes le 15 juillet à 4h. p.m., et
                            devront être adressées avec le montant des entrées an Secrétaire du
                            Trotter Egyptian, Mr. C. della Marra, Rond-Point, ex Vélodrome,
                            Alexandria</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB</head>
                        <head>FIRST WINTER MEETING.</head>
                        <head>(December 20th and 22nd 1905 ).</head>
                        <p>COUNTRY BRED STAKES. Value LE. 100.</p>
                        <table>
                            <head>Scale of Weights.</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>3 yean.</cell>
                                <cell>4 yean.</cell>
                                <cell>5 and over,</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>1st Class C.B’s...</cell>
                                <cell>10.7</cell>
                                <cell>11. 3</cell>
                                <cell>11.10</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>2nd „ „ ...</cell>
                                <cell>9.3</cell>
                                <cell>9.13</cell>
                                <cell>10.10</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Arabs...</cell>
                                <cell>7.0</cell>
                                <cell>7.10</cell>
                                <cell>8. 7</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>GERMANY AND TURKEY VERSUS ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST.</head>
                    <byline>BY W. M.</byline>
                    <head>I. THE DANGER. (Continued.)</head>
                    <p>The great line that runs like an artery from Constantinople to Konieh is to
                        be carried on across the Taurus to branch off eastward to Bagdad and Koweit,
                        southward to Aleppo and the Syrian system, is a military line <hi
                            rend="italic">par excellence</hi>. Its two branches will one day aid the
                        German Empire to strike Britain in Asia and Africa. German diplomacy in
                        Turkey has never ceased to keep the question of Egypt and Arabia alive and
                        to suggest the possibility that a new Turkish army may one day inflict on
                        Britain the stroke of Excalibur, from whioh there is no recovery, cleaving
                        in twain the Empire without the slightest interference on the part of the
                        fleet on which England’s hopes are centred.</p>
                    <p>The Tnrko-German Staff aims at nothing less than an immediate advance on
                        Egypt by an overwhelming Ottoman army, should war unhappily break out
                        between Germany and Great Britain after the completion of the Ottoman
                        strategic lines. The success of the invasion would involve the suppression
                        of the Mixed regime, the substitution of a delegate of the Sultan for our
                        enlightened Sovereign and his British friends and advisers, while the
                        directing power—which would not emphasise its position too strongly— would
                        be the German Empire. “Delenda est Carthago ” and “ Unsere Zukunft liegt am
                        Wasaer" have an identical meaning in Germany. Her chief continental rival
                        has been beaten down at Mukden and Tsusima by her adversary’s ally, and the
                        Turkish alliance originally designed against Russia or England may now be
                        directed exclusively against the latter. Beware, England, or the day of yonr
                        overthrow will see this fulfilment of the German dream and the wings of the
                        eagles overshadowing half the world !</p>
                    <p>Neither in the Suez Canal, which a few merchantmen could block to-morrow, nor
                        in the straits of the Dardanelles, impregnably fortified by Von der Goltz
                        and Brialmout against all the navies of the world, can England meet her
                        future foes. Her influence inEgypt, her share in the Sudan, her domination
                        in the Aden Protectorate, Uganda, and East Africa are doomed, and these
                        lost, will not the decay of British prestige lead to the loss of India from
                        internal causes, unless—</p>
                    <p>Yes, that will be the inevitable consequence of Britain’s Egyptian and
                        Arabian policy, which has earned the frown of the Shadow of Allah, unless
                        her people, bringing into play the foresight and sagacity that have made
                        them great, have recourse to the sole remedies that can conjure the
                        peril.</p>
                    <p>(To be continued).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>The Regent, <persName>H.E. Mustapha Pasha Fehmy</persName>, is leading for Europe to-day by the
                        Austrian Lloyd steamer.</p>
                    <p><persName>Scander Pasha Fehmy</persName> arrived at Alexandria yesterday. </p>
                    <p><persName>Yacoub Pasha Artin</persName> and <persName>Abdallah Bey Sfer</persName> have returned to Cairo from
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p><persName>Coles Pasha</persName>, with <persName>Mrs. Coles</persName> and the Misses Coles, left Cairo for Port Said
                        yesterday to join the Bibby boat.</p>
                    <p><persName>Harvey Pasha</persName> arrived to-day from Cairo.</p>
                    <p>We regret to report the death, whioh occurred on the 19th ult, in the Bahr
                        el Ghazal Province, of <persName>Kaimakam H. L. H. Fell Bey, R.N.</persName>, Senior Inspector
                        of the province. The deceased officer resigned from active service in the
                        Royal Navy with the rank of lieutenant, his commission being restored
                        under the provisions of the Order in Council of May 13, 1901. He was
                        universally regarded as an officer of great promise ; his work in the Bahr
                        el Ghazal had been conspicuously good, and his personal qualities endeared
                        him to his comrades in the Sudan service. Fell Bey was about to relieve
                        Kaimakam Drury Bey, R.N., Suakin.</p>
                    <p>The <persName>Rev. F. B. N. Norman-Lee, S.C.F.</persName>, and <persName>Mrs. Norman-Lee</persName> are leaving on the
                        4th inst by the P. &amp; 0. “Egypt” for England. Mr. and Mrs. Norman-Lee take
                        this opportunity of thanking their numerous friends for their kind enquiries
                        and sympathy daring Mrs. Norman-Lee’s severe illness. Mr. Norman-Lee will
                        be away for four months and during that time his duties at Alexandria will
                        be performed by the <persName>Rev. Arthur H. Manning</persName>, acting chaplain to the Forces,
                        who is staying at the Miramare Hotel, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>A cable from London states that <persName>Baron de Kusel Bey</persName>, manager of the Egyptian
                        Trust and Investment, Limited, has left for Egypt via Brindisi, and is due at
                        Alexandria on Wednesday next</p>
                    <p><persName>Dr. Warpoek</persName>, medical superintendent of Abbassieh Asylum, left Egypt
                        yesterday for England on three months’ leave of abeence.</p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. S. G. Violara</persName> left Alexandria to-day for a short holiday in Greece.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
