<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Logan Wills</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-29">September 29, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, Friday, September 29</head>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLAND AND JAPAN WORLDS RECEPTION OF TREATY ALARM IN RUSSIA</head>


                    <p>Paris, September 28 The French press has received the Anglo- Japanese treaty
                        favourably, and it is believed that there is no reason why it should cause
                        any ill feeling between Great Britain and Russia, and that the safety of
                        Indo China is strengthened by the alliance of Japan with a power which is in
                        excellent relations with France. (Reuter)</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 28. Article IV M the treaty is viewed with alarm
                        here, and it is considered that it is open to the widest interpretation.
                        (Reuter</p>

                    <p>Berlin, September 28. A few of the weighty German papers consi- der the
                        treaty unobjectionable. The rest declare that it is most menacing and urge a
                        Russo German counter alliance, of which it is believed that M. Witte's visit
                        is the precursor. They advocate the inclusion of France in the alliance.
                        (Reuter</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 28. The "Novce Vremya” says that the Anglo-
                        Japanese alliance enslaves Asia, and that it is aimed particularly at
                        Russia. It enables the allies to co operate either for the eventual
                        annexation by Great Britain of part of Afgha- nistan or of Northern
                        Saghalien by Japan, For these reasons Russia must counterbalance the treaty
                        by a now alliance.</p>
                    <p>Liberal circles here welcome the alliance as tending to restrain aggressive
                        policy, and to concentrate the attention of Russia to the improvement of the
                        home situation. (Reuter</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. AGREEMENT SIGNED.</head>

                    <p>Paris, September 28. The Agreement between Franco and Ger- many with regard
                        to Morocco, which was signed at Paris to day, is virtually a confirma- tion
                        of the agreement of the 9th July. The French are satisfied because it is
                        considered to be a recognition on the part of Germany of the legitimacy of
                        French colonial expansion. (R.)</p>

                    <p>Paris, September 28. M. Rouvier and Prince von Radolin have signed the
                        Morocco agreement. The conference will meet at Algeciras. (Havas</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHATHAM EXPLOSION.</head>

                    <p>Port Said, September 28. The explosion of the Chatham blew the vessel to
                        pieces and threw a huge column of water, sand, and debris 2,000 feet into
                        the air. The East bank of the Canal is destroyed for a distance of 600 feet.
                        The West bank is unda- maged It is impossible to state when the Canal will
                        be opened for navigation, probably it will be after four days. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES. FURTHER DIFFICULTIES FEARED.</head>

                    <p>Paris, September 28. New financial difficulties are feared by the Sucreries.
                        (Havas</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>M. WITTE ARRIVES IN RUSSIA.</head>

                    <p>St. Peteruburo, September 28. M. Witte has arrived. He was greeted very
                        warmly. (Havas)</p>

                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 28. M. Witte had a long conference with Count
                        Lamsdorff to day. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL STOESSEL ILL</head>

                    <p>Moscow, September 28 General Stoeasel has had a paralytic stroke (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY. ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head>

                    <p>In view of the 3rd annual aquatic sports, members will please meet the
                        handicapper at the Marina to morrow. Boats will leave the landing stage at 3
                        and 4 p.m. for the Khe divial Floating Dock.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. ANDREWS CHURCH, ALEXANDRIA.</head>

                    <p>The Sacrament of the Lord’s Supper will be Celebrated in this Church on
                        Sunday next at 10 30 am. Visitors and friends are cordially invited.</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES SITUATION- DEATH OF M. DE LA BOUGLISE</head>

                    <p>Our Cairo Correspondent telephones that M. de la Bouglise, while leaving a
                        confec- tioner’s shop in the Sharia el Manskh in company with M. Laroux at
                        6.30 p.m. yester- day, suddenly staggered and fell. Medical aid was
                        unavailing, death, which is stated to have been caused by heart disease
                        having been instantaneous. The body of M. de la Bonglise was removed to the
                        French hospital from which the funeral will start at 4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>The sad news caused considerable excite ment on tho Alexandria bourse this
                        morning, the shares of the Societe des Sucreries falling to 45 from 50
                        frs.</p>
                    <p>Sir William Wilcocks has been appointed by Judge Tuck as the third
                        agricultural expert to replace Nourisson Bey. The Societe des Sucreries is
                        to be congratulated on its choice since it would be difficult to find in
                        Egypt one more suitable in every way to fill this difficult and important
                        position.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>(By Telegraph).</head>
                    <p>Cairo, Friday 11.4 p.m. M. de la Bouglise, who has been suffer- ing from
                        arteriscelerosis for a long time, died suddenly in Sharia Suliman Pasha from
                        an attack of angina pectoris. His death was notified by the French consul
                        yesterday evening.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA. LETTER PROM Lord CROMER.</head>
                    <p>Our contemporary “Al Lewa” publishes an important letter from Lord Cromer to
                        H.H. Prince Ibrahim Pasha Halim concerning the action to be brought by the
                        Princes, sons of the late Khedive Ismail, against the Govern- ment claiming
                        the restoration of the remaining surplus of the Daira Sanich after the
                        satis- faction of all the creditors of the said admi- nistration, as being
                        heirs of the former owner the late Khedive. One of the claimants, Prince
                        Ibrahim Pasha Halim according to our con- temporary, wrote to ask Lord
                        Cromer’s opinion on his claim. Lord Cromer's reply left no doubt as to his
                        opinion ; he expressed his agree- ment with the view of the Coutentieux and
                        after drawing the attention of Prince Ibrahim to the opinion he had given in
                        1878 when serving on the Commission of tho Egyptian Debt, vix., that the
                        Daira properties had been illegally acquired, that their acquisition was
                        prejudicial to the interests of the country and that the Khedive should
                        restore the properties illegally obtained, he added : — “ I still maintain
                        my opinion and regret to inform your Highness that not only am I unable to
                        support your claim but that should the Egyptian Government be disposed to
                        admit it, I would be obliged to protest in the most effective fashion in the
                        interests of the Egyptian people and taxpayers.”</p>
                    <p>This excellent and uncompromising answer appears to have greatly annoyed our
                        confrere, Mustapha Pasha Kamel, who calls upon the Egyptian public to show
                        their resentment at the affront offered to the sons of the late Khedive
                        Ismail and to support the demand of the princes for the restoration of their
                        rights. We imagine that the Egyptian public will prefer Lord Cromer's advice
                        to that of the "Nationalist leader” and Turkish pasha.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHEMIN DE FER DE L’ORIENT.</head>

                    <p>We are informed that the number winning the first prize in the Chamin de Fer
                        de l’Orient lottery is 41698, provided there is no error due to faulty
                        transmission by telegraph.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASILE KAISER WILHELM.</head>

                    <p>A concert was given on Tuesday afternoon at the Asile Kaiser Wilheim under
                        the patronage of the vice-consul of Germany by Mme Meyer and her pupils and
                        was very largely attended. Mme Tonelli, sister of the well-known Alexandria
                        musician Professor Lombardo, also assisted, playing a duet with Mme Meyor
                        which was very much appreciated and in which both ladies showed great
                        musical talent. MM. Astorre and Michel Mabardi sang together in an excellent
                        manner, and M- Amodio greatly pleased the audience by his rendering of a
                        selection from the opera Aida which he played on the violin. M. Egon Mabardi
                        recited excel- lently. We must also mention Miles Lea Ponta, Eveline
                        Tonelli, Mario and Olga Philippides, all of whom performed their part of the
                        pro- gramme most faithfully and showed a wonderful technical knowledge of
                        music, although they are still quite children.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FAYOUM MURDER.</head>

                    <p>The "Bashkholi” ol Messrs. Green’s ezbeh with his brother, son, and
                        daughter-in-law, the late M. Mataloti’s cook, and his ghaffir have been
                        arrested with ten other arabs, who are believed to have aided and abetted
                        the actual murderers, if they were not guilty themselves. The inquiry
                        continues.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Bulkily (near Alexandria) BAMLEH’s FASHIONABLE HOTEL PATRONISED BY THE
                        ELITE.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHATHAM EXPLOSION MR. HARRIS' GREAT SUCCESS WATER ASCENDS 500 YARDS.
                        (From our Port Said Correspondent.)</head>
                    <p>Port Said, Thursday 2 p.m. I am now able to send you full details of the
                        world's record dynamite explosion, which, as I telegraphed you as soon as
                        the wires were in working order at 1.30 p.m., was successfully performed,
                        and if I may be allowed to say so, reflects the greatest credit upon Mr.
                        Harris. The divers, who bad been specially selected on account of their
                        previous experience and because they bad been down all over the ship on
                        former occasions, were on the scene last night as well as tags and material,
                        so that all should lie in readiness for laying the mines at the first streak
                        of dawn. Mr. Harris, his two assistants, Mr. Schmitt and Mr. Plata, Lieute-
                        nant Cunningham and the interpreter, left here at 5 a.m. in the Albatross
                        arriving at Ras el Esh at 5.45 a.m. where they dropped Mr. Plum who
                        proceeded to kilometre 15.5 to prepare the north end of the firing wires and
                        cut everything else. At Ras el Esh the party took on board two skilled
                        telegraph wire workers and the vessel left at once, towing the dabsbeah,
                        with the charges on board, after them, to the Chatham. The mines were made
                        up in huge bolsters of sail canvas and each had two submarine detonators in
                        them with about eight feet of cable attached, to which the submarine cable
                        was to be connected.</p>
                    <p>Arriving alongside the Chatham the divers were at once sent down to open the
                        hatches ready for lowering the mines into place, whilst Mr. Harris himself
                        proceeded to attach the connecting wires. These wore each of 100 yards long
                        and were, at the proper time, led ashore and fixed on to Nos. 2 and 4
                        telephone wires on the posts on the canal bulk. The joints were made most
                        care fully, and in about half an hour the 300 lb. mine for No 1 hold was
                        ready for lowering. The mine was put into a canvas hammock, the rings of
                        which served as slings, All was now ready, and the charge was care- fully
                        raised and put into a boat, which, in its turn, was taken under the derrick
                        head with which the dahabesh had been specially fitted. The piece of cable
                        which was to connect the mines in Nos 1 and 3 holds being attached, and the
                        joint being covered with guttapercha, the mine was lifted by the winch and
                        gently lowered to the divers who were standing on the trunk deck waiting for
                        it, some 14 feet below the surface. Great care and gentleness was exercised
                        in the lowering of the charge as it would have been absolutely fatal had the
                        mine received the least shock, and after some little time taken in
                        manipulating the awkward ‘baby’ it eventually, some 15 minutes later, lay
                        resting on the cases of dynamite in the vessel's hold. To avoid any shock,
                        the rope by which the mine was lower- ed, was then cut, and the dahabeah
                        with its greatly relieved operators on board proceeded to the next hold to
                        which the divers had already gone, whilst the cable which would complete the
                        circuit between the two charges was enrolled from a boat. Before going any
                        further the first shore line was sent away and tied to a post as it was not
                        safe to connect in any way with shore lines until all the work on the
                        Chatham had been finished.</p>
                    <p>The divers then opened np hold No. 3 whilst Mr. Harris went on with his
                        joints and con- nections, if anything more carefnlly than before. All being
                        ready at eight o’clock, the second charge was lowered in its hammock and
                        placed in dose proximity to the case of detonators, which had been the Canal
                        Company’s "bate noir” in the early days of this dangerous and most anxious
                        problem. By 8.15 a.m. all was ready, and the boats were sent away to the
                        tugs waiting some little distance north of the ship, and these vessels at
                        once left for Port Said at top speed. Mr. Harris and his little select group
                        then went about their final shore connections, whilst Mr. Tillier
                        telegraphed to Port Said to hoist the signal which would tell the people of
                        that town that in an hour, vix., at 9.50 a.m., the wires would be fired. In
                        a few moments the wires were connected and the party left for the firing
                        point where were assembled Mr. Tillier, Mr. Coallant, Mr. Doyen, Mr. Schmid,
                        and Mr. Perrier, no one else being allowed within the cordon of sol- diery
                        which had been drawn at an early hour at kilometre 3.1.</p>
                    <p>Arriving at the firing point, kilometre 12.52, the experts proceeded to test
                        the wires, the result of which would prove whether the explo- -ion would
                        occur or not, for were there the very least fault in the wires or
                        connections the galvanometer would show at once the use- lessness of
                        proceeding further, and the need fir at once lifting the charges anew and
                        making new joints and examinung the whole length of three miles of wire. The
                        galvsnomoter register- ed a force of 11, and with a sigh of great relief the
                        party lit up pipes and cigars to await the appointed time knowing that the
                        ship would go up the moment the twist exploder lever was put down. </p>
                    <p>At 9.45 a.m. the first wire was screwed on to the exploder and in four
                        minutes the other wire was treated similarly, whilst the little party stood
                        round, watches in hand, waiting the word from Mr. Tillier on whose time the
                        order to hoist the Port Said signal was made. Precisely at 9.50 a.m Mr.
                        Harris quietly took out his handkerchief and firmly grasped the lever,
                        thrusting it down with all his force. Istant- aneously, and before he had
                        taken his hand off the lever, a shock was felt as if the ground had been
                        struck heavily in the near vicinity, and an immense column of water, sand,
                        debris, stones, and pieces of iron ascended and con- <cb/>tinued to ascend
                        for five seconds, getting blacker every moment as the fragments in- creased
                        in number. The column appeared at first like a huge fountain, and as it grew
                        it assumed the form of an immense black tree with great branches. Up it went
                        with great rapidity, growing in height, density, and volume, till 15 seconds
                        after the explosion it had attained a measured height of 560 yards and had
                        spread the width of the canal twice over. The water boiled and foamed, being
                        scattered the while in a hundred ways all across the canal. The report,
                        which resembled that of a 4.7 gun at a distance of say 500 yards, reached
                        the firing point 16 seconds after the lever was put down and considerably
                        surprised me by its feebleness. I think most of the other untechnical
                        watchers, like me, expectated a much louder report and several of them
                        remarked on the weakness of both sound and shock. Thirty-five seconds after
                        the charges were fired, the greater part of the debris had fallen, but for
                        fully two min- utes the sir was full of mist and the water above the remains
                        of the unfortunate ship continued to boil up violently and tear up the banks
                        of the canal. Whilst awaiting the train, which was in readiness with some 50
                        guests on board at kilometre 8, the party amused itself in trying to
                        discover the extent of the damage to the canal, but this distance was too
                        great and nothing was certain. No tidal wave accompanied the explosion
                        though a current with a veloc- ity of about two miles an hour ran past
                        kilometre 12 and back some few minutes after; nor did any debris reach the
                        spot—both of which points Mr. Harris had declared himself sure of.</p>
                    <p>The train arriving shortly after, the party proceeded slowly fearing
                        accidents to the wires at Ras el Esh where telegraph line staffs were
                        stationed to get their lines at once in order. Slowly and carefully we went
                        on to kilometre 18 and there stopped, finding the line smother- ed in grass,
                        reeds, trees, telegraph wires, frag- ments of iron etc., and the country
                        inundated, but rapidly drying, for some 1,009 yards round the spot.</p>
                    <p>With great excitement the guests and Mr. Harris' party left the train and
                        crossed the fresh water canal by the bridge which had been erected the
                        previous day, find- ing the fresh water canal intact, though very muddy and
                        thick with weeds, grass, and trees. Arriving on the maritime canal bank
                        walking became difficult. Wires, posts, pieces of ship's plates, beaxs, and
                        frames were sticking up in all directions and the surface of the ground was
                        under water in places, and muddy in the extreme.</p>
                    <p>No telegraph posts were actually down but all the wires were off the posts,
                        lying about everywhere and covered with a thick coating of oxide. Along the
                        African bank, which had not suffered in the least except for numerous and
                        immense holes in the ground where the masses of water had descended, all was
                        desolation and wreck.</p>
                    <p>In a circle of about 600 yards radius thous- ands of pieces of the ship lay
                        in confusion and all the country had been covered deeply in water. Dead fish
                        were plentiful and were secur- ed by the Arabs on the train.</p>
                    <p>The Railway staff at once proceeded to their survey but found no damage
                        beyond a few loose bolts and the telegraph parties started at once to repair
                        the damage to their lines. The Asiatic bank presented a truly awful sight
                        with a huge hole driven into it of some 70 yards wide and 250 long, strewn
                        with wreck- age and coke in a fine powder.</p>
                    <p>The fore end of the ship as far as abaft the engine room had completed
                        disappeared, the mainmast in small pieces lay resting on what little
                        remained of the poop and no signs were visible of anything else belonging to
                        the ship except the hundreds of pieces with which the East bank and its
                        environs were strewn.</p>
                    <p>Immense fissures were cut in all directions, the wreck lay everywhere in
                        thick mud, half a mile way great pieces of engines and plates were standing
                        sentry over the surronnding waste of marsh and desert. All was black from
                        the coke dust and smelt strongly of nitro- glycerine, the fumes from which
                        were contin- ually rising from what was left of the vanished but famous
                        Chatham.</p>
                    <p>A hurried survey with the lead line was made before the officials and Mr.
                        Harris’ party left for Port Said after their mostt anxious and tiring day.
                        At the spot where the fore end of the ship lay -yesterday there were 22
                        metres of water. The depths varied from 20 to 15 metres and in the middle of
                        the canal where originally 9 metres covered the bottom, only 6, or even
                        less, could be measured. The shock had excavated hundreds of tons of mud and
                        sand and deposited it towards the African shore.</p>
                    <p>Railway traffic was resumed this afternoon by 3 o'clock, whilst the State
                        telegraph lines were repaired and in use by half past one and those of the
                        Canal Company only half an hour later. Great relief is felt at the little
                        damage which has been done and Port Said especially congratulates itself
                        upon the escape of its fresh water supply from any interuption, as this was
                        regarded as more than possible. It cannot be definitely said for how long
                        the canal traffic will be delayed but I hardly think that a clear passage
                        will be obtained for another ten days. I shall, however, be able to tell you
                        more when I have learnt the results of the soundings which are, at the time
                        of writing, being taken. Tags, divers, sounders, and dredgers are all on the
                        spot and the Canal Company officials are displaying the same activity which
                        they have shown ever since the boat caught fire on the 5th inst Mr. Harris,
                        upon whom the respon- sibility of the carrying out of this experiment lay,
                        mast indeed be pleased with the result of his work, and fully deserves all
                        the con- gratulatory terms which I hear on every side, whenever his name is
                        mentioned, which is not seldom.</p>
                </div>


                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>(From Another Correspondent.)</head>
                    <p>A remarkable example of the terrors of the unknown has been affurded by the
                        scare created in Port Said by the blowing up of the Chatham which was
                        successfully effected shortly before ten o'clock. Shops in the town remained
                        unopen, people left their houses in fear that they would collapse, and in a
                        variety of other ways showed their dread of the effects of the explosion.
                        And yet when it did take place, even the sound of it in the still morn- ing
                        air was so dull that it might well have passed unnoticed by any one not
                        expecting anything out of the common. Seated on a chair placed on the frail
                        covering of the water tank on the roof of the Eastern Exchange and exposed
                        to the foil glare of a burning sun, with eyes or glass fixed on one spot,
                        the time of waiting, seemed long. The signal flag was hoisted on the Canal
                        Company’s offices a little before nine o'clock. The hour struck, all of us,
                        (about a dozen) were gazing intently on the distant landscape, but the
                        minutes went by, the chimes told the quarter-past, half-past,and a quarter
                        to ten without the least sign of anything having happened. But directly
                        after wards two or three steam launches were seen to be rapidly coming in
                        the direction of Port Said and it was evident that the moment for which we
                        were eagerly waiting was at hand. At seven minutes to ten a huge gray column
                        slowly rose and spread out like a tree, disap- pearing again in the space of
                        a few seconds, almost before the dull muffled sound of the explosion was
                        heard. This column rose to an enormous height impossible to estimate, and
                        consisted of water and sand, though it looked more like smoke. Not the
                        slightest earth tremor could be detected and the water below us was not in
                        the least disturbed.</p>
                    <p>I understand that little more than I have described was experienced by those
                        who went by the special train and who were unable to get any nearer than
                        five miles from the scene of explosion.</p>
                    <p>Altogether the damage done has been far below even the minimum estimate and
                        it seems to be only a question of the removal of the wreckage of the ship
                        and the time in which this can be effected, before the traffic of the canal
                        can be resumed. The present estimate is that it will take about three or
                        four days only.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>( By Telegraph. )</head>
                    <p>Port Said, Friday, 9.22 a.m. The following were present at the electric
                        generative station at kilometre 12 yesterday:— iMM. Coallant, Tillier,
                        Diyeo, Jasserand, Schmitt, Lieutenant Cunningham, Mr. Harris and his two
                        assistants. The first wire was connected at a quarter to ten exactly, the
                        second at 9.49 a.m. and the explosion took place in less than one second
                        after Mr. Harris had pressed the lever of the twist exploder. In one second
                        the column of water had risen to a height of 100 yards, in eight seconds it
                        measured 400 yards and in twelve seconds a height of 550 yards was reached.
                        Then the debris was seen to rise in great masses, and pieces of iron
                        weighing more than a ton were thrown into the air as high as half a mile.
                        The mixture of water, sand, and debris continued to rise for thirty five
                        seconds. It is anticipated that further explosions will be necessary to
                        complete the destruction of the vessel. Prompt measures were taken by the
                        Canal Company officials towards repairing the damage done. At two o’clock
                        sounding and repairing gangs, engineers, divers, and dredgers were hard at
                        work and careful surveys were being made. The length of time for which the
                        canal traffic will be interrupted cannot be estimated accurately until the
                        report which the engineers make as a result of their survey is to hand, but
                        it is generally anticipated that it will be a week. Mr. Harris, however,
                        considers that ships will be able to pass through in safety in less than a
                        week's time.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>

                    <p>H.H. The Khedive remained at Montazah to-day and attended Friday prayers at
                        the Montazah Mosque.</p>

                    <p>H.E. Coles Pasha, C.M.G., inspector general of the Prisons Department is
                        returning to Egypt by the Bibby liner Cheshire leaving Marseilles on the 6th
                        proximo.</p>

                    <p>Sir Elwin Palmer will arrive in Cairo on Tuesday next from England.</p>

                    <p>Mr. K Speir, the newly appointed secretary general of the State Railways,
                        will arrive in Cairo from England on the 4th October.</p>

                    <p> Mr. John Perret has been appointed surve- yor of the Zifta circle of
                        irrigation at a salary of L.E. 18 per month.</p>

                    <p>The P. and 0. Persia leaving Marseilles to- day for Port Said is bringing out
                        a good number of well known residents amongst whom are Sir Malcolm
                        Mellwraith, H.E. Crookshank Pasha and Mrs. Crookshank, Schalch Bay, Mr. and
                        Mrs. C. Snow, Mr. and Mrs. Hooker, Captain MoMnrdo, Mr. and Mrs. Noel Beyts
                        and the Misses Beyta, etc.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LIST. DEPARTURES.</head>
                    <p>La paquebit Perro), de la Cie Fiorio Rubat tino parti bier pour Genes avait a
                        bord : Mlle Simmer, M. Catalafago, cap. Silvestri, M A Capua, M. Charon, M.
                        Fechox, M. Max Jabaties, Willie Betts, M. N. Ferri, M. John Stevens, M. P.
                        Sorionte. M. R. Leoni, M. J. Watson et IS passagers de some classe.</p>
                </div>


                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET (From our Financial Correspondent).</head>
                    <p>London, September, 22. The dominating factor during the earlier part of the
                        week has again been the money market and the question as to what action
                        would be taken by the dimeters of the Bank of England at their meeting
                        yesterday was dis- cussed. Opinions were fairly evenly divided respecting a
                        rise in the Bank rate but three discount houses which accepted six months
                        Bank bills at 2 1/2 have proved correct in their anticipations rather than
                        those which declined them under 3 2/5, for no change was made of the
                        directors yesterday, the weekly return showing a stronger position then was
                        expected. The Bank rate therefore remains for the present at 3 %. The
                        opening of the markets yesterday shows that this was pretty well anticipated
                        before midday with the consequence that there was a more cheerful tendency
                        all round, and prices generally hardened. Consols, which we quoted last week
                        at 89 13/15. have been up again to 89 7/8, and today close at. 89 9/25 This
                        upward tendency has permeated all other gilt- edged securities, and they may
                        be said to be on the advancing tack again.</p>
                    <p>Foreign Government bonds gained renewed strength on Continental buying.
                        Japanese stocks were in special requests on a report which comes from a
                        creditable source that Japan is already rewiring large amounts of money in
                        respect of the Manchurian railway. The new loan is quoted at 4 7/8 Russian
                        bonds have been firmer, it being reported that M. Witte has had an interview
                        with Messrs Rothschild. Baron Hottingner, and Herr Pisehel. of Berlin, for
                        the purposes of raising a "Peace" loan. The situation is considered
                        favourable for the launching of this shortly, and it is believed that the
                        loan will be offered in France, Germany, Belgium and Holland, but not the
                        United States.</p>
                    <p>In the Home Railway market, increased traffics, the result of the steady
                        improvement in trade, have produced a hardening tendency in prices. The
                        amalgamation of the Great North of Scotland Railway with the Highland
                        Railway, which is now on the tapis, and will probably be consummated era
                        long, is looked upon favourably. The Amarican market has been stronger
                        throughout the week, and Pacifica have taken the lead again. Not with-
                        standing that the bulls have been taking profits, the shares have steadily
                        risen, and it is predicted that they will shortly reach 200.</p>
                    <p>There is little to report regarding, move- ments in the Egyptian share market
                        generally. Stocks have been quite inactive since our last, with, if
                        anything, a slightly easier tendency. It is expected that the new Bank of
                        Abyssinia, is about to make its appearance under the auspices of the
                        National Bank, and, although nothing definite is yet known of the exact
                        nature of the issue, it is favourably spoken of. It is believed that the
                        last issue of New Natio- nal Bank shares was with connected with the
                        Abyssinian venture. National Banks close to-day 27 7/8 and Agricultural
                        Banks 14 5/8.</p>
                    <p>The only news to hand since our last with reference to the Societe de
                        Sucreries et de la Raffinerie d'Egypt is that the accounts show a loss of
                        L.F.213,000 over a period of ten months to the end of August last. In this
                        is not included a deficiency of £920,000 which must be added to the former
                        sum in the event of the Company being declared responsible for the bills
                        drawn by M. Cronier. Daira Sugar shares are still quoted 4 3/4 and Daira
                        Sanieh 27 7/8. Some business has been taking piece in the 1/2%. Preference
                        shares of Walker and Meima- rachi which are quoted at 3 3/4 to 4 1/4. , In
                        the mining market, the week has ended with a slightly firmer tendency in
                        prices, and in the Rhodesian market Bankets are well maintained at £4. Mr.
                        Garthwaile’s report, whilst not entirely optimistic, is looked upon with
                        more or less favour as giving a tree version of the real state of affairs in
                        the Banket section.</p>
                    <p>In the Egyptian mining market, Nile Valleys have slightly eased off since
                        last week, and are now 1 3/16. ‘'Vigilant," in "Truth," says regard- ing
                        these:—“Nile Valleys are being favourably influenced by a cable announcing
                        that good rich ore has been located at the 200 feet level, the extent and
                        value of which has not yet been ascertained. This is pleasant reading
                        bearing in mind the discouraging developments of the past month or so.”</p>
                    <p>New Egyptians have also been easier at 1, whilst 15/ is the beet price for
                        Egyptian Mines Exploration. Egyptian Estates and Egyptian Trust are also
                        quoted at lower figures. United African Exploration, the mother company of
                        several Egyptian ventures, have improved in price to 1 1/4.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The following is the menu of the dinner at the San Stefano Casino tomorrow
                        evening on occasion of the small dance. Consomme double glare Soles fritos
                        Sauce Pommes nature Quartier d’agnean cultivateur Oband-foit de Poulardes
                        Pelle vus Asperges en Brancho Cailles de vigne retic Salade de Salson Fruite
                        Dessert</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>ARISTEN AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p>Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
