<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>John White</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-01">October 1, 2010</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-30">May 30, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7201] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, MAY 30, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
            <div type="item">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, MAY 30, 1905.</head>
            </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TOGO’S VICTORY.
                    CAPTURE OF NEBOGATOFF.
                    
                    PURSUIT CONTINUED.</head>
                    
                    <head>LIST OF SHIPS SUNK OR CAPTURED
                        
                        TOGO’S FLEET UNDAMAGED</head>
                    
                    <p>Tokio, May 29.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Nebogatoff has been captured, with 3,000 bluejackets. Admiral Rodjestvensky appears to have escaped.</p>
                    <p>The battle began on Saturday. The pursuit continues.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Togo states that he has sunk the following ships . — “Borodino,” “Imperator Alexandre,” ‘ Admiral Nakhimoff,” “Dimitri Donskoi,” “Vladimir Monomakh," “Admiral Oushakoff," “Svietlana,” “Jemchug,” “Kamchatka," and “Irtessim.”</p>
                    <p>He has captured the “Orel," “Imperator Nikolai I.," “Admiral Seniavin,” “General Adm. Apraxine," and “Admiral Sissoi Veliky.’’</p>
                    <p>The Japanese Fleet sustained no damage.</p>
                    <p>(Havas.)</p>
                    
                    <p>Tokio, May 29.</p>
                    
                    <p>The battleships “Borodino, “Ushakoff," and “Alexander III.,” the cruisers “Nakhimoff,'' “Dimitri Donskoi," “Vladimir Monomakh," “Svietlana," “Jemchug, “Kamchatka", and "Irtessim have been sunk. The battleships “Orel," “Nicholai I.," “Admiral Seniavin, " and “Admiral Apraxine," have been captured.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Niebogatoff and 3,000 officers and men have been captured. Admiral Rodjestvensky appears to have escaped. The pursuit continues.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Togo reports that three more destroyers have been sunk and one transport and one destroyer captured. The fighting lasted Saturday and Sunday. The Japanese fleet is undamaged.    (Reuter.)</p>
                    
                    <p>Washington, May 29.</p>
                    <p>The Admiralty learns that the battleship Sisoi Veliki has been captured, and the flag-ship “Knyaz Suvaroff" seriously damaged, (R.)</p>
                    <p>The following are the characteristics of the vessels sunk or captured by Admiral Togo :--</p>
                    <p>Name        Date of  Completion. Speed Crew</p>
                    <p>Souvaroff        Tons.  ... 13,516    1904 18.0 740</p>
                    <p>Orel        ... 13,516    1904 18.0 740</p>
                    <p>Imperator Alexander III.    ... 13,516    1904 18.0 740</p>
                    <p>Borodino        ... 13,516    1904 18.0740</p>
                    <p>Sissoi Veliky         .. 10.400    1897 16.0 550</p>
                    <p>Imperator Nicholai I        .. 9,672    1892 14.8 604</p>
                    <p>General Adm. Aprazine .    ... 4,126    1898 15.0 310</p>
                    <p>Admiral Seniavin ... .    ... 4.792    1895 16.0318</p>
                    <p>Admiral Nakhimoff ... .    ... 8,524    1888 16.7 567</p>
                    <p>Dimitri Donskoi        .. 6.200    1885 16.5 510</p>
                    <p>Vladimir Monomakh ... .    .. 5,593    1885 15.2 550</p>
                    <p>Jemchug         ... 3,106    1904 23.0 340</p>
                    <p>Svietlana        3,862    1897 20.2 360</p>
                </div>
               
                    <div type="item"><head>RECEPTION OF NEWS IN LONDON.</head>
                    <p>London, May 29.</p>
                        <p>There has been a sharp advance in Japanese securities. All markets are stronger. The news of the victory is received with general satisfaction here and is regarded as improving the prospect of peace.    (Reuter. )</p>
                    </div>
                <div type="item"><head>BARON HAYASHI INTERVIEWED.</head>
                    
                    <p>London, May 29.</p>
                    
                    <p>Baron Hayashi, in an interview with Reuter’s representative, said that he rejoices that Admiral Togo’s victory is in the centenary year of the battle of Trafalgar. The Japanese have not been without anxiety ; but their minds are easy now with regard to further operations.    ( Reuter.)</p>
                   </div>
                <div type="item"><head>MR BALFOUR INDISPOSED
                    VOTE OF CENSURE POSTPONED.</head>
                    <p>London, May 29.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Balfour is laid up with a severe chill. The vote of censure has been postponed. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CRETAN DISTURBANCES.
                        DESPATCH OF BRITISH TROOPS.</head>
                    <p>Malta, May 29.</p>
                    <p>540 of the 2nd Sussex Regiment have left for Crete, which continues to be much disturbed.    (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ATLANTIC YACHT RACE.
                        WON BY AMERICAN BOAT.</head>
                    <p>Plymouth, May 29.</p>
                    <p>The American yacht ''Atlantic'’ has been signalled off the Lizard, thus winning the Emperor William s Cup for the Atlantic race. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>CRICKET</head>
                    <p>London, May 29.</p>
                    <p>England beat Australia by 196 runs. Tyldesley 56. Australia made 158 for 4 wickets, when the innings was declared closed. Noble 50, Hill 54. (Reuter).</p>
                <p>[We give this telegram as received, but the more probable reading should, we think, be that England made 196 runs in their first innings, and that Australia had scored 158 for 4 wickets, when the stumps were drawn at the end of the first day’s play. ---Ep. E.G.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <p>Epidemic.—Relapsing fever has broken out in the Kafr Zayat district.</p>
                    <p>The Austro-Hungarian Diplomatic Agency will be transferred to Alexandria
                        about the middle of June.</p>
                    <p>German Mission.—The remaining portion of the German Mission to Abyssinia has
                        arrived at Port Said and embarked for Berlin.</p>
                    <p>The Ministers.—The Regent and the Ministers will remain in Cairo until June
                        12, when they will proceed to Alexandria for the summer.</p>
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Boulac district of Cairo during the
                        night of Thursday and at daylight on Friday, will be poisoned by the
                        police.</p>
                    <p>Horse Show.—Persons attending the Horse Show at the Trotter Egyptien on
                        Saturday next may have lunch on the grounds by ordering tables not later
                        than Thursday.</p>
                    <p>Quarantine in Turkey.— A telegram from Constantinople states that arrivals
                        from Fort Said arc subjected to a medical examination and disinfection,
                        while rats on board are destroyed.</p>
                    <p>English Church Services.—Since the June list of the Mansourah and Tantah
                        services was published it has been thought advisable to alter the hour of
                        the morning service from 11 a.m. to 9.30 a.m. until further notice.</p>
                    <p>Dramatic Performance. — The Ernesto Rossi dramatic club are giving a mixed
                        programme to-morrow evening at the Popular Conservatoire of Music, no
                        theatre being available. The performance will begin at 9.15 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.—12 vessels passed through the Canal on the 26th inst., 8 of which
                        were British, 1 Austrian, 1 German, 2 Italian. The day’s receipts were frs.
                        299,075.71, making the total amount received from 1st inst. frs.
                        8,015,643.61.</p>
                    <p>The Cotton Worm.—The Ministry of the Interior has sent to each of the members
                        or the Legislative Council a copy of the circular giving a description of
                        the cotton worm which has made its appearance at Kafr Khadr, Gharbieh
                        province.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial School of Law.—Yacoub Pasha Artin, Under Secretary of State for the
                        Ministry of Public Instruction, has informed Omar Bey Loutfy that in
                        consequence of the decision of the medical commission on the 23rd inst. his
                        resignation has been accepted.</p>
                    <p>Official Salaries. — The report on the salaries of officials in the service
                        of the Egyptian Government, which Mr. Machell has recently drawn up, is now
                        in the hands of the Financial Adviser. It is not as yet decided whether it
                        will be given in full to the Press.</p>
                    <p>An Outbreak of Fire occurred in a house in the native quarter of Cairo at
                        Darb el-Hamr, on Sunday morning. The Fire Brigade, under the command of
                        Captain Blake, promptly arrived on the scene and the fire was quickly
                        extinguished, though not before three rooms had been destroyed.</p>
                    <p>Hotel Beau-Rivage.—On the occasion of the first ball of the season at the
                        hotel, by kind permission of the Colonel and officers, the band of the Royal
                        Berkshire Regiment will perform during dinner and for the dance. Tables for
                        dinner on that evening should be retained by Wednesday night.</p>
                    <p> Murder by Ghaffir.—Two days ago a native of Itlidim attempted to enter the
                        pre cincts of the market there to sell his cattle, when he was stopped by a
                        ghaffir, who told him that all such business was prohibited owing to the
                        cattle plague. A row ensued, and the ghaffir ended the discussion by killing
                        the fellah with his nabout.</p>
                    <p>Death from Alcoholic Poisoning.— A Sudanese was found by the police yesterday
                        in Bab el Bahr street in a very advanced state of intoxication, and as he
                        had entirely lost the power of speech be was taken to hospital, where he
                        soon afterwards expired. The post-mortem examination showed that death was
                        due to alcoholic poisoning.</p>
                    <p>Army of OCCUPATION.—Colonel J. Magill, M.D.,C.B., R.A.M C., P.M.O. in Egypt,
                        accompanied by Major F. W. Hardy, R.A.M.C., Sanitary Officer in Egypt, will
                        go to Candia, Crete, on the 14th June, to make the annual inspection of
                        barracks and hospitals in that station. During the absence of Colonel J.
                        Magill, the duties of officiating Principal Medical Officer will be
                        performed by Lieut. Col O. Todd, R.A.M.C.</p>
                    <p>Water Main Bursts.—On Sunday after noon the water main leading from the
                        Station square, Cairo,to the Esbekieh burst and flooded the square and
                        adjoining streets. The Water Company immediately stopped their pumps working
                        in order to reduce the pressure, and sent workmen to repair the main, a task
                        which lasted well into the night A large number of men were also sent to
                        clear the streets from the flood of water, which made them almost impassale,
                        and very quickly effected a great improvement in their condition.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA. HARBOUR.
                    NEW PASS TO BE MADE.
                    IMPORTANT UNDERTAKING.</head>
                    <p>A most important improvement in the port of Alexandria is to be undertaken
                        immediately, and to morrow the first dredger for the work is arriving at
                        Alexandria. The Egyptian Government has determined to construct anewpassfor
                        entrance to the harbour as owing to the enormous and continuous increase in
                        the size of modern vessels the present entry by way of the Boghaz pass is
                        too small for the largest type of ships. For instance, when the White Star
                        liner “Celtic” arrived here the season before last she had to lie outside
                        the harbour.</p>
                    <p>The Boghsz pass is only 31 feet in depth and can only admit as a maximum
                        vessels drawing from 29 to 30 feet of water, and then only in the smoothest
                        sea. The Dew pass is to bo dredged to the depth of 35 feet and will thus be
                        able to admit the largest ships alloat</p>
                    <p>The dredger, which arrives from Malta tomorrow, is convoyed by H. M. S.
                        “Juno," a second-class cruiser under the command or Captain Christian, R.N.
                        This dredger, the “St. Lawrence,” belongs to the Admiralty and is of the
                        type known as “Saints.” She has very powerful machinery and it is expected
                        that her dredging capacity is approximately six hundred tons per hour.</p>
                    <p>The construction of the new pass will begin at once. It will make the harbour
                        most efficient for the alternative entrance will be especially useful when
                        one orotherof the passes gets blocked. The new pass will be the same as the
                        present pass from a navigator’s point of view, with leading lights.</p>
                    <p>The Ports and Lighthouses Administration is also negotiating with the
                        Admiralty for the hire of a second dredger for the same work. Another
                        dredger is arriving from Cyprus in about ten days’ time.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>FRUIT AND VEGETABLE DISEASES.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Balls, the botanist of the Khedivial Agricultural Society, has been paying a visit to Alexandria in order to examine the cause of the strawberry disease in the gardens of the Mahmoudieh Canal. He found a worm, which he took to Cairo to be examined by the entomologist, Mr. Willcocks. He also collected worms that attack the sweet potato crop, and several specimens of diseased apricots, French beans, tomatoes, roses, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LAND AND MORTGAGE OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The report of the annual general meeting of the Land and Mortgage Company of Egypt should afford considerable encouragement to the various land and trust companies which have been lately started in Egypt, for if this company can find such scope for useful and extensive operations, there is no reason why the new ventures should not have equally pleasant prospects. That the making of loans on first mortgage can be made remunerative is evidenced by the satisfactory story which the chair-man, Sir E. L. Pemberton, had to tell at the meeting in London on Saturday week. The dividend of 10 per cent. is the highest ever declared by the company. The chairman explained that although in consequence of increasing competition the rate of interest had been reduced, the loans were so well placed that no falling off in the business need be anticipated. Looking at the above results, it is evident that the company’s prosperity is increasing with that of the country generally.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE PIGMIES</head>
                    <p>Colonel Harrison, who has been ill since his return home, has been engaged in
                        making all arrangements before the pigmies’ arrival in England. The
                        directors of the London Hippodrome have engaged them to appear at the London
                        Hippodrome immediately after their arrival at the Royal Albert Docks,
                        probably on June 5.</p>
                    <p>There is a sort of disposition still prevalent to regard these little people
                        as filling, more or less, the part of the “missing link,” but low though
                        they stand in the comparative social scale, they seem to present no marked
                        features whatever to warrant their being placed outside the class of various
                        other ill-developed peoples. Even the silence and apathy of which so much
                        has been made are fully paralleled among the Indian forest races of South
                        America. They are directly attributable to the oppressive gloom and monotony
                        of the surroundings in which for generations they have passed their</p>
                    <p>It is not generally known that several of these little people have been
                        educated and baptised in connection with the C.M.S. Mission in the Uganda
                        Protectorate. One of them is a teacher in a mission school in Toro, near the
                        Ruwenzori Mountains. Writing of the school to children in England, a lady
                        missionary says : "Listen to this ; one class that is being taught by a
                        pigmy from Stanley’s Great Forest, who recently was baptised. His name is
                        Bulasio, and be is very fond of dealing out whacks with that little cane,
                        whenever a pupil slackens in his reading, or does not show him due
                        respect.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p> 2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>xxxxx-1x.7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p> Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste. </p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                   
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>ANGLO-AMERICAN NILE.
                    YEAR OP EXCEPTIONAL PROSPERITY.</head>
                    <p>The following is the report of the board of directors of the Anglo-American
                        Nile Steamers &amp; Hotel Co., Ltd., read at the general meeting of share
                        holders held in Cairo to-day :—</p>
                    <p>The directors, in presenting their fifth annual report and balance sheet, are
                        able to congratulate the shareholders on a year or exceptional prosperity in
                        the history of the company, and to point to a steady increase in all
                        branches of their business, the profits from all sources rising from LE.
                        18,086 in 1903 to L.E. 19,471 in 1904, and LE. 24,197 in 1905. These results
                        have been achieved in the face of very severe competition in the freight
                        service dating from the reduction of the Railway Administration’s tariff,
                        which involved a corresponding decrease in the rates charged by the company.
                        The increase of river and canal traffic between Cairo and Alexandria had led
                        to the issue of certain Government regulations which, if adhered to, are
                        likely to have serious results upon the future of transport by steam barge
                        in this country, Representations are, however, being made to the Public
                        Works Department which it is hoped will lead to their modification </p>
              </div>
                <div type="item"><head>MENZALEH CANAL &amp; NAVIGATION Co.</head>
                    <p>Allusion was made in the last report to an arrangement by virtue of which an option on the unissued share capital of the company was given against £10,000 of debentures in the company taken firm by a local group and the New Egyptian Company. The results of this operation have been fully commensurate with the directors’ expectations. A valuable holding has been secured in the Menzaleh Canal and Navigation Company shares; the order for the construction of their fleet is being carried out in the company’s workshops ; and the central management thereof is assured to this company for a period of two years at a remuneration of £500 per annum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL, ASSOUAN.</head>
                    <p>Apart from profits derived from the usual sources of business, a special profit has been made on the sale of the Savoy Hotel at Assouan, which has been transferred for a sum of £60,000 to the newly-formed Upper Egypt Hotels Co. The sale was made for cash, and the second instalment of £30,000 has been paid over since the accounts have been closed. The directors are of opinion that this profit should be considered as extraordinary and dealt with accordingly. They therefore propose that ten thousand pounds shall be placed to reserve and that the whole of the preliminary expenses, amounting to L.E. 2,983.202 m/m, be written off. The continued existence of this account, which has no realisable value, appears to them undesirable. The directors, although entitled by law and precedent to their percentage of this profit, are strongly of opinion that in cases where a profit is dealt with as extraordinary and not distributed by way of dividend, the Board should also forego their claim to a share in it. No deduction on this account has therefore been made.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REDEMPTION OF DEBENTURES</head>
                    <p>The sale of the Savoy Hotel had allowed of the amortisation of the debenture debt of the company amounting to £35,000. The interest on these debentures at the rate of six per cent. constituted a heavy charge for the company, and the directors are confident, that should occasion to borrow arise in the future, they will be able to do so on more advantageous terms. As amortisation only commenced as from May 1, no change is shown in the balance-sheet in the total amount of debentures outstanding on 30th April, 1904.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RESERVE FUND</head>
                    <p>Out of a total issue of £35,000, £1.500 had already been redeemed ; this amount, being in the nature of a reserve, will now be definitely transferred to that fund which, with the propos ed addition of L.E. 10,000 and the existing sum of L.E. 541.164 m/m, will then amount to over L.E. 12,000. The directors have decided that the reserve fund shall be invested outside the ordinary business of the company.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>EMPLOYMENT OF CAPITAL</head>
                    <p>A portion of the company’s capital remain ing at the present time unengaged, the means by which it can be profitably employed are having the careful consideration of the board. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Mr. THUBRON’S RETIREMENT.</head>
                    <p>Mr. E. B. Thubron having informed the board that his numerous engagements did not admit of his devoting as much time to the business of the company as seemed to him desirable, an arrangement was concluded, dating from September 1, 1904, by which Mr. Thubron, while retaining certain benefits of contract, retiree from the service of the com nany as managing director.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DIVIDEND.</head>
                    <p>The directors propose to pay a dividend of 8% , and a bonus of 1 % and to carry forward a balance of L.E. 2,748.357 m/m. After making provision for depreciation and maintenance, interest on debentures and on the bank over draft, and the writing off of the whole of the preliminary expenses, there remains to be distributed on this season's working alone, a sum of…..L.E. 20,207 457
                        from which the directors pro pose to pay a dividend 5% ….        „    4,956,250
                        Leaving a balance of….L.E. 15,251,207 
                        To reserve account ….   10,000,000
                        10 % to board ….L.E. 5,251,207
                        525,120
                        Brought forward from last year…..L.E. 4,726 087
                        1, 987,270
                        L.E. 6,713,357
                        L.E.
                        Supplementary dividend 3%.. 2,973,750
                        Bonus of 1% 991,250   “   3,965,000
                        Carried forward to profit and loss account next year… L.E. 2,748,357</p>
                        <p>The directors have to announce with great regret the retirement of Mr. F.T. Rowlett from the board owing to pressure of work. Mr. Astley Friend, manager of the Cairo Water Works, has been elected to a seat on the board, and the general meeting will be asked to confirm his nomination.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.
                    DEPARTURE OP JAPANESE AGENT. ( From Our Correspondent.)</head>
                <p>Port-Said, Monday.</p>
                <p>
                    Mr. Tanaka, the Japanese Agent who has been in Port Said since December last, leaves for the East to-day on board the North German Lloyd S.S. “Sachsen.”</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIRE AT THE STATION.</head>
                    <p>Port-Said, Sunday.</p>
                    <p>Last night, one or two waggons filled with general merchandise, among which was a large quantity of petroleum, caught fire at the railway station. In a very short time a spare locomotive was brought along and the burning waggons were pulled away up a siding, where they were allowed to burn themselves out. No damage was done to the station itself.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHERCHEZ LA FEMME.</head>
                    <p>About 10.30 p.m. yesterday the police were summoned to what is commonly known as the rue Babel, in a particularly disorderly house of which, called the Hotel d'Athènes, a fight was in progress, terminating in a Greek firing with a revolver at another, and severely wounding him in the head. The cause of the discussion is somewhat shrouded in mystery, but there is no doubt that it is a case “cherchez la femme,” having due regard to the locality. The man was arrested and conveyed  to the caracol, and his victim taken in, an ambulance to the hospital, where, on enquiry, I learn he is progressing favorably.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GYMKHANA.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon, close to the tennis ground, there was held a Gymkhana, which, though in itself successful, was very sparsely attended owing to the fact of its taking place being so little known. It is said that several will be held this summer, at regular intervals.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ. RUSSIAN HOSPITAL SHIP.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Suez, Monday.</p>
                        <p>The British India steamer “Jelunga,” from Shanghai, chartered by the Russian Government as a hospital ship, arrived at Suez at 5 o'clock this morning, and entered the CaEal at 11 a.m. bound to Sebastopol. The “Jelunga” had on board 1,019 naval officers and men from the destroyed battleships and cruisers in Port Arthur, all of whom took an active put in the defence of the fortresses and were subsequently taken prisoners and released on '‘parole.” Several of the men were in a pitiful state, having their legs, arms, and eyes missing. Amongst the prisoners there were eight ladies who had acted as nurses at Port Arthur during the siege.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COAL FOR RODJESTVENSKY.</head>
                    <p>The Hamburg-Amerika liners “Batavia” and “Badenia,’ chartered by the Russian Government, returned to Sues and entered the Canal last Saturday evening and this day respectively, in ballast, after having delivered their cargo of coal to Admiral Rodjestvensky 's squadron near Madagascar.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH MISSION STARTING.</head>
                    <p>To-morrow morning a French mission, con sisting of one naval and one military officer and five other Frenchmen, accompanied by a Syrian doctor and escorted by about 60 Bedouins, with about 40 camels laden with water and pro visions, will start from Moses’ Wells en route to Muscat, in the Persian Gulf The mission will travel the whole way by camel, and its objects are said to be scientific and geographical.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO WATER SUPPLY.</head>
                    <p>It will be interesting to Cairo residents to learn that in a fortnight’s time
                        all possibility of shortage of water supply will be removed as by that time
                        the Water Company will have start ed pumping water from the artesian wells
                        at Rod-el Farag, which will enable them to pump an extra 25,000 cubic metres
                        of water per day, should the necessity arise. This method of water supply
                        will be continued for two years, when, if it is found satisfactory, the
                        system will be entirely adopted, and the present system done away with. But
                        in the meantime should the amount pumped from the artesian wells prove
                        insufficient they will be able to pump from the plant at present in use, end
                        thus prevent any shortage.</p>
                    <p>Regarding the insufficient supply, of which we have of late received
                        complaints, we learn that the maximum amount which the company is compelled
                        to pump per day, according to the contract with the Government, is 30,000
                        cubic metres, whereas they have pumped as much as 75,000 cubic metres in one
                        day. It is also interesting to note that they have pumped 68,101, 940 litres
                        of water so far this year, whilst during the corresponding period last year
                        they only pumped 44, 835, 880 litres, thus making an increase of 23, 266,
                        060 litres.</p>
                    <p>We have mentioned before that the price of ice as supplied by the company is
                        P.T. 3-5 per block. The company informs us that they sell the whole of the
                        ice produced to Messrs. Boehms and Anderer, who are under control not to
                        sell at any higher rate than P.T.3-5, whatever the consumption may be, and
                        it is only on account of people buying ice from other persons than the
                        recognised agents that a higher rate is paid.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>It is stated that the Sultan intends to confer the rank of Moushif on the
                        Regent and the Minister for Foreign Affairs.</p>
                    <p>The native Press is speculating a good deal on the reasons which led to the
                        selection of Boutros Pasha Ghali to accompany the Khedive to Europe. It is
                        said that he went to Constantinople in order to settle the question of the
                        Coptic Convent at Jerusalem. Another theory is that he is to be Prime
                        Minister on the retirement of Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, and so he has gone to
                        England to make himself acquainted with the King.</p>
                    <p>The Earl of Galloway, who is to be chairman of the new North Egypt Land
                        Company, is the eleventh holder of the title, and is concerned in no small
                        amount of land nearer home, the death of his brother four years ago having
                        made him not only an Earl but the owner of eighty thousand acres. Lord
                        Galloway was known until that event occurred as Captain Randolph Stewart, of
                        the Black Watch, a veteran of Crimea and of the Mutiny, and in October next
                        he will be entering upon his seventieth year. Descended from the Stewarts of
                        whom the Kings of Scotland and of England were a branch, Lord Galloway owes
                        his title to that Sir Alexander Stewart who, in 1607, was created Lord of
                        Garlies, and advanced to an earldom by James the Sixth in 1623.</p>
                    <p>H.E. Mokham el Dawla Mirza Mahmoud Khan arrived at Alexandria yesterday
                        evening from Cairo. His Excellency is leaving for Europe in order to be in
                        attendance on the Shah of Persia during his Majesty’s visit to Europe.</p>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive has conferred the grade of Mirmiran (pasha) on Amin Pasha
                        and Ghamzi, notables of Zagazig.</p>
                    <p>Lieut.-Gen. F. G. Slade is on promotion to retain his appointment as
                        Inspector-General of Royal Garrison Artillery.</p>
                    <p>Sir Wm. Willcocks’ journey to Constantinople is said to be connected with his
                        project for the irrigation of Mesopotamia.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Ruffer, Director of the Quarantine Service, will leave for England on the
                        15th of next month.</p>
                    <p>Contrary to former announcements, Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Governor of
                        Alexandria, will leave for Europe on June 17, and will be absent from Egypt
                        for, 3 ½ months.</p>
                    <p>El Miralai Matchett Bey, Commanding Cairo District, and El Bimbashi Clayton,
                        Deputy Assistant Adjutant General, who have been in Alexandria on duty,
                        returned to Cairo on Sunday.</p>
                    <p>Three months’ leave has been accorded to Saghcolaghasi V. Jarvis, Inspector
                        of Police, Cairo from June 22.</p>
                    <p>The following visitors are staying at the Beau Rivage Hotel, Ramleh: Mr. and
                        Mrs. G. D. Hornblower, Judge and Mrs. J.E. Marshall, the Misses Marshall,
                        Mrs. J. H. Farrar and courier, the Misses Farrar, Mr and Mrs. G. Heins and
                        family, Mr. and Mrs. A. Miller and family, Mr. W. S. Balls, Mr. F.S. Walton,
                        Mr. Temple, Mr. Edgeworth, Miss Lewis Stewart, Miss L. Wahrmer, Dr. and Mrs.
                        Amb. G. Ralli, Capt. and Mrs. W. H. Rotheram, Mr. and Mrs. B. Bernandos,
                        Miss A. Ardener, Miss H. Cay, Miss E. Mason.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                        correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to
                        permit---within certain necessary limits--free discussion.</p>
                    <p>A.S.C. AND PIGEON SHOOTING.</p>
                    <p>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</p>
                    <p>Sir,-- I was delighted to see the noble protest of your correspondent in
                        to-day’s “Gazette” against the scheme of having pigeon shooting at the
                        Alexandria Sporting Club. The latest London papers announce that this wicked
                        and cruel so-called “sport” has been expelled from Hurlingham. Every genuine
                        sportsman will rejoice at the decision of the Hurlingham Club to erase
                        pigeon shooting from the list of “sports” practised at the club. It would be
                        difficult to advance a single argument in favor of its continuance, save
                        that of ancient usage, from which standpoint is claims are equalled, if not
                        surpassed, by those of cock-fighting or bear-baiting. Even in its least
                        objectionable form, pigeon-shooting falls far below the modern standard of
                        sport, in the lack of a fair chance of escape for the quarry. In its lower,
                        hole-and-corner aspects, it lends itself to abominable cruelties, inflicted
                        upon the birds in order to affect their flight when they rise from the trap.
                        The value of Hurlingham’s decision lies not only in its immediate effect,
                        but in the promise which it holds out that either by force of example or by
                        actual legislation the “sport” may be abolished altogether throughout
                        England, and a blot which disfigures our sporting annals be thus for ever
                        removed. Let the A.S.C. take note, I am, Sir,</p>
                    <p> SPORTSMAN</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, May 29.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER </p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                    <div type="page" n="4">
                    
                </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </div>
</body>
    </text>
</TEI>