<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="subsection">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="subsection">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"><div type="item"><head>A SECOND 8UEZ CANAL.</head>
                <p>As supplementary to the remarks in our leading article yesterday we may state that one of the difficulties in the way of the con­struction of a second Suet Canal—assuming that the question whether the original con­cession gives the Canal Company a monopoly is shelved—is the supply of labor.</p>
                <p>The construction of the Canal in the ’sixties was only made possible at the start by the relentless application of the con-tie, and it was not till the ghastly loss of life and widespread suffering caused thereby had beoome a scandal in the eyes of Europe that Ismail Pasha ceased the supply of forced labour and paid a very large forfeit to the Company.</p>
                    <p>Lady Duff-Gordon’s letters, give a vivid description of the misery ; of the fellaheen at the time, and to-day no one dreams of reviving the abuses of the past But without the oorvto where is the labour fbr our hypothetical canal to be found 1 Tens of thousands of workmen most be fed and boosed. The coun­try near the canal produces nothing and there is no unemployed population in Egypt. Ask the fellaheen to come to the new canal and work—they will prefer'to cultivate their own fields. The towns have not enough work­men for buildings and poblio works, wages have risen with the prioe of commodities, and we doubt if the offer of P.T. 5 a day would attract a quarter of the neoessary laborers.</p>
                    <p>It remains to import labor—from wbat quarter t European workmen are too oostly, the Egyptian and other Governments ijould have a word to say about the employment of Chinese and Indian oooliee, and their transport and housing would enormously increase thd expenses of construction. These considerations alone seem to us to oondemn the scheme entirely.</p></div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 11, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PORT ARTHUR</head>
                        <head type="subsection">PRISONERS FOR JAPAN. MINES DESTROYED.</head>
                        <p>Port Arthur, January 10.</p>
                        <p>On the 6th inst. 5,000 men of the Russian garrison marched from Pigeon
                            Bay 15 miles to Chang-ling-tsu railway station, and thence took the
                            train for Dalny. Pathetic scenes occurred.</p>
                        <p>The Japanese have already repaired the railway and changed the gauge as
                            far as Port Arthur. Trains will be able to enter here in a few days.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>Tokio, January 10.</p>
                        <p>Large batches of Port Arthur prisoners are arriving in Japan daily.</p>
                        <p>It is officially announced that hitherto the mine-clearing vessels have
                            destroyed 395 mines within a radius of 40 miles from Port Arthur.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GENERALS STOESSEL AND NOGI.</head>
                        <head type="subsection">HONOURED BY THE KAISER</head>
                        <p>Berlin, January 10.</p>
                        <p>Emperor William has conferred the Order of Merit on Generals Stoessel and
                            Nogi. (Havas)</p>
                        <p>Berlin, January 10.</p>
                        <p>The Kaiser has confered the Order of Merit on Generals Stoessel and Nogi
                            in recognition of their heroic bravery at Port Arthur. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRENCH SENATOR AND THE WAR.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>M. Gouin, senior Senator, in his opening address to the Senate, said that
                            he hoped the new year would see the end of this bloody war between two
                            Powers, one of which has seen so many of its soldiers immolated in the
                            finest defence ever known, whilst the other has gained the admiration of
                            Europe by the greatness of the bravery which it has displayed.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>The Enquiry Commission has again discussed its mode of procedure
                            privately. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRENCH CHAMBER OF DEPUTIES.</head>
                        <head type="subsection">ELECTION OF M DOUMER.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>M. Doumer has been elected President of the Chamber of Deputies by 265
                            votes against 240 polled by M. Brisson. (Havas.)</p>
                        <p>Paris, January 10.</p>
                        <p>The Chambers have reassembled. Doumer, a notable opponent of M. Combes,
                            has been elected President of the Chamber by 265, defeating M. Brisson,
                            who polled 240 (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO.</head>
                        <p>Tangier, January 10.</p>
                        <p>M. René St. Taillandier will leave to-morrow for Fez in order to give
                            advice concerning reforms to the Moorish Government, who have declared
                            that they will abide by it. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GOLD FOR JAPAN.</head>
                        <p>San Francisco, January 10. The S.S. "China” is shipping half-a-million of
                            gold to-day from here for Japan. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>one night only Saturday, January 14, at 9.30. KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Under the distinguished Patronage and in the presence of: E. B. GOULD, Esq.,
                        I.S.O., H.B.M.’s Consul-General; Brig. General G. M. BULLOCK, C.B., and
                        Admiral Sir MASSIE and Lady BLOMFIELD.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <p>H. SCOTT LESLIE (The well-known London Entertainer and Raconteur) Will give a
                        Humorous and musical RECITAL Supported by Mr. David H. Norton, Pianist
                        (Queen's Hall, London). - - - - ADMISSION P.T. 20. M*4 M</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Rifle Meeting is to be hold in Cairo early in March, after the
                            manoeuvres.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at G.P.O., Alexandria, at 7.45 a.m.
                            to-morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Inspection.—Major-General Slade, C. B., will inspect the detachment of
                            the 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade at the Citadel, Cairo, to-morrow morning
                            at 9.30.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Bracale Orchestra plays at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, on Wednesday
                            afternoon and Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, and Saturday
                            evenings.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A GamBling Hell was raided on Monday morning by the Cairo police. It was
                            situated in Rue el-Mahdi and baccarat was being played at the time the
                            descent was made.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Italian Cruiser "Urania" (Capt. J. Tutinelli Reudina) arrived at Port
                            Said on Monday from Massowah, bound to Taranto. She carries 7 guns, and
                            has a crew of 124.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Zizinia Theatre.—Owing to the indisposition of Signa. Angelica
                            Pandolfini, there was no performance yesterday evening. This evening the
                            29th performance of the season will be given, when Siberia will be
                            staged.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Camel Post—Owing to the train service between Haifa and Kerma, and
                            vice-versa, having been discontinued on the 31st December, 1904, all
                            mails between these two places are now carried by camels, and the money
                            order service to and fromm stations on this line—other than Kosha—has
                            ceased.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Hired Transports "Plassy” and "Dilwara" are due to arrive at Port
                            Said on the 17th and 18th inst., respectively. Military details
                            proceeding home in the "Plassy" will leave Cairo by the 6.15 p.m. train
                            and Alexandria by the 3.30 p.m. train on the 16th, and those to go in
                            the "Dilwara" will leave Cairo and Alexandria by the trains leaving at
                            the same hours on the 17th instant.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Late Menshawi Pasha has bequeathed by his will properties producing
                            no less a sum than £40,000 a-year to various mosques and charitable
                            institutions in different parts of the country. His eldest son, who was
                            sentenced eleven years ago to penal servitude for 20 years for acts of
                            brigandage, has addressed a petition to the Khedive and the Government
                            for a remission of the remainder of his sentence.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Indicateur Egyptian for 1905 has made its nineteenth annual
                            appearance, and, usual, contains all the essentials which are so
                            conspicuous a feature of this old-establlshed directory. Mr. Stefano
                            Pottandi, the editor of the work, is to be congratulated, for many new
                            features have been added to this year's directory, which is the best of
                            its kind in the country. Tantah and many other provincial centres have
                            been included in this edition.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Recital. — Mr. Scott-Leslie, the society entertainer, is giving a recital
                            at the New Khedivial Hotel on Saturday next, at 9.30 p.m. Mr.
                            Scott-Leslie, who is an artiste to his finger tips, is almost too
                            well-known to need any recommendation on our part. He comes with an
                            excellent reputation, and we hope to see a large audience greet him on
                            Saturday. He is assisted by Mr. David W. Norton, pianist (Queen’s Hall,
                            London), and his programme includes pianotorte selections, musical
                            monologues, songs, character sketches, and funny stories, at telling
                            which Mr. Scott-Leslie is an adept.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo Hospitals and Nursing Homes. — As a proof of the immense increase
                            in the population of Cairo, and especially the European portion, during
                            the past twenty years or so, it is interesting to note that whereas in
                            1882 there were only three hospitals, viz., the European General
                            Hospital at Abbassieb, since, disused, the Kasr el Aïni Hospital, and
                            the Hospital for the Insane, there are now no less than fifteen
                            hospitals and nursing homes in the Metropolis, scattered over an area
                            extending over ten square miles. In this number are included the
                            different military hospitals for both British and Egyptian troops.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>E.T.C. Dramatic Entertainment at Suez. —The festivities in Suez to
                            commemorate the recent visit of a Port - Said football team culminated
                            on Friday last in an entertainment in the E. T. C. theatre, given by the
                            "Exiles" Dramatic Club. The first part of the programme was vocal.
                            "Good-bye, Dolly Gray" was well rendered by - Mr. Durrant, but it must
                            have been very sad for poor Dolly, who should have felt convinced of the
                            absolute finality of the poor man’s departure. Messrs. Churchill,
                            Dug-more, and Blyth were all good, but the “clou" was undoubtedly the
                            ventriloquial sketch by Mr. O. D. Harris; in fact, it has seldom been
                            our experience to hear a better sketch of this variety off the
                            professional stage. The second part, an original farce, '"The Mummy and
                            the Mummer,” by Mr. O. D. Harris, made many of the audience wonder
                            whether we have not in this gentleman a future Pinero. All the recent
                            political and social events in Suez were cleverly brought in by the
                            young author, and we hope an occasion will soon be found to give this
                            talented young dramatist an occasion to write another local sketch.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p> On Monday night the Khedive was present at the performance of Les Trois
                        Anaptistes at the Khedivial Opera House.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday morning, his Highness gave a private audience to the Grand Mufti,
                        Sheikh Mohamed Abdou.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE INTERVIEWED</head>
                    <p> A French journalist has published in the Parisian newspaper “Gil Bias" an
                        interesting account of an interview which be had with the Khedive on
                        December 20. The article concludes with the following anecdote :—</p>
                    <p>"Et pour terminer une anecdote que le Khédive nous a racontée au sujet du
                        mariage d’uue de ses sceurs qui alla visiter l’Exposition de Saint-Louis
                        l’été dernier avec son mari. Je laisse de nouveau la parole à Son
                        Altesse.</p>
                    <p>— J’ai toujours eu, nous dit-elle, la plus grande envie d’aller aux Etat-Unis
                        et, certes, je ne me serais jamais douté que la princesse, ma sœur, y irait
                        avant moi. Elle m’a, du reste, rapporté une collection magnifique de
                        photographies, dont plusieurs ont été prises dans des circonstances
                        extraordinaires. La princesse eut le malheur de se trouver dans un accident
                        de chemin de fer, mais au lieu de perdre la téte, comme presque toutes les
                        personnes qui l’en-touraient, elle photographia toute la scene! Il eu fut do
                        meme quand elle se trouva a bord d’un bateau à pétrole qui prit feu.</p>
                    <p>" Voilà qui est vraiment intéressant : le calme et la présence d’esprit de la
                        princesse égyptieune sont tout-à-lait dignes du pays ou elle les déploya—le
                        pays des femmes libres et fortes. "</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOLY CARPET.</head>
                    <p> The departure of the Holy Carpet will take place with trie usual ceremonial
                        on Thursday, 19th inst., at Cairo. The Khedive will preside and all the
                        Government administrations will be closed on that day.</p>
                    <p>The Mahmal and its escort will leave on the 20th and 21st inst. by special
                        trains for Suez en route for Jeddah.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of the Interior has decided that persons desirous of
                        accompanying the Mahmal caravan as pilgrims must be at Suez at the latest on
                        the 19th inst, when they must await the Mahmal. No pilgrim will be allowed
                        to leave Cairo by the special train which will convey the Mahmal.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                    <p> The Khedive has been most graciously pleased to confer the 3rd class
                        Osmanieh on El Miralai G. F. Gorringe Bey, C.M.G., D.S.O. Sudan
                        Government.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been moat graciously pleased to approve of the following
                        promotions;</p>
                    <p>El Bimbashi W. B. Drury, Sudan Government, to be Kaitnakam.</p>
                    <p>El Bimbasbi R. C. K. Owen, Sudan Govern-ment, to be Kaimakam.</p>
                    <p>Captain A. E J. Wilson, Northumberland Fusiliers, having reported his arrival
                        in Egypt from England, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army,
                        with the rank of Bimbashi and has been posted to the 13th Sudanese.</p>
                    <p>Paragraph 3, "War Office Gazette” No. 49, of 1904, striking El Kaimakam N.T.
                        Borton Bey, Sudan Government off the strength of the Egyptian Army from
                        1-12-04, has been cancelled.</p>
                    <p>The following transfers and appointments have been approved from dates
                        stated:— El Kaimakam A. Cameron Bey, Officer Commanding, Arab Battalion, to
                        Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi W. F. Sweny, 11th Sudanese, to be
                        Acting Officer Commanding, Arab Battalion, 1-1-05. El Bimbasbi H. D. E.
                        O'Sulivan, 12th Sudanese to Sudan Government, 1-1-05. El Bimbashi F. G.
                        Poole, D.S.O., 4th Battalion, to Sudan Government 1:1-05. .El Bimbashi J.C.
                        Gruhame, D.S.O., 12th Sudanese, to Sudan Government 1-0-05. El Bimbashi J.
                        H.M. Arden, 1st Battalion, to 4th Battalion, 1-1 05. El Bimbashi K. B.
                        Airey, Department of Supplies, to Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi L. W.
                        Le M. Carey, 10th Sudanese to 16th Battalion, 1-1-05. El Bimbashi R. L.
                        Moore, Cavalry, to Sudan Government 1-1-05. El Bimbashi A. Wise, 16th
                        Battalion, to 1st Battalion, 1-1-05.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BENSILUM CASE.</head>
                    <p> The verdict in the enquiry into the circumstances attending the death of Mr.
                        Angel Bensilum will not be given until Friday next. The enquiry has been
                        continuing at H.M.’s Consular Court, Cairo, but there are some more
                        witnesses to give evidence, including Herz Bey, in whose employ the deceased
                        was. The jury consists of Messrs. Biancardi, Spiro, and Heath. The report of
                        the discovery of the body of Mr. Bensilum in the Nile appeared in our
                        columns recently.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT AND JAPAN.</head>
                    <p> Some Turks living in Cairo sent a telegram of congratulation to the Mikado
                        on the fall of Port Arthur, to which his Majesty, has replied through his
                        Minister of the Imperial Household thanking them for their telegram.</p>
                    <p>Two leading Armenians of Cairo also wrote to Marshal Yamagata congratulating
                        him on the recent triumphs gained by the Japanese over the oppressors of the
                        Armenian inhabitants in the Caucasus, and sent a small case of cigarettes
                        manufactured specially at their factory and stamped with the arms of Japan
                        and the Marshal's initials for his own use. They have just received a letter
                        of thanks in reply, of which the two Armenians are very proud.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RUSSIAN SQUADRON</head>
                    <head type="subsection">MOORED AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p> (From Our Own Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Port-Said, Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Batrovsky’s Squadron was off the port at 2.30 p.m. and the ships are
                        now all moored in the positions specified in my wire of yesterday. They will
                        be permitted to take fresh water, provisions, and a limited quantify of
                        coal.</p>
                    <p>The squadron consists of 4 cruisers, “Oleg, "Izumrud," "Rion,” and "Dnieper,”
                        and 3 torpedo-boat destroyers, “Rezvi,” “Gromki,” and "Grozin."</p>
                    <p>The time of entry into the canal is not yet fixed.</p>
                    <p>The British yacht .“Emerald,” which preceded the last squadron and cruised in
                        the Red Sea, has also arrived from Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The Coast Guard cruiser “Abbas” entered the harbour after the fleet.</p>
                    <p>The town is full of Russian secret agents, but there is only one Japanese
                        here.</p>
                    <p>The Russian Diplomatic Agent, and Russian Naval Attache arrived from Cairo
                        last night, also a force of extra police.</p>
                    <p>The same precautions will be taken as were taken when the last fleet
                        passed.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that nothing is known at the British Agency in reference to
                        the alleged protest made by the Japanese Government against the supply of
                        fresh water and provision to the fleet</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ CANAL PILOTS.</head>
                    <p> While the present agitation against the treatment meted out to shipowners
                        generally by the Suez Canal Company is before the public, an opportunity is
                        afforded of drawing attention to another instance, in which justice, at
                        least, is not done to British shipowners, namely, in the pilotage
                        service.</p>
                    <p>To deal with the 4,000 ships which annually either transit the Canal or touch
                        at Port Said and Suez, the company employs some 94 pilots of various
                        nationalities, as follows:--</p>
                    <p>No. of Pilots National percentage of shipping in transit.</p>
                    <p>Greek 29 0.2</p>
                    <p>Italian 20 1.9</p>
                    <p>French 16 7.0 </p>
                    <p>Austrian 14 3.4</p>
                    <p>British 11 60.6</p>
                    <p>German 2 13.1 </p>
                    <p>Dutch 1 5.9</p>
                    <p>Danish 1 0.3</p>
                    <p>The figures speak-for themselves. Surely the number of British pilots should
                        be increased proportion to the percentage of British vessels.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PORT OF ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p> We are glad to see that the London newspapers are beginning to take up the
                        question of dock deficiency at Alexandria, and Mr. Cornish's article on the
                        subject has been quoted at home.</p>
                    <p>The "Standard" of December 31st, in the course of some oomments on the
                        subject from its Manchester correspondent, remarks :—</p>
                    <p>In the course of an interview yesterday with a representative of the firm of
                        Messrs. Gough and Crosthwaite, who are among the largest shippers from
                        Manchester to Egypt, our correspondent was informed that there had been, and
                        were now, delays in the discharging of cargoes at Alexandria, owing to the
                        lack of proper dock space. In some instances the delays were very serious,
                        especially in the case of vessels which had to proceed up the Syrian Coast
                        alter leaving Alexandria. The shipments to the last-named port were steadily
                        growing, the increase in the last ten years having been somewhere about
                        fifty per cent, and it was absolutely necessary, in the interests of the
                        country generally, that steps should be taken as promptly as possible for
                        affording proper facilities for loading and unloading boats with despatch.
                        He was greatly pleased to find that the International Chamber of Shipping
                        had taken up the question, and hoped it would be pushed forward with
                        vigour.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A LETTER OF MOHAMED.</head>
                    <p> Cairo magazines are not often honored by newspaper notice written by learned
                        profes-ssors, but the November number of the verna-cular contemporary Hilal
                        has obtained the signal honor of a disquisition by Professor Margoliouth in
                        the latest issue to hand of the Athenaeum. The occasion was the publication
                        in the Hilal of of a photographic reproduction of the supposed original of
                        Mohamad’s letter to the “Mukaukis.” Of this document an account was given by
                        M. Belin in a letter to Reinaud, published in the Journal Asiatique for
                        December, 1854; a certain M. Etienne Barthélemy declared that he had
                        discovered it in the binding of a MS. purchased by him at Akhmim. Sir W.
                        Muir, in his 'Life of Mohamet,’ vol. i. p. lxxvii (1857), said it was
                        desirable that the genuineness of this singularly acquired document should
                        be further discussed by the scholars of Europe; and in the Zeit-schrift der
                        DM.G., x. 543 (1856), there is a brief note by Rӧdiger, who thought the
                        genuineness doubtful, yet on the whole probable. Nӧldeke, ‘Geschichte des
                        Korans’ (1860) pp. 140, 302, expressed his conviction of its genuineness:
                        "Ein Original, an dessen Echtheit nicht zu zweifeln ist" The photograph,
                        reproduced by Zaidan, was taken from the original before it went into the
                        collection of relics of the Prophet in Constantinople</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID</head>
                    <head type="subsection">(FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT).</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ACCESSION DAY.</head>
                        <p>Port Said, Tuesday.</p>
                        <p>A reception was held at the Gouvernorat by the Governor, assisted the
                            Sub-Governor, on Sunday. The consular representatives and prominent
                            citizens called and paid their respects. The Lyre Band played selections
                            of music on the terrace of the Gouvernorat during the reception, and a
                            guard of honor saluted the consular representatives upon their arrival
                            and departure. After the recep-tion the guard marched past to the music
                            of the Lyra Band.</p>
                        <p>The whole of the proceedings were favored with most beautiful weather. A
                            word of praise in due to the extremely smart turn-out ff the police. The
                            march-past was perfectly executed, and the bearing of the men was smart
                            and soldiery.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WELL-DESERVED HONORS.</head>
                        <p> News Has’ just been received that the Khedive has conferred the Order of
                            the 3rd Class Meedjidieh on the Sub Governor, Hassan Bey Kassib. The
                            news has given the liveliest satisfaction here, both gentlemen being
                            held in high esteem, in their official as well as in their private
                            capacity.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head>
                        <p> H.M.S. "Essex" is due at Alexandria on the 26th inst. The Duke and
                            Duchess of Connaught will atonce proceed to Cairo, whence they will
                            depart on the following day for Luxor. They are due at' Luxor the 28th
                            inst., Assouan the 29th inst., Wady Halfa the 39th inst., and Khartoum
                            on the 2nd proxo.</p>
                        <p>The Duke arid Duchess will be accompanied by the Princess Margaret and
                            Patricia of Connaught.</p>
                        <p>Nothing is as yet known as to the duration of the stay of the Duke and
                            Duchess of Connaught at Khartoum. It is quite possible that the Duke of
                            Connaught will take the opportunity of having some big game shooting on
                            the White Nile.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
                        <p> Yesterday's plague bulletin records a fresh case, a death in hospital,
                            and a cure at Suez, and a cure at Port Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO FETES</head>
                        <p> At the last meeting of the Cairo Fêtes Committee, held at the Grand
                            Continental Hotel, it was decided to add to the programme of the
                            festivities to be given in Cairo this season, and of which we have
                            already published the list, a high-class concert, to take place on
                            .Wednesday,18th instant, at the Savoy Hotel.</p>
                        <p>The battle of flowers at Ghezireh will be held on the 5th February and
                            the Grand Corso, or Carnival procession in town, has been finally fixed
                            for the 7th March.</p>
                        <p>A working or executive sub-committee composed of seven members has been
                            formed to carry out the details of the several projects that have
                            already met with the approval of the general committee, or any others
                            which, ay be decided upon later on in the season.</p>
                        <p>A vote of thanks was at the last meeting accorded to .Mr. Baehler for tbe
                            excellent arrangements made at Shepheard’s Hotel, which greatly
                            contributed .to trie success of the ball that was held there last
                            Wednesday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“ORIENT AND OCCIDENT.”</head>
                        <p> A new publication has made its appearance under this title. It is a
                            weekly moral and religious magazine, and is to be conducted on the
                            broadest lines, as indicated by the motto adopted, “God bath made of one
                            blood all nations of men for to dwell on the face of the earth.” Part of
                            the first number is in English, a second part in English and Arabic, and
                            the remainder in Arabic only. A very ably written article, and one of
                            great general interest, is entitled ''What the West has learned from the
                            East.” Another, on “The Drink Question in Egypt,’’ is well worthy of
                            being carefully studied.</p>
                        <p>We welcome the new magazine, and heartily wish its editors the Revs.WH.T.
                            Gairdner and D.M. Thornton, every success in their attempt to rouse
                            interest in subjects of such importance as those that they propose to
                            bring to the attention of their readers. The effort is one worthy of
                            support, and should be instrumental in bridging racial enmities and
                            prejudices, or at least lessening the harm they do. So long as the fact
                            is fully recognised that it is possible to work for good quite
                            independently of religious belief, and that there is no necessity to
                            intrude dogma into efforts for the moral and social advancement of the
                            people;-- so long and no longer will efforts of this nature deserve the
                            success they seek to obtain.</p>
                        <p>“Orient and Occident” is published at Bait Arabi Pasha,Cairo, and the
                            annual subscription is P.T. 25, post free.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p> The Ellerman S.S. “Britannia” sailed yes-terday for Liverpool direct
                            with general cargo.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CAIRO GRAND HAMMAM r - " ..wvn ffaiii mir iutr-.V- n</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Nungovich Bey will accompany the Duke and Duchess of Connaught on their
                            trip to Khartoum, where they will arrive on the 2nd February.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Earl of Londesborough and Lord George Cholmondeley, who are at
                            present at Khartoum, are expected back at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, about
                            the 18th inst. Lady Londesborough will come out from England the same
                            week.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>After visiting the Pyramids in the company of the Marquis Salvago-Raggi,
                            the Marquis di Rudini left on Monday night for a fortnight's trip to the
                            Sudan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>H.E. the Governor of Alexandria left for Cairo this morning, and will
                            probably remain four days in the Capital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Brevet Major Martyn, Royal West Kent Regiment has been selected for
                            employment with the Egyptian Army.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Capt. Collins, D. S. O., Royal Berkshire Regiment' will shortly leave the
                            depot at Reading and join headquarters at Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Monroe Coats and a big party are expected at the Savoy on the 23rd
                            inst., arriving by the “Schleswig.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. and Mrs. Livingston, who were at the Savoy for a long time two years
                            ago, are expected there shortly.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>In consequence of Mr. Wakeman Long’s appointment as judge of the Native
                            Tribunal, Me. Demetriades, with whom the new judge was associated, has
                            taken into partnership Mr. Frederick Leveaux, who is an English
                            solicitor and a member of the Cairo Bar.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mrs. Robert Goelet’s steam yacht, the "Nahima," is now out of dry dock at
                            Greenock, and is expected to leave for the Mediterranean next week.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said; are Mr. and Mrs.
                            A. Robin-son, Mr. Hugh Cayley, Mr. von Posch, Mr. Glucther, Mr.
                            Barthell, Mr. Henry Lants, Mr. Louis Dohme, Mr. S. V. Schieston, M. and
                            Mme. Maximoff, Commandant and Mme. Schwank, Herr von Blucher, Mlles. von
                            Blucher, Mr. Rhouberg and Baron von Koenig.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The following are the passengers by the P.S. “Rameses, which left Cairo
                            yesterday : Mr. S. Bourgeois, Mr. and Mrs. Steinmeyer, Mr. and Mrs. G.
                            Brauer, Mr. Alfred John, Mr. H. J. Martin, Miss M. A. Martin, Mr. R.
                            Jackson, Mr. and Mrs. Thott, Dr. and Mrs. Frank Vanderoel, Mr. and Mrs.
                            E. Raymal, Miss Creardson, Miss Lindsay; Mr. Julian B. Huff, Mr. Evander
                            B. Schley, Mr. Girardelli, Mr. and Mrs. Fairchild, Miss Regina Jaffe,
                            Mrs. Grete Kreffer, Mr. and Mrs. A. Congreve, Mr. and Mrs. W. P. Beaver,
                            Miss Mary Chamberlain, Miss Edith Furst, Miss Waterhouse, Miss H. Agnes
                            McKelvey, Mrs. H. Schou, Mr. C. E. Day, Mr. and Mrs. W. G. Henshaw,
                            Misses Henshaw, Master Henshaw, Miss Grimes, Mr. Henry Swindells, Miss
                            Marie Booth, Col. Robt. J. Pratt Saunders, C.B., Capti Ulgo. Bedinello,
                            Miss Augusta Bedinello Mr. Wm. Johnston, Miss E. W. Johnston, Mr.
                            William H. Reeves, Mr. Egon von Szentivanyi.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <head type="subsection">ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Le paquebot Salazie, des Messageries Mari-times arrive hier de Marseille,
                        avait a bord:</p>
                    <p>Mr. Jas. Peekie, Mr. E. R. Alderson, M. Leon Moch, Mr. Arth. Moch, Mr.
                        AIgnier, Mr. et Mme J. Moray, Mr. Alchewtki, Dr. Loew, Mr. Arloing, Mr. L.
                        Laurens, Mr. Sezary, Mr. Billard, Mr. Vacher, Mr. J. W. Barrett, M. et Mme
                        de Grandcourt, M. Louis de Grandcourt, Mme Chauliaguet, M. et Mlle Robinson,
                        Mme Clarke, M. et. Mme Zeky bey Kahlar, M. et Mme Barbier, M. Bijard, Frere
                        Etienne, M. Nicolas, M. Antony, M. Assayas, M. Deater, M. Smith, M. R.
                        Hacco, M. C. Shakespeare, M. F. Lebon, M. Triadon, Freres Sylvanus and
                        Pergentinus, M. Pritmann et 22 passagers de 3 éme et 4 éme classe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE</head>
                    <head type="subsection">TOURIST FACILITIES AT KHARTOUM.</head>
                    <p>A steamer will meet the express train due at Khartoum North on Mondays and
                        Fridays, and will leave the Station Landing Place for the Post Office
                        landing Place Khartoum at 7 a.m. conveying Officers, Officials and others
                        who may Wish to land at that point.</p>
                    <p>The Steamer will return to the Station Landing Place and leave at 8 a.m. for
                        the Hotel direct conveying tourists and their baggage, afterwards proceeding
                        to Omdurman. Post office is ten minutes walk from the Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Passengers not in possession of through tickets to Khartoum or Omdurman will
                        be charged fares as under:—</p>
                    <p>Khartoum. Omdurman.</p>
                    <p>1st Class P.T. 5 P.T.10</p>
                    <p>3rd Class P.T. 2 P.T. 3</p>
                    <p>Trips are arranged to Omdurman, the battlefield of Kerreri and the Blue
                        Nile.</p>
                    <p>Messrs, Thos. Cook and Son’s Agent</p>
                    <p>(Signed) E. E. Bond, Miralai,</p>
                    <p>Director of Steamers and Boats</p>
                    <p>25225-1-8</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>L’anglais, langue judiciaire</head>
                    <p>Monsieur Directeur</p>
                    <p>de Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                    <p>L'admissdm de U laûjue anglaise aux tri­bunaux de?la IWfort .iKôüt un fiait
                        d'autant plus importait qug l'organisme mixte est ap­pelé à vivre un oo«àuu
                        nombre d’aunées encore, surtout depuis la séparation des- "bureaux de
                        publioité" de l’Administration de la Justioe, a laquelle d’ailleurs, par
                        leur essence même, iis étaient complètement étrangers. Ce qui re­tardera
                        encore davantage la chute de œtte institution, et la fera survivre aux
                        autres créa­tions mixtes, c'est la difficulté de la reniptaCei\ Soulever la
                        question de l’abrogation des capi­tulations est une maladresse sa us
                        exemple, le le pays n’étant pas encore mûr pour un change­ment aussi
                        radical. Confier aux tribunaux indi­gènes le lourd héritage que leur
                        laisserait les tribunaux Mixtes serait h l’heure actuelle une mesure
                        prématurée, malgré les progrès réalisés par ces tribunaux depuis leur
                        fondation.</p>
                    <p>D'autre part, pour exercer leur juridiction indistinctement sur toute la
                        population, l'orga­nisation des Tribunaux indigènes devrait étie modifiée,
                        surtout en ce qui couoerue les langues étrangères, qui ne sont pas admises
                        en ce mo­ment, mais qui seront toujours usitées et cou­rantes en Egypte, de
                        par la situation géogra­phique et commerciale du pays.</p>
                    <p>Dans les tribunaux dos Etats-Unis des juges européens ont été engagés pour
                        juger les étrangers. Les différentes langues européennes sont aussi admises
                        dans certaines localités. Le ^système est suivi pour ce qui oonceme la
                        po­lice et la justice sommaire en Alsace-Lorraine et ailleurs.</p>
                    <p>Cette constatation en faveur des langues étrangères est un argument de plus
                        pour justi­fier l'admission de l’anglais dans les cours de justice. Cette
                        langue est, d’ailleurs, devenue presque indispensable &amp; la suite du
                        grand développement qu'elle a pris dans le pays, par la multiplication des
                        sociétés et. maisons de commerce britanniques, par l'importance du commerce
                        de l'Egypte avec l'Angleterre et enfin par la présence d'une importante
                        oolouio anglaise qui vient chaque hiver accroître le nombre des touristes
                        anglo-américains.</p>
                    <p>Les propositions de Lord Cromer, auxquelles la France est sur le point
                        d’adhérer, peuvent être considérées, d’ores et déjà, comme un fait accompli.
                        On objectera, peut-être, qu’il e$t dif­ficile d’imposer aux magistrats ia
                        connaissance de quatre langues judiciaires. Mais combien;y a-t-il de juges
                        européens qui connaissent l'A­rabe, qui est pourtant une langue judiciaire!—
                        Il y en a aussi qui comprennent fort peu l'Ita­lien et le Français. En teras
                        cas ceux qui con­naissent l'Anglais sont assez nombreux et le nombre des
                        greffiers possédant cette langue au Tribunal Mixte d'Alexandrie est assez
                        im­portant.</p>
                    <p>Veuillez agréer, etc.</p>
                    <p>Rhadamante</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie le 10 janvier 1905.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Débouchés Possibles</head>
                    <p>Nous extrayons de ""l'Exportation Française'' un intéressant article sur
                        l'Egypte, en taut que débouché</p>
                    <p>Il y a actuellement en Egypte nombre de débouchés dont les exportateurs ne
                        devraient pas se désintéresser. La prospérité croissante et l'accroissement
                        de la population ont donné naissance à toute une série de projets pour la .
                        distraction et la récréation du public. A Alex­andrie, on se propose de
                        construire dans le Fort-Rit, deux jetées-promenades en fer. Ces I jetées
                        seront arrangées de la même mauière que les stations baluéaires ordinaires.
                        La Mu­nicipalité fait tracer un grand parc dans les faubourgs de la ville et
                        la Compagme des Tram­ways d'Alexandrie a obtenu la permission de construire
                        une nouvelle ligne de tramways allant jusqu’à ce parc.</p>
                    <p>Des demandes de concessions ont été faites pour la construction de casinos,
                        l'un à l'extré­mité de la jetée dans le port de l’Est, l'autrq, à Mariout,
                        qui est un nouveau faubourg.</p>
                    <p>Le chemin de fer de Mariout qui est la pro­priété du Khédive, doit être
                        prolongé jusqu’au centre de La ville. Une compagnie à laquelle serait
                        intéressée la "Société Egyptienne des Etudes et Travaux'' est en formation
                        pour la construction d’un casino avec bains, restaurant et club, à
                        Port-Saïd. La même compagnie a demandé la concession de tramways électriques
                        qui iront du casino dans toutes les parties de la ville. A Tantah, Menchaoui
                        Pacha, le plus riche propriétaire foncier de la contrée, a décidé de faire
                        construire un grand théâtre dans le goût le plus moderne et on parle de la
                        construction d'un nouveau tbôfttre au Caire. Il existe plus d’un projet
                        d’hôtel pour le Caire, et à Alexandrie, on s'est décidé à construire un
                        hôtel de premier ordre à la station terminas des ohemius de fer électriques
                        de Ramleb. Le trafic de ces chemins de 1er augmente dans une telle
                        proportion qu'on va être obligé de conrtoander un grand nombre de voitures
                        en plus pour suffire aux besoins, l’été prochain. Il se pourrait que la même
                        compagnie achetât des rails.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" scope="financial">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>Aujourd hui à midi et demie)</p>
                    <p>Le marché manque d’entrain aujourd'hui. Les réalisations causent un certain
                        malaise et 1 c'est en baisse qu’on a clôturé ce matin pour certaines
                        valeurs.</p>
                    <p>On offre la Banque Nationale &amp; 24 5/16, l’Agrioole à 10 1/16, les Eaux
                        d’Alexandrie à 16, les Eaux du Caire à 1100 et les Privilé­giées Tramways à
                        144.</p>
                    <p>La Béhéra est en demande à 51, la Daïra à 32 8/16, la Filature K 16/16, les
                        Markets à 24 et la Banque d’Athènes à 123 3/4.</p>
                    <p>Le Sait &amp; Soda fléchit à 41/3, l'Anglo-Ameri- ÇftoNileki 15/16 et la
                        Khédivial Mail à 3 8/é,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Délégation Municipale</head>

                    <head type="subsection">(Communication officitüt)</head>

                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s’est réunie le 10 janvier 1905 soua la présidence
                        de M. Ambroise A. Ralli.</p>

                    <p>Présenta : MM. E. Benachi, P. Penderl, Manaour Bey Youasef, Soliman Bey
                        Abani, K. Strosa, membres, W. P. Chataway, administrateur, I. Sedky,
                        secrétaire.</p>

                    <p>La Délégation accepte une oession d’nne rue faite par M. Kamel Boy Teymour, à
                        Ramleh.</p>

                    <p>Elle soumettra h la Commission Municipale un projet de construction d’une
                        jetée promenade dans la baie des quais du Port-Est</p>

                    <p>Diverses demandes pour l'installation de services de voitures automobiles
                        sont ajournées, en attendant l'étude de la question de principe dont le
                        Comité du Contentieux est chargé.</p>

                    <p>La Délégation autorise une dépense supplémentaire pour l’installation de
                        bouches d’arrosage sur la route do Ramleh.</p>

                    <p>Elle soumettra à la Commission Municipale un état défiais nécessités pour la
                        transformation du jardin Nouzha.</p>

                    <p>Sur rapport des servioee, la Délégation dé-oide de confier à Mr. Stefacelli
                        Luigi, adjudicataire des travaux de construction d’une aile à la
                        bibliothèque, les nouveaux travaux de surélévatifin décidés par la
                        Commission pour l’aménagement do nouvelles Balles.</p>

                    <p>Une lettre du Ministère de l’Intérieur contenant approbation du colleoteur
                        Est sera soumise à la Commission.</p>

                    <p>La séanoe est levée à 8 h. p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>

            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> <div type="section"><head>ACCESSION HONOURS.</head>
                <p>The following is a list of the most prominent people who have received grados and decora­tions on the occasion of the anniversary of tho Khedive's accession »</p>
                <div type="subsection"><head>ministry of the interior.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>Civil, OFFICIALS.</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>GRADES.</head>
                        <p>Moutamaiz. Aly Siddick Bey, Sub-Governor of Cairo.
                            Sanieh. Mukamed iieddaya Bey, Gouver- norat of Alexandria, Ismail Sidky Bey, Admi­nistrative Secretary, Municipality of Alexan dria, G. Norsa Bey, Financial Secretary, Muni­cipality of Alexandria.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p> r Osmanieh. Grand Officer (2nd Class) : Adly Yeghen Pasha, Governor of Cairo.
                            Commander (3rd Class): Mustapha Ibadi Pasha, Governor of tho Suez Canal, Dr. Johu Waraock, Director of the Lunatic Asylum.
                            Officer (4th Class) : Kaiuiakam Snow Bey, Chief Inspector, Coast Guards, H. Can tel Bey, Sub-Director, Miuistry of the Interior, Gaston Buhl, Sub-Director, Sanitary Service, Elvidio D’Orsi, Chief Engineer, Ministry of the Interior, L. E. Corringe, Inspector, Servioe of the Re­pression of the Slave Trade, Dr. J. Batko,. Chief Physician, Quarantine Office, Suez, Oscar Dinkier, Chief Pharmacist, Sanitary, Servioe. Rodolphe Arnster, Chief Storekeeper to the Sanitary Service.
                            Medjidieh. Grand Officer (2nd Class) Harvey Pasha, Inspector, Ministry of the Interior,- Hassan Radwan Pasha, Moudir of Gharbiuh, Mustapha Mao or Pasha, Moudir of Dakhalieh.
                            Commander (3rd Class): Dr. John Garner, Inspector of Sanitary Department, Antoiue Mesciaca Bey, Sanitary Department, E. A. Branch, Inspector, Veterinary Department, Gobrau Muscat Bey, Chief of the Security, Gouveruorat of Cairo, Dr. P. Trfhaki, Sanitary Delegate of Denmark on the Quarantine Board, G. Harlsmendy, ex-Sanitary Delegate for Pranoe on the Quarantine Board.
                            Officer (4th Class) : L. de A vierino, Chief Clerk, Quarautiue Board, Henry Cooper, Inspector,Veterinary Department, Mix Powell, Inspector of the Cairo Scavenging and Watering Service.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>police officers.</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head><p>
                        Otmanieh. Commander (3rd Class): El Miialai Shalch Bey, Commaudant of the Suez Canal Police.
                        Medjidieh. Officer (4th Class): V. H. Jarvis, Inspector, Cairo Police, C. D’Aubuz, Iuspector, Alexandria Police, Nicolas de Turis, Moawen, Suez Police.
                        Chevalier (5th class): Paul Langermann mamour of kisiu, Alexandria, Hafez Amin effeudi, mamour of kisin, Alexandria, Angelo Frauri, moawen, Alexandria Police, Fraucesco Loschiavo, moawen, secret police, Cairo Qouver- norat, Emmauuel Dobarro, chief engineer, Cairo Fire Brigade</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>NOTABLES.</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p>Otmanieh. Grand Officer (2nd Class): Am- broise Ralli, Vice-President of the Municipal Commission of Alexandria.
                            Commander (3rd Class) Emmanuel Benachi, Municipal Commission of Alexandria, Louis Escoffier, Municipal Commission of Alexandria, Ahmed Veins Bey, Municipal Commission of Alexandria
                            Officer (4 th class;: Yanni Giovanni Gregorio, late of the Municipal Commission of Mansou- rah, Alfred Maksud, late French vice-consul at Mansourah.
                            Medjidieh.—Grand Officer (2nd class) : Albert Bey, of the Municipal Commission of Alexandria	—-
                            Commander (3rd class) : Emmanuel Stress, of the Municipal Commission of Alex­andria, Georges Zouro, of the Municipal Comiiiissiou of Alexandria, Paul Penderl, of the Municipal Commission of Alexandria, Man- sour Youssef Bey, of the Municipal Commission of Alexandria, Noel Henry Beyts, General Agent of the Kbedivial Mail Line at Suez.
                            Officer (4th class): Henri Fould, of the Local Commission of Fayoum.</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>MINISTRY OF PUBLIC WORKS.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>GRADES.</head><p>
                        Sanieh.—Michel Zananiri Bey, 3rd Circle
                        of Irrigation.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head><p>
                        Otmanieh: Commander (3rd class) :—Mah­moud Sidky (Bey, Inspector of Irrigation of the 5th Circle, Hussein Wassif Bey, director of the Girgeh irrigation works.
                        Officer (4tli class) : — Arthur Adamson,' director of works (3rd Circle ot Irrigation).
                        ?Medjidieh, Grand Officer (2nd class) :	
                        Fi-rid Babasougli Bey, chief of the adminis- • trative service of the Central Administration.
                        Commander (3rd class) : W. R Williams, in­spector of the 3rd Circle ot Irrigation, P. M. Tottenham, Inspector of the 4th Circle pi Officer (4th class) J. D. Waghorn, direct tor of the Assiout Barrage.
                        n„ administration</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>PORTA(w’ TELEGRAPH8 AND PORT OR ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>GRADES.</head><p>
                        Sanieh George Baine B-y, ^ 0ttJ -</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS</head><p>	7
                        R?Ts,.i™r“d“a'dd“>
                            Medjidieh : Commander (3rd class): la Gobrial Bey, J. B. Malaval, engineer of im­port of Alexandria
                            Officer (4th class): J. Diaeomidis,—Plum, stationmaster at Isniailia.
                            Chevalier (5th c'ass): Em. Giovanelli, specter of trafic, Romano Paoletti inspector tf Telegraphs,</p></div></div><cb n="1"/>
                <div type="subsection"><head>MINISTRY
                    OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>GRADES.</head>
                        <p>Moutamaiz : Ismail Hassanein Bey, head­master, Ras el-Tin Scjiool.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p>Otmanieh : Commander)(3rd class): Dr. "Mu Jtenzie, director of the Polytechnic School and School of Agriculture, Bernard Bey, in­spector in the Ministry.
                            Officer (4th class) : Dr. F. Milton, professor I at the School of Medicine.
                            Medjidieh : Commander (3rd' class) : M. I Sharman, head-master of the Khedivieh School.!</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>MINISTRY FOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p>Otmanieh. Officer (4th class)-. Artin Stephan Bey, head of the translation bureau. 		</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>MINISTRY OF FINANCE.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>GRADES.</head>
                        <p>Mirmiran : Khalil Hamdy Harnada Pasha, Director of the Alexandria Custom House.
                            Moutamaiz .- Selim Michalla Bay, Director of the Tobacoo Department at the Direotioa General of Customs.
                            Sanieh : John Falconer Bey, Port Captain at Suez.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p>Otmanieh, Offioer (4th class): Socrates Spiro Bey, director at the Ports and Lighthouses.
                            Medjidieh, Grand Offioer (2nd class) : Rear- Adioiral Sir M. Blomddld,Coutruilor-General of Purts aud Lighthouses.
                            Offioer (4tli class): Charles Randall, inspector of the Customs Guards, Cesare Musso, local director of the Cairo Post Office.
                            Chevalier, (5th class)": Edmond Ivoy, chief mechanic and electrician at the National Printing Office, Alexander Goldstein, section mamour at the Alexandria Customs.</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>MINISTRY OF JUSTICE.</head> <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                    <p>Otmanieh: Grand Officer (2ud class) : Mr. W. B. Brunyate, khedivial counsellor, director of the legal department, Saleh Sabet Pasha, President, Court of Appeal.
                        Commander (3rd elaas) : M. Halton, Judge, Court of Appeal.</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>PUBLIC DEBT COMMISSION.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>DECORATIONS.</head>
                        <p>Otmanieh : Officer (4th class) : Maurice Chaffin, Jacques Wieland, and S4bastien Oamugli.
                            Medjidieh : Commander (3rd class) : Pierre Riga Bey and Alfida Froli.
                            Medjidieh : Officer (4 th class) : Serafino Mirauduli and Riooardo Hopper.</p></div></div>
                <div type="subsection"><head>STATE DOMAINS.</head>
                    <p>Otmanieh: Commander (3rd class): M. Jules Douzieh.
                        Officer (4th class): Adrien Hdnon Bey. Medjidieh : Commander (3rd class) : J. B. Piot Bey.</p></div></div>
            
            <div type="item"><head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT</head>
                <p>The first portion of the Corporation of Western Egypt’s expedition despatched to the oases by Messrs. Lake and Carrie, the consult­ing engineers to the corporation, and consisting of surveyors, mechanics and boring men, arriv­ed at Farshut, on the Nile, on the 1st inst, and are now busily engaged in arranging for the transport of the drilling plant and a large amount of stores and material to the aoses of Dakhla and Kharga, where extensive boring aud prospecting operations will be commenced at a very early date. Elaborate arrangements have been made by the directors and officials of the corporation for the conduct of the work, and important developments may be expected jn the western oases in the near future. \*</p></div><cb n="2"/>
            <div type="item" scope="sporting"><head>ROYAL HENLEY WEEK.</head>
                <head type="subsection">THE MOST FAMOUS OF REGATTAS.</head>
                <p>Not to know'Henley argues one’s self un­known in the Rowing world. No aquatio event since Noah set sail in the Ark interests so many jpeoplo as the great July week at Henley The famous Regatta Course is lined with House-boats visited by all that are famous and fashionable. The races themselves attract oarsmen from all tho world, from Yale to Parramatta.	s</p>
                    <p>Racb-Boats and Housb-Boats.</p>
                        <p>A racing boat, with its thin mahogany plauks, its wide outriggers and sliding seats, designed to give the long, long pull which sjiells victory in a race, are veritable works of art. Sp, in their way are the House-boats whioh wealthy families use as Summer Homes, resting here a week,' there a month or more, on the Banks of the Thames. And most of’all they congregate at Henley.</p>
                            <p>A UtnUy House-Boat.</p>
                                <p>The fact that the eyes of all England are on Henley every year gives special interest to the words ot a Henley man, Sir. Charles Sarney, in a local paper. Pour years ago, ween he was lying helpless in Reading Hospital with para­lysis and spiual disease, Mr. Sanity thought bo would never be able to handle oar or scull again. For the hospital authorities told him he was incurable, aud sent lor his friends to take him away.</p>
                                <p>‘•But," said Mr. Sarney (whose home is at Royal Oak Cottage, Gniy's-road, Henley), "I read in a newspaper of a mau, afflicted like myself, who had been completely restored to health by Dr. Williams’ pink pills for pale people."</p>
                                <p>“Why don’t you try them 1’’ asked a friend.</p>
                                <p>Mr. Sarney did try them, and their effect was extraordinary. Before ho had finished one box be could actually walk round the table with the aid of a stick. This was after months aud months in bed. After he had got partly through the second box he weut lor a short walk I His friends were amazed to see him out, aud asked him what he had t^keu to bring about such a marvellous recovery. He told them, and gladly, that it was owing to I)r. Williams’ pink pills that he was able to get out of doors again. After the third box be was able to throw away bis stick. He persevered with tlie^piUs, aud when he had taken eight boxes he was looking for work, after nineteen months without doing a single stroke.</p>
                                <p>This is a remarkable cure, but there is no difficulty in explaining it. Paralysis is a disease of the nervous system, it is a sign that the nerves are ill-nounshed. The food ot the nerves is blood. l)r. Williams' pink pills for pale people make new blood. Ordinary mediciue could not cure Mr. Sarney; Reading Hospital was perfectly right in sending him away as incurable by ordinary medicine. Dr. Williams' pink pills have cured thousands of persons whom ordinary medicine could not benefit, because ordinary medicine does not make new blood. Any ailment that arises from lack of blood, or lrom poisoned, impure blood, as annmia, skin diseases, eczema, chronic erysipelas, rheumatism, gout, can be speedily cured by Dr. Williams’ pink pills; and disorders arising indirectly from lack of blood, as neuralgia, spinal disease, indigestion and bile (which are caused by the blood not being able to absorb food from the stomach) can be cured in the same way. But it mart be the genuine Dr. Williams’ pink pills for mile people that are taken—not a substitute. Genuine pills bear the full name. Dr. Wil­liams' medicine company, Holbom-viaduct, London, will send a box post free for two and ninepeuce (or six for thirteen aud nine) : but they can be bad at all medicine shops if you insist otftljB genuine.</p>
                                <p>Sold in Egypt by all chemists at P.T. lfper box or P.T. 70 per G boxes. Can be bought at the general depot: Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel dn Nil St. (1st floor), and Alexandria, Rue Stamboul, No. 8.</p></div><cb n="3"/>
            
            <div type="section"><head>LETTER8 TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                <p>-V* do DOI hold oowlne r*F*MlbU tor Uw optolooi eipnwd kr oar aamepeodem, bal wo wtah. In • opirU ot (sir ploj •o on. to permit - wUh.o carlsla nnomry limit* — troo</p>
                <div type="item"><head>ABOUKIR LANDS.</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of tub Eotftian Gazette.
                        Sir,—The recent correspondence in your columns relating to the deplorable destruction ot valuable archa-ological finds at Aboukir, as also the report of the trial in your issue of 5th inst (Prince Omar Pasha Tonssoun versus Mr. Richmond, iu which the former was non suited in his claim of preemption), may serve to direct the attention of the Government, and also of the public, to this district.'</p>
                    <p>Until within the last few years, oertain native families of Aboukir and Kharaba had for generations exercised proprietary rights over the surroucdiug country, and sales of land had now and again been effected by them.</p>
                    <p>The only part ft whioh they did not lay claim were the hills near the forts, whioh were looked upon as Government property, and it is on one of these hills oloee to a fort that the remains of the temple were unearthed.' It would be interesting to know how these natives have been dispossessed of such a large tract of oountry, and if all thfe wells and roads are also to be absorbed by the new claimant to these lands.</p>
                    <p>The whole matter requires investigation, and ventilation, on Ins we are to believe that, as in ths good 6U1 days ot oppression aud corruption, so in these present days of progress and enlightenment:—</p>
                    <p>Great it the power of the Pasha, and it shall prevail.</p>
                    <p>Yours, etc.,</p> <p>Enquirer.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, January 9, 1905.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>INFANT MORTALITY IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>To thb Editor of tub Egyptian Gazbttk.</p>
                    <p>Sir,—“Humanity" quotes from Mr. Lang Anderson’s paper on “Land Values in Bgypt” some remarks about infant mortality, and thinks if the figures are true Government ‘should investigate the causes of this terrible , waste of human life.’ I happen to have come ar.-o>s Dr. Engel Bey’s mortality statistics for ths towns of Lower Egypt for the 5-year period from 1806-1890. For 100 births there are 71*7 deaths, as follows ,</p>
                    <p>Age	0	to	1	year	24.8
                        1	to	5	years	21.1
                        5	to	10	„	25.8***MAKE TABLE</p>
                    <p>These figures bear out Mr. Lang Anderson’s statement that “roughly one-third of the deaths are ot childreir> under 1 year, another third of children^ from)l to 5 years.”</p>
                    <p>It would be reassuring if someone with later statistics would show the present rate for towns, and also for the oountry generally.</p>
                    <p>I am, etc.,</p>
                    <p>Observer.</p>
                    <p>Cairo, January 10. </p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>OFFICIAL SPELLING.</head>
                    <p>To tub Editor of thb Egyptian Gazbttb.</p>
                    <p>Sir,— I quite agree with Professor Sayce as to the existing discreditable spelling of Arabio names, but the solution is not quite so simplfe as Professor 8ayoe assumes. “Shari’el-Qishlaq,” which Professor Bayoe gives as the oorreot transliteration of the name of a street near the British Agency, is just as much a philological horror to a Frenchman as “Chareh el-Kochlak," the adopted spelling, is to an Englishman. The same forms and oombinations,bath consonantal and vowel, represent different sounds in different languages, and it is therefore im­possible to secure universal approval for any national mothod of transliteration. All attempts at an international system are mere com­promises, which satisfy nobody, and are far from being “scientific transliterations," as Professor Sayce would have us believe. A scientific transliteration could be secured only by the adoption of a special alphabet similar in form to the Latin letters, bnt corresponding phonetically to the Arabio characters ; bat 1 feel sure that Professor Sayoe has no idea of recommending this solution. What I think he wishes is to see an English system of translite­ration universally substituted for the French system, without consideration for the suscepti­bilities of those who do not understand English. Perhaps, after all, this would be the easiest solution.</p>
                    <p>A Reader.</p>
                    <p>Cairo, January 9.</p></div></div></div><cb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
