<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-11-09">November 9, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-03">July 3, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7229] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, JULY 3, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
SOCIALISM IN GERMANY.
A FRENCH “UNDESIRABLE.’
Berlin, July 6.
The Government has forbidden the French
Socialist Deputy M. Jaurès to lecture in Berlin
upon the international duties of Socialists with
reference to war, on the 9th inst., on the ground
that the German Social Democrats would
utilise the occasion to advance their anti-
national efforts.	(Reuter.)

Paris, July 6.
Prince Radolin has informed M. Rouvier
that Germany declines to have M. Jaurès at
the Berlin Conference.	(Havas.)

FOUNDERING OF FRENCH
SUBMARINE.
LOCAL AND GENERAL,
The Plaque.—Yesterday’s bulletin records
two cases, one of which was fatal, at Alex-
andria.	\
l
./
A Cabinet Council.will be held to-morrow
at San Stefano under the presidency of H. E.
Fakhry Pasha, Acting Regent.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
Mousky district of Cairo during to-morrow
night and at daylight on Sunday, will be
poisoned by the police.
Ras el-Bar.—A temporary post office for all
branches of the service, specie-packets exempt-
ed, has been opened at Ras el-Bar, near Da-
mietta, for the bathing season.
-
Bizerta, July 6.
A French submarine with 13 on board has *
foundered in the lake here.	(Reuterjf
Ferryville, July 6.
The submarine “Farfadet” has sunk with 13
hands. Attempts at rescue are being made.
(Eavai.)
UNITED STATES.
MR. HAY’S SUCCESSOR.
Mr. Root, formerly
ceeds Mr. Hay.
Washington, July 6.
Secretary of War, suo-
( Reuter.)
GORDON-BENNETT RACE.
CUP TO BE RETURNED TO D()NOR.
Paris, July 6.
The cup will be returned to Mr. Gordon-
Bennett, owing to the decision of the 28th
June of the Automobile Club of Franoe to no
longer take part in the contests. England is
the only country besides France, whose three
competitors completed the course. (Reuter.)
I" —
HENLEY REGATTA.
Double Execution at Alexandria. —El
Sayed Ali Selim and Ramadan Mnrsi, who
murdered a female egg-seller at Souk El Bqrsim,
will ha executed at Hadra prison on Monday,
10th inst.
Suez Canal.—8 vessels passed through the
Canal on t’ne 4th inst., of which 3 were British,
2 German, 1 Ottoman, 1 French, 1 Dutch. The
day’s receipts were fra! *226,420.69, making the
total from the 1st inst. frs. 1,267,505.15. '
Plague Precautions.—The medical officer
in charge of the Labbane quarter has ordered
a cordon to be drawn round two houses where
deaths have occurred which are believed to
be directly due to bubonic plague.
Henley, July 6.
Grand Challenge Cup. The Leander beat the
Sport Nautique of Ghent by 2| lengths.
Diamond Sculls. Kelley beat Blaokstaffe
easily. Time 8 minutes and 10 seconds, which
is a record.	(Reuter.)
RACING.
London, July 6.
The Princess of Wales Stakes. 1, St. Denis ;
2, Exchequer ; 3, Lancashire.	(Reuter.)
Egyptian Army.—El Kaimakam Herbert
Bey, Assistant Adjutant General, Recruiting
Department, will take over command of the
Cairo Distriot from El Miralai Matchett Bey,
who proceeded to Khartoum on temporary
duty yesterday.
NAT1VH PRESS OPINIONS.
Hashish Smuggling. — A Greek subject,
named Nicolas Assimacopoqlos, was arrested
this morning while attempting to smuggle
four torbas of hashish, which were wrapped
round his legs, through the gates, of the Cus-
tom-house.
‘Quis Custodies Ipsos Custodes V—The se-
cret police arrested Constable Alexandrello, of
the City Police, at 6 a.m. to-day on disembark-
ing from the S.S. “Athens.” This man was
implicated in the recent shooting affray in
Sisters-street.
Dramatic Performance. »- The Ernesto
Rossi dramatic club will give a performance
at the Pyramids Theatre on the 12th inst. of
an Italian version of Bisson’s comedy Les
an
LORD CROMER’S SPEECH.
In discussing Lord Cromer’s speech, “A1
Moayad” remarks that tho better the reiar
tions between Abdeen and Buckingham Palace,
the better for Egypt, and that the attitude
of the extremists, whose idea of patriotism
is a systematic opposition to all that has
to do with theV Iccupation, is brainless and
even opposed to the principles of the Koran.
With Lord Cromer’s four conditions the
“Moayad” expresses its agreement subject to one
or two reservations. While admitting that a di-
rect control of Egyptian afiairs by Parliament
would injure Egypt, it remarks that Parlia-
ment must never lose its control of what are,
after all, its agents in Egypt,and must be able
to check any abuse of , their powers. In this
connection., it is earnestly to be desired that
some means existed of bringing the Egyptian
point of view before Parliament as clearly as
Lord Cromer’s point of view is set forth in the
Blue-books. The caution in the introduction
of Western ideas must not be exaggerated, for
Egypt has made great strides, and finally, while
there is no question of Lord Cromer’s sincere
devotion to the good of Egypt, many of his
projects have been diverted from their end
by those charged to carry them out.
"A1 Lewa” expresses its disagreement with
“A1 Moayad’s” views. Opposition to the
British Occupation is an absolute necessity, and
it is strange that “A1 Moayad,"‘after 14 years
in opposition, should abandon its policy and
support Lord Cromer’s views. The opponents
of the Occupation are the only veritable patri-
ots. If Lord Cromer’s wishes for the welfare of
the Egyptian people are sincere, he should
permit them to occupy many of the important
positions now reserved for Englishmen, and
reduce the expenses caused by the Occupation.
, The Egyptians were the first civilised race in
the history of the world and are to-day as
capable of assimilating modern civilisation as
the Japanese or the English themselves. The
future will show their capaoity beyond dispute.
mm hotel muni
ALBX&KDBIA.
•a. PCIt BAY, WINE INCLUDED'
fSSS9 if 1
Surprises du Divorce. The caste is a strong
one and the performance should meet with
thh usual success.
TUmt.eh Railway Crossings.—It appears
that automobiles and carriagSto are frequently
driven at great speed over tblf level crossings'
on the Ramleh Railway, especially at Bulkeley,
which renders the precautions taken by the
company valueless, notwithstanding the special
watchmen placed on duty at these crossings.
The dangers to which antomobilists and car-
riage drivers expose themselves are most
serious, as with this exaggerated speed it is
certain that more often than not the watch-
men have hardly time to signal to them before
they are on the line. Consequently, we are
asked by the company to appeal to the public,
when driving over these crossings, to slacken
speed in order to avoid any chance of accident.
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL
Dr. Rucker-Jenisch, German
Agent, will leave Cairo for San
Sunday.
Diplomatic
Stefano on
Judge Bond, vice-president of the Native
Court of Appeal, has left for Zurich.
ARISTON AERATED WATERS
Guaranteed BlatlUed.
ALEXANDRIA:	I
7. W «e fa Porta	I "gf SfflKSj
Mr. II. Boyle, Oriental Secretary to Lord
Cromer, left yesterday by the Rubattino boat
for Europe.
Count von Wedel, First Secretary at the
German Diplomatic Agency, is expected back
in Cairo on Monday or Tuesday next
Abdallah Bev Sfqr leayes for Italy to-day.
At Rome he will meet the Maronite Patriaroh,
whose visit to Europe has given rise to a variety
of conjectures.
Major B. W. Longhurst, R.A.M.C., has been
granted an extension/ of leave from July 14
to January!8,1906.
M. Skinder has been appointed architect to
the Aptian hand and Qtfieral Troit
sV
R A8-EL-B A.R.
t/

^ SYRIAN PROTESTANT
COLLEGE. ,	'
36th ANNUAL COMMENCEMENT
EXERCISES.
( From a Correspondent. )	i
Beyrout, July 2.-	(
For over three decades the Syrian Protestant 1
College stood, as it were, on an eminence as a 1
jeaoonW knowledge shedding a growing light <
on Syria, and in its - later phases of develop- ‘
ment it has" plainly become odo of the rnhst -
potent educational factors in the Near East. 1
One has but to glance at the latest edition of , ’
its prospectuses, of Which a judicious distribu- 1
tion is annual'y made, to realise the magnitude 1
of its infiuen o and the soope of its field of
action. This magnifioent institution reornits <
its army,of about • 700 students from various 1
countries. Its radios of power extends from <
Armenia in the East to Greeoe and the Etonian 1
sles in the West, and from Asi/Minor in -the •
North down to Egypt in the South. But its ]
influence has been mostly felt in Egypt, di- <
reotly through the preponderant numbhr <Sf <
seekers for knowledge that the Land of1 the
Pharaohs has always supplied, and indireotly ’
but uo less mightily through the Syrian *
settlers who constitute a strong ' intellectual 1
element in Egyptian life, and who, under the 1
strong, capable, and judicious guidance of 1
British rulers, are contributing largely to the 1
progress of the country. Therefore any event 1
of public character in this birthplace of learn- 1
ing should not fail to appeal to the interest of 1
the readers of the “Gazette.”
The commencement exercises this year 1
began on Saturday, 24th June, ten days earlier
than the usual and traditional time. This has
been determined by the early arrival of the
mperial Medical Commission from Constan- 1
tinople. Although the exercises commenced on
Saturday yet they may be considered to have
been publicly inaugurated by the Bhccalaureate
service on Snnday, when President Howard
Bliss delivered his annual valedictory and
exhortatory address to the medical and phar-
maceutical graduates: The scene was, as it
may easily be imagined, one calonlated to oall
Forth deep and stirring emotions and inspire
thoughts of the noblest kind, and the young
; ^resident’s fiery eloquence rose splendidly to
the occasion. The meeting was well attended
by 8tndent8 and many of the public. The bless-
ing was fitly given by the old President Eme-
ritus, whose appearance in pnblio functions at
the college is still inspiring and reoalls to the
ieart» of older students happy memories of
the godd old dayB.
The exercises closed on Wednesday with
the ceremony of the distribution of prizes and
diplomas. The. principal afid striking •'feature
of that day wks the processional march. At
Ada Dodge Hall the procession, consisting of
the old graduates, the faculty, and the staff of
teachers, formed, and proceeded to the
Memorial Hall at 3.30 p m. preceded by the
American Consol and the Imperial Medical
Commission. The President and members of
the Faculty wore their'academic gowns, and as
it marched forth with measured step and took
.ite'Seats on the platform in the Memorial Hall,
the procession presented a sight of unusual
solemnity.
The closing event was a delightful entertain-
ment on Wednesday evening at the President’s,
Marquand House, wound up by a series of
hilarious and comic songs, lustily sung by a
part of the American staff of teachers. The
entertainment is given principally in honor
of the Imperial Medical Commission, composed
this year of General Mahmoud Hakki Pasha, a
vejy distinguished officer, Colonel Ahmed
-p'ehmi Bey, and Major Esoret Roushen Bey.
The reception was held in the president's
class-room, a hall of specious dimensions, but
which, owing to the large crowd, could afford
only standing room. This, coupled with the
torrid heat of June, made it particularly
uncomfortable to the invites, and called forth
suggestions from some of them for an enlarge-
ment of the hall, which would not be inad-
visable considering the growing importance of
the'college. But the welcome was so hearty,
and there was such a general air of conviviality,
that the heat and other little* discomforts were
forgotten. Besides, to those blessed with a
sense of humour and that rare power of self-
detachment, there was afforded a rich fund
of/amusement by the presentation of the
myites to the Imperial Commission. This
3Anguished body was victimised by a pre-
tation of almost all the large crowd of
Quests, and for about half an honr there was
something like a pantomimic show of a fi'e
of ladies and gedtlemen coming forward with
different degrees of grace and awkwardness to
-hake hands with^ the three commissioners,
who cut carious figures, repeating with
automatic sameness the stiff, jerky, and deep
German how in reply to each introduction.
After the ordeal they withdrew to the cooler
reoesses of the garden on whioh the hall opens,
to indulge in timely refreshments and the
necessary accompaniment of the fragrant weed.
These entertainments form a cheerful
ending for fhe graduates of a year of hard
study, wakeful anxieties, and stirring emo-
tions, and no donbt they-procure the hospi-
table President and his charming wife many
a farewell word of blessing from the grateful
pupils who are to face the hard realities
of life.
I had almost forgotten to add that 28 medi-
cal students were presented to the Commis-
sion for the final examination. Of these one
did not oomplete his examination, one failed
to pass, 36 took the oath of office before
the commission and reoeived their oollege
diplomas. Their Turkish diplomas will be sent
to them later.
Nine pharmacy students were presented to
the commissioners lor final examination. 0:'
1 these All pasted pnd took the oath And reo*v-
M diplomas.
THE EGYPTIAN MARGATE.
NOmFW>MuPQ!W.»AID-,

(From a Correspondent.)
Now that the summer has began in earnest,
many dwellers in inland towns will be thinking
of making a move soon to' some favored spot
by the seaside where the invigorating ocean :
breezes will once more brace the jaded residents
of the interior. For those who have the means
San Stefano is incomparably the Queen of
Egyptian summer resorts,but-to those to whom
money is a primary consideration, and others
who prefer a free-and-easy and happy-go-lucky
existence, I know of no Better place close at
hand than Ras-el-Bar, not far from bamietta.
I very tfmch doubt whether the frequenters
of this little place, which springs into life with
the advent of the great heat, would seek to
qualify its attractions by comparison with
those offered elsewhere, say at Ramleh o/ Port
Said, but I do not hesitate to say that it
possesses a charm of its own, and I am not
surprised when I discern the same familiar faces
there^ear after year. *
* The season proper at this Egyptian Margate,
if I may term it so, does- not commence in
earnest until the middle of July, and is in fall
swing until about the end of September, So that
the hotel-keepers and others who minister to
the wants of the strangers have, in a sense, to
make My while the sun shines, although, con-
sidering the shortness of the season, no one
can say that the prices charged are exor-
bitant The majority of the visitors are
Levantines and Egyptians, leavened by a fair
number of Europeans of all the nationalities
that inhabit this country.
The hotels, if one oan honor them with this
name, and dwellings aria mainly if not entirely
coDstrncted of the nafive rush mat fastened to
wooden uprights and are slighly raised from
the land or ground in the same manner as
bungalows in India. Naturally, in a country
like Egypt, where rain is unknown for nine
months at least of the year, snch habitations
are possible, but one could not calmly con-
template what would happen to the wkole place
were it visited by a good monsoon (rain of an
hoar’s duration.	\
Of course, of amusements of the fashionable
kind there are none to begnile the time, bnt
for those who love sea-bathing, fishing, and an
bnt-of-door life, Ras-el-Bar is a small paradise.
The bathing is the best in Egypt, and eaoh
hotel has a hnt wherein batherr-oan undress
and dress. There are a few shops, sutoh as the
-inevitable bacals, & good barber, q chemist,
and last, but not least, a branch ppst-office.
There is also from Jane, to October ) a small
body of police under the \orders of a native
officer.
» I should not omit to mention, for the infor-
mation of would-be new-comers, who may likq
to give the place a trial, that there ia a regular
steam boat service that. carries the mail
between Damietta and Ras-el-Bar, the trip
occupying about an hoar and rnnning in ooin-
cidence with the arrival of the passenger trains
from Mansonrah. Daring the busy season the
Egyptian Railway Adminstration runs an ex-
press train weekly each way whioh starts from
Gairh every Thursday.
THE CAIRO HOTELS.
THflSPRMBRGED DREDGER,
(From our Correspondent).
Port Said, Thursday.
Work on the submerged dredger “Pharaon. "
ill.” is now being rabidly pushed towards com-
pletion. I learn that the vessel is to be raised gl
by quite a novel method,’ which' should prove “
most interesting. As I noted'some time back, 6<
she lies bn her side, And a kind of bed is being r!
.dredged ont along her side, at the bottom'of 1
i whioh is to be placed a patent slip cradle. A* g
'cutting is to be made in the bank into which
the dredger lying on the cradle is to be towed. **
The entranoe to the basin will be dosed, and it 8
is then to be pumped out and the vessel attend- *
ed to as if she lay in a dry-dock. Hopes Are *
expressed that the “Pharaon II.” will be
hauled into the basjn in two weeks’ time.
Np,TES FROM CYjP^IJ^.
*	•	.	V
DESTRUCTIVE RAIN STORM,
(From our Correspondent.) f
CHARITY CONCERT.
The massed bands of H.M.S. “Suffolk" aod
“Lancaster,” by permission of the oaptains
and officers of the vessels, are giving a concert
on Saturday evening in aid of the Society for
tM Prevention of Cruelty to Animals! !Tha
concert is to be held in the garden qf the
’ Sastem Exohauge, whioh is being very prettily
arranged.
;ly vejy
gs* Fehi
In reference to the recent rise in the shares
of the two leading hotel companies of Egypt,
it is worth noticing that the principal reason
of the rapid appreciation within the past few
months of this class of securities is the
enormous increase since two years or so in
the value of the land on which the Grand
Continental and the Savoy Hotels are built in
the case of the Nungovioh Hotels Company,
and in the case of the Egyptian Hotels Com-
pany, of the land at Ghezireh, whioh has been
and is being sold at rapidly increasing prices.
The former company bought $he New Hotel,
now the Grand Continental, About six years
ago, including the land it stands on and the
furniture it contained, for £105,000, which, at
the time, was considered the foil value. The
present-valne of the land alone, whioh measures
11,000 square metres, at the modest price of
£20 per square metre, represents an increase
of no less than £4 per share on the entire
share capital of the company, not reckoning
the building, furniture and good-will of a
concern that pays yearly dividends of ten
per cent
The Savoy Hotel,' as it is, was bought about
a year later than the other from Prince
JDjemil Pasha Toussonm,we believe for£55,000.
The land is 5,000 sqoare metres in extent, bnt
owing to the' extraordinary increase in the
price of land in the best part of the Ismailia
quarter the site alone to-day is worth the fifty
five thousand pounds, without counting the
palatial buildings erected on it. Thiff repre-_
sents an increase in value of at least £2 per
share on the whole of the share capital. With
these figures before us can one wonder that
the £4 shares of the Nungovioh Hotels are
now worth £10 or thereabouts, and those of
the Egyptian Hotels at an equally1 high
premium ?	.
As we mentioned a few weeks back, the
former company hays purchased by pre-
emption a portion of the estate of the late
Sabet Pasha, adjoining the Savoy Hotel, am
on the ground so acquired they are to ereot
additional buildings to accommodate the large
and ever-increasing clientele that patronises
this hotel daring the winter season, besides
enlarging the restaurant and making other
mnoh-needed, improvements.
.	-----------P----------------------------------
BECK & CO’jj’fiSEHER BEEB
TJ8AB8 HO HOHNfT CONFITITIOH fOR QUALITY.
H.8.—Intaiot Brands now Mag otfmg to Man
•go* of Mttoin good sotata.
Beware ofovOy m*emi	nnb*
lotoalUe fctty BnmA#* mJm
.#£» $  	t*
THE
FOURTH OF JULY
MANSOGRAH.
AT
(From a Correspondent).
Mansonrah, July 5.
Mr. W. L. Lawton, of the Jewell Export
filter Co., having jnst completed the installa-
tion of a plant ’ of these filters at the perir
waterworks in this town, entertained his
numerous friends on the dahabieh “Ariadne,”
rindly lent for the occasion by Mr. Dale, yes-
terday. Anchored in mid-stream, the rigfeisg
dresiled with the flags of all ti&tions, fhatfof
the star-spangled banner predominating, with
a tapestried awning overhead, and palm-
jranches arched over the columns around the
sideSj flte dahabieh made a gay show by day.
At night, the numberless ooloured lights,
strung on high amongst the rigging and al
quite tt fairy-hid appearance. On the aland
in mid-stream two cannon had been plaoed, the
thunders of whioh were interrupted 'by the
authorities, it being against the Government
regnlAnhqs to fire artillery within 250 metres
of th0 town, hut our courteous Moudir ' kindly
permitted the fireworks, rockets, Roman
candles, etc., on this special oocasion, the first
time, in the annals of Mansonrah, that this
American fete Ms been oelebrated in such a
publio manner. Unfortunately the members
of the American Mission were absent, having
been > called away- the . previous day to
attend a meeting at Alexandria, so that
Mr. Lawton was the only citizen present,
bnt he a host in hiniself, and received
his guests for afternoon tea at 5 o’clock on
the deck of the dahabieh. This funotntp over
the company crossed over to the island amid-
stream, where the gentlemen entertained the
ladies by engaging in athletic sports. On
their return to the boat, they found a sump-
tuous dinner spread out on a table whioh had
been prettily decorated with flowers and plants
by Mrs. Dale. Toasts, songs, and musio follow-
ed to a late hour of the night.
Mr. Lawton was ably assisted in the efforts
to celebrate his national fete-day by Messrs.
McCrae, Anderson, and Holeman, whose
hearty bo-operation went far to make the affair
the success that it was. Daring the evening,
maoh was said in praise of our most energetic
Moudir, MustapM Pas hi Saber, for the many
improvements he has introduped into the
town, amongst them the paving of the main
streets, their present oleanlkess and order,
and the construotion of a/ carriage drive and
promenade Along the hanks of the river, south
of the town into the open oonntry. This
drive is to be planted with trees, which will
form a shady avenue* A new street haj
already been commenced, crossing the town
and opening up a route from the river to th<
open fields by the cemeteries. Not only hat
the Mondir had “Benr Adam” at heart in hii
endeavours to benefit the town, bnt his esta
blishment of a branoh of the Society for th<
Prevention of Cruelty to Animals has been s(
successful, with the aotive and able support oi
hisofficers, the police, and our veterinary snr
geon Dr. Trydel, that it is an exception now-a
days to find a siok animal about the streets, anc
whereas the S.P.C.A’s hospital was Jormerlj
crowded with siok blasts, many having to b<
shot, all the stalls are now often empty.
Nieosu, June 80.
f?.'.:	'•	'»lfr Xt t*	•
As mentioned, in my last week’s notes, a
good deal pfinpenvei^eLee was threatened (o
travellers on the Niopei*:Tjopd<» •r91^ ¥* «»-'
sequence of $e. damage caused by the heavy
rain stonn in the
the mountain, stream, whjph( had f bftoofape
greatly swollen, washed,/aw^l a portion, of
the road which, winds in andLjpntj a^ tknt.
point, and, many tons of
sited. The Publio Works Department, cam.
promptly, to the rescue^ and gangs of men
agd ,women wine, v»ry qfodffe^tL, to w«)f
to repair, the damage. Little delay qr incon-
venience was caused to the officials who were
then on their way to their Troodpe enoamp-
mpnts, and .the road was openW to traffic
after an interval of some 24 hours or so.
NEW RAILWAY UNE.
a- .	- ■
The railway is now laid to within four mile*
of Nicosia, and the whole line, frees Nicosia
to Famagusta is expected to be completed
by about the 1st August. I hear that* the
Government is already using the completed
portion for the movement o£ grain frees the
threshing floors to the gmia atone, which
Mve beta established at one or two points
along the line.
SALE OF GRAIN.
The Government has advertised for aalg
the following grain of this year's harvest,
which represents tithe and recoveries from
the seed corn advances :
Wheat 316|6QO kilos (English bushels)
Barley 411,000	„
Vetches	42j«50. „	„	„
Oats	50,600	„	„	„
all of whioh quantities, with the exception
of vetches,-whieh are very (^htiy !h,(ixteto,
are less than' those advertised for sale last
year. I understand that practically the whole
of this has been sold, and at higher prices
than in 1904.
INVESTIGATION OF FLORA.
expert
Mr. Jens Holmboe, a Norwegian expert
botanist, is now in. Cyprus for the purpose
of investigating the flora or the Island on
behalf of the Botanical University tiwria-
tiania. He Me already spent Borne months in
Cyprus and contemplates remaining some
THE GHIRGEH SCANDAL.
The lengthy text of the judgment of the
Court of. Appeal in the Rifahi case has been
given to thi Press. It leaves no manner of
doubt as to the gailt of the acoused, while it,
admits the presenoe of extenuating oiroom-
stanoes.	<
We hear tMt Hassan Bey Wassif has been
sent to the infirmary at Menshieh prison owing
to a slight indisposition.
STRAMBR MOVEMENTS.
The S.S/Versiau Prinoe,” from Antwerp,
left London yesterday with general osrgo for
Malta and Alexandria.
The SB. "Tuscan Prinoe,” from Manchester,
left Maka yesterday and is dee here on Monday
morning next* with passengers and general
°*The Khedivial Mail SB. "Isnualia” wilj
leave Alexandria on Wednesday for PirsuA
Smyrna, Mitylsns and Constantinople.
FOOD AND DRUGS ACT.
The Food and Drags Act passed lata session
by the Legislative Council provides, «n«wig
Other things, tMt any purchaser of any ar*
tide of food or of a drag or medfeine shaH
be entitled; on payment te an' analyst of
the sum of five shillfrkgB, to Mve such article
or drag or medrane analysed by him, and
to receive from thy analyst a oertific&te of
the result of his analysis. It Also defines what
is fr> be regarded as adulteration uuderthe
Act, and hewVffenoes are pnfishaMe. Duly
authorised persons are empoiwsBlI to ponltota
any suoh articles .**The sapnss purpose of
analysis, and power ia givea to thaGont to
destroy the sntgeot mattes of. any ejbaqpA It
is hoped that the enforoemtat of this law itttf
Mve a salutary effect.
■ t
C * ■	ta	? * -
JEWISH COLONISATION; •
A small ohiftlik near Luntoa has lately
been acquired by the Jewish Colonisation
Society, and it is intended in course of "time
to imjtort a limited number of Jewuft people
as settlers, who Will be taught to oarry on
certain agricultural and industrial under-
takings '.here. It is toe soon to praffiothow
'this will answer, hut, if wisely’yianaged anj a
capable, industrious, and intelligent oolony
is formed, with a Mr amoqnjb ’ tjlf papi^al
at, its disposal, it may not be nmyajonaMl to
anticipate good results both to the oblohyyAnd,
as an object lesson and a meaiU of Intend-
ing the trade of the'Island, to Cyprus' ih
general. '	.	»
PASSENGER LISTS.'
DEPARTURES.
Le paquebot “Tebe” de la Cie Florio Rfl-
battino parti hier pour Gfenee avail A bord :
M. et Mme V. Oliva^M. et Mme Fiandro,
Cav. Giordano, Filippo' Gressb, Lombardi
Bocoia et tamille, F. -V* -Piatet- L 9Bta*k.p.
Petroni, J. Soares, M. Magrin, C. Garbua,
Av. Sooolis, Leonida ^i.'A.^Dem
V. Pinto, M. Blattner, Carlo Naggiar, GaDah
Mu 830, Mme M. Midi, Anfamnikiaarft famille,
M. et Mme 6. Nahman, Mme Vve Anastasia
et fiUe, Mm6 BenUduooi, Ludwig et fils, Wahby
Ibrah. Bey, V. Sporio,^ ^nno^ Bey et fiunilK
Padre Carlo, Mme JL Aim Mme floooja,
Mme ColliDgwood, Mile L. Quid! pvoseo Bey
et famifie, E. fterty et fragile; Dr. U! Mussp,
B. Mailer et fainille, Bceurs Landi, A. Biroher,
Mme SerVetOe, Aziz Nader et sceisi; G.
Mailer, H. Boyle, Av. I. Mosoa et MUille,
Prof! R VanDiok et fille, M. et Mme A. Sali-
nas, G. Bennioi et faaitte, D. Simha, Anra
SassoU, Moh. Bey Ttafiok, MmaB-Aghyy.
Baron V. Morena, M. et Mw M***0"**0
Granato, R J. Nsggar, M-.d MniaBstoPP.
Wispo et Secrdtaire, jtm ?rux**»h¥-
Mma A. Cangiani, A. Inrwnin,i StaP
Sudani, G. SG*	t
Lamberti, R-
70 passegen de 8me dasse.
.Beyeti

                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
