<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Gwen Lofman</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-10-02">October 2, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Monday, October 2, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, OCTOBER 2 1905</head>
                <div type="section">
                    <div type="item"><!-- TODO: CHECK ITEM AGAINST IMAGE OF THE NEWSPAPER -->
                        <head>RUSSIA AND GERMANY</head>
                        <head>PROPOSED ENTENTE</head>
                        <head type="sub">RUSSIAN PRESS OPINION:</head>
                        <dateline>Paris, October 1.</dateline>
                        <p>The “Matin asserts that the Tsar, under the influence of Count Witte, is desirous of agreement with Germany, which would become a alliance.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                        <dateline>St Petersburg October 1</dateline>
                        <p>The suggestion of a Russo German alliance has been coolly received in Russia. Many prominent papers, including the “Novosti" and he "Russ," advocate an understanding with England in preference to an alliance with Ger-nany, which would involve Russia in fresh</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE HUNGARIAN SITUATION COUNTER DEMONSTRATIONS.</head>
                        <dateline>Budapest, October 1</dateline>
                        <p>The Coalitionists are arranging a great torchlight procession past the Kossuth Club on the 3rd inst The Socialists are arranging a simultaneous counter demonstration. The police are taking extensive precautions to prevent lighting.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CYCLONE IN SOUTH AFRICA SEVEN KILLED, MANY INJURED</head>
                        <dateline>Cape Town, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Seven persons have been killed and many injured in a cyclone The town of Malmesbury is wrecked and hundreds of people are homeless.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRO CALABRIA LORD BRASSEYS OFFER</head>
                        <dateline>Rome, October 1.</dateline>
                        <p>Lord Brassey has offered to erect a large number of wooden cottages on the English model for the Calabrian earthquake sufferers. The offer has been gratefully accepted.</p>
                        <byline>(R.)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PROPOSED PEACE CONFERENCE.</head>
                        <head type="sub">FRANCE ACCEPTS INVITATION.</head>
                        <dateline>Paris, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>France has accepted Russia’s invitation to a new peace conference at the Hague.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRANCE AND RUSSIA.</head>
                        <dateline>NEW COMMERCIAL CONVENTION.</dateline>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, September 30. The now commercial convention with France has been signed.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
                        <dateline>Paris, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Parliament will re assemble on October 30.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHOLERA IN POLAND</head>
                        <dateline>Warsaw, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Daring the past weak there have been 50 cases of cholera in Poland, of which 28 were fatal.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>YELLOW FEVER IN AMERICA</head>
                        <dateline>Nkw Orleans, October 1.</dateline>
                        <p>There has been a marked decrease in the yellow fever epidemic, which is supposed to he on account of the systematic destruction of mosquitoes.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>YORK RACES.</head>
                        <dateline>London, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Great Ebor Handicap, York. 1, Capo Verde ; 2. Glenamony , 3. Challacorobe.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ENGLAND’S REVENUE.</head>
                        <head>SATISFACTORY INCREASE.</head>
                        <dateline>London, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>The revenue for the half-year shows an increase of ₤74.350 compared with 1901, not withstanding the reduction of the duty on tea.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.</head>
                        <head type="sub">NEW CRUISER LAUNCHED</head>
                        <dateline>London, September 30. </dateline>
                        <p>The cruiser Natal of 13.550 tons has been successfully launched at Barrow. Her speed sill be twenty two and a half knots.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>REOPENING OF CANAL</head>
                        <dateline>Fori Said. September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>(Official) Alter a technical examination the Suez Canal will be opened to the traffic of all ships about the 8th October.</p>
                        <byline>(Reuter)</byline>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="local and general">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Bubonic Plague</head>
                        <p>During the week ending last Saturday two cases of bubonic plague wore notified in Egypt, both of which occured at Alexandria. One case ended fatally and there are now only two cases remaining undor treatment Since the 1st January there have been in all 259 cases as against 80S during the corresponding period of last year.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE'S VISIT.</head>
                        <byline>(From our CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                        <dateline>Constantinople, September 26.</dateline>
                        <p>By the time that yon receive these notes H.H. the Khedive, who left here yesterday evening on board the S.S. Dalmatia, which was specially chartered for his Highness from the Austrian Lloyd Company, will have arrived at Alexandria. Before bis departure from this town grand fetes were held in his honor at the Yildiz palace.</p>
                        <p>During his stay at Alexandria his Highness receive the English ambassador, Sir Nicholas O'Conner, and returned the visit same day. He also received the Hellenic minister, M. Gryparie, who was .for a long diplomatic agent at Cairo. On Sunday the Sultan gave a banquet at the Yildiz palace at which both the Khedive and Prince Mohamed Ali were present, and daring the evening the Imperial Band played a number of selections, and a theatrical performance was given by the artistes of the palace. At an audience with the Saltan, the Khedive pressed his thanks for, and appreciation of, the welcome which had been accorded him during his visit.</p>
                        <p>His Highness was accompanied on board by Prince Muhamed Ali and H. E. Ibrahim Pasha, grand master of ceremonies to the Sultan, and shortly before the departure of the boat H. E Abdul Ghani Phasha arrived to bid good bye to the Khedivah and the Khedivah-Mother on behalf of the Sultan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SIRDARS ARRIVAL</head>
                        <p>H. E. the Sirdar, Sir Reginald Wingate Pasha, and Lady Wingate arrived at Alexandria by the Austrian Lloyd mail boat this morning. Sir R. Von Slatin Pasha also arrived by the same boat.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FreemasonRY in EGYPT</head>
                        <p>We are authorised to announce that during this week a historical summary of the actual situation of Freemasonry in Egypt will be published with official documents annexed. The intention of this publication is to show that the sole legitimate supreme council to the Scottish Rite is the one sitting at Alexandria legalised by the supreme coucil of Italy, and not the one under the charter of Spain as declared by Ugo Lusena Bey at the Mixed Court of Alexandria in 1902 during the proces Zola against divers of Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Kaiser Asile Wilhelm</head>
                        <p>In our account of the concert which was given at this institution, by Madame Meyer we omitted to mention the names of Mile L'Abbate and M. Luigi Azarelli, who contributed to the success of the entertainment by their excellent playing, and Mlle L'Abbate in addition sang Mercandante's "Ave Maria'’ most sympathetically. Silvestri's “Tosca" was played on the mandoline hy M. Azarelli, who was accompanied by Mlle B. Reitz, and though we cannot consider that such a piece of music can be well adapted to the mandoline, it was admirably rendered by both artistes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Maltese National Band</head>
                        <p>Yesteraday afternoon the concert ball of the Maltese National Band, which was formed on June 5 last, was opened opposite the Minet el Bassal exchange. The ceremony was presided over by the Rev. Father Giuseppe, honorary president of the society, and Professor Caruana, honorary secretary, represented those members ot the committee who were unable to attend ; the Rev Father Gardien was also present After the conclusion of the ceremony the prosperity of the club was toasted amidst cheers, and the instruments, which have been furnished by an Austrian manufacturer, where then distributed to the members. We trust that this band will find an early opportunity of demonstrating its musical capabilities to the public.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>British Chamber of Commerce.</head>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed 1896 with the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring information on trade matters generally, including the question of appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Homo enquirers can obtain further particulars from our London office, 36, New Broad-street, which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BOMBS IN TURKEY.</head>
                        <dateline>Constantinople, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Discoveries of bombs and other explosives in the houses of Armenians are causing much ill-feeling in Turkey</p>
                        </byline>(Reuter)<byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE TSAR PRAISES COUNT WITTE.</head>
                        <dateline>St Petersburg, October 1.</dateline>
                        <p>The Tsar declared in a toast that Count Witte is the most clever diplomatist in the world.</p>
                        <byline>(Havas)</byline>
                        <dateline>St. Petersburg, September 30.</dateline>
                        <p>M. de Witte has been created Count. </p>
                        <byline>(R.)</byline>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COUNT WITTE’S DECORATION</head>
                        <dateline>Berlin, October 1.</head>
                        The Emperor personally decorated M. Witte with the Grand Cross of the Red Eagle (R.)
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Kidnapping Case.</head>
                        <p>In August of last year the Slave Trade Department received advice that a Sudanese boy, son of Mulazim Awal Farag Effendi Ibrahim, had been napped. Subsequently one of the inspectors of he department arrested a Bedouin of the Besbariab tribe named Hassabo Mohamed for having taken part with another Bedouin of the Ababda tribe in the kidnapping of the boy and selling him to some Bedouins in the Hedjez. A special court which assembled on Saturday at the Native Tribunal in Cairo, consisting of Yemen Buy Ibrahim, who presided, Messrs de Hults and Willmore, Ahmed Bey Ziwar and Mohamed Bey Mehrez, for the trial of Hassabo Mobamed, found the accused guilty and sentenced him to two and a half years’ imprisonment with hard labour. Abdel Hamid Bey Hilmi appeared on behalf of the Parquet and Saghologasi Ahmed Effendi Bahir, inspector of the Slave Trade Department, who arrested the accused, represented the depart-ment,</p>
                        <p>The Sirdar and Lady Wingate left for Cairo by the nine o'clock train taking a special saloon carriage Shortly before the arrival of the train at Cairo a guard of honor, consisting of three officers, a hundred nor.-commissioned officers men with the battalions colours, and the cavalry band were drawn up inside the station and as the train steamed into the station at 12.2ft p m. \ salute of 19 guns was fired. A large it of officers both of the Egyptian Army and the Army of Occupation were present on the platform, and after shaking hands with all who bad come to meet him the Sirdar, escorted by a guard of one officer and twenty five non-commissioned officers and men, drove to the Sirdarieh.</p>
                        <p>Among those awaiting his Excellency on the platform we noticed Brigadier-General Bullock, Lord Edward Cecil Pasha, E. Bernard Pasha, the Staffs of the headquarters of the Egyptian Army and the Army of Occupation, the War Office, and the Sudan Administrative Office,</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARMENT TEFTISH.</head>
                        <p>Some time ago, on the transfer of the Daira Sanieh lands to the Daira Sanieh Company, the inhabitants of four villages comprised in the above teftish sent a petition to the former administration protesting against the sale of their lands, alleging that these belonged to them by right and that they had been unjustly deprived of them some sixty years ago by the Viceroy Mohamed Ali, and that later the lands were incorporated with those of The Daira Sanieh of the Khedive Ismail. The administration granted the petitioners’ request by leasing the lands in perpetuity to the inhabitants at a very low rental, equivalent to the Government tax. Oar Cairo Correspondent states that the authorities have now decided upon returning the lands in question to the rightful owners, the conditions being that they pay half the estimated cost in 20 yearly instalments with interest at 5 per cent, plus the usual tax. The of the properties in question is 12.000 feddans. and their present value is estimated ₤50 the feddan.</p>
                        <p>Oar Correspondent adds that it is probable that the Government will ask the Agricultural Bank or the National Bank to undertake the sale of these lands, and The collection of the annuities as they become due. Some of the native papers express their approval of the settlement of this long-standing dispute, and praise the Government for the equitable way in which it has arranged matters.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>OBITUARY.</head>
                        <head>CAPTAIN CECIL CAREY.</head>
                        <p>Captain Cecil Edward Eden Carey, died on the 19th ult. at Ashbourne Lodge, Winchester, Aged 40. He was the son of the late lieutenant. F. Carey, and joined the Servics as Cadet Jan. 15, 1879, being promoted to Lieutenant Dec. 23 1885, Commander June 30,1898 and Captain Jure 30. 1901. at which time he was in command of the Defiance, torpedo school ship at Devonport. He retired on Feb. 25 last through ill-health. As Midshipman he served in the Agincourt during the Egyptian War, 1882, and when sub Lieutenant obtained five firsts in his examinations. A few weeks before his retirement he was appointed assistant Direotor of Naval Intelligence.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ENGINEER COMMANDER WEBB</head>
                        <head>THE MC.MILLAN EXPEDITION.</head>
                        <head>INTERESTING INTERVIEW.</head>
                        <p>Mr. W. McMillan, the well-known American explorer, who arrived in Cairo last week from England with bis party, is leaving there tomorrow for Port 8aid to join the P. & Q. steamer Persia, by which the expedition proceeds to Aden, and thence by British India steamer to Mombasa, and from the latter port by rail to their destination. The other members of the party are Messrs. Bulpett, Jessen, Bayliss, Kay, Marlow, and Towell.</p>
                        <p>In an interview with one of these gentlemen on Saturday, our Cairo correspondent elicited some interesting particulars of a country still very little known to the outside world.</p>
                        <p>Last year Mr. McMillan paid a visit to this same oountry, and was so struck with it that he is now returning to take ap a tract of land 15,000 acres in extent, which he and two others of The party have purchased from the Protectorate of British East Africa with the intention of introducing ostrich farming on an extensive scale. This part of the country is admirably adapted to ostrich farming, and also farming in general, as a great portion of it consists of lands naturally fertile, and resembles some of the most beautiful districts of southern England in its picturesqueness. The property acquired is situated 35 miles to the north east of Nairobi, the capital of the Protectorate, and 330 miles distant from the coast,on the Attir plains, close to the Donyo-Sabuk mountain ranges which is 1,500 feet above the plain, the mountain itself being 5,000 feet above sea level. The rainy season Lasts for three months in these districts, from the beginning of April to the end of June, and daring this period the rainfall is about 25 metres. The rest of the year the climate may be described as almost perfect, the nights being cold and the thermometer falling about 35° Fahrenheit Nairobi is 30 hours distant from Mombasa by the Uganda railway. Mr. Mc Millan intends raising his first stock of ostriches by incubation; the eggs of the wild birds will be gathered by trained natives and placed under incubators, of which a large munber are being taken out by the party, and in this way it is hoped to get in time a fine race of ostriches, equalling in plumage and value those of South Africa. He is of opinion that most parts of British Bast Africa are most suitable for European colonisation, and thinks that the Zionists made a great mistake in declining the generous offer made them by the British Government lately of a free grant of a large tract of country.<p>
                        <p>We wish the adventurous American explorer and his party every success in this their first attempt at colonisation, and the opening up of an almost unknown district to civilisation.<p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUGAR SPECULATION.</head>
                        <head>THE SAN STEFANO SUICIDE.</head>
                        <head>INQUEST ADJOURNED</head>
                        <p>The inquest touching the death of Tom, Peter,who committed suicide at the San Stefano Casino at 8 p.m. on Friday, took place at the Deaconesses’ Hospital on Saturday.</p>
                        <p>The jurors were Messrs. Douglas Allen, H. S. Martin and Otho. S. Constantino. After the body had been viewed by the jurors it was identified by The manager of the San Stefano Casino as that of a man he bad seen at 8.9 p.m. lying dead on the beach in front of the between the gentlemen’s and the ladies’ bathing place, with a revolver containing three undischarged and two empty cartridge cases beside him.</p>
                        <p>One bullet was sticking in the forehead of the deceased, the other had penetrated his heart. From the medical evidence it appeared that the deceased had died of a self inflicted wound. He was presumably of about 85 years of age and had P.S. tattooed on one of his arms. In his pockets were found a registered postal packet addressed to Mrs. Schablousky of Arnold Street, Liverpool, and some postal odrders made out to Joanna Shcablousky, also of Liverpool. The deceased has been given at Paris a passport to travel in Russia, which had been visaed by the Russian consularauthorities, on the strength of a passport from Christiania., He is described in the Paris passport as a British subject named Tom Peter, resident in Ceylon, and a Christian by religion. As some doubt was fait whether the deceased was really a British subject it was decided to adjourn the inquest sine die pending farther enquiries.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CALABRIAN DISASTER.</head>
                        <p>The "Matin” of the 23rd ult. announces that the Minister of Public Works has ordered an inquiry into the subject of the alleged purchase by the Orleans Railway Company of several thousand shares in the Egyptian 8ugar Refineries and in the Say Refinery. The Government is absolutely determined, if the purchase is confirmed, to make the private estate of the railway company bear the loss caused by the recent slump in the value of the shares.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUDAN MERCANTILE CO. LTD.</head>
                        <p>September 19th, by Herbert Smith and Co., 62, London Wall, EC. Capital, ₤10,000, in 8,500 '’A” and 1,500 "B” shares of ₤1 each. Objects: To carry on the business of financiers,merchants, manufacturers, miner, explorers, contractors, etc. No initial public issue. The first directors are to be appointed by the signatories. Qualification, 400 shares. Remuneration, as fixed by the company. Registered office, 5-6, Great Winchester Strreet, EC.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAND AND MORTGAGE COMPANY.</head>
                        <p>The annual drawing of the four-and-half per cent. debentures (Series "B”) of the Land and Mortgage Company of Egypt, Limited, will take place at 11.30 a.m. on October 6, at the offices of the company at London.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Messageries Maritime mail boat Niger, which left Marseilles on the 28th ult, passed the straits of Messina on Saturday and is due at Alexandria to-morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ESTATES.</head>
                        <p>The Committee of the London 8took Exchange has ordered the under mentioned security to be quoted in the official list: —</p>
                        <p>Egyptian Estates, Limited —250,006 Ordinary shares of ₤1 each 15s. paid, Nos. 1 to 250,006.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head>
                        <p>Engineer Commander Arthur Thomas Webb died on the 14th ult. at Haslar Hospital, aged 43. He joined the Service July 1, 1883, and was promoted to Engineer-Commander July 9, 1902. As acting assistant Engineer of the Tyne he served during the naval and military opera tions in the Eastern Sudan at Suakin, 1884 85 (medal with clasp and bronze star), and as assistant Engineer of the Starling was present at the battle of Gemaizeh, Dear Suakin, December 20, 1888 (clasp).</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="notes from port said">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Port Said, Sunday.<dateline>
                        <p>It has keen officially intimated the Suez Canal authorities that they hope to be in a position to establish regular traffic through the canal by the end of the week and I can personally testify to the enormous amount of work which is being done at kilometre 18 by the large staff of engineers others who have been sent on special duty there. Hopes have been expressed that the canal will be Via sufficiently good condition to permit of the passage of the mail on Wednesday next, which proves beyond dispute how mash hard work is being done.</p>
                        <p>Mr. Harris is to leave on the 5th. I have, in company with MM. Coallant and Tillier. The divers who have been specially engaged for the work of blowing up the few remains of the Chatham, have arrived, and are now being instructed by Mr. Harris in the work of electric firing, etc. in which the famous chemist is, to say <unclear>sok.</unclear> The astonishingly quiet and plucky way in which this gentleman's party arrived on the work of this most dangerous experiment is spoken of here on all sides; people, now the great soars is over, have time to think, and one hears bat one opinion of the way in which Mr. Harris and his assistants performed their task.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <byline>(By Telegraph).</byline>
                        <dateline>Monday, <date value="1905-10-02">10</date>. 16 a.m.</dateline>
                        <p>Mr. Harris and his two assistants will probably leave next Sunday. The homeward mails <unclear/></p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Italian Consul General, Baron Acton has addressed the following letter to the press.</p>
                        <quotedLetter>
                            <opener>
                                <dateline>Alessandria, li <date value="1905-09-30">30 settembre 1905</date>.</dateline>
                                <salute>Gentilissimi Signori,</salute>
                            </opener>
                            <p>Mi pregie seguare riceruta e ringraziaro de</p>
                            <p>SS.VV. della loro lettera di ieri con cai mi confermano la rimessa a questo Consolato della somma di P T. 5493, ammontare del ricavo netto della serata data dalla stamps alessanddrina la sera del 18 corrente, a favore dalle vittime del terremoto della Calabria.</p>
                            <p>Colgo l'occaisione per pregare le SS.VV. di voler gradire ed esprimere i miei sentimenti di viva gratitudine ai membri della stampa che vollero organizzare la serata di beneficenza, cosi ben riuscita grazie allo slacio ammirevole di carita di questa cittadinanza</p>
                            <closer>
                                <salute>Con distintissima considerazione</salute>
                                <signed>Il R. Console Generale E. Acton.</signed>
                            </closer>
                        </quotedLetter>
                        <p>The issue of the unique newspaper published yesterday in five languages by the Associazione Internationale dei Soccorsi Sanatari d’Urgenza was a great success, and reflects not a little credit upon those who were charged with its publication and the organisation on the day’s proceedings, which consisted chiefly in distributing the paper and making a street collection. In this way a sum of P.T. 10,270.5 was collected, and will be handed over to the Gouvernorat for transmission to the proper quarter. The collection was made by a number of young ladies, each wearing a broad rad band with the words "Pro Calabria" written across it in large gold characters, and the sam collected shows that bat few closed their ears to the appeals, or their eyes to the charms, of these</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="personal and social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        Among those who arrived by the Austrian Lloyd mail boat we noticed Sir Reginald and Lady Wingate, Sir R. Von Slatin Pasha, Johnson Pasha, Baron Menasce, and many others.
                        Mr. M. di Collaito, the Cairo correspondent of the “Phare d’Alexandrie”, has been appointed editor of the "Progress" in succession to Mr. Marengo, who has joined the firm of H. Devries & Co.
                        Antoine Bey Mesciaca returned to Cairo from leave and resumed his duties as director of the administrative service of the Sanitary Department.
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PASSENGER LIST.</head>
                        <p><unclear>Suex fey</unclear> the P. and 0. SS. Victoria, being brought to Port Said by passenger train. Should the canal still be blocked on the arrival of the outward mail on Wednesday, which is pretable, a similar plan will be adopted.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM FAYOUM.</head>
                        <head>A CASE OF BRIGANDAGE.</head>
                        <byline>( From our Correspondent ).</byline>
                        <p>Medinet el Fayoum, Sunday. The other day a gang of brigands the Shinoda esbeh, which is quite close to the mudrrieh buildings. They killed one man who was working on the esbeh and injured two others severely. Both of these men are now in the hopsital, and the condition of one of them is made to be precarious. Unfortunately such ocurances are by no means infrequent in this province, and statistics show that crime is on the increase in these districts.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SENNOURIS MURDER.</head>
                        <p>I mentioned in my last notes the natives who are living on Mr. Graea's esbah refused to give any information concerning the murder of Mr. Matalon, and asserted that they nothing about it Six of them have, however, now confessed that the sheikh of the esbeh and his son are guilty of the crime.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE MIXED TRIBUNAL,</head>
                        <p>Mr. Simpson, manager of the National Bank, Shoonah, and M. A. Arbib, of the Bank of Egypt, have been selected as members of the Mixed Tribunal.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="sport and play">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>  <!-- TODO Re-OCR this section -->
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CRICKET.</head>
                        OVER 29 v. UNDER 29.
                        Played on Saturday resulting in a draw. The good batting of Brereton, McLean and Dawson pat the senior XI. in a strong position though their opponents were not in good fielding form. For the under 29 XI. da Regemont played a good innings of 36. The other batsmen mostly found Maraden's bowling too tempting. Score and analysis.
                        Over 29.
                            O.	M.	R. W.
                        Byrne...		 13	4	42 -
                        Barnard		 13	8	51 1
                        Robertson	... 10	1	47 1
                        Watt ...		 4	1	18 -
                        Cheesman		 2	1	7 -
                        Henley.		 4 Under 89.	..	21 -
                        r. Weedon o. Freeman, b. Marsden ...
                        de Rougemont b. Marsden .........................................
                        Barnard b. Marsden ...................................... __
                        Byrne o. Logan, b. Marsden.......................................
                        Henley st. Dawson, b. Marsden...
                        Macaulay not out..................................................
                        CHeesman c. Dawson, b. Graves ... Harrison not out .................................................
                        did not bat
                        Mr. Stacey run out ........................ 18
                        „ Graves b. Robertson
                        „ Marsden run out .............
                        „ R. McLean b. Barnard ..
                        „ Breveton not out ... . 39
                        „ Dawson not out ..............
                        Capt. Bingley
                        Mr. Winter
                        „ Logan	 did not bot
                         Freeman  Lucas
                        B. 16, l. b. 1, w. 2 .................
                        7, n.b. 1.
                        Total for six wickets . Over 29 Bowling.
                        0.	M.	R
                        11	2	28
                        5	2	7
                        •	2	52
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARRIVALS.</head>
                        Le paqubot Hasburg, da Lloyd Autriohien arrive ce matin de Trieste avait a bord:
                        M. et Mme Rose et 2 enfants, M. et Mme Fracca, Riga Bey, M. et Mme Stabile, M. et Mme Kobn et 3 enfants, Mme Milcnvich et 4 enfants, Palelogo, M. et Mme Aghion, Castro et 6 de fam., Blaicher, Mardulfo et 3 de fam., Menasce et 6 de famille, Mme Ades et sa fille, Cohen, Castiglioni, Col. Nikie, Mamlouk et 4 de fam., M. et Mme Moroni, Zagdoun et 6 de fam., Nahum, Israel et 9 de fam., M. et Mme Tilche, Mme Tilche et 4 enfants, M. et Mme Jabos, Lindemann et 4 de fam., Francia, Sadler, Lidy Wingate, S.E Wingate Pacha, Cottins, Fenderl, Pini Bey, Reinhardt, Kenny Herbert, Sir von 8latin Pacha, Levy, Aghion et 2 de fam., Bialobos Bey, S.E. Johnson Pacha, Mortera, Husgar, Mme Kauky et 8 enfants, M. et Mme Constantin Sava, Arthur Wilson, G. Heller, Mme Victor Aghion et 3 enfants, Mme Stakia nos et 2 fils, L Sarkissian, D. A. Rizzi Mustafa Bey Fayed, Skill, Dietterle, Vangam, Srack, Mr. Graves 11 2 28 Aghion, Greaves, Kolischkine, Michalek, et 62 , passengers de 3me classe.
                        Watt
                        Lester
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        By kind permission of Lieut Colonel C. J. Markham commanding, and officers, 1st Battn. King’s Royal Rifle*, the Band will play the following programme of mosio by special request in the Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Tuesday) evening, commencing at 9 p.m.
                        1 March-The BnlewlThe Qtrl-CerylL 1 Overton-Mlrelle-Oooood.
                        » Oeenlee- I» Derain imoar-Ottng'1.
                        Two-etep—Weldmera—Doeoy.
                        S Selection—Ure Cloche* 4* Ocroertlle -PlecooeUe.
                        T Velee—Le Premier Belem-Leroolhe.
                        DU Wetohtpeiede Kmmnt
                        BetlmraanjUr^ ^ tin*	.
                        Tran* Blows.
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
