<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!--Daisy Vazquez--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- November 20, 2016 --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- 1905-02-02 --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE TSAR FORGIVES</head>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. The police yesterday
                        surprised a meeting of strickers in a tavern. They fired upon the people;
                        killing a girl and wounding four men. A supplementary official statement
                        give the number of killed on the 22nd ult. as 96, and the wounded 333, of
                        whom 32 died. {R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName> Warsaw,</placeName> February 1. The number of killed and wounded
                        during the recent disturbances here are variously estimated at from 500 to
                        1,200. The former is the more probable figure. There are still occasional
                        exchanges of shots in the suburbs. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. The Tsar has received a
                        delegation of workmen. He told them that he pardoned the revolt, and that he
                        would try and better their condition. Prince Mirsky has been relieved of his
                        functions at his own request. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName> Warsaw,</placeName> February 1. Quiet has been restored, and work
                        is being resumed. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. Today the Tsar will
                        receive a deputation of workmen at Tsarkoe Seto. Except at Warsaw, where
                        there is will considerable torment; the Russian provinces seem to be
                        generally settling down. Well-informed persons believe, however, that the
                        effects on the movement will be lasting, as it shows a remarkable ana
                        unsuspected vitality of co-operation among the Russian masses, which is
                        likely to manage itself whenever occasion arises. The deputation to the Tsar
                        numbered 34. They were accompanied by Generals Kokovstself aud Trepott. The
                        Tsar said that the incident, the deplorable consequences of which were
                        inevitable as the result of disorder, were due to the workmen permitting
                        themselves to be misled by traitors. Strikes and demonstrations constantly
                        resulted in disorders which must always no repressed by troops, He
                        recognised that the workmen's lives were not easy, but they must be patient.
                        It was a crime to come in crowds to declare their needs to him. He promised
                        to take measures to amenorate their lot and to assure a legal examination of
                        their demands. The Tsar concluded: —"1 pardon your transgression. Return to
                        work and do your duty." (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OUTRAGE AT ODESSA.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Odessa,</placeName> February 1. An attempt to assassinate the
                        Chief of Police here was made today. The chief was wounded by a revolver
                        shot. The assailant has been arrested. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HEAVY RUSSIAN CASUALTIES SANDEPU' IGNITED.</head>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. General Sakharoff
                        estimates the Japanese prisoners at over 300. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>London,</placeName> February 1. The “Daily Telegraph" learns from
                        Tokio that the Russian casualties from the 25th to the 29th ult. are now
                        estimated at from 36,000 to 42,000, and the Japanese 7,000. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. General Kuropatkin cables
                        that on the 31st ult. Sandepu was ignited as a result of the Russian
                        cannonade, thus compelling the Japanese to partially evacuate it. The
                        Japanese attacks on the neighbouring villages and passes were repulsed.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RESIGNATION OF PRINCE MIRSKI.</head>
                    <p><placeName>St. Petersburg,</placeName> February 1. Prince Mirski, Minister of
                        the Interior, has finally resigned. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HUNGARIAN CABINET CRISIS.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Budapest,</placeName> February 1. Count Tisza has resigned.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>Vienna,</placeName> February 1. Count Tisza has handed in the
                        Cabinet’s resignation. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p><placeName>LOCAL AND GENERAL</placeName> The Ibrahimieh Canal was re-opened
                        on Saturday last. The Post Office at Ibrahimieh (Ramleh) has been admitted
                        to the inland and foreign money order service. The P.0. Liner "Osiris”
                        entered the Khedivial Mail S.S. and Graving Dock Company’s pontoon at
                        Alexandria this morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Quail Exports-The total value of the quails exported from Egypt during the
                        last twelve months was LE. 9,873, as against LE. 10,169 in 1903.</p>
                    <p>Ottoman Bane Theft—The theft of LE 1,000 from the Ottoman Bank is still the
                        subject of an enquiry, but so far no results have rewarded the police.</p>
                    <p>Lots Turcs — The Credit Lyonnais informs us that at yesterday’s drawing of
                        the Ottoman Railway Lottery, the holder of bond No. 1,841,389 was the winner
                        of the "gros lot”</p>
                    <p>Alhambra Theatre.—Two debuts are announced for this evening, while Lumiere et
                        Tenebre is meeting with continued success. A ball will take place after the
                        performance this evening. The Fitzner Quatuorgave a most successful recital
                        at the New Khedivial Hotel, Alexandria, yesterday evening. Tomorrow evening
                        they will appear at the Grand Continental Hotel, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal— On the 30th January 13 vessels passed through the Canal, of which
                        9 were British, 2 Dutch, 2 Italian. The receipts for the day were frs.
                        313,398.67. The total amount received in dues from January 1 to 30 was frs.
                        10,776,436.32 Annoucements that they are opening a house at Cairo under the
                        same name as here, viz., R. J. Moss Co. In respect of the business of their
                        Cairo house, they have admitted into partnership and entrusted its direction
                        to Mr. John C. Cavafy, who for many years has held their confidence and
                        occupied a position of trust with them at Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Cairo Tragedy— An enquiry has been opened by the Cairo police into the
                        circumstances attending the death of an Armenian, Serkis Papayian, who died
                        in Abbaasieh Hospital on Monday from wounds inflicted in a murderous attack.
                        A certain Michel Marxian has been arrested on suspicion of being his
                        assassin.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Investment and Agency, Limited. —The “Pall Mail Gazette." in
                        discussing the prospectus of this company, says: There ought to be plenty of
                        opportunities for a business of this kind, and the company seems to start
                        with everything in its favor. It is not often the public are allowed to come
                        in on the same footing as the promoters, and we sincerely hope that the
                        experiment will be justified by brilliant success.</p>
                    <p>Bank or Egypt.— The directors recommend a further dividend of 6 per cent.
                        making 10 per cent for the year ended December 31, and also a bonus of 15s
                        per share on the old shares, and on the new shares one-fourth of the
                        dividend and bonus for the year, less the interim dividend paid in July last
                        on the other shares, after adding £170,000 to the reserve, including premium
                        on new shares, leaving £12,643 to be carried forward. For 1903 the dividend
                        was the same, but the bonus was 10s. per share.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Abbas Helmy Theatre.—There are few artistes who exercise such a fascination
                        over the public as does Signora Bellincioni, who gives the first of a series
                        of five performances at the Abbas this evening. And this is but natural. Her
                        talent is immense ; her interpretations are always original, always
                        fascinating, always in keeping with her enormous talent as an actress and a
                        singer. Her voice is of the softest; her manner of phrasing is an example of
                        elegance and good taste. The expression of her singing is grand, her art
                        conquers and enchants ; she is an artiste in every sense of the word, and no
                        one should miss seeing her in Traviata, in which she has acquired fame.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Tourist Steamers. — The White Star liner “Republic,” which arrived at
                        Alexandria yesterday from New York and Naples,made a remark ably quick
                        passage from the Utter port, whence she sailed on Sunday afternoon at 4
                        o’clock, thus accomplishing the voyage in 67 hours. She had 235 passengers
                        on board. Readers of this paper will observe in our advertising columns
                        particulars of the sailings of the vessels of the White Star Line from
                        Alexandria to Naples (reached in four days) and America. This service is
                        undoubtedly one of the best for reaching Europe and should be well
                        patronised by the many travellers nowin Egypt, who will soon be
                        contemplating their return journey. The immediate sailings are : S.S.. “
                        Romanic" (11,400 tons) Feb. 16; S.S. “ Canopic ” (18,000 tons) Mar. 9 ; S.S.
                        “ Republic ” (15,400 tons) Mar. 16 ;S.S. “ Romanic ” (11,400 tons) Mar. 30,
                        and the fares from Alexandria to Naples are £10 and upwards. Bookings may be
                        effected at the White Star agents in Alexandria, Messrs J. Ross and Co., and
                        at Cook’s Tourist Offices, in Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMLEH RAILWAY COMPANY. THE CITY EXTENSION.</head>
                    <p>A number of complaints have lately been made by the public against the
                        Alexandria and Ramleh Railway Company on the subject of the want of
                        accommodation at the temporary terminus of the line at Alexandria. Owing to
                        the recent bad weather these complaints became very rife, because there was
                        no shelter at all at the terminus. The company, it is only just to state,
                        has for some months past been urging the Alexandria Municipality to grant
                        provisionally permission to make a turning-point (bonde) and a shelter for
                        passengers at the new terminus in order that the trams should not have to
                        wait, and that thereby accident might be avoided. The compauy asked that
                        this request should be granted until some decision was arrived at on the
                        subject of the new city terminus in Mohamed Aly-square. The Municipality
                        refused to consider the question unless the company gave them a supervisory
                        control over the line in the interests of the publics. But according to the
                        company’s concession this control was vetted in the Egyptian Government, and
                        the board of directors of the compauy has no power to resign this right to
                        the Municipality, as it is the fundamental part of the concession. At the
                        present moment, therefore, the state of affairs is as follows. The
                        Municipality has given the company the power to extend the line to the
                        square according to the contract for the cession of the land for extending
                        the Ramleh-boulevard. But the Municipality has not yet come to any decision
                        as to the actual terminus of the proposed extension of the line into the
                        city. In the meantime it refuses to let the company make a provisional
                        terminus by the old station. The inconvenience resulting from this state of
                        things is obvious, and it is sincerely to be hoped that the Municipality
                        will find some means to solve the difficulty.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RAILWAY ADMINISTRATION.</head>
                    <p><placeName>Shebin-el-Kom,</placeName> January 30. For a long time past the
                        traffic to Tantah on the Ashmonn-Tantah line has been very heavy, especially
                        on Fridays and Mondays, when large numbers of the fellaheen visit Tantah for
                        the purpose of praying in the famous Mosque of Sidi Ahmed el-Bedawi. To
                        provide for this heavy traffic, the Administration in the begin-ing of the
                        year put on a 3rd-claas special train. This was a great boon to the
                        inhabitants of this province also as it gave them an opportunity of joining
                        the express to Cairo and Alexandria at Tantah at 9 am. For some reason or
                        other, this train has now been discontinued, and in its place an engine and
                        three carriages have been added to the ordinary train which leaves Ashmoun
                        at 8.40 am. for Tantah and returns from Tantah at 6.30 pm. Therefore anyone
                        travelling from Ashmoun or any intermediate station with the intention of
                        going on to Alexandria or Cairo, must sleep at Tantah all night if be
                        desires to reach his destination at an early hour in order to transact his
                        business and return the same day. The Administration is increasing it
                        expenditure without increasing the utility of the line so for as the
                        passengers are concerned. We would draw the attention of the Administration
                        to this matter, and urge it to run the extra carriage and engine as a
                        special train starting from Ashmoun at 6 a.m. in the morning and returning
                        from Tantah at 4.40 pm.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will attend prayers at Mariout Mosque to-morrow, H.E the Governor
                        being in attendance. His Highness will hold a reception at Abdeen Palace on
                        Monday, 13th inst The reception will be reserved for those who have recently
                        received grades and decorations from his Highness.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>
                    <p>The Legislative Council will meet on Saturday next. Yesterday it took
                        cognisance of a note from the Ministry of the Interior announcing the
                        election of five new members.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOTOR BUS SERVICE.</head>
                    <p>It is to be hoped that the Alexandria Municipality will be careful, before
                        sanctioning motor bases in Alexandria, to draw up an elaborate set of
                        regulations for strict observance by the concessionaire company who propose
                        to start the innovation. Unless most careful rules and regulations are made,
                        our main roads will be unsafe for man or beast,and cabs and private
                        carriages will be driven from the streets by the instinct of
                        self-preservation. For as matters at present stand anybody can be a driver
                        of a motor and there is no system of examination or licenses for chauffeurs.
                        It is appalling to contemplate the results of a service of rapid motor bases
                        careering wildly through the busiest parts of the city coder the guidance of
                        irresponsible native driven. We are decidedly in favour of a motor bus
                        service for Alexandria, and we think, if properly worked, it would be a
                        great boon to the city and suburbs, but before sanctioning it the
                        Municipality ought to impose the most strongest conditions with a view to
                        public safety.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Manage ment Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>S.S. “FORTUNA” REPORTED TOTALLY LOOT.</head>
                    <p>Rumours are afloat that the S.S. “Fortuna,” formerly of the Bell’s Asia Minor
                        Line, has become a total wreck in the Red Sea.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNHAPPY STATE EMPLOYES.</head>
                    <p>We are authorised to state that the Commission which is at present enquiring
                        into the position of the smaller employes of the various Government
                        departments, is taking into consideration the claims of the telegraphists
                        with those of the employes of the other branches of the public service. The
                        telegraphists will be treated in exactly the same way as the employes of the
                        various Ministries, who have petitioned for an increase of pay. Their claims
                        will be examined and, if substantiated, satisfied.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH CHARITY BAZAAR</head>
                    <p>Tuesday's Charity Bazaar at the French Agency was an entire success. The
                        large salon and the patio of the Agency had been decorated with great taste
                        for the occasion, the fair members of the French colony who sold at the
                        different stalls made the most charming and persuasive of saleswomen, and
                        their efforts were crowned with well-deserved success, a large sum having
                        been netted for the orphans and the aged or ailing poor. M. de la Bouliniere
                        was unable to preside over the function owing to his recent sad bereavement,
                        but his place was ably filled by Mme. de la Bouliniere and her daughters,
                        who received their numerous visitors and presided over the bazaar with their
                        accustomed amiability and graciousness, assisted by MM. Lecomte, Prevost,
                        Quercy, and de Vitasse, of the French Agency. The first visitors were
                        Princess Hussein and the Princess of the Khedivial Family, and later in the
                        afternoon Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, Mazloum Pasha, Ghazi Ahmed Mukhtar Pasha,
                        Lady Cromer, M. and Mlle. Gennadis, General de Negrier, M. and Mme Bousquet,
                        with the personnel of the French Consulate and numbers of other prominent
                        members of the French and of the foreign colony generally, were there and it
                        was not till 7 p.m. that the bazaar was over. The drawing of the lottery
                        tickets taken will take place on the 5th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VERDI THEATRE, CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>The Verdi Theatre company gave their farewell performance "I Puritani" on
                        Sunday night; and we may say that it can rank with anything they have so far
                        given us. Signor Tomisani was charming, above all during the 3rd act Signor
                        Baldelli was excellent, and Signor Borteoni—who usually has had only minor
                        parts—was most creditable. Signora Svicher was as wonderful as ever, and she
                        added to her lustre by a special performance of a fantasia by Offenbach. We
                        may say at once that her mastery over this (and, we under stand, other
                        instruments) is fully as great as that over her voice. The “harmonics" were
                        extraordinary, not merely as a “tour de force” bet for delicacy and tone. It
                        is not given to every cellist to prodoce faultless violin effects on a
                        violoncello ; therein not merely skill but also a considerable knowledge of
                        music is involved. And the rest of her playing was artistic, quiet, and
                        indeed thoroughly admirable. We understand that the company will, after
                        their present visit to Alexandria, return to Cairo, and that, among the
                        pieces to be given, Mignon will figure. We have, in these columns, said much
                        about the excellence of the Verdi Theatre, and unfortunately have had
                        occassion to compare it with the Khedivial Opera, most unfavorably (but
                        deservedly so) as for as the latter is concerned. The Verdi Theatre has
                        given us Signora Svicher and Signori Tomisani, Bal-delli, and Badini, four
                        singers of unusual merit. And we sincerely hope that the company will, on
                        their return, meet with a more appreciative—we bad almost said less churlish
                        —reception, and that Cairo may bo induced by experience to believe that
                        opera (and good opera) may be obtainable independently of abonnement and
                        State subsidy. To conclude, we may hazard a prophecy that if the Compagnia
                        Lirica is appreciated and remunerated according to its undoubted deserts, it
                        will be enabled thereby to afford a chorus and general ensemble worthy to
                        support and enhance the merits of its excellent “principals.” We quite agree
                        with the “Journal du Caire” that the chorus and staging of the Khedivial
                        Theatre beyond reproach. The orchestra is not so much so, witness the
                        Tristan et Isolde, though it is numerous and well organised. Naturally the
                        one theatre can and the other oannot indulge in these luxurious necessities.
                        And once more we repeat that the Verdi Theatre management deserve the
                        highest possible praise for the good work they have done. That they should
                        be at all comparable with, not to say at time* better than, the Khedivial
                        Theatre is the best possible testimony to the excellence of that work.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Asiatic Prince,” from Manchester, left Malta on Wednesday and is
                        due here on Sunday next, with passengers and general cargo. The S.S. "Creole
                        Prince" arrived in Manchester from Alexandria on Wednesday last. The
                        Messageries Maritimes S.S. “Sydney” arrived at Alexandria from Marseilles at
                        2 a.m. yesterday. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Djemil Pasha Toussoun. Turkish Ambassador at Vienna, arrived at Alexandria
                        yesterday from Cairo en route for Europe. Princess Said Bey Toussoun has
                        left London and embarks on the P.O. Rfl. “Isis" at Brindisi. Her Highness
                        'hopes to be in Cairo on the 8th inst, and will, as usual, take up her
                        residence at the Ghexireh Palace Hotel The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire
                        have chartered Messrs. Cook’s dahabieh “Hathor" for a trip up the river.
                        Lord Cromer leaves Cairo on Friday or Saturday for a dahabieh excursion up
                        the river which will last a fortnight Hon. John Ward, equerry to the King
                        and brother of the Lord Lieutenant of Ireland, who recently underwent a
                        successful operation for appendicitis, arrived at Cairo yesterday evening.
                        The Savoy Restaurant has now every evening the aspect of being en fete, all
                        the tables being engaged. Yesterday evening. Sir Ernest Camel entertained a
                        large party, including the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire, Lord and Lady
                        Howe, Birch Pacha, Major General Sir Stanley Clarke and Sir Edward and Lady
                        Colebrooke. At another table we noticed Mr. W. Heaton Armstrong and a party,
                        including Mr. Machell. Maitie Carton de Wiart, the Hon. 0. Murray, Master of
                        Elibank, Mr. Hobhouse, M.P., Johnson Pasha, and Col. Clark. Mr. and the
                        Misses Zakrewsky entertained a large party, including M. and Mme. Maximoff,
                        M. and Hoeltzke, and Baron von Haeften. Mme. Wetzlar entertained Com.
                        Clician and Marchese di Rudini. We also noticed Major Pine and Mr. Carter
                        Wilson, Count Kozsiebrodski and party, Lord and Lady Dalhousie, Princesse
                        Bonaparte de la Moshowa, Count Primoli, Count de Clary, etc. The latest
                        arrivals at the Savoy Hotel include Sir Ernest C easel and party, including
                        Mrs. Ceasel and Lord and Lady Howe, Sir Edward and Lady Colebrooke, Dr.
                        Scott and Lady Sarah Wilson. Other arrivals are Major Pirie, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Peter Martin, New York, Mrs. and Miss Whelen, Mr Xavier Charmes, Mr. David
                        King, Messrs. Arthur and Francklin Beebe, Miss Devahl, etc. Lady Colebrooke,
                        who has come to Egypt as one of Sir Ernest Cassel’s party, prior to once
                        more taking up the role of political hostess, proposes daring the coming
                        session, it is. reported, to revive the party salon of a generation or so
                        ago; convinced that so far at least as the Liberal cause is concerned,
                        society is not rendering to politics its full meed of duty. It is something
                        over two years ago that Sir Edward and Lady Colebrooke first opened the
                        doors of their charming house in Stratford-place to the liberal League with
                        Lord Rossbery as the lion of the evening. As a political hostess, Lady
                        Colebrooke was a signal success as she has always been in a purely social
                        sense, for she has wit, sympathy, and beauty. Lady Colebrooke is a daughter
                        of the late Lord Alfred Paget, and is a cousin of the Marquess of Anglesey.
                        The King and Queen stood sponsors at her christening, and attended her
                        marriage in 1889. Sir Edward, who is forty-three or thereabouts, is the
                        fifth baronet of a creation of 1759; and is the owner of some thirty
                        thousand acres. Among the passengers for Egypt by the “Marmora" is Mr. H. T.
                        Anstruther, who is bound for Ismailia. He is one of the official directors
                        of the Suez Canal Company and will take part in the annual inspection of the
                        canal by the directors. He is accompanied by his wife, the Hon. Mrs.
                        Anstiuther, who is a daughter of the 4th Baron Sudely. Boutros Pasha Ghali,
                        Mr. Malcolm Mellwraith, M. de Rocca Serra, and M. Bernardi left Cairo last
                        night to attend the last meeting ot the technical commission or the Mixed
                        Tribunals. The marriage of Neghib Bey Fehmy, the son of Scandar Pasha Fehmy,
                        to Miss Abontxia was celebrated at Zeitoun on Tuesday. We regret to lean
                        that Miss Friend, eldest daughter of Mr. E. C. Friend, of Max, had a nasty
                        fall while out riding, and dislocated her right elbow. She is, however,
                        progressing satisfactorily. Dr. Giffen, American missionary in the Sudan, is
                        expected to arrive from America next Tuesday by the Messageries Maritimes
                        Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice- Sir
                        Thomas Lipton, Major Johnstone, Mr. Fleming Burnyeate, Mr. Longworth, Mr.
                        and Mrs. H. W. Lee, Mr. and Mrs. Johnson, Mr. W. Bales Header, Exellen von
                        Blucher and daughters, Admiral Alfred F. Dale and Miss Dole, Mr. Clifford,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Nichols, Major de Winton, Major Hickman, Mr. and Mrs. Dymond,
                        Mrs. Taylor, Capt Sherbrooke, Mr. Lesly Bayley, Major and Mrs. Lombe, Mr. B.
                        G. Thornton, Mr. Bernheim, Mr. and Mrs. W. and Miss Campbell, Mr.
                        Smulders.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <p>H.S.C. SECOND WINTER MEETING.</p>
                    <p>In connection with the above, which will take place at Helonan on the race
                        course adjoining the Tewfik Palace Hotel on Saturday next, the management of
                        the Tewfik issue Tewfik race coupons at P.T. 55 for visitors and P.T. 40 for
                        ladies, to include 1st class rail to Helouan, luncheon at the Tewfik Palace,
                        entrance to grand-stand and paddock, afternoon tea in members' enclosure,
                        and 1st class rail to Cairo. These coupons are sale at the booking office
                        (Cairo), Bab-el-Louk, but to facilitate matters for the public and avoid the
                        usual rush at the station on race day, arrangements have been made for them
                        to be also, on any day previous to the races, at Stephenson and Co’s,
                        English chemists, Operasquare, Cairo. A military band will be in attendance,
                        as on previous occasions. The following is the lunch programme. 1.
                        Polonaise— Chopin 2. Overture-Emma de Resburgo 3. Value-Soiree d'Ete 4.
                        Selection-La Poupee-Audran 5. Sketch-By the Swanee River-Myddalton 6.
                        Valse-Sabre las Olas-Rosas The following program will be played during the
                        races: 1. March-Imperial Edward-Sousa 2. Overture-Romantique-Bela 3.
                        Valse-The Distant Shore-D'Albert 4. Selection-The Belle of New York 5.
                        Polonaise-Mashen 6. Toreader et Andalose-Rubenstein. 7.
                        Valse-Ballseeggez-Chabulka Moustafa Effendi el Aishy, Infantry Band.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BILLIARDS.</head>
                    <p>On Monday and Tuesday, 6th and 7th inst, a billiard match of 1,200 up will be
                        played at the Grand Hotel Continental between Mr. Jose Ortiz, champion of
                        Spain, and Mr. B. Melikian, champion of Egypt. Calendar of Coming
                        Events.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>February. Thurs. 2 Zizinia Theatre. French comedy company in Oiseaux de
                        Passage. 9 p.m. Abbas Helmy Theatre. Italian Opera Company in La Traviata,
                        9.30 pm. Fri. 3 Alderson’s Garden. Variety Entertainment 4 pm. Football
                        Ras-el-Tin School Grounds. Cup Tie. Yacoub Pasha Artin’s Cop for Lower Egypt
                        Government Schools Ras-el-Tin. Da-manhour. Kick off 3.30 p.m. Zizinia
                        Theatre. Armenian Benevolent Society. Benefit performance of Le Petit Lord.
                        9pm. Sat 4. A.C.C. ground. Cricket. A.C.C. R. Berks XI. l.45 p.m. sharp St
                        Andrew F.C. Captain’s XL Vice-Captain’s IX. Opening of New Ground Mobarrem
                        Bey New Khedivial Hotel Professor Felix’s Concert 9.15 pm. CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>February, Thurs. 2 Khedivial Opera House. Italian Opera Company in Adrienne
                        Lecouvreur. 9 pm. Theatre des Nouveantes. Variety Entertainment 9.30 pm.
                        Trocadero. Variety Entertainment. 9.3O pm. Ghezireh Pekoe Hotel. Small Dance
                        10 pm. Fri. 3 Mena House. Gymkhana. 3 pm. Zoological Gardens. Performance by
                        Ghizeh Boys’ Band in afternoon. Ezbet Gourgi Point-to-Point Races Sat 4
                        Helouan Second Winter Race Meeting. 2.30 pm. School of Medicine. Lecture on
                        Sleeping Sickness by Capt Grieg. 4 pm. Shepheard’s Hotel. Band Royal
                        Inniskilling Fusiliers. 4 to 6 p.m. Savoy Hotel Small Dance. 10 pm.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>“AU DE ROUGE.” GENERAL DRAPERY ESTABLISHMENT.</head>
                    <p><placeName>(Central Tramway Station),</placeName></p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>P. PLUNKET PROPRIETOR. DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH And IRISH TEXTILE
                        MANUFACTURES.</head>
                    <p>Ladies' Fanoy Silk Blouses and Skirts, and Fanny Material for Evening Wear.
                        Also Fans, Fancy Pins, Artificial Flowers, Pearl necklets and Chiffons.
                        Ladies’ and Gents’ Pocket Handkerchiefs In Real Irish Linen.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BEC PILSENER BEER</head>
                </div>

                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
