<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-07"> February 7, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 7, 1905
<div type="item">
<head>ENGLAND AND GERMANY</head>
<head>MR. LEES BELLICOSE SPEECH</head>
<head>SENSATION IN GERMANY</head>
<p>London, February G.
Mr. Lees speech, mentioned in yesterdays
telegram, has caused a sensation in Germany.
The papers are angrily demanding an explanation.
Some of them declare that Germany will
now Work with redoubled energy in order to
increase her sea power.</p>
<p>.Mr. Lees now writes that he was incorrectly
reported, and that what he said was that we
must assume all naval powers to bo possible
enemies. Owing to the growth of. such naval
powers, our possible enemies are more numerous
tliau hitlierto, aud, consequently, wo have
to keep an anxious eyu not ouly on the Medi-
terranean but also on the North Sea.
Tlie "BuuiUanl" Iranis from Berlin that,
unless Lord Lausduwuo promptly repudiates
the speech, Germany will ask for an explaua-</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>L'lCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
<p>A Foundlino.—An infant was found by the
police yesterday in a street in the Kom-el-
Shougula quarter.
The Pilorimaue.—A telegram from Jeddah,
dated last Saturday, states that the number
ol pilgrims who have lauded there to date
amounts to 46,000.
Stray and Ovyxerless Doos found in the
Kamleh and Moharrem Boy districts on tho
night of Saturday will ho poisoned by the
police.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>SITUATION IN RUSSIA.</head>
<p>Lodz, February 0.
Two persons were killed aud 15 wounded at
the cemetery hero yesterday in a oontliut win.
the troops during the funeral of some of the
previous victims.	(Heater.</p>
<p>St. l’ETKUSBllKO, February 6.
The address of llie nobles asks the Tsar to
allow the elected of tho uaiiou to participate
in the discgssion of the measures taken by th.
Govern men i.	t Haute</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GEN. G RIPEN BE KG'S RESIGNATION.</head>
<p>St. I'lteksul'hu, February 6.
Gene.al Kuiopatkin rep.rtssome skirmishes.
St. Petersburg, February ti.
^ With referonco to ibe rumours relating D.
certain thai the .luestiou was con idored some
days ago but mat It was tbeu s-.lvod by llie
acceptance of General Gnpeuberg's resignation</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>NORTH SEA COMMISSION.</head>
<head>A COMMISSIONER'S VIEWS</head>
<head>LORD CROMER’S TRIP.</head>
<p>(Prom our Correspondent.)
Medinet el-Fayoum, Sunday.
Iron! Cromer's speech boro yesterday has
made a vory good impression, and his strongly-
worded criticism on tho growth of drinking
habile has boeu taken to.hoart Many of the
otndeh\ who were araodg Lord ’ Cromer’s au-
dience, were so impressed that they have told
uio that they intend to potition the Govern-
ment against the manner in which liquor shops
are being opened everywhere in the villago’
without let or hindraoco. I intend to lowj “
local society hero to combat tho aloobolio qabit
among tho natives.	g. |~ . '
Lord and Lady Cromer and - I^yfrphetrioe
Tliynne paid a visit to xon* of’ t^Lnative
ku: tabs hero which is uniter th6 care of the
Ministry of Public InatruetUld.	,
They also visited the native Sefa Coulop
rohool. Della Bey, French consular agent here,
and tho members of tho school committeo
rec-ivod bis lordship there.
Tho party took tea at the Moudir’s residence
and left at 3.15 nun. for West*.
Gruesome Discovery.—The body of a native
woman, witti tho head, bauds, and legs out oil,
was luuml yesterday on tho banks of the Mah-
muudieh Canal, near Kamleh, aud removed to
the Government Hospital.
Bank or Egypt.—In regard to tho recently
declared 10% divideud of the Bank of Egypt,
wo may mention that this aud abouus ot 15s.
per share is equal to a uot distribution to the
shareholders of 16% ou the bauk's capital lor
one year.
Tub Maumal Theft.—It is suggested that,
m luture, to avoid iheit of bullion and valu-
able.-, »uch as occurred in the recent case ol the
Alabina., tbo Railway AduuulstiatlOu should
cousuucl special cars titled up as strong-rooms
tor tue transport ol treasure.
Ploughing Competition. — Tho Khodivia.
Agricultural Society bas decided to hold some
..racial trials ol a number of stoam-ploughiug
machines at alluubra on tuo 24lb lust About
six diltereut uincbiuea have already beeu
eutcreo tor the Competition.
Suez Canal.—34 vessels passed through the
Canal on Uio End aud 3rd lusL, 23 ot wbicU
were Bnusu, 2 Norwegian, 4 French, 2 Aus-
trian, 1 Tu-kisu, 1 Swedish, 1 Dutch, 1 Get-
man, tbo receipts for the two days being
irs. SS4.bSl.Uti. The total for the 3 days lu
Fubiuary amounted to Jrs. 1,123,1UU.51.
Delta Light Railway Co.—The Committee
ol the Loudon Stock Exchange bas ordered me
loliowiug securiiy to be quoted m tue Olliciai
Cist : tjjypttan Delta Clgkt Hatlxoagt, tUrUie.
issue ol 11,113 5] per cent. Cumulative Fie-
.ciouoe Shaies oi 4,10 each, luily paid, Noe.
03,32510 74,437 uRcgistcrod Shares aud Share
H arrai.ts to Bearer).
A1 enaHouse Gymkhana.—Tho totalnumber
u. visilois on Uriday wuo paasetl Uirougu tue
gules at the Mena liouse Gjiukhoua was SOU,
wuich is a record “gain.". No less than 53o
.uucueous were' served ou tliat day u the big
•iluiug-hall at Mena House Hotel, Tue
.triungcmeuls were througuout excellent.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>NOlViTTOOM SUAKIN.</head>
<head>H. M. S. “9EALARK" DAMAGE^.</head>
<p>(Prom ocr Correspondent).
Suakin, January 28.
H. M. S. '‘Sealark’’ arrived here from 8hiikh
Barghout on the 14th init in a damaged ion-
dition, having struck a rock about 4 milei off
8beikh Barghout whilst iurveying. Sho had to
como into Suakin for the nooessery repairs,
which have now been carried, out with thejaid
of dhrera and material obtained from 'the
,™', after surveying here bn'd
at Sheikh Barghout, will probably go into qook
and then 'ooqtiuae her survey as far: a*
Australia, which ia bar. final deetination.
The British fta "Dart” arrived from ]W
laud on thA 14th idst. with a very largo son-
nigumeut.lrf and fishplates for tho Soakin-
The British S.S. "Thomloy” arrived fjom
England on the 16 th inst, witha large oous%n-
ment of iron deepen for the railway.
THE POt^ELIrCOTrOK EXPEDITlbN
Aoooiding'to’tetelHljBncojuat tohand,Mljor
Powell-Cottdbi WhoWI Kbartouqi bjr an expo-
dition front the Tflle 'to'the &itabhfi, wa* at
Lado at the end of JJeojiyber.. Yip expddif on
was making good progress and was moelng
with every assutaoow from the ofSoala. The
, explorer was in good hqaith.
le	___
,r Lord and lady Cromer are expected to
arrive at Beni Hasan this evening.'
Wo hear that Lord CreraOr Is busily engagod
on his annual report,</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE PLAGUE.</head>
<p>During the week ending Saturday only two
cases of plaguo wore reported throughout
a. Egypt, ono at Suez and thoother in the Toukh
ie district.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>BOVINE TYPHUS.</head>
<p>During last week, 11 deaths from bovine
typus wore reported throughout Egypt, as
against 6,164 deaths daring the corresponding
week last year. Tho total number of deaths
to date amounts to 146,803.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>A CASE FOR ENQUIRY.</head>
<p>The Khedlvial Opera HAuw reasserted
itself in La Totea. The performance was in
overy way oxcelkut. Signora Pandolfitti obtain-
ed and justified.thJ welcome due.to an old
entire favorite both by hec singing and hy heh
acting. Signor Girand waaplooiiug and artistic,
and Signor Pohso was oonspicuous for the
excellence of bis acting; we oould wish: that
all opera s'ligat* would give as rnnob attention
to details. "II Sagrestaoo'': w*a amusing ;
and wo should likq.M hear more of Sig-
nor Sola, the “timbre" of vfcoaa.- vpiile
Ptat some chona. Staging aed cboqis were
alike all that jxrubi. bo-.dewed.. We trust
that other performance* will maintain this
level, and do away with tho undoubtedly
W irumwMA noosed- to Rigoletto (amongst
Other ptepee given). We .would say on* word
as to the orchestra. Though, it :i« certainly
composed of good musicians. anddireotedhy an
efficient oonductor, there is often apparent a
certain want of judgment, which might well be
remedied.—* leek of oomplete harmony with
the singers, This, in light opera, where the
melodies for the ohief performers are the most
prominent part, ffiay opt, be so harmful in
effect: bat it is fatal in any suoh opera as
Trie tan, or indoed m any pieoe where the
composer bas dovoted his attention to the
music and not only to those who execute ii In
a word, we would wish to find (and we-have
a right to expect) that sense of tnfemble
which it is the duty, as it should be the
pleasure, of the Khedlvial Opera Honse to</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
<p> m -SihliWiv 'XMi at Alexandria
at 4 o'cl&ir yt^wAsy fltornoou and moot
of the passengezs, 92 first class and 62
?h£2 iSkl®
Amita,Biion and BariiWi £i®£i«Cfount
von TruutflWJsdiwff, Ctourefc :d’Crsri,:and a
-tteonMJtaitaiwmd
this  The.-^tareM^ptaeeagets
wW. h* m^Wwd. to«m«»ta.(tt*. Sfcktawi*"
laavs. AWdria act Wednreda, rftamnn
at 5 o'clock, as' usuaL A number of p'staefigum
One of tbc foreign Admirals ou lL»< Couqui
non ol Enquiry, in an interview »llb <•
rarrcspoiBlc.il, Mini tliat, «Ui.c Utc Lomu..
jt the b>rpe>i«rls»ts, the trauimia.loi.crs a
The Admi.nl cxpcc cd tl.at tbc decision »ou
be sucti a.- to enable lira llussiaus to »alK o<
Battle or Flowers.—lUauks to the euergy
oi lira Fetes trammitwe, Cairo is becommB
uioie and more attractive as a winter resort,
louitsta tiud there all kinds ol distraction..,
■J aid tue battle ot dowers has been a iloci.nx.
I , icess. Ibtelrauluai disiraelious are uot Want-
j .yg either, ana aiuuug luese one may meutiou
I sue BeillizSellout, which is dosoived.y popu.ai
wlieiuver its brunches are luuutl. 25327-1
Tuberculosis at Alexandria is beiut
A Cairo correspondent writes:—To the west
if Abdocn-square is a nasty quarter where few
military aud moral laws are enforced and
sliero tho grossest criminality prevails. While
n that locality to-day (Friday) I learned that
n a quarrel between an Armenian and three
inn lives the Armenian waa so badly beaten that
be alter a week or more, died, and nothing
ban b -en done to the assailant* or murderer*.
In fact, the principal was pointed one to me,
.ml 1 was informed tliat a sergeant of police
was bribe.) to strike this man’s name off tho
*>ik—for they all were arrested at tho time of
the quarrel. I wish this matter to be inquired
into, fur it Is a mast gross outrage if it is true,
as I am led to believo it is.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN INVHSTMBNT AND
AGENCY. '</head>
<p>Some foolish oomplainta have appeared in
some Of the Cairo newspaper* In rt^ard to
allotment of the'shares of the Bg&tian In^st-
mentapd Agency, Limited. This outdry is
absolute nbnseuse, for the oompany has‘no
ocncession nor patents, and any ono of the
persons who consider themselves aggrieved in
uot having been allotted shares, oan start las
many companies for general financial business
u they like on exactly rimibir condition*</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>PROF. FELTSES RECITAL.</head>
<head>RUSSIAN LOAN IN FRANCE.</head>
<p>Paris, February 6.
Negotiations have been CompleUM lor the
issue ol a Russian loan Here. Near.y u
milliaiil »l Inu.e. ba e be. u entrusted to ibe
Russian loan* in Frai.ee- It is iin.len.lood the
whole loan i.n. I>eeb placed. The rate ot issue
Tuberculosis at Alexandria is beiug
vigorously fought by the bgypliau Anti-tuber
niunis League. During last year 2,363 inedica.
ouu.ullaiiuiis were gi.eu and 336 tubeieulou-
,-atlei.ls were Healed. During Uoramber last
1U3 persons were found to bo suffering from
tuberculosis, 76 were under observation, and 23
persons succumbed, the 1U3 tuoerculous pa
t.euLs were uisiributed as lollows among the
various laces.- 39 Greeks, 22 Arabs, 2D 1 tails..»,
■J Jews, 7 Maltese, 3 Armeutaus, 2 Austrians, 1
Russian, amt 1 Frenchman. From November,
l'J03, to the eudot December, l‘JU4, the league
■ssUed 1,235 preseriptlou* gratuitously. Di.
.cliiots Bey, the chairman of this excellent
institution, is heartily to be cougratn.ated on
ibe good work the league is dotug.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>OUTRAGE IN FINLAND.</head>
<p>Helsingfors, February 6.
A mail, disguised as a., officer, lias assassi
a ted .Mr. Johi.ssoii, Procurator ot the 8Se.ua
Finn, but intensely ..I'populu. as a proi.oui.a
pio-Kussiuii. His assailsnt has been arrested
{Heater</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GERMANY AND BULGARIA.</head>
<p>Sofia, February 6.
Prince Ferdii.aiid is to officially visit the
Emperor'William.	{Uacat.
COLLIERS' STRIKE IN BELGIUM.</p>
<p>Brussels, February 6.
A general strike of the colliers, in sympathy
with the Germun workmen, began in Belgium
to-day. Ouly 12 pits are now working. (it.)</p>
<p>Chahlehai, February 6.
A strike has broken out in the mining basin.
FRENCH MILITARY SERVICE.</p>
<p>Pa Kin, February 6.
The Senate liaa passed the clause fixing the
period of military service at two years. (B.)</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
<p>Tho Khedive lias returned to Kunbbeb. Hm
Highness will come to Alexandria on Thurs-
..ay next.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT.</head>
<p>Tho Public Work* Deportment has fixed
.lie following salaries lor tho under-oieutiuueG
ffirinls. The figures given represent pounds
Egyptian
Technical Service :— C. Crawley, 700; J.
Lamella Bey, 450.
Towns and State Buildings.—Clifton, 1,000 ;
Hewat, 1,000; Reboot, 700 ; Chapman, 600;
Pastour, 600 ; Ehrlich, 600; Euser, 400 ; Wat-
son, 400 ; Zoucas, 831 ; H. Passe, 360 ; Srnir-
giassi, 300 ; Bertrand, 276; M. H. FitzPatriok,
276.
Irrigation Service.—H. G. Piulaison 800 ;
Mahmoud Bey Sidky, 900; Moleaworth, 700 ;
Adamson, 600 ; B xwell, 600 ; Lamb ton, 430 ;
C-raper, 480 ; Sullivan, 300.
Survey Department—Captain Lyons, 1,400,
H. Hmuplireys, 720 ; Robert Bey 540 ; L.
Craig, 076 ; A. Lucas, 540, G. Fraser, B.
Wade and Dowson, 480 ; H. Skill, 360 ; B.
Weldon, 300; E Binosi, 240 ; Bertrano,
276 ; Elias Bey Sabbagh, 420.
Antiquity Service.—E Brugsch Bey, 800 ;
J. Quibeli and H. Carter, 600 ; G. Daressy,
500G. Leg rain, 480.</p>
<p>Professor Felix's concert took place at the ,
Khedivial Hotel on Saturday night as an- (
iounco.1, und considering the wet and tem- ;
pesinoits weather, was well attended. We mnst ;
congratulate the professor on his courage in ,
fixing a more modest price for the tickets than ,
is customary here for local artistes, who ex-
pect their kind friends to pay the sarao price ,
for tho pleasure of bearing them perform as |
they would do for distinguished artistes from
Europe who can command audiences without (
ho  touting system in vogue in
this country. Mr. Felix's selection of piece
was as it ought to bavo been, a happy one, as
his silvery touch was shown off to perfection
m mast of them. If there was one piece
more than another that elicited enthusiastic
applause we might pick out an exquisite
Nocturne of Chopin's (Opus 15 No. 2), in
which an olt-recumng melody framed in flow
mg cadenzas brought ont the pianist's remark
.blu agility of finger. Wagner’s "Chrcur dc*
Pileiiscs” from his "Vaisseau Pantffine,”
arranged by Lizt, was also much appreciated.
Mr. FtSlix'k wonderfully delicate touch is not
so well suited to tho heavier German music,
which requires greater breadth of tone and a
deeper sentiment. To our mind his conception
of Mendelssohn’s "Frffhlii.gs Lied” was quite
incorrect and far removed from the traditional
one as tangbt iu German Conaervatoirea,but on
the other hand, the Duo by the same com-
poser waa laultlesaly played.
Professor Pdlix was ably supported by Mr-.
Frederick Cree, who sang, first, a romance by
Giordano from Andrea Chenier with great
rofinnment, aud in tho socond part Beetho-
ven's famous “Per Pieta.” Her passionate
rendering of the presto, “Ah crudel I” quite
carried away her audience, aud on being eooor-
o.l she repeated it with even more verve than
the first time. We must not omit the lovely
little duet by Missa, “Los Koroaux Chanteurs,"
charmingly suug by Mrs. Cree and Mme.
Felix, nor tho instrumental trio performed
very ably by Mr. H. and Mr. L. Suzan accom
panied by Mr. Felix. Altogether a very plea-
sant concert, but we must suggest that another
time tho piuses between tbo items should be
curtaiU'd,and tliat a performer does not usnallt
rerire from the p'atforin between two pieoes
bracketed a and b. All praise to Mr. Lifonti
for tho splendid Pleyel pianoforte lent for the
oocasion.</p>
<p>British Chamber or Commerce.—We would
call the attention of persons Interested in
. Egyptian trade to the work of the British
Chamber of Commerce • of Egypt, whose office
l in Alexandria gives information as to stand-
ings, trade, Ac., to its members, and whose
monthly publication reviews our eommeroe-
: The annual suWription is XI and all British
I traders should become members. Our London
■. office, 86, New Broad street B.C., wt* *M
i | Lonond agency to th# Chamber,<p>
</p>
<div type="item">
<head>3EU  CO'S PILSENER 8Hh
TSARS SO HORST COMPETITtOI fOB OOitm.</head>
<p>N.B.—Infaoor Brandt now b«n* offtrtd to
Beware of »vin» 4»»o#ad eouiRsnors renara,
leva this very Buraajw Basse erBsj,</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>PASSENGERS’ LISTS.</head>
<head>ARRIVALS.	</head>
<p>Le paquebot "Tebo”, de la Cie PlOrio Ruljat- B
tino arrivd avant-hicr de Ulnae avail k bord:	c]
MM. Seb. Uualtieri, Arrigo Ro»si, ig. „
Autouello d'Uulx, Comte Carlo, cheY. Tummjwo- e
Saudri, Bug. Ultouo, sa Game et 2 tillea, Coijite a
Giac. Suardo, Com. Em. Maraini et sa dame,
tiius. Muller, 0. J. Bucblcy, M. etMmoBrown, g
3 demoiselles, Gtov. de Martino, Kiciotii Gin- p
baldi, A. Voyl, B. Schiavons, Palioiti, Matijde *
Boccacia, Diana Duly, Bontiiglio, Maria Frito a
25 paasagers de 3mo clause.	0
Lo paquebot ‘ Semiramis” du Lloyd Autri- (i
ebieA arrivi htae de Tn^te avail k heed:	J
M.et51meStooit,MmoKrumviede,M.Buihb, J
Spiegelberg, Poridis, Consul Nordenbolz eb’s* «
dame, M. et Mmo Klenivoska, M. et Mjne t
de Wale lie, M. et Mme E. Gilbertson, M. et \
Mme Hostoup Schulz, Lumbart et 4 comp., <,
Mayer, Coheu, Ernest Grill, Eugei Grew et deux u
de lam^ Lehlug, avocat Lorenzo Rmsi, M. et i
Mme Betokto, Scarpa, M. Mmeet MlleNabgcl,
Werdort Kuh.my, Flengffi, Bouche, M. et
Mme Gritoer, Breitncr, Mme Frankel, Lum-
berger, M. et Mme Gooke, Margradi, Dapli, a
Hunter, Aspis, Hicbaum, M. et Mme Ot}t>, '
Strauss, Eugei, M. et Mme Ulrici, Mme Jeitdee ‘
et 8 paasagers de 3uio ciaose.
Le paquebot ■,Sala*ie'’ des Messageries Ma <
ritimes, arrivd do Marseilto oe matin, avait 1
a bord :
M. et Milo Cemeray, M. et Mmo Bacpe- I
mrd. Mile Mane Armiugaud, Mmo 1. M. Ha. >
verua, M-, Mme. et Mile. W. Carr, Miles M.
et C. Simpson, Mile Blanche Power, MlleCblo-
lotuj Young, M. K- S. Hiuckes, M. Salama,
M. Julio Herrera, Dr. Johuaton, M. E. W.
Huated, M. ot Milo de Roqueteuillo, M. et
Mine Baillitre, Mmo Gaudm, M. et Mine
Gruot, M. Soymour de Rioci, M. Robert Ca-
moD, M. et Mile Van Doormmck, Milo Van
deu Boroh, Mme et MUe Cavanagh, M. et Mine
Lesbos, M- ot Mme Brtaaon, M. Rouanir,
M. et Mmo Bastert, M. Knupple, Mme flo
t’Aigle, M. Herbert S. Job, M. W. J. Stonlake,
M. H. Ordeu, Mme Roussefet, M. E. Buruel,
M. G. Zmtrus, M. Beylier, Mme G. Begay, M-
M. Briguon, Mmo et Mile Barrozzi, M. et Mme
ganval, M. Bug. AUatn, M. Kahn, M. R. I.
Floreutz, M. K. W. Gaskin, M. T. Lesto, Mile
I.laarl, M- Urauoux,M.Malin,MllaMellerag*s,
Mine ot MUe Oelzmann et 19pae«agera de 3me
et 4the classes.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>DEPARTURES.</head>
<p>Le paquebot “Habsborg'' du Lloyd Autri-
chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait k bord :
MM. lo Comte Dandidi de Sylva, 8.E. le
lieutenant-manichal Siedler et sa dame, Victor
vou Kbver. Consul gu‘ni!ral Orzedechi, M. et
Mme Rolleston, M. et Mme H. L, Koopfer,
tram. Path Palintfe, Mile Palmde, MUe voti I^il-
mader, Hon. A. Murray, M. P. de Portheim,
■	A. von de Hazay, Mme Jeanne de Lavigene,
■	Mme Hlltue Rumbold, M. et Mme Mooettig.
H. Kit tor von Waguer etsadamo, E. M. SeUtjn,
. Luhmanu, C. Sohinalz, cap. de Kodolisoob,
i Comte Huraco do Choiseul, M. et Mme Gold-
i schmid, P. lasoola, Johann Haekl, Pranza
Wirtschafter, Dr. RafaeUe Castellano et famille,
Hugo Rosenbaum, Meyer, Zueke'rbaoker, Revd.
• Ladislas, L Wol/dorf, Mme M. Winberger, Dr
. B. Friedmann, Napoleono Candiani, M. et Mme
j Carmelo Giovanni, et 4 paasagers de 8me
, olasse.
Colonel Sir Adolphus PRxfifeorg*, m Wd
son of U>e late Dulta of C*mWWi, V ytom
private secretary and equerry he way'for many
yeah, has arrived in B|jypt from Marseille*.
Sir John and.Ijady Evans will leave for
Khartoum next week.
^MiraUiC. EWi^^^bwaigpomted^
LteutsoanVCofo^el Kenne, Y. C, D. S. 0,
who was such a popularfignre in (Wfo eooety
when the 21st Lancera werp here, is to be
married in London early pisxtfeioiijzife Azfoela
Maty, youngest daughter of the late finbert
Hibcert and Mrs. Hubert Hibbert, of 2,</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ABBAS HELhfY THEATRE.
LUCIA DI LAMMKRMOOR.</head>
<p>Signora Isabella Sricher, the celebrated
operatic artiste, who created such a furore at
the Verdi Theatre in Cairo, and whose advent
bad been anxiously awaited by a Urge section
of the musio-loving public, made her debut at
the Abbas Uolmy Theatre ou 8atdrday Even-
ing iu Lucia di Laumermoor, and her magni-
ficent performance reached to the -full the
highest expectations which had been formed
regarding her. To'say that Signora 8richer
waa admirable or exoeQent, would be but to
very mildly express the quality of her per
formapoe, from every point of view. Indeed,
we venture to say that never has Egypt before
been honored by the presence of two such
magnificent artistes as Signs. Gemma Bellin-
cioni and Sigua. Isabella Sricher, and fr<>m the
rapturous applause so lavishly bestowed by
>■ enthusiastic and delighted audiences on each
1 of these accomplished ladies, it is oertain that
i the season will bo a successful one. Signa.
>	Svicher'a Lucia, on Saturday, was an inter-
' pretatiou such as is seldom seen. Her singing
1 was oertainly a revelation to many present,
>	and bar acting was of a high order and showed
careful study of this mobt difficult rfllo. The
■ tenor, Signor Tomiaaui being unwell, the
rile of Sir Ertgard waa sustained by Signor
. Pagaui, who scored a distinct suooeas. In fact,
v wo thiuk we have never heard Signor Pagani to
* better advantage. Signor Baldelli, in the
t small part of Raimondo, was excellent. The
. other minor parts were in good hands and the
t orchestra and chorus were fully up to their
t usual standard.
lire 2nd t)f ttie.0r8et of ^.Medraieh
has been conferred by Kheilive on Mr.
Lewj Judge of the Mixed Tr^bwEU sit Cairo,
on the oocasion of bis retuenmCE^ JBigb-
ness wiU give audience to Judjgii iAw 'on" the
lSthinst
Mr. Peny has gone.td Ppri Said, and
will return to Cairo ota Wedbeed*y-
. Th# gnat Italian actor, Sig. Novrili. wiU
arrive at Alexandria from Italy early next
month.</p>
<p>W» regret to announce the death o well-
known Egyptian resident at Btambenl in the
person ot Mehmed Bey, member of the finan-
cial section of tho Coandl of State, who died on
thritaMninjf aCUie 24th olio.' at his residence
atBeshiktash. The funeral took place in the
atcerooon at the expense of the-Privy Purse.
The list* Bey was the son of Ibrahim Pasha,
aud grand-nephew of Mohamed Aly Paaha.
Amougothers to be seen dining in Shepheard'e
Restaurant, yesterday evening, we noticed
Friuoe Ltchteqatciu, Baron von Drasch and a
party, including Mr. and Mrs. Beckham, Mr.
Baines and a party of 8, Marquis de Corea,
Barou de Walzdorf awl friends, Mr. and Mrs.
Lewis Nixon and a party of 10, including £fr».
Mather, Mr. Morton, Mr. and Mr*. JobnJ)upeo;'
Baron de \Vticker, M. Ernpaiu and soma Crispds,
Vtoomte aqd Vicomtease de Ftmtarbe, Vioomte
do Sapucahy, Mr. and Mrs. O'Donnell Hiller,
Liuut. and Mrs. von Meyer and a few fripod*,
ii/-, Mrs., and the Mieees Runerty, Mr. E. d«
Szeut-Ivauy and.friend* Mr. P. del*Bella
Casa aud a party, etc.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ANDREA CHENIER.</head>
<p>An admirable performance of Giordano’*
Andrea Chenier was given on Sunday night
Signor Pagani -was in splendid voice and gave
an excellent interpretatiorfof the exceedjngly
trying title rile. He waa the suooes* of, the
eveuiug. Signora D. Bassich, who mads bar
debut ou this oocasion, gave a fairly good
rendering of p«t of Maddaleua di.'Coigny,
but her voice'Ts not robust enough to stand
her in good steed iu an opera like Andrea
Chenier. As Carlo Gerard, the baritone Badini,
who possesses a voice of delightful freahue**,
was eminently successful. Sig. Montanari also
soured a distinct suocess.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>NOTIOl.
RIGOLETTO.</head>
<p>Last night, a very excellent perform an oe
of Rigoletto waa giver at the Abbas Theatre.
Excellent, we say, because in every respect
the “ensemble” waa a matter for admiration
and, at time*, even for Surprise. In Rigoletto
Verdi began to realise in a way which he
hitherto had not surmised, the'hnportant and
extensive powers of his miriL Up to thi-
poiut he bad written many lonea which had
been hummed and sung throughout the whole
world, but here he seemed to forego the I
enormous spirit of tune that was within
him, and to give himself up entirely to the
dramatic matter iu hand. Last night's per
formaucc Of tbo opera was eminently successful.
Signora Sricher, in the part of Gilda, wa*
from every point of view a very great suooeas ;
her voice, which possesses some of the most
exquisite qualities of modern vocalisation, was
proved on this oocasion to possets an exquisite
and, if ono may use the adjective in connection
with singing, a shining quality that impressed
one euoruiously, by reason of theabsolute purity
of it* ovocatiou. Her range is enormous; she
never misses her effects, and, to sum up, wo
regard her in no other light than that sho
is daxslingly brilliant She was frantioally
applauded, especially after her delightful
rendering of “Caro* noms,” which she was
obliged to repeat Sig. Tomisaui took the part
of tho Duke and enchanted everybody by the
magnificence of his singing. He is a tenor of
great power, and waa- in good form last
night, enthusiasm on the part of the
audience following everything he did. It stands
to reason therefore that his rendering of "La
Donna e mobile” waa triumphantly successful.
In the part of Rigoletto 8ignor Badini sang
excellontly, though be did not imprest na very'
much with his acting. The other parts were in
good hands. The chorus waa at at rims* disap-
pointing, bnt on the whole good, while the
: orchestra deserves oredit. ...........
Tomono# night, Signore Belhn«oni will
|*pp*rln F*hr*</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE CHAMBER8 of Mr. J. Norton</head>
<p>Kvshe. Baniater-at-Lew, are situated at
Maison Spiro, first floor, opposite the Saroy
RoW. ImmUN, (to. 8JWH*-*
The small danoo at Shtpfccaid's laet-night,
it ia U oodles* to i+y, gas a great success. Among
the dancers we remarked Mia. and Miss Car-
otid t, the Mioses Rafferty, Miss Wildbur.Miss
U. Porter, the Mi ses Budhead, Mrs. ftfd the
Aliases Haiseu, the Misses de Gelshemsn,
(ho Misses Hillen, Baron ^nd&rooets dft.yaa-
ailko, Baron M. Uppeuheim, Baron DobssmiVi,
Chevalier de Kappaid, Herr von Fob), Ijr. and
Mr*. Calami, etc.</p>
<p>Mr. Gibson Bowles, M.P, and Sir Curso* and
Udy Wyllie arc among the latest arrivals at
the Cataract Hotel, Assouan.
fptiier arrivals at this popular upriver hotel
include: Mr. and Mrs. K. Willis Swan, Mr. and
Mia. R. Leek, Mrs. H. Meyef, Mr. J. Laaoot,
Mr. C. Mohr, Mr. R. L and Mies Gardiner,
Meear*. Jungfleisoh, Messrs. Cohen, Mr. J.
Tremayne, Mr. John L. Lew, Mr. C. 8. Fried-
richs, Mr. and Mss. B. R Aokannan, Mr., Mrs.,
aud the Misses Pinkerton, Mr. Max Heunux,
Mr. Jean Lofobre, Mis* 8eott, Mis* Dreiser,.
Mr. and Mis L Braithwaite, Mr. Fuller Mait-
land, Miss Maitland, Mrs. Webrier, Misses Ar-
uiiilide, Mrs. Saunders, Capt Jackson, Mioses
Miles, Mias Waterhouse, Col. Wataod, Mr.
Jules Aghion, Mr. G. Chaix d’Est Ange, Count
B, IVsikiewicz, Mr*. Standish, Mr. and Mr*.
Hugh Cooper, Mr. Otway Toler. Mr. CS. R.
McVicar, Mrs. and Miss Henry Lee. ,</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR,</head>
<p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its
position on Nile bank. Under Garmon Manage
rnent. Moderate chargee. Patronised by oOoer
if Army of Occupation. Concert* twice daily.</p>
<head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
<p>Largest 1st class and meati oomfertaMe
li.ll.IOS
Anglo-American Nile Steamer,</p>
<head>Sa HOTEIL COMPANY.</head>
<head>iiyiR TRAIINR7 Xlf OOoCJTnTOl AUUIMHA 4 OHM</head>
<p>Three Sellings a-Weak.
''TuumSTiSw naasaa
u.ioeo*</p>
</div>
</div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
