<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Dante Grieco</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">October 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-03">May 3, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, MAY 3, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="section" element="weather">
                    <head>DAILY WEATHER REPORT</head>
                    <p>OBSERVATIONS BY THE SURVEY DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <table rend="frame" xml:id="deg-ta-dawr01">
                            <head>ALEXANDRIA</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">Direction of wind</cell>
                                <cell>North</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">Force of wind</cell>
                                <cell>Light</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell cols="2">State of Sea</cell>
                                <cell>Slight</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell rows="4">During 24 hours ending ? a.m.</cell>
                                <cell>Max. Temp in the shade</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="degC">27.6</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Min. Temp in the shade</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="degC">23.0</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Humidity</cell>
                                <cell><measure type="percentage">89.0</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Rainfall</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="mm">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>RUSSIAN UNREST. RENEWED DISTURBANCES. BRUTAL CONDUCT OF TROOPS.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Warsaw, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>The disturbances were renewed in the suburb of Praga at 11 o'clock yesterday
                        evening. The Hussars fired on the crowd, killing four per- sons and wounding
                        many. At 9.45 p.m. a bomb was thrown into a military patrol which was
                        passing through the chief street. The troops fired three volleys. The bomb
                        killed two Cos- sacks and a policeman, and wounded two ladies. Many persons
                        were killed and wounded by the volleys, but the number is unascertain- able
                        as the troops immediately surrounded the whole district. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Lodz, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>The crowds have stoned some patrols. The soldiers fired, killing two persons
                        and wound- ing a boy. Two other persons were killed during a similar
                        encounter with a police patrol. A bomb was thrown on a patrol yesterday
                        evening but without any effect. The patrol fired and killed three persons
                        and wounded two. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Lodz, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>Eighty-five thousand workmen are out on strike in this district. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Warsaw, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>During the fighting yesterday the troops not only fired but used the butts of
                        their rifles, bayonets, and swords, breaking the heads and limbs of women
                        and children, and inflicting serious injuries. 10 wounded died at the
                        hospital. The death-roll is at least 50.</p>
                    <p>Outwardly all is quiet to-day, but workmen are going from factory to factory
                        to compel the men to strike.</p>
                    <p>The troops at Kalismi, in Poland, entered a church when the congregation was
                        singing patriotic songs. A fight ensued. A soldier and some women were
                        killed.</p>
                    <p>In consequence of yesterday’s bloodshed a general strike has been proclaimed
                        throughout Poland and Lithuania. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Lodz, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>The strikers here number 75,000. (Reuter.) Minsk, May 2.</p>
                    <p>A bomb exploded yesterday evening at the police station here. A detachment of
                        Cossacks was fired on from the crowd and replied. The casualties are
                        unknown. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NAVAL MANOEUVRES. TORPEDO-BOAT GOES ON REEF.</head>
                    <dateline>Berenhaven, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>During the manoeuvres here yesterday night the torpedo-boat destroyer “Syren”
                        ran on a reef and broke her back. There is no loss of life.</p>
                    <p>(Later). The "Syren” and 33 other torpedo- boats and destroyers were
                        attacking the cruiser “Sapphire” in the harbour with lights out. The "Syren"
                        was steaming at a rate of 26 knots when she struck the rock. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY AND MOROCCO.</head>
                    <dateline>Tangier, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>Count Tattenhach, accompanied by the German mission, has started for Fez.
                        (Reuter,) Tangier, May 2.</p>
                    <p>The German mission has left for Fez. (H.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KAISER AT VENICE.</head>
                    <dateline>Venice, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>The Emperor William has arrived. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE QUEEN AT ATHENS.</head>
                    <dateline>Athens, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>The Queen of England has arrived. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEWMARKET RACES.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 2.</dateline>
                    <p>Two Thousand Guineas.—Betting: 2 to 1 against Croix; 4 to 1 against Vedas; 5
                        to 1 against Llangibby, 100 to 9 against Measure; 100 to 8 against Shilfa.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PAPAYANNI LINE.</head>
                    <p>The "City of Cambridge,” 3,844 tons, will sail for Liverpool on or about the
                        6th May and will be followed by the "City of Oxford," 4,019 tons, on or
                        about the 20th May. Both ships have excellent first-class accommodation
                        amid- ships and are fitted throughout with electric light. Fare £14 single
                        and £24 return. Special terms for officers of the Army of Occu- pation and
                        Government officials. For further particulars apply to the Agents, Barker
                        &amp; Co., 25824-6A6 Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>The Annual General Meeting of local sub- scribers to the Alexandria Merchant
                        Sea- men’s Home will be held at H.B.M.'s Consulate, on Thursday, the 4th
                        May, at 4.45 p.m. 96886-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G. P. 0., Alexandria, at
                            9.30 p.m. today.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Egyptian Delta Light Railway’s</head>
                        <p>summer time-table came into force on May 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p>One fatal case of plague was reported from Toukh yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Licenses</head>
                        <p>The Ministry of the Interior has granted licenses to Mr. George Michel
                            Nicrilis to practise as a pharmacist and to Mrs. Evangelista Tuti to
                            practise as a midwife in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Customs Administration</head>
                        <p>The Val de Tra- vers Asphalte and Paving Company, Limited, has obtained
                            the contract for the repair and renovation of the Customs shoonah at Bab
                            el Karasta.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Khedivial Opera House</head>
                        <p>We understand that tho Government has decided to rebuild the Khedivial
                            Opera House on its present site. The new building will be a great
                            improvement on the present one and the structure will be fireproof
                            throughout.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Onions</head>
                        <p>The onion crop this year is a record one. Already 1,700,000 bags (85,000
                            tons) haveE arrived at Alexandria, and from 800,000 to 400,000 bags have
                            yet to come down. The total crop is expected to be from 120,000 to
                            140,000 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>American Mission</head>
                        <p>The Rev. A. C. W. Saunders, of the Church of Scotland in Cairo, will
                            conduct the service at the American Mission in Tantah next Sabbath, May
                            7, at 11 a.m.. This will conclude the English ser- vices at the mission
                            for this season.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>P. W. D. Contracts</head>
                        <p>The contract for the earthworks to be executed west of the Yousfi, in
                            Beni Souef province, has been awarded to M. Chasseaud for the Koftan
                            tarrad and saliba, at the price of L. E. 1,762, and to M. D. Andrus for
                            the Dechacha tarrad and saliba, at the price of L.E. 3,601.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Italian Newspaper</head>
                        <p>A weekly Ita- lian newspaper, entitled “Il Tempo," is to be founded at
                            Alexandria and will make its first appearance on Sunday next. The editor
                            and manager is Sig. Quintavalle, the well-known Alexandria publicist. On
                            June 1 “Il Giornale" will again be published at Cairo as a daily Italian
                            newspaper nuder the management of Sig. Santorelli.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre</head>
                        <p>The début of the Magnani operetta company took place last night at this
                            theatre before a large and repre- sentative audience. The operetta given
                            was Joseph Strauss's “Fruhlingsluft," which was billed as "Primavera
                            Scapigliata." This lively operetta has been a great success in Europe,
                            and the performance last night did full justice to the brightness of the
                            dialogue and the vivacity of the music. The costumes were very
                            elaborate, and as the period was that of the Directory there was plenty
                            of scope for display. Where all were excellent it is invi- dious to
                            single out any artiste for special praise, but we must make an exception
                            for Signa Imbimbo, whose lively representation of a soubrette created
                            great enthusiasm. Owing to pressure on our space we must hold over a
                            detailed criticism until to-morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Cromer leave Cairo to- morrow on a steamer trip in the Delta
                        which will last for about ten days.</p>
                    <p>Viscount Milner will return to Cairo from Assouan to-morrow. He will come
                        down to Alexandria the same day and will stay here for a couple of days,
                        leaving by the Austrian Lloyd boat on Saturday next for Europe.</p>
                    <p>Brig.-General G. M. Bullock, C.B., Com- manding tho British Force in Egypt,
                        came down from Cairo to-day.</p>
                    <p>Sir William Garstin leaves Cairo for the Sudan to-day.</p>
                    <p>Count Antoine de Zogheb is paying a short visit to Ramleh and is staying at
                        the San Stefano Hotel-Casino.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Pigott, Judge of the Supreme Consular Court in the Ottoman Dominions, is
                        expected to arrive at Cairo on Monday next.</p>
                    <p>M. Bousquet, French Consul at Cairo, re- turned from Jerusalem via Port-Said
                        yesterday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Carter Wilson left Cairo for Europe yesterday. He will be absent for
                        three months.</p>
                    <p>Among the passengers who are leaving for Europe to-day by the "Hohenzollern"
                        are Count Gabriel de Zogheb, Gallini Pasha, Mr. F. Formby Back, Major
                        Rhodes, Major MacMahon, Mr. E. A. Harrison, Mrs. Willmore, Miss Caillard,
                        etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TYROL.- Weissenstein Castle 3410 ft. First class private hotel near
                        Windisch-Matrei; Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                        mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September.
                        Prospectuses and Pho- tographs, "Egyptian Gazette" office, Cairo.
                        253655-48*-37</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANDMANN-DALLAS OPERA. “THE TOREADOR"</head>
                    <p>The manager of this company deserves our congratulations on two things;
                        firstly, on con- ceiving the idea of giving an extra performance in aid of
                        the Jewish schools, and secondly, on chosing for such an occasion the
                        “Toreador.” The latter is probably the best play that has appeared at the
                        Gaiety in recent years: com- posed in a cheery strain the music is more
                        tuneful and original than usual, the libretto clever and witty, and during
                        Act I. the plot is quite interesting and easy to follow. The second act, it
                        is true, has suffered from changes, not all for the best, but it plays
                        brightly and seldom allows the attention of the spectator to leave the
                        stage. Of the eight plays we have just heard we should prefer a repetition
                        of the “Toreador" to any of the others. This impression is due to the foot
                        that most of the principals seemed more familiar with their lines and songs
                        than before. The part of "Giggs" gives great chances to the comedian, and
                        Mr. Cotter missed very few of them putting an amount of energy into his
                        acting that the house warmly appreciated. Miss Cor- lass made us wonder
                        whether she is more delightful and fascinating as a girl or a boy, while Mr.
                        Roberts—who surely should have played "Giggs"—made a lot of points in the
                        small part of "Gus Traill." Susan is not a character that suits Miss Morra,
                        though she made a very fair success of it, and Miss Marie Elba sang her
                        songs, especially "On, on he’s dashing," with great spirit and éclat. We
                        much admired the dancing of the little Gaiety trio and should have liked to
                        see them again, their one effort being very short and sweet.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>"VERONIQUE."</head>
                    <p>Musically and dramatically "Veronique” is on a higher level than any of the
                        pieces given previously by the Bandmann opera company and it may fairly be
                        described as "operetta” in contradistinction to “musical comedy.” There is
                        nothing very remarkable about the plot, and the music contains too many
                        reminiscences, though the "Swing Song" is pretty enough in an unassuming
                        way, but there is at least a thread running through the piece and some of
                        the dialogue is really amusing. On Monday night the Bandmann opera company
                        were at the top of their form, and in spite of some "cutting" (justified
                        perhaps in one or two spoken passages and quite wanton in the case of some
                        of the songs sacrificed), the piece went well. The honors of the evening
                        were carried off by Miss Georgia Corlass, who made a very gay and attractive
                        Veronique, dancing and singing well and looking extremely attrac- tive, and
                        by Mr. Ralph Roberts, who had studied Willie Edouin to some purpose and gave
                        an admirable rendering of Mons. Coquenard. His duet with the bailiff (Mr.
                        Sinclair Cotter) and his flirtation with the Countess de Champ Azur (Miss
                        Wilmot Karkeet) delighted the audience. Mr. Cotter was also good—if a little
                        inclined to overact—while Mr. O’Connor showed almost too much restraint, but
                        was in capital voice. The parts of Agatha and Denise were also well filled
                        by Miss Ziegler and Miss Nora Morra. On the whole it was the best
                        performance that we have heard, though the orchestra and the performers were
                        at sixes and sevens on several occasions, owing, as a rule, to
                        misunderstandings with regard to the encores which were frequently demand-
                        ed. There was a large and appreciative au- dience and we hope that the
                        Bandmann opera company will be as much appreciated in the further East as
                        they have been in Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>“THE HOLY CITY”.</head>
                    <p>The choir of St Mark's Church, Alexandria, assisted by several members of the
                        choir of All Saints' Church, Ramleh, who afforded so much pleasure by their
                        able rendering of Gaul's “Holy City” in St Mark's last week, gave this
                        beautiful cantata again yesterday evening in All Saints' before an
                        appreciative congregation. The work was again given with much spirit and
                        effect, and soloists, chorus, organist and pianist deserve much credit for
                        their excellent interpretation of the work. In the unavoidable absence of
                        Mrs. Bayliss and Mr. Percy Smith, the soprano and bass solos in “List the
                        Cheru- bic Host" were most kindly and ably taken by Miss MunGavin and Mr.
                        Johnston. We hope this will not be the last time we may hear these choirs in
                        similar work.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette. Dear Mr. Editor,— I willingly confess
                        to be the writer of the letter signed "Harmony,” wherein it was stated that
                        I, and many others, thought Gaul's beautiful music deserved comment. It was
                        very disappointing to see my letter misinterpreted by "Accord,” of whose
                        letter I entirely disapprove. Only those who know certain details (which it
                        would not be wise to print) understand the real cause of complaint.
                        "Ex-Choirmaster" has written a letter which is a disguised apology for a
                        stupid blunder. If the person who was entrusted to write the report had done
                        so in time for you to publish it with the rest of the programme of events on
                        St Mark's Day, all this heated con- troversy, which has now assumed a most
                        unpleasant and un-Christianlike form, would have been avoided, and I think
                        it would be better that no more anonymous letters be published on the
                        subject, which I am sure must be very hurtful to Canon Ward, who is away at
                        Jerusalem and for whom we all have a most profound respect—Yours faithfully,
                        Walter F. Sarjeant. Alexandria. 8rd May. [This correspondence in now
                        closed.—Ed.E.G.]</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DERELICT IN THE RED SEA.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent).</byline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Suez, Thursday.</dateline>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes steamer “Nera” reported that on the 28th ult. at
                        6.15 p.m., at 23 miles S. 40 E. of Shadwan, she passed the wreck of a large
                        barge (probably a native craft) and again the same wreck was sighted at
                        10.10 a.m. on the 1st inst. by the Dutch steamer “Sule”; the position given
                        is 27° N. 34° 35 E.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>From the above position it would seem that the wreck has drifted S. 60 E. 14
                        miles, and may be considered a danger to navigation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive is due to arrive at Bab el- Ghedid station to-morrow morning at
                        11.30 o’clock.</p>
                    <p>His Highness’s last reception at Cairo was held yesterday morning at Abdeen
                        Palace. His Highness arrived at Abdeen from Koubbeh Palace early and the
                        reception commenced shortly after eight o'clock and was not con- cluded
                        until noon.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivah also held a reception yester- day morning at Koubbeh Palace.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                    <p>No detailed news has been received at the Ministry of the Interior concerning
                        the engage- ment that took place recently at El Hamra. We note that some of
                        the Arab papers throw the blame on the Egyptian soldiers, who are accused of
                        mishandling some vendors of cigarettes and thereby precipitating the
                        conflict which took place. Whatever the actual cause of the con- flict, our
                        Arabic contemporaries, who can find nothing to criticise in the Ottoman
                        Admini- stration, would do well to abstain from criticism of the conduct of
                        the much-tried soldiers of the escort till an official report of the
                        occurrence reaches the Ministry of the In- terior.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MARONITE CATHEDRAL</head>
                    <p>The project of building a cathedral for the Maronite sect at Cairo is likely
                        to be realised in the immediate future. Negotiations are in progress for the
                        purchase of a residence for the Patriarchal Vicar in the Zaher quarter. The
                        site for the cathedral alone will cost £2,500, and the total cost of the
                        site for all the appur- tenances will amount to considerably more. One
                        wealthy Syrian Maronite has subscribed £8,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW LINE TO EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The Roumanian Steam Navigation Com- pany, which inaugurated its new service
                        from Constantinople to the Piraeus last week with the “Regele Carol,”
                        intends to extend this service to Egypt at a future date.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN TRUST &amp; INVESTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon a special meeting of the committee of the Alexandria
                        Stockbrokers’ As- sociation was convened for the purpose of con- sidering
                        the application made by the general manager of the Egyptian Trust and
                        Invest- ment, Limited, to the effect that the shares of this company be
                        admitted and quoted officially on the Stock Exchange lists. When the votes
                        were recorded it was found that the application had been voted unanimously
                        and this was notified publicly amid load acclamations. Now that the shares
                        are quoted officially we expect to see a brisk movement in them.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A. S. C. NOTICE TO OWNERS.</head>
                    <p>The Great Annual Handicap not having filled under its altered conditions, the
                        following race has been substituted: Great Annual Handicap of L.E. 100, 2nd
                        horse to receive L.E. 20 and 3rd horse L.E. 10 out of the Stakes. For Arabs
                        and C. Breds. Distance 1 1/2 miles. Entry on 15th May, 1905, P.T. 500.</p>
                    <p>Handicap to be published on 1st June 1905. Winners after publication of
                        weights of P.T. 8,000 or more to carry 7 lbs. extra.</p>
                    <p>Unless 10 entries are received the stakes will be reduced to L.E. 50, of
                        which L.E. 7 to 2nd horse and L.E. 3 to 8rd horse. A. S. Preston, Hon.
                        Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The following are the handicaps for the 1st Summer Meeting, second day, on
                        Saturday next:—</p>
                    <p>Ramleh Scurry.—Capt. G. B. Byrne's Fitz, 9.5; Mr. E. Karam's Coeur de Lion,
                        9.3, and Tamerlan, 9.7; Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Bana- back, 11.0, and
                        Klondyke, 10.0; Omar Bey Sultan and Ahmed Bey Bakri's Rachid, 11.7; Ishack
                        Bey Hussein’s Moofid, 10.11; Hussein Bey Sioufi's Sweetie, 9.9; Prince Omar
                        Tous- sonn’s Marzouk, 9.0: Saleh Bey Yaghen's Wassal, 8.10; Mr. Tueni's
                        Ajax, 9.0; Mohar- rem Pasha Chehim's Mizzaud, 9.10.</p>
                    <p>Pony Handicap.—Mr. E. Karam's Nimrod, 9.0, and Eclipse, 9.8; Mr. E. Bustro's
                        Roland, 9.6; Khalil Pasha Khayat's Suleik, 10.7, and Sadik, 11.0; Messrs. W.
                        B. Rees and G. H. Barker's Suari, 10.3, and India, 9.3; Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s
                        Fantazia, 10.4, and Royalist, 10.4; Ishack Bey Hussein's Shahrour, 10.10;
                        Hus- sein Bey Sioufi's Peacock, 8.12; Prince Omar Toussoun's Hadban, 8.2;
                        Saleh Bey Yaghen's Abou Arkoub, 9.0, and Spectre, 8.10; Hassan Pasha
                        Mohsen’s Taib, 8.6; Mr. M. Tueni’s Viking, 9.5; Elie Bey Sursock’s and Mr.
                        Tueni’s Amory, 9.6.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER’S SANE IMPERIALISM.</head>
                    <p>No one whose business it is to study the varying phases of public opinion can
                        have failed to notice that at the present moment a certain pessimism
                        prevails among thoughtful men in regard to the future of the Empire. People
                        are inclined to talk as if there were no alternative to that egotistical
                        Imperialism which strives for monopoly abroad and protec- tion at home save
                        a Little Englandism which is fearful of all responsibility, which suspects
                        the right of the Anglo-Saxon race to develop and to role the “lesser breeds”
                        and which looks with anxiety and dread upon that vast heritage of Empire to
                        which we have succeeded. To men of sane and liberal ideals both alternatives
                        are odious. They do not want a grasping, arbitrary, material, “tied-house"
                        Empire on the one hand, and on the other they cannot endure the thought of
                        abandoning our heritage of rule, and of shrinking from the responsibilities
                        and duties which go with the “white man's burden." “Is there no third way?
                        Must the choice lie between these two alternatives?”—such are the questions
                        which they ask. In our opinion, there is another alternative. The true
                        solution of the Imperial problem is, we hold, to be found in that sane
                        Imperialism of which Lord Cromer is the latest, and one of the greatest
                        exponents. That sane, liberal, and dutiful Imperialism has made Egypt and
                        the Sudan what they are, just as in the past it gave us the India of
                        Dalhousie and the Lawrences the India we possess to-day—and laid the
                        foundations of those daughter-States on whose freedom and loyal independence
                        the safety and welfare of the Empire depend. The shrill, ir- responsible,
                        and reckless Imperialism which asserts that it is force or self-interest,
                        the sword or a protective tariff, which alone can maintain the Empire is
                        only a passing phase. The Empire owed nothing to it in the past, and can
                        gain nothing from it in the future. It is by the application of a wise and
                        free Imperialism that Empires such as ours are built up, and can alone be
                        developed and maintained. Such sane Imperialism tolerates no cant in regard
                        to the abstract right of persons who are obviously incapable of govern- ing
                        themselves to attempt the task, and makes no pretense that the Hindoo is
                        capable of rule because he can pass an examination in English literature. It
                        knows also that freedom and complete self-government are the only condi-
                        tions on which the white Anglo-Saxon com- munities oversea will remain
                        within the Empire, and that in their case the race-feeling and sentiment
                        which it is now the fashion to deride as worthless bonds are links of
                        adamant to unite the Empire, if only we keep them un- corroded from the mat
                        of a sordid materialism and selfish interests. In truth, the antiseptics of
                        Empire are two:- In the case of the subject and coloured populations,
                        strength and justice and the determination to govern not in the interests of
                        the governors but of the governed. In the case of those white communities
                        which are in reality Britains oversea, absolute free- dom and the resolve to
                        rest the Empire on sentiment and loyalty, and not on mere material
                        bonds.</p>
                    <p>But it may be asked,—How are we to learn and to preserve the spirit of this
                        sane Impe- rialism? The answer is,—By studying the work and carrying out the
                        principles of the great exponents of such Imperialism. As a concrete
                        example, we would point to Lord Cromer's Annual Report on Egypt and the
                        Sudan published this week. It is true that Lord Cromer has only been called
                        upon to deal in practice with one portion of the Imperial problem,—that
                        which concerns the subject races. None the less, those who have eyes to see
                        cannot fail to note that he has the root of the whole matter in him, and
                        that if he had been asked, either at the Colonial Office or in the
                        Anglo-Saxon communities oversea, to help to build np the self-governing
                        portions of the Empire, his influence would have been equally potent and
                        equally sound. It is impossible to read what he writes on subjects connected
                        with the Empire without realising that he under- stands the principles of
                        freedom as well as those of justice on which the Empire rests. Mr.
                        Chamberlain, in one of those moments of reck- lessness which have marked the
                        last phase of his Imperialism, has proclaimed the monstrous doctrine, "No
                        Preference, no Empire." It is to the men who, like Lord Cromer, have de-
                        termined, while shirking no responsibility of government, to let their role
                        and work be inspired by liberal ideals that we owe the Im- perial
                        fabric.</p>
                    <p>We wish we had space to draw attention in detail to the great number of wise
                        and inform- ing things said by Lord Cromer in his new Annual Report. What
                        makes that Report of special interest this year is the fact that it marks an
                        epoch. The Anglo-French Agree- ment has legalised our position in Egypt and
                        has given us a free hand. We have now the right to build as we will. That we
                        can now build for the prosperity of Egypt, and the honor of Britain and the
                        Empire, is due to the circumstance that Lord Cromer and the band of men who
                        have worked so loyally under him have laid the foundations of government
                        well and truly. But though we cannot follow Lord Cromer in detail through
                        his account of his stewardship in Egypt or in his various suggestions for
                        new developments, we may notice one or two of the principles of govern- ment
                        which are laid down in the Report. Lord Cromer, like the wise and practical
                        statesman he is, does not attempt to formulate principles of government in
                        the abstract. It is in the course of his handling of concrete facts that
                        these principles emerge. Perhaps the most striking example of what we mean
                        is to be found in the following passage:—</p>
                    <p>"In deciding what general policy is to be adopted in countries such as Egypt
                        and the Sudan, low taxation should be the keystone of the political arch. It
                        brings general tran- quillity in its train. It is an essential preli- minary
                        to steady and continuous moral and material improvement. It allows, either
                        at once or eventually, of the adoption, without serious danger to the State,
                        of a policy in other matters which is in general conformity with the liberal
                        views and traditions of the British Government and of the British nation.
                        Ex- penditure on objects, however desirable in themselves, should, I venture
                        to think, be rejected, or at all events postponed, rather than that the
                        principle of maintaining taxes at a low figure should be in any degree in-
                        fringed. That is the policy which, for more than twenty years, has been
                        adopted in Egypt and for some seven years in the Sudan." This sounds simple
                        and obvious enough, yet we believe it contains the grand secret of
                        government in the case of Orientals. To make men good subjects they must be
                        contented; but no Oriental will be contented merely because of roads,
                        railways, and other public improve- ments, even though these in reality
                        confer great benefits upon him. The one thing that he cares for, and in a
                        sense is grateful for, is low taxation. Hence Lord Cromer has always
                        insisted that as far as possible public expendi- ture should be kept low. He
                        has never yielded to the fatal temptation of arguing that even if taxation
                        is made high, the people cannot grumble when they receive all the benefits.
                        If you give an Oriental population reforms and improvements, you may give
                        them what is good for them, but you will not be giving them what they want.
                        If you give them low taxation, you are certain to be giving them what they
                        want, and what they understand. Another admirable statement which may prove
                        of use to administrators is to be found in the para- graphs that deal with
                        the European Civil ser- vants in Egypt, with the method of their selection,
                        and with the salaries of such officials. In the first place, Lord Cromer has
                        devised an excellent system for avoiding jobbery in appoint- ments on the
                        one hand, and the difficulties of pure competitive examination on the other.
                        In regard to the question of salaries Lord Cromer follows in the steps of
                        Lord Cornwallis. Lord Cornwallis, it may be remembered, once told the
                        Directors of the East India Company that they could get plenty of men to
                        take the post of Governor-General of India for nothing, but that it would be
                        extremely improvident of them to adopt such a course. It is in the spirit of
                        this luciferous saying that Lord Cromer handles the question of high
                        salaries. Before we leave the subject of Lord Cromer's Report we most find
                        space for the very satis- factory passage in which he awards praise and
                        credit to the young British officers who have helped that able
                        administrator, Sir Reginald Wingate, in the government of the Sudan:— “I am
                        not called upon to discuss, and still less to defend, the British military
                        system considered as a whole. But I wish to say something of the officers,
                        and more especially of the young officers, with whom I am brought in
                        contact, and of whose work, in connection with the civil affairs of the
                        Sudan, I have had some special opportunities of judging. Nothing has struck
                        me more than their, versa- tility. The readiness with which they adapt
                        themselves to novel ideas and circumstances is remarkable....It is generally
                        found that the officer throws himself with whole-hearted zeal into the work
                        which lies before him, whether it be military or civil. He identifies
                        himself with the people over whom he has to rule....As for capacity for
                        civil administra- tion, all I can say is that some of the most valuable
                        suggestions which have been received about such matters as land settlement,
                        agri- cultural loans, &amp;c., in the Sudan, have emanated from officers who
                        but a short time before were performing purely military duties. ......I
                        doubt if any country in the world can dispose of agents who are their
                        equals. They certainly cannot find their superiors. All they require, to
                        supplement any want of knowledge or experience on their part, is technical
                        advice on professional subjects, and a little friendly guidance on matters
                        of principle from some superior civilian authority. When once they are taken
                        away from the routine of the barrack- yard, given some interesting work to
                        perform, made responsible for the proper performance of that work, and left
                        a good deal to them- selves, they speedily develop that power of government
                        which, I trust I may be lowedal to say without incurring a charge of undue
                        national pride, is the prerogative of their Imperial race.”</p>
                    <p>That Lord Cromer’s experience is in no way exceptional we have not a doubt.
                        The ma- from which the British officer is ma- nufactured is the best
                        material in the nation, —the material which produces in the Law, in the
                        Church, and in commerce, keen, able men. If the British officer—though, in
                        our opinion, his defects are greatly exaggerated —sometimes fails to do
                        himself justice, the fault is not his, but that of the system under which he
                        works. Lord Cromer's splendid tri- bute to the young British officer will,
                        we trust, not only tend to encourage men who have to a very considerable
                        extent been un- fairly criticised, but also force the home authorities—on
                        whom, after all, the main responsibility rests—to consider whether there is
                        not something wrong in an organisation which is unable to get better results
                        out of such good material.</p>
                    <p>We can only end as we began, by strongly urging any who are inclined to
                        despair of the Empire, and to imagine that it cannot be maintained except
                        under the principle of monopoly, to turn to Lord Cromer's Report. They most
                        not, as we have said, expect to find strings of abstract disquisitions on
                        the art of government: but if they will study it carefully, and note the
                        spirit which inspires it, they cannot but rise from its perusal strength-
                        ened and vivified. They will realise that the carrying on of the work of
                        Empire is consistent with the maintenance of Liberal ideals—we use the word
                        in the non-party sense—and that instead of injuring those ideals at home,
                        the possession and development of an Empire governed on the principles of
                        sane Imperialism will lend them support. Imperial duties and
                        responsibilities, properly understood and carried out serve as antiseptics
                        in the body politic, and prevent the growth of that narrow and selfish
                        materialism which, as history shows, is apt to overcome the moral force of
                        small, popu- lous, and wealthy states. ("The Spectator”.)</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <head>ARABIC TYPE. FIRST APPEARANCE IN ENGLAND.</head>
                <dateline>By Mr. Falconer Madan (B. N. C. Oxford).</dateline>
                <p>The use of Arabic and Syriac type in England can be carried a few years farther
                    back than Mr. Talbot Reed was able to do in his "History of Old English Letter
                    Foundries” (London, 1887), which is the recognised authority on such points. He
                    did not find any book in which Arabic occurred earlier than 1648, when Miles
                    Flesher printed at London a work ‘De Siglis Arabum.' And of Syriac he says that
                    it “did not make its appearance in England till the middle of the seventeenth
                    century"—in fact, not till the prospectus and specimen of Walton's Polyglot were
                    issued in 1652.</p>
                <p>In turning over a volume of the Thomason Civil War Tracts at the British Museum
                    lately, I was struck by a profusion of types of both languages in the margins of
                    ‘A Discovery of the Rebels' and ‘The Great Antichrist,' both by “J. V.,
                    Prisoner," and dated 1643 Thomason has noted that the author was Vicars, who was
                    not the well-known John Vicars, author of the ‘Parliamentary Chronicle,' but
                    John Viccars, an Oriental scholar, who was concerned with the preparation of the
                    Polyglot mentioned above. And on reference to Viccars’s one great work, the
                    “Decapla in Psalmos' (Londini, apud Robertum Young, Anno M. D. C. XXXIX), the
                    position became clear. ThE 'Decapla' is a commentary on the Psalms from sources
                    written in ten languages, and the title expressely states that it was "Novis
                    Typis Arab, and Syriacis Donates.” Here, then, is the first use of Arabic and
                    Syriac printing in England, in 1689. The whole fount is displayed on the last
                    leaf of the prefatory matter, and even Arabis and Syriac ligatures are to be
                    found in it.</p>
                <p>The dedication to Archbishop Laud states that “Decapla hæc, post annum integrum
                    sub prælo xXu3uvilisiav novis Typis Syriacis and Arabicis (sumptibus haud
                    exiguis) adornata in lucem emittuntor." This carries back the actual printing to
                    1638, and fits in with the letter from John Greaves of February 10th, 1637/8
                    (“Domestic State Papers,' vol. 381, No. 75), where a rather indefinite mention
                    is made of a purchase of Oriental puncheons (and ma- trixes?) by a Mr. Browne on
                    the Continent. This letter is mentioned by Mr. Talbot Reed. Even the "J. V.
                    Prisoner” is cleared up in the same dedication, where the author speaks of
                    himself as “post septennii vincula captivus.”</p>
                <p>It is interesting to note that in this very year 1639, when Dr. Thomas Greaves
                    printed his oration ‘De Linguæ Arabicæ utilitate’ and wished to print an Arabic
                    sentence, it is found in some copies written in in Arabic, and in some copies
                    printed in Hebrew type! The first Arabic printing at Oxford was in 1648, and the
                    first Syriac in 1661.</p>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ARAB CONQUEST OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Butler announces that he has come across a fresh piece of evidence for
                        the identi- fication of Al Mukaukas with Cyrus, Patriarch of Alexandria. In
                        the Syriac ‘Chronicon Ano- nymum,' edited with a Latin translation by Guidi,
                        occurs the following passage :- “Potiti sunt Arabes tota regione Syriæ et
                        Palæstine. Ægyptum quoque ingredi erat in animo: sed non valuerunt: custo-
                        diehantur enim fines magno exercitu et vi a patriarcha Alexandrino, locis
                        quoque quibus hostes in regionem ingredi aut egredi possont præclusis et
                        exstructis in ripa Nili per omnem regionem muris.” In other words, the
                        Moslem forces which over- ran Syria from 631 to 640 were deterred from an
                        earlier attempt on Egypt by a powerful Roman army placed on the borders, and
                        power- ful defences prepared, by the Patriarch of Alexandria. It is not open
                        to doubt that the Patriarch referred to is Cyrus, who was sent to Egypt as
                        Viceroy in 631, and the importance of the passage is that it furnishes
                        conclusive proof that Cyrus had the supreme military as well as civil
                        command, a point which has been called in question. Thus Prof. Lane-Poole,
                        in criticising the theory, remarks (Proc. Royal Irish Acad., vol. xxiv. sec.
                        C. 13, p. 254):- "Cyrus was Patriarch and civil governor, but not military
                        prefect; yet we find him (if be be El Mukawkis) commanding at the battle of
                        Heliopolis,” i.e.according to the Arab historians. Precisely, and given the
                        fact that Cyrus was responsible for the military defences of the country,
                        his command at the battle follows quite naturally.</p>
                    <p>Now as to the authority of the "Chronicon Anonymum.” Guidi is clear that the
                        document as it stands can be assigned with certainty to a date between 670
                        and 680, while the portions relating to the Persian kings have an air of
                        still greater antiquity. The writer was thus contemporary with, if not
                        earlier than, John of Nikiou, and may well have been actually con- temporary
                        with the conquest of Syria and Egypt. His authority, therefore, is of the
                        very highest order; it is independent of all Egyptian writers; yet, agreeing
                        as it does with John of Nikiou, it must be preferred, in any case of
                        collision, to that of the Arab historians, who were all much later.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>INNSBRUCK - TYROL.</head>
                    <p>Ideal Spring and Summer Resort. Beautiful promenades and mountain
                        excursions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOTEL TYROL</head>
                    <p>1st Glass Hotel, enlarged lately with an ex- tensive palatial addition with
                        every modern comfort. Fireproof System Hénnébique. Illustrated pamphlet on
                        Innsbruck free from proprietor: CARL LANDSEE.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAYY.</head>
                    <dateline>(From our Correspondent). London, April 22.</dateline>
                    <p>Colonel the Hon. M. G. Talbot, R.E., who recently went on half-pay on giving
                        up the appointment of Director of Surveys under the Egyptian Administration,
                        has taken his retired full pay. He entered the service just 82 years ago and
                        saw a great deal of service in Afghanis- tan, 1877-78, the Mahsood-Wuzeree
                        Expedi- tion, 1881, and the smashing of Mahdiism in the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Lieutenant Cecil Pearce, 1st Battalion Royal Berkshire Regiment, at Dublin,
                        has been promoted captain after a little over eight years' service. He
                        obtained his first commis- sion in February, 1898. This is the second
                        company promotion in the Royal Berks. this year.</p>
                    <p>At the Southern Police Court, Dublin, last Wednesday, Lieutenant Charles
                        Howard, Royal Berks. Regiment, was charged with being disorderly the
                        previous night in Dame Street, by having his coat off, shouting at the top
                        of his voice, challenging the crowd to fight him, and violently resisting
                        arrest. He was also charged with assaulting three constables. A medical
                        student, named M’Swiney, and Cap- tain T.R.B. Clifford, 3rd Connaught
                        Rangers, were also charged with attempting to rescue Lieutenant Howard. It
                        seemed that the de- fendants got involved in a row with the crowd coming out
                        of the Empire Music Hall, when the alleged assault on the constables took
                        place. For the defence it was stated that the defendants were assaulted by a
                        disorderly crowd, and that when Lieutenant Howard was being brought to the
                        police station he was struck twice by one of the constables on the eye. The
                        two officers were returned for trial to the City Sessions, in £10 bail, and
                        M’Swiney was fined in 20s., or 14 days, afterwards increased to 21s. to
                        admit of appeal, in addition to being returned for trial.</p>
                    <p>The following appears in the newspapers to- day :— Lieutenant Howard, of the
                        Berkshire Regiment, was charged at Dublin with participa- tion in a street
                        row, and was allowed out on bail to appear at the City Sessions. This was on
                        Wednesday. On Thursday a detective at Queenstown reported that he had
                        searched the luggage of a passenger giving the name of Courtney, who was
                        going on board the “Teu- tonic," bound for New York, and had strong
                        suspicions that he was Lieutenant Howard. Instructions were at once
                        telegraphed to Queenstown that Mr. “Courtney” should be detained, but
                        fifteen minutes before they were received the “Teutonic" had left, and Mr.
                        "Courtney” is now on his way to America.</p>
                    <p>The Sessions commence on May 6, and it is felt that the police cannot move in
                        the matter until then, as it is quite possible for Lieutenant Howard,
                        supposing it is he who left on the “Teutonic”, to voluntarily return by
                        then.</p>
                    <p>The friction between Lord Kitchener and the Military Member of the Council
                        was not al- together unexpected. Though the details of disagreement are not
                        yet specified, sufficient is told to give a broad, if not deep, insight into
                        the question. Lord Kitchener went to India as a reformer. Experience has
                        shown us that he belongs to the root-and-branch variety of that valuable
                        species. What is more, the country holds the firm opinion that this is just
                        the sort of reformer needed in India. Lord Kitchener, then, is interpreting
                        his duty as we would have him interpret it. In any circum- stances, perhaps,
                        he was bound to come into conflict with those who are euphemistically called
                        his colleagues. He could not by any possibility escape when his functions
                        are not clearly distinguished from those of the Military Member. It is a
                        consolation to be assured that there is no personal bitterness between the
                        two authorities who are at variance. It should be equally comforting to know
                        that Lord Kitchen- er has not disgressed from his intention. He means to
                        make the Indian Army an adequate machine for the tremendous purpose it has
                        to serve—the defence of the most vulnerable, or, at least, the most
                        threatened, part of the Empire. Nothing must be allowed to prevent him from
                        carrying that purpose into effect. If we cannot do without a really strong
                        Indian Army—and so much is absolutely certain—we certainly cannot allow the
                        man best capable of producing it to leave his plans half ac- complished.</p>
                    <p>The information furnished by Mr. Arnold- Forster in the House of Commons
                        regarding tho recruiting for the past six months, is any- thing but
                        encouraging to the chances of a long-service system of recruiting becoming
                        popular. It was hoped that it might have boon otherwise, since enlistments
                        for short ser- vice have been stopped for some six months now. The winter is
                        usually the best recruit- ing time of the year, and trade during the past
                        winter has been unusually slack. Yet for each month from October, 1904, to
                        March, 1905, there has been a falling off in the numbers taken, which
                        amounts to a loss of 3,140 as compared with the same period of 1903-4. All
                        this is very discouraging, but not in the least surprising to those who
                        doubted the success of Mr. Arnold-Forster’s methods. Meu do not en- list
                        nowadays from a sense of patriotism; the upper classes are sadly deficient
                        in patriotism, they are showing an increasing disinclina- tion to joining
                        even the commissioned ranks, because the prospects are so poor. It is hardly
                        to be expected that the poorer classes are going to enlist to gratify Mr.
                        Arnold- Forster and the Army Council. When the Army is made a career that
                        will compare favor- ably with civil occupations, recruits in plenty will to
                        forthcoming, and of the right sort. But there must be some assurance or
                        security that when a man leaves the Army he will be better off in the matter
                        of employment than if he had remained a civilian. In the present state of
                        feeling, I am afraid that any system of long- service recruiting is doomed
                        to failure.</p>
                    <p>After the termination of the combined man- œuvres of the Mediterranean and
                        Atlantic Fleets, the Second Cruiser Squadron under the command of H. S. H.
                        Prince Louis of Battenberg will proceed to Phalerum Bay to give leave for 24
                        hours. A cruise on the 11 Grecian coasts will follow, and about the 28th May
                        the squadron will leave for passage trial of 24 hours to Gibraltar. From the
                        latter place the squadron will leave tor Portland on the 3rd June.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRITISH GOODS IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>Messrs. W.P. Thompson and Co., chartered patent and trade mark agents, have
                        addressed the following letter to several home papers :—</p>
                    <p>We have received word from our agents in the Egyptian Sudan that that country
                        is being simply deluged with cheap Continental goods marked with English
                        trade marks; that the Custom House is desirous of stopping this trade, but
                        cannot do so, as the English manu- facturers have very few of them
                        registered their trade marks, but that they will at once stop such fradulent
                        importations of any regis- tered trade mark on the marks being put on the
                        register. The German manufacturers have been very much more wideawake than
                        the English in this respect. The Associated Brewers, of Pilsen, registered
                        their marks, and then got the Government to at once stop all beer imported
                        into Egypt and the Sudan with the word Pilsen or any of their marks on it,
                        unless shipped by them, and the Munich brewers have lately done the same as
                        regards Munchen and Munich. Some little time ago our agents discovered a
                        printing works in Egypt engaged almost exclusively in printing fraudulent
                        labels, which were used on goods sent not merely all over Egypt, but to
                        Singapore, Hong Kong, and elsewhere in the East. This place was broken up
                        through our agency by getting the rightful owners of these labels to
                        register, and then pouncing on it.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COAL IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>In regard to the statements of experts as to the absence of coal in Egypt, it
                        is interesting to remember that less than forty years ago scientists
                        declared it impossible that diamonds could exist at Kimberley, unless they
                        were carried thither in the crops of ostriches from some unknown land.</p>
                    <p>Captain Lyons in a recent report states:— “No reliable evidence of the
                        occurrence of coal in workable quantities in Egypt has yet been forthcoming;
                        most of the strata are of marine origin, and those which are not, have so
                        far yielded no traces of carbonaceous deposits, beyond local layers of
                        lignite a few inches thick at the most. The chance that larger and thicker
                        deposits may yet exist at points where they are overlaid by other beds is a
                        very slight one, and up to the present no indications of such have been met
                        with, in spite of the borings 400 feet deep in the oases, and the wide area
                        which has been traversed without finding any outcrop of beds of this
                        nature.”</p>
                    <p>It will be remembered that last year, with the consent of the Emperor
                        Menelik, a geo- logical expedition, under Mr. Barron, had been sent into
                        Abyssinia with a view to discovering, first, whether the native reports of
                        the existence of coal wore correct; and, secondly, whether, there were any
                        coal-bearing strata running into the Sudan. Mr. Barron's report is to the
                        effect that coal exists in the neighbourhood of Chelga. The question of
                        whether there are any strata running into the Sudan remains un-
                        determined.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TRADE WITH CYPRUS.</head>
                    <p>Principal Exports from Larnaca and Limassol to Egypt during March.<table
                            rows="10" cols="4">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>Larnaca</cell>
                                <cell>Limassol</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Barley</cell>
                                <cell>kiles</cell>
                                <cell>3,330</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bran</cell>
                                <cell>okes</cell>
                                <cell>10,092</cell>
                                <cell>11,850</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Potatoes</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>50,472</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Onions</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>8,220</cell>
                                <cell>540</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Wine</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>2,062 gallons</cell>
                                <cell>97,802</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Commanderia</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>– "</cell>
                                <cell>852</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cheese</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>23,574</cell>
                                <cell>3,048</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Pumpkins</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>680</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Snails</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>390</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Lemons</cell>
                                <cell>No.</cell>
                                <cell>62,280</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Linseed</cell>
                                <cell>okes</cell>
                                <cell>1,458</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mavrokokko</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>188</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Straw</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>18,690</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Gypsum</cell>
                                <cell>tons</cell>
                                <cell>785</cell>
                                <cell>785 1/2</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Spirits</cell>
                                <cell>gallons</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>520</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Vinegar</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>4,936</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Lambs' meat</cell>
                                <cell>okes</cell>
                                <cell>10,764</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Eggs</cell>
                                <cell>No.</cell>
                                <cell>62,250</cell>
                                <cell>8,200</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Goats and kids</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>119</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Oxen</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>189</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mules</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>15</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Horses</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Donkeys</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Pigs</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>19</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Camels</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Turkeys</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>109</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fowls</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>2,769</cell>
                                <cell>43</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Sumac</cell>
                                <cell>okes</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>1,230</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Beans</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>700</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Raisins</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>10,954</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carobs</cell>
                                <cell>kantars</cell>
                                <cell>– </cell>
                                <cell>928-63</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table></p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALDERSON'S CARDEN, RULKELEY.</head>
                    <p>In consequence of extensive alterations to the theatre in Alderson’s Garden,
                        there will be no play next Saturday, but tea will be served as usual.
                        25886-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WEAPONS AND EXPLOSIVES IN EGYPT. IMPORTANT LAW.</head>
                    <p>In a fortnight’s time the new law will come into force regulating the trade
                        in weapons, ammunition and explosives in this country. The following are the
                        main provisions of this law :—</p>
                    <p>Le commerce des armes, des munitions, du matériel et des matures explosives,
                        dont l'im- portation est admire par lee Conventions Com- merciales ne pourra
                        être exercée que par les personnes dûment autorisées par le Gouverne- ment
                        et dans les magasins désignés dans l’autorisation.</p>
                    <p>Cette autorisation est personnelle, et elle devient nolle si elle est cédée à
                        un tiers. Nul ne pourra transporter d’un endroit à un autre une quantité
                        d’armes excédant celle qui lui est nécessaire pour son propre usage, sans
                        une autorisation specials du gouverneur ou du moudir, et, si le transport
                        doit avoir lieu d’une ville à une autre ou d’un village à un autre, on
                        indiquera dans la permission le nombre et la nature des armes, ainsi que la
                        personne à la- quelle elles sont destinées.</p>
                    <p>Toute personne qui exerce actuellement le commerce des armes, des munitions,
                        du maté- riel et des matières explosives devra, dans le délai d’un mois à
                        partir de la publication du présent règlement, en faire la déclaration au
                        gouverner ou au moudir, en indiquant le ma- gasin dans lequel ces objets
                        sont mis en vente.</p>
                    <p>Il est absolument défendu d’avoir dans la Province-Frontière, des dépôts
                        d’armes ou au- tres objets indiqués à l’article précédent.</p>
                    <p>L’autorité de police aura, dans cette pro- vince, le droit de fairs dee
                        visites domiciliaires, dans les formes prévues dans les Conventions
                        commerciales et le procès verbal y annexé pour les perquisitions faites dans
                        la ligne douanière, de saisir et de confisquer les armes et les autres
                        objets désignés ci-dessus.</p>
                    <p>Est permise l’importation des armes de chasse et de luxe, ainsi que des armes
                        de com- merce, des munitions et du matériel ci-dessous spécifiés:</p>
                    <p>1. Les fusils âme lisse et les mousquetons de chasse, système Lefaucheux,
                        Lancaster, et autres, à un ou deux coups, se chargeant par la bouche, à la
                        condition que le diamètre de la bouche ne dépasse pas 20 millimètres.</p>
                    <p>Mais il est permis aux voyageurs d'importer des fusils rayés et leurs
                        cartouches pourvu qu'ils signent une déclaration par laquelle ils
                        reconnaissent que ces fusils sont pour leur pro- pre usage et que la vante
                        en est défendue.</p>
                    <p>Toute contravention à l’une ou 1'autre des conditions de cet engagement
                        entrainers, de plein droit, la confiscation du fusil.</p>
                    <p>2. Les armes de luxe, savoir: les armes anti- ques, ainsi que les fusils,
                        carabines, mousque- tons, revolvers et pistolets de toute longueur dont la
                        crosse, le chien ou le canon sont es- sentiellement enrichis d'or ou
                        d'argent ou ci- selés artistiquement. Pour que les armes de luxe, à
                        l’exception des armes antiques, soient admises, le prix de vente ne devra
                        pas être inférieur à 500 francs par arme pour les fusils, carabines et
                        mousquetons; à 200 francs pour les revolvers, et à 80 francs pour les
                        pistolets. Il est entendu que les armes dont l'introduc- tion est admise en
                        vertu des autres disposi- tions de ce tableau ne sauraient être considé-
                        rées comme armes de luxe et interdites sous prtexte que leur valeur est
                        inférieure aux prix fixés.</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui important des armes de luxe seront admises à importer en
                        même temps cent cartouches chargées à petit plomb, pour cheque fusil,
                        carabine ou mousqueton; toute- fois le prix des cartouches n'est pas compris
                        dans la valeur fixée pour ces armes.</p>
                    <p>3. Les fusils, carabines et pistolets dits Flobert et les armes semblables de
                        petit calibre, ainsi que celles à spirales dites de salon.</p>
                    <p>4. Les sabres dont la poignée ou la lame est essentiellement enrichie d'or ou
                        d’argent ou ciselée artistiquement.</p>
                    <p>Les épées et lames d’épées, fleurets d'es- crime et couteaux de chasse.</p>
                    <p>Tout voyageur muni de passeport ou teskéré en règle ne pourra importer qu’un
                        seul pistolet revolver ou une paire de pistolets de n’importe quelle sorte
                        plus cent cartouches chàrgées au maximum.</p>
                    <p>Toutes les armes dont l'importation est admise seront, après vérification de
                        la Douane, sans délai ni frais pour le propriétaire, à son choix, et par les
                        soins de cette administration, munies d'une ficelle plombée ou
                        poinçounnées.</p>
                    <p>L’introduction de tout matériel d'arme, de toutes munitions non mentionnés
                        dans le pré- sent tableau, de toute sorte de poudre, ainsi que de toutes les
                        compositions qui ont la même destination ou qui, inventées plus tard,
                        pourraient produire les mêmes effets que la poudre, telles que la dynamite,
                        la poudre coton dite fulmi-coton et coton azotique, la nitro- glycérine, les
                        picrates et fulminates, les mèches à mines et autres matières fulminantes de
                        ce genre, du salpêtre raffiné et non raffiné et du chlorate de potasse, est
                        interdite.</p>
                    <p>Toutefois, la défense d'importer des matières explosives n'emporte pas
                        prohibition d'impor- tation et de vente des produits qui, en vertu de leur
                        composition, sont explosifs dans cer- taines conditions ou qui peuvent
                        servir à la fabrication de matières explosives, comme, par exemple, le
                        soufre, l’éther, le nitrate de soude. Elle doit seulement empêcher
                        l’introduction de matières qui sont destinées à être exclusive- ment ou au
                        moins principalement employées comme poudres à carrière ou pour des usages
                        analogues.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Kaiserlich Deutsches Konsulat. BEKANNTMACHUNG.</head>
                    <p>Jm hiesigen Handelsregister ist die offene Handelsgesellschaft W. G. HERZ
                        &amp; Co. mit dem Sitze in Cairo und Zweigniederlassung in Alexandrien
                        eingetragen worden. Persönlich haftende Gesellschafter sind die Kaufleute
                        Friedrich Robert Wilhelm Gottlieb HERZ und Rudolf KIRCHMAYER, beide wohnhaft
                        in Kairo. Zur Vertretung der Gesellschaft sind die beiden Gesellschafter
                        unbeschränkt er- mächtigt. Die Gesellschaft hat am 15. Novem- ber 1901
                        begonnen. Alexandrian, den 2. Mai 1905. Der Kaiserliche Konsul. LS. J. No.
                        1815 25879-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Societe Internationale des Employes D'ALEXANDRIE </head>
                    <head>Siège Social: Rue Mosquée Attarine No. 21 </head>
                    <head>BUREAU DE PLACEMENT</head>
                    <p>Offres d’Emplois </p>
                    <p>BONNE MAISON d’Alexandria demande: </p>
                    <p>1. un employé connaissant bien la Mercerie. </p>
                    <p>2. un jeune homme aide-vendeur. </p>
                    <p>Demandes </p>
                    <p>Comptable pr. Le Carre sachant bien la Comptabilité et connaissant
                        l’Anglais.</p>
                    <p>Comptable pr. Le Caire avec connaissances en langues. </p>
                    <p>Comptable pr. Port-Said avec connaissances en langues. </p>
                    <p>Comptable pr. Alexandrie, comme employé général. </p>
                    <p>N.B.—Pour tous renseignements s’adresser soit directement, soit par lettre au
                        Siège Social de la Société, Rue Mosquée Attarine No.21. </p>
                    <p>Le Secrétariat est ouvert les Lundi, Mercredi et Vendredi de 7 h. 1/2 à 8 h.
                        1/2 du soir. </p>
                    <p>Les insertions ci-dessus sont faites gratuite- ment par lea soins de la
                        Société et seals, les sociétaires peuvent en bénéficier. 25735—7-4-906</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <div type="article" xml:id="deg-el-exma01">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS</head>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="8" cols="5">
                            <head>For Liverpool, by the S.S. &quot;Belgravian&quot;, sailed on the
                                19th April:</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>200</cell>
                                <cell>tons</cell>
                                <cell>cotton</cell>
                                <cell>seed</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Barker &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>151</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>T. Ghirghis et fils,</cell>
                                <cell>2,000</cell>
                                <cell>quarters</cell>
                                <cell>beans</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>184</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>cotton</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>F.C. Baines &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>200</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bank of Egypt,</cell>
                                <cell>455</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Peel &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>84</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Planta &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>66</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G. Frauger &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>65</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>157</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>1,211</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>cotton</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>N. Trianfafileu fr.,</cell>
                                <cell>241</cell>
                                <cell>bags</cell>
                                <cell>onions</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Deghem,</cell>
                                <cell>2,091</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>O.K. Levick,</cell>
                                <cell>5,157</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Eastwood,</cell>
                                <cell>1,516</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Hindi,</cell>
                                <cell>1,800</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Moh. Deff,</cell>
                                <cell>1,400</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Abouchanab,</cell>
                                <cell>377</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>M. Osman,</cell>
                                <cell>342</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>W. Crossley,</cell>
                                <cell>895</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>M. Deff,</cell>
                                <cell>1,380</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Hindi,</cell>
                                <cell>917</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>B. Antoun,</cell>
                                <cell>635</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Huileries &amp; Sav.,</cell>
                                <cell>955</cell>
                                <cell>bags</cell>
                                <cell>oil</cell>
                                <cell>cake</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>C. Bolonachi,</cell>
                                <cell>30</cell>
                                <cell>barils</cell>
                                <cell>cogniac</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Holz &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>42</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>wool</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>10</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Ross &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>665</cell>
                                <cell>empty</cell>
                                <cell>casks</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J.B. Caffari,</cell>
                                <cell>84</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Papapandelides,</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                                <cell>wagons</cell>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Various,</cell>
                                <cell>8</cell>
                                <cell>packages </cell>
                                <cell>sundries</cell>
                                <cell/>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>Pour PORT SAID et MERSINE, par le bateau ang. "Dakahlieh", parti le 22
                        avril:</p>
                    <p>Divers, 2,049 sacs riz, 410 sacs sucre, 100 sacs oignons, 22 sacs henné, 25
                        sacs fèves, 137 balls peaux, 31 colis légumes, 1,500 colis divers</p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="3" cols="4">
                            <head>POUR KOBE</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Peel &amp; Co., </cell>
                                <cell>300</cell>
                                <cell>balles </cell>
                                <cell>coton</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Barker &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>50</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>350</cell>
                                <cell>balles </cell>
                                <cell>coton</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="20" cols="4">
                            <head>For Liverpool, by the S.S. &quot;Anatolia&quot;, sailed on the
                                26th April:</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell>T. Ghirghis et fils,</cell>
                                <cell>1,000</cell>
                                <cell>quarters</cell>
                                <cell>beans</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Moursi Bros., </cell>
                                <cell>500</cell>
                                <cell>tons</cell>
                                <cell>cotton seed</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>M. Tilche e figli,</cell>
                                <cell>41 </cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>cotton</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>B. Tilche e figli,</cell>
                                <cell>64</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>325</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>B.J. Coury &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>129</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bank of Egypt Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>128</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mohr &amp; Fenderl,</cell>
                                <cell>302</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Peel &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>50</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>R. &amp; O. Lindemann,</cell>
                                <cell>50</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>330</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell> </cell>
                                <cell>1,419</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>cotton</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Tarpinian &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>44</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>wool</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Bank of Egypt Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>33</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>9</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Scriven Bros. &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>29</cell>
                                <cell>bales</cell>
                                <cell>fleshings</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Khedivial Mail,</cell>
                                <cell>42</cell>
                                <cell>cases</cell>
                                <cell>oranges</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>B. Hazan &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                                <cell>cases</cell>
                                <cell>cigarettes</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Alex. Bonded Warehouse,</cell>
                                <cell>7</cell>
                                <cell>cases </cell>
                                <cell>cigarettes</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cook &amp; Son,</cell>
                                <cell>9</cell>
                                <cell>packages</cell>
                                <cell>effects</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Moh. Osman,</cell>
                                <cell>650</cell>
                                <cell>bags</cell>
                                <cell>onions</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G. Scrivano,</cell>
                                <cell>1,208</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>C.H. Schoeller,</cell>
                                <cell>4,950</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>O.K. Levick,</cell>
                                <cell>1,740</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>N.D. Adamandiadis,</cell>
                                <cell>168</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Th. Eastwod,</cell>
                                <cell>3,912</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>L. Onofrio,</cell>
                                <cell>600</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>T. Ghirghis et fils,</cell>
                                <cell>3,150</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>M. Deff,</cell>
                                <cell>600</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G. Pappa,</cell>
                                <cell>670</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Moh. Eid,</cell>
                                <cell>650</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Ibr. Deff,</cell>
                                <cell>2,990</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>N. Antoun,</cell>
                                <cell>274</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Hindi,</cell>
                                <cell>1,219</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Various</cell>
                                <cell>11</cell>
                                <cell>packages</cell>
                                <cell>sundries</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="21" cols="4">
                            <head>Pour Brindisi et Treiste, par le bateau autr. "Habsburg&quot;,
                                parti le 29 avril:</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H.A. Deghem,</cell>
                                <cell>2,000</cell>
                                <cell>sacs </cell>
                                <cell>oignons</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>L. Tolentino,</cell>
                                <cell>3,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Banca Mobiliare,</cell>
                                <cell>3,500</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Griva fr.,</cell>
                                <cell>3,768</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Coen &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>600</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Hess &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>3,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G.D. Kaniskeri,</cell>
                                <cell>3,500</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Stern fr.,</cell>
                                <cell>998</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G. Brach &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>1,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Banca Anglo-Austriaca,</cell>
                                <cell>3,075</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Grioni,</cell>
                                <cell>3,600</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>S.G. Violara,</cell>
                                <cell>3,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>C. Constantinidis,</cell>
                                <cell>2,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Stavridi,</cell>
                                <cell>1,000</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Riches &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>260</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fili Facchini,</cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                                <cell>sacs </cell>
                                <cell>noix de coco</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>R. Delia,</cell>
                                <cell>81</cell>
                                <cell>cages</cell>
                                <cell>tomatoes</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Sté An. Le Khédive,</cell>
                                <cell>12</cell>
                                <cell>cais. </cell>
                                <cell>cigarettes</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>F. Iglich,</cell>
                                <cell>53</cell>
                                <cell>cages</cell>
                                <cell>tomatoes</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Frick,</cell>
                                <cell>14</cell>
                                <cell>barils</cell>
                                <cell>poisson frais</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Divers,</cell>
                                <cell>23</cell>
                                <cell>colis</cell>
                                <cell>divers</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <table rows="19" cols="4">
                            <head>Pour Trieste, par le bateau autr. &quot;Daphné&quot;, parti le 1er
                                mai:</head>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Birra di Graz,</cell>
                                <cell>1,400</cell>
                                <cell>barils</cell>
                                <cell>vides</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cook &amp; Son,</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                                <cell>cais.</cell>
                                <cell>tissus égyptiens</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>F. Oberhofer,</cell>
                                <cell>2,000</cell>
                                <cell>sacs</cell>
                                <cell>oignons</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. Stavridis,</cell>
                                <cell>998</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Grioni,</cell>
                                <cell>998</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Filli Facchini,</cell>
                                <cell>484</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Griva fr.,</cell>
                                <cell>233</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>R. &amp; O. Lindemann,</cell>
                                <cell>545</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Planta &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>154</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd,</cell>
                                <cell>250</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>G. Riecken,</cell>
                                <cell>30</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mohr &amp; Fenderl</cell>
                                <cell>255</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>F.C. Baines &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>32</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. Hess &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>33</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Schmid &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>108</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>30</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>B. Barki,</cell>
                                <cell>33</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Birch &amp; Co.,</cell>
                                <cell>30</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>1,500</cell>
                                <cell>balles</cell>
                                <cell>coton</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="7">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dbc01">
                    <head>DAVIES BRYAN &amp; Co.</head>
                    <p>Continental Hotel Buildings CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>St. David’s Buildings, ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>and 35 - 37 Noble Street LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>English Tailors, Drapers and Outfitters.</p>
                    <p>TRAVELLING REQUISITIES: COMPRESSED CANE TRUNKS. SOLID LEATHER OVERLAND
                        TRUNKS. GLADSTONE &amp; KIT BAGS. SUIT CASES, RUGS, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>ATHLETIC GOODS: A VARIED STOCK, INCLUDING Slazenger’s Doherty “E.G.M.” Demon.
                        AND Ayre’s Central Strung Racquets.</p>
                    <p>TENNIS BALLS FRESH SUPPLY WEEKLY.</p>
                    <p>BOOTS &amp; SHOES.</p>
                    <p>All the newest shapes in the best English makes:—</p>
                    <p>BUCKSKIN TENNIS BOOT AT £1 A SPECIALITY.</p>
                    <p>Owing to the increased business in this Department a new Showroom has been
                        fitted up where better attention can be given to Customers.</p>
                    <p>CLOTHS: The largest Stock in Egypt of Cloths of the best British Manufacture
                        : TROPICAL TWEEDS, FLANNELS, DRILLS, &amp; c., &amp; c</p>
                    <p>All garments cut by experienced English cutters. Fit and style
                        guaranteed.</p>
                    <p>GENTS’ OUTFITTING: The newest Shades in Crepe de Chene Ties. Cellular,
                        Oxford, Zephyr Shirts and Pyjamas in great variety.</p>
                    <p>Special Attention paid to Shirts Made to Measure.</p>
                    <p>HOSIERY AND UNDERCLOTHING IN THE BEST MAKES.</p>
                    <p>PANAMA, STRAW, &amp; FELT HATS CORK &amp; PITH HELMETS. CAPS.</p>
                    <p>HOUSEHOLD LINEN AT SPECIALLY CHEAP PRICES. TABLE CLOTHS, NAPKINS, SHEETS, AND
                        PILLOW CASES. FLANNELETTES, VIYELLAS AND CEYLON FLANNELS.</p>
                    <p>SOAP, PERFUMERY, RUBBER SPONGES, BRUSHES, STUDS, MIRRORS (Hand &amp; Shaving)
                        FOUNTAIN PENS, &amp;c., &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Davies Bryan &amp; Co., Cairo &amp; Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="8">
                <div type="section" scope="financial" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-el-ameb01">
                    <head>ARRIVAGES A MINET-EL-BASSAL</head>
                    <p>du mois de mai 1904</p>
                    <table rows="31" cols="7" xml:id="deg-ta-ameb01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>Du</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">Coton</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">Graines de coton</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">Fèves</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>684</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2023</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>169</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,177</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>271</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>891</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2,393</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>999</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,906</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1,340</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>5,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>178</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1229</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,268</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3285</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>7,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>5,010</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>2156</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>8,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,154</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1876</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>9,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>548</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1248</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>418</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>818</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>—</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>11,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>209</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>3,239</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1015</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>12,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>250</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>701</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1383</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>13,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>—</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2,550</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1243</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>14,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,859</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3922</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>15,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>316</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,626</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1835</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>16,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>476</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>8,372</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>2554</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>17,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>37</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>838</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>4051</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>18,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>5,001</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3416</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>19,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>—</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>682</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1578</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>20,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>511</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2,237</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>2290</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>21,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>326</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,852</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>1989</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>22,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>188</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,542</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3150</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>23,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>162</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>3,777</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>4138</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>24,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>181</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>3,853</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3951</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>25,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>98</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,633</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3205</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>26,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>357</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>3,015</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>7159</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>27,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2,598</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>5705</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>28,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>70</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>1,122</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>2465</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>29,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>2,107</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>7007</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>30,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>—</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>251</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>5801</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>31,</cell>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>3,238</cell>
                            <cell>sacs</cell>
                            <cell>3238</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>S/B </cell>
                            <cell>5,946</cell>
                            <cell>Ard.</cell>
                            <cell>68.561</cell>
                            <cell>Sacs</cell>
                            <cell>83,622</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>N.B.—Cette liste est relevée des Registres de l’ “Alexandria General Produce
                        Association”; nous la publions afin qu’on puisse la comparer avec les
                        arrivages du mois de juillet de cette année.</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
