<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
    <editor><!-- Hank Thompson --></editor>
    <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
   </titleStmt>
   <editionStmt>
    <edition>
     <date when="2016-10-15"><!-- October 15, 2016 --></date>
    </edition>
   </editionStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
   </publicationStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <bibl>
     <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
     <date when="1905-10-31"><!-- October 31, 1905 --></date>
    </bibl>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <div type="page" n="1">
    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
    <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
    <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
    <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
   </div>
   <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
   <div type="page" n="3">
    <div type="item"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, OCTOBER  31 1905</head>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>MANIFESTO BY TSAR</head>
      <div type="item"><head>CIVIC LIBERTIES GRANTED</head></div>
      <div type="item"><head>M. WHITE PRIME MINISTER.</head></div>
      <div type="item"><head>REVOLT SMOULDERING.</head></div>
      <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 30.</dateline>
       <p>There are one or two indications that the strike is weakening on account of lack of funds, and the general conditions of scarcity which affect all classes.
       A manifesto was issued by the Tsar to-night appointing M. Witte Prime Minister, with powers to co-ordinate and unify the different branches of the administration. It also grants civic liberties to the people and extends the legislative powers of the National Assembly, besides enlarging the franchise.
       It is rumoured that the crews of four ships of the Black Sea Squadron have mutinied, and that Admirals Bir[   ] and Tchuknin have been murdered.
       It is also rumoured that General Trepoff has been assassinated.	(Reuter)</p></div>
       <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>The Tsar has promulgated a manifesto in which he says that in presence of agitations threatening the integrity and the unity of the empire, he has resolved to unify the action of the superior Government, and he has granted the Duma to the empire on the electoral principle, with the privilege of the civic liberty of conscience, speech, meeting, and association, and with participation of all classes in the elections to the Duma and surveillance over all the acts of the authorities. (Havas)
         </p></div><div type="item"><dateline>Riga, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>Repeated encounters have taken place between the populace and the Cossacks. There are many wounded.	(Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><dateline>Reval, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>There has been much bloodshed here. The troops fired two volleys, killing 45 and wounding 90.	(Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><dateline>Odessa, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>Outwardly the town is becoming quieter, but the revolt is still smouldering. Yesterday’s fighting led to serious carnage, followed by unbridled repressive measures on the part of the Cossacks.	(Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><dateline>Warsaw, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>The city is still very disturbed. (Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>The situation is becoming worse in Warsaw, Lodz, Riga, Rostow, Odessa, and Tiflis. (H.)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>THE POWERS AND THE PORTE.</head>
       <head>JOINT AUDIENCE IMPOSSIBLE.</head>
       <head>Constantinople, October 30.</head>
        <p>The Porte has intimated to the Ambassadors that a joint audience is impossible, being without precedent.	(Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>THE MULLAH GIVING TROUBLE.</head>
       <dateline>Rome, October 30.</dateline>
        <p>It is reported that the Mullah has attacked a tribe on the Italian coast and looted all their cattle. This is probably the reason for the despatch of the Fox and Proserpine. (Reuter)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>JAPANESE RICE CROP.</head>
       <dateline>Tokio. October 30.</dateline>
        <p>It is believed that the Government will abrogate the import maty on rice owing to the serious shortage in the crop. Measures for relieving the consequent distress are being considered.	(Reuter</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>FRENCH CHAMBER.</head>
       <dateline>Paris, October 31</dateline>
        <p>The Chamber of Deputies has voted the amnesty.	(Havas)</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Alston aerated waters
       Ouni-finteecl Distilled.
       \	|	CAIRO:
       ALEXANDRIA :	Pppo*it* Ilia Traavaji Co. Work*.
       7. Euo de lft Poete.	j gkiril g^] Kasr-cUSU.
       BEUK AND DO’SPILSfcEB Btfci*
       FEAB8 NO HON,EST COMPETITION FOB QUALITY
       N.B. —Inferior Brands now being offered U Managers of eertain good circles. Beware of evilly disposed competition running down title very
       SUPERIOR BRAND OF BEER.
       CAKLTON HOTEL.
       MLKILEY (near Alexandria.) BAMLEH’S FASHION ABLE HOTEL.
       PATRON18ID BY TH1 MUT*. ran PfilM Oni p.T.« a any. VhdUm tnm  AND *It# aHafet at aMMiatwr stattea. tmm*m	o, AOUILINA. FwW"-</p></div></div>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
      <div type="item"><p>School of Medicine. The post of demonstrator of anatomy at the Cairo School of Medicine has become vacant.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Stray Dogs.—Stray and ownerless dogs found in the Boulac quarter of Cairo during the night of Wednesday will be poisoned by the police.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Cairo Fire Brigade—Three fine English horses for the stables of the Cairo Fire Brigade arrived from England yesterday by the S.S. Scottish Prince.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Alexandria Horticultural Society.—The committee of the society have postponed the Chrysanthemum Show, to be held at San Stefano, until November 4 and 5, owing to the flowers being late.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>New British Club. — We are asked to remind our readers that applications for membership in the new British Club to be formed at Alexandria must be handed in not later than to-morrow, according to the terms of the circular issued.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Alexandria’s Fortification Park.—The plans for the new gardens outside the fortifications by the Rosetta Gate having arrived from France, the question of commencing the work will shortly be placed before the Commission.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Sudan Officials Salaries.—This month’s issue of the  Sudan Gazette” contains the text of the Official Salaries Ordinance, an ordinance for regulating the taking in execution of the salaries and pay of Government officials</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>The Chatham Explosion.—On a seismograph at Simla (India) presented to the Meteorological Department by Professor Or-mori, the Japanese earthquake expert, the shock caused by the blowing up of the steamer Chatham in the Suez Canal was recorded.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>The New Quay Pier.- The question of granting a concession for a new pier on the quay will be shortly taken up again by the Alexandria Municipality. It was discussed last year by a committee of the Alexandria Municipal Commission, but no conclusion was arrived at.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Orwat el Woska.—A new school was opened at Mex last week in the presence of H.E. the Governor of Alexandria and other notables. The new school was built by and endowed by Haji Mansour El Rulei, and by him handed over to the above-mentioned benevolent society.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>A Destructor Wanted.—Constant complaints are being made to the Alexandria Municipality in regard to the depositing of the city’s refuse at Gebel, Gileh iu the Mohar-rem Bey quarter. We understand that the Alexandria Municipality is powerless to do anything until a destructor is obtained.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Zagaziq Consular AGENCY.- It will be with pleasure that the British community will learn of the probable nomination of Mr. George Diacono to the post of H.M.’s Consular Agent at Zagazig. left vacant by the death of Mr. Felice. Mr. Diacono is the manager of the National Bank of Egypt at Zagazig, where he is held in great esteem. The choice could not have been better placed, and we congratulate Mr. Diacono on his new appointment.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><p>Butcher Murdered in Cairo.—An agent of the secret police recently informed the Court of Saida Zaynab, Cairo, that he had discovered evidence of a murder at the Abattoir. The mamour of the prison went to the place accompanied by the detective. There they found in the cellar of the slaughter-house the body of a batcher named Abd-el-Al El Nawawi, with a knife thrust in the left leg. After a cross-examination the murderer was identified as Omar Farghal, a butcher of Cairo. Omar denied the crime,but some other batchers who knew him and his victim reported that the two men were on bad terms, and that they had quarrelled with each other not long before the murder. The strange feature of the case is that the respective fathers of the murdered man and his murderer had been making minute and concerted arrangements for the concealment of the dead body.</p></div></div>
      <div type="item"><head>VISITORS LIST.</head>
       <head>WINDSOR HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
       <p>Major and Mrs. Rotheram, Mr. and Mrs. Tothill, Mr. and Mrs. Hague, Mr. and Mrs. Joromides, Lt Grill, Rev. Fleming, Miss Fleming, Mr. and Mrs. Rosolato Bey, Mr. Coidan, Baron de Cheder, Mr. Randoi, Mr. G. Otto, Mr. J. Moriee, Mr. Cumming, Mr. M. Fresco, Mr. Scassy, Mr. Colling, Dr. Gotslich, Dr. Morrogh, Mr. Nicoly, Mr. G. Rossi, Mr. Char-ton, Mr. J. Sargeant, Mr. and Mrs. Samarina, Mr. Betecsh, Baron de Steiger, Mr. Peacock and family, Mr. Maule, Mr. and Mrs. Rose dimos, Mr. Casantiny. Mr. Mathaw, Mr. Hark-ness, Mr. Cable, Mr. E. Kerr, Mr. Sebton, Mr. Sheldrick, Mr. J. Kidis, Mr. de la Vigne, Mr. Osborne Sheppard, Mr. Sotaly, Mr. V. Sevaoly, Mr J. 8kylark, Mr. Papapan, Dr. Msgaraky, Mrs Magaraky, Mr. Perez, Capt.Waterloo, Mr. Wilson, Mrs. Lewellin, Mr. Salomone, Mr. Da-han. Mr. Smith, Mr. Chinn, Mr. Orovetz, Mr. Gratner, Mr. Wood, Mr. and Mrs. Page, Miss MoCaul, Dr. Monte da Santos, Mr. Batson.</p></div></div>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>THE AGRICULTURAL SHOW.</head>
      <head>NOT TO BE HELD.</head>
      <p>An official notice has been issued to the effect that the annual Show of the Khedivial Agricultural Society will not be held next year. No reason for this step is given in this intimation, and the news has caused considerable annoyance among many intending exhibitors. The Show is usually held in February, and many firms have already been put to considerable expense in arranging for exhibits, many of which were fixed to leave England in November.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
       <p>A meeting of the Council of Ministers was held on Sunday afternoon, his Highness the Khedive presiding, when the following decrees were approved: —
        (I) The appointment of Ibrahim Mekih Bey, Moudir of Galionbieh, to be Moodir of Gairgeh; Mastapha Maher Bey, Moudir of Assouan, to be Moudir of Galioubieh; Hassan Hassib B y, Sob Governor of the Suez Canal, to be Moudir of Assouan; Khalil Riad Bey, secretary to the Adviser to the Ministry of the Interior, to be Sub-Governor of the Sues Canal.
        (3)	The appointment of Abdel Hakim Askar Effendi to be 3rd class judge of the Cairo Tribunal ; of Mohamed Abdel Kadi el Guindy to be 4th dans judge of the Assiout Tribunal; of Ahmed Zeki Abou el Seond Effendi to be 5th class judge of the Tantah Tribunal.
        (3)	A decree modifying the annual taxes on fishing '‘roksas” on Lake Menzaleh.
        (4)	A decree authorising the construction of two houses for the use of the Irrigation Service It Nag Hamidi, Keueh province, and Birket el Sab, Menoofieh province.
        (5)	A decree authorising the construction of a “sayalah” at Gaeziret el Maabda el Bahria, Abnoub markaz, Assiout province.
        (6)	A decree authorising the construction of the canal El Kokm in the Manfalout markaz, Assiout province.
        (7)	A decree authorising the lengthening of the “masraf ’ of Deirout Um Nakhla, Maliawi markaz, Assiout province.
        (8)	A decree authorising new cemeteries for the Mohamedans of the esbets of Abdallah Bey el Mihi, in the Kalioubieh province, and of Zedan el Salahib and Abon Khalil, in the village of El Kamoul, Gharbieh province.
        (9)	A decree approving the formation and statutes of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Company.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>THE ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND ALLOTMENT CO.</head>
       <p>The Khedivial decree authorising the formation of the above company was signed by H.H. the Khedive on Sunday at the Council of Ministers, and it will appear in to morrow’s “Journal Officiel.” Yesterday, a quarter of the entire capital, as required by law, was deposited at the Anglo-Egyptian Bank in Cairo, and the public subscription will take place on Thursday and Friday at that bank. As most of the capital has been already privately subscribed, only 43,000 shares are offered to the public. The company, whose success seems already assured, is to be congratulated on having secured as Chairman of the board, Sir William Willcocks, who has entered into an agreement to hold that post for not less than five years.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>SUDAN GOVERNMENT.</head>
       <head>The following extracts are taken from the ‘Sudan Gazette” :—</head>
        <p>El Kaimakam D. K. E. Hall Bey, Assistant Civil Secretary, is re-transferred to the Army, to date 25-9-05.
        El Kaimakam Viscount W. J. H. Frankfort de Montmorency Bey, Senior Inspector, Dongola Province, is re-transferred to the Army, to date 9-9-05.
        El Bimbashi Huntley Walsh, transferred to the Sudan Government, is appointed Junior Inspector, Bahr-el-Ghazal Provinoe, to date 25-8-05.
        The following gentlemen have been appointed Deputy Inspectors in Agriculture and Lands Department, to date 19-9-05:—Mr. W. A. Davie, Mr. H. Burkitt.
        The following gentlemen have been appointed Deputy Inspectors, to date 19 9 05 :—Mr. H. A. MacMichael, Mr. F. P. Osborne, Mr. C. A Willis, Mr. M. S. MacDonnell, Mr. W. R. G. Bond, Mr. J. G. Matthew, Mr. W. H. B. Evans, Mr. O. Bentley.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
       <p>H.H. the Khedive has been most graciously pleased to approve of the promotions of Local Miralai Hamid By Mukhtar, Recruiting Department, and El Kaimakam Radwan Bey Shukri, commanding 8th Battalion, to the rank of Miralai, and of El Bimbashi Mohamed Effendi Ramzi, Department of Stores, to the tank of Kaimakam.
        Captain E. N. Broadbent, King’s Own Scottish Borderers, has arrived in Egypt from England and has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank of Bimbashi. He has been posted to the 16th Battalion.
        El Kaimakam C. J. Hawker Bey, commanding the Camel Corps, has been transferred to the Sudan Government.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
       <p>The Ellerman S.S. Britannia sailed from Liverpool last Friday for Gibraltar, Malta, and Alexandria, with general cargo and passengers.</p></div></div>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>NEW LINE TO ALEXANDRIA,</head>
      <head>FRENCH COMPANY’S PLANS.</head>
      <p>The Compagnie de Navigation Mixte (Com-pagnie Tonaohe) intend starting a new line of steamers from Marseilles to Alexandria by way of Malta, Jerbah, and Tripoli. The service will be monthly to begin with and steamers will be put on at shorter intervals as the trade develops. The steamers on their return voyage will proceed direct from Alexandria to Marseilles.
       The Compagnie de Navigation Mixte possesses fourteen steamers and has a number of services between Marseilles and various ports in Algeria, Tonis, Morocco, Tripoli, and Spain. The company believe that a profitable trade can be developed between Tripoli and Egypt. A large number of cattle will be imported into Egypt from Tripoli, as well as a special kind of wood which is grown expensively in the neighbourhood of Benghazi and is of great use for dying purposes. Esparto grass, camels, etc., will also be imported thence, and besides a kind of calico which is largely manufactured at Jerbah and Tripoli.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>CUNARD LINE AND EGYPT.</head>
       <p>The Cunard Company has made an arrangement for a joint service with the Peninsular and Oriental Steamship Company and the Orient Steamship Company by which passengers via England or the Mediterranean may be hooked through to or from Egypt.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>HAMBURG-AMERIKA LINE.</head>
       <p>We mentioned a short time back that the Hamburg-Amerika Line had purchased from the Union Steam Navigation Co. the steamer Scof, of 6,000 tons register, which has been re-christened  Oceana, for their new quick Mediterranean service between Naples and Alexandria. The company had intended to inaugurate this new service on the 10th January, but as the necessary alterations to the Ocean will not be completed in time, the inauguration will in all probability not take place until February at the earliest.
        Mr. Dino E. Monari has arrived in Cairo and opened the new offices of the Hamburg-America Line, which are situated in the Continental Hotel buildings. Mr. Stangen, the well-known tourist agent of Berlin, arrives in the course of a few days to arrange for the next season’s Nile services in connection with the company.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>THE LOSS OF THE BEHARA.</head>
       <head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
       <head>Port Said, Sunday.</head>
        <p>I have to-day had a most interesting talk with one of the gentlemen who were on board the ill-fated Behara when she struck a rock close to Aquada on the Burmese coast some few weeks ago. The vessel is one of the very fast Indian and Burmese mailboats, and owing to rainy, misty weather and abnormal currents, drove on to the reefs, with which, it would appear, this coast is strewn. The vessel struck at 10 a.m. and the crew, without the loss of a single life or even the injury of a man, had by nightfall taken ashore, at great risk, the entire 1,352 passengers, and had by daylight next day removed everything of value to safety on the island, which was four miles away.
        The remains of this 'fine ship are, I am told, still visible above water though fast disap pearing.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>RAILWAY ADMINISTRATION.</head>
       <p>Several of our contemporaries have published articles announcing increases in the salaries of some of the officials of the Railway Administration , and also mentioning others who are understood to be about to retire on pension or indemnity. We are, however, in a position to state that the information published is inaccurate. These matters are still in the hands of the Board and have not yet been decided. That increases of salary will be granted several officials is an undoubted fact, and it may also be taken for granted that some of the officials named by our contemporaries will retire on pension or receive substantial indemnities, but we await an officinal announcement before stating names or sums.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>TANTAH MUNICIPALITY.</head>
       <p>The Syrians residing in Tantah have published in the columns of some of our native contemporaries the text of a telegraphic petition submitted by them to the Ministry of the Interior seating forth that the Syrians of Tantah, who are 500 in number, all have the right, according to the Khedivial decree,of voting for the eleotion of members of the council, but that at its last sitting the Moudirieh of Tantah enrolled only eighty Syrians as electors, of whom twenty are long since dead. The petitioners begged the Ministry to order the election to be delayed. But it is reported from Tantah that the elections have taken place and that the appointments have already been made.
        In our opinion the aggrieved members of the Syrian community at Tantah should have approached the Ministry of the Interior in time. They might have sent a delegation to explain their grievances, which would, we are sure, have been listened to at the Minister,</p></div></div>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>NILE-BED SEA BAILWAY.</head>
      <head>LINKING UP THE LINES.</head>
      <head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
      <dateline>Suskin, October 25.</dateline>
       <p>After the linking of the last rails of the Suakin-Atbara line at both railheads on the 14th inst., a semi-official ceremony took place on the spot, over which Kaim. Midwinter Bey, R.E., and Kaim. Longfield Bey presided. The Sudanese played their tom toms and danced their usual war dance, the day being considered a holiday for them. A large signboard was erected on a hill opposite the point where the lines from Suakin and the Atbara met, bearing the inscription :
       Sudan Government Railways Nile and Red Pea Line
       Director Miralai Macaulay Bey.
       and the first train then passed over the newly complet'd line. Twenty-five material trains are ordered to leave for the Abou-Hamed-Krema line, from which material was loaned to make up the Nile-Red Sea line from the Nile end.
       The Sudan Government S.S Makhbir, which was docked and repaired at Suez, has arrived at Port Sudan, and will be used as a sort of floating headquarters for the resident engineer and director of works. A temporary wooden pier is being erected from the shore to the ship to obviate the necessity of frequent visits by boat.
       Among the resent arrivals here by the Khedivial Mail S.S. Dakahlieh, whioh came in on the 21st inst., are Dr. Crispin, medical inspector, and Sagh. Ali Effendi Ahmed, deputy inspector to Suakin Moudirieh. Mr. Miohallani, district traffic manager at Snakin, his left for a ten days’ change of air at Atbara.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>MARRIAGE OF CAPTAIN C. S. ROME.</head>
       <p>The marriage was solemnised at St. Margaret’s Church, Westminster, on Tuesday in last week, of Captain Claude Stuart Rome, 11th Hussars, attached to the Egyptian Army, son of Mr. Thomas Rome, and Miss Grace Londeune Blyth, second daughter of Sir James Blyth, who is one of our greatest authorities on agriculture, and who for his services has been honored, among others, by the Khedive. The officiating clergy were Bishop Welldon, Canon Hensley Henson, Canon Page Roberts, and the Rev. E. D. Shaw. The bride, who was given away by her father, was attended by twelve bridesmaids, and Captain Leslie Rome, a brother-officer and cousin of the bridegroom, was best man.
        After the ceremony a reception was held at 33, Portland Place, W., at which there was a very large gathering, among those invited being the Countess of Donoughmore, Lady Norah Hely-Hutchinson, Lord and Lady O’Brien, Sir Squire and Lady Banoroft, Lord Gle-nesk, Sir Harry and Lady Johnstone, Viscount and Viscountess Wolseley, Sir Mile and Lady Fenton, Sir Alexander and Lady Henderson, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Rome, the Earl and countess of Aberdeen, Sir Walter Gilbey, the Earl and Countess of Warwick, the Lord Chancellor and the Countess of Halsbury, Sir Thomas Lipton, the Countess of Egmont, Mr. and Mrs. George Alexander, the officers of the 11th Hassars, and many others. Among the many handsome presents was one from the late Sir Henry Irving, who sent the bride a ruby brooch.
        The Queen sent the bride a portrait of herself in foil Coronation robes, with the request that Sir James Blyth would hand it to his daughter on the morning of her wedding-day with the Queen’s very best wishes.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>THE ZEIDIEH TWELVE VIRTUES.</head>
       <p>Our Ottoman contemporary “Turk” states that, in 1891, when the Yemen province was in revolt, Imam El-Mansour Billah died leaving, at Host village, which he occupied, fifteen thousand men-at-arms. Imam El-Mansour Billah was the father of the Imam Yahia, and in his will he desired that his son should succeed him in the Imamet. According to the Zuidi sect, the Imam (Caliph) must possess the following twelve peculiar qualifications :— He must be a descendant of Ali and Fatimah (daughter of the Prophet) ; must be learned ; diligent; religious; handsome and physically sound ; generous; zealous; brave; honest and must go to war in person and not prefer peace to war when the latter is necessary, taking the law as his guide ; he must also be economical in his home life, and his people must have full confidence in him and must agree to acknowledge him as their Caliph.
        The followers of Imam El Mansonr were doubtful whether his son Yahia possessed all these qualifications. However, complying with his father’s will, they acknowledged him as their Imam. The Zeidieh confess no Caliph except their own because they say, no other Imam can possess the twelve qualifications of the Imamet.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
       <head>(From our Correspondent).</head>
       <head>Port Said, Monday.</head>
        <p>Last night a concert was given by the orchestra of H.M.S. Suffolk at the Eastern Exchange. A large crowd occupied over 800 seats, and many of the audience had to remain standing. The concert was one of the best ever given at Port Said, and the band, under the direction of Bandmaster R. Lamari, are to ba congratulated on their evening’s performance
        H.M.S Suffolk left this morning for Malta.
        H.M.S. Cambrian arrived here for station orders at 5.30 this evening and moored in Navy Bay.</p></div></div>
     <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>“DOING” EGYPT ON SKATES.</head>
      <head>ROUND-THE-WORLD TOUR</head>
      <p>A visitor arrived at Alexandria yesterday from Europe, who intends “doing” Egypt and the Sudan in a highly original manner, his means of locomotion bring nothing more nor less than a pair of road skates-—or, when the roads are rough, bis own sturdy legs. This enterprising traveler is Mr. A. W- Crawford, native of St. John, New Brunawick. He started a few months ago from Rouen and has crossed France, Spain, Algeria and Tonis. Tripoli is a closed country and everyone who desires to traverse it with security has to obtain a special permit from the Sublime Porte. Such a permit is almost impossible to procure at the present time and moreover necessitates a journey to Constantinople, so Mr. Crawford had to give up the idea of making his way to Egypt by land, and came on here by way of Malta. He is equipped with a pair of Ritter road skates on the acme pattern and intends travelling by the help of these appliances to Cairo and thence up the Nile valley to Khartoum. From Khartoum he will make his way to Abyssinia and on to Adan and via Persia, Afghanistan and India round the world.
       At the first blush the idea of travelling from Alexandria, to the Sedan . and Abyssinia on road skates strikes one as being a somewhat eccentric method of .locomotion. and when one thinks, of the vast tracks of desert between here and Abyssinia the adventurous spirit that will essay a journey through this part of Africa in the fashion here related is likely to be more pitied, than commended. But Crawford is, not actuated by the hope of winning a wager or of gaining notoriety. He merely wishes to see if the thing can be done without a penny in his pocket, only depending on the assistance and encouragement of those who appreciate pluck and endurance. Mr.Crawford, who has already covered 5,000 kilometres on foot and on wheel, looks wonderfully fit considering the hardships inseparable from an undertaking of such magnitude.
       Mr. Crawford left Rouen on May 1 last and is due at Boston in April, 1907. He is a good specimen of a young Canadian and is the son of the late Dr. Crawford, of Andover, New Brunswick.</p></div>
      <div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
       <div type="item"><p>Prince Mohamed Ibrahim arrived at the Carlton Hotel, London, last week from Paris.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Prince Leopold of Battenberg has been in much better health of late, though he is still lame. He starts on the 18th of next month for Egypt, where it is hoped that another winter may restore him.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Count Sala, who has become well known in London, and is a great social favorite^ is leaving the French Embassy for Cairo, .where he has been given a good post.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Mr. H.S. Smiley, who has been staying at Claridge’s Hotel for a few weeks, has started for Cairo, whence he will proceed ,for some big game shooting through Abyssinia.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Major H. C. French, Royal Army Medical Corps, has retired from the Army.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Major W.D. Erskine,, Royal Army Medical Corps, has been granted sick leave until February 28. He left for England yesterday via Port Said,where he embarked on the P. and O. S.S. India.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>Dr. and Mrs. Wakeling are returning by the P.AND O. Egypt and will arrive at Mena House In a day or two.</p></div>
       <div type="item"><p>The estate is valued at £188,050, with net personalty of £107,654, of Mr. Samuel Gurney Sheppard, of Leggatta, North Mimms, senior partner in the firm of Sheppards, Petty, and Co., 57, Old Broad-street, and the Stock Exchange, a director of the London and Lancashire Life Assurance Company, for many years chairman of Dr. Bernardo’s Homes, and well known in Egypt owing to his connection with the Aboukir Company, who died on October 8, in his seventy-seventh year. Having given largely to charitable institutions in his lifetime he leaves nothing to them under his will, but he earnestly hopes that his reridnaty legatees will deal liberally with the same charities in respect of any written or verbal promise made by him. He gave £50 to each clerk and porter who has been in the employment of his firm for 10 years, and £25 each for those of five years’ service; and to each domestic servant of five years service £10.</p></div></div>
      <div type="item"><head>OBITUARY.</head>
       <head>M. THEODORE IVANOFF.</head>
       <p>We regret to announce the death at Alexandria of M. Theodore Ivanoff, formerly agent of the Russian Navigation and Commercial Co., which occurred at midnight yesterday. The deceased occupied this post for 35 years and was then promoted to the rank of principal agent of the same company [    ] transferred to Constantinople retiring on account of ill health after he had rendered very valuable services to the company.</p></div></div></div>
    </div>
    <cb n="1"/>
    <cb n="2"/>
    <cb n="3"/>
    <cb n="4"/>
    <cb n="5"/>
    <cb n="6"/>
   </div>
   <div type="page" n="4">
    <cb n="1"/>
    <cb n="2"/>
    <cb n="3"/>
    <cb n="4"/>
    <cb n="5"/>
    <cb n="6"/>
   </div>
   <div type="page" n="5">
    <cb n="1"/>
    <cb n="2"/>
    <cb n="3"/>
    <cb n="4"/>
    <cb n="5"/>
    <cb n="6"/>
   </div>
   <div type="page" n="6">
    <cb n="1"/>
    <cb n="2"/>
    <cb n="3"/>
    <cb n="4"/>
    <cb n="5"/>
    <cb n="6"/>
   </div>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
