<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-08"> February 8, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, FEBRUARY 8, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, FEBRUARY 8, 1905.
<div type="item">
<head>SITUATION IN RUSSIA</head>
<head>STRIKE MOVEMENT SPREADING</head>
<head>ANOTHER ADDRESS TO TSAR</head>
<p>St Petersburg, February 7,
A remarkable feature of the situation in 
Russia is the constant spread of the strike
movement in all directions.  
Warsaw and Lodz are generally quieter, 
though there are occasional disturbances.
Work is still suspended.
The agitation is increasing at Tiflis and 
Batum.  In the former town, there have been
sanguinary conflicts in the streets between the
police and cossacks and the revolutionary mobs.
The strike is spreading on the Trans-caucasion
railway.  A troop train proceeding to 
Batum was derailed, the line being cut.  (R.)</p>
 <p>St Petersburg, February 7,
 The assembly of Nobles for the province of 
 st. Petersburg have adopted by 158 votes
 against 20 an address to the Tsar urging him to 
 summon elected representatives of the nation  (Reuter.)</p>  
    <p> Tiflis, February 7,
    Disorders have taken place in consequence of the strike.
    Many people were injured. (R.)</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>KING GEORGE'S YACHT FIRED ON</head>
<head>ANOTHER RUSSIAN BLUNDER.</head>
<p>Paris, February 7.
A fact hitherto undisclosed by the North
Sea Commission is being discussed in official
circles here.  It appears that the yacht of the
King of Greece, which was proceeding from
Denmark to france at the time of the dogger
Bank incident, was fired upon by the russian fleet.  
His Majesty told the story in paris, adding, "if they
took by yacht for a torpedo boat, how much easier 
it must have been to have made a mistake with 
the trawlers (R.)</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>ADMIRAL TOGO.</head>
<head>REJOINING HIS FLEET.</head>
<p>Tokio, February 7,
Admiral Togo has left m older to rejoin the
fleet.</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>GRAND DUKES FAVOR PEACE. </head>
<p>Berlin, February 7,
The Berliner Tagebiatt say that at a meeting
of the grand dukes a decision of peace was taken</p>
</div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE FINNISH OUTRAGE</head>
<p>Helmngfors, February 7,
Mr. Johnsons associate was a former student
at the university here.  He has been lately 
living in sweden. (Reuter.)</p>
</div>
   <div type="item">
   <head>NEW RUSSIAN CONSUL-GENERAL FOR CAIRO</head>
   <p>St. Petersburg February 7.
   M. Maximoff, the Russian Consul-general 
   at cairo, has been appointed Minister at Cettinge.
   M. Smirnoff, Secretary to the Legation
   at athens, succeeds M. Maximoff</p> </div>
   <div type="item">  
   <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
    <p>The cairo salon opens friday, 17th instant</p>
    <p> A heavy gale is blowing in cairo today, 
     and the cold is intense.</p>
    <p>Cercle Mohamed Aly.- The club's annual ball 
    will take place on the 25th inst.</p>
    <p>The brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G.P.O,
    Alexandria at 9:30 p.m. today.</p>   
    <p>Concert- Mme. Arctowski will give a concert
    at the savoy hotel next friday at 5 p.m.</p>
    <p> The Plague- Yesterdays plague bulletin 
    recorded the recovery of the two patients at the suez.</p>  
    <p>Fire- The damage done by the recent fire
    in the wood sheds in the Boulac-road, Cairo, 
    amounts to L.E. 71</p>   
    <p>Horse Show- The Khedivial sporting
    clubs anual horse show will take place at 
    Ghezireh on saturday, 18th inst., under the
    patronage of the khedive</p> 
    <p>The cyprus journal- for January contains 
    intersting articles on the teeth of 
    horses- a guide to their age, Cyprus 
    Raisins, The fawagusta port, which is now
    open, the english school at nicosia, and other
    useful information</p>   
    <p>Wakfs Administration.- The revenue of the 
    administration from the 1st january to the end
    of november, 1904, amounted to L.E. 242,783, 
    as against L.E. 208,383 in 1903, when the 
    expenditure amounted to L.E. 186,147, as 
    against L.E. 178,669 in 1903.</p>  
    <p>Suez canal- on the 4th and 5th inst. 30 
    vessels passed through the canal, 13 of which
    were british, 1 american, 5 french, 1 turkish,
    1 dutch, 5 german, 1 norwegian, 2 greek.  The 
    receipts for the two days were 826,885.61 
    making the total from 1st inst. 1,955,986.12</p> 
    <p>The Plagues of egypt- american hournalists 
        have a genious for neway scareheads.
    The report of a sermon on the plagues of
    egypt recently figured in a Yankee newspaper
    under enormous headlines: Horrible affair in 
    Egypt- bones and brains everywhere- 
    pharaoh interviewed, and so on.</p>  
    <p> THe Germania lodge is giving a ball in
    Monetrratos hall on satruday, 18th inst.
    the net proceeds of which will go to purchase
    warm winter clothing for indigent children of 
    all nationalities.  The distribution of the 
    wearing apparel will take place at 4 p.m. on 
    Sunday, March 3, in the lodge rooms, 2, Maromte Church street.</p>
    <p>Egyptian mining- a very useful handbook
    to egyptian and sudan mining has just been issued.
    It contains a sketch map of the mining concessions
    in egypt and the sudan copies of a sudan government
    prospecting license and of an egyptian mining lease, 
    and very full details of the various mining companies.
    It is issued by Messrs. Birch and Co., stock and share
    brokers, St angel court, throgmorton street, london, E.C.</p>
    <p> English Soap in Egypt- The well known
    brand of sunlight soap is every day becoming
    more and more popular in egypt, and last year
    was a record one for Messrs. Lever brothers
    great product.  Their representative, Mr. O. C.
    Hebb, arrived at Alexandria yesterday from
    Syria and is proceeding to cairo and thence
    to khartoum.  Mr. Hebb will be staying at the
    grand continental hotel, cairo, in a few days
    time, where he will be very pleased to recieve
    any orders</p>
    <p>The International Employes Society, of 
    alexandria, seems to be in a very fair way, to 
    judge by a circualr which has just been sent out.
    Owing to the improvement in the financial 
    condition of the society, a number of advantages
    have been added to those already existing, 
    among them the free supply of medicine
    to members.  Certain other provisions have 
    been made in the event of a members death
    or his burial and the relief of his family
    should they be necessitous.  a registry office is 
    open in connection with the society, and 
    female members are now admitted.  The society
    has a large sphere of usefulness.</p>
   </div>
       <div type="item">  
<head>DEVELOPMENT OF EGYPT</head>
<head>STEAM TRAWLING SUCCESSFUL</head>
<head>THE SPONGE FISHERIES</head>
<p>The nile cold storage company is experimenting
in a new direction.  A steam trawler hired by the
company for six months, with option of purchase
at the expiry of the period should the results
obtained justify the course, has commenced 
operations off port said, and has met with 
decided success in her first two ventures.
Good takes of merlan, soles, skate, loup-de-mer,
and John dory are reported with a fair number of red 
mullet of better quality and far larger size than
those usually seen in Egyptian restaurants and hotels.
The latter, taken as a rule within a few miles of the 
coast, are almost all immature fish weighing as a rule
from 1.5 to 2 ounes, but the trawler has already
taken a few half pounders, with a large
proportion of six ounce fish.
It is of, course, too early yet to anticipate
large takes of excellent soles and transcendant 
red mullet finding their way to cairo
and alexandria, to the delight of dinners out.
Nothing, or next to nothing is known of the 
feeding grounds and general habits and 
distribution of the numerous specis of fish 
that occur in Egyptian waters, except within
a belt not exceeding a dozen miles in distance
from the coast.  The fisherman of our 
coast line from alexandria to port said rarely
venture further, but a steam trawler can
work in the waters for thirty miles without any
risk of finding her return impeded by adverse winds.
Among the recent catches of the companys trawler- 
which by the way is an up to date
boat manned by a british crew and commanded
by capt Micholson on fleetwood, who is known
as the pioneer of steam trawling in england-
are a number of large trukish sponges of large
size and fine quality.
A sponge fishery has been for some time
established at marsa Matrouh, but the frequent 
roughness of the sea outside the small and
obstructed harbour has frequently proved a 
great hindrance to diving.  The discovery of
sponges of a good quality within 30 miles of 
port said is valuable in itself, and there is
every reason to suppose that the development 
of the egyptian fisheries will be of great 
economic importance to the country.  The 
coast fishermen, with inadequate appliances
frequently succeed in making good takes of 
fish, and the steam trawler and her two sisters
shortly arriving should be far more fortunate.  </p>
       </div>
           <div type="item">          
 <head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT</head>     
<p>The directors of the corporation of western 
egypt, limited, who have been staying at the 
savoy hotel for the last fortnight, have now
left cairo for england via naples.  The party 
included Messrs. the Hou. Alexander O.
Murray, master of eubank, J.P., D.L., M.P., 
chairman of the corporation, Charles E.H.
Hobhouse, J.P., M.P., the Hon. W. Twilough
O'brien, William Heaton Armstrong, and W. 
Chas Scales.  The object of their visit was to
discuss the companys policy wit the local 
board and railway and mining engineers, and
to thoroughly investigate the companys interests
on the spot.  We understand that Mr. Waller, 
of the well known firm of Messrs.
Kincard, waller, maville, and dawson, the 
corporations consulting engineers, has now
completed his report on the section of the
railway which the corporation are building to
connect the Oasis of Kharga with the egyptian
governmetn ranway at farshut, a distance of 118 miles.
It was feared taht the first ten miles of this 
section would be very expensive, but Mr. 
Waller now reports that by taking the line
among a certain Wadt the plateau can be reached 
without any extra expense.
It is evident that the directors are actively
attending to the business in hand, and we
understand that they have expressed themselves 
as being much impressed with the corporations 
various interests.  Taking into consideration
the high standing and ability of the directorate, 
the importance of many of the names on the list
of shareholders, and the enormous porenrialites 
of the corporations concessions, which
will be opened up by the new railway, it is
evident that the corporation has before it a brilliant future.
Application has been made to the london 
stock exchange committee to appoint a special
setting day in corporation of western egypt, 
seven shares of $1 each, fully paid, Nos
250,001 to 250,007 and 250,000 shares of 
$1 each, 10s. paid, Nos. 1 to 250,000.</p>
           </div>
               <div type="item">   
 <head>EGYPTIAN POST OFFICE</head>
 <head>INVESTIGATION OF ACCOUNTS</head>   
 <p>Messrs. Hoare and Russell, having been charged
 to audit the accounts of the Egyptian post office
 administration, have drawn up on the subject
 an exhaustive report which has jsut been handed
 in to the ministry of finance.  The auditors
 report that they have found, as the result of 
 their elaborate investigation, that the detailed
 work of the accounts department at the head 
 office is genearlly satisfactory but
 that, good as the sytem is up to a certain point, 
 it lacks completeion and therfore cannot
 be so effective as it otherwise would be.  Many
 of the branch offices were visited, and the auditors 
 declare themselves satisfied with the results
 of their inspections.  The system of returns, so 
 far as they record current transactions, is well 
 adapted to the requirements of the head office.
 They consider that the completion of the system
 on the lines laid down in the detailed report
 is much required and recommend that steps
 should be taken to carry this into effect.</p> 
               </div>
                   <div type="item">                  
 <head>NOTES FROM KHARTOUM</head> 
 <head>THE ROYAL VISIT</head>
 <p>(From our correspondent)
 Khartoum, February 2. 
 T.R.H. the duke and duchess of connaught, 
 with the princesses margaret and patricia
 arrived here this morning, and wer recieved at 
 the railway station by H.E. the governor
 general, accompanied by the principal military
 and official heads of the departments, with full
 military honors.  They have taken up their residence 
 at the palace, over which is flying the 
 royal standard.  In the forenoon H.R.H visited
 the british barracks, and in the afternoon 
 was present at the garden party in the Palace.
 Tomorrow the duke of connaught will again
 visit the british barracks and in the 
 afternoon be present at the opening of 
 the agricultural show</p>   
                   </div>
       <div type="item">
<head>BUILDING OF ANGLICAN CHURCH</head> 
<p>A meeting of residents interested in the Khartoum
Anglican church services and
building fund, was held on tuesday in the 
temporary church room in the palace, H.E. 
the governor general presiding.  After the 
usual formal proceedings, it was decided to 
proceed forth with the building of a church
sufficiently large to accommodate for
the present 300 persons and so adapted that it can
be enlarged at any future time without 
interfering with the original design of the construction.  
In deference to a wish expressed by H.R.H. princess henry
the building will be a replica of the mausoleum at frogmore.
Mr. Richmond, of cairo has volunteered to submit the 
necessary drawings.
In announcing this decision, H.E. the 
governor general trusted that further funds
would come in more lavishly than hitherto.
At the same time his excellency was pleased
to continue his kindness in allowing the use
of any portion of the palace or grounds
required for congregataional services, pending
completion of the church.  Conolen stanton and Mr. Hayler
were reelected churc wardens for the ensuing year.</p>   
       </div>
       <div type="item">
<head>LAUNCH OF NEW STEAMER</head>
<p>The Sudan Development and exploration
Company, Ltd., have issued a handy and
tastefully got up guide for the season 1904-5.
The latest addition to the companys fleet, 
the P.W.S. Cairo, has just been launched 
from the companys dockyard at khartoum
north, and left the day before yesterday for
the white nile on her maiden trip.  His
excellency the governor general inspected the
boat and make a short run up river.  He 
expressed his satisfaction with the general
arragnements provided in the boat, and called
her a most magnificent steamer.  She has a
length of 120 feet, 22 foot beam and 2ft 6
draught, 300 indicated H.P., speed 12 miles an
hour.  She possesses a handsome and spacious
saloon, bentilated form the ceiling, over which
is situated the smoke room, four singel state
rooms, six double state rooms with appendices
and promenade fore and amidships.  The cabins,
saloon and smoke room are mosquito proof.  
The owners claim that the style, finish, and 
general furnishings of this boat are equal
to any first class liner, while the cabins
are much larger than is usually found 
in the latter.  It is the first of a new class,
competent to vie with any steamer on the 
nile, lower egypt included, with regard to 
comfort and luxurious traveling.  A special
leasure are the beautiful bathrooms, lavatories
with cold and hot water, spray, etc. It is a
credit to the company and to their local 
manager, Mr. Harold F. Hall, and the staff
under him.  
I must not omit to state that the cairo is
fitted throughout with an acetyl gas plant
of the most modern and approved type.  It is 
to be hoped that this is new venture of the
company will meet with that measure of success
which enterprise, skill and intelligence call for.</p>  
       </div>
       <div type="item">
           <head>THE TOURIST SEASON.</head>
           <p>The Grand Hotel Khartoum is filled with
               visitors at the present time. Among those
               who are staying at this charming hotel are
               Lady Russel and her daughter, Count and
               Couutess Churimsky, Count de Nettauoourt, 
               Count de las Coses, Colonel Saunders, Mr.
               P. 0. Murphy, Mr. H. Viollet, Mr. H. Lake, 
               Mr. T. Atkinsou, Dr. Hooper, Dr. Sassi, Dr.
               Werner, Mr. K. Gurer, Mr. E. Comerup, Mr.
               and Mrs. Finlay, Major and Mrs. D. D. Nicol,
               Mrs. L. Oort, Miss Green, Miss Thomson,
               Miss Cobb, Miss Crewdaou, Miss Lindsay, wt
               Rev. I. and Mrs. Watson, Mr. A. B. de
               Guerevillo. Mrs. W. May, Dr. Beam, Mrs. M
               Stevens, Mr. Bryant, Mr. Ch. Campbell,
               Mr. MoChanliaquet, Copt. H. Fraser, Miss K.
               Caminaky, Mr. Topalian.
               of</p> </div>
       <div type="item">
<head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
 <p>The khedive will probably not return to
 Koubbeh till this evening or tomorrow
 morning.
 His highness is expected to open the
 agricultural societys show at ghezireh on
 monday next</p> </div>
       <div type="item">
           <head>THE SAKHARA INCIDENT</head>
           <p>The report that Mr. Howard Carter is being 
               transferred to Luxor from Cairo is, we believe, 
               untrue. The commission of enquiry has not yet
               given its decision in the matter, but we may
               say that certain facts have been brought before
               its notice which place Mr. Carter's action in a
               very different light.</p> </div>
       <div type="item">
 <head>Grand Hotel Bonnard Alexandria</head>
 <p>8s. Per day, wine included</p> </div>
       <div type="item">
<head>EGYPTIAN GOVERNMENT AND THE RUSSIAN FLEET</head>           
           <p>A correspondent writes: The leading ar-
               ticle in the "Egyptian Gazette" on the position
               of the Egyptian Government in its policy
               towards the Russian fleet was admirably
               oogent in its logic. But viewed in its purely legal
               aspect, this question should be looked at As
               one which concerns Egypt alone and without
               reference to Great Britain. A copy of the Suez
               Canal Convention lies before me. It was signed
               at Constantinople on the 29th October, 1888,
               and ratifications were deposited at Constanti-
               nople on the 22nd December of that year. The
               Convention was made between Great Britain,
               Germany, Austria-Hungary, Spain, France,
               Italy, the Netherlands, Russia, and Turkey.
               "Egypt's political status is," as the Judicial
               Adviser correctly observes, “that of a part of
               the Ottoman Dominions." She has therefore
               no individual power to make treaties save such
               as the firmans of the Sultan of Turkey ex-
               pressly authorise. Those firmans did not
               invest her with power to enter into the Suez Canal
               Convention, which was consequently made
               on her behalf by her Turkish suzerain. It
               follows then that if the Convention was
               binding on Turkey it was binding on
               Egypt. If it was binding on Egypt in
               1888—the date of its signature—it was equally
               binding upon her in 1898, at the time of the
               passage of the Spanish Fleet, and in 1904, at
               the time of the passage of the Russian Fleet
               through the Canal. The Egyptian Government
               held—so the Judicial Adviser informs us—
               that the Convention was not binding upon
               Egypt in 1898. Assuming that view to be
               correct, and nothing having been done by
               Turkey to render the Convention binding in
               the interval between that date and 1904, it
               was not binding upon Egypt in 1904.-
               The fact that the British Government did
               not consider the Convention binding upon
               them in 1898 by reason of a reservation made
               in 1888 with reference to retaining full liberty
               of action regarding the British Occupation of
               Egypt, could in no respect affect Egypt's con-
               tractual obligations in 1898 any more than
               Great Britain’s announcement of her adherence
               to the Convention as recorded in the Anglo-
               French Agreement of April, 1904—to which,
               by the way, Turkey was not a party—can
               affect Egypt’s obligations at the present time.
               It will be seen that, starting from the same
               premises as the Judicial Adviser, I arrive at a
               different conclusion. The difficulty of the
               Judicial Adviser was from the first obvious,
               and, I venture to think, insurmountable,
               namely, the divergence between the technical
               and the actual position—the status de jur and
               that de facto—of Egypt He may well be
               pardoned for having tailed to reconcile the
               irreconcilable.</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NATIVE BAR</head>                   
                    <p>The Native Bar has recently gained a victory 
                        over the Ministry of Justice and, although it
                        is only a trifling matter, the successful issue 
                        has given great satisfaction, as the native 
                        barristers are by no means content with the 
                        persistent efforts of the Ministry to rule 
                        over them “par conseil de discipline." Recently
                        a circular was issued to the barristers' clerks
                        requiring them to furnish to the Court of
                        Appeal a certificate of good conduct and a
                        photograph. This arbitrary interference natur-
                        ally called forth a number of protests, and a
                        meeting of the clerks was held, when it was 
                        agreed that they should strike if the circular
                        was put into force. The vote of this meeting 
                        was unanimous and the decision was com-
                        municated to Judge Bond, Vice-President of 
                        the Native Court of Appeal, by the members 
                        of the Bar, who stated that their clerks one 
                        and all refused to submit to any such con-
                        ditions whatsoever. The result was that the 
                        obnoxious circular was withdrawn.</p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY</head>
                    <p>Councillor Alderson has addressed the 
                        following letter to the administrator of the 
                        municipality:
                        Dear sir,—Please put in your next minutes 
                        following proposition : I propose that all 
                        matters to be discussed by the Delegation 
                        should be sent to all members of the Commis-
                        sion, and that those of the members who feel 
                        interested in the subject, shall be informed 
                        of the date and hour of the meeting and allow- 
                        ed to attend. As it is at present, those 
                        who are not on the Delegation are not really 
                        "au courant" with what is going on with the 
                        municipality.	
                        Also, that we should have a printing press 
                            and proces-verbaux should be sent to every 
                            member, at least within 48 hours, not as now. 
                            I received on the 4th of Feb. the proces-verbal 
                            of the Delegation of the 17th Jan. Again, the 
                            proces-verbal of the Commission of the 30th 
                            Nov. 1 received on the 10th of January- 
                            yours sincerely,	
                            Geo. B. Alderson
                            A propos of the above, Mr. G. B. Alderson
                            writes:—Only at the meeting of the 11th Jan-
                            uary, some members of the Delegation spent 
                            two hours complaining that the secretary had
                            not correctly reported their own discussion. It
                            was then I proposed the phonograph. It being 
                            then late, we all wanted to go, and passed the 
                            remaining four questions on the ordre du jour 
                            in about 10 minutes </p> </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The S.S. " trojan prince" from manchester, 
                    left malta on tuesday and is due to arrive on 
                    saturday with passengers and general cargo.
                    The moss liner "seti" passed holyhead yesterday
                    bound for manchester.</p></div>
                <div type="item">     
                <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>        
                    <p>The P. and O. S.S. “Persia” (Commander W.
                        H. Haighton) arrived at Port Said yesterday
                        afternoon from Marseilles en route for Bombay.
                        She landed 108 passengers for Egypt, amongst
                        whom we notioed Sir Benjamin Baker, Lady and
                        Miss Bell, and the Hon. S. Peel</p> 
                        <p>The earl of stair is also a passenger by the
                        "persia" for bombay</p>
                    <p>The marchioness of Donegall has gone for a 
                    trip on the second Cataract reach and left
                    Shellal for wady halfs today.</p>
                    <p>The ex prime minister of italy, the marquis
                    di rudini, left cairo today for suez en rout
                    for massowah.  The italian statesman has
                    thoroughly enjoyed his visit to egypt and the
                    sudan, and was greatly impressed with the progress
                    the coutry is making under the guidance of england.</p>
                    <p>The following are the visitors staying at the
                        Savoy Hotel, Port Said: M. and Mme.
                        Frey, Mr. A. Perry, M. and Mme. Bienola,
                        M. and Mme. Cantel Bey, Misses Gibeon, M.
                        and Mme. Riddook, M. and Mme. Wflhsms,
                        Prof. Cobbett, Lieut B. T. Curiing, Lieut
                        Willoocks, Mr. A.L. 8cottand family, Mrs. Som-
                        morville, Sir J. and Lady Franklin, Mr. W. A.
                        Percy, Mr. Crone, Mr. T. Preitz, Mr. Shaw,
                        M. P. and Mrs. Shaw, Mr. Baner, Mr. D'Orsy</p>
                    <p> M. de la bouliniere left for luxor on monday evening</p>
                    <p>The Savoy Restaurant seemed to be en fete
                        yesterday evening, on the occasion of the extra
                        small dance which took place at the hotel.
                        Among those giving dinner parties we noticed
                        Sir Ernest Cassel, whose party included lady
                        Londesborough, General, Mrs. and Min Blade,
                        Eir William Garstin, Izzet Pasha, Baron von
                        Oppenbeim, Sir Edward and Lady Colebrooke,
                        tho Countess of Lovelace, General 8ir Stanley
                        Clarke, Birch Pasha, Mrs. Forester, Mr. Ward,
                        Mr. Webb, and Tueni Bey. Count Gabriel
                        de Zogbeb had a select party of 10. Mr.
                        and Mrs. Peter Martin had two gnests,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Coatee a party of 8, Mrs. K.
                        Simon a party of 7, and Mrs. Jaoquee a party
                        ot 10. The dance proceeded with the usual
                        animation until one o'clook, and a large num-
                        ber of suppers were served afterwards in the
                        restaurant.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left Assiout yester-
                        day by the P.B. "Amasis.”—Miss Nellie Hay,
                        Miaa Margaret Caille, Mr. and Mrs. Walter
                        Prestou, Mr. and Mrs. W. and Miss 8mithett,
                        Mr. and Mrs. J. M. Comae, Mr. and Mrs. A.
                        Meller, Mr. Lenaaer, Mr. Weiss, Mr. and Mrs.
                        W. J. Thome, Mr. Kavier d’Udekem d'Aooz,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Henri d’Udekem d'Aooz, Mr.
                        and Mrs. and D. Blood, Mr. Kurt Baaeennan,
                        Dr. Healey, Dr. T. A. and Mrs. MoGraw, Mr.
                        and Mrs. W. H., Mr. Henry S. and jiiss
                        Gertrude BrintnaU, Mr. Edward A. Field,
                        Mr. G. W. Dennis, Mr. C. Burge, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Wilhelm Streit, Mrs. David King,
                        Mrs. Blise Umlaut Mr. Siegfried Trebitsch,
                        Mr. Geo., Mrs. Lewis and and Mist Buthie
                        cohen, Mr. koritzky</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGERS LISTS</head>
                    <p>Departures
                        Per North German Lloyd S.S. “Schleswig,"
                        arrived at Alexandria on Monday:— .
                        From Marseilles:—Baroness de 8erelaee, Mr. -
                        d Mrs. R. Preston, Mr Vaxelaire,' Mr. Alagg,
                        misses Brinville and Kartin, Mr., Mrs. and
                        ss Moss, Mr. and Mrs. A Dumont, Her and
                        au Irlirt Pol Kohler, Mr. and Mrs. J. and
                        ssar, Mr. E. S. Grew and party, Capt. B.
                        lodes, Herron Tiedeman seeheim, herr and
                        au Fromm, Frau Seaff, Mrs. M. MoCallum,
                        herr Gemperli-Beckb, Herr B. Pagenstecker,
                        herr J. Witbold, ilerr W. Vogel and Falekso- '
                        stein, Countess Amim, Mrs. and Miss Wollfe,
                        mr. Jules K Schweizer,Miss Bdwards ajjd maid,
                        mr. L. Hochapfel, Mr. and Mre, Ellsworth,
                        mr. and Mrs. G. Sachs, Herr Oberiandee-
                        richtsrat Quincke, Frmftan and Freun
                        lelabein, Mr. William C. Lupton, Mr. Ed.
                        allaerts, Mme. Bertholet and eon.
                        From Naples: — Mrs. H. Hogg, Mr. R.
                        ihrmann, Mrs. Gabriel and Mrs. Sprague,
                        r. E. Walton and Miss Clara Walton, Mr.
                        R. Meyer, Mr. John Woodruff, Mr. Lyon
                        d party, Herr and Frau Vollmer, Mrs.'
                        ankliu, Mr. Smau, Mr. Demperoli, Mr. Sam
                        Crozer and party, Count A d'Urset M.
                        . Gartou I. Serstevents, FrL Babe and FrI.
                        nose, Generallt Tbumen Graf. G. von Annin,
                        au B. Lanson, Herr W. Lanson, Herr and
                        au Warburg and dootor, Frau von Boeohan',
                        err and Frau von Lie ben, Herr and Frau A.
                        bor Herr R. FelamanD, Prinz Franz Lichten-
                        in, Graf Traatmansdorff, Messrs. G. and W.
                        Brady. Mr. W. C. Benedict, Herren W. and .
                        Semigradoff,Raymond and Whitcomb’s party
                        Capt Atkin Higgins, Mr. Debourg, Mr. W. K.
                        filing, Mr. R. B. Gregory.</p> </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Savoy hotel luxor</head>
                        <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its
                        position on nike bank.  Under german management.
                        moderate charges.  Patronised by officer 
                        of army of occupation.  Concerts twice daily</p> </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>TYROL</head>
                            <p>Weissenstein castle 8410
                            ft first class private hotel near 
                            windisch-matrei, station, liens (reached from venice
                            or treiste). Bracing air, good mountaineering centre.  
                            Tennis, fishing, best june, september.  Apply proprietor.</p> </div>
                        
  </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
