<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Dante Grieco</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-27">October 27, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-06">May 6, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7191] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, MAY 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dll01">
                        <head>Deutsche Levante-Linie.</head>
                        <p>Mail and Passenger Steamships. Regular three-weekly Service from<lb/>
                            HAMBURG, via ANTWERP &amp; MALTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice-versa,
                            admitting<lb/> goods from all chief German Railway Stations on direct
                            Bill of Landing to<lb/> ALEXANDRIA and all chief ports of Egypt, Syria,
                            etc., at favourable through<lb/> rates of DEUTSCHE<lb/> VERKEHR
                            (traffic).</p>
                        <p>EXPECTED AT ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                        <p>S.S. Lemnos now on the berth discharging will sail for Beyrout on or
                            about the 6th May.</p>
                        <p>S.S. Chios May 6 from Hamburg bound for Rotterdam and Hamburg</p>
                        <p>S.S. Fera May 6 from Odessa bound for Hamburg.</p>
                        <p>S.S. Patmos May 16 from Antwerp bound for Beyrout.</p>
                        <p>S.S. Andros May 18 from Hamburg bound for Beyrout.</p>
                        <p>For tariff and particulars apply to ADOLPHE STROSS, Alexandria,
                            Agent.</p>
                        <p>15-2-905</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun01">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>A great economiser and saver of time, health, and strength.</p>
                    <p>Laundry worries went out of woman's life when Sunlight Soap came into it.</p>
                    <p>It is the purest Soap going.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET. LEAVING FRENCH WATERS.</head>
                    <dateline>Singapore, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Six Russian warships and four colliers have been sighted passing in the
                        semi-darkness and haze at 5.30 a.m. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Saigon, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Admiral Rodjestvensky’s Fleet was lying near Son-Kohe on the 2nd inst. but
                        was preparing to sail on the 3rd. He informed the French authorities of his
                        impending departure. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Saigon, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Admiral Rodjestvensky, who was in the 2nd inst. in the Bay of Son-Kohe,
                        informed the French authorities that he would leave the next day.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL KUROPATKIN. PROBABLE IMMEDIATE RECALL.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>It is stated that GeneraL Kuropatkin will be immediately recalled for reasons
                        of health. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN TORPEDO-BOATS BUILT AT KIEL</head>
                    <dateline>Lubeck, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The police authorites have stopped the sail- ing of two torpedo-boats built
                        at Kiel for Russia, and sent to Lubeck in sections by rail for shipment as
                        machinery. The shipment was neatly completed when it was stopped. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARGENTINA’S WARSHIPS.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The “Times" learns from St. Petersburg that the report that Russia has
                        acquired the Chilian and Argentine navies, continues to be denied, but it is
                        intimated from a good diplomatic source that the warships will be brought to
                        the Baltic and will serve as a nucleus for a new navy in case Admiral
                        Rodjestvensky should come to grief. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>London, April 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The Argentine Government denies the sale of warships; it is willing to sell,
                        but dare not deliver during the war. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SITUATION IN THE CAUCASUS. BORDERING ON ANARCHY.</head>
                    <dateline>St. Petersburg, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The situation at the Caucasus continues to border on anarchy. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Warsaw, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Work has been resumed in several factories. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WORD-WIDE NAVAL MANOEUVRES. POSTPONED INDEFINITELY.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 5</dateline>
                    <p>(Official). The grand naval manoeuvres arranged for next mouth have been
                        postponed, as, if carried out then as planned they may cause inconvenience,
                        but if not carried out at all the lessons it is desired to inculcate would
                        not be given.</p>
                    <p>This apparently refers to the world wide manoeuvres mentioned in the
                        despatches of 10th December and is possibly due to the desire to have a
                        large fleet in home waters on the occasion of the visit of the French
                        squadron. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION. GERMANY'S LATEST PROPOSAL.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The "Times" reports from Paris that failing a European conference Germany
                        would now be content with an exchange of views among the Powers regarding
                        Morocco, but does not think that this will find favor with the three
                        governments concerned. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>Paris, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The French proposals regarding Morocco include the formation of a State Bank
                        which will place the finance of the country on a firm footing. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KING’S RETURN.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>Some comment has been caused by the fact that Lord Lansdowne, who met the
                        King at the station yesterday evening, was practically the first visitor his
                        Majesty received today. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEWMARKET RACES.</head>
                    <dateline>London, May 5.</dateline>
                    <p>One Thousand Guineas. — 1, Lass O’Glory; 2, Koorhaan; 3, Jongleuse.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Holy Carpet is expected to return to Cairo on the 13th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a.m.
                            to-morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The P. &amp; 0. S.S. “Isis” has finished dry- docking and leaves
                            Alexandria for Port Said this evening.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague.</head>
                        <p>Yesterday's plague bulletin records a recovery at Alexandria. No cases
                            are reported to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Anglo-American Nile Co.</head>
                        <p>It is expected that the Anglo-American Nile
                            Steamer and Hotel Company will declare a dividend of 8 per cent this
                            year.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Shoubra district of Cairo at dawn
                            tomorrow, and in the Waily district at the same time on Monday, will be
                            poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Police Case.</head>
                        <p>There is to be an investigation at the Alexandria
                            Gouvernorat into the alleged brutal conduct of a policeman in Cherif
                            Pasha-street on Thursday last.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Khedivial Appointment</head>
                        <p>We are pleased to learn that the well-known
                            engraver and printer, Mr. J. Margosches, has lately been honored with
                            the appointment of engraver to H. H. the Khedive.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mohamed Aly Centenary</head>
                        <p>The Fête Committee at Alexandria officially
                            requests us to inform the public that it is hoped that private homes
                            will be illuminated on the evening of the Mohamed Aly Centenary.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Trams to Abou Roash.</head>
                        <p>It is stated that the Public Works Ministry has
                            postponed consideration of the scheme submitted by Boghos Pasha Nubar
                            for the construction of a tramway between Abou Roash and Mena House.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Splendid Hotels of Egypt Co.</head>
                        <p>A meeting of the shareholders of the Splendid Hotels of Egypt Company
                            will be held on the 24th inst. in order to approve the purchase, etc.,
                            of the New Khedivial Hotel at Alex- andria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p>On the 3rd inst. 16 vessels passed through the Canal. Of these, 6 were
                            British, 1 French, 2 German, 3 Austrian, 2 Turkish, 1 Dutch, 1 Greek.
                            The day's receipts were frs. 445,080.74, making the total from the 1st
                            inst. frs. 945,9500.1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Garrison Directory.</head>
                        <p>The May issue of the Garrison Directory of the British Force in Egypt is
                            to be the last issue of the 1904- 1905 season. The contents have been
                            increased by six pages and several improvements have been made to this
                            useful local directory.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Alhambra Theatre.</head>
                        <p>The Magnani operetta company is meeting with great success at the
                            Alhambra. By general request Primavera Scapigliata will be repeated this
                            evening and tomorrow a matinée performance of it will be given. In the
                            evening of Sunday Venditore di Uccelli will be produced.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports.</head>
                        <p>From the 1st January to 4th May the quantity of coal imported into Egypt
                            was 281,462 tons, of which Newcastle sent 68,434, the Welsh districts
                            146,032, the Scotch districts 36,412, Yorkshire 16,466 and other places
                            13,118 tons. During the same period of 1904, 369,165 tons were
                            received.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Union Artistique Francaise has established at its premises in 2,
                            Cairo station- street, a French elocution class. This class is quite
                            free, and may be attended by outsiders as well as members of the
                            society, of both sexes and all ages. Further particulars may be obtained
                            on application at the society’s offices any day from to 6 to 8 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Credit Foncier.</head>
                        <p>Our Constantinople Cor- respondent status that the last "gros lot" of
                            100,000 francs of the Crédit Foncier Egyptien (No. 363,181 ), fell to a
                            scullion, named Joseph, in the service of the well-known Con-
                            tsantinople banker, M. L Zarifi. The latter had himself purchased the
                            lottery bond for his servant.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ottoman Official Salaries.</head>
                        <p>It it stated that for the first time in living memory every Turkish
                            official was punctually paid his full salary on April 1. There is
                            something very subtle about the selection of this precise date by a
                            paternal Government. It suggests so clearly that the recipients are very
                            much mistaken if they think that it is going to happen again.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>“La Revue Internationale d'Egypte."</head>
                        <p>M. Canivet is to be heartily congratulated on the first number of his new
                            review, the contents of which are very good, and include articles by M.
                            Leopold Julien on the economic situation of Egypt, by M. Victor Sinano
                            on the Société Artistique, by Professor Breccia on Arsinoe II., by M.
                            Nourrison on Richard Wagner and Mathilda Wesendonck, etc.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Institute.</head>
                        <p>A meeting of the Egyptian Institute will be held at 4 o'clock on Monday
                            afternoon next. M. Pachundaki will lecture on the geology of the Marta
                            Matrouh neighbourhood. A discourse will be given by Dr. Adamidi on the
                            invasions of Egypt by European races during the pre-historic period.
                            Another interesting paper to be read at the meeting will be Yacoub Pasha
                            Artin’s, on Egyptian Press statistics up to 1904.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Coptic Monasteries.</head>
                        <p>Owing to the bad state of repair into which the old Coptic monasteries,
                            known as “El-Abyad” (the White) and "El-Ahmar" (the Red), at Sohag, have
                            fallen, steps are to be taken to preserve them. An examination of these
                            monuments has been made, and it has been decided to restore them. The
                            Coptic Patriarch has consented to provide LE. 1,000 of the total sum
                            required for this purpose, on condition that the Government finds the
                            rest.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suspension of a Moudir. </head>
                        <p>Hassan Bey Wassif, Moudir of Ghirgeh, has been suspend- ed temporarily
                            from his official functions, because it is alleged that he was an
                            accomplice in a serious case of fraud committed by Mo- hamed Effendi
                            Badaoui, son of Badaoui Bey, a notable of Sohag. The Moudir has been
                            summoned to Cairo and an enquiry is to be opened on the subject by the
                            Ministry of the Interior. Another official is also accused of being an
                            accomplice in the fraud, namely the judge of the Mehkemeh Sharieh of
                            Tahta Markaz, and the judge is to be brought before a council of
                            discipline of the Ministry of Jostice.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cairo Cigarette-maker’s End.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Joseph Helpern, who had been brought up in Cairo and was of Roumanian
                            nationality, and by trade a cigarette-maker, 30 years of age, entered a
                            restaurant in Whitechapel-road, Loudon, a few days ago and called for a
                            cup of tea, which was supplied. He was seen to drop the contents of a
                            white paper into the cup, and, after drink- ing, exclaimed to the
                            waiter, "Don’t use it; there is poison in it. Take me to the hospital.”
                            A constable who was called gave Helpern an emetic, and took him to the
                            London Hospital. He died on the way there. At the inquest, a letter,
                            written in German, and addressed to a Jewish journal, was read. It
                            concluded:— This voice calls to you, a young venturer, Joseph Helpern,
                            born in Roumania, brought up in Cairo, and a cigarette-maker by trade.
                            My friends and acquaintances; I am warning you all. Keep away from the
                            cards, and your head will be clear for work and business, and you also
                            retain with your money and your health, and not have the same end as I
                            have.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Shoubra School</head>
                        <p>It has been decided to hold the examination for the scholarships offered
                            in connection with this school about the last week in May, and the
                            successful can- didates will receive a year’s education free of charge
                            at the above school. The competition will be open to all English
                            children, whether now attending at Shoubra school or not, between the
                            ages of 9 and 13. The subjects for examina- tion will be: Scripture
                            (questions on the four Gospels to be answered in writing); Dictation;
                            Geography (of Africa); and simple Arithmetic. In addition the girls will
                            be required to make a button-hole and sew on a button. With reference to
                            the above scholarships the term “English” will be held to include a
                            citizen of the United Kingdom, Canada, or Australia. Children whose
                            mothers only are English in this sense, will not be eligible unless the
                            father is a British subject. The full names, and age last birthday of
                            candidates, should be sent in to Miss Taylor or Miss Cullen on or before
                            May 15. No scholarship will be awarded unless there are at least three
                            competitors. In each case the boy or girl who has the second highest
                            number of marks will receive a prize.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Major-General Sir Roland Lane, formerly G.O.C. at Alexandria, has been
                        selected to succeed Major-General Schwäbe as lieutenant general and
                        secretary of Chelsea Hospital.</p>
                    <p>The “Army and Navy Gazette,” in announc- ing the appointment of Brevet
                        Lieut-Colonel Lord Edward Cecil to be Under-Secretary of State for War in
                        the Egyptian Government, remarks:- “It will be admitted by all who have
                        followed Lord Edward Cecil’s services since he arrived in Egypt that he has
                        spared himself in nothing where duty has been con- cerned. He ought in this
                        new position to be as successful as he undoubtedly has been in all other
                        posts he has filled.”</p>
                    <p>Mr. Martin Macdermott, whose death is recorded at Bristol on Wednesday week
                        at the ripe old age of eighty-two, formerly held the position of chief
                        architect in the Administra- tion of the Viceroy of Egypt under Nubar
                        Pasha.</p>
                    <p>The Sultan has been pleased to confer the Order of the Shéfakat on Mme.
                        Bartau, wife of Bartau Pasha of Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Captain H. W. Dumaresq, 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade, left Cairo for Khartoum
                        to-day on duty.</p>
                    <p>M. Alexander Petropoulo, formerly directeur- adjoint, of the Russian
                        Navigation Company at Alexandria, has been appointed to the same position at
                        Constantinople.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <dateline>(Aujourd’hui à midi et demie)</dateline>
                    <p>Le ca'me le plus complet a prévalu durant toute la matinée.</p>
                    <p>Il y a eu, cependant, quelques fluctuations.</p>
                    <p>La Banque Nationale hausse de 27 7/16 à 27 5/8, la Nungovich de 10 1/8 à 10
                        3/16, la Delta Light de 13 7/16 à 13 1/2, les Privilé- giées Tramways de 151
                        1/2 à 152 1/4.</p>
                    <p>Par contre, la Banque d'Athènes fléchit de 118 1/2 à 118, la Béhéra de 43 1/2
                        à 43 1/4, la Delta Land de 2 11/16 à 2 9/16, la Salt &amp; Soda de 35/3 à
                        34/9.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO WATERWORKS. REMOVAL OF SITE.</head>
                    <p>The Cairo Water Company has just pur- chased from the Government a large area
                        of about 10,000 square metres near the rue Abou el Ela, in the Boulac
                        quarter, for the installa- tion of new refrigerating apparatus.</p>
                    <p>Several refrigerating chambers are to be let to the Nile Cold Storage
                        Company.</p>
                    <p>The Water Company intend to transfer all their plant and offices to this
                        spot. The whole installation and transference of the said plant and offices
                        from the present site will be com- pleted by the end of 1907, when the
                        company will have sufficient engine power and accom- modation to produce 200
                        tons of ice per day. The maximum output in any one day last year did dot
                        exceed 94 tons.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PHARMACY REGULATIONS</head>
                    <p>The International Association of Pharmacists held a meeting on Wednesday
                        evening at Alexandria to read Lord Cromer’s letter on the subject of the new
                        pharmaceutical regulations.</p>
                    <p>The society thoroughly appreciated the value of these regulations, and were
                        unanimous in recognising that their enforcement would be of benefit to all
                        orthodox pharmacists. It was acknowledged that the Egyptian Government,
                        represented by the Sanitary Administration, had, after thoroughly studying
                        the matter, taken this course in order to protect legitimate pharmacists, as
                        owing to the difficulties inhe- rent in the system of the Capitulations, it
                        had been hitherto impossible to suppress or inspect so-called pharmacies,
                        where the proprietors or employés had no knowledge of or qualification for
                        the compounding and dispensing of drugs.</p>
                    <p>In relation to the regulations, the only regret of the society was that the
                        Sanitary Administration should not have stringently put in force the
                        application of the regu- lations, as in Egypt’s commercial capital there are
                        a number of so called pharmacists who have never conformed to the
                        regulations and thus openly set the Government at de- fiance. The society
                        demand nothing better than a stringent and permanent application of the
                        regulations which are now accepted as law.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive held a largely attended recep- tion at Ras-el-Tin Palace this
                        morning, on the occasion of his return to Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>His Highness is leaving Alexandria this afternoon in order to inspect his
                        estates in the Mariout district.</p>
                    <p>Great preparations are being made, says our Constantinople Correspondent, for
                        the recep- tion of the Khedive on his approaching visit. His Highness's
                        Konak on the Bosphorus is to be renovated throughout.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY</head>
                    <p>This morning the Khedive received the members of the Municipal Commission at
                        Ras- el-Tin Palace in order to receive their thanks fur his Highness's
                        letter on the subject of the Municipality’s decision in regard to the cele-
                        bration of the centenary of Mohamed Aly at Alexandria Mahmoud Pasha Sidky,
                        as Presi- dent of the Commission, made an eloquent address to the
                        Khedive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army"><head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                    <p>Lieut. C. H. Lucas, 2nd R. Berkshire Regiment has been taken on the
                        strength of the Egyptian Army, with the rank of Bimbashi. He has been posted
                        to the 1st Battalion.</p>
                    <p>Captain B. W. T. Danford, R.E., having reported his arrival in Egypt from
                        England, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army, with the rank
                        of Bimbashi. He has been posted to the Department of Works.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PORTS AND LIGHTHOUSES.</head>
                    <p>The following is the text of the decree appointing. Rear Admiral Sir Massie
                        Blomfield, K.C.M.G., Director-General of the Ports and Lighthouses
                        Administration. The appointment, we believe, is a personal one in
                        recognition of the Admiral’s services:—</p>
                    <p>Le Contre-Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, contrôleur général des Ports et
                        Phares, est nommé Directeur général de la dite Admi- nistration, à partir du
                        1er mai 1905.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A HORRID SPECTACLE.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday’s express to Upper Egypt ran over three camels, just past the
                        Embabeh bridge. At this point there is a crossway, but instead of there
                        being a proper gate, to close this up when the trains are passing, there is
                        only a chain, that is pulled across, not a foot from the ground. The poor
                        beasts, who had got over this, were run down, and jammed between the line
                        and the railings of a garden, belonging to some railway employés. The
                        animals were not quite dead, hut they could not be moved, as between the
                        railing and the train there is just enough space for a man to pass. The
                        train moved slowly on, with the natural consequence that the animals were
                        drawn under the wheels, and the train had to stop, then moved again and
                        stopped, till at last, they did what they ought to have done at first, that
                        is, cut down the wooden railing and draw the animals away. It would have
                        also been more humane if they had killed them at once.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>VISIT OF JAPANESE PRINCE.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Friday.</dateline>

                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The S.S. “Prinz Heinrich, which arrived here yesterday, had on board as
                            passenger to Germany, H.I.H. Prince Arisugawa, the Mikado’s
                            representative at the forthcoming wedding of the German Crown Prince.
                            His Imperial Highness landed here, and Mr. Tanaka, the Japanese Agent,
                            who has been in Port Said since December last, had a long interview with
                            him. Both lunched in one of the special dining saloons of the Eastern
                            Exchange, which had been reserved for the purpose.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SHIP ASHORE:</head>
                        <p>The S.S. “Kamil Pacha”, which was to have left last evening for sea,
                            after having weighed anchor, drifted ashore through some cause or other,
                            and remained there all night. She was got off this morning with the aid
                            of tugs, and proceeded.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE S.S. “CANDLESHOE.”</head>
                        <p>The surveys on the hull of the “Candleshoe" are to be made next week; the
                            entire portion of the damaged cargo being expected to be out by that
                            time.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE S.S. “CONGAL”</head>
                        <p>The hole in this side of the “Congal” is, I believe, now blocked up; the
                            building of the caisson still goes on, and it is rumoured all will be
                            ready for the pumping out by the last week of the month.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BANDMANN COMPANY.</head>
                        <p>Among the visitors now staying in the Eastern Exchange Hotel are three
                            Members of the above company, who are leaving for England by the P.
                            &amp; 0. mail on Monday. They are Miss Treseden, who will be remem-
                            bered as one of the dancers, and Messrs. Tillett and Williams, the
                            latter the musical conductor.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GARDEN PARTY AT NOUZHA.</head>
                    <p>A delightful garden party was given by Mrs. Chataway yesterday afternoon in
                        Nouzha Gardens. From five to six hundred persons were present, including all
                        the rank and fashion of Alexandria and Ramleh. The gardens form a unique
                        site for a garden party in the neighbourhood of Alexandria, and yesterday
                        afternoon they looked their best. After tea dancing was indulged in on an
                        excellent floor, which had been laid down for the occasion. An Egyptian Army
                        band played a charming selection of music. During an interval in the dancing
                        Baron René de Menasce and Mr. Ramsay gave an exhibition of the Cake Walk.
                        The guests did not disperse till 7 o’clock, after enjoying a most pleasant
                        afternoon.</p>
                    <p>The host and hostess were indefatigable in entertaining their numerous
                        guests; Mrs. Chataway after having greeted, with her usual courtesy and
                        charming manner, all arrivals, went round to each table and had a chat with
                        her friends, looking after them herself.</p>
                    <p>The display of handsome gowns was quite a feature; it is impossible to give a
                        detailed description. Whilst the grown-ups were enjoy- ing themselves, over
                        a hundred children were being entertained. A conjurer and a gramo- phone
                        gave the little folks intense delight for a time, after which they were all
                        grouped round a huge "horse-shoe” table, where tea, cake, and all sorts of
                        good things were provid- ed for them.</p>
                    <p>We will close our notice by saying that the Municipality deserves great
                        credit for having taken over Nouzha. Considering that it is scarcely two
                        months since the work was taken in hand, the results already obtained are
                        simply marvellous. Avenues have been opened up, fine specimens of trees
                        hidden away have been brought to light, valueless shrubs have been removed,
                        etc, thus obtaining vistas pleasing to the eye.</p>
                    <p>We have no doubt that if the tram lines reach Nouzha, these gardens will
                        resume their pristine glory, and become a fashionable resort for
                        Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PIGMIES AT CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>The "Globe" remarks:- There are many in- teresting facts in the papers about
                        the pigmies who are coming over to this country. “Life in the forest,” says
                        the "Express,” “is dreary in the extreme. It is always twilight, the sun
                        never penetrates through the dense foliage, and for nine months of the year
                        it pours with rain.” An English summer will make the poor fellows feel quite
                        homesick.</p>
                    <p>They are not dandies. Their whole personal belongings, we read, consist of a
                        poisoned spear or two, an old day cooking-pot, and a scrap of skin round the
                        waist. They should create a sensation on church parade.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Khedivial mail S.S. “Prince Abbas” will leave Alexandria on Wednesday for
                        Piraeus, Smyrns, Mitylene and Constantinople.</p>
                    <p>The Papayanni liner “Belgravian" arrived in England yesterday and the same
                        company’s liner “Flavian” left England for Alexandria on 3rd inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army"><head>ARMY AND NAVY.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>London, April 21.</dateline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>It has been ruled that in future the em- ployment of officers as attachés of
                        foreign armies in the field will not reckon as active service in the field
                        for the purposes of the grant of a foreign decoration. The grants of medals
                        and clasps by the Egyptian and other Governments and the reckoning of war
                        service of officers in the employment of those Govern- ments will be
                        dependent on the express sanc- tion of the Army Council.</p>
                    <p>Captain C. G. Grazebrook, 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, Cairo,
                        has been ordered home for two years’ duty at the Depot, Omagh.</p>
                    <p>Major J. A. Hope, Depot, King's Royal Rifle Corps, on promotion, has been
                        posted to the 3rd Battalion in Bermuda, and Captain H.C. Warre, D.S.O., on
                        return to regimental duty from staff employment, has been posted to the same
                        battalion.</p>
                    <p>The 2nd Battalion K.R.R.C., at Bareilly, defeated the 1st Battalion Seaforth
                        High- landers in the final of the Infantry Polo Tournament in India lately.
                        The Seaforths, it may be remembered, had a splendid reputa- tion when at
                        Cairo last year, and the defeat of their team came as a bit of a
                        surprise.</p>
                    <p>The cruise of the combined Atlantic and Mediterranean Fleets in the Levant
                        will last for a month. Much useful practical manoeuvring based on the
                        "blue-water school” doctrine of crushing an enemy to our naval supremacy
                        will be carried out, and ports will be visited by detached cruisers for the
                        purpose of showing the flag.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <dateline>London, April 27.</dateline>
                    <p>As was anticipated in these notes some time ago, Brigadier-General G.M.
                        Bullock, C.B., who has been in temporary command of the British troops in
                        Egypt since the retirement of Major- General Slade, has been confirmed in
                        that appointment, to the great gratification of the many friends of the hero
                        of Colenso and Honingspruit.</p>
                    <p>In the new infantry drill sanctioned by the Army Council the ancient custom
                        of rifle Regiments presenting arms with unfixed bayonets, and marching
                        past at the trail, has been resum- ed. These differences from the Line
                        regiments were highly prized by the gallant "Green Jackets” and their
                        revival will be learned with pleasure by the foreign service battalions of
                        the Cameronians, Royal Irish Rifles, King's Royal Rifle Corps, and the Rifle
                        Brigade.</p>
                    <p>It is very gratifying to learn that the Cape- to-Cairo Railway, the life
                        dream of Cecil Rho- des, is making good progress, having been . completed
                        almost to Ralomo, which is about 100 miles north of the Victoria Falls. From
                        the latter point the line will be continued via Broken Hill to tap that
                        mining country, rich in copper and zinc. The Falls Bridge will be open early
                        in June for traffic. In addition to the important bearing which the line
                        will have on British commerce, it will be possessed of immense strategical
                        importance, not the least of which will be the easy transfer of troops from
                        Egypt to the Cape and vice-versa. A French settlement at Fashoda would have
                        been fatal to that.</p>
                    <p>A London contemporary has just caused a great sensation by announcing that
                        fifteen of our battleships are unfit to go into action owing to faulty guns.
                        A lengthy article on the subject alleges that the 12-inch mark VIII. guns,
                        which constitute the principal armament of fifteen out of thirty-seven of
                        our battleships of the latest type, are incapable of firing more than fifty
                        full charges under active service conditions. The most recent type of the
                        6-inch gun, which is largely mounted in the secondary batteries of our
                        battleships and cruisers, is also condemned. It is farther stated that the
                        12-inch guns of the “Majestic" class of battleship have also foiled to stand
                        the test of hard service, and still worse, that a shell burst in seven out
                        of sixteen big guns on board British-built Japanese battleships. The article
                        points out that the facts are indisput- able, and that now is the time to
                        act and have our fleet equipped with the best type of guns obtainable.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="visitList"><head>VISITORS LIST.</head> <head>WINDSOR HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Leage de Mieux, Mr. Leslie Black, Mr. Gagonelli, Mr. Coïdan, Mr. Acheson,
                        Mr. Pekmezian, Mr. Ohanian, Mr. Murrel-Wright, Mr. Bahari, Dr. Phitaco, Mr.
                        and Mrs. Berla, Mr. P. Coucoutzi, Mr. N. Saliba, Capt. Halley, Baron de
                        Brockdorff, Le Comte de Sizzi-Noris, Mr. Boulad, Mr. Mathiopoulos, Dr.
                        Stiassin, Mr. Aders, Mr. Blanchard, Mr. Doulcaridis. S.E. Saleh Bey Zaphen
                        Pasha, Mr. G. Martin, Mr. Aéroat Bey, Mr. Humpreys, Mr. and Mrs. Naeff, Mr.
                        Matsoukis, Mr. E. Centelli, Mr. M. Schüller, Mr. Kitroeff, Mr. Malezian, Mr.
                        Crewe, Mr. H.G. Andres, Mr. and Mrs. Robaly and family, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Manzalaoui, Mr. Proja, Mr. and Mrs. Bigiavi, Mr. Perry, Mr. Bereketty, Mr.
                        Stefanados, Dr. Manolakis. Mr. Moraïtopoulos, Mr. Kalamba- kidès, Mr. Testa,
                        Mr. Mansfield, Abaza Bey, Mr. O. Formstecher, Mr. John Edleman, Mr. Page,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Débonne and family, Mr. and Mrs. Saraffy and family, Mr.
                        Thorou, Mr. de Cramer, Dr. Choueri, Mr. H. Ebano, Mr. and Mrs. Cortazzi, Mr.
                        Normandeau Eng. Stöffler, Capt. Borton, M. Pearson.</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-map01">
                    <head>Maple &amp; Co.</head>
                    <p>The Largest, and Most Convenient Furnishing Establishment in the World
                        HUNDREDS of THOUSANDS of POUNDS WORTH OF HIGH-CLASS FURNITURE, BEDSTEADS,
                        BEDDING, CUTLERY, CHINA, GLASS, SILVER WARE, CARPETS, CURTAINS, BLINDS,
                        &amp;c., always ready for immediate shipment. A house furnished throughout
                        in three days.</p>
                    <p>The “Cathcart ” Dining-Room Suite in Mahogany, Walnut or Fumed Oak, with
                        brass mountings, consists of 6 ft Sideboard with handsomely carved pediment
                        and panels, bevelled mirrors in back, lower portion usefully fitted with
                        drawers, cupboards and cellarette; 3 ft 6 in Silver Cabinet, extreme height
                        7 ft fitted with clear glass shelves and mirrored back; 3 ft 6 in Dinner
                        Wagon with two drawers and cupboard; Dining Table 4 ft wide and extending to
                        8 ft long, with extra leaves and patent screw; six very strong Dining Room
                        Chairs with carved backs, upholstered in best marone morocco: Price includes
                        packing and delivery F.O.B. London .. £70 0 0</p>
                    <p>Separate prices on application</p>
                    <p>“ONE of the SIGHTS of LONDON”</p>
                    <p>Maple &amp; Co invite residents of Cairo, Alexandria, Damanhour, Tantah,
                        Mansourah, Damietta, Samahud, Rosetta, Miniah, Ismailla, Port Said, and
                        districts, when visiting London to walk through these spacious showrooms and
                        galleries, and see for themselves all the latest novelties and new
                        productions. MAPLE &amp; CO also send patterns of all kinds of material, and
                        illustrations of furniture, bedsteads, &amp;c., on application, and give
                        Inclusive f.o.b. estimates when desired.</p>
                    <p>TOTTENHAM COURT ROAD LONDON ENGLAND</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">

                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <div type="article" xml:id="deg-el-dllr01">
                    <head>DELTA LIGHT RAILWAYS, Ltd.</head>
                    <table cols="5" xml:id="deg-ta-dllr01">
                        <head>Traffic Returns</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>The week ended <date>April 29.05</date></cell>
                            <cell>Same period*04.</cell>
                            <cell>Inc.</cell>
                            <cell>*Dec.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Kilometres open</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="km">837</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="km">813</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="km">24</measure></cell>
                            <cell>—</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>L.E.</cell>
                            <cell>L.E.</cell>
                            <cell>L.E.</cell>
                            <cell>L.E.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coaching</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">1749</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">1775</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">26</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Goods and Sundries</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">842</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">575</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">267</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>

                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">2591</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">2350</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">241</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Receipts per kilometres open</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">3095</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">2890</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total from commencement of half-year</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">97469</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">91428</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">6041</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>*Week ended <date when="1904-06-25">23rd April 1904</date>.</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="7">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sla01">
                    <head>The Standard Life Assurance Company.</head>
                    <p>Established 1825.</p>
                    <p>Accumulated Funds £11,300,000</p>
                    <p>Bonus Year, 1905.</p>
                    <p>The next division of profits will be made amongst participating Policies in
                        existence at 15th November 1905.</p>
                    <p>All With Profit Policies effected on or before that date will be entitled to
                        share in the Division.</p>
                    <p>The Company have already declared Bonus Additions to Policies to the amount
                        of more than Seven Million Sterling.</p>
                    <p>Head Office for Egypt: Sharia Kasr-el-Nil, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>B. Nathan &amp; Cl, Chief Agents for Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>A. V. Thomson, Secretary for Egypt.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="8">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-okl01">
                    <head>Orenstein &amp; Koppel, Ltd.</head>
                    <p>Capital 10,000,000 Frs.</p>
                    <p>Purveyors to H.H. the Khedive.</p>
                    <p>Portable and permanent railways. Passenger and ggods cars.</p>
                    <p>Tipping and platform waggons for all purposes. Locomotives from 10-400
                        H.P.</p>
                    <p>Large stocks of rails, trucks and locomotives always kept in Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt and Sudan of:--</p>
                    <p>COMPTOIR METALLURGIQUE EGYPTIEN</p>
                    <p>Bridges and iron frame works.</p>
                    <p>HUMBOLDT ENGINEERING WORKS CO</p>
                    <p>KALK, NEAR COLOGNE.</p>
                    <p>Steam engines, Boilers, complete installations for Factories.</p>
                    <p>R. HORNSBY &amp; SONS, LTD., Grantham (England).</p>
                    <p>Fixed and Portable oil engines.</p>
                    <p>KIRCHNER &amp; CO., Leipzig.</p>
                    <p>Wood working machinery.</p>
                    <p>CARL MEISSNER, Hamburg.</p>
                    <p>Oil motor boats and launches.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH AND AMERICAN SYSTEMS OF STEAM PLOUGHING ENGINES TO PLOUGH 8 TO 20
                        FEDDANS PER DAY</p>
                    <p>Offices:</p>
                    <p>Cairo: 24 Kasr-el-Nil Street, opposite Bank of Egypt. P.O.B. 690. Telephone
                        No. 139.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria: 29, Cherif Pasha Street. Telephone No. 661.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
