<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Courtney Coyle</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-03-28">March 28, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, MARCH 28, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OUTBREAK IN CRIMEA</head>
                    <head>BUILDINGS WRECKED AND FIRED</head>
                    <head>WARSHIPS EN ROUTE.</head>
                    <p>Yalta (Crimea), March 27.</p>
                    <p>Serious disorders have broken out here. The police barracks and most of the
                        warehouses and vodka shops have been wrecked and the Chief of the Police
                        wounded. A number of shops are still burning. Reinforcements have been
                        summoned. Warships are going from Sevastopol. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Warsaw, March 27.</p>
                    <p>A bomb was yesterday thrown into the carriage of Baron Nolken, Chief of
                        Police, who was severely wounded. He was driving to investigate an earlier
                        outrage at the police station, across the Vistula, in which 6 police-men
                        were wounded. M. Nolken's assailant escaped alter shooting the pursuing
                        policeman dead. The man who threw the bomb into the police station was
                        wounded. He was captured and removed to the hospital. The whole affair was
                        an elaborate conspiracy on the part of the revolutionaries, who perpetrated
                        the first outrage with the object of inducing M. Nolken to cross the
                        Vistula. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, March 27.</p>
                    <p>The rioters have set fire to the police offices at Yalta, where great
                        excitement prevails. (H.)</p>
                    <p>THE PROSPECTS OF PEACE.</p>
                    <p>“AIR PULL UP RUMOURS.”</p>
                    <p>London, March 27.</p>
                    <p>Reuter's Agency learns from St. Petersburg that the Ministers at their
                        Council last Friday agreed to the principle that the present time is an
                        opportune one for initiating steps in the direction of peace. This
                        resolution was probably communicated to the Tsar on Saturday. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, March 27.</p>
                    <p>The air is full of peace rumours. The latest reports go to show that
                        tentative "pourparlers” of a most secret kind arc proceeding in a
                        Scandinavian Capital with the object of ascer taining the conditions on both
                        sides. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>REPORTED MASSACRE AT MUKDEN.</p>
                    <p>Mukden, March 27</p>
                    <p>The report of the massacre here, mentioned on the 23rd inst, is untrue.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>AUSTRALIAN HORSES FOR JAPAN</p>
                    <p>Sydney, March 27.</p>
                    <p>Eight steamers have been chartered by private firms here to convey to
                        Hong-Kong nearly 10,000 horses which have been purchased on behalf of Japan.
                        The first steamer sails in a fortnight. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>JAPANESE FLEET.</p>
                    <p>Sandakan, March 27.</p>
                    <p>Theenisers "Kasagi," "Chirose," "American and the “Yamata Marn” arrived at
                        Labium on the 18th just and left on the 19th. Vice-Admiral Dewa was in
                        command. (R.)</p>
                    <p>TROUBLE IN PERSIA.</p>
                    <p>Kushan (Persia), March 27.</p>
                    <p>The population here have broken out against the Russian residents, who lied.(
                        Reuter)</p>
                    <p>THE KAISER AT LISBON.</p>
                    <p>HELLENIC PARLIAMENT</p>
                    <p>THE PRINCE OF WALES</p>
                    <p>London. March 27.</p>
                    <p>The Prince of Wales has been appointed Grand Master of the Order of St.
                        Michael and St George is succession to the Duke of Cambridge. ( Reuter)</p>
                    <p>FOOTBALL</p>
                    <p>London, March 27. -England beat Wales by (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>RACING</p>
                    <p>LINCOLNSHIRE HANDICAP.</p>
                    <p>Betting—5 to 1 against Andria and Rosebery ; 6 to 1 against Vadas ; 100 to 9
                        against Catty Cray; 100 to 8 against Green Peter; 100 to 7 against Le
                        Blizon. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DISONTENT IN CRETE</head>
                    <head>UNION WITH GREECE PROCLAIMED INSURGENT MOVEMENT.</head>
                    <p>Canea, March 27.</p>
                    <p>As a result of discontent following the Prince’s most absolute rule, 600
                        armed Cretans assembled near the town as a provisional national assembly,
                        under the presidency of M. Papayanuakis, and proclaimed the union of the
                        Island with Greece. They appealed to the Powers not to employ force for the
                        maintenance of the present regime. Prince George has issued a proclamation
                        appealing to the population and denouncing the movement. A Russian gunboat
                        has brought reinforcements for the Cretan gendarmery at Canea.
                        (Reuter.)Canea, March 27. The insurgents have addressed a proclamation to
                        the Powers in favor of the union of Crete to Greece. (Havas.) OUTRAGE AT
                        TANGIER. “TIMES” CORRESPONDENT STABBED. Tangier, March 27. Mr. Harris, the
                        "Times" correspondent, hue standing in the British Post Office here, was
                        stubbed in the stomach by a man. The injury inflicted, however, was only
                        slight. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Gatti' s Circus will make its debut at the Abbas Helmy Theatre to-morrow
                        evening. Asile Rudolph.—M. Pericles Anastasiadi has sent 1 to the Home in
                        memory of the rate Giuseppe Salfati.Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
                        Gamalieh quarter of Cairo during the night of Wednesday and at daybreak on
                        Thursday will be poisoned by the police. Postal Guide.—The 1905 issue of the
                        Egyptian Postal Guide has just reached us. It is replete with all
                        information concerning the administration, and is sold at the minimum price
                        of 10 mills. Suez Canal.—10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 24-th
                        inst., 5 of which were British, 2 Italian, 2 Russian, 1 French. The days
                        receipts were frs. 231,356.99, making the total from the 1st inst. frs.
                        8,271,390.16.The Sanitary Administration has granted licenses to Mr. Tatius
                        Samuel to practise as a pharmacist, to Mr. Annesley de R. Gordon, to
                        practise as a veterinary surgeon, and to Mr. Missak Chamlian to practise as
                        a doctor in Egypt. Agriculturists’ Union. — The March Bulletin of the Union
                        Syndicale des Agriculteurs d’Egypte contains a,report of the Union's
                        banquet, with the text of the speeches delivered, also a review of the
                        exhibits at the Agricultural Show. Tantah Fair.—The fair of Sid Ahmed
                        el-Bedawi will begin at Tantah on the 14th April. Owing to plague and
                        cholera, the fair has not been held for six years, and it is therefore
                        expected that an enormous concourse of people will attend. Red Sea
                        Lighthouses.— A packet of newspapers, magazines, etc., has been received
                        with many thanks by H. H. S. “Aida,” from Mrs. Watkins, wife of Commander
                        Watkins, R N.R., of the R.M.S. “Isis,” for distribution amongst the Red Sea
                        lightkeepers, during the present visit of inspection of the ship to the
                        lighthouses.Egyptian State Railways.—The Board of Administration inform us
                        that, commencing from Saturday, 1st April next, a sleeping car will be
                        attached to the 11.15 p.m. trains from Cairo to Alexandria and from
                        Alexandria to Cairo. The system of supplying rugs, etc., on hire in these
                        trains, will be discontinued on and from the above-mentioned date. They also
                        state that on and from Saturday, the 15th April, the dining-car service on
                        the Luxor-Sheilal line will be suppressed.Waste Ground in the City.—Our
                        attention has been called to the fact that there is a vacant plot of land in
                        the El Naga quarter, at the corner of the two roads Sidi Awad and Sakai
                        Bakir, where nuisances are constantly committed by natives, and from which a
                        most unpleasant smell issues, in addition to the disgusting sights daily to
                        be seen there. This is not by any means the only place of the kind in the
                        city, and we are asked to urge upon the Municipality the necessity for
                        effectually closing such places,—especially in view of the hot weather which
                        is now setting in. Tableaux Vivants.—A series of “living pictures," entitled
                        “Cinderella,” is to be given at the Zizinia Theatre on April ll in aid of
                        the Foundlings’ Home. The characters are as follows : Cinderella, Mme Bacos;
                        Prince Charming, Mr. Caravia; Fairy Godmother, <cb/>Mrs. Planta ; two wicked
                        sisters, Mrs. Critch- ley and Baroness A. Menacco; the King, Mr.
                        Constantinidis; the Queen, Mrs. Chataway, The pavanne will be danced by
                        about 40 ladies and gentlemen. The music has all been arranged and adapted
                        by Mr. Nicholas Sinadino. Col. McCracken has kindly promised the band of the
                        Berks Regiment free of charge, for the charity.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Maltese Benevolent Society. — At the annual general meeting of the Alexandria
                        Maltese Benevolent Society the following gentlemen were elected to form the
                        committee for the year 1905 :—Avv. Mario Vella, president; Mr. Roberto
                        Stabile, vice-president; Mr. H. Caruana Nani and Mr. F. French, secretaries;
                        Mr. S. A. Frendo, hon. treasurer, and Mr. Roberto Csrailleri, Mr. P. Bonnet
                        and Mr. G.P. Podesta, auditors. The members of the committee are Messrs. A.
                        Bajada, C. Buhagiar, Leandro Camilleri, A. Cilia, G. Morello, A. Thei, and
                        Antonio Zarb. The accounts for the past year were read and approved. The
                        receipts are largely on the increase.</p>
                    <p>Hotel Beau-Rivage. — This fashionable Ramleh hotel, which opened for the
                        summer season on the 20th inst, has lately undergone some structural
                        alterations, with the result that its appointments are now of the most
                        up-to- description. Every effort is being made by the management to ensure
                        the comfort and convence of their visitors. Special care and attention is
                        paid to private dinner parties, banquets, and catering for social functions
                        of all descriptions, fetes, marriages, etc., for which ample room is
                        provided by the hotel, its renowned garden, and the spacious terrace. An
                        excellent cuisine, under the direction of an experienced French chef, will
                        be a feature of the hotel. Amongst the | latest arrivals at the Beau Rivage
                        we notice: Capt. and Mrs. W. H. Rotheram, Mr. A. S. White, Fieldmarechal
                        Rither von Pallini, Dr. W. Y. Gambi, Mr. and Mrs. H. Peters, Vice-Admiral
                        Count Cassini, Mr. and Mrs. Ferd. Bortolotti.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Yesterday the Khedive gave audiences to M. Maximoff; Sheikh Abd-er-Rahman El
                        Sher-bini, the new Rector of Al Azhar, and M.B. Moritz, director of the
                        Khedivial Library. This morning his Highness paid a visit to the Institute
                        for the Blind at Zeitoun. The Khedive has conferred the third class of the
                        Medjidieh on Mr. Allred Sachs, late engineer of the 4th Irrigation Circle,
                        on the occasion of his retirement from the service of the Government. His
                        Highness has promoted the following to the rank of Sanieh (Bey):—Mohamed
                        Behgat Bey, moufetish of Ghezireh, Mausour Sidki Bey, secretary to Prince
                        Mohamed Aly Pasha, and Elias Hakim Bey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL HONORS.</head>
                    <p>The King has given his sanction to the undermentioned to accept and wear
                        decorations conferred upon them by the Khedive:— Imperial Ottoman Order of
                        the Medjidieh, Grand Officer.—Mr. Alfred Berry Brewster, Private Secretary
                        to His Highness the Khedive. Imperial Ottoman Order of the Medjidieh, First
                        Class.—Mr. Alfred Mitchell Innes, Under Secretary of State for Finance.
                        Imperial Ottoman Order of the Medjidieh, Second Class.—George Samuel
                        Abercrombie Harvey (Pasha), Inspector in the Ministry of the Interior.
                        Imperial Ottoman Order of the Osmanieh, First Class.—Mr. Vincent Henry Edwin
                        Corbett, Financial Adviser to His Highness the Khedive. Imperial Ottoman
                        Order of the Osmanieh, Second Class.—Mr. Ambrose Anthony Ralli,
                        Vice-President of the Alexandria Municipality. Imperial Ottoman Order of the
                        Osmanieh, Third Class.—Brevet-Col George Frederick Gorringe, C.M.G., D.S.O.,
                        Royal Engineers. Imperial Ottoman Order of the Medjidieh, Third
                        Class.—Quartermaster and Honorary Capt. George Whitefield Anderson, Seaforth
                        Highlanders; Capt. Robert Vesey Savile, Nottinghamshire and Derbyshire
                        Regiment; and Capt. Alan Colquhoun Grant, Highland Light Infantry.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZEITOUN BLIND SCHOOL. VISITED BY THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive visited the Institution for the Blind at Zeitoun this
                        morning. His Highness was met at the entrance and conducted over the
                        institution by Mr. A. D. Alban, chairman of the committee of manage ment,
                        Dr. Kenneth Scott, the hon. secretary, and Mr. W. R. W. Gardiner. His
                        Highness took a great interest in the management of the institution and
                        expressed his approval of its aims and work.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Menes” arrived yesterday evening from Liverpool, via
                        Gibraltar, Algiers, and Malta, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.
                        The S.S. “City of Cambridge” arrived at Liverpool last night, and the S.S.
                        “City of Khios" sailed for that port this morning.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW HOTEL ENTERPRISE.</head>
                    <head>UPPER EGYPT HOTELS COMPANY</head>
                    <p>The above Egyptian company has been formed for the purpose of taking over all
                        the three hotels at Assouan, viz., the Cataract, the Grand, and the Savoy
                        Hotel on Elephantine Island. It is the intention of the new company to
                        increase the accommodation of all the above hotels. The company has also
                        acquired the Luxor Hotel and the Karnak Hotel, together with 50,000 square
                        metres of land adjacent to the Luxor Hotel and the banks of the Nile, which
                        they consider the finest position in Luxor. Their intention is to build at
                        once a large and entirely new hotel therein with at least 200 rooms, also at
                        least twenty suites of private apartments, with bath-rooms and all the
                        latest sanitary improvements and comforts attached thereto; thus enabling
                        those visitors who may be desirous of making a long stay at Luxor and Thebes
                        to do so in the greatest comfort and luxury. Both Mr. George Nungovich and
                        Mr. Baehler are personally participating in this business, as are also their
                        respective companies, the Nungovich Hotels Co. and the Egyptian Hotels Co.
                        Under such auspices this new venture cannot fail to be a great success. We
                        hope to be able to give full particulars as to the capital and constitution
                        of the company in our to-morrow’s issue.</p>
                    <p>DISTINGUISHED DEPARTURES. ( From our Correspondent ). Port Said, Monday. The
                        train which arrived here from Cairo this afternoon was composed of two
                        portions, on account of the large number of passengers leaving Egypt by the
                        P. and 0. Company’s S.S. ‘‘Arabia.” A special saloon-car was attached to the
                        first portion for H.H. Prince Leopold of Battenberg, and the Duke and
                        Duchess of Devonshire and the Countess de Pierrefonds arrived by the second
                        portion in another saloon oar. They were received at the station by Mr.
                        Tarrell, Director of Customs, M. Philipidis, and Mr. Watson, superintendent
                        of the line.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO HORTICULTURAL SHOW.</head>
                    <p>The following is the list of prize-winners in Division G. (Fruit):— AMATEURS.
                        Class. 55. 12 Cedrats. Mr. Giliberti. 58. 24 Citrous, beladi. Reformatory.
                        60. 24 Blood Oranges. Bouiteau Bey. 61. 24 Mandarines. Bouiteau Bey. 62. 24
                        Narings. Bouiteau Bey. 64. Basket of different kinds of Fruit Boni-teau Bey.
                        65. Boniteau Bey for a kind of lemon; Mrs. Joseph Allen for paupans.
                        NURSERYMEN. Class. 66. Bunch of Bananas. Abdou Eid; Moh. Said el Kebir; Moh.
                        Eid. 67. 12 Cedrats. Moh. Mustapha Ganigni. 24 Citrons, sweet Hafiz Haasan;
                        Abbas Hassan; Moh. Said el Kebir. 24 Citrous, bitter. Ahmed Mohamed; Hafez
                        Hassan; Hassan Shinawi 70. 24 Citrons, beladi. Hafez Hassan; Abbas Hassan;
                        Moh. Said el Kebir. 71. 24 Ordinary Oranges. Hafez Hassan; Badr Ali; Moh. el
                        Sinari. 72. 24 Blood Oranges. Moh. Said el Kebir; Moh. Eid; H. Shenawi. 24
                        Mandarines. H. Shenawi; Moh. Said el Kebir; Ali Es-Sayed. 24 Narings. H.
                        Shinawi; Abbas Hassan; Moh. Hassan. Strawberries, 1 kilo. Hassanem el Agamy;
                        Basket of different kinds of Fruit Moh. Eid. Abdou Eid, for melons.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEUTSCHER SPORTVEREIN.</head>
                    <p>The annual theatrical performance of the German Sporting Club came off on
                        Saturday night at the Eden Theatre, which had been profusely decorated for
                        the occasion. The curtain rose for the comedy “English Spoken,” in which
                        Miss von Tschudi interpreted the runaway young lady exceedingly well, Mr.
                        Sick providing a clever character study of the rich father. Among the minor
                        parts which were held by Messrs. Frey, Quelle, Loucke, and Liudemann, we
                        must specially mention the latter, who greatly amused the audience as
                        interpreter. The next items, "The Siamese Triplets" and the imitation of
                        Fregoli, caused roars of laughter, but the last item, the “Kalam Arabi," was
                        universally considered as the “clou” of the evening. The authors of this
                        farce, Messrs. Lindemann and Mors, are to be congratulated on their
                        excellent rendering of Alexandrian kitchen life and kitchen Arabic. All the
                        parts of the five servants and the lady were held by members of the club,
                        undoubtedly the best being Mr.Cohnitz's Vienna cook, a type ertainly
                        well-known to the numerous ladies present in the audience. Last, but not
                        least, we have to mntion the International Art Convention, where Mr.Binder,
                        our well-known Alexandrian Artist, had exhbited some 30 oil and water-color
                        sketches painted in the most hypermodern and eccentric style. The exhibition
                        room was crowded during the entr'actes and the general appreciation of the
                        objects exhibited is best proved by the fact that al the pictures were sold
                        off before midnight, a result which might make many a member of the Royal
                        Academy feel jealous. Danoing was indulged in until 2am, when a most
                        enjoyable evening was brought to a close. </p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ST. MARK'S CHURCH.</head>
                    <head>JUBILEE OF ITS CONSECRATION</head>
                    <p>On St Mark’s Day, April 25, 1855, Samuel Gobat, D.D., then Bishop of the
                        United Church of England and Ireland in Jerusalem, oonse-crated St. Mark's
                        Church at Alexandria. The church had been founded on August 22, 1838, at a
                        meeting held in the house of Colonel Patrick Campbell (Agent and
                        Consul-General in Egypt 1838-1839), and the foundation stone was laid,by
                        Col. Campbell on December 14, 1839. The first chaplain, the Rev. Edmund
                        Winder, M.A, R.N., was nominated by the Lord Bishop of London on August 10,
                        1840. It is proposed, we understand, to observe the 50th anniversary of the
                        consecration, which falls on April 25 next On the evening of that day an
                        augmented choir will render in the church a sacred cantata entitled “The
                        Holy City," composed by A.R. Gaul, Mus. Bac. Camb., organist of St
                        Augustine's Church, Edgbaston.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BISHOP BLYTH’S VISIT.</head>
                    <p>On Saturday last (the festival of the Annunciation) Bishop Blyth celebrated
                        the Holy Communion at St. Mark's Church at 8 a.m., assisted by the Rev. R.
                        F. Rynd, B. A. This festival of the Annunciation was the 18th anniversary of
                        his lordship’s consecration as Anglican Bishop in Jerusalem and the East. In
                        the afternoon, at 5.15 o'clock, the Chaplain, assisted by the Rev. R. F.
                        Rynd, administered holy baptism to five adult candidates for confirmation.
                        At 6.15 p.m, there was evensong, the confirmation service, and address by
                        the Bishop. The clergy present were the Chaplain, the two assistant
                        chaplains, and the Rev. F. B. N. Norman-Lee, M.A., senior chaplain to the
                        forces in Egypt. The prayers were taken by the R.F. Rynd, the lessons by the
                        Rev. F.B.N. Norman-Lee, S.C.F., and the preface was read by the chaplain.
                        The Rev. R. Wormell, M.A., acted as the Bishop’s chaplain and carried the
                        staff. Twelve candidates were confirmed and a large congregation assembled
                        to witness the administration of the rite. The service was choral, and
                        thoroughly bright and hearty. On Sunday, the Bishop, assisted by the
                        chaplain, celebrated the Holy Communion at 8 a.m. in St. Mark’s, and
                        preached at 11 a.m. and in All Saints', Ramleh, in the evening. The
                        collections throughout the day were given to Jerusalem and the East Mission.
                        At St Mark's P.T. 661 and at All Saints’ P.T. 819 were the amounts given at
                        the collections. The Bishop, in the course of his sermon, pointed out that
                        of £8,000 raised by Jerusalem and the Eat Mission, nearly £1,000 was spent
                        in Egypt. The needs of Tantah were also brought forward. On Monday, the
                        Bishop paid several visits, including one to Victoria College, where the
                        headmaster, Mr. C.R. Lias, M. A., conducted his lordship, who was
                        accompanied by Canon and Mrs. Ward, through the various classrooms. The
                        Bishop was particularly struck by the bright and happy faces of the boys,
                        and the spirit of friendliness and kindness which everywhere prevailed. At
                        noon Dr. Blyth and the Chaplain proceeded to the Deaconesses' Hospital to
                        administer the rite of Confirmation to a can didate who through illness was
                        unable to be presented on Saturday evening. At 5.45 p.m. the Bishop,
                        attended by the Chaplain, dedicated the marble portrait recently erected in
                        St. Mark's Church in memory of the late Rev. Canon Davis, for 40 years the
                        chaplain of this church. The Bishop left to-day at noon for Cairo. On Friday
                        next his lordship expects to leave Port Said by the Messageries Maritimes
                        steamer for Beyrout. </p>
                    <p>TRADE WITH CYPRUS. Principal Exports from Larnaca and Limassol to Egypt
                        during February, 1905.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS</head>
                    <p>ARRIVALS</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire left Cairo for England by the 11.10 a.m.
                        train yesterday. The Duke and Duchess expressed to Mr. Wild, the popular
                        manager of the Savoy Hotel, their great appreciation of their stay at the
                        Savoy and their regret that it was not longer. The Sirdar left Cairo at 6.30
                        p.m. on Sunday evening for Khartoum. He was accompanied by Sir R. Von Statin
                        Pasha, Col. Talbot Pasha, Col; Watson Pasha, and several other members of
                        the Sudan Government. Herr von Mohl, German Commissioner of the Public Debt,
                        has come down to Alexandria to meet his son, who arrived by the Messageries
                        steamer from Marseilles and Oxford for the Easter vacation. The. P. and 0.
                        S.S. “Arabia”(Capt J. Leigh), which left Port Said yesterday for Marseilles
                        and London, had on board many distinguished passengers from Bombay. Among
                        them were the Earl of Stair, Hon. Mrs. Gerard, General Sir George and Lady
                        Pretyman, Lady Maclean and two daughters, Sir P. and Lady Playfair, Sir J.
                        Lambert, Sir C. A. and Lady White, Sir Grey Egerton, and the Kani Saniba of
                        Kaparthala. Last night’s small dance at Shepheard’s Hotel was a great
                        success. Several dinner parties were given in the restaurant and in the
                        private dining-rooms. Baron Drasche entertained a party of 11, including
                        Mrs, Bailey, Mrs. Campbell, Miss Hurley, Capt. Byrne, Miss Thurley, Mr.
                        Higgins, Mr. Goschen, Mr. Rumbold, Mr. Tod and Mr. Hume. Mr. Kirkwood had a
                        party of 6, Mrs. Mathews bad a party of 8, including Prof. Hunt and Prof
                        Grenfell; Mr. Pennimann enter-tained a party of 6, including Consul-General
                        Riddle; Mr. Kirkwood a party of 6; Baroness de Furstenweith and Mrs. de
                        Heydweiler, Baron aad Baroness von Alton, Oberfieutenant V. Wedl, etc. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OBITUARY. W. DEMPSTER</head>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death of Mr. W. Dempster, of the New Egyptian Co.,
                        Ltd., Cairo. Deceased had retired to bed last night at the Grand Continental
                        Hotel, to all appearances in perfect health, and was found dead by the
                        servant this morning. Heart failure is believed to be the cause of his
                        death, the news of which has been received with extreme regret by a large
                        circle of friends.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DR LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Avjourd kui a midi et demie)</p>
                    <p>Apart la.Daira, qui est tres forme a 25 1/2, toute la cote est faible ou en
                        baisse. La National Bank recule a 26 15/16, l'A-gricloe a 11 3/16, la Banque
                        d’Athenes a 117. l’Investment a 2 11/32, la Bebera a 49, la Salt &amp; Soda
                        a 40/3, les Privilegiees Tramways a 145 1/2 et la Ramleh Railway a 7 11/16.
                        On offre les Cotton Mills a 5/9, las Markets a 23, l’Anglo-American Nile a 5
                        29/82 et la Khediviaial Mail a 5 3/16. Bes affaires defaut et le mahise
                        domine sur le marche</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
