<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Cassandra Frederick</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-24">October 24, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-05-10">May 10, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7194] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, MAY 1O, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND JAPAN. THE NEUTRALITY QUESTION. FRENCH PRECAUTIONS.</head>
                    <p>Paris, May 9. The Japanese Minister has not lodged a formal protest, but
                        pointed oat the facilities accorded to the Russians for concentrating and
                        revictualling in Indo China. M. Delcassé as- sured him that France will
                        scrupulously respect neutrality. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, May 9. The French resent considerably the charge that they have
                        violated the neutrality. They insist that they have done everything possible
                        from the moment Admiral Rodjestvensky arrived unannounced at Kamaranh. They
                        are certainly now bestirring themselves to move on Admiral Rodjestvensky
                        whenever he shows signs of stopping in French waters. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Paris, May 9. France has given formal orders to prevent the, junction of
                        Rodjestvensky’s and Niebo- gatoff’s squadrons in Indo-Chinese waters.
                        Admiral de Jonquiecres confirms the depar- ture of the Russian squadron from
                        Vanfong for an unknown destination. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LONDON PRESS OPINION.</head>
                    <p>London, May 9. The newspapers admit that the situation is unsatisfactory but
                        do not consider it critical. The "Standard” is not surprised that the
                        Japanese are bitterly aggrieved at the assist- ance given to their enemy,
                        but trusts that they will refrain from any. semblance of dictation. Tokio
                        will be playing the game of St. Peters- burg by introducing into the war a
                        new factor of au incalculable magnitude.</p>
                    <p>The "Morning Post" says that nobody in England dreams of escaping the
                        obligations of the Japanese alliance. The maintenance of tho entente
                        cordiale is only possible if Great Britain and France will abstain from
                        assisting their respective allies. People in Great Britain rely on the
                        chivalry of the French to strictly observe neutrality. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
                    <p>Saigon, May 9. The Russian fleet left Hon Koke southwards towards another
                        bay, where the French men- of-war located it, Admiral Rodjestvensky stated
                        that he is leaving immediately. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MANCHURIA. JAPANESE TACTICS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 9. The Russian correspondents in Manchuria concur in
                        believing that the Japanese are moving slowly and surely under the screen of
                        advanced posts so impenetrable that our cavalry can learn nothing.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PARLIAMENT FOR RUSSIA. RUSSIAN MINISTER'S SCHEME.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, May 9. The Russian Minister of the Interior has dratted a
                        scheme, which is liable to modifica- tion, for the establishment of a form
                        of Parlia ment with two Houses, whereof the lower will consist of 550
                        elected deputies, while the existing Council of the Empire will constitute
                        the upper. (Reuter )</p>
                    <p>Moscow, May 9. The congress of delegates of the Zemstvos has passed a vote in
                        favor of universal suffrage and the creation of two Chambers. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GODLESSNESS IN GERMAN ARMY. KAISER'S CHARACTERISTIC SPEECH.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, May 9. The Church paper publishes a characteristic speech made by the
                        Emperor to the naval recruits on tLe 9th March. The Emperor Wil- liam said
                        be feared that godlessness is pene- trating into the German Army, and that
                        he hoped it would riot be punished some day as Russia is now being punished
                        by Japan, which is acting as God’s scourge like Attila and Napoleon.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANTI-SEMITIC OUTBREAK.</head>
                    <p>Warsaw, May 9. An anti-Semitic outbreak baa taken place at Jitomir. It was
                        attended by fierce fighting as the Jews were armed, having been forewarned.
                        There are 12 killed and 50 wounded. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DESTRUCTIVE TORNADO.</head>
                    <p>Kansas City, May 9. A tornado razed a track 120 feet wide throughout the
                        whole length of the town of Marquette. There are 24 killed and 35 injured.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CRETAN INSURRECTION.</head>
                    <p>Rome, May 9. It has been decided to send two warships to Crete. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                    <p>London, May 9. Lancashire beat Leicestershire by 9 wickets. Yorkshire beat
                        Gloucestershire by winnings and 55 runs.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will be distributed at the G. P. O., Alexandria, at
                            9.30 p.m. to day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Gambling Hell Raided</head>
                        <p>The Alexandria City Police made a raid last night on a gambling hell at
                            Gabbari.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Foot and Mouth Disease</head>
                        <p>exists in Egypt The bills of health of ships leaving our ports bear an
                            annotation to that effect.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BOOK CLUB</head>
                        <p>We are requested to state that in future the library will be open on
                            Tues- days and Fridays between 4.45 and 6 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STRAY AND OWNERLESS DOGS</head>
                        <p>found in the Khalifa district of Cairo during the night of Thursday and
                            dawn of Friday, and in the Mousky during the night of Friday, will be
                            poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"TURKISH” TOBACCO</head>
                        <p>The British South Africa Company has received from Rhodesia a
                            consignment of "Turkish” tobacco which was grown near Buluwayo this
                            season. Fifty acres were planted with this tobacco.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SADAT AFFAIR</head>
                        <p>The Mehkemeh Sharieh of Cairo will enquire into the case of the wife and
                            daughter of Sheikh el Sadat, who fled from the sheikh’s house some weeks
                            ago. The Court will meet on the 24th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HELLENIC ASSIZES</head>
                        <p>The opening of the Hellenic Assize Court at Alexandria will take place on
                            the 14th-inst. M. Antonopoulo, of tho Athenian Appeal Court, will arrive
                            .here on Saturday to preside over the Assize Court.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SUEZ CANAL</head>
                        <p>20 vessels passed through the Canal on the 6th and 7th inst. Of these 12
                            were British, 5 German, 1 French, 1 Norwe gian, 1 Spanish. The receipts
                            for the two days were frs. 635,838.58, making the total from the 1st
                            inst. frs. 2,370,686.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Khedivial Geographical Society</head>
                        <p>Owing to the fêtes prepared by tho committee ad hoc, the Khedivial
                            Geographical Society has post- poned to the 19th the stance
                            commemorative of the geographical work of Mohamed Aly, which it had
                            prepared for the 13th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Frauds on Illiterate Persons</head>
                        <p>The man who, in bis capacity of public letter-writer, was in the habit of
                            stealing the stamps affixed to letters, which ho posted unpaid, and who
                            was detected by the Abbassieh post- master, has been sentenced to two
                            months' imprisonment</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Police Outrage</head>
                        <p>A great scandal has been created at Mellawi owing to the disgraceful
                            conduct of a police officer in that town, who attempted to commit an
                            assault on a Coptio lady. Her screams attracted the neighbours, who
                            succeeded in rescuing her from the clut- ches of the officer. The matter
                            is being inves- tigated by the Ministry of the Interior.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Dismissal of Cadi</head>
                        <p>A council of discipline was held this morning under the presidency of HE.
                            Fuad Pasha, Minister of Justice, when the case of the Cadi of the Tahta
                            Mehkemeh was tried. The question of falsification was not considered,
                            but the cadi was found guilty of administrative irregularities to the
                            prejudice of the magistracy and was dismissed from the service.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Repression of Slave Trade</head>
                        <p>A general court martial will assemble at the Rod Barracks, Abbassieh, on
                            Thursday under the presidency of El Miralai Mahmoud Bey Taufik, director
                            of the Military School, when Gameh Abou Said, an Ababdeh Arab, will be
                            tried for purchasing and attempting to resell Aisha, a Sudanese woman.
                            El Saghkolaghasi Ahmed Effendi Bekir has been appointed prosecutor.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Oeuvre des Enfants' Abandonnés</head>
                        <p>The annual meeting of the charity sisters, presided over by Rev. Father
                            Amaddio Amato, in the absence of the Archbishop, took place on Monday.
                            The ladies of the committee of the Foundlings' Home and a number of
                            patronesses were present. The report on the good work done during the
                            past year was read and approved. Pressure on our space prevents us from
                            dealing with this interesting document to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord Cromer has not returned to Cairo from Jus trip in the interior.</p>
                    <p>It is most likely that M. Smyrnoff, the new Russian Diplomatic Agent and
                        Consul-General at Cairo in succession to M. Maximoff, will not officially
                        present his credentials to the Khedive until his Highness returns to
                        Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Among the departures to-day by the "Schleswig” for Marseilles are Prince
                        Canta- enzini, Sir Henry Tanner, Prof Spiegelberg, Mr. John Home, Mr. Hugo
                        Fenderl, Mr. Max Fischer, Mr. N. Spathis, M. and Mme H. de Vries, etc.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death of Here Gustav Hess, secretary of the German
                        Agency at Cairo, who baa died at the Deaconesses' Hospital after a long
                        illness,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN IRRIGATION SCHEME. THE NEW CANAL.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <p>Khartoum, May 2. One of the most important irrigation schemes under
                        consideration in the Sudan is the pro- posed canal across El Ghezireh,
                        whereby the White end Blue Niles will be connected,and so form a main canal
                        which will extend to Khar- toum. Great difficulties are likely to be en-
                        countered in the realisation of the scheme, but when the canal is completed
                        it will prove of the greatest utility to the lands it will traverse, and
                        will repay all the difficulties of construc- tion.</p>
                    <p>Cattle plague has made its appearance in Kassala Province. The necessary
                        steps have been taken for stamping out the disease and preventing it from
                        spreading to the adjoining province of Sennar and the Blue Nile Pro- vince.
                        Admirably equipped quarantine stations were established on the boundary of
                        each pro- vince and the rind rpest was kept out This should serve as a
                        lesson to the Egyptian authorities.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IMMIGRATION TO EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The recent boom in things Egyptian, and the great publicity which this
                        country enjoys in the English Press at the present time, appears to have
                        given many people at home and in the colonies the opinion that it is a
                        likely country to emigrate to. We have received some letters asking for
                        advice on the subject, of which the following is a sample:—</p>
                    <p>"Dear Sir,—There are a lot of young men down here, who are wishing to go up
                        to Egypt or in that direction. If you could advise mo through your colomns
                        as to what prospects there are likely to be you will greatly oblige.—Yours
                        faithfully, E..A. Crosbie. "Bloemfontein, Orange River Colony, April 4.”</p>
                    <p>In regard to the above, we earnestly advise these young men of the Orange
                        Free State to refrain from starting for Egypt without having first obtained
                        satisfactory, assurance as to the situations they will fill on arriving
                        here. To come to Egypt on the look-out for something to “turn up” may in
                        some cases turn out a successful venture. But for "a lot" of young men to
                        arrive here on the off chance of finding appointments will only lead to
                        disappointments.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ECLIPSE IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>Arrangements are being set on foot which ure of interest to Egypt by the
                        British Astronomical Association, towards making complete and accurate
                        observations of the solar eclipse, which is due. b about four mouths' time.
                        At the monthly meeting of tho association Mr. A.CD. Crommelin, the presi-
                        dent, intimated to its members that if was imperative that every class of
                        observation should be taken. With this end b view endea- vours are being
                        made to dispatch parties or observers to Egypt and Labrador, the object
                        being, of course, to take full advantage of the fact that this year, for the
                        first time for many, there will be a long totality, of eclipse visible in
                        these and other accessible places. As the association lacks nothing b zeal,
                        energy, and enterprise in the pursuance of both observation red research, it
                        is certain that the arrange- ments for the sending of observers to Egypt and
                        Labrador will be brought to a satisfactory completion.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UPPER EGYPT HOTELS COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>The site of the new hotel at Luxor, which this company has chosen, is on the
                        right side of the Nile, at the end of Luxor village, com- manding a lovely
                        view of the Theban moun- tains and of the river. Building operations are to
                        be commended at once. The architectural designs have already been made, and
                        it is expected that the hotel will be ready for the reception of visitors by
                        October, 1906. It will contain 250 rooms and will accommodate 280 people. </p>
                    <p>The construction of a new wing to the Cataract Hotel at Assouan has already
                        been commenced. This wing will accommodate 75 visitors.</p>
                    <p>The Grand Hotel at Assouan is also being enlarged this year and rooms for 75
                        tourists are to be provided.</p>
                    <p>A number of improvements are also to be made at the Savoy Hotel on
                        Elephantine Island.</p>
                    <p>The hall at the Cataract Hotel is to be greatly enlarged so as to give ample
                        space for the 350. visitors which the hotel will accom- modate under its new
                        management. Already a great number of tourists have ordered apart- ments at
                        the hotels at Assouan and Luxor for next season, as this season it was most
                        difficult to find rooms and habitues of Upper Egypt have therefore
                        determined to be betimes in their orders for the coming season. The
                        financial position of the company is considered to be very satisfactory, as
                        all its properties are bound to rise in value, and the board of di- rectors
                        is so strong that the greatest confidence is felt in their management</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Asiatic Prince” left London on Sunday last with passengers and
                        general cargo for Malta and Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>TYROL- Weissenstein Castle 341 ft. First-class private hotel near
                        Windisch-Matrei; Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieste). Good
                        mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing, best June and September.
                        Prospectuses and Pho- tographs, “Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RETURN OF THE MAHMAL. ARRIVAL AT SUEZ. (FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</head>
                    <p>Suez, Tuesday. The Mahmal arrived at Suez this morning by the Khedivial Mail
                        liner "Rahmanieh, and last year’s Holy Carpet was landed at the docks in the
                        forenoon.</p>
                    <p>At four o’clock this afternoon the usual pro- cession took place through the
                        principal street of Suez, accompanied by infantry, cavalry artillery, the
                        military band, etc., and pre sen ted a remarkable aspect. Towards evening;
                        the Mahmal was placed in a special train which will leave for Cairo at 9
                        o’clock. Large numbers of Egyptian pilgrims arrive) yesterday by the
                        Khedivial steamers "Mariout” and “Missir,” of whom the majority left in the
                        evening by a special pilgrim train, thus bring- ing to an end the pilgrim
                        season.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOHAMED ALY CENTENARY.</head>
                    <p>Prince Said Halim and other members of the Khedivial Family have decided to
                        commemorate the centenary of the founder of the dynasty by opening a
                        subscription for sending ten young Egyptians to complete their education in
                        the Universities of Europe. The first list of sub scriptions amounts to
                        £5,000, and includes the following:—Prince Said Pasha Halim, £1,000 Prince
                        Abbas Pasha Halim, £1,000 ; Prince Haidar Bey Fazel, £500 ; Idris Bey Ragheb
                        Hassan Pasha Wassif, Youssef Pasha Talaat Omar Bey Soultan, and Medhat Bey
                        Yaghen £500 each.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SANITARY DEPARTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Dr. Charles Todd, resident bacteriologist at the Serum Institute tor cattle
                        plague Abbassieh, has been appointed bacteriologist of the 2nd class to the
                        Sanitary Department at a salary of L.E. 50 per month. Dr. Werner von Rathen
                        has been appoint- ed bacteriologist of the 3rd class— at a salary of L.E. 40
                        per month.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW ITALIAN CONSUL.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Tuesday.</dateline>
                    <p>Yesterday morning, Comte Mancinelli Scotto who, with his wife and child,
                        arrived from Alexandria during the night and took up residence in the
                        Eastern Exchange Hotel, took over his new post at the Italian Consulate This
                        gentleman relieves Comte Cassis Domi- nioni, who left to take up an
                        appointment in the diplomatic service in Innsbruck, Austria Since Comte
                        Dominioni left, over seven months ago, Comte Senni has been in charge of
                        Italian interests in this town. The new Consul brings with him an excellent
                        record, he having served his department for many years, the last few in
                        America and Europe. He speaks English and French most fluently.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW SUEZ CANAL DIRECTOR</head>
                    <p>Referring to the feet that Mr. Hughes, of I. and J. Harrison and Co., of
                        Liverpool, ha been lately offered and has accepted a seat on the board of
                        directors of the Suez Canal Com- pony, "Fairplay," in a recent article,
                        remark that it is a little strange that this gentleman is a prominent member
                        of the only shipping association in England which has no con- nection with
                        the Chamber of Shipping. The Chamber has for a length of time been at the
                        root of all the agitation for a reduction in rates on ships going through
                        the Canal and fo the appointment of a representative “tramp” owner on the
                        board. In Mr. Hughes, the Bri- tish ship-owner, it is firmly believed, will
                        be moat ably represented. He is a gentleman whose connection with one of the
                        most go- ahead firms in England is well-known, and if reductions and drastic
                        alterations are in any way possible, tip interest of the British ship owner,
                        both tramp and liner, may most safely be left in his hands.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The management of the San Stefano Casino inform is that the opening ball of
                        the season will take place on Saturday, 20th inst.</p>
                    <p>The concerts to be given by the Casin orchestra will commence on Sunday, 21st
                        inst., and will take place regularly every Tuesday Thursday, Friday, and
                        Saturday afternoon, as well as on Sunday morning and afternoon. The season
                        promises to be a gay one. A large num- ber of fetes, night fetes, balls,
                        concerts, chil- dren’s dances, etc., will be organised. Subscrip- tions for
                        the season will be P.T. 150 single and P.T. 250 family. Family subscriptions
                        indue parents and their unmarried children living under the same roof Young
                        men over 20 years of age must take out a single subscription for themselves.
                        Subscriptions are strictly personal</p>
                    <p>Subscribers are entitled to make use of the reading-room, billiard-room, and
                        the reserve portion of the verandah, and are admitted free to the casino on
                        days when a charge is made to the general public. Subscription tickets may
                        be obtained on application to the secretary.</p>
                    <p>Entrance to the card-rooms of the club exclusively reserved to members of the
                        do who are passed by the committee. These have the same advantages as
                        subscribers to the casino.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PIGMIES AT CAIRO. SIR H. JOHNSTONE'S OPINION.</head>
                    <p>In regard to the permission, sanctioned by Lord Cromer and the Foreign
                        Office, for the pigmies to leave Cairo for England, as announc- ed in our
                        issue of yesterday, it is worth noting that the humanitarian protest that
                        has been raised against Colonel Harrison's enterprise of bringng specimens
                        of the pigmy or Akka race from the African interior is met by the more than
                        sufficient reason that the little people have desired for some years past
                        for a few of their people to make the trip. And the views put forward b the
                        follow- ing conversation, coming as they do from an independent and eminent
                        authority, should correct a deal of illusion that has been generally
                        entertained concerning the project and its aims.</p>
                    <p>Sir Harry Johnstone, interviewed by a Pressman, illustrated several of his
                        points by drawing attention to a couple of water-colour sketches from his
                        own accomplished pencil. One represented a man and woman of the races in
                        question; the other a native of a neighbouring tribe of higher caste and
                        origin. The pigmies—both typical—reveal a copper- coloured tinge of skin, an
                        obesity of build possibly due to overmuch squatting, and certain negroid
                        qualities of feature — the swollen lips, spatulate nose, receding forehead
                        and half-frizzy hair. The type in the sketch alongside might rank as an
                        aristocrat not only in this region but anywhere else, by virtue of a certain
                        nobility and command in his facial expression, and a featuring not unlike
                        the faces that come to light in the mummies of his ancestral Egypt But it is
                        with the baser race that we are at present occupied, and Sir Harry Johnston
                        had some- thing to say at the outset regarding his own attitude in the
                        matter.</p>
                    <p>THE HUMANITARIAN VIEW.</p>
                    <p>"I never resented interest,” he said, "on the part of persons in England
                        whose concern is for races unable to protect themselves, as no doubt Exeter
                        Hall and all that it implies have again and again kept the British nation in
                        the right track as regards its treatment of defenceless people. At the same
                        time, the parallels advanced by those who wrote to protest against Colonel
                        Harrison’s bringing these people to England were not altogether correct. My
                        own action was quoted in having, first, stopped a German who kidnapped a
                        large number of pigmies in the Congo forest for the purpose of exhibiting
                        them in Paris and, secondly, for having sent back pigmies to their homes who
                        had come to us at their own wish in order that they should be taken to
                        England to greet England’s new King.</p>
                    <p>"With regard to the first case, the German in question was refused permission
                        by the Belgian authorities in the Congo Free State to recruit pigmies for
                        conveyance to the Paris Exhibition. In spite of this prohibition he had
                        entered the forest where these pigmies lived, had lured them to his camp by
                        small presents of trade goods, and had then suddenly kid- napped a number of
                        them whom be placed in bonds and conveyed out of the forest by devious
                        tracks until be reached British territory."</p>
                    <p>THEIR DESIRE TO SEE ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>“Did they show their gratitude?” we inquir- ed.</p>
                    <p>" Certainly. One result of my conveying these pigmies back to their own homes
                        was a much-increased interest in the white people, especially those of the
                        race that ruled in Uganda; and it is a fact that a few-months afterwards
                        several pigmies came to me at Entebbe and asked to be taken to England to
                        see the new King. At that time, however, I was in indifferent health, and
                        did not feel able to take upon myself the responsibility of conveying these
                        little people to England, looking after their health and comfort, and then
                        taking mea- sures to have them safely transported bock to their homes.</p>
                    <p>"In Colonel Harrison's case I happen to know that he has omitted no
                        formality, and that the pigmies really wish to accompany him to see what
                        England is like. About four years ago the wife of a German official in
                        German East Africa took two pigmy women back with her to Berlin, who had
                        previously been in her service in Africa, and proved very deft
                        maid-servants. They stayed about a year in Berlin, and on their return to
                        the interior of East Africa appeared to have brought back very favourable
                        accounts of the way in which pigmies were treated by white men.”</p>
                    <p>CONSIDERATIONS OF PIGMY HEALTH.</p>
                    <p>“There is no reason, of course,” we remark- ed, “why the present visit should
                        not have the same happy results.”</p>
                    <p>"No," was the reply, "but I do not think that it would be right that these
                        pigmies who have come with Colonel Harrison should be made a show of. Let
                        them spend two or three months in our country and then return to their own
                        land. If they are able to take back favor- able impressions, and, above all,
                        if their health has not suffered, then it may be time to con- aider an
                        invitation for a large number to come amongst us, as the Somalis have done,
                        and exhibit their curious and interesting dances and songs."</p>
                    <p>On this same question of health—and, after all, it is the most important
                        aspect of the question—Sir Harry Johnston forbore to say anything for fear
                        of being betrayed into pro- phecy. He remarked, however, that the pigmies
                        are hardy enough while leading a forest life, and it is only when they
                        emerge into glaring sunshine like that of Egypt that they exhibit any
                        physical weakness or discomfort. The natural retort to this is that England
                        is not likely to disturb their physical balance by sunshine in excess ; and
                        after this view on onr part. Sir Harry passed on to discuss their remarkable
                        natural powers and quickness of a apprehension. He recounted how is his
                        first <cb n="6"/> dealings with them he was at a loss for fear mouths,
                        simply because of their ignorance of any language he was acquainted with;
                        but when they set themselves to master the rudi- ments of Arabic their
                        progress was amazing.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DIPLOMATIC AND MISSIONARY ASPECTS.</head>
                    <p>“If only these pigmies are properly treated," Sir Harry continued, "and sent
                        back with good reports, it may have the most potent effect b bringing this
                        race into touch with so much civilisation as would benefit them. In this
                        respect we cannot do better than persuade the Church Missionary Society of
                        Uganda to establish a branch of their mission b pigmy- land, to do for the
                        pigmies just what it has done for the Baganda—that is to say, not to attempt
                        to turn them into coloured imitations of white people, dressed in utterly
                        unsuitable white men's clothes; but to teach them to lead healthy, happy,
                        and useful lives.</p>
                    <p>"The work of the missionaries in Uganda has been so absolutely successful
                        that it ought to serve as a model for all mission work in other parts of
                        Africa. This opinion is echoed, I may say, by every recent administrator of
                        those parts of Africa. In a way, it reminds me of the work of the French in
                        Tunis. The French have everywhere introduced law, order, safety, comfort,
                        cheapness, and celerity of transport into Tunis without disturbing one
                        particle of the picturesqueness of the country. In the same way, missionary
                        work in the Uganda Protectorate has relieved the people from a most
                        oppressive and bloodthirsty from of religion, and from an immorality which
                        was rapidly leading to depopulation. It has done more, for it has introduoed
                        just that amount of the white man’s civilisation which is suited to the
                        native of equatorial Africa; and yet, marvellous to relate, there is no cant
                        and no hypocrisy. I should strongly recommend, as the first missionary to
                        the pigmies, such a man as Mr. A. B. Fisher or Mr. Maddox, both of whom have
                        done such excellent work b approaching and rendering friendly hitherto
                        recalcitrant tribes on the western borderland of Uganda."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="navalNotes">
                    <head>NAVAL NOTES.</head><byline>(From our Correspondant).</byline>
                   <dateline>Suez, Tuesday.</dateline> <p>  Three British torpedo-sestroyers
                        arrived at Suez from Port Said last Sunday afternoon, and two more followed
                        yesterday afternoon. They all entered Port Ibrahim basin and are taking in
                        coal. The sixth destroyer is expected shortly, and then they will sail bound
                        to /?/</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OUR POET’S CORNER. BUKRA.</head>
                    <p>My friend, have you heard of the town of Yawn, On the banks of the River
                        Slow, Where booms the Wait—a-while flower fair, And the Some-time-or-other
                        scents the air, And the soft Go-easys grow </p>
                    <p>It lies in the valley of What’s-the-use, In the province of Let-her-slide ;
                        That old “tired feeling" is native there— It's the home of the listless
                        I-don't-care— Where the Put-it-offs abide.</p>
                    <p>The Put-it-offs smile when asked to pay up, And they say "Well do it
                        to-morrow” ; And so they delay from day unto day, Till death sidles up and
                        steals them away, And the creditors beg, steal, or borrow. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:id="deg-el-coce01">
                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>May.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 10 Alhambra. Italian operetta com- pany. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sat. 13 Ce’ebration of Mohamed Aly Cen- tenary.</p>
                    <p>Mustapha Rifle Range. 2nd Spoons Competition 2.30 p.m. Practice at same
                        time.</p>
                    <p>Alhambra.Children's Ball. 3.30p.m. Sun. 14 Gabbari. Pigeon Shooting. 2.30
                        p.m. Tues. 16 Behera Co.’s Offices. Extraordinary General Meeting. 3.30
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Sat 20 San StefAno Casino. Opening Ball of Season.</p>
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>May.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 10 Theatre des Nouveautés. Variety Entertainment 9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Trocadero. Variety Entertainment 9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 12 Zoological Gardens. Performance by Ghizeh Boys' Band in
                        afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Sat 13 Mohamed Aly Centenary. Grand River Fâte.</p>
                    <p>Tues. 16 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 19 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11
                        p.m.</p>
                </div></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea
                        Central position. Under English management 1.1.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate, English
                        Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern sanitation,
                        Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
