<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>William Crawford</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, JANUARY l0, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section"><head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>PORT ARTHUR.</head>
                        <head type="sub">JAPANESE NAVAL STATION.
                            SMALL GARRISON ONLY.</head>
                        <p>TOKIO, January 9.</p>
                            <p>Vice-Admiral Sibeyama will probably be placed in charge. The military administration will retain only a small garrison (Reuter.)</p>
                            <p>Port Arthur, January 9. Twelve naval Attachés have visited the town, and inspected the remains of the Fleet.
                                (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>EFFECT OF FALL IN RUSSIA.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, January 9.</p>
                        <p>The wave of popular emotion which was caused by the surrender of Port Arthur has already subsided. Christmas has created a diversion, and the people are joyously celebrating it in the theatres, music-halls, restaurants, and taverns. On the other hand, the solemn funeral services held at the Isaac and Kasau Cathedrals for the fallen at Port Arthur were poorly attended.</p>	<p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>STOESSEL'S IMPRESSIONS.</head>
                        <p>Port Arthur, January 9.</p>
                        <p>Captain Tsunoda, who took to General Stoessel the Mikado's message desiring that the garrison should be well treated, bad a long conversation with General Stoessel, who enquired where General Kuropatkin was. Captain Tsunoda replied that he was on the Sha-Ho. Stoessel was incredulous as he bad not heard of Kuropatkin since the 6th October. He was amazed on hearing that the Baltic Fleet was only at the Cape of Good Hope.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE “ANDROMEDA” INCIDENT.</head>
                        <head type="sub">A MISUNDERSTANDING.</head>
                        <p>Tokio, January 9.</p>
                        <p>The Navy Department regrets the misunderstanding in connection with the ‘‘Andromeda." The commander at Port Arthur acted in accordance with general instructions. The “Andromeda" returned to Wei-bai-wei before the message gratefully accepting the aid had arrived from Tokio.		(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE BALTIC FLEET.</head>
                        <head type="sub">THE THIRD SQUADRON.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, January 9.</p>
                        <p>The following men-of-war will leave Libau between the 28th inst. and 2nd February in order to join Admiral Rodjestvensky’s squad-dron , Battleship “ Imperator Nicholai," coast-defence ironclads “ General Admiral Araxin," “Admiral Senyavin," “Admiral Ushakoff,” and the cruiser “Vladimir Menomach.” (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>Libau, January 9.</p>
                        <p>Four battleships and a cruiser will sail on the 31st inst to join Admiral Rodjest-vensky’s squadron. 	(Havas.)</p>
                        <p>Paris, January 9.</p>
                        <p>The Temps learns from Copenhagen that Admiral Rodjestvensky will return to Malta to await the third squadron.	(Havas.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY COMMISSION.</head>
                        <head type="sub">PRESIDENT ELECTED.</head>
                        <p>Paris, January 9.</p>
                        <p>The North Sea Enquiry Commission has elected Admiral Fournier as president	(H.)</p>
                        <p>Paris, January 9.</p>
                        <p>A full meeting of the North Sea Enquiry Commission was held to day. It was decided to admit the press. Admiral Fournier was reelected president, Admiral Spaun having withdrawn in favor of him.	(Reuter.)</p>
                        <div type="item"><head>FOURTH JAPANESE LOAN.</head>
                            
                            <p>Tokio, January 9.</p>
                            <p>It is proposed to shortly float a fourth domestic war loan on the same conditions as the third one.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ADMIRAL BIENAIME’S ELECTION.</head>
                            <p>Paris, January 9.</p>
                            <p>Admiral Bienaimé has been elected by the Opposition to replace M. Syveton. He defeated the Ministerialist candidate by 1,272 votes.</p>
                            <p>(Reuter.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>FRANCE AND SIAM.</head>
                            <head type="sub">EVACUATION OF CHANTABUN VALLEY.</head>
                            <p>Bangkok, January 9.</p>
                            <p>The evacuation of the Chantabun Valley was completed yesterday.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>TRADE OF U. K.</head>
                            
                            <p>London, January 9.</p>
                            <p>The increase in the exports, mentioned on the 7th inst., is entirely due to an increase of £l0,000,000 in Lancashire goods and £2,000,000 in woollens.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>FRENCH CHAMBER.</head>
                            <p>Paris, January 9.</p>
                            <p>M. Doumer is a candidate for the presidency of the Chamber of Deputies.	(Havas.)</p></div></div>
                    <div type="section"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                        <div type="item"><p>The British Steam Yacht “ Emerald" left Alexandria harbour last night for an unknown destination.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Appointment.—Mr. Nicola G. Sabbag, 2, rue de la Gare du Caire, Alexandria, has been appointed sole agent lor Egypt lor the firm of Messrs. G. Goulet and Co., of Reims, the well-known wine-growers.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Pay of State Employes.—We hear that the Commission appointed to study the question of the pay of the Government employés will be composed of Mr. Macbeth (president), Harari Pasha, Chitty Bey, Capt. Lyons, and Mr. Brunyate.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Shepheard’s.—The date of Shepheard’s annual grand cotillon ball has been definitely fixed for Monday, 30th instant. About 400 invitations will be issued this week. To-morrow a concert will be given by the full Tsigane Band from 9 to 11 p.m. at Shepheard’s.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Suez Canal.—On the 5th and 6th inst., 31 vessels passed through the Canal, the amount paid in dues being lrs 695,333.78.	21 of the
                            ships were British 1 Austrian, 1 Russian. 1 Turkish, 3 German, 1 Dutch, 1 Danish. The total receipts from 1st to 6th inst. were lrs. 2,316,979.74.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>R. Berks.—The return of the three companies of the 2nd Battalion Royal Berkshire Regiment from Cairo to Alexandria, which had been postponed, will now take place on Thursday next. The troops will leave Abbassieh riding by a special train leaving at 9.15 a.m. and arriving at Sidi Gaber at 2.25 p.m.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>KhartoUm Garrison. — Lieut.-Colonel O. Todd, R.A.M.C, P.M.O. in Egypt, accompanied by Major F. W. Hardy, R.A.M.C, Sanitary Officer, left Cairo on the 7th inst, en route to-Khartoum, to make the annual inspection of barracks and hospital and detachment, R.A.M.C, at that station, returning on completion of the duty.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Commendable Charity.—Mr. S. Hanna, a banker of Assiout, who was on the train at time of the recent accident to the train-de-luxe, got up a subscription in Assiout in aid of the family of the assistant cook, who was killed, and has sent Mr. Tito, general manager in Egypt of the Wagons-Lits Co., a cheque for L.E. 3,616 1/4, to be handed to them in such a way as to guarantee its fair division among the widow and children.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Society Notes.—Paris, the centre of all elegance and all intellectuality, has been spreading its influence more and more in Egyptian society, and especially among the feminine public. The study of languages by the Berlitz system has also been affected. We could mention the names of several ladies of English society learning French and Italian. English, German, Greek, and Arabic are also studied by those of other nationalities. This fashion will soon spread because here pleasure is joined to usefulness. [Advt.]</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>A Fire broke out early yesterday afternoon in a shop in Toussoun-street, Alexandria. The shop contains a store of chandeliers, lamps, etc., and there was also a considerable quantity of petroleum. It is the property of Count Jacques de Zogheb and was insured for £3,000. The cause is said to be due to a petroleum engine. There was a fire at the same shop three years ago, when it was completely gutted. The shopkeeper is a local subject, of the name of William Guttman. The alarm was given at 1.50 p m. and the engine was on the spot at 1.55 p.m. Owing to the petroleum the blaze and smoke were very great and it was two hours before the Brigade completely mastered it, although eight hoses were kept continually playing.</p></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>CARLTON HOTEL.</head>
                        <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                            <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every  respect. Very moderate charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber Station.	
                            26660-26-5-005	C. AQUILINA, Propriotor.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>ENGLISH IN THE COURTS.</head>
                        <head type="sub">LORD CROMER’S PROPOSAL. THE “ENTENTE CORDIALE."</head>
                        
                        <p>The sub-commission, which has recently been studying the question of certain changes which it is proposed to introduce into the Codes now administered by the Mixed Tribunals, having partly completed its labors, the plenary Commission, which is composed of the diplomatic representatives of the Powers, met yesterday.</p>
                        <p>Lord Cromer announced that he, was about to invite the Egyptian Government to issue a circular to the Powers requesting them to agree to a proposal that English should be admitted  as one of the judicial languages recognised by the Mixed Courts, on the same footing as French, Italian, and Arabic, which are at present the only recognised judicial languages. Lord Cromer recommended the proposal to the favorable consideration of his colleagues.</p>
                        <p>M. de la Bouliniére, the French Consul-General, stated that, when the circular was received, the question would be considered in a very friendly spirit by the French Governmentp</p>
                        <p>Lord Cromer expressed his thanks for the manner id which his proposal had been received by his French colleague.</p>
                        <p>It is almost needless to dwell on the importance and necessity of the step Lord Cro-mer is about to take. When we consider the enormous preponderance of the part which the United Kingdom and her colonies play in the commerce of this country, the exclusion from the Mixed Courts of our language becomes an obvious anomaly. As long back as 1897 the committee of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt made strong representations to Lord Cromer, praying him to urge H..M..’s Government to call for the admission of English as one of the recognised languages to be employed in the Mixed Courts from the period of the renewal of their powers for another term of years in February, 1899. Lord Cromer forwarded the letter of the committee to Lord Salisbury. But the time was not yet ripe. The change is one which must be treated diplomatically, as it can only be made with the acquiescence of the fourteen Powers interested in the formation of the Tribunals, and the political status of Egypt did not admit of such a change being then entertained. This state of things has been changed, and the reform can now be undertaken without letting loose a whirlwind of petty- international jealousies.</p></div>
                    <div type="section"><head>THE KHEDIVE</head>
                        <p>In the course of Sunday's reception the Khedive received Saba Pasha, who presented his son-in-law, Mr. Joseph Nahas; Mr. Harry Russell; Sheikh Mohamed Abou Zeid, professor at the Khedivial Law School, who presented his work on personal statics; Maitre Carton de Wiart, who presented Maitre Merybach; Col. Sir Howard Vincent, etc.</p>
                        <div type="item"><head>KHEDIVE’S ACCESSION.</head>
                            <p>Sunday night’s festivities continued to a late hour, and a special performance was given at the Khedivial Opera House at which H. H. the Khedive was present. His Highness’s entry was the occasion of an enthusiastic demonstration.</p>
                            <p>On returning from the review in the afternoon H. H. the Khedive ordered H.E. Ahmed Zeki Pasha to telegraph to the Sirdar his congratulations on the fine appearance and martial bearing of the troops. An order of the day will be issued by the Sirdar giving the army the text of his Highness’s message.</p>
                            <p>To our description of the review we should like to add the fact that the Khedive personally expressed to Lewa Lord Edward Cecil Pasha, who was in command, his great satisfaction at the discipline and manoeuvring powers of the troops, and especially of the cavalry, whose riding and drill were praised on all sides.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ACCESSION DAY HONORS.</head>
                            <p>Owing to abundance of matter we have been obliged to hold over until to-morrow the publication of the Accession Day honors.
                                The Khedive has conferred the following decorations :—</p>
                            <p>Osmanieh: Grand Cordon, 1st Class. Abani Pasha, Mr. Corbett, Sir R. Wingate.</p>
                            <p>Medjidieh : Grand Cordon, 1st Class. Ibrahim Naguib Pasha, Sir E Zohrab Pasha, Mr. Mitchell Innes, Count de Vauvineux.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>JUDGE ASSESSORS.</head>
                            <p>The following gentlemen have been elected Judge-Assessors for commercial cases in the Mixed Courts at Alexandria for the present year. The numbers after each name signify the votes obtained :—</p>
                            <p>Messrs. Michel Sinadino, 110, Ambroise Zervoudachi, 110, Theocharis Cotzikas, 109, Emanuele Stross, 109, H. P. Kingham, 108. Georges Caram, 107, Henri Nahman, 106, Ambroise A. Ralli, 106, Dante Rieti, 105, Richard C. Abdy, 104, Emanuel Benachi,104, Paul Fenderl 104, Paul Hanlohser 104, Fre-deric Hess 104, Oscar Rothacker 104, Henri Bindernagel 103, Ernest Mallison 103, Luigi Stagni 103, Sidney Carver 102, Auguste Frenay 101, Louis Escoffier 100, Adolphe Stross 96, Charles Schoeller 93, Léon Schuler 64.</p></div></div>	
                    <div type="item"><p>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD,
                        ALEXANDRIA
                        8a. PER DA, WINE INCLUDED
                        22888.16.7.905</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE RUSSIAN SQUADRON.</head>
                        <head type="sub">ARRIVAL AT PORT SAID. JAPANESE GOVERNMENT’S PROTEST.</head>
                        <p>(from our own Correspondent).</p>
                        <p>Port Said, Monday, 9 p.m.</p>
                        <p>Admiral Botrovosky's squadron, from Suda Bay, consisting of four cruisers and three destroyers, will be off the port at 4 a.m. to-morrow. The vessels will be moored at buoys 6, 7, 8, and 9, and the three south berths of the rive Asie.</p>
                        <p>There are no orders yet for passing through the Canal.</p>
                            <p>No store-ships are with the fleet.</p>
                            <p>The Japanese Government has lodged a protest against the supply of provisions or fresh water, which, it will be remembered, were supplied to the last fleet</p>
                            <p>The ships will be guarded by patrol boats, as before.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head>
                        <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught are leaving Lisbon to-morrow on H.M.S. “Essex” and will arrive at Cadiz on the following day. Their itinerary afterwards will be as follows:— Leave Cadiz 12th or 13th ; arrive Gibraltar 14th, leave 17th ; arrive Algiers 18th, leave 20th ; arrive Tunis 21st, leave 22nd; arrive Alexandria 23rd. Their Royal Highnesses are expected to remain in Egypt about three weeks.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>ABOUKIR COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                        <head type="sub">11 % INTERIM DIVIDEND.</head>
                        <p>The Directors of the Aboukir Company, Limited, have resolved that out of the estimated profits for the year ending 31st December, 1904, an interim dividend be paid on ordinary shares of 10s. 10 3/4d. per share, being the balance of arrears of dividend to 31st December, 1903.</p>
                        <p>As the shares are £5, this interim dividend
                            is 11 %.	</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>HELOUAN.</head>
                            <p>The Grand Hotel, Helouan, is quite full already and there are many arrivals daily. A number of rooms bare already been booked by visitors now up the Nile. It has been arranged that the famous Bracale Orchestra will play several times at the Grand Hotel, in the afternoon on the terrace and during dinner, as well as for small dances. A beautiful open-air tent saloon has been lately erected on the terrace of the Grand and is the admiration  of all visitors.</p>
                            <p>The Bath Establishment has lately been more frequented than usual, and the famous Helouan Baths are recommended specially to people suffering from gout and rheumatism. The strong sulphur water and the massages given by the experienced masseurs and masseusses do ever so much good to all sufferers, and visitors to Egypt should not fail to pay a visit to the Bath Establishment at Helouan.</p>
                            <p>The golf links is much visited by all keen golfers, and the professional Fulford has a great deal to do in giving lessons to those desirous either of learning the royal and ancient game or becoming perfect golfers.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>ZIZINIA THEATRE.</head>
                            <head type="sub">SIBERIA.</head>
                            <p>Giordano’s opera Siberia was produced the first time in Egypt at the above theatre on Saturday evening and was not received with any very great demonstration of enthusiasm by the large audience present. This is scarcely to be wondered at when the peculiarly depressing nature of the drama is taken into consideration. Two acts of Siberian penal settlements and chains are scarcely calculated to make the ordinary theatre-goer feel particularly lively or demonstrative. Certain passages in the music remind one of Germania and the effects arrived at are occasionally somewhat similar. The opera, however, requires a second bearing to fully appreciate the ideas intended to be conveyed by the composer. That the work is a very meritorious one is without question. The orchestra on many occasions absolutely drowned the voices of the artistes, who did their best, if the expression may be so used, to make themselves heard above the crash and din of drums, brass, and cymbals. Signorina Amelia Pinto was in splendid voice and gave an admirable interpretation of the exceedingly trying role of Stephana, being rewarded with several handsome bouquets. Signor Giraud gave a fairly good rendering of the part of Vassili, but bis voice is not sufficiently robust to stand him in good stead in an opera like Siberia. As Gleby, Signor Nani made a good impression, and gave, as he always does, an excellent interpretation of the character. Sig. Tisci Ru-bini and the other artistes were equally good in their respective roles. The choruses were particularly well rendered, and both male and female members of the chorus entered fully into their supposed miserable lot in life. The staging was excellent, and the costuming perfect in every way.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                            <p>The Moss liner "Rameses" arrived at Liverpool yesterday morning.</p>
                            <p>The S.S. "Asiatic Prince" arrived at Manchester from Alexandria on Sunday Last.</p>
                            <p>The S.S. "Grecian Prince" left Manchester
                                on Monday, with passengers and general cargo, for Malta and Alexandria.</p></div>
                        <div type="section"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                            <div type="item"><p>H.H. Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoun and General Ahmed Pasha Djelal-ed-din are expected  back from up-river next Thursday..</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Sir William Garstin will probably return from the Sudan on the 16th inst..</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Our Edfou correspondent writes: — The P. W. D. steamer “Dendara' arrived at Edfou on Saturday with the following party on board: Mr. Vincent Corbett, the Financial Adviser, and Mrs. Corbett, Mr. Anthony, of the State Lands Dept, Mr. Richmond, of the Tanzim, and Mr. Quibell, of the Antiquities Dept., who disembarked in order to pay a visit to this interesting village. They were cordially received and accompanied by the Mamour and other principal officials to the great Temple of Horus, where they passed a pleasant hour. They climbed to the top of the tower, where they bad a charming view of the valley at sunset They afterwards returned to the steamer, where they spent the night, and at peep of day they set off for a visit to Kom-Ombo whence they will go on to Assouan.</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>We hear that Mr. MacGillivray, of the National Bank, leaves this week for Mombasa to enjoy three weeks’ big-game shooting in Somaliland..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>M. and Mme. Pierre Lebaudy, of Paris, with a big party, including M. Luzarche d'Azoy and Comte de Morsey, arrived at the Savoy Hotel yesterday..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>Leave of absence in extension, for the recovery of his health, has been granted to Major B. W. Longhurst, R.A.M.C., from 14th inst. to July 13..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>Mr. H. Scott-Leslie, the well-known entertainer, has arrived at Alexandria and intends giving a few recitals here..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>The following passengers left Cairo by  the “Amenartas" for the Nile trip yesterday :— Mr. and Mrs. R. Lemk, Capt. and Mrs. Hiltrheimer, Miss D. Garstang, Mrs. B. R. Headlam, Miss Majendie, Miss Cochran, Baron Munk, Mr. and Mrs. Otto G. Wolff, Mr. and Mrs. Schwerin, Mr. Schwerin, Jr, Mr. Fred Krumm, Mr. D. R. Perry, Mr. F. T. Dwyer, Mr. W. V. Aldridge, Major Scott Murray..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>The following passengers by the P.S. “Ama sis” leave Assiout to-day: Field Marshal Lt Ferd. and Mrs. Siedler, Mr. A. Pedro Andrade, Mr. Max Thomas, Mr. Dietrich, Dr. Max Tho-roy, Mr. George Gladstone, Mme. Emilie Tho-rey, Mme. Lisa Dieckhoff, Dr. R. Weiss, Dr. Otto Seehagen, Mrs. Rosetta Joseph, Miss Elise Joseph, Miss Joseph..</p></div>
                                <div type="item"><p>Amongst the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port-Said are Lord and Lady Emusmore, Mr. S. H. Nichols, Mr. A.W. Ellis, Col. J. Huddlestone, Mr. G. Cookson, Mr. F. E. Mason, Mr. and Mrs. A. Taylor, Mr. J. W. Clark, Mr. M. J. R. Ceclow, Mr. and Mrs. E. Batis, Mr. H. I. Greaves, Mr. and Mrs. J. Fisher, Miss Meade, Lt. Col. Sir Curzon Wyllie and Lady Wyllie, Mr. E. E. Cooner, Mr. J. O. Mullings, Mr. S. H. Nichols, Mr. H. P. Wasenkagen.</p></div></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                                <head type="sub">ARRIVALS></head>
                                <p>Per S.S. "Schleswig,” arrived yesterday :— From Marseilles. — Mr. and Mrs. Heidel-bach, Mr. J. Oppenheim, Comte B. Tyskie-wicz, Mr. and Mrs. O. E. Beer, Frau Gertrud Scheels, Frau and Frl. Godart, Mrs. Halliday  and Mrs. Rogers, Mme. de Weerth and party, Herr de Oberstlieut. v. Winning, Herr Max Trinkaus, Herr Consul E. and Fran Muller, Messrs. Henraux and Lefévre, Messrs Lewison and Miller, Herr Geo. Hammer, Mr. and Mrs. Fairchild and Miss McKelvey, Mr. Ed. Empain, Mrs. and Miss Wild, Mr. Jules Aghion, Mr. and Mrs. Rob. Plummer, Rittm. Baron Schilling, Herr and Frau Unger, Mr. and Mrs. Neville, Comte de Zogheb et famille, Consul and Frau Hory, Mr. Rogers and son, Mr. Robert Hampson, Count de Nettaucourt, Comte de Las Cases, Rev. Mr. and Mrs. Watson, Mr. Lazarche d’Azay, Herr and Frau Lenz, Herr della Riccia, Mr. N. Achillopulo, Mr. Vernon Musgrave, Mrs. Postlewhait and party, Mr. and Mrs. Degrawe, Mr. Graham. From N aples.—Mr. and Mrs. Bradles Martin, Mr. and Mrs. Henry W. Bull, Hen Dr. Kochenburger, Misses Mosman, Mrs. F. Chahoon, Mr. and Mrs. Peter McCallum. Mrs. A. Pancoast and party, Mr. J. Foulkes and party, Mr. and Mrs. Butt, Mr. and Mrs. Hurlbut, Mr. and Mrs. McClintock and maid, Mr. and Mrs. Honigmann, Famille S, Schwabacher, Mr. and Mrs. Berwin, Mrs. Kipley and Miss Davis, Ph. Ritter von Schӧller, Hen and Fr. O. Wolff, Herr and Frau A. Huckel, Herr and Fran N. Steinmeyer, Herr St. Bourgeois, Hen Sofas Madren, Herr Otto Nielsen, Misses Howell, Mrs. Hearst and party, Mr. and Mrs. Van-derpoele, Mr. Robbins, Mrs. Paxton and party, Herr Philip Schnell, Prof. Dr. and Frau Philippson, Mr. and Mrs. Calame, Herr Obit Edlez and Frau v. d. Plainitz, Herr v. Watz-dorf, and Frl. v. Watzdorf, Miss Grace Chess, Mr. V. E. Chess, Mr. and Mrs. G. Brauer..</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>WINDSOR HOTEL
                                Largest 1st class and most comfortable Hotel in Alexandria. Facing the sea, Central Position. Under English management
                                01-11-904.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>DEATH OF LOUISE MICHEL</head>
                                <p>Marseilles, January 9.</p>
                                <p>Louise Michel is dead.	(Havas.)</p>
                                <p>The remarkable woman who has just passed away, and wbo was often so prominent as a French revolutionary leader, was born at Vron- coart in 1830, and first distinguished herself by her poetical and musical talents, which were recognised and encouraged by Victor Hugo. In 1860 she opened a school in the Quartier Montmartre, Paris; and in 1870 took an active part with the revolutionary Commune, and was made prisoner; and though she eloquently defended herself before the judges, she was sentenced to transportation for life. On the amnesty to political prisoners in 1880 she returned to Paris; and, continuing to take part in Communist assemblies, she was re-imprisoned in 1883, and again in 1886. As an Anarchist, she frequently addressed Hyde Park meetings, and as an authoress she was well-known, having written many revolutionary publications and a novel entitled “The Microbes of Society.".</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>DAILY WEATHER REPORT.</head>
                                <p>
                                    —	Mu. »	Mia. s	—	Max. •fattW.
                                    u 10	7	Wed/Haifa-	15 a
                                    T-—	U	6	O-U. -Z	
                                    ■iohleefi....	10	0	Xhartma—	97
                                    •Ml Out—	-	"	Wad MeSaaL	10
                                    ——		U		
                                    fOMIOH STATIONS._________________
                                    -iwn	JIM	Cain	•	Odm
                                    —■*»	......... : m o Freeh 1« Roush
                                    IMS__________________fOOJ	Violent	11	£gv.
                                    __________VI7J	Freeh	M	Beer
                                    OMMtf---------------- JW.7	Light	If	wie,..1*
                                    PHASBB OS THB MOON. |
                                    li	UxMJnarir\Z1~.	10.il I AM LsL	Alt Si'll	*>"**■-------->.M •.*. I AM «-■»	ID pa.
                                    .	S	leg quarter----IDtalMu.	US Jua..</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>IN HIS BRITANNIC MAJESTY'S
                                CONSULAR COURT AT CAIRO.</head>
                                <head type="sub">PROBATE JURISDICTION.</head>
                                <p>In the Goods of</p>
                                <p>EDMUND KELLY DE WILTON BEY Deceased.</p>
                                <p>Pursuant to Act of Parliament 22nd and 23rd Victoria Cap. 35, Section 29,</p>
                                <p>Notice is here by given that all persons and Creditors having any claims or demands upon or against the Estate of Edmund Kelly De Wilton Bey, late of Suez, Egypt, deceased (who died at Cairo on the 25th day of March 1903, and Probate of whose Will dated the 2nd day of March 1903 was granted by the above-mentioned Court on the 19th day of February 1904 to the undersigned L. Carton De Wiart, as Attorney of Signora Georgina Paretto, the Executrix therein named) are hereby required to send particulars of their claim or demands to the undersigned on or before the 10th day of February 1905, and Notice is hereby given that after that day the Executrix will proceed to distribute the assets of the deceased having regard only to the claims of which she shall then have notice and will not be liable for the Assets or any part thereof so distributed to any person of whose debt or claim she shall not then have rereived notice.</p>
                                <p>Dated this 9th day of January 1905.</p>
                                <p>L. Carton De Wiart, Wairt,</p>
                                <p>Legal Practitioner for the Executrix.</p>
                                <p>25215 2-l.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</head>
                                <p>CAIRO.
                                    Open aU tbe year round,
                                    tlEOTRlO IIOHT. - UH. - ■OOEHtf.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><head>BECK and CO’S PILSEHEB BEER</head>
                                <p>mu io Bonn oonmmui rot qoautt. H3.—InMcr Breads new bring oflmd to Mtt-•€« of Mfaln good cantos..</p></div>
                        </div></div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

