<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
				<title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
				<editor>Logan Wills</editor>
				<principal>Will Hanley</principal>
			</titleStmt>
			<editionStmt>
				<edition>
					<date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
				</edition>
			</editionStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
				<pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<bibl>
					<title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
					<date when="1905-09-27">September 27, 1905</date>
				</bibl>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div type="page" n="1">
				<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
				<head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
				<div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="2"> </div>
			<div type="page" n="3">
				<div type="item">
					<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 27 1905.</head>
				</div>



				<div type="item">
					<head>KARLSTAD CONFERENCE. THE ARBITRATION TREATY FRONTIER NEUTRAL ZONE.</head>

					<p>Stockholm, September 26. The agreement of Karlstad confirms the terms
						published on the 24th instant. The arbitration treaty is renewable in a
						decade. A neutral zone along the frontier will be esta- blished and the
						historic portions of the fortifi- cations allowed to stand. Both countries
						appear to be satisfied. (Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS. MEETING OF OPPOSITION PARTY.</head>

					<p>Budapest, September 26. The Hungarian Opposionist parties will meet on the
						3rd of October to draft a formal reply to the Emperor. (Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. IMMINENT AGREEMENT.</head>

					<p>Paris, September 26. Following a consultation between M. Rou- vier and Prince
						von Radolin, a definite agree- ment on the Moroccan question is imminent
						To-morrow's meeting will draw up the terms of the declaration. (Havas)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>THE ZEMSTVOS CONGRESS POLITICAL FREEDOM</head>

					<p>Moscow, September 26. The Congress of the Zemstvos and Munici- palities which
						has assembled here has decided that it is possible to utilise the National
						Assembly with a view to the attainment of political freedom, and that it is
						therefore advisable that tho people take part in the elections to secure as
						many seats as possible. (Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>FINNISH REVOLUTIONARY AGITATION. STRONG MEASURES BY GOVERNMENT.</head>

					<p>St. Petersburg, September 26. Prince Obelensky, Governor of Finland, has
						informed a deputation that if the revolutionary agitation be increased the
						Government will refuse all concessions, and vigorously resort to repression.
						(Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>FINANCIAL CONTROL IN MACEDONIA. NOTE FROM THE POWERS</head>

					<p>Constantinople, September 26. The Powers have presented the Porte a note
						insisting on the establishment of foreign fi- nancial control in Macedonia,
						and informing the Sultan that the controllers will arrive in Salonika on the
						first of October. (Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>A RUSSIAN CABINET. M. WITTE AS PRESIDENT.</head>

					<p>St. Petersburg, September 26. The “Novoe Vremya" states that a Cabinet of
						which M. Witte will be President will be formed before the meeting of the
						new Parlia- ment. (Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>SUBMARINE SCARE BASELESS.</head>

					<p>Paris, September 26. The scare regarding the submarine proves to be baseless.
						(Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>KAMCRA LEAVES FOR JAPAN.</head>

					<p>New York, September 26. M. Kamura leaves for Japan to-morrow, via Vancouver.
						(Reuter)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>M. WITTE’S INTERVIEWS.</head>

					<p>Berlin, September 26. M. Witte has had prolonged interviews with M. de
						Richthofen and Count do Bulow. (H.)</p>

					<p>Berlin, September 26. M. Witte visited the German Emperor. (H.)</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>SIRDAR LEAVES FOR EGYPT.</head>
					<p>London, September 26. Sir R. Wingate leaves for Egypt to-day. (R.)</p>
				</div>


				<cb/>
				<div type="item">
					<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

					<p>The Brindisi Mail arrived at Port-Said early this morning and will be
						distributed at the G.P.O., Alexandria at nine o’clock to-night.</p>

					<p>The Val de Travers Asphalt Company has obtained the contract for the
						construction of two sheds to be erected on the platform of the Gebel Zeitoun
						station fur the Railways ad- ministration.</p>

					<p>The State Railways.-From next Sunday a new halt called Sandanhour situated
						between Toukh and Benha will be opened for passenger service only. The
						trains which stop there are shown in the time-tables coming into force on
						October 1.</p>

					<p>Cairo Medical School.—A commission has been appointed under the presidency of
						Dr. Graham, deputy director general of tho Sani-, tary Department, for the
						examination of the third and fourth year's students attending the medical
						school at Kasr-ol-Aini Hospital. These examinations will be held on Sunday
						next.</p>

					<p>Heavy Rains in the Sudan.—A telegram was received at the Sudan office
						yesterday morning announcing that the damage caused to the railway line
						between Haifa and Khar- toum by the terrontial rains of last week south of
						Berber, had been repaired and that the mails which were due inn Cairo on
						Monday would arrive there to-day.</p>

					<p>The Ramleh Season.— The delightful weather prevailing at Ramleh is still
						attract- ing many visitors. Splendid accommodation can now ho obtained at
						the beautiful Beau- Rivage Hotel which has been full up to the present.
						Meals are now served in the renowned garden, where non-residents may enjoy
						dinner or supper. This comfortable Ramleh hotel offers a most pleasant stay
						for tourists arriving from Europe before proceeding up country.</p>

					<p>Another Steamer Theft.— We understand that a well-known Alexandria resident
						lost his gold watch and chain whilst going on board the Russian steamer last
						Saturday to meet a friend. We called attention to a similar case of
						pickpocketing about a week ago, and pointed out that the customs guards
						allowed far too many roughs on board in coming steamers in the capacity of
						por- ters etc. It is to be hoped that the authorities will give their
						attention to this matter and impose the same restrictions upon Arabs of a
						low class going on board as they do upon respectable and well-known
						Europeans.</p>

					<p>San Steyano Casino.The programme of the entertainment to be given to-morrow
						after- noon, commencing at 5 o’clock at the San Stefano Casino in aid of the
						victims of the Calabrian earthquakes includes selections by the band of the
						charity schools for the children of the Customs porters, selections from
						Verdi’s operas by the Bracale orchestra, a “pavane de cendrillon” danced by
						children, a cake walk danced by Mlles. Riaz, Salama, Karem, Lusena, and
						Nahas. The entrance fee will be five piastres and, in view of the whole
						receipts being devoted to the Calabrian relief fund, subscribers will also
						be required to obtain tickets of admission.</p>

					<p>The Alcazar Parisien —The Alcazar Pa- risien music hall frequently differs
						from similar places of amusement in Cairo in providing a number of English
						items which do not fail to please the audience and probably increase it. Tho
						Gardiner-Browue troupe only left quite recently and they are now replaced by
						the three sisters Davies who made their debut last night, and at the same
						time established themselves as great favorites with the patrons of this
						music-hall). These three English artistes sing in trio, and delight the
						audience with their vivacity and original dancing. Last night they were
						loudly applaud- ed and encored several times, especially for the manner in
						which they danced the cake- walk. Miss Cissie Davies, the youngest of the
						trio, also sings solos and greatly delighted the several English soldiers
						who were present with her rendering of "British Boys," and other patriotic
						songs. A fourth member is shortly to be added to the troupe and should she
						prove to be as capable in her art as her "sisters," they will form a strong
						and excellent combination of English artistes.</p>

					<p>The Coming Season. —As the welcome season rapidly approaches Cairo becomes
						once again 'alive to the fact that a vigorous endeavour must be made to
						accord her visitors the very best possible reception and in all quarters of
						the town feverish preparations are in evidence. The hotels in particular,
						waking from their comatose state, rival one another in the excel- lence of
						their intentions and internal splendour. Foremost amongst these must be
						mentioned the old established Hotel du Nil. Luxurious as have always been
						the arrangements and management of this renowned hotel, no pains or expense
						have been spared during the past summer in endeavouring to improve the al-
						ready excellent interior and thus place the Hotel du Nil on a throughly
						up-to-date foot- ing in very respect. Apart from the elaborate repainting,
						papering, etc. which has been in progress at the Hotel du Nil we are obliged
						to drawn attention to the new arrangements that have been made in regard to
						the opening of a first class restaurant and bar ; a want which has often
						been felt. There is no doubt that this will attract all who know what good
						cooking and palatial surroundings mean. The drawing and music rooms etc.
						just opened cannot fall to draw an even greater number of guests than
						heretofore.</p>
				</div>


				<cb/>
				<div type="item">
					<head>A SCENE AT WARDIAN. RIOT NARROWLY AVERTED.</head>

					<p>Disturbances which might have culminated in serious rioting took place near
						Wardian, Alex- andria, yesterday forenoon. It appears that a body of
						labourers employed by the Ports and Lights Administration on the harbour
						works to the east of the abattoir, while engaged in laying rails for the
						transport of material were sum- moned to stop work by a number of the in-
						habitants of the quarter. The interference was caused by a number of the
						occupants of houses fronting the road on which the rails were being laid,
						who grew nervous about the safety of their houses, the founda- tions of
						which were threatened by the excava- tions of the working parties, and not
						having been informed that they would receive full compensation for any
						damage done, decided to take the law into their own hands and stop all
						work.</p>
					<p>In this they succeeded. After a slight souffle the workmen ceased their
						digging but the crowd had assumed dangerous proportions and a general affray
						seemed probable, when the acting Commandant of Police with a body of mounted
						policemen opportunely arrived on the scene and put a stop to the disturbance
						by arresting fifteen ringleaders of the mob who are now detained under
						preventive imprison- ment in the caracol. A substitute of the Parquet opened
						an enquiry at Minet el Bassal yesterday and measures have been taken to
						acquaint the inhabitants of the quarter with the fact that they will be com-
						pensated for any damage done by the laying of the rails. Work has been
						suspended to-day as a precautionary measure but will be resum- ed to-morrow
						morning if all goes well.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>

					<p>We hear that it has proved impossible to find un agricultural expert to
						replace Nourissou Bey and that Judge Tuck has therefore decided to dispense
						with a third export. M.M. Fourneron and Sampaolo are at present hard at work
						investigating the books and examining the material of the company, but it is
						not expected that they will be in a position to furnish the meeting of
						creditors to be held on the 4th prox. with anythiug like a detailed
						statement of the actual position of the Societe des Suc- reries. It is
						therefore not improbable that the meeting may be adjourned.</p>
					<p>Judge Tuck has confirmed the Hon. A. J. Davey’s position as acting manager of
						the business of the Sucreries under the control of Sir Elwin Palmer, Harari
						Pasha, and M.Deboorg, the three assessors previously appointed. Harari
						Pasha, who arrived at Cairo yesterday confered with the Hon. A. J. Davey and
						M. Naus this morning.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>MURDER IN THE FAYOUM.</head>

					<p>At about 9. p.m. on the 23rd. inst. M. Isaac Matalon, a young and promising
						agricul- tural engineer employed by Messrs. Green was killed by three shots
						fired at short range at Tarnish near Senouris in the Fayoum province. As far
						as is known revenge was the motive of the crime, the body of the victim,
						according to the accounts that have reached us, having been left unplundered
						by the murderer or murderers. At Fayoum rumours were current that an
						important landowner with whom the late M. Matalon had had certain
						differences of opinion had been arrested on suspicion of having committed,
						or aided and abetted the murder, but we understand from our corres- pondents
						that a discharged employe recently expelled from Messrs. Green’s service for
						theft is believed to be the real culprit and is being searched for by the
						police. The Mudir of the Faynum with the Commandant of Police have visited
						the scene of the crime and it is hoped that an arrest will speedily be
						effected. The late M. Matalon was considered by all who knew him to be a
						yonng man of great intelli- gence and promise and great sympathy will be
						felt for his relatives at his untimely death.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>NEWSPAPER PROSECUTIONS.</head>

					<p>The Saida Zenab Tribunal has found Ahmed Abasi and Abdullsh Roosi, joint
						proprietors of the Cairo paper "Khalag," guilty of the charge of publishing
						a malicious libel against Mo- hamed Bey Shoukri, professor at the medical
						school, and sentenced the former to one year and the latter to six months’
						imprisonment with hard labour.</p>
					<p>The case against Ahmed Fouad, editor of the “Sayeka," for libelling Sheikh
						Ali Yosef, editor of the "Moayad”, which was also set down for hearing
						before the same Tribunal on Monday has been adjourned for one week.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

					<p>The Khedivial mail steamship Minieh will leave Alexandria at 4 pm. on
						Saturday and Port Said at 4 p m. on Sunday for Beyrouth, Tripoli, Mersina,
						Alexandretta, Caiffa, and Jaffa.</p>
					<p>The S.S. Kaffir Prince left Malta on Monday with passengers and general
						cargo, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Friday.</p>
					<p>The Moss liner Seti arrived at Liverpool yesterday morning.</p>
					<p>The Moss liner Rameses sailed from Liver- pool yesterday and is due at
						Alexandria on the 10th October with passengers, mails, and general
						cargo.</p>
					<p>The Ellerman S.S. City of Cambridge sailed from Malta on Tuesday night and is
						due at Alexandria on Saturday morning with passengers, mails, and general
						cargo.</p>
				</div>


				<cb/>
				<div type="item">
					<head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID. THE CHATHAM EXPLOSION. (From our Port Suez
						Correspondent).</head>

					<p>Port Said, Tuesday. The experts met at Ras el Esh station on Tuesday morning
						to superintend the re- moval of the high explosives which had been sent for
						especially from Alexandria, where Messrs. Nobels have an enormous stock of
						the newest forms of explosive material. The train, which I believe had been
						especially ordered by the authorities to assist matters, arrived at 11 a.m.
						and the ton and a half of red dyna- mite and blasting gelatine was removed
						at once without accident, put into a special dahabieh with a house on deck,
						and carried at once to the tents arranged for its reception on the Asian
						shore.</p>
					<p>The party then proceeded accompanied by Mr. Plum, the chief electrician of
						the Canal Company, to set wires and make practical test trials of the power
						of the battery current. Mr. Harris attached small detonators in pairs to the
						wires intended to be used on Thursday and made repeated trials with the
						switches and various combinations of cells using only a few yards of
						wire,the idea being that if the detonat- ors fired easily at Ras el Esh,
						close to the batteries the power would only be required to be slightly
						augmented to fire similar detona- tors over four kilometres away. The
						required number of cells being found, the telephone wires connecting with
						Port Said were out and the power of the battery increased slightly. Mr.
						Harris then proceeded to kilometer 19 and cut the wires there, attaching to
						them a submarine cable etc. such as would be used at the actual explosion,
						and also fitted the same number of fuses. Then by a system of signals,
						evidently prepared before hand, the fuses were fired from Ras el Esh as was
						pre- viously done with the few yards of wiring at the station. Slight
						modifications, were found necessary, but finally all was found to work
						satisfactorily, and the wires and power were considered sufficient for the
						great event. The party returned to Port Said at a late hour leaving guards
						over the magazine after having once more coupled up the telephone wires,
						thus restoring communication between Port Said and the southern
						stations.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>( By Telegraph. )</head>
					<p>Cairo, Tuesday, 4.50 p.m. We have received the following official tele- gram
						from the traffic manager of the State Railways:—</p>
					<p>Lattest advices state that railway communi- cation for passengers will be
						continued as usual between Port Said and Ismailia etc., to- morrow
						(Wednesday) but that some delay may be anticipated on Thursday though to
						what extent, if any, the railway will be affected by the explosion cannot be
						foreseen.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>(From another Correspondent.) (By Telegraph).</head>
					<p>Port Said, Wednesday, 12.3 p.m. A special train containing explosives under
						the charge of Mr. Harris arrived at Ras el Esh yesterday afternoon. The
						explosives were transferred without accident to the Asiatic bank of the
						maritime canal where trials were made with a twist ( l switch) exploder. Six
						e-d fuses were fired successfully by its means from a distance of three
						miles. The power of the electric current amounted to 151 amperes 54 volts.
						Seven hundred soldiers under the command of Lord Edward Cecil have arrived
						with a hun- dred additional police. The wires will be cut to-night for a
						distance of three and a half miles. The cable will be relayed as soon as
						possible after the explosion, which will take place at 9 a m. It is not
						anticipated that the mail and train service will be greatly delayed.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>NOTICE.</head>

					<p>We have the honor to inform you that the undersigned, Mr. HENRY BARKER, who
						for upwards of 55 years has carried on business at Alexandria under the
						style of BARKER and Co., Merchants, Steam Ship and Insurance Agents has
						retired altogether from business as from this date, 25th September 1905.</p>
					<p>Mr. HENRY BARKER has transferred his business to his three Sons, HENRY EDWARD
						BARKER. GODFREY HAROLD BARKER, and CYRIL LANCELOT BARKER, who will carry it
						on in co-partnership, as from this date, under the same style of BARKER and
						CO. All outstanding accounts and contraits will be liquidated by the new
						partnership of BARKER and Co.</p>

					<p>Mr. HENRY EDWARD BARKER, who for several years past has been associated with
						his Father and who has taken an active part in the management of the
						business, will alone have the signature of the partnership.</p>
					<p>Mr. HENRY BARKER takes this oppor- tunity of thanking you for the confidence
						so long extended to him and, in bidding you farewell, commends to your kind
						consideration his Sons and Successors. 26481-1 Signed,</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item" scope="advertisement">
					<head>BECK and CO’S PILSENER BEER</head>
				</div>


				<cb/>
				<div type="item">
					<head>RAILWAY ADMINISTRATION. HISTORICAL SUMMARY.</head>

					<p>The following are some of the general conclusions of the directors in their
						report for 1904, which may be said to give a histori- cal summary of railway
						administration in Egypt. This summary gives the reader a com- prehensive
						view of the development of the Egyptian State Railways since 1877 and is of
						such importance to all who are interested in the economic history and
						progress of the country that it deserves to be reproduced in extenso. The
						following is the text:-</p>
					<p>The year 1904 was an important epoch in the history of the management of the
						Rail- ways, the Telegraphs and the Port of Alex- andria. On 28th November,
						1904, a Khedivial decree was promulgated, with the concurrence of the
						European powers concerned,under which the earnings of this administration
						cease, from 1st January, 1906, to form a guarantee for the Egyptian
						Privileged debt: and the decree under which the existing system of manage-
						ment exists was repealed. From 1st January, 1905,therefore, the receipts of
						this Administra- tion with those of other Public Departments are paid direct
						to the Ministry of Finance in place of being paid to the Commissioners of
						the Public Debt, and the Government has sole control of its expenditure. A
						further decree of 23rd March, 1905, separates the Port of Alexandria from
						the Railway and Telegraph Department, and combines it with the Ports and
						Lighthouses Administration under the Ministry of Finance, while the Railways
						and Telegraph remain a department of the Ministry of Public Works. We will
						therefore briefly describe the phases through which this Admi- nistration
						has passed.</p>
					<p>The principal decrees on which its organisa- tion has been based are as
						follows:—</p>
					<p>1— That of 18th November, 1876, which created a board of management composed
						of 5 directors, two of them British, one French, and two Egyptian: and
						provided that its receipts should be paid to the Commissioners of the Public
						Debt to defray the interest on certain loans.</p>
					<p>2— The decree of 25th December, 1879, reduced the number of Directors to
						three, one of each nationality, and provided that the British Director
						should be Chairman of the Board. Both decrees provided that the British and
						French Governments should be unofficially consulted as to the nomination of
						Directors of those nationalities respectively.</p>
					<p>3 —Finally the Law of Liquidation of 17th July, 1880, assigned the receipts
						of this ad- ministration towards payment of ;he interest in the Privileged
						debt.</p>
					<p>Since 1877, when the Board was first con- stituted, the changes in the
						financial situation of the Government and the economic develop- ment of the
						country have naturally caused great changes in the conditions of working the
						Railways. From 1877 to 1885 the expen- diture was kept at an excessively low
						figure — between 33.5% and 42.8% of the gross receipts Maintenance was
						unavoidably sacrified to the necessity of meeting the interest on the Public
						Debt. The Convention of London in 1885 re- cognised the evils to which this
						was leading and provided that 45% of the Railway receipts should be
						sanctioned for expenditure on main- tenance and working. But even this
						propor- tion proved insufficient; and when the financial position of the
						country permitted it, the Decree of 21st May, 1902, allowed of the
						proportion being increased to 55%. The proportion actually sanctioned since
						that date has been 52% in each year.</p>
					<p>Notwithstanding there progressive increases, the system of sanctioning a
						fixed proportion has always proved troublesome, for it is almost impossible
						to spend to the best ad- vantage a sum which varies from year to year
						according to the state of the crops, the state of the market, and the
						condition of trade gene- rally. As, in addition to this, the expendi- ture
						on working and maintenance was for many yean excessivelyy low, the whole
						system was at one time in an alarming condition, while the supply of rolling
						stock was altogether insufficient.</p>
					<p>Special financial measures to deal with this state of affairs were absolutely
						necessary.</p>
					<p>To provide for exceptional expenditure, the law of liquidation provided that
						the general resources of the Egyptian Treasury should meet such expenditure
						as purchase of real pro- perty, construction and equipmentof new lines,
						repurchase of lines ceded to companies, doubling lines, construction of new
						buildings, banks, platforms, and the like. In practice, such expenditure has
						frequently been charged to revenue.</p>
					<p>The special credits granted for new works have been based rather on the
						Financial con- dition of the Treasury than on the commercial development of
						the country. The total expen diture on such credits has been :— From 1877 to
						1869........... Nil „ 1890 to 1898............. 9,089,237 „ 1899 to
						1904............. 1,883,397 Total............. 3,973.114</p>

					<p>The first of these three periods was a period of stagnation for the Railways:
						they were barely able to exist During the second period, the Railway system
						was being rapidly extended, lines were constructed by this Administration
						from Kafr Shaikh to Sherbin, from Damanhour to Rahmanieh, from Shibin el-Kom
						to Ash- moun, from Fayoum to Senouris, and from Assiout to Keneh: while the
						Government arranged for the construction of a line from Keneh to Assouan, of
						which the portion from Luxor to Assouan is of a narrow gauge, and handed it
						over to this Administration to work. Its cost is not included to the figures
						given above. During both these periods, the Per- manent Way, buildings, and
						accessories of the Railways suffered severely from want of expenditure on
						maintenance, while the rolling stock was overworked and insufficient for the
						traffic. During the third period, special credits were allotted chiefly to
						compensate for the insufficient revenue expenditure of the past by putting
						the line into good working order, and increasing the rolling stock. At the
						same time, the arrangements at the more important sta- tions were improved,
						and a system of signalling suited to the increased traffic was commenced.
						Finally, the line from Cairo (Embabeh) to Wasta was doubled. In addition, an
						arrange- ment was made with the Suez Canal Company to extend the standard
						gauge Railway to Port Said, thus giving a new outlet to the east of the
						Delta, and adapting the Railway system of Lower Egypt better to the
						requirements of the country. During this last period, the econ- omic
						position of the Railways was materially altered in one respect: up to the
						end of 1900 the Railways were in a favoured position com- pared to boat
						traffic : to protect their earnings navigation dues had been imposed which
						were almost prohibitive. On 1st January, 1901, in the interest of the
						country these dues were entirely suppressed. This measure, coming at a
						moment when the prosperity of Egypt was increasing rapidly, (scarcely
						affected the Rail- way receipts which continued to increase almost without
						intermission ; it was necessary however to adjust the tariffs to the new
						condi- tions created by water competition.</p>
					<p>Much yet remains to be done before the system can be in a satisfactory state,
						especially as regards the arrangements at the principal stations, the
						construction of some necessary extensions, the doubling of certain angle
						lines, and the increase in the quantity of rolling stock. The Government,
						having resolved to expand a sum of L-E 3,000,000 on such improvements,
						desired the advice of a Commission composed of well known British Railway
						authorities before sanctioning this large expenditure. The President of this
						commission was Lord Farrer, a director of the Midland and other Railway
						Companies; be was assisted by Mr. Oliver Burv, General Manager of the Great
						Northern Major le Breton, formerly of the Royal Artillery and of the Indian
						Railway Accounts Department. </p>
					<p>After spending a portion of November and December in the country, the
						Commission submitted a report which in most respects confirmed the opinion
						of the Board as to the necessity of the expenditure proposed. A part of the
						grant was at once placed at our disposal on which a programme of works is
						now being undertaken and a large quantity of rolling stock has been
						ordered.</p>
				</div>

				<cb/>
				<div type="item">
					<head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN The Railways And Rain (From our Correspondent.)</head>
					<p>Suakin, September 90. Although the first shower of rain which fell over
						Suakin and Graham’s Point on the 16th inst. was very welcome after the
						fearfully hot and trying summer which we have passed through the rains on
						the mountains are viewed with anything bat pleasure. It has fallenn in
						torrents in those districts since the 14th inst and has done a considerable
						amount of damage to the railway, washing away some 140 rails and breaking
						the line in several places.</p>
					<p>Bimbashi Sowerby, R.E., acting director of the railways, went up by special
						train to determine the extent of the damage, and immediately on arrival he
						telegraphed for a hundred men of the railway battalion, who were sent up the
						next day. On the 17th inst the rest of the battalion were sent up but in
						spite of the large number of workers and the great activity which they an
						displaying, the line is not entirely repaired, up to the time of writ- ing.
						This unlooked for work seriously delays the joining of the two lines as all
						the officials’ attention has been turned to the work of of repair.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>THB NEW SALLOM LINE.</head>

					<p>The British steamer Den of Olgin arrived here the day before yesterday from
						London with a large consignment of material for the construction of the new
						railway line from Sallom to Port Sudan, which will be started immediately,
						and which, it is anticipated, will be completed early in November. The
						absence of the railway battalion has caused consider- able difficulty in
						getting workmen together and the assistance of the modirieh authorities had
						to be obtained before any of the natives could be prevailed upon to
						work.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>THE HADJI DAOOD LINK</head>

					<p>The Ottoman S.S. Maria of the Hadji Daood company arrived here from Suez and
						Port Sudan on the 18th inst, but left after an hour’s stay as she had no
						cargo to pick up and the Khedivial mail steamer was in har- bour. A report
						is current that the Hadji Daood steamers will shortly start calling here
						once week and will also touch at Port Sudan to pick up passengers and cargo
						for Suez.</p>
				</div>

				<div type="item">
					<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>

					<p>H.H. the Khedive will hold a reception Ras el-Tin palace on Monday next. </p>
					<p>H.E Mahmoud Pasha Sidki returned his functions at the Gonvernorat this
						morning. H.E the Governor, who is in excellent health, received the
						congratulations of the employes of the Governorat on his return.</p>

					<p>We hear that Sir William Garstin, who is returning next month, had to undergo
						a slight operation, which was performed at a private hospital with complete
						success. Sir William Garstin is now in the best of health.</p>

					<p>MM. Leroux and La Bouglise arrived at Alexandria yesterday by the Messageries
						Mari- times mail boat.</p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<div type="page" n="4"> </div>
			<div type="page" n="5"> </div>
			<div type="page" n="6"> </div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
