<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-10">October 10, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-01">July 1, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bam01">
                    <head>Bell's Asia Minor Steamship Co.</head>
                    <p>Despatch weekly a steamer with good passenger accommodation carrying Mails
                        from Alexandria to Cyrpus and the Syrian Coast and vice-versa.</p>
                    <p>For particulars of freight, passage, etc., apply to the Agent Ed. A. Minotte.
                        1099-25.2.905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-iob01">
                    <head>IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK.</head>
                    <p>CAPITAL: £10,000,000.</p>
                    <p>HEAD OFFIOE IN CONSTANTINOPLE. CHIEF AGENCIES: LONDON &amp; PARIS.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES IN ALL THE PRINCIPAL TOWNS IN TURKEY.</p>
                    <p>Agencies in Egypt : ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, &amp; PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>Advances on Merchandise and Securities in current account and for fixed
                        periods. Purchase and sale of stocks and Shares on the London and
                        Continental exchanges, letters of credit issued, valuables reoeived in safe
                        custody. Drafts, cheques and telegraphic transfers issued on the principal
                        towns of the world. Foreign exchange purchased, bills discounted, bills,
                        invoices, annuities and dividends collected and every description of banking
                        business transacted. 18-4-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jma04">
                    <p>Numbering Machines and Dating Stamps</p>
                    <p>J. Margosches</p>
                    <p>Cairo Bulac Road</p>
                    <p>Stationary Engraving and Printing Office</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-alf01">
                    <head>The IDEAL MILK FOODS for HOT CLIMATES. The 'Allenburys' Foods.</head>
                    <p>The "Allenburys" Foods give strength and Stamina, and supply all that is
                        required for the formation of firm flesh and bone. They promote perfect
                        health, and give freedom from digestive troubles and the disorders common to
                        children fed on farinaceous foods, condensed milk, or cow's milk. </p>
                    <p>ALLEN &amp; HANBURYS Ltd., LONDON, ENGLAND. </p>
                    <p>Depot in Cairo:— E. Dell Mar, 25, Août.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-dlc01">
                    <head>D C L Scotch Whisky</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt &amp; Sudan</p>
                    <p>G. G Drossos &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Late Prazzica &amp; Drossos.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria. Cairo. Port-Said and Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>1080 31-5-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jbc01">
                    <head>John B. Caffari's "Economical Stores"</head>
                    <p>Cairo and Alexandria</p>
                    <p>The Perfection of Quality and Value.</p>
                    <p>In Sterling Silver, "Welbeck" &amp; Silver Plated Goods</p>
                    <p>Provisions, Wines, Cigars, Crockery, Brushes, &amp;c., &amp;c., at</p>
                    <p>Price List on Application.</p>
                    <p>16-11-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-vdt01">
                    <head>THE VAL DE TRAVERS ASPHALTE PAVING COMPANY, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>Hamilton House, Bishopgate St Without, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>CONTRACTORS TO BRITISH WAR OFFICE</p>
                    <p>Pyrimont-Seyssel, Servas (France) Ragusa (Sicily), Guanipa, (Venezuala), Mine
                        Owners.</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN BRANCH - FIRST ASPHALT FACTORY ESTABLISHED IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Moharrem-Boy Factory, 171, Mahmoudieh Canal, Alexandria.- Office in Cairo:
                        Haret-el-Mashady (Ismailieh Quarter).</p>
                    <p>For Sales of Mastic Asphalte Blocks, Trinidad Refined Bitumen, Bricks in
                        Compressod Asphalte for Paving, Compressed Asphalte Roadways. — Contractors
                        for every description of Asphalte Works in the whole of Egypt.</p>
                    <p>25-45-14-7-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sde01">
                    <head>SUDAN DEVELOPMENT &amp; EXPLORATION COMPANY, LIMITED</head>
                    <p>KHARTOUM: CAIRO Office, Sharia Kasr-el-Nil.</p>
                    <p>TRANSPORT DEPARTMENT. Six days White Nile Tourist Trip dep. Khartoum
                        Tuesdays. Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at all Cairo Tourist
                        Agents. - Special Steamers for private charter. - Trips arranged and
                        transport of goods undertaken to all places on White and Blue Niles within
                        navigation limits.</p>
                    <p>ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT. Shipyard for construction of sternwheel steamers,
                        barges, stream, motor launches, etc. Contractors for supply and erection of
                        all classes of machinery, buildings, irrigation pumps, etc.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENTS FOR Dudbridges Oil Engines from 1 to 25 B.H.P. as supplied to
                        Sudan Government. Seamless xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-mil01">
                    <head>Milner's Safes</head>
                    <p>Sole Agents for Egypt</p>
                    <p>G. Marcus &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Large Stock Kept in</p>
                    <p>Alexandria<lb/>Rue Constantinople Maison A. N. Abet</p>
                    <p>Cairo<lb/> Hoss Issa rue Neuve</p>
                    <p>Tanta<lb/>Sharia El Alail.</p>
                    <p>17 11-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-baa01">
                    <head>BOEHME &amp; ANDERER.</head>
                    <p>NEXT DOOR TO TURF CLUB, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GREAT STOCK OF ACCOUNT BOOKS.</p>
                    <p>Speciality : Account Books made to order.</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH NEWSPAPERS &amp; MAGAZINES.</p>
                    <p>Rodgers Cutlery.</p>
                    <p>7-8-90</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah02">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria.)</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Patronized by the Elite.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber
                        Station.</p>
                    <p>21440-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cgg01">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPECIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN,</p>
                    <p>NICOLA G. SABBAG</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA, 2, Rue de la Gare du Caire</p>
                    <p>Telephone; No. 559.</p>
                    <p>24528-15-3-905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hbc01">
                    <head>HOTEL BRISTOL. CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>Full South, Electric Light, opposite Esbekieh Gardens, Large Verandahs,
                        Moderate Charges,</p>
                    <p>CHAS. BAUER, Proprietor.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel is beautifully fitted up and is in the most central part of Cairo.
                        Terms for pension fare at the rate of ten shillings a day. Special terms for
                        officers of Army of Occupation. 24,882-31-10-5</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hdi02">
                    <head>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper</head>
                    <p>Made in 70 Colors</p>
                    <p>An artistic wall covering.</p>
                    <p>This celebrated water paint is made in two qualities for Inside and Outside
                        work</p>
                    <p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
                        tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only
                        requires the addition of water to make it ready for use. It is quickly and
                        easily applied with a whitewash brush, with half the labour and at one third
                        the cost of paint. HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing to
                        the eye. It appeals alike to artistic and practical house decoration.</p>
                    <p>HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special value in hot climates. Owing to its cool,
                        pleasing colours, great weather-resisting and germ-destroying properties, it
                        lends itself to every kind of wall, wood, brick or stone coating, possessing
                        all the advantages of paint, colour- wash, and disinfectant at one third the
                        cost of oil paint. It never blisters in the hottest sun, and the fact that
                        it can be washed adds greatly to its sanitary advantages.</p>
                    <p>Supplied in Tins and Iron Kegs.</p>
                    <p>Sole Manufacturers :</p>
                    <p>SISSONS BROTHERS &amp; CO., LTD., HULL.</p>
                    <p>Stocks are held In Cairo by Frank Ratcliffe, Sanitary Contractor and
                        Engineer, Sharia Saptieh.</p>
                    <p>In Alexandria by Ramadan Youssef, Sanitary Contractor, Rue Sesostris.</p>
                    <p>General Agents: George Morris &amp; Co.. Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun01">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>A great economiser and saver of time, health, and strength.</p>
                    <p>Laundry worries went out of woman's life when Sunlight Soap came into it.</p>
                    <p>It is the purest Soap going.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sun02">
                    <head>Sunlight</head>
                    <p>WORK WELL DONE . . GIVES TIME FOR PLAY.</p>
                    <p>Hard work is not easy unless you use Sunlight Soap.</p>
                    <p>It shortens the wash-day and brings comfort.</p>
                    <p>It has the Largest Sale in the World.</p>
                    <p>Soap</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-gwy01">
                    <head>GWYNNES, Limited.</head>
                    <p>(J. &amp; H. GWYNNE, LTD., &amp; GWYNNE &amp; Co., UNITED.)</p>
                    <p>Telegrams--GWYNNE, LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Telephone--544 BANK</p>
                    <p>Codes-- ABC, 4th and 5th Editions, A1.</p>
                    <p>MORNING &amp; NEAL'S.</p>
                    <p>Trade Mark — “INVINCIBLE."</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURERS OF THE LARGEST AND MOST EFFICIENT Centrifugal Pumping Machinery
                        In the world, suitable fcr all purposes, including RECLAMATION, DRAINAGE,
                        IRRIGATION, SEWAGE WORKS, GRAVING &amp; FLOATING DOCKS, MINES, &amp; ALL
                        MANUFACTURING PURPOSES.</p>
                    <p>These Pumps can be driven by Steam, Gas, Oil, Water, Electricity, or other
                        power, for Lifts of from 1 ft. to 500ft., and from 5 to 500,000 Gallons a
                        Minute. Makers of the Mex Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Results Guaranteed.</p>
                    <p>Over 50 Years' Practical Experience.</p>
                    <p>All kinds of Pumping and Irrigation Machinery specially designed to meet
                        Egyptian requirements.</p>
                    <p>London Offices— 81, Cannon Street, London, E.C.</p>
                    <p>The British Engineering Company of Egypt, Ltd: Rue de la Gare du Caire,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Works- Hammersmith, London, W</p>
                    <p>23362-11-12-904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-rea01">
                    <head>ROYAL EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>Incorporated A. D. 1720.</p>
                    <p>Chief Office: ROYAL EXCHANGE, LONDON, E.C.</p>
                    <p>FUNDS IN HAND EXCEED £4,500,000 CLAIMS PAID £40,000,000</p>
                    <table rows="2" cols="2">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>FIRE</cell>
                            <cell>MARINE</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK.</cell>
                            <cell>ALEXANDRIA … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>CAIRO … Mr. J. B. CAFFARI</cell>
                            <cell>SUEZ … Mr. GEO. MEINECKE.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>21281-216905</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-lea01">
                    <head>Lea and Perrins' Sauce.</head>
                    <p>By Royal Warrant to His Majesty the King.</p>
                    <p>The original and genuine Worchestershire.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RUSSIAN, DISORDERS.</head>
                        <head>MUTINY SPREADING</head>
                        <head>"ODESSA BOMBARDED.</head>
                        <head>THE POTEMKIN SURRENDERS!</head>
                        <p>Sevastopol, June 30.) Four battleships, one cruiser and several torpedo
                            boats left here yesterday evening under the command of Admiral Kruger,
                            with orders to sink the "Potemkin" if she refuses to sur- render, and
                            then assist in restoring order in town. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Odessa, June 30. The "Potemkin" began to bombard the town at 11.30
                            yesterday evening. The transport "Vecha" has joined the muti- neers. The
                            central railway station has been burnt. The funeral of the sailor who
                            was shot tor presenting the petition for better food, was a great
                            popular demonstration. There was do disorder. Neither police nor troops
                            were on the route. The burnt ships include the "Satatow" of the
                            Volunteer Fleet. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Libau, June 30. The seamen here have mutinied and wrecked the barracks.
                            'The Cossacks and artillery have been called out and fighting has
                            ensued, but there are no details. (Reuter.)</p>
                        <p>ODESSA, June 30. Nii e vessels have been burned, but it is believed that
                            none of them were British. Machine guns were used to clear the streets.
                            Two more regiments have arrived. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St. Petersburg, June 30. It is reported that a mutiny has broken out at
                            Cronstadt, and that the sailors have stoned a number of officers. The
                            troops at Peterhof, where the Tsar is, have been reinforced. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Washington, June 30. The American Consul at Odessa telegraphs that the
                            fleet arrived at noon, and that the "Potemkin" surrendered without
                            firing a shot. (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Odessa, June 30. Martial law has been proclaimed. The funeral of the
                            sailor, whose death was the cause of the mutiny, took place yesterday.
                            The police did not make an appearance. Owing to the arrest of the
                            sailors, the "Potemkin" bombarded the town. The sailors were released.
                            (Harm.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE "PERES VIET" REFLOATED.</head>
                        <p>Port Arthur, June 30. The battleship "Peresviet" has been refloat ed
                            here. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY.</head>
                        <head>EARLY SETTLEMENT EXPECTED.</head>
                        <p>Paris, June 30. It is announced that M. Rouvier will hand a note to
                            Prince Radolin to-day accepting the conference, regarding Morocco.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Paris, June 30. It is expected that the Franco-German inci- dent will be
                            settled next week. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPT’S JUDICIAL REFORM.</head>
                        <p>Paris, June 30. The Chamber of Deputies has agreed to the prolongation of
                            the judicial reform in Egypt. (Havas.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EAST FINSBURY ELECTION.</head>
                        <head>LIBERAL GAIN.</head>
                        <p>London, June 30. Mr. Baker, Liberal, 2,320, Mr. Cohen, Con- servative,
                            1,552; in succession to Mr. Richards, deceased. This is a Liberal gain.
                            (Reuter.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HOME CRICKET</head>
                        <p>London, June 30. Kent beat Yorkshire by six wickets. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghb01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL BONNARD, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>2s. PER DAY. WINE INCLUDED.</p>
                    <p>22855-16.7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Anglo-American Nile Steamer</head>
                    <p>.HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:—</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA RCNIil WAREHOUSE CO. LB.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-epi01">
                    <head>ENGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA.</head>
                    <p>The best halfway home between Egypt and England is VIAREGGIO. near PISA.</p>
                    <p>Main line expresses stop. Fine woods, Sands, Sea bathing mild climate,
                        English Pension, Villa Shelly. Ever home comfort. Electric light. Modern
                        sanitation, Sunny aspect, close to sea and gardens.</p>
                    <p>1-48-31</p>
                    <p>Proprietress. English Ladies</p>
                </div>

                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Plague.-Yesterday’s bulletin records a fatal case at Port Said and
                            another at Ashmoun.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Foundling..—A lining new-born child was found yesterday in the Haret el
                            Balkatria, and was sent to the hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Public Instruction.—Mr. Dunlop will select 25 gentlemen whilst he is in
                            England to add to the staff of Government school instructors.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Course the Nile.--A credit of L.E. 6,350 has been opened for an
                            examination of the course of the Nile near the Upper Cataracts.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Crown Casino.—A variety company makes its debut this evening at the new
                            theatre which has been built at the Crown Casino, Ibrahimieb.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Esbekieh district of Cairo during
                            the night of Monday and at daylight on Tuesday will be poisoned by the
                            police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>French Comedy.— The Gonnet Levy-French comedy company arrived at
                            Alexandria this morning and opens this evening at the Eden Theatre with
                            the 3-act comedy Mme Mongodin.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Suez Canal.— 9 vessels passed through the Canal on the 28th ulto., 4 of
                            which were British, 2 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Turkish. The day’s receipts
                            were fra. 207,947.32, making the total from 1st June frs.
                            7,714,139.54.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Fatal Accident. — An Italian named Gae- tano Flatino, aged 65 years, was
                            run down by a cab in the Attarin quarter yesterday. His skull was
                            fractured and he expired within a few minutes after being conveyed to
                            the French Hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>"Under the Mosquito Net."—The notes under this title which we usually
                            publish in our Saturday’s issue will not appear during the next few
                            weeks. The concluding portion of the article entitled "The Principles of
                            Heredity" is also similarly postponed.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Shepheard’s Buildings.—A short while ago we informed the public that the
                            shops which form part of the buildings of Shepheard’s Hotel were to be
                            pulled down and larger ones erected in their place. The work of
                            destruction has already been commenced and four of the shops are being
                            rapidly demolished.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Sudan Mines.—Application has been made to the committee of the London
                            Stock Exchange to appoint a special settling day in Sudan Mines,
                            Limited—Further issue of 400 shares of £1 each, 2s 6d paid (Nos. 1 to
                            200 and 401 to 600); and 3,896 shares of £1 each, fully paid (Nos. 7,605
                            to 11,500).</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Coal Imports. — From 1st January to 29th June, 458,233 tons of coal were
                            imported into Egypt Wales sent 260,729 tons, Newcastle 87,864, Scotland
                            65,132, Yorkshire 26,876 and other places 17,632 tons.During the same
                            period of last year the imports amounted to 482,943 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Alhambra Theatre.—The excellent Italian operetta company which is holding
                            the boards of this playhouse continues to attract large audiences. This
                            evening, the company will stage Suppe’s popular operetta Donna Juanita.
                            To-morrow afternoon La Gran Via will be given with the first and second
                            acts of I Grandtieri.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Seizure of Hashish.—On Wednesday and Thursday last the Coastguards made
                            seizures of no less than 500 and 200 okes of hashish on the small
                            islands oil Agamc. It had been de- posited on the islands by the
                            smugglers while awaiting an opportunity to pass it to the shore, which
                            is so well guarded that it is now a matter of extreme difficulty to land
                            hashish. Before the transfer of the above large quantities coaid be
                            managed the Coast- guards got wind of its concealment and seized it.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Kanaan Affair.— The Native Par- quet of the Minet-el-Bassal Kism has
                            presented its report to the Gouvernorat on the Kanaan affair. We are
                            glad to hear that an enquiry has been opened on the subject, and hope
                            that it will be possible to discover who was respon- sible for the
                            extraordinary mistake made by some one in the Native Hospital who
                            ordered the burial of the corpse without a proper inquest, and noted the
                            discovery of the body of a Sudanese 1 Why not a Japanese or an Eskimo
                            ?</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>"King’s English."—A very interesting ar- ticle appeared a short time ago,
                            showing the great differences in the language, add espe- cially of
                            pronunciation, in different parts of England, and a witty allusion was
                            also mud? to. '"American English." It admitted, however, that many modem
                            Americanisms were in use in the time of Shakespeare, but the universal
                            opinion- is that there is only one English worthy 'of the nine, which is
                            "King’s English," and special care is taken to keep only to the form
                            throughout all the Berlitz Schools, [b. 2vt] .</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPEECH BY LORD CROMER. THE CONDITIONS OF EGYPT'S PROGRESS.</head>
                    <byline>(Special Cable to the Gazette.)</byline>
                    <dateline>London, June 30. </dateline>
                    <p>The Earl of Cromer has received the honorary freedom of the Skinners’
                        Company. His lord- ship, in replying to. the toast of his health, declared
                        that the Anglo French Agreement had been of unmixed benefit to all who had
                        to deal with the local affairs of Egypt and wore now relieved from the
                        constant friction and annoyance that haul marked the past. The story
                        circulated in the Press to the effect that representations had been made to
                        H.H. the Khediv as to the presence of British troops in Egypt was purely
                        mythical. Four conditions were necessary to secure the uniform progress of
                        Egypt : first, no hurry; second, that Egyptian affairs should be kept
                        outside the domain of British party politics ; third, that the utmost care
                        should be taken not to force Western ideas and exotic institutions upon the
                        Egyptian people before the country was ripe for their assimilation; fourth,
                        that Egypt should continue in the future as in the past to be governed in
                        the interests of the Egyptians themselves.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>(Reuter’s Telegram)</p>
                    <p>London, June 30. The Earl of Cromer, speaking at the banquet of the Skinners’
                        Company, dwelt upon the benefit to Egypt caused by the Anglo-French entente,
                        and the valuable co-operation of the Egyptian Government. His relations with
                        the Khediv were most satisfactory.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL</head>
                    <p>At- Thursday’s meeting of the Legislative Council, Ibrahim Effendi Abd el Al,
                        the new Fayoum delegate, was presented to the mem- bers, and the proposal
                        for the formation of an Armenian Catholic community discussed. It was •
                        finally decided to have these proposals printed and distributed among the
                        members of the Council The Coined meets again on August 1.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PUBLIC WORKS</head>
                    <p>Among varions credits that have been opened by the Ministry of Finance we
                        note the sum of LE. 11,000 for the necessary repairs to the Tewfikieh
                        School, LE. 4,750 I or the construction of new agricultural roads in Ghizeh
                        Province, LE. 1,500 for repairs to the Alexandria Mixed Court of Appeal, LFL
                        950 for the improvement of the harbour lights at the entrance to the port of
                        Alexandria, and smaller credits for the purchase of the necessary material
                        for the sinking of artesian wells in the mining districts, for the purchase
                        of pomps,and for the purchase of dog muzzles rendered necessary by the new
                        law relating to rabies.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DANGEROUS GAMINS.</head>
                    <p>We wish to call the attention of the autho- rities to the dangerous use of
                        catapults in the streets by European and Arab boys. These gapiins appear to
                        be supplied with up-to-date weapons, and samples of their ammunition which
                        we have seen look most formidable, small bolt heads and chopped iron bars
                        being the pattern most in favour. Every evening parties of boys may be seen
                        in the quieter streets, especially in the Moharrem Bay quarter, shooting at
                        the small birds whioh settle on the tamarisks planted'by the road. We
                        imagine' that the use of catapults on the public roads is forbidden, and
                        there can be no doubt about the i'legality of their nse when missiles are
                        fired into gardens with disastrous consequences to windows and grave risk to
                        the eyesight of those who happen to be in the line of fire. Even the Mohamed
                        Aly-sqnare is rendered unsafe : the windows of St Mark’s Church have
                        repeatedly been broken by stones and lamps of iron. Mr. Casimatis, of the
                        Anglo- Egyptian Bank, whom is also in charge of part of the business
                        administration of the church, has made an interesting collection of ammnni-
                        tion fired into the windows and has captured two of the culprits, whom he
                        handed over to the police—without any obvious result. This morning the bowab
                        of the church^w^s struck on the left side of the face by a stone from a !
                        catapult which infiioted a very nasty wonnd. Had the missile struck the
                        unfortunate man an inch higher he would probably have lost the sight o^one
                        eye. We hope that the autho- rities will take steps to render the repetition
                        1 ot the offence highly dangerous to the offenders.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAN STEFANO CASINO.</head>
                    <p>The following is the programme . of the Wagner concert to be given to-morrow,
                        com- mencing at 10.30 a.m. :— 1 Huldigungs Marsch. 5 Ouverture do Rienzi, 3
                        Proludo Lohengrin. 4 Entire dos dieux dana le Walhall do "l’or du Rhin." 6
                        Ouverture doe Maitre-Chantours.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Raineses" sailed yesterday afternoon for Liverpool, via
                        Malta, with pas- sengers, mails, and general cargo, including 4,247 bales
                        cotton.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bcp01">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable Firm In Cairo, Alexandria &amp; the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to</p>
                    <p>V. J. FLEURENT, Cairo</p>
                    <p>F. MICALLEF, Sole Agent, 11 Bab Midan, Alexandria</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE S.S. "ST. KILDA." CREW LANDING AT PORT SAID INTERVIEW WITH CAPTAIN.
                        HOW THE VESSEL WWAS SUNK. (From our owmn Correspondent.)</head>
                    <p>Sfiez, Friday. As I advised yon this morning by wire, I proceeded on board
                        the Russian cruiser "Dnieper" (ex "St. Petersburg") In order to interview
                        the crew of the sunken British steamer "St. Kilda," but the officer on duty
                        absolutely refused tO allow me to see any of the British offCoers, saying
                        that it was strictly forbidden. He added at the same time that they would
                        probably oe landed at Fort Said, I understand, however, that the S.S. "St.
                        Kilda" left Hongkong for Yokohama on the 4th June, with a cargo of rice,
                        cotton, and hemp, and when 40 miles out she met the Russian Cruiser
                        "Dnieper," which signalled to her to stop. A "prize crew was subsequently
                        put on board, and next- day, when the crew had been removed, the cruiser
                        sank the "St. Kilda" after firing ten shots. All the personal effects
                        belonging to the crew were lost. 41 of the Chinese crew belonging to the "St
                        Kilda" were transferred to the Dutch steamer "Flores" and landed at
                        Singapore, while the British officers were retained and brought here. It is
                        remarkable that' the "Dnieper,’’ in spite of the long voyage and the heavy
                        seas she en- countered, has the appearance of having been recently
                        drydocked. She is heavily armed with large and small machine guns, and
                        fitted with wireless apparatus. She is also flying the naval flag. J At
                        about 9.30 a.m. to-day the Russian com- mander paid an official call on the
                        commander of the British battleship "Canopus," which was duly retamed. The
                        same offcoial calls were exchanged later on between the battleship
                        "Goliath," which arrived at 10.30 a.m., and the "Dnieper." The battleship
                        "Goliath" was reported by the "Canopus" as approaching Suez at 7 a.m., >eing
                        in wireless communication with her. Finally the battleship "Canopns" entered
                        the Canal at i 1.15 this morning. * The "Goliath" left at 1.40 this
                        afternoon, and the "Dnieper" at 1.55 for Port Said, where, !, understand,
                        she will take in about 300 tons of ooal, not having taken anything at this
                        port.</p>

                    <p>(From our own Correspondent.) , Port Said, Saturday. After considerable
                        difficulties had been put in my way I at last obtained an interview with
                        Captain Jones, of the S.S. "St. Kilda." Captain Jones states that' the "St.
                        Kilda" left Hongkong on Jane 2 last. The Europ%p crew refused to proceed to
                        Japan and were lauded at Hongkong on Jane 3 and impri- soned. A Chinese crew
                        was shipped and the "St. Kilda" sailed for Yokohama on the same day. 'On
                        Jane 4 theRassian cruiper "Dnieper" stopped and.captured the "St. Kilda,"
                        putting a prize orew on board. The ships proceeded at a speed of nine knots
                        in oompany into deep water and at 6 a.m. on the 5th Jane an un- successful
                        attempt was made to sink the "St. Kilda" by means of dynamite, after the
                        crew had been taken off. The Russians then opened fire with their
                        quick-firers and sank the captured vessel with 16 4.7 inch projectiles at 10
                        a.m. The "St. Kilda" was bound from Rangoon to Yokohama with a cargo of
                        rice, cotton, and sugar. The "Dnieper" had been warned of her departure by
                        Russian agents at Hong- Jcong. After the vessel had been sank the Chinese
                        crew were put on board the S.S. "Flores," bound for Singapore. The
                        prisoners, who were thirteen in number, were well treated on the "Dnieper,"
                        being each allowed a cabin and having perfect freedom of movement abont the
                        decks. The commander of the "Dnieper"' refused to receive the visit of the
                        captain of H.M.S. •’Lancaster" this morning. The Russian cruiser carries
                        eight 4.7q.f. -guns and 27 pieces of smaller calibre ; she is bound for
                        Liban and the prisoners have received orders to disembark at Port Said
                        to-night. .</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALVAGE OF "FOYLE" PROBABLE.</head>
                    <byline>( From oui Correspondent. )</byline>
                    <p>Suez, Friday, The S.S. "Foyle" is now slightly making water in No. 2 hold,
                        and about 70 tons of rice las been thrown overboard. Owing to the fine
                        weather, disoharge is continuing satisfactorily, and up to the 24th inst.,
                        over 800 tons of dry rice, and 500 tons of damaged rice, haul been
                        discharged into lighters and landed at Perim. It is now expected that the
                        "Foyle" will be shortly refloated if the weather continues favorable. The
                        divrs report that tittle damage is visible but fear it is considerable
                        underneath the forepeak.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MISSING SUEZ TUG.</head>
                    <p>Suez, Friday. The lighters laden with rioe belonging to the German steamer
                        "Helene Riokmers" have been seen lying at anohor 20 miles south of Ras
                        Gharib^ lighthouses, but nothing has been heard of the tog. Strong northerly
                        winds prevail and a heavy sea is running in the Sum Gulf, so it is expected
                        that the tng has taken shelter.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO TO PORT SAID. MENZALEH CANAL AND NAVIGATION CO.</head>
                    <p>This new company, founded last year, hopes to inaugurate the Port Said to
                        Matarieh branch of its service across Lake Menzaleh about the middle of
                        October. The Matarieh to Damietta section will also be completed soon after,
                        dredging operations being now hastened for that purpose. The distance
                        between the former two places is some 28 kilometres, and the same distance
                        separates; Damietta from Matarieh, where the lake service works in
                        conneotion with the passenger trains of the Compagnie des Chemins de for de
                        la Basse Egygte to Mansonrah and at the latter town in coincidence with
                        those of the Sta’e Railways. c In October therefore there will be a through
                        service between Cairo and Port Said by rail- way and passenger steamer. For
                        the latter traffic there are two stern-wheelers for passen gers besides two
                        togs and six lighters for the freight traffic. All these were constructed in
                        England, brought oat in sections, and put together at Karpati, near Port
                        Sail, by the Anglo-American Nile Steamer Co., who have entered into a
                        contract to work the lines of the Menzaleh Canal and Navigation Company for
                        two years from the date of inauguration. The steamers have good
                        accommodation each for a certain number of first and second class
                        passengers, besides 15^> of the third class.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY CO.</head>
                    <p>A correspondent writes:—Apropos of acc cidents on this railway, they are of
                        almost daily occurrence now. On Friday last the Nesleh engine broke down as
                        it was about to leave for Fayoum ; another engine was sent, bat never
                        reached its destination, and as no other was available passengers and train
                        had necessarily to wait until one of the other branch trains arrived at
                        Fayoum, when -that engine was sent and succeeded in returning home with its
                        unfortunate com- panions "hoars late." The Shawashna train on the same day
                        was never seen at Fayoum. A few days ago a funeral party ordered a "special"
                        for 3 p.m. for Daire el Azab; they arrived and had to sit in the train in
                        the broiling afternoon sun until 5.30 p.m., when the engine from Lahoon took
                        the train. No other was available. Last year the traffic receipts were
                        published pretty regularly and always showed an increase. It would interest
                        many to know' why they are now suppressed, as LE. 300 a month will not cover
                        the decrease of receipts, and from what can be gathered it is likely to be
                        still more. It really is time the public were better served and these
                        directors were stopped Splaying at railways," for I am told that the native
                        who is "running the show" at the moment, seising the moment'of chaos,
                        actually threatened to resign "playing at puff puffs" unless he got more
                        pay, and, in the face of this large and continued decrease of receipts, I
                        hear he 4So have an increase of P.T. 200, so that the fiuce may continue—
                        "Great Soot 1"</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"TROTTER EGYPTIEN."</head>
                        <p>The following is the programme of the fourth day’s racing at the
                            Hippodrome, Round Point, which takes place on the 22nd inst:— Prix de
                            Hadra.—P.T. 700 (400 200 100). Pour chevaux ambleurs (Rahouan) atteles
                            on months. Eprenve nniqne—4 tours de piste 2364 metres—Entree P.T. 50.
                            Egyptian Maiden.—P.T. 6.000 (3.000-1.500- 1.000-500—Poor ohevaux arabes
                            et indigenes mf Jen (qni n’ont jamais gagne de premier prix)—En denx
                            dpreuvee 3 tonrs de piste 1784 metres. Entree P.T. 500—(Cette conrse am*
                            lien s’il y a an moins 6 engagements). Prix de la Promenade.—P.T. 300 de
                            Sweep- stakes. Poor cbevanx de la m®me dearie attelei en paire A des
                            voitnres americaines A qnatre rones caontchontdes. Pour ohevanx de tons
                            pays. Seront exolns lea trottenrs de conrse. Le.ler reoevra an objet
                            d’art et le 65% sur les entrdss. Le 2me le 35%— Eprenve nniqne.—Distance
                            4 tours de piste 2364 mdtres. Grand Handicap International. — P.T. 5.000
                            (3.000 1.000 700 300) En 2 eprenves— Pour tons chcvaux de Ire, 2me, 3me,
                            4rre classe avec rendementi de distanoe anivant la vitesse opnstatde en
                            Egypte. Les ohevanx qni n’ont pas de vitesse constatde partiront
                            scratch. Distance 3 tours de piste 1.780 m. minimum. Entree P.T. 300.
                            Conditions G£n£rales.—Les courses sont sonmises aux rdglements da
                            Trotter Egyptian. Les inscriptions seront oloeee le 15 juillet A 4h.
                            p.m., et devront Stre adressdes avec le montant des entries an
                            Seordtaire du Trotter Egyptian, Mr. O. della Marra, Rond-Point, ex
                            Vdlodrome, Alexandria</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY AND TURKEY VERSUS ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST. BY W. M.</head>
                    <p>THE DANGER (Continued.)—^ -The great line that runs tike an artery rom
                        Constantinople to Konieh is to be carried on across the Taurus to branch off
                        eastward to Bagdad and Koweit, southward to Aleppo and the Syrian system, is
                        a military line par excellence. Its two branches will one day aid the German
                        Empire to strike Britain in Aria and Afhoa. German diplomacy in Turkey has
                        never ceased to keep the question of Egypt and Arabia alive and to suggest
                        the possi- bility that a new Turkish army may day inflict on Britain the
                        Btroke of Exoatibnr, \ from whioh there is no recovery, cleaving in 1 twain
                        the Empire withont the slightest inter ference on the part of the fleet on
                        whioh England’s hopes are centred. The Turko-German Staff aima at nothing
                        less than an immediate advance on Egypt by an overwhelming Ottoman army,
                        should war unhappily break out between Germany and Great Britain after the
                        comply., 0f the Ottoman strategic tines. The snooessof the invasion would
                        involve the suppression of the Mixed regime, the substitution of a dele-
                        gate of the Soltan for our enlightened Sovereign and his British friends and
                        advisers, while the direoting power—which wonta not its position too
                        strongly -» would be the German Empire. " Delenda eat Carthago " and "
                        Unsere Zukonft liegt am Wasser" have an identical meaning in Germany. Her
                        chief continental rival has been beaten down at Mukden and Tsusima by her
                        adversary’s ally, and the Turkish. alliance. originally d— against Russia or
                        England may now be direoted exclusively against the latter. Beware, England,
                        or the day of yonr overthrow will see this ful- filment of the German dream
                        and the wings of the eagles overshadowing half the world ! Neither in the
                        Suez Canal, which a few merchantmen oould block to-morrow, nor in the
                        straits of the Dardanelles, impregnably for tified by Von der Goltz and
                        Brialmont against all the navie of the world, oan England her future foe*
                        Her influence in ^ypt^ her share in the - Sudan, her domination in the Aden
                        Protectorate, Uganda, and East Africa are doomed, and these lost, will not
                        the decay of British prestige lead to the loss of India from internal
                        causes, unless— Yes, that will be the inevitable consequence of Britain’s
                        Egyptian and Arabian policy, which has earned the frown of the Shadow of
                        Allah, unless l er people, bringing into play the foresight and sagacity
                        that , have made them great, have reoonrse to the sole Remedies that oan
                        conjure the peril. (To be continued).</p>
                </div>

                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>



                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Rev. F.'^B. N. Norman-Lee, S.O.F., and Mn. Norman-Lee are leaving on
                            the 4th inst by the P. and 0. "Egypt" for England. Mr. and Mn.
                            Norman-Lee take tins opportunity of thanking their numerous friends for
                            their kind enquiries and sympathy daring Mrs. Norman- Lee’s severe
                            illness. Mr. Norman-Lee will be away for four months and daring that
                            time his duties at Alexandria will be performed by the Rev. Arthur H.
                            Manning, acting chaplain to the Forces, who is staying at the Miramare
                            Hotel, Ramleh.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A cable from London states that Baron de Knsel Bey, manager of the
                            Egyptian Tnut and Investment, Limited, has left for Egypt viA Brindisi,
                            and iB dne at Alexandria on Wednesday next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Dr. Warpoek, medical superintendent of Ab- bassieh Asylum, left Egypt
                            yesterday for England on three months’ leave of absence.</p>
                        <p>Mr. S. G. Violate left Alexandria to-day for a short holiday in
                            Greece,</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT’S TRADE.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>COAL IMPORTS IN 1904.</head>
                    <p>(From the Journal of the British Chamber of Commerce.) </p>
                    <p>So far as Alexandria is concerned, there is very little to be said about its
                        coal trade diving the past year of 1904. One feature of relief to what
                        proved a very humdrum course of busi- ness may be seen in the increase of
                        imports by 87,044 tons, thus making 1904, by its total of 1,095,014 tons, a
                        record importing year. Prices, beyond a temporary advance (notably in Car-
                        diff quality) immediately following the out break of the Russo-Japanese war
                        (9th February 1904), evinced a gradual decline during the year and freights,
                        demonstrated a similar giv- ing way, notwithstanding the plaintive echo of
                        the shipowners’ usual warcry of "Low Freights." The highest freights
                        obtained were 6/6 from Cardiff and 6/- from Newcastle, during April and May,
                        and the lowest 4/3 and 4/7 from the respective ports during September.</p>
                    <p>No strikes at home interfered with the re- gular course of supplies, and
                        probably the only cause to overbalance the regularity of a steady trade was
                        the excessive import which from time to time was forced on the port,
                        temporarily congesting its quays, taxing the powers of the Egyptian State
                        Railways, and the loading facilities of the Nile boats, and depressing the
                        market generally.</p>
                    <p>The value, free into waggons, of Cardiff best, early Jan. 1904 was 24/-. The
                        value, free into waggons, of Newcastle best, early Jan. 1904, was 20/-. The
                        value, free into waggons, of Scotch heat, early Jan. 1904, was 19/-, and the
                        tone of the market was firm, merchants, stocks being estimared at 65,000
                        tons. At the end of Decem- ber these same qualities ruled respectively 1/-
                        9d. and I/O lower, the market being calm and stocks fully 105,000 tons,
                        irrespective of the stocks held by the Egyptian State Railway Administration
                        on their special re- served storage ground at the N. W. end of the mole.</p>
                    <p>In both quality and quantity, Cardiff takes the lead, Newcastle follows
                        second, and Scotch takes a good third ; then, in order of merit, come the
                        lower qualities of Yorkshire and Lancashire, these rival counties now vie
                        with each other as peaceful coal exporters and contributed conjointly to the
                        year’s Alex- andria market some 88,000 tons.</p>
                    <p>The competition between the counties is fairly even} the average price during
                        the year being 14/6 C. F. and I including export tax. The freight out from
                        Hull fell to as low as 4/- and never surpassed 4/9, whereas the freight from
                        Liverpool ruled at 5/- per ton. Both qualities are fairly well liked in this
                        country, probably by reason of their relative cheapness. Lancashire’s better
                        class is in- creasing in favor, and Lancashire Slack competes with Newcastle
                        Slack and finds ready purchasers among some of the lime- burning
                        community.</p>
                    <p>The total importation into Egypt during 1904 of coal, coke, and patent fuel
                        amounted to 2,£04,314 tons, Great Britain sending 2,102,455 tons, Germany
                        88,825 tons, Turkey 9,338 tons, Belgium 3.6C6 tons, and France 30 tons ;
                        total 2,204,314 tons. Neither America nor India contributed.</p>
                    <p>As compared with figures given in 1903, the supplies forwarded by rail inland
                        by the trade at Alexandria increased, during 1904, by 5,971 tons, whereas
                        the trade increased their forwarding by water inland during 1904 by 23,505
                        tons. One outcome of this increased Nile traffic has been a natural
                        assumption of independence on the part of the native boat owners, who, in
                        many cases, demand payment of their entire freight oa sailing, instead of
                        their hitherto current acceptation of two-thirds on sailing and one third on
                        arrival at destina- tion. By this latter arrangement, the current outturn at
                        destination was -manifestly guaran- teed. The native boat -owners may revert
                        to their old conditions if they can look ahead, and if they can grasp the
                        possibilities of com- petition—already started by powerful and influential
                        Nile towage companies. Of these, there are now seven, all well
                        established,owning steam barges, pontoons and tow boats, working
                        systematically under organised staffs and regular departures. These
                        advantages our native friends lack.</p>
                    <p>The towage hence to Boulac, the port of Cairo, occupies 4 to 5 days, a
                        distance of 185 miles. The native sailing boats, dependent on wind and
                        weather, and often on the caprice of the raissa, take 15 to 25 days to cover
                        the voyage vi5 the Mabmoudieh Canal to Atfeh and thence via the Nila. The
                        railway route hence to Boulac-Dacrour or to one of the goods stations of
                        Cairo iB 130 miles.</p>
                    <p>Loss by shortages so far appears incurable. Stocks ashore lose, partly, by
                        natural wastage, from 1 % to 2 %. The process of discharging from colliers
                        is always and everywhere waste- ful. The 2 % allowance for non-weighing
                        taken off the very low freights current dur- ing the year is a very bare
                        compensation. Railway transit shows a loss of from I f to 4%; whilst river
                        transit by undecked native craft requires careful watching and and
                        protective freight arrangements. The results of carriage by the Nile towage
                        companies are, so far, satisfactory—the cargo being stowed under
                        hatches.</p>
                    <p>The quantity salved horn the harbour during 1904 by the Company of Dredgers,
                        licensed by the Port Office, was declared at 984 tons 12 cwt. On this the
                        Customs levy, for a second time, the import duty, the "jetsam" being
                        "abandoned property" (when the collier leaves her discharging berth) is
                        treated as a new property for purposes of import duty when recovered by the
                        subservient and handy dred- german, licensed or otherwise. There may he a
                        difference of opinion as to whether part of a cargo being only Imported"
                        once Should be struck twice by the duty.</p>
                    <p>The trade still suffers from inadequacy of discharging berths.</p>
                    <p>Claims for demurrage are sometimes com- promised, but, during the autumnal
                        conges- tion, sums, amounting to E500, were paid in demurrage, positively
                        incurred by three Happy go-lucky consignees.</p>
                    <p>The situation is still strained and delays will occur from to time until it
                        be relieved by accommodation necessitated by the deve- loping trade of the
                        port. The Railway Admin- istration could help, matters by giving up at least
                        two thirds of their own specially reserved and at the N.W- end' of the mole,
                        capable of holding for them an unnecessary and uncalled-for stock of 30,000
                        tons, and could help further by modifying the terms on which they allow the
                        trade to accost two of 1 their specially reserved berths, say, Nos. 0 and
                        5.—The terms ruling now are that "No " ship, except those having railway
                        coal or " railways stores, shall accost Nos. 9 and 5 " without a written
                        engagement to haul off if "the berth be required by a ship consigned to the
                        Administration." — Few consignees can afford to accept such one-sided
                        conditions.</p>
                    <p>Again, on the congestion of the port, the merchants of Alexandria have been
                        told in the last report of the Financial Adviser that the "blocking was
                        partly due to their apathy in not providing sufficient lighters to land
                        their goods nor sufficient carts to carry them away." Now so far as the coal
                        merchants are concerned, they object to this charge of apathy—unless it be
                        understood to mean their point-blank refusal to invest cash in fleets of
                        lighters, which have not, during the last twenty years, earned even the
                        basis of a depredation fund, still less a fair percentage for profit.</p>
                    <p>Moreover, it is not so much the lack of lighters as the absence of
                        accommodation for their protection during rough weather and during
                        night-time, and the actual want of , quay space during crowded times where-
                        at to effect discharge, which have been 1 and still are matters of
                        complaint. These r have been over and over again pointed out to the
                        authorities since the so called improve- ments of the port A correspondent
                        wrote 1 from Alexandria on 9th October 1880 in a letter, already quoted in
                        these columns, addressed to the Liverpool Incorporated Cham- ber of Commerce
                        :—"No corner of the port has been set apart for the accommodation of the
                        lighters and there is actually no place available for the purpose."</p>
                    <p>Lighters will be imported and lighters will be built fiat enough if the
                        industry should chance to pay its way. The authorities would encourage the
                        revival of the trade were they to provide some sheltering basins to protect
                        these useful little craft and their attendant craftsmen who, a score of
                        years ago, were numbered by their hundreds.</p>
                    <p>As to the insufficiency of carts, the master carters can speak for
                        themselves, hut it may be suggested it is not the insufficiency of the
                        vehicles but rather the difficulties the employers have in using them, owing
                        to the congested state of the roads, blocked as they hare been during this
                        year by merchandise and obstructions of all sorts. The coal quay is not
                        allowed to sin in (his respect, for a clear road-way is maintained from one/
                        and of the quay to the other, and it kept open by a simple supervision which
                        appears to be lacking over the streets of Alexandria. The construction of an
                        arm, extending-from the N.W. end of the mole and pointing towards the Mex
                        Coast,is planned, so far, for four new berths. Of these long expected and
                        patiently waited for desiderata,• one berth should be ready early next
                        season and the other three early 1906. The land storing accommodation held
                        fully 105,000 tons of merchants’ coal during the busy time at the' end of
                        the year, but the close stacking, with 1 its risk of fire, caused
                        inconvenience, expense and trouble.</p>
                    <p>Generally speaking, the condition of the trade is healthy. Home supplies have
                        not been interfered with, and means of transit inland have been
                        uninterrupted. Shorter and more reasonable credits are now given. A shady
                        class of purchasers has been more or. less eliminated, and fewer bad debts
                        have been contracted. One weak feature, however, has been the uneven
                        importation—sometimes for- tuitous, but often caused through shortsight-
                        edness or sheer carelessness. It cannot be said that the total import is
                        excessive, because every ton imported finds its purchaser—but a more even
                        import would check sudden and uncalled for increase of stocks, and would
                        prevent the locking up of capital, invested in what is a deteriorating
                        merchandise.</p>
                    <p>Some six or seven years ago, an actual stock jf 30,000 tons was named ample.
                        Now, with increasing consumption, this figure may be altered to 50,000 tons,
                        and were merchants to keep this fact before them and endeavour to arrange
                        for their imports accordingly, they would lessen their expenses and their
                        risks. Competition here is always keen and not altogether undesirable. When,
                        however, it becomes wild and leads to unprofitable realisa- tions, it is
                        hard to see how legitimate traders can get a fair return for their
                        labour.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Constipation</head>
                    <p>To ensure a natural movement, of bowels, it is most important to take plenty
                        of exercise every day. Many men and women don’t do this, and they become
                        more/or less costive, sometimes going two or three days without a passage
                        from thief bowels! This is at very serious thing, not only because
                        constipation makes our food and blood impure, but because the prolonged
                        presence of waste patter in the bowels strains the muscular walls,
                        eventually paralysing them, so that instruments have to be used to remove
                        the impurities.</p>
                    <p>Those who cannot get enough exercise, or whose work is sedentary, should use
                        Doan’s Dinner Pills, which are ma.de from pure roots and herbs that act on
                        the bowels, invigorating the muscular walls, and toning up the nerves,
                        liver, stomach, and whole digestive organism. Doan’s Dinner Pills soften the
                        mass of dogging waste, preventing piles, and inflammation of the intestines
                        ; and, they cure sluggish liver, indigestion, biliousness, headache, poor
                        appetite, impoverished blood, and every symptom of liver, stomach, or bowel
                        trouble.</p>
                    <p>Doan’s Dinher Pills are for sale by all chemists and druggists at P.T. 5 a
                        box; or they may be had direct from the general agent for Egypt,. Max
                        Fischer, Hotel du Nil Street, Mousky, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>DOAN’S OINTMENT cures every form of itching skin disease — Eczema, Ringworm,
                        Itching Piles, etc. The price of Doan’s Oint- ment is P.T. 13 per pot, or
                        P.T. 71 for 6 pots. To be had of all chemists, or direct from the general
                        agent for Egypt,—Max Fischer, Hotel du Nil Street, Mousky, Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREAT SPECIAL SALE</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOR ACCOUNT OF THE</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                    <p>On Thursday, 6th July 191)5, and(following days, at 9 a.m., M. Della Torre,
                        Auctioneer, will proceed to sell by public auction, in the Ordnance-yard at
                        Kasr el Nil barracks, Cairo, a great number of article), new and old, of
                        general utility, comprising carte, char-k-banca, drays and Wagons of various
                        kind), wheels, axletrees, casks, harness and saddlery, tents, cordage,
                        sacks, blankets for men and for horses, mattresses and pillows, tanks for
                        wafer or petroleum, of iron and of copper, packing oases, boxes of various
                        kinds, tools and materials for shoeing smiths and others,a great quantity of
                        iron, leather, bronze, gunmetal, wood, oakum, etc., etc., etc!</p>
                    <p>The articles can be seen at the place of sale on the three days preceding the
                        sale from 9 to 11 a.m.</p>
                    <p>For any further information.please apply to M. Della Torre, at his saleroom,
                        Sharia Abdin, Maison V. Bittar et fik 26163-3*-3</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian Delta Light Railways Ltd.</head>

                    <head>DIVIDEND WARRANT No. 15 BEARER WARRANT COUPON No. 12.</head>
                    <p>An Interim Dividend at the rate of 2,% for the half year ended 31st March
                        1905, (subject to Income tax) on the Preference Share Capital will be
                        payable on and after the 23rd June 1905, at the National Bank of Egypt,
                        London or Cairo and Alexandria, the current rate of exchange.</p>
                    <p>beRegistered Share Dividend Warrants will at posted on the 23rd Jane.
                        26171-5-4</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVIAL MAIL STEAMSHIP</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AND GRAVING DOCK COMPANY LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>NOTICE is hereby given that the half- yearly 5^ % Cumulative Preference
                        dividend coupon No. 13 krill be paid by the Imperial Ottoman Bank,
                        Alexandria, or Messrs. Glyn Mills Carrie and Co., London, on and after June
                        30th 1905. 26167-6-6</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905 </head>
                <p>THE MOST ANCIENT TEMPLE AT THEBES. (Continued)</p>
                <p>Many new fragments of reliefs from the enclosure wall of the pyramid-hall have
                    been found this year ; especially noticeable is a fragment of a shrine with a
                    relief depicting King Meutuhetep and his wife, who would seem to have been a
                    Nubian, judging from her portrait. The portrait of the King, though small, is
                    very line. The name of a new King, Ra-kha- .... has been found, and also re*
                    mains of shrine-inscriptions of the KiDg Men- tuhetep, who bore the "Horns" name
                    Neter- hetjet. It will be remembered that on the front or eastern face of the
                    temple-platform, on either side of the ramp, there are colonnades, each
                    consisting of a double row of square columns. These colonnades, of which the
                    northern was excavated last year, the southern this season, were designed to
                    protect sculptures engraved on the facing wall of the platform. The same
                    arrangement was adopted by the architects of the neighbour-temple of Queen
                    Hatshepsu, and it is permissible to suppose that the later architects copied
                    this feature from the earlier tempi â€¢. The sculptured facing-wall, originally
                    built of large limestone blocks like those of the similar wall in the North
                    Court, is now nearly destroyed, but during the excavations we found many
                    fragments of its reliefs ; hunt- ing scenes, in which the King ^ seen chasing
                    antelopes and other big game of the desert; boats carrying soldiers or passing
                    across the river in solemn religious procession ; heaps of enemies slain by the
                    King's arrows, c. Men- tuhetep was certainly a warrior, and waged war against
                    the Semites ; the slain enemies, yellow men with pointed beards, are called in
                    an accompanying inscription Aamuâ€”i.e., no- mads of the Sinaitic peninsula. Up
                    to the present we have not found any corresponding mention of Punt or the
                    Punites, though we know that a King of this dynasty sent an expedition to that
                    laud of theT^r south. The excavation of the temple began last year with the
                    discovery, on the north side, of a court, with facing-walls of magnificent ma-
                    sonry, separating it from the temple of the XVIIth dynasty. On the opposite side
                    of the platform, the southern, we have this /ear found another court,
                    corresponding to the other one, and bounded by the southern horn of the Deir
                    el-Bahari cliffs. So that we now see that the whole width of the space within
                    the circus of cliffs was occupied by the two tem- ples, which at the time of the
                    XVIIIth dynasty the visitors coming from the Nile saw before him rising side by
                    side against the background of the cliff*. It is the aim of the Egypt
                    Exploration Fund to enable the modern visitor to see the same sight, and it is
                    qgr wish to enable him to do so as quickly^ possible. Three sides of the
                    platform have b;en laid bare ; what has to be done now is 4 to excavate the back
                    part of the temple and to ascertain how far it goes back westward towards the
                    mountain, whether it joins this directly or whether there is something between.
                    At present we can see a few columns, and remains of a building of the XVIIIth
                    dynasty ; we may discover the passage to a shrine, perhaps even the shrine and
                    rock-cut tomb of the King himself. In the Southern Court we found remains of a
                    gallery of statues which one of the Kings of the XIIth dynasty, Usertsen III.,
                    had erected in his own honor. There were at least six standing statues of black
                    granite. They pro- bably stood on the platform, and were broken and thrown down
                    into the court All have been broken off at the knees, and the lower parts of all
                    have disappeared. Four have the heads in a fairly good state of preservation,
                    except the nose. They are all alike, showing that each is a portrait. Perhaps a
                    certain difference between them might suggest that they represent the King at
                    different ages. They are very good specimens of the Royal type of the XIIth
                    dynasty, a thoroughly Egyptian type ; curiously, there is a great similarity
                    between the face of Usertsen and that of the mummy of the Princess Tua, found by
                    Mr. Theodore N. Davis in the Valley of the Kings, although she lived about a
                    thousand years later than our king. That we have a portrait of the king is also
                    shown by the fact that the statues of Usertsen III, with exactly the same face,
                    in red granite, have been found by M. Legrain at Karnak. These are also good
                    specimens of what we might call the Theban school of sculpture. This is a point
                    of view which has too often been left in the shade by the students of Egyptian
                    art. Art has too often been considered as being uniform through the whole
                    country, and its various modifications have been classified chronologically,
                    while no sufficient account has been taken of local tastes and local traditions
                    which might preserve in Egypt longer than anywhere else, owing to the
                    conservative character of the Egyptians. Later dynasties worked in the temple,
                    for instance the Ramessides of the XIXth and XXth; but it may be doubted whether
                    these kings did not do more ham than good to the construction. Siptah, who left
                    a representa- tion of himself offering to the cow of Hathor on the western face
                    of the pyramid-ban, seems Jp have been the chief later renovator,â€™in his time
                    it is evident that the temple was falling into rain, as in the North Colonnade
                    rough Ramesside graffiti are scratched upon the pillars, and subsidiary brick
                    piers were built to sustain the falling roof. The beautiful walls of large
                    limestone blocks were very soon used as quarries. But in the time ff XVIIIth
                    dynasty, and probably up to the reign of Rameaes II., it seems to have been in a
                    good state of preserva- tion. We have found a great many statues and steles,
                    more or loss fragmentary, which belong to this epoch, when the two temples of
                    Deir el-Bahari existed side by side. The monarchs of the XVIIIth dynasty seem to
                    have specially reverenced Mentuhetep, since it was from him that they derived
                    their origin. Both Amenhetep I., the second king of the dynasty, and Mentu-
                    setep were venerated as tutelary demons of the necropolis of Western Thebes,
                    Mentuhetep more especially at Deir el-Bahari, his burial place. On a small stele
                    we have representations of funerary statues of both these kings, and we have
                    found the actual statues themselves ; one of them, a great Odiride figure of
                    Amenhetep in Sandstone, painted red and white, has been brought back to England.
                    The XVIIIth dynasty representation of these actual statues is a very interesting
                    find. Two votive statues save been found of Faiser, a XIXth dynasty governor of
                    Thebes, whose tomb is known in this neighbourhood. A very beautiful trophy is a
                    cowâ€™s head in alabaster, the eyes of which were originally inlaid with lapis
                    lazuli; this is of the best possible work of the XVIIIth dynasty sculptors; it
                    no doubt belongs to one of the images of Hathor preserved in the shrine built to
                    that goddess by Hatshepsu. This hue work of Egyptian art will also be exhibited
                    in July. It will be remembered that an important result of last year's diggings,
                    from the anthro- pological point of view, was the collection of a large number
                    of small votive offerings, of the time of the XVIIIth dynasty chiefly, which lad
                    been thrown out when broken or useless ay the sacristans of the Hathor-shrine
                    into the court between the two temples, which thus became a dust heap. A large
                    number work- menâ€™s tools, hoes, baskets, c., were also found. This year no
                    further discovery of votive offer- ings is to be recorded, with the exception of
                    fragments of blue glazed faience ; but a larger number of tools has been found
                    than last year; especially worthy of mention is a small bronze graving tool,
                    mounted in a wooden handle, which was evidently intended tor cutting
                    hieroglyphs. This object has been kept at Cairo. These discoveries of
                    antiquities of a later period are interesting ; but what gives to this
                    excavation its importance is all that belongs to the XIth dynasty. Of the art
                    and architecture of this dynasty but little was known before these two last
                    seasonsâ€™ work; but now we have a more intimate knowledge than ever before of
                    the peculiar character of both, and of the per- fection of workmanship to which
                    the sculpture of this early period attained. This, the first temple yet
                    discovered of the Middle Kingdom period, and the oldest temple in Egypt of which
                    so much has been preserved, is of a character quite different from any other
                    ancient building to be seen elsewhere in the valley of the Nile. Besides,
                    history has gained from this work the name of at least one new king, possibly
                    the names of two new kings, of this dynasty. This is enough to show how import-
                    ant it is to science that this excavation should be completed as soon as
                    possible. The western end of the temple remains to be excavated. That further
                    important results will be gleaned and more interesting antiquities found, we do
                    not doubt. We commend this work to the friends of Egyptian antiquity, whose
                    monetary support could not be given for a worthier object, and we trust that the
                    Egypt Explora- tion Fund will be able to find the necessary resources for
                    completing the thorough explora- tion of the oldest temple at Thebes. In
                    conclusion, it should be said that the Egypt Exploration Fundâ€™s exhibition of
                    the temple-reliefs, statues, and other objects dis- covered this year at Deir
                    el-Bahari will be held in the rooms of the Society of Biblical Arch- eology, 37,
                    Great Russell-street, W.C., daring the month of July, by kind permission of the
                    council of that society. Edouard Naville. H. R. Hall. WANTED.â€” Good Waiters
                    for Hotel, speak- ing English and French. German preferred. Apply No. 26,198
                    "Egyptian Gazetteâ€. EGYPTIAN HOTELS A RECORD YEAR. The eighth annual general
                    meeting of the shareholders of the Egyptian Hotels, Ltd., was held on June 21 at
                    the restored offices of the company, No. 5, Lothbury, London, E.G., Lord Claud
                    Hamilton, chairman of the company, presiding. The secretary (Mr. William B.
                    Peat) read the notice convening the meeting and the auditorsâ€™ report. The
                    Chairman said : Before proceeding with the business of the meeting, I desire on
                    behalf of myself and my colleagues to express our regret at the loss of our
                    distinguished colleague, Sir Robert Herbert, whose valua- ble services we very
                    much appreciated. I think I shall not be too sanguine in assuming that the
                    results of the yearâ€™s trading, as disclosed by the report and accounts,
                    already in your hands, have met with the entire satisfaction of the
                    shareholders, and that these results fully justify the policy of the Board which
                    has been backed up by the able assist- ance rendered by Mr. Baehler, the manager
                    of the hotels. This great progress of the com- pany has followed the gradual,
                    but now finally completed, removal of the system of dual man- agement of the
                    hotels. Under this system the hoteâ€™s were managed by the Compagnie Inter-
                    ternationale des Grands Hotels from Paris, and the deadweight of management
                    expenses involv- ed by that administration render a dividend to the ordinary
                    shareholders a somewhat remote contingency. We have now got past that stage of
                    the companyâ€™s- history, and on# capacity of the present time to pay a 10 per
                    cent, dividend on our ordinary shares, and to place the equivalent of a yearâ€™s
                    preference dividend to reserve, marks a re- cord in the companyâ€™s existence. I
                    will now briefly refer to the accounts. On the credit side of the profit and
                    loss account it will be observed that the profits of the hotels for the year
                    amount to Â£39,734, or about Â£6,300 more than in the preceding year. On the
                    debit side it will be seen that a large portion of this sum has, as usual, been
                    applied in payment of the service of the debentures, which requires the setting
                    aside annually of Â£13,305. The remaining expenditure shown in the profit and
                    loss account amounts to Â£5,572. This includes Â£2,571 written off the
                    compensation for the cancella- tion of the agreement with the Compagnie
                    Internationale des Grands Hotels, and the earn of Â£80J as a final payment to
                    that com- pany under its agreement with us. We have therefore been able to
                    effect a large increase in the expenditure as compared with former years.
                    Turning to the balance-sheet, it will be seen that the sale of surplus lauds has
                    con- tinued; the amount received during the year by way of installments, or
                    otherwise, for the part chase of land is Â£2,128, and this sum has been expended
                    in the purchase of debentures which have been cancelled. Practically nothing has
                    been expended on capital account daring the year. ISMAILIA HOTEL GIVEN UP. Hotel
                    Victoria, Ismailia, the lease of which was taken over from the vendors to the
                    Egypt- ian Hotels, Ltd., has been given up on account of its being
                    unremnnerative. In recent years the traffic, which formerly made Ismailia a
                    convenient place of call; has been diverted, and it is no longer possible to
                    make the small hotel there a commercial success. It will be observed that our
                    goodwill account is gradually dimin- ishing, and the compensation pÂ«d to the
                    Compagnie Internationale des Grands Hotels, which originally amounted to
                    Â£17,997, has been reduced to Â£10,284. The directors hope that, given another
                    good year or two, they will be able to write off this last item out of profits.
                    We have sufficient oash on deposit to pay our dividend, and to more than meet aH
                    onr ourrent liabilities. As regards the liability side of the balance-sheet, I
                    have little to say. The debentures outstanding are diminishing, partly by the
                    operation of the sinking fund and partly by purchases effected with the proceeds
                    of land sales. Some legal diffi- culties connected with the title of one of our
                    hotels, of too technical a nature to explain, and which have heretofore involv-
                    ed considerable legal expenses, are now, the directors believe, within reach of
                    settle- ment, and in dealing with this they are acting under the advice of the
                    companyâ€™s solicitors and in accord with the solicitors of the trustees of the
                    debenture holders. To fill the vacancy caused by the death of Sir Robert
                    Herbert, the Board propose to recommend the election of Mr. W. B. Peat to a seat
                    on the Board, as indicated m the directorsâ€™ report. The abound- ing prosperity
                    of Egypt, and the increasing favor with which travellers regard the Valley of
                    the Nile as a holiday and health resort,have done much to improve the position
                    of our company, and to enable us to hold out to the shareholders a good prospect
                    for the future. The same causes have led to a substantial appreciation of the
                    value of our surplus lands at Ghezireh Palace. Up to the present, sales of these
                    lands have been made to the total value of Â£40,262,opt of part of the proceeds
                    of which the estate itself has been developed with roads, an ample supply of
                    water, and electric light. Negotiations have been on foot for some time to grant
                    to a local syndicate an option on the unsold portion of the estate at a price
                    which would materially enhance the prosperity of the company and expedite the
                    redemption of the debentures. EFFICIENCY OF THE HOTELS. We are informed by Mr.
                    Baehler that the hotels have been maintained in a thorough state of repair and
                    efficiency out of revenue. While Wb are much indebted to Mr. Baehler and the
                    resident directors in Cairo for their untiring efforts to place the company on a
                    dividend- paying basis, we do not fail to appreciate the value of our connection
                    with our good friends, Messrs. Thomas Cook and Son, who are so ably represented
                    on our Board by Mr. Harrison, their managing director in Egypt. I now beg i to
                    move that the directorsâ€™ report and accounts l for the year ending 80th April,
                    1905, as I submitted to the shareholders, be received and adopted TO THE WOMEN
                    OF THE UNITED STATES. Successful Home Treatment. Dr. Hartmanâ€™s Cure for Female
                    Diseases-A Generous Offer to Women. MRS. J. P. COADY, Treasurer of the Ivy Leaf
                    Club, 1,702 6th Avenue, Council Bluffs, Iowa, writes: â€œPeruna la no
                    experimental medi- cine. / have used It oft and on now for three years. At that
                    time I was cured of Irregular and painful men- struation. Since that time I have
                    taken It for Indigestion or whenever I felt overworked and In need of a tonic,
                    and I have always found that It was of great benefit to me. J am therefore
                    pleased and happy to say a word In Its praise and shall gladly Indorse It to my
                    friends. â€™â€™â€”Mrs. J. ft Coady. Miss Hattie Grace, 254 West 40th St., New
                    York, writes: â€œPerunaMhas changed me from a fretful. Irritable, nervous woman
                    Into a healthy and a happy one. Nothing seems to worry and to fret me any more.
                    Since early womanhood I suf- fered with bearing doyvh pains and nervousness. I
                    was thin and worried, but Peruna restored me. Those who knew me before cannot
                    understand the change, but I can sum It all up In the blessed word,
                    Peruna.â€â€”Hattie Grace. Mrs. Elizabeth Ferguson, No. 181 51st St., Brooklyn,
                    N. Y., President West Brooklyn Audubon Society, writes: â€œI am pleased to tell
                    what a blessing Peruna has been to me. Several years ago my constitution seemed
                    broken down and / cared little whether 1 lived or died. I bad taken so much
                    medi- cine that the sight of a bottle made me sick. I had read about Peruna
                    curing women, and I thought perhaps It would help me. I bought a bottle and
                    before It was finished / felt better. I kept on taking It, and after three
                    months' faithful use I was a well woman and able to do the work and undergo the
                    strain of younger days.â€™â€™â€”Elizabeth Ferguson. In view of the great
                    multitude of wo- men suffering from some form of female disease and yet unable
                    to find any cure, Dr. Hartman, the renowned gynecolo- gist, has announced hi*
                    willingness to direct tho treatment of as many cases as make application to him
                    during the Bummer months without charge. The treatment will be conducted by
                    correspondence. The doctor will pÂ»e- scribe all medicines, applications, hy-
                    gienic and dietary regulations necessary to complete a cure. The medicines pre-
                    scribed can be obtained at all drug stores. This offer will hold good only
                    during the summer months. Any wo- man can become a regular patient by sending a
                    written statement of her age, condition of life, history and symptoms of her
                    derangements. All cases of female diseases, Including menstrual Irregularities,
                    displacements, ulcerations, inflammations, discharges, Irritation of the
                    ovaries, tumors and dropsy of the abdomen, should apply at once and become
                    registered as regular patients. All correspondence will be held strictly
                    confidential. As is well known, Dr. Hartman Is the president of The Hartman
                    Sanitarium, an Institution which has a department devoted exclusively to the
                    treatment of female diseases. He is thus brought to see thousands of such cases
                    every year, the most of whom return to their homes to be treated by
                    correspondence. The principal remedy he relies upon in such cases Is Paruna,
                    which every woman should hive who has any affection of this kind. Those wishing
                    to become patients should address Dr. S. B. Hart- man, Columbus, Ohio, No one
                    knows better than Dr. Hart man how much the women suffer with diseases peculiar
                    to their sex. No one knows better than he does how many of them suffer with such
                    diseases. Patiently, hopefully, wearily, and often silently, they eke out a
                    miserable exist ence, year after year. No martyr In poetry or heroine id
                    romance.makes a more touching appeal to human sympathy than the woman burdened
                    with the cares of a family trying to carry the extra load of torn tormenting and
                    over present female disease. Dr. Hartman's sympathy for such is unbounded, and
                    his willingness to help them limited only to his power. Mr. B. A. Harrison
                    seconded the motion, which was unanimously agreed to without dis- cussion. The
                    Chairman then moved that a dividend of 5 per cent on the preference shares and
                    10 Ter cent on the ordinary shares for the year encling 30th April be declared;
                    Mr. Harrison seconded the. motion, whioh was adopted. The Chairman proposed that
                    Mr. E. Har- rison, one of the retiring directors, be re-elected a director of
                    the company. Mr. Baehler seconded the motion, whioh was unanimously passed. The
                    Chairman said that in the report they would have noticed that one of the
                    retiring directors was Comte Albert du Chastel. That gentleman had intimated his
                    intention of offer- ng himself for re-election; bat since the issue if the
                    report he had signified to the Board his intention of not offering himself again
                    in that capacity. A vacancy therefore existed. The Board were in negotiation
                    with a gentleman who, they thought, would serve the interest of the company by
                    occupying the position ; but rations preliminaries had to be settled Wore h^
                    could be elected, and therefore, he was going to move, at the conclusion of the
                    meeting, that this meeting be adjourned till that day week in order to give them
                    an opportunity of sleeting the gentleman in question. He now desired to move
                    that Mr. W. B. Peat be elected a director to fill the vacancy caused by the
                    death of Sir Robert Herbert. Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which was
                    adopted. The Chairman also moved that the firm of Messrs. W. B. Peat and Co. be
                    appointed secre- taries of the company. Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
                    was approved. The Chairman then moved that the fees of the directors as from 1st
                    May, 1905. be rein- stated to the amount provided by the articles of
                    associationâ€”namely Â£1,200 per annum. Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which
                    was agreed to. On the proposition of Mr. Baehler, seconded by Mr. W. B. Peat,
                    Messrs. Turquand, Youngs and Co. were appointed auditors of the com- pany. The
                    Chairman then moved that the meeting stand adjourned till 12.15 on 28th instant,
                    with a view to appointing a director in place of Comte Albert Chastel, who since
                    the issue of the report, had intimated his intention of not offering himself for
                    re-election. Mr. Harrison seconded the motion, which was agreed to. Mr. Baehler
                    moved a cordial vote of thanks to the Chairman and directors for their services
                    daring the year. Mr. W. B. Peat seconded the proposal, which was agreed to amid
                    applause. The Chairman, on behalf of the directors, returned thanks far the vote
                    thus accorded. and remarked that he was sure all were pleased at the year
                    prosperous rendition at which tho company had now arrived. The proceedings then
                    terminated.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, JULY 1, 1905 REVUE COMMERCIALS Cotons. â€” Eu
                    exprimant lâ€™espsir, samedi der- nier, que, quels qua soient Ids dvdnements en
                    Amdrique, la raoldration serait la note domi- nante chez nons, nons dtions
                    certainement k pjille liene3 de croire que lea ciroonstances anraient si tot
                    jastifid notrs fa^on de voirou pour mieux dire dâ€™apprdoier lâ€™dtat dâ€™esprit
                    et les dispositions de la spdoulation sur notre place. â€”S Rarement, bien
                    rarement,en effet, Alexandria sâ€™est montrde anssi eage et anssi ponddrde dans
                    ses agissements qnâ€™elle lâ€™a dtd cette semaine avec les nonvelles de hansse
                    si stimnlntes que nous avons ones dâ€™Amdriqne, et on ne pent que fdliciter la
                    corbeille dâ€™avoir an dviter nn de ces emballements qui Ini ont dtd si fatals
                    par le passd.' An fond, pourtant, nous ne sommes pas pen snrpris de voir que,
                    avek New-York gagnant prds de 70 points depuis low, la situation chez nons pour
                    la semaine se rdsume en nne baisse de 3/32 pour la vieille rdcolte et en nne
                    hansse de 9/32 en tout ponr le novembre, mais nous sommes aussi des premiers k
                    applandir k ce procddd des haussiers qui a consistd k considd- rer les
                    manipulations de ces derniers temps des marchds de New-York et de New-Oridanr;
                    comme excessivement malsaines et nnllement en rapport avec la rdalitd des
                    choses.â€” Dâ€™aillenrs, touts poussde des prix aurait dtd peut-dtre nne cause
                    dâ€™dloignement de la con- sommation, et, tout compte fait, il a certain nement
                    mienx vain laisser la porte onverte k lâ€™dcouâ€™emont de nos ootons, dâ€™antant
                    plus que lâ€™dcart. de k tallaris entre dgyptien et amdricain est ddji
                    snffisamment large, surtont que les perspectives ohe'z nons sont ttes brillantes
                    pour la prochaine rdcolte. La vieille rdcolte, comme on a pu le voir plus haut,
                    est en pleine ddfaveur, ce qui ddmontrerait qne les ddtentours de Juillet et
                    dâ€™Aoftt se rendent finalement compte quâ€™il nâ€™y a plus rien fi faire pour
                    eux sur ces dchdances et qnâ€™il ne 'eur reste plus qnâ€™k profiter des
                    occasions qui se prdsentent pour liquider les positions rapprochdes on pour les
                    reporter sur le Novembre. Quant au commerce, il ne se passe presqne pas de jour
                    sans quâ€™il achdte qnelqne chose en contrats Juillet et câ€™est bien Ik le
                    seule solution logique prdvue depuis longtemps ponr la vieille rdcolte, solution
                    que la husse de 1â€™Amdricain contribue dnor- mement k faciliter. La filature,
                    de eou cdtd, ne se fait pas prier et, estimant les choses k leur juste valeur,
                    continue ses achats, au point que dâ€™aucuns pensent ddjk que malgrd nos
                    disponibilitds actuellea, le stock pourrait bien, k la fin de la campagne,
                    raster infdrieur k celui de lâ€™annde dernidre an.31 Aont. Lâ€™Aoftt a dtd bien
                    moins reoharchd ces jours- ci et le report, qui dtait de 5/16, est tombd a 1/4,
                    voire mdme k 3/16 par moments. Le Novembre devient de plus en pins le champ de
                    bataille gdudral et les transactions qni sâ€™y passant pourraient bien
                    reprdsenter les sept huitidmes des affaires qui se traitent snr place. Et puis,
                    en somme, quoi de plus natnrel que de vo'r le spdoulateur jeter son ddvolu snr
                    les dchdances dloignde3, surtont lorsque la vieille rdcolte finit comme câ€™est
                    actuellement le oas, sans positions k ddcouvert ponvant se pteter k un jeu
                    quelconque. Rien de particulier nâ€™a transpird au sujet de la demande de la
                    part de la consommation; mais il serait bien dtonnant que celle-ci nâ€™aitpas
                    opdrd largement, avec la situation des amdri* cains qui est de nature - k faire
                    paraltre nos ootons bon marchd, du moins ponr les filatenrs de fin on les
                    fabricants de spdcialitds. La semaine finit ferme ponr le disponible avec nn bon
                    courant dâ€™affaires, dit le bulletin officio! de C9 jonr; k cela, nons
                    ajouterons qne la demande a dtd gdndrale ponr toutes les qualitds et qne Ie
                    marchd de Minet-el-Bassal a prdsentd beancoup dâ€™activitd avec des prix stables
                    et abeolument rdgnliers. En rdsnmd, les choses vont lenr petit train et
                    nâ€™dtait la question du choix, les transactions seraient pins importantes
                    encore. Les exportations, oette fois, ont dtd infd- rienres k celles de
                    lâ€™annde demidre ponr la semaine correspondante, mais il y a lien de ne pas
                    perdre de vne qnâ€™en 1904 ellescomprenaient nne partie dÂ°s embarquements de la
                    premidre quitizaine j uillet, tandis que cette annds-ci elles restent limitees
                    anx derniers engagements de jnin. Le marchd de Liverpool a dtd excellent poor
                    nos ootons: les ventes sâ€™y sont dlevdes k nn chiffre assez important et les
                    prix y finissent avec nne hausse de 3/16 ponr le disponible et de 16 k 17 points
                    pour lelivrable.â€”Malgrd . cela, nos ootons sont pins avantageux k acheter k
                    Liverpool, mais on dit dâ€™antre part qne las bona lots sâ€™y paient rdellement
                    plus cher qne ne le feraient croire les ootatioDS officielles donndes poor
                    qnelques olassements. Avant dâ€™en finiraveo notre marohd, signalons
                    lâ€™inportante ddcision prise par lâ€™asaenblde ex* traordinaire de
                    1â€™Alexandria Produce Associa- tion qni admet, k partir dâ€™Avril 1906, la
                    livraison contra oontrats des ba'les pressdea k vapeur, et ce moyennant nn 1/2
                    tal. de bonifica- tion et lâ€™abandon des frais de pressage k lâ€™ache-
                    tenr.â€”Cartes, oes conditions ne sont gndre favorables au veadeur, mais, somme
                    teste oelni-oi, en cas dâ€™dgorgement, a anjoardfeunee jj, El Aohou, M. Moh.
                    Bayonm, M. arme de pins ponr se ddfendre.â€”, q Price etconsort3ont beauooup
                    fait parlor dâ€™enx q oette semaine et lâ€™on se demande si Ton doit p faire cas
                    de oe qnâ€™ils disent de lâ€™avenir, on sâ€™il jj faut simplement considdrer
                    lenr propaganda ^ tdldgraphiqne comme destinde k faoiliter nn conpquâ€™ils
                    tententdeCairo avant lâ€™apparition dn j( prochain rapport da Bareaa
                    dâ€™Agrioaltare ds q Washington, attendn lnndi, soit dans deux m jours et que
                    beauconp de maisons sdrieuses p( disent devoir dtre de 81 k 83 (et non pins 71),
                    g, contre 88 lâ€™annde dernidre. Quoi quâ€™il en soit, pour le moment, oe gronpe
                    est en pleine rdus- site, mais si lâ€™on doit oroire lâ€™information q cablde
                    parun grand journal anglais, Priceserait q en train de chauffer dâ€™nn cdtd ponr
                    venire de et lâ€™autre. Pdohd Vdniel, car en somme cela ran- g trerait dans
                    lâ€™ordre naturel des choses ! ! g Graines de Coton : La faiblesm a domind jy
                    chez nons et elle est dfte anx rdalisations de jy; la petite spdonlation,
                    fatigude dâ€™attendre et g qni oraint lâ€™effet dorasant de la premidre filidre
                    M de juillet, effet qni, nne fois la premidre im- qi passion passde, pourrait
                    etre minima si, comme g on lewdit, beancoup de reports ont ddjk dtd g. faits.
                    Dans tous les oas, les petite embarque- 8t ments de la semaine nâ€™ont pas pen
                    oontribnd k -y poser sur la situation. ^ Derniers oonrs pratiqnd^r P.T. 57 1/2
                    pour , -ft le disponible et 58 3/4 pour le juillet, ce qui jy ferait ptes de
                    P.T. 1 1/2 de baisse pour la p la semaine. g Lâ€™Angleterre est,ferme et Hnll
                    offre de non- q veau Â£5. 15/- pour juillet, mais la demande g est pen
                    importante et ddoourage nn pen ! y La nonvelle rdcolte est inaotive, fante de 2
                    gros vendeura ; toutefois, comme prix, elle se a maintient trd3-bien anx
                    alentonrs de P.T. 60. Lâ€™Angleterre paierait le Novembre-Janvier Â£5. 17/6. '
                    Fives : Les arrivages vraiment mesqains de â€œ ces temps derniers ont prodait
                    nne nonvelle hansse et, anjonrdâ€™hui, la valeur de lâ€™artiole en disponible
                    est de P.T. 96. Câ€™est duorme, nwrts il y a si peu de marchandise k la vente et
                    Ton sâ€™est montd tellement la tdte avec an charge- ment venda pour le continent
                    il y a deux on trois semaines ponr embarqnement Juillet k 32/9 oif London terms,
                    que tout acheteur be30gneux nâ€™hdsite pas k surenohdrir sur son voisin pour
                    trouver ce quâ€™il lui faut. Eu contrats, par oontre, on ne fait rien et la oote
                    nâ€™est dtablie, ponr ainsi dire, que dâ€™aprds la valeur du spot. L Dernier
                    prix affichd P.T. 96 3/4 k 97. L Alexandrie, 30 Juin 1905. Â£ </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" element="passList">
                <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                <p>. k DEPARTURES. Per S.S. "Ramosesâ€ sailed from Alexandria yesterday foy
                    Liverpool, vifl Malta : â€” Miss Alderson, Mrs. J. K. Aitken, Miss Cooper, Mr.
                    Degiarddâ€™s two nurses and three ohildren, Mrs. if. Evans, Mrs. Hunter, Mr. and
                    Mrs. Mancantelli and obild, Mr. and Mrs. J. MUburn, Miss Milbum, Mr. D. N.
                    Nicol, Mrs. Parvis, Mrs. Snead, Mr. apd Mtf. C. W. Stricjslanjl and three
                    children, Mr. C. Wighton, MW. T. Parsonage anl iutanty Mrs. G. Att- wood, Serg.
                    G. Tomlinson, Mr. and Mrs^Snajth and child, Mrs. Smithâ€™s child, Mrs. G.., Azar
                    and fUgentlemen, Mrs/ Delesohamps, Mrs. Allen and 2 children, Mr. and ^Ira.
                    Olivier, Mr. H. Camilleri, Miss Gorzolia, Mrs. St. John, Mrs. Hanterâ€™s
                    eervant, Mr. G. Likia,. and 22 deck passengers. Le paqnebot â€œPortugalâ€ des
                    Messageries Mari times parti le 30 join ponr Marseille avait k bord: â– â€˜â€œV
                    Famille Kabis de St. Chamas, Famille Pila- vacchi, Mme Bonrgeois et enfants,
                    Famille Valassopoalo, M. de Vanvinenx, Mme Charlton, Mile Dafay, Famille Toriel,
                    Famille Bonlad, M. Millet, M. Kahbe, M. Simond Bey, M. et Mme Rayband, M.
                    Cochard, M. Smith, Mme Mahmond Bey Salem et enfants, M. et Mile Rini, Dr Ahmed
                    Bey-Ali, Mila Gitardin, M. Mohamed Fauzy.M. Amin Yeya Bey,M. et Mme Riso, Mme de
                    Lagarenne,M. et Mme Florimondi M. et Mme Maksnd et enfants, famille Marne- lanok
                    Bey, Famille Hnrri Caroujbin, Me Padoa Chalet, Famille Bantata, M Abouchanab, M.
                    C. Coury, M. Sacazin, Miss'Biadfield, Famille Debband, Famille Cjury, M.
                    Lefevre, M. et Mme Bayonm, Fteres Silvanns, Sire et Roch, M. et Mme Beltran et
                    enfant, M. et Mme Poll, M. Lehirdy Ivon, R. P. Alexis Mallon, Mme Jovannides, M.
                    Mnsld, 3 enfants de M,' Glasbarg, Mme et M.Glasbjrg, Mme Glasberg mkre, pera
                    Giovanni, M. Schlinker, R. P. Fernandez, M. Nakmias, M. Bone, oapt. Collins,
                    Heat. Slaughter, M. Fairfowl, Nazim bey, Mr., Mme et Mile Vaillant Bey, M.
                    Meimara- chi, M. Abdil Bey Aiod, Mme Reville, M. Chedid, M. A. Dimitraki, M. H.
                    A. Reid, Dr. Giti* M. et Mme Papazian Bey et famille, M. et Mme AnnÂ£, M. et Mme
                    Miohel Manopoli Bey, M. C> Colombani, M. Wamook, M. H. Kienzy, M. dela
                    Boulinikre, M. Paul Pkstour, M. G. H. Dempster,- M. Kheraclah Abougabel, M., Mme
                    et Mile de Codt, M. A. Balfour, M. S. Omer, M^Satow, M. et Mme Abbas Helmy, sa
                    mre et enfant, R. P. M. Guilsmet, M. G. Tomioh, M. L. Jacobs, M. A. Sikaly, Mme
                    Leoolon, M. Moh. Zaki, M. S. Balles, Mile J. Silva, M. Habib Joseph, Mile Alex.
                    Berthier, scear St. Alphonse, R. P. J. Gyan, P. Denmier, M. Papasian et
                    gonvernante, M. Mohamed Abdelhalim, Mme Garabachian et Miles Kula- fian, Mrs.
                    Joseph Bogos et Alex. Garabedian, Mme Fortis, M. et Mme Gropper, M. Welkins,
                    Fteres Rolland, Lesoin, Noel Joseph, Dosith^e, Ltfonce et Joachim, M. A. Nahoum,
                    M. P. Gindice, M. G. Gbbi, R. R. Dalemme, M. Bayoumi, M. J. Conrad Ott, Cap. A.
                    D. Saw, M. Hayat, M. Tonrne, M. Artin Halfaian et 27 passagers de 3me
                    olasse.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse">
                <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                <p>(Autowrdhui d midi et demie) Nons avons eu, comme câ€™est lâ€™habitnde le
                    samedi, un marchd calme et ddlaissd. Le man- qne dâ€™acheteurs a fait reculer
                    les oonrs de quelqnes valeurs. Câ€™est ainsi qne la Banqne Nationale fldohit de
                    26 1/16 k 26, lâ€™Agrioole de 13 5/8 k 13 9/16, la Banqne dâ€™Athknes de 120 k
                    119 1/2 la Bdhdra de 44 k 43 3/4, ia Dai'ra de 28 1/8 k 28, la Salt Soda de 34/9
                    k 34/3, lâ€™Alexandria Water de 15 1/4 k* 15 1/8, la Ramleh Railway de 7 1/4 k 7
                    3/16 eto. Les Estates se maintiennent k 27/32 aohe- teurs et les Trust k 1 9/32.
                    La tendance dn marchd est inddoise. / </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="mouvementMaritime">
                <head>MOUVEMENT MARITIME DU PORT D'ALBXANDRIS</head>
                <p>ABBIVtetB J 30 jnin vap. ital. Margarida, oap. Troja, ton. 1066, k Pellerano. ^
                    ler juillet Hadikswall; 21 j. 3/4, vap. ang. North Gwalia, oap. Roberts, ton.
                    1418, k Barber Son. Constantinople et Pirde; 40 h., vap. ang. Prinoe Abbas, oap.
                    Anderlich, ton. 851, k la Khedivial Mail.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="7">

                <div type="section" element="londonLetter">
                    <head>OUR LONDON LETTER</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent). London, Jane 23.</p>
                    <p>At Ascot, yesterday, the leading event was the Plate, which, in the early
                        years of her marriage, was named after the Queen Alexandra that is, and it
                        would seem, with the happiest results. "Racing,â€ King Edwardâ€™s
                        great-grand-uncle, the Duke of Cumberland, is said to have re- marked,
                        "languishes for want of support from the Crown and aristocracy.â€ So he
                        went a- racing, with "the best stock, the best blood, and the most numerous
                        stud in the kingdom.â€ Later on, the Ascot he virtually made felt the
                        influence of the â€œadded moneyâ€ of the big gate meetings. The Alexandra
                        Plate was the first instance, on classic ground, where Â£1,000 was added to
                        the stakes. True, the race was inaugurated by the victory of Count de La-
                        grangeâ€™s Fille de lâ€™Air, so named after a fairy- tale by Cogniard
                        Freres, which was drawing all Paris to the old "Fol. Dram.â€ â€œBut
                        since,â€ remark the Earl of Suffolk and Berkshire and Mr. W.G. Craven, "the
                        wealth and liberality of the Royal Meeting have increased pari passu."
                        Twenty years ago, these authorities could aver, "all that is most excellent
                        in horseflesh, and most ambitious in ownership, is annually attracted to
                        this favoured spot.â€ The favored spot has lost none of its attractions
                        since 1886, and the brillianny of the era which the writers dated from the
                        founding of the Alexandra Plate has, assuredly, suffered no eclipse.</p>
                    <p>The most effective and artistic incident of the Royal trip down the Thames on
                        Saturday, when the Prince of Wales inaugurated the London County Council
                        steamboat service, was the skillful display of the Prince of Walesâ€™s
                        feathers in water by the Metropolitan Fire Brigade on their fire float. The
                        pretty device was exceedingly wellâ€™ reproduced. An unsa- tisfactory
                        circumstance of the trip was that the Prince allowed himself to be so
                        closely surround- ed by his friends on the â€œKing Alfred,â€ that the
                        crowds on the Embankment and on the bridges had the utmost difficulty in
                        distinguishing His Royal Highness.</p>
                    <p>The principle on which Civil Lis; pensions are granted is sometimes hard to
                        understand. There is, happily, no difficulty in approving Shat just
                        published. The names which have called forth official bounty are either
                        great names or names associated with solid, benefi- cial, But alas !
                        unremunerative work. J. G. Frazer, le Neve Foster, Yorjf Powell, and Freeman
                        : under these cognomens the educa- tion and well-being of mankind have been
                        furthered. So in a smaller degree with the others mentioned in the list.
                        But, though satisfactory, it is a sad record. To many of the pensions the
                        phrase â€œstraitened circumstancesâ€ is added as a reason for the giving.
                        Astronomers and physicists, men who have given -their lives to history and
                        research, die without monetary reward for their services, leaving their
                        families in such a condition that a hundred pounds from the Civil List comes
                        as a real blessing. Supposing, for instance, that Professor York Powell had
                        devoted his great gifts to commerce or finance, he would perhaps have died a
                        millionaire ; certainly his daughter would noÂ£. have struggled with
                        â€œinadequate means of support." It is to such cases that Civil List
                        pensions are properly applied.</p>
                    <p>The great Indian controversy is over, and Lord Kitchener has scored a great
                        victory. The anomalous position of the Commander-in- Chief, which brought
                        about the regrettable possibility of his resignation, is a thing of the
                        past, and Mr. Brodrick was able yesterday to make the important and welcome
                        announce- ment that Lord Kitchener will in future have a free hand in the
                        management of all the mili- tary combatant services. It would have been a
                        serious calamity for India had the outcome been any other. Glad as we should
                        and shall be one day to have the benefit of that master- mind in the
                        organisation of our own military affairs, it is a matter of greater urgency
                        that the work so well begun in India should first be accomplished. The
                        details of his reorganisation scheme Mr. Brodrick also laid before the House
                        of Commons. It entails a considerable expenditure, but the consideration
                        that it will not only increase and improve the Indian Army, but render it
                        independent df home probably disincline him to attempt any settle- ment of
                        the Norwegian difficulty. If Swedish Princes can recover them the affront to
                        their dynasty, and on of them should be asked to accept the Norwegian Crown,
                        there are younger sons of the King who might suit The Crown Princess of Den-
                        mark, a Swedish Princess by birth, also has a son or two who could be spared
                        for a situation worthy of acceptance.</p>
                    <p>With a courtesy and a touch of sentiment so characteristic of the Japanese,
                        acknowledgment of subscriptions to the Japanese Soldiersâ€™ and Sailorsâ€™
                        Widows and Families Fund is made in very graceful fashion. A correspondent
                        for wards his receipt for my inspection. It includes an acknowledgment from
                        the Treasurer of the Red Cross Society of Japan, a printed note in Japanese,
                        and a pretty little lacquered cup wrapped in a silk handkerchief and
                        forwarded from Tokio in a sandalwood box tied with green silk cord. The cup
                        constitutes a charming 'souvenir of the gratitude of our Eastern allies.</p>
                    <p>Whether war correspondence is declining or not as a permanent profession, it
                        seems to be the quickest way to prominence. The eldest son of the late Sir
                        Ellis Ashmead-Bartlett has beer through a tolerable slice of the Japanese
                        war, and watched the siege of Port Arthur with General Nogi. After the
                        surrender he came back through the States, and lectured to many military and
                        civilian audiences, one of his marked successes being at West Point Academy,
                        for the benefit of us here at home he lectures on Monday afternoon at the
                        United Service Institution, accompanying his remarks with photographs of his
                        own taking. And soldiers of an older generation may not be disinclined to
                        earn something from this enterprising junior of twenty-four.</p>
                    <p>The Prince of Wales, on his arrival at Cardiff on Friday of next week, will
                        drive straight to the Castle, ,the Marquis of Buteâ€™s magnificent residence
                        in the centre of the town, where Lord Bute will entertain him at lun- cheon.
                        In the afternoon His Royal Highness will lay the foundation-stone of the new
                        Uni- versity College in Cathays Park, and later will attend the graduation
                        ceremony. The Prince will be the guest on Friday night of Lord and Lady
                        Windsor at fit. Faganâ€™s, their seat just outside Cardiff, where a
                        distinguished party will be invited to meat him. The functions on Saturday
                        include the conferring on the Prince of the freedom of the borough, followed
                        by a municipal banquet, and he will leave Cardiff forâ€™ London the same
                        day.</p>
                    <p>The finding of the court-martial upon the submarine disaster is satisfactory
                        in so far 88 it acquits Lieutenant Candy and the other survivors of all
                        blame ; but unsatisfactory, and necessarily so, because it was found
                        impossible exactly to determine what brought about A 8â€™s loss of trim and
                        inability to answer the helm at the last. Only the dead helmsman, probably,
                        could have cleared up one doubt. It is certain that the submarine somehow
                        got out of trim, owing to some shifting of weight, either on the part of the
                        crew or by the ad- mission of water. But it cannot be known whether the
                        horizontal diving rudders really were put hard up in good time to counter-
                        act the forward dip, as Lieutenant Candy ordered. They were found hard up
                        finally, but may have been put so too late. A blunder may have been made
                        earlier and the rudders put down instead of up, or they may have been in-
                        adequate to counteract the loss of trim. These seem to be the alternatives,
                        and both raise questions as to the delicate stability of these ships which
                        call for farther expert investigation.</p>
                    <p>It is perhaps better for all parties that the Norwegians declared their views
                        openly before the marriage of Prince Gustavua Adolphus. The Royal bride and
                        bridegroom, with relatives on both sides, now know what not to expect, and
                        will* not be obliged to include Norway in their tourist programme, or to
                        waste civilities on people who do not wish to see them.</p>
                    <p>The separate Crown of Norway would not be worth the acceptance of any Prince
                        of standing, were it not that the existence of a Republic in northern Europe
                        might lead to considerable awkwardness, and weaken the monarchical principle
                        neighbouring countries It remains to be seen whether one of Berffa-
                        dotteâ€™s Swedish or Danish descendants will be able to adjust matters, less
                        to benefit the self- assertive Norwegians than to maintain the prestige of
                        the Royal caste.</p>
                    <p>Prince Charles of Sweden, third son of King Oscar, is forty-four years of
                        age, and is married to his kinswoman, Princess Ingeborg of Den- mark, who is
                        twenty-seven. They are a cheer- ful, sensible couple, and would make a good
                        King and Queen. Prince Eugene of Sweden, King Oscarâ€™s fourth son, is forty
                        years of age unmarried, and has artistic tastes which would their last
                        phrase. Except for this, and for the men who go out at the end of each act
                        and wonâ€™t return in time for the beginning of the next, there is nothing
                        at all to complain of the opera. Between acts there is, of course, a regular
                        babel of chatter, and some of it is so funny, especially this week when the
                        Londoner points opt to the country cousin all the great folk present, and
                        the country cousin is quite satisfied, never thinking that the people
                        pointed out are at Ascot and their boxes occupied by friends. After all, the
                        country cousin is gratified, and no one is a pinâ€™s point the worse. One
                        wonders what the real people would think -could they see those pointed out
                        for them!</p>
                    <p>The docking of a ship at Portsmouth is gene- rally looked forward to by the
                        dockyard â€˜â€˜mateysâ€ as an excellent opportunity of obtain- ing some
                        good fishing. About a foot of water is always left in the dock for cleaning
                        out, and the fish can he easily seen swimming about un- able to escape. Last
                        Saturday at one of the docks quite a number of bass were - discovered by the
                        dockers, and much amusement was caused by the trantic efforts of the men en-
                        deavouring to comer the fish with spikes and brooms. It takes an expert in
                        this kind of fish- ing to land a prize successfully, but on this oc- casion
                        about half-a-dozen large fish were caught Quantities of oysters were also
                        gathered by some of the men from the bottom of the vessel docked.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAVY</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                    <dateline>London, June 23.</dateline>
                    <p></p>
                    <p>My readers will regret to learn of the death of Colonel E. H. Burney, C.B.,
                        who , retired a few months ago from the command of the 2nd Battalion Royal
                        Berkshire Regiment, at Alexandria. Colonel Burney,. who was in his 44th
                        year, was visiting Paris when he contracted his fatal illness. He saw
                        service with the Royal Berks in the Egyptian War of 1882, and commanded the
                        2nd batta- lion in the late South African War.</p>
                    <p>Lieutenant B. G. Bromhead, Royal Berks Regiment, has been ordered to embark
                        for Egypt on the 14th prox. to join the 2nd Bat- talion, on absorption. He
                        recently returned home from the Cape, where he did duty for three years with
                        the South African Consta- bulary. </p>
                    <p>Major H. B. Mainwaring, Lincolnshire Regiment, has left the 1st Battalion at
                        Se- cunderabad, and taken his retired pay, after a little over 27 yearsâ€™
                        service. Major Main- waring got his first commission in February, 1878, ways
                        promoted captain in 1884, and major in. 1896. He was in Kitchenerâ€™s
                        expedi- tion to Khartoum and was present at the battles of Atbara and
                        Omdurman (mentioned in dispatches, 4th class Osmanieh, British medal, and
                        Khediveâ€™s medal with two clasps).</p>
                    <p>The Rifle Depot at Winchester is to be maintained at its present
                        establishment Curiously, whilst other regiments have a difficulty in getting
                        recruits the "Green- jacketsâ€ have none.</p>
                    <p>It has been decided, says a contemporary, to discontinue the carrying of the
                        revolver in civilised warfare. In the South African war the drivers of the
                        R.H.A., and the R.HA. drivers of transport, staff sergeants, farriers, and
                        others were served out with Webley revolvers. These were only carried for a
                        short period, when they were relegated to the kit bag. Offioers who served
                        in that campaign say that however useful the six-shooter is in savage
                        warfareâ€”and it is a very good weapon for rough and tumble fightingâ€”it is
                        useless for oivilised warfare where fighting is carried on at long range.
                        It. is now proposed to replace the revolver by a light carbine. Farriers are
                        still to carry the Webley for shooting horses.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOME ERRORS OF ARTISTS.</head>
                    <p>In an interesting article on â€œArtistic In- congruities and Anachronisms,
                        â€uÂ» â€œChambersâ€™s Journal,â€ reference is made to a picture,painted
                        about the eighteenth century, in which Abra- ham appears ready to sacrifice
                        Isaac with a loaded blunderbuss. This antedated the use of firearms by more
                        than three thousand years. Pictures are knoWn of the Israelites crossing the
                        Red Sea armed with muskets and other weapons of offence of comparatively
                        modern date.</p>
                    <p>It is in the matter of costume that the early painters found such a stumbling
                        block. In the Edinburgh National Gallery is a picture in which Pharaoh's
                        daughter and her ladies are arrayed in the long-waisted bodices and hooped
                        skirts common to' Europe in the sixteenth century. In another picture of the
                        same date, representing â€œJoseph and his Kindred in Egypt,â€ which is hung
                        in the National Collec- tion in London, there is no trace of the distinctive
                        feature of Egyptian architecture about the buildings ; they are all Italian
                        in type. Note, again, another picture by,Paolo Veronese in the same gallery,
                        "The Family of Darius at the feet of Alexander after the Battle of I88U8.â€
                        Again we have these pointed waists and enormously distended skirts, which
                        are certainly incompatible with an event which occurred- in the year 333
                        B.C. The artist was a Venetian, and he drew the Venetian costumes of his own
                        period, 1528-88.</p>
                    <p>Raphael, like so many others, drew his Madonnas, his saints, and his martyrs
                        from Italian models, and clothed them in contempo- rary Italian costume,
                        giving the figures as a background the scenery with which he was so
                        familiar. It was only when travellers came to visit the Holy Land, and saw
                        the people there, unchanged in sentiment, habit, and customs for centuries,
                        that a few came to realise that the pictures were wrong.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A MODERN SACRIFICE TO ANCIENT GODS.</head>
                    <p>It has been calculated, according to â€œEngi- neering,â€ that a storage
                        capacity of two mil- liards of cubic metres^ or two thousand million tons,
                        is required to convert each million acres of the land of Egypt from flood to
                        perennial irrigation. Hence the problem is, to supply reservoirs capable of
                        storing four milliards of cubic metres of water. The Assouan reservoir at
                        its present level stores one milliard of cubic metres, leaving three
                        milliards yet to fie retained, if it bad not been for the senti- mental
                        outcry of certain European archaeolo- gists, to whom the preservation of a
                        ruined temple, which most of them had never seen, was of more interest than
                        the welfare of millions of their fellow-oreatures, the Assouan reservoir
                        would now be of twice its capacity, and another half-million acres rendered
                        able fa produce the long-stapled Egyptian cotton which is so greatly in
                        demand, As â€œEngineeringâ€ expresses it, the fellaheen cried to the
                        Govern- ment for bread, and it has given them stones, in deference to the
                        withes of a few foreign antiquaries. However, the fault is now com- mitted;
                        Egypt is poorer by 15,000,000, but retains a useless pile of half-submerged
                        ruins.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>AGARDâ€™S INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES AND TRADE MASKS REGISTER. -</p>
                    <p>A useful business directory containing addresses of all important business
                        firms of Great Britain the Continent, and Egypt. Circulating all over Europe
                        and America. Priceâ€”One pound Sterling. Poe=st Free.</p>
                    <p>AGARDS INTERNATIONAL HOTEL GUIDE</p>
                    <p>sent poet free to all first class Hotels throughout Europe, America, the
                        Colonies and Egypt. The beet reference book for traveller.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISING AGENTS.â€”The best public a Advertising sites in Alexandria
                        belong to G. Vestri and Co., Advt Agents, St Catherineâ€™s Square. Special
                        rates for permanent clients. Moderate terms. Prompt despatch.
                        26642-81-12-906</p>
                    <p>ARABIC LESSONS given by an'Bgptian H tutor to Europeans. Apply M. Snefik,
                        â€œEgyptian Gazetteâ€™^ offices. 25888- 25888-</p>
                    <p>APPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German, ax. to the Berlitz Schools,
                        Alexandria (26, Rue de l'Eglise Copte Cairo Sharia Kamel), Most rapid method
                        Trial lesson free. Evening classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per month.
                        23069-30-9A-906</p>
                    <p>AMERICAN MANUFACTURERâ€™S Agency ax. wishes to advise having reoeived a fresh
                        consignment of Roll-top Desks, Morris Chairs, Sewing Machines,
                        Refrigerators, Typewriters and various other American goods. No. 7 Rne de
                        lâ€™Anoienne Bourse. 25878-2-5 906</p>
                    <p>BLICK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 Â£9, No. 7 A> Â£11. W.T. Emmons, 99 Rue Attarine,
                        Alexandria, Address, Post Offioe Box 35. 30-6-905A</p>
                    <p>CHIEF ACCOUNTANT first-rate Cairo firm '-J wants occupation after office
                        hours. Apply to this paper, XV. 348. 26185-3-1</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
