<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, MAY 20, 1905.</head>
<div type="item"><p>The SUDAN' TO-DAY.
The author of “Pyramids, and Progress" has 
written another delightful work, which is in I
fact the best book yet published descriptive of 
the Egyptian Sudan. “Skip the letter-press, the ;
pictures will teach you all you need to know,’’ 
is the author's own advice to his readers—yet !
he succeeds in turning out books which is i-1
impossible to put down unfinished when once |
begun. With four, six, or eight illustrations
to each page, he has here presented a sort of
sketch, alike of the antiquities and of the
present appearance of the Sudan, which leaves
the most lively impression on the mind of tho
reader.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward’s book bears, in some respects, a
semi-official character.“Lord Kitohener asked me
to dedicate the book to him,” says the author,
“and this compliment inspired me with a desire
to do my best.” The distinguishing feature is
the illustrations. The work is literally crowded
with photographs, many hundreds in all, a
large number of which are provided by the
present Sirdar and Lady Wingate, and others
who have had the privilege to penetrate into
remote and strange regions. The most gruesome
are those representing the last stand of the
Khalifa, reproduced from photographs of Sir
Reginald Wingate, showing in ghastly realism
the dead bodies of the leader and his sons and
followers a few minutes after the conclusion of
the battle. The most satisfactory are those
giving the pictures of the Sudan and the work
in its destruction, the “saner war” and “sweeter
wars" against the hostile forces of nature, in
which lies the real test and triumph of the
work of civilization.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE LAND AND ITS FUTURE.
The description is exhaustive. Here is the
journey to Khartoum, its temples and monu-
ments visible along the voyage. Then follows
the history in outline of the reconquest. The
new cities are described springing up on the
land of so many great and terrible memories,
the Omdurman and Khartoum of to-day. Mr.
Ward passes on to the interior in its possi-
bilities of irrigation, the encouragement of
peaceful agriculture, and especially sugges-
tions for the control of the waters of the Nile,
and Sir William Garstin’s great scheme for
utilising in the service of man that which is
now wasted.</p>
<p>At the end Mr. Ward takes his readers up
into the remote heart of Africa, through a
really astonishing collection of illustrations, to
the region of the lakes and expeditions and ex-
plorations hitherto unrecorded in literature.
The author, in visiting "Our Sudan,” which
is almost as large as Europe, and possesses
nearly as many nationalities, was struck with
the gre.it exec .t and variety of the physical
characteristics. What was labelled "desert”
in the maps frequently proved to be fertile
land. It was once cultivated, and can be tilled
again when supplied with irrigation. The land
in many parts, he thinks, is admirably adapted
for cotton culture.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward, in applying to his friends of the
Government departments for photographs, was
almost overwhelmed with their kindness. "I
thought to make a selection,” he says, “but
tj all were so good and many so curious,represent-
/ ing places never depicted before, that I said
I ‘Let them all come.”' “The advice I give to
' people studying this book,” is his genial com-
ment, "is, Skip the letterpress; the illustra-
tions will teach you all jrou want to know."
Among the most interesting is the account of
the tonr of Mr. Dupuis in Abyssinia and the
surrounding regions, with illustrations of a
country hitherto unknown. There are also
accounts of the visits of the Governor-General
to remote provinces, where Sir Reginald Win-
gate is shown “everywhere welcomed by happy
faces and hailed by chiefs and sheikhs and head
men and village people, especially by the
fomale population, as their deliverer.” Kordo-
fan, hitherto almost iuaooessible, here yields
up its secrets, and Darfur will come next,
“though at present it is impossible to get a
single illustration of that region.”</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>NAGA TEMPLE.
Mr. Ward supplies a much-needed account
of the pyramids at Meroe and of the temples
at Naga and Solib, built by Egyptiauisiug
longs of Ethiopia, which we have looked for in
vain elsewhere.</p>
<p>The author's description of the beautiful
temple at Naga is set off by an excellent
photograph by Eimbashi Lord, R.E. Here is
the description</p>
<p>But the chief object of interest here, is an
exquisite little temple in the classic style,
quite a gem. It bears no inscription, but as
it is partially buried in the sand, scientific
excavation may discover its origin by careful
search for a foundation deposit under the door
sill, or at the corners, as is so often found in
Egyptian temples. We are told that the
Romans never settled so far south. Yet here
we find undoubted evidonce of Roman in-
fluence with distinct Egyptian characteristics,
facing lions of Egyptian style, along with
pilasters and arched opqnings carved with what
might be called Renaissance treatment I The
date of the latest buildings cannot be earlier
than 200 A.D. while some structures hore may
possibly goback to 1,000 years B.(J. These ruins
are ft puzzle as to the period of their erection,
that can only be solved by scientific search.
The danger is, that if not protected till the
time comes for legitimn’: inquiry, they are in
such a crumbling con : tion that ignorant dig-
ging, or search for ti .sure, may destroy them
entirely. Several of these temples at Naga,
though erected for Egyptian, have been subse-
quietly applied to Christian worship, as is
shown by the symbol of the cross which they
tevr. One of them has been approached by an
avenue of sheep, or lambs, of which several
remain. This is another Egyptian feature in
architecture. The Egyptians had the sphinx
•"OafStxUor IuPrmal4<u4 ProgrtM.” Dy John Wt>4.
LsadSB i Job* Mam/. 111. sit.
ram headed to tepifv their God Amon, the
Christians imitated tho style but transformed
he sphinxes into figures of the sacred Lamb.
Dnemichen carried the cross to the remotest
corners of the Snd.-in, and every shrine of the
old faith had been converted to Christian
worship.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE REMOTE INTERIOR.
There is still ranch land unexplored—in
Darfur, Kordofan, and the Bahr el Ghazal.
The last has great possibilities of future de-
velopment Here ‘“les brave Beiges,’" says
Mr. Ward, “do not seem to take our peaoeful
treatment of the natives as complimentary to
their management of the adjoining Congo
State” Captain Bethell's description of a walk
and a visit in Bahr el Ghazal is incorporated
in the narrative, and forms one of the most
interesting chapters.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>GORDON’S STATUE.
A picture of the statue of Gordon in the
principal square of the new city forms the
frontispiece to this book.
The hero is represented on his camel with all
its native trappings correctly shown, just as he
was wont to start on his expeditions through
the country. It was related in “Tho Times”
recently how one day a poor old black woman,
who had been .a prisoner of Gordon’s days,
came back to Khartonm, and, soring the statne,
exclaimed: “God be praised, the pasha Gordou
has come again!” Here she had seated herself
for an entire day—and she related how she
had sat long by his camel, and that still he
would not look at her—he who had never
passed her without a kindly nod before. "Is
he tired, or what is it she said: but after
many visits she came home glad at last, for the
Pasha had nodded his head to her!</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE NEW KHARTOUM.
The new Khartoum now stands the model
city of Central Africa. It is a city embosomed
in a grove of trees undestroyed by all the
shocks of war. When Kitchener crossed im-
madiately after the battle of Omdurman the
place .vas a tangle of weeds and demolished
houses, with not a living creature in the ruins,
surronnded by a spacious garden. Noble in-
situations and imposing private houses are aris-
ing on all Bides. There are several handsome
banks and club9, a good hotel, and the Gordon
College, with</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>THE SIRDAR'S PALACE
The author gives a pleasant picture of the
life of the palace, and the energy and devotion
which is being thrown into the work of ex-
ploration and civilisation.
The interior of the Palace is most charming
in every aspect I enjoyed many visits to it,
thanks to its hospitable hosts, Sir Reginald
and Lady Wingate. The Sirdar’s wonderful
collection of trophies and relics of his long
experience at the Intelligence Department are
well worth a journey to Khartonm to see. Every ;
day some young officer would arrive unexpect-
edly, bringing news from the remoter pro-
vinces, and their keen interest in their duties
added much to one’s pleasure. All were so
young, active, full of life, hope, and thorough
enjoyment of their profession. And when there
was a gymkhana, and officers and men, white,
black, and yellow, all competed together in
equality in splendid efforts of field sports and
military exercises, it was easy to tell how the
Egyptians and Sudanese had become each
well-disciplined and effective soldiers.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ZUBEIR PASHA.
There is an interesting account at the and
of the serene old age of Znbeir Pasha, once all
powerful in this region, whose name became
the centre of many violent controversies.
He is now very old. He lives on his paternal
estates, Geila near Khartonm, and is a great
agriculturist. He has laid aside all his old
objectionable habits, and is now a tall old man,
rather good-looking, and very fond of showing
himself in his Pasha’s uniform at all functions,
and never loses a chance of potting in
an appearance at the Palace. He appears
thus in several of tho photographs. Ho is
now quite harmless, and his sympathy with
us, and antipathy to the Mahdi, joined
to a unique knowledge of every remote pro-
vince, has made his friendship valuable. Sir
Reginald Wingate likes him, and most of those
in power have a certain amount of respect for
the old, once powerful, Znbeir Pasha. Yet,
when there was a deputation of native chiefs,
a few years ago, from the Bahr el Ghazal,it was
seen that the poor ‘ braves” trembled in every
limb, and could hardly be restrained from belt-
ing when they saw their old enemy in gold lace
standing beside our governing powers—they
feared we were all slave-dealers, after all</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>CONVERTS DISCOURAGED.
The natives are evidently not encouraged
by officials to become Christians, as the
following story about Archdeacon Gwynn. the
Chaplain at Khartoum, and a would-be Chris
tian shows-:—
This man came to Mr. Gwynne and asked
him to admit him and his family into his
church. Mr. Gwynne said ho could not, as he
was Government chaplain, and there was a
regulation against his doing so. The man went
away sorrowful, for ho had three daughters,
and he wanted them to be Christians because,
he said, a woman had no life she could call her
own under Islam. Of course by and by when
there is a public church he and his family may
become Christians if they so desire.
Many other interesting extracts cooed easily
be made, but the above suffice to show the
varied characteristics of this book, which ought
to be in the hands of every visitor to the
! Sudan.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SECK & CO’S PILSENER BEEB
I Obtainable fraai every Raapaatabla firm
la Cuao, Ataxmoxu A na Bros*.
OUttmU* t*
1 *. J. ruutwr, F. WCALLEF- Bote Agsat,
c,:u	>1, (e« Midst, s mtnn>
THE ARM AND HEART
OF QUEEN ZER.
A WARNING TO EGYPTOLOGISTS.
By Baroness de Malortie.
Monsieur de Naville searches through
Historic tombs and temples too,
With their faint dusty smell.
His mind is fall of Hatshepsut
And all the things she did, and knew
Deep in his besom dwell.
A cloudy moan looked down on Thebes,
Where there were other pairs than these—
Like phantoms flitting by.
T. Davis dressed in stars and stripes,
Was wandering on the distant heights,
With his last find Queen Thy.
Professor Budge goes rather far
In excavating Napata—
Though hope his bosom fills
With aloes, cassia, spice and balm,
And pre-historic robes of palm,
Beneath those stony hills.
At least we heard it Baid at ‘Queen's’
When basking mid the classic scenes
Of the Alma Mater
A learned one gave ns the news
Of Egypt, long before the Jews—
To C****r the Dictator.
He brought us from tho realms of Death,
Fair spirits not of mortal breath,
Whispering their story.
We heard the tinkling of their beads,
The prancing of their warriors' steeds
Tales—of love and glory.
Perhaps their secrets they confessed,
And why they lie so quaintly dressed
In faded garlands pale,
And seem to point from amber palls
To pine and crimson on the walls
That could unfold the tale.
As in tho after dinner time
Some gossiped over mellow wine,
Within the College Courts.
Strange plans evolved before the eyes
Of one we deemed, both good and wise—
And far away his thoughts.
He saw once more a waveless shore
Where visions flitted as of yore
Beneath the starry host
He breathed again—in spacious tombs,
And tore the woof of silken looms,
The shroud of some poor ghost.
They say be did far more than this,
On sealed brow e’en breathed a kiss
In ecstasy of mind.
And clasped an arm, once soft and fair
Though many a magic charm was there,
Held fast as gold could bind.
Poor little arm, thus cast away
In some rough spoiler’s hurried day
Who threw you from the rest.
And married tho dwelling of the Sonl
By breaking up a perfect whole
How could yon then be blessed.
Part of a queen—so precious too—
How little they had left of yon
When Flinders Petrie came,
Who gently took the jeweled bands,
Of fine gold chased by skillful hands,
And brought them forth to fame.
And at the back of those fair bands
Were woven tiny fragile strands
Of softest human hair,
Twisted about with golden thread
The Amethyst and Royal Hawk’s head—
Turquoise and crystals rare.
’Neath centuries of yellow dost
Great Mother Earth held you in trust
Among the Holy Dead.
Swatched and wrapped in unguents rare
The spirit still could enter there
Waiting Osiris dread.
But eh I what now remains to tell,
The spoilers did their work so well,
Then Ages stole along.
That silent land Time’ yet sleeps
And over all the sunlight sWeeps
In everlasting song.
But he, the wise one, sat alone
In that small cabin then his home
That floated on the Nile.
Osiris—Isis—Horns there
And many others gods less feir,
With their Egyptian Smile.
He saw them not, but heard a sigh
That echoed as the wind swept by,
Among papyrus reed—
He seemed to feel a presence there,
Whore moonbeams fell across his chair
Upon the ‘Books’ dead creeds.
A feint voice said—“I cannot rest
"Or ever join that throng so blest
"But wander everywhere
"The issues of our life apart
"Are sometimes gathered in the heart
"Mine—lies unburied there.
“Yes 1 in an alabaster jar,
"Just where the rocky lintels are,
"They hid it in their fear,
"Go place it ’neath the shaft of light,
"That I may find it in my flight,
"Until that Day appear.
"It never more shall be disturbed,
“When all the rites have been observed.
"Go—gentle stranger—go 1”
The silver river, calm and deep
Heard a man matter in his sleep
I thought it would be so —I
Alas 1 that heart cannot be found
Within the tomb, or on the ground.
So lost, an act of grace,
A spirit hovers night and day
About the boat, so sailors say—
, Of grave Professor Ssyoe 1
Administration des Chemins de Fer,
des Telegraphs et da Portd’Alexandrie.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
Faisant suite k l’avis public en date da 12
Mai ct, 1’Administration des Chemins de Fer
ile l’Etut po:te k la connaissance de intressa
qne le coucoura poor les 2 posies de deasiny
tear vacant* au Service de la Voie et des Tra-
vanx. anca lien an Bureau Central da Service
de 1* Voie lo Simoli 27 Mai ct. k 3 h. 30 p.m.
Les candidate y prenant part devront se
munir des boltes k compas ainsi que des rfeglee,
donble-d&)im6tre et t-qnerres qui leurserviront
ponr les dprenvee de dess in.
Le Cairo le 17 Mai 1905.	25999-1</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
Le CoDseil d’Administration des Chemins
de Fer et des TMdgrajihss a l’honnenr de feire
savoir an Public qu’k partir da 20 ot le bu-
reau telographique de la gare de Ghizeh sera
termB k la oorrespondan .c commercials.
Le Cairo le 17 Mai 1905.	26000 1</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
Le Conseil d’Administration des Chemins de
Per et des Tdldgraphes a l’honneur de feire
savoir an Public qu’k partir du 20 Ct l’horaire
dee bureaux telegraphiques snivants sera modi-
fit1 comma suit:
Khatta de 8h. a.m. k 4h. p.m. sans interruption
Acmantde ah. a.m. k 5h. p.m. id.
Chagab	id.	id.	id.
Mataana	id.	id.	id.
Sebaieh id. k 7h. p.m.	id.
Silwa	id.	id.	id.
Le Cairo, le 17 mai 1905.	26001-1</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EGYPTIAN STATE RAILWAYS.
NOTICE.
The Board of Administration has the honor
to inform the public that, on and after the
17th May, the openings of Hagar-Nawatieh
swing bridge will be modified as follows
from	7.55	a.m.	np	to	8.25	a.m.
„	11.30	a.m.	„	„	12.10	p.m.
„	1.10	p.m.	„	„	1.25	p.m.
„	4.15	p.m.	„	„	4.50	p.m.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>The Standard Life Assurance Company.
ACCUMULATED FUNDS £11,300,000
BONUS YEAR. 1005.
THE NEXT DIVISION OF PROFITS will be made protecting Folldoo In exlotonco MlUb Nonmbor 1M
AU Witk ProJU PMeia iJleOA « O'	«• .W. im U. ft™,
Tho Compony tore niraodj docinrod Bonuo Addition* lo Pollci</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SEVEN MILLIONS STERLING.
Heart Onto© tor Egypt: Is liaria KuMr-el-NU, Cairo.
B. NATHAN & Oo.,	A. V. THOMSON,
Ck'tf Agent i for Alexandria.	Secretary for Egypt.
WINDSOR HOTEL
Lugosi 1 *t olaat and moat oiraf.-rtible
Hotel l’I Alexandria. Peeing toe ei
Central position. Oudor SagUeh tn*ua ;em-*nt</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
DE SECONDE CONVOCATION
Messieurs les Actionnairos de la Fayonm
Light Railways Compauy sont oonvoquds en
Assemble (Wngrale Ordinaire ponr le vendredi
neufjnin 1905 k 4 heures de l’aprfes-midi an
Sifcge de la Soci^td an Cairo Bharia Tewfik</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ORDRE DU JOUR :
Rapport du Conseil d’Administration aveo
presentation das comptes depnis le ler mars
1904 jusqn’au 28 fevrier 1905.
Rapport desoenseors.
Approbation dea comptes du susditexeroioe.
Fixation de i'iudemnitd des oeaseoza poor la
periods 6oooUe.
Nomination des censenrs ponr Fannie en
cours.
Pour prendre part k 1’Assemble, il feat Stre
proprtemire de Dix Actions an moins ddposdee
truis jours an m-jiue avant la reunion suit au
plus tard le 6 juiu 1905 dans Fun des lieux oi-
aprfcs iudiquls oil serene ddlivrdea aux ddpo
s&uts des cartes d’ailmission k I’Aaterablle.
Les d6p0ta d’actions seront re^us : au Sifege
Social de la Socidtd an Caire Sharia Tewfik
maison N” 11.
A la Banqne Imperials Ottomans an Cairo
etk Alexandria.
A 1’Anglo Egyptian Bank an Caire et k
Alexandria.
Ponrront assister k F Assemble mais sans
droit de vote les purtenre de Dix Obligations
au, moins qni juatifieront de meme dn dgpOt
de leurs obligations effeotud dans le ddlai et
l’nn des lieux sna-indiqnds.
Pour Is Conteil d' Administration.
Kualed Louth.
Caire le 18 mai 1!
259952*1
SOCIETE ANONYME
Agricole et IMostrielle d’Egypte</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
Le public est prdvenn qu’opposition a dtd
feite an paiement des 32 coupons No. 8 des
action8 de capital de la Socidtd qui ont dtd
dgards et dont les numdros suivent:
No. 13187	k 13190	4
S, 13699	,. 13708	10
„	14301	„ 14303	3
„	14403	„ 14410	3
„	14412	„ 14414	3
„	14421	„ 14429	9
	Total	32 25998-:
Municipality d Alexandrie</p>
<div type="item"><p>AVIS
La Municipality met en adjudication la
fbamiture nessaire poor sou service pour un
ftn.de Ponrrages, soit: orge, fives saidi, paille
blanche, paille de liti&re et son.
Le cautionnemant eat fixd k L.E. 420.
Le cahier des charges eat ddposd au Bnrean
du Service de Nettoiement oh il peut dtre oon-
snltd par les intéressés tons les jours do 9 h. k
miili, les jours fdrids exceptds.
Les offres devront dtre adressdea sous pli
ca«hetd .k Monsieur Administrateur de la
Mnnicipalitd avant le $0 juin 1905.
Elies pourront dg&lemant dtre ddposdes en
sdanoe de laDdldgation le mdme jour k Sh.p.m.
L’enveloppo devra porter en outre la men-
tian:“Sonmission pour fourniture du Poarrage."
Lo cautionnement on le refa d’une banque,
d’aprda les conditions du cahier des charges,
devra dtre remis séparément au Service de la
Comptability Gdndrale avant 1’onverture dea
offres et au plus tard le 20 join pr. k midi.
Tonte offre qni ne romplit pas les conditions
ci-desaus sera dcartde.
L’Administrateur
W. P. Chaxawax.
Alexandrie, le 18 Mai 1905.	15996-3-1
______ The Lc</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>HUNDREDS of THOUSANDS of POUNDS WORTH OF
BEDSTEADS, BEDDING, CUTLERY, CHINA, GLASS,
CURTAINS, BLINDS, 8Lc., always ready for immediate
throughout in three days
•f{est and Most
:£ Establishment
Convenient
in the. Wot:
HIGH-CLASS,
SILVER WARE, CARPETS,
A house furnished

“Oothcart" Dining Room Salto In Mahogany, Walnut or Fumed Oak. with braie. mountings, oonelets of 6 ft
with handsomely carved pediment and panels, bevelled mirror* In baok, lower portion usefully fitted with
cupboards and cellarette; 3 ft 6 in Silver Cabinet, extreme height 7 ft fitted with clear gla»» •helve*
>rod baok; 3 ft 6 In Dinner Wagon with two drawers and cupboard; Dining Table 4 ft wide and extending
The “Oothcart" Dining Room Sqlte In
sideboard with handsomely carved pedlmen
drawer*, oupboards and oellarette; 3 ft 6
and mirrorod back; 3 ft 6 In Dinnar Wagor
and mirrorod back; 3 ft 6 In Dinnar Wagon with two drawers and oupboai
to 8 ft long, with extra leaves and patent screw 1 six very strong Dining I
In beet marone moroooo: Prioe Includes paoklug and delivery F.O.B. London
Baparats prlooe on applioatlon
r portion
;te3 with
‘able ^ ft
vide and extend
ndlng
tered</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ONE OF THE SIGHTS OF LONDON
M/r APLB A 00 Invite resident* of Cairo, Alexandria, Damanhour, Tantah, Maneou.-ah, Damletta, Bamahud, Roeetta. Mlnlah,
*”• I inn all I a, Port Said, and dletrlot*. whan Visiting London to walk through these spacious showroom* and galierl**, and
■ee for themselves all the latest novelties and new production*. MAPLE A CO also send pattern* of all kind* of material, and
illastvmtiona of furniture, bedsteads, Ao„ on applioatlon, and give Inoluelv* f.o.b. estimates when desired.
COURT ROAD LONDON ENGLAND</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

