<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-25">January 25, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7106 ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 25, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <!-- missing material -->
                    <head>DEATH OF BISHOP OF LLANDAFF.</head>
                    <dateline>London, January 24.</dateline>
                    <p>The Bishop of Llandaff is dead. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>The Right Rev. Richard Lewis, D.D., Bishop of Llandatf, born in 1821, was
                        educated at Worcester College, Oxford (B.A., 1843; M.A., 1846). He was
                        instituted to the rectory of Lampeter-Velfry, Narberth, Pembrokeshire, in
                        1851, and was appointed Archdeacon of St. David’s in 1875. In 1883 he was
                        appointed Bishop of Llandaff in succession to Dr. Ollivant, and was
                        consecrated to that Bee by the Archbishop of Canterbury in St. Paul’s
                        Cathedral, on April 25 of that year.</p>
                </div>
                <!-- missing material -->
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- missing material -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                    <p>—On the 21st and 22nd inst. 31 vessels passed through the Canal, the amount
                        received in dues being frs. 817,481.46. 18 were British ships, 5 German, 3
                        Austrian, 2 French, 1 Norwegian, 1 Egyptian, 1 Italian. The receipts from
                        the 1st to 22nd inst totalled frs. 8,137,811.66.</p>
                    <p>The Telephone Company of Egypt has now completed telephonic communication in
                        thirty markazes between the police officers of the districts and the
                        moudiriehs, as well as between the former and the omdehs of the different
                        localities in each district or markaz. It is intended to extend the system
                        gradually in the remaining moudiriehs of the country.</p>
                    <p>An Exile in Egypt.—In pursuance of a decision of the Central Criminal Court,
                        Constantinople, a further term of ten days has been granted to Iskender
                        Shehkub, a fugitive, to appear before it. He is in Egypt, where he publishes
                        seditious matter against the Imperial Government. If he fails to return to
                        Turkey within the prescribed term, he will be tried in absentia, and his
                        property will be confiscated.</p>
                </div>
                <!-- missing material -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT.</head>
                    <p>OFFICIAL VERSION.</p>
                    <p>I regard to the theft from the Mahmal's escort, we may state that the
                        allegation in to-day's issue of a Cairo morning newspaper, that the case
                        containing L.E. 8,000 in gold had after all been left in the Finance
                        Ministry at Cairo, is quite untrue.</p>
                    <p>With regard to the theft, the following is the official version of the
                        facts:</p>
                    <p>The money sent with the Mahmal was packed in twenty-two cases, three of which
                        contained gold, the remainder silver coin. The packets were duly numbered
                        and sealed at the Finance Ministry, and handed to over the “saraaf’ of the
                        Mahmal caravan, who counted them, found them correct, and gave the receipt
                        for them. They were then taken down to Abbassieh under guard, and put in a
                        waggon belonging to the baggage train of the Mahmal, which started overnight
                        for Suez. In a carriage next to the waggon containing the money travelled an
                        escort of two officers and 6 men. The waggon had been duly locked and
                        sealed, as soon as the money had been placed in it at Abbas-sieh, and at
                        each station at which the train stopped the escort got down and formed up on
                        each side of it. On reaching Genife station, just before Suez, the escort
                        found one of the seals broken, and investigation at Suez revealed the fact
                        that a case containing L.E. 8,000 in gold had disappeared.</p>
                    <p>How the money was removed from the train is a mystery. There was no
                        foot-board, by which an agile thief could have reached the waggon while in
                        motion, and the weight of the case being over 50 okes appears to preclude
                        the possibility of only one thief having been concerned. It is also
                        remarkable that the thieves were able to select one of the three cases
                        containing gold. Of course, this may be a case of fortune having favored the
                        enterprise.</p>
                    <p>Investigations are being made by the police and the Parquet into the matter,
                        and we hear that Morice Bey is actively engaged on the spot. The whole case
                        presents very extraordinary features, and the theft appears to bo the work
                        of at least two very ingenious criminals.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H. H the Khedive returned from his Ismailia estates to Koubbeh yesterday. His
                        Highness will be at Abdeen to-morrow.</p>
                    <p>His Highness has been pleased to bestow the following grades on the
                        undermentioned gentlemen :—</p>
                    <p>Mirmiran . Ibrahim Klhattab Pasha, notable of Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Abdel-Al Abd Errazek Bey, Cairo . Ahmed Eddai Bey, Cairo ; Mohamed Abounnasr
                        Bey, Alexandria ; Ismail Hafez: Bey, Alexandria ; Hassan Bakry Bey. Sanieh
                        Mohamed Tewfik Ettourgonman Bey. director of the “l’Ecole de la Mère T Abbas
                        1 ", Mohamed Hanafy El-Hennawi Bey, Cairo , Mahmoud Roustom Aids Boy,
                        landowner . lieirgiiis Abd Echéhid Boy, Bebah; Mahmoud Yoasin Bey, Abonsir
                        El-Mal.ik, Hassan Mohamed Essawi Bey, Mi'-ieh . Mourad Ecbéréi Bey, Minieh ;
                        Matta Eddaïf Bey. Minieh , Dr. Abd el-Hamid Parid Bey, Zagazig ; Mahmoud
                        Ahmed Youssef Ihwlallah Bey. Ras el-Khalig, (Qharbioh) ; Ibra-lim Moliamed
                        Youssol Boy, Cherbine, (Qhar-web) , Mustapha Said Ahmad Ramadan Boy, Kesta,
                        Gharbielij , Naguib Chakra Bey, Mah-iioud Hsssib Bey, of the reviow
                        "Magallet-el-Wagallat" , Alslallah El-Gberiani Bey, Alex-oelria , Ibrahim
                        Bey Hamdy, ïsmall Bey Lain b.</p>
                    <p>Salissah (with the title of Bey) : Bassili Mansour el-Gabalawi Bey, Cairo</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLISH CHURCH AT TANTAH.</head>
                    <p>The Church Council have issued an abstract of the accounts of the English
                        Church at Tantah since the beginning of the movement there to 31st December,
                        1904. The local fund shows a credit balance of a little over £8, and the
                        S.P.G.. fund of something like £16. The council, however, make an appeal for
                        sub scriptions in aid of the local fund. The objects of the latter are (l)
                        to cover the rent of Church House. (This the local com-munity in Tantah will
                        meet, but extra help is asked for the land and building referred to in next
                        item) ; (II) purchase of land on which to build a small Church House, the
                        church to be on ground floor and chaplain's residence above it. Payment of
                        rent will then cease and the whole of the money now going on item No. I will
                        be available for No. Ill ; (III) subscrip-tion to S, P G (Society for the
                        Propagation of the Gospel) to help their grant for chaplain's stipend.</p>
                    <p>What is principally wanted is land on which to build a Church House, and
                        that, we believe, would cost from £120 and £150. Wo shall be glad to receive
                        and acknowledge subscriptions for this deserving objeot, or they may be sent
                        direct to Mr. F. Murrell Wright, hon. secretary and treasurer, English
                        Church Fund, Tantah.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. "Heathfield," of the Prince line, from London, left Falmouth on
                        Saturday last, with general cargo, &amp;c , for Malta and Alex</p>
                    <p>andria.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. "Grecian Prince,” from Manchester, left Malta on Monday last and is
                        due here on Friday, with passengers and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Khédivial S.S. "Mariout" will leave Alexandria on Saturday and Port-Said
                        on Sunday for Jaffa, Caiffa, Beyrouth, Tripoli, Mersina and
                        Alexandritta.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EMPRESS EUGENIE</head>
                    <p>ARRIVAL IN CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>The ex Empress Eugenie, travelling incognita as the Comtesse do Pierrefonds,
                        arrived at Cairo last night, viA Port Said, and is staying at the Savoy
                        Hotel.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT.</head>
                    <p>The Duke and Duchess of Connaught will start for Cairo as soon as possible
                        after landing to morrow forenoon. A special train will be awaiting the Royal
                        party on the quays.</p>
                    <p>The landing of the Royal party at the Arsenal wharf being private, the publie
                        will not be admitted to the Arsenal yard.</p>
                    <p>T.R.H. will be met on their arrival at Cairo by the Earl of Cromer, the
                        Ministers, and Mr. Vincent Corbet</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAIRO SEASON.</head>
                    <p>The latest “Pall Mall Gazette" to hand remarks :—</p>
                    <p>The Cairo season this year will present some exceptional features. Next week
                        the Duke of Connaught will put in an appearance, on his way up to Khartoum,
                        and will, doubtless, be reminded of the first time he was there — the day
                        after Tel-el-Kebir. Lord Wolseley, who is cruising in Levantine waters, may
                        not impossibly look in. There is a certain bridge he will hardly cross
                        without reminiscence of the "Good morning" ho gave Hamley there. Hamley
                        thought he had earned something more than that, and Lord Wolseley has learnt
                        since what it feels like when the powers that be do not behave quite well to
                        you.</p>
                    <p>Then, his Grace of Devonshire, and his neighbour at Newmarket, Sir Ernest
                        Cassel, are due to arrive in Egypt in time to welcome the Inspector-General
                        of the Army. Sir Ernest has "been there," before ; his Grace not quite so
                        often. Monte Carlo has been mostly the limit of his search for sunshine. One
                        can imagine him contemplating the Sphinx without any particular appreciation
                        of its reason to be, and the Pyramids from a Whig's point of view of
                        Pharaoh, tempered with a constitutional wonder that any fellow should have
                        taken such a lot of trouble</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="army">
                    <head>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                    <p>We are authorised to contradict the statement made by a Cairo contemporary on
                        Monday that the Royal Berkshire Regiment rod the 2nd Battalion of the Rifle
                        Brigade are shortly leaving Egypt and will not be replaced ; nor is there
                        any intention to further reduce the number of British troops in this
                        country.</p>
                    <p>Wo may also state that the other statement of our confrère, that the barracks
                        at Kaar-el-Nil, now occupied by the Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, and those
                        newly built it Abbassieh are to be vacated and made ' over to the Egyptian
                        Army, is wholly devoid of foundation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA AND PORT SAID. NOVEL SUGGESTION.</head>
                    <p>A well-known member of the German oolony at Alexandria sends us the following
                        communication:—</p>
                    <p>There are a good many people, and I belong to them, who think that Port Said
                        means a danger to the future of Alexandria. The new ’ full gauge railway to
                        Port Said and the various * harbour improvements planned there are so many
                        blows dealt at the further development ' of our city. Alexandrians ought to
                        bestir themselves and devise means bow to meet and possibly obviate the
                        threatening danger. While still in time I venture to throw out an idea in
                        his direction. Why not bring the Suez Capal ' to the doors of Alexandria By
                        straightening, widening and deepening the Mahmoudioh Canal, ' continuing it
                        across the Rosetta and Damietta branches of the Nile, and making it join the
                        Suez Canal somewhere near Ismailia or at the Bitter Lakes, a second waterway
                        for the shipping trade to and from the East could bo created, by which
                        Alexandria ' would bo bene-fitted in the same way as Port Said now is by the
                        Lesseps canal.</p>
                    <p>There ought to be no more technical diffi-mlties concerning the execution of
                        such an undertaking across cultivated country, than there were in the case
                        of the Manchester ship canal or the canal that unites the Baltio and North
                        seas. </p>
                    <p>In case of the existence of a monopoly in favour-of the 8uez Canal it ought
                        not to be forgotten that after some 60 years the present ( Suez Canal
                        becomes the property of the Egyptian State.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SLAVE DEALER SENTENCED.</head>
                    <p>A court-martial sitting at Abdeen barracks J has condemned the Bishareen
                        Mohamed Hussein, found guilty of slave-dealing near the Red Sea coast, to
                        seven years’ hard labour.</p>
                    <p>It will be remembered that the accused and his brother wore recently captured
                        by a patrol from Etbai, acting on information received, while taking a
                        Sudanese girl called Hawn, whom Mohamed had bought, to sell to Hedjazi
                        traders.</p>
                    <p>Hamed Hussein, the brother of the accused, has been acquitted.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Management. Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>H. R. H the Archduke Otto of Austria Alexandria for Marseilles to-day by the
                        , North German Lloyd S.S. "Schleswig."</p>
                    <p>Prinoe Mirza Arfat Ed-Dawlah Khan has had to give up his proposed Nile trip
                        and leaves Alexandria by the "Tchitchagoff for</p>
                    <p>Constantinople on Friday.</p>
                    <p>General de Negrier arrived at Alexandria by the Messageries Maritimes steamer
                        this morning, and after paying a visit to Cairo will go on to Abyssinia.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Thaddeus Count Bolesta Kozsiedrodzki, the new Austro-Hungarian Diplomatie
                        Agent, arrived by the 7.20 p.m. express at Cairo on Monday night,
                        accompanied by Coant Stadnicky. He will visit Alexandria next Saturday for
                        the Austro-Hungarian charity ball.</p>
                    <p>The P &amp; 0. S.S. "Macedonia” (Capt C. D. Bennett, R.N.R.), which arrived
                        at Port Said yesterday afternoon, brought one hundred and fifty-three
                        passengers for Egypt, among the moat distinguished being the Duke and
                        Duchess of Devonshire, Earl and Countess Dalbousie, Marchiness of Donegal,
                        Lady and Miss G. Goret, Major the Hon. and Mrs. Bourke, General Sir J.
                        Maxwell, the ex-Empress Eugenie, (Comtesse de Pierrelonds), Comte Primoli,
                        and Comte Clary.</p>
                    <p>A large number of visitors who arrived by the "Macedonia” proceeded to the
                        Savoy yesterday evening, amongst them the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire,
                        General Maxwell, Mr. George Faber, M.P., Lord and Lady Dal-housie, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Maguire, etc. All these parties had reservod their suites beforehand
                        and the Savoy was quite fall yesterday evening.</p>
                    <p>Sir Thomas Lipton is expected at the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, to-day.</p>
                    <p>The Savoy Restaurant is fall up every evening, many residents being usually
                        to be seen among the Savoy's visitors. Yesterday evening wo noticed the
                        Archduke Otto and a party of 4, Mr. Birkenruth and a party of 8, Mr. Phillip
                        and Baroness Reinlein and a party of 6, the Earl and Countess of
                        Londesborough and party, including Mr. Vincent Corbett and Lord George
                        Cholmondeley, Capt. the Hon. Stanley and party, including Col. and Mrs. J.
                        K. Watson, Mr. Mac hell aud Mr. Guest, the Master of Ellibank, etc.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Lawford, who has been representing the Egyptian Government at the St.
                        Louis Exhibition, has returned to Cairo.</p>
                    <p>The following passengers left Shellal by the "Memnon" to-day -Mr. Brand, Mr.
                        Alfred John, Mrs. Camisky, Miss Chance, Miss Dudgeon, Mrs. E. Cochrane, Miss
                        Cochrane, Miss Booth, Mr. Tunbridge, Mrs. Stevens, Mr. and Mrs. L. S.
                        Montague, Mme. Chanliagent.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUNICIPAL DELEGATION.</head>
                    <p>(Communication officielle)</p>
                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s’est réunie le 24 janvier 1905 à 4 h. p.m. sous la
                        présidence de M. Amb. A. Ralli.</p>
                    <p>Préseuts : MM. Fcnderl, Mansour Bey Youssef, K Strosa, Dr. G. Vole nain,
                        membres, W. P. Chat away, administrateur, I. Sedky, secrétaire.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation prend note et décide de soumettre &amp; la Commission, deux
                        lettres de S. E. lo Ministre de l'Intérieur informant 1* qu'il approuve le
                        budget de 1905, 3* qu’il se voit obligé de suspendre le règlement sur le*
                        chiens et la rage, le Ministère ayant mis à l'étude un règlementqui devra
                        s’appliquer i tout^l'Egyptc.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation fiait remarquer à oet égard qu'étant donné le* circonstanciés,
                        U y aurait lieu d’insister pour permettre à la Municipalité d'appliquer à
                        title provisoire son règlement jusqu'à oe que d'aatroa mesures générales
                        interviennent.</p>
                    <p>Va la lettre de 8 JS. le Ministre des Finances relative à la question de
                        l'agrandissement du pont route du Gabbari et demandant à la Municipalité de
                        contribuer à cette dépense à raison de LE. 6,000 en y oomprenant l’appoint
                        des corporations intéressées telles que le Commerce d'exportation, les
                        tramways, etc., la Délégation se référant à la oorrespuudanoe échangée dans
                        le temps à oe sujet avec l'administration des chemins de for et de laquelle
                        il résulte que la oontribation demandée était de L.B. 4,000 au minimum, mais
                        désirant participer dans la pins large mesure possiblo à ce travail
                        d'ntilité publique, décide de proposer à la Corn, de fixer la contribution
                        municipale à L.E. 2,500, oe qui ajouté aux LE. 1,500 promises par le
                        oommeroe d'exportation, et L.E. 1,000 promises par la Sté des tramways
                        portera à LE. 5,000 la contribution de la ville à oe travail dont le ooût
                        est évalué par loi chemins de fer à L.E. 17.000.</p>
                    <p>Va la lettre do la Cie de Ramleh tendant à oe qu'elle .oit autorisée à
                        établir un butoir et une guérite au terminus de sa ligne, la Délégation
                        estime que n'ayant reçu aucune réponse de la Cie en oe qui concerne 1a
                        question du droit de oontrôie que la ville désire appliquer dans l'intérêt
                        du public, elle se voit obligée de ne donner aucune suite à la nouvelle
                        demande de la Société.</p>
                    <p>la Délégation prend note et décide de soumettre à la Commission nne lettre de
                        S. R le Ministre de l'Intérieur informant qu'il ne voit pas d'objection à ce
                        que la ville prenne possession pour la transformer en pare d'nne partie dn
                        terrain de l'bfipital bordant la rue d'Allemagne.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation déoide de mettre en eradication les travaux de pavage en
                        vieilles dalles de 8 rue* et ruéOee des quartiers d'Anfouohjr.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>QUESTIONS MUNICIPALES</head>
                    <p>Un placement de 30,000 L.S.</p>
                    <p>Si le Gouvernement et les contribuables, excédés par le gaspillage qui se
                        fait à la Municipalité, se décidaient enfin à remplacer le système actuel
                        par on système pins pratique, d'où le fonctionnarisme serait exclu, il
                        resterait pour le senrioe de la ville un excédent de recettes d'au moins
                        50,000 lrvreo, actaellemmt consacrées à payer an innombrable p—onnel qui ne
                        fait rien, ou qni fait des riens, ce qd «et la même chose. Supposons eooote
                        que cette heureuse modification ait lieu demain, usa que la nouvelle
                        administration garde en ses mains l’excédent ainsi obtenu sans jamais an
                        tandis compte. Partout ailleurs il en ifsnltisail nne explosion
                        d’indignation publique. loi efadà peine si l’on daigne en parier.
                        L’iaditttenoo pour tout oe qui touche à l'intérêt public est telle que les
                        pires scandales n'arrivent pas à émouvoir la population.</p>
                    <p>Qu’on an juge. En 1890, la commission d’é-dilité oédait la plaça à la
                        Municipalité en laissant à œlleci un reliquat da 80,000 livrée. Dette somme,
                        au lieu de rentrer dans la eaiats oommuna, fut aooaparée par le comité daa
                        exportateur», soi-disant pour être placée à intérêt ou profit da la ville. H
                        y a quinze ans dn cela et avec l’intérêt que rapporte l'argent en Egypte
                        cette somme a pu être plus que doublée dans oe laps de tempe. Ce n'est dono
                        plus 80.000 mais 60,000 livra* sa moins dont le comité des exportateurs a
                        désormais à rendre compte.</p>
                    <p>Va-t-il se décider à restituer cette ou préférera-t-il verser un intérêt
                        proportionné. JL* résistance qu'il a constamment opposée à chaque
                        réclamation qui lui a été adressée à oe propos n'est pas faite pour calmer
                        les inquiétudes : c'eut, eu effet, sur les instanoes réitérées de plusieurs
                        membres de la Commission que le comité des exportateurs fut obligé dan« les
                        commencements de s'inscrira pour 600 livres au budget idnnicipaL Cela
                        continua pendant quelques année*. Plus tard, M. AchiUoponlo, ayant soulevé
                        de nouveau la question des 30.000 livres, se heurta à un mauvais vouloir si
                        manifeste qu'il crut de sa dignité de donner sa démission de conseiller.</p>
                    <p>Le 26 décembre 1908, M. Zouro fait remarquer que l'allocation de LE 600
                        ordinairement payée par le oommeroe d'exportation ne figure pas au budget de
                        1904. Il en demande le motif. Cette allocation devrait, ajoute-t-il, être
                        plus importante, car elle représente lee intérêts de la somme de L.B. 30,000
                        qui restait en caisse lors do la création de la Municipalité. La
                        Municipalité dépense bien plus que le montant de cette allocation pour
                        l'entretien da quartier de Minet-el-Bassal et il est jnate qu’elle profite
                        du produit intégral dee fonds payés par les contribuables pour les travaux
                        d'édilité.</p>
                    <p>On lui répond que, cette année, le oommeroe d’exportation a fiait face à die
                        grosses dépenses pour l’achat d'nne pompe automobile et de tuyaux ainsi qne
                        poor dss réparations A la pompe flottante. Les intérêts et pins ont été
                        consacrés à ces frais ; s'il y a des intérêts disponibles ils seront à la
                        disposition de la Municipalité.</p>
                    <p>N’est-ce pas exquis t On fait remarquer an détenteur illicite d'une somme que
                        s'il ne veut pas la restituer il ait du moins à en servir lee intérêts au
                        créancier et il répond que s'il lui reste quelque chose après avoir fiait
                        ses petites fredaines, U y songera et l'affaire en est restée là.</p>
                    <p>Cette année, le oomité des exportateur* s'est inscrit pour 800 livres, alors
                        que la somme qu'il détient, capitalisée depuis 15 ans, doit représenter un
                        intérêt supérieur à 3,000 livres.</p>
                    <p>Il serait temps, croyons-nous, de s'expliquer. Que le oomité rende oompte de
                        sa gestion et fasse oonnaltre le montant actuel du capital qu’il s'est
                        chargé lui-même d'exploiter. La situation actuelle peut d’autant moins
                        s’éterniser que l’entretien des rues de Minet-el-Bsssal, auquel la dite
                        somme était destinée, est tombée entièrement à la charge de la Municipalité,
                        du jour où MM. les exportateurs s'en sont emparés, ne voulant ni entretenir
                        les rues en question ni affecter à oet entretien les intérêt* du oapital
                        qu’ils détiennent St que les producteurs de ooton avaient destinés à oet
                        ussge.</p>
                    <p>Si oe Messieurs s'obstinent à garder le secret sur leurs bénéfices, fl y a
                        .un moyen bien simple pour la Municipalité de le* contraindre à parler,
                        c'est de cesser d'entretenir les ruos de Minehel-BassoL Comme elles servent
                        à peu près exclusivement au commerce et principalement au oommeroe
                        d'exportetioo, celui-ci devra bien y pourvoir dans son propre intérêt. Et
                        lorsque le comité réolamera à la Municipalité, oe sera au tour de oelle-ci
                        do faire la sourde oreille. Malheureusement les membres du oomité étant
                        aussi membres de la Commission on se trouve en face de deux têtes sous un
                        même bonnet C'est pour ce motif que oela a pu durer quinze ans et que dans
                        15 autres années la solution ne sera pas plus avancée.</p>
                    <p>Le oomité des exportateurs ne s’est pas contenté de garder pour lai le magot,
                        il s'est débarrassé du même coup de son lot de vieux employés et de vieux
                        matériaux, dotant ainsi là Municipalité naissante du germe du
                        fonctionnarisme qui l'étouffera.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
