<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Valerie Curcio</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-11-08</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-05-18</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, MAY 18,1905</head>
<div type="item"><p>Large Assortment oF Old and NEw Carpets,
ALL MADE BY HAND.
Purveyors to all large CARPET IMPORTERS in Europe and America.
LOOMS and DYE WORKS in all centres of production in Asia, employing 10,000 workmen.
CARPETS made to order in all sizes and dyed with permanent vegetable colours.
I«r Great Choice of Rich Designs. "»l
MODERATE, FIXED PRICES.—Central Hovse : SMYRNA, Est. 1842. Branch in London
Cairo Show Rooms s Rond-Point Soliman Pacha, opposite Savoy Hotel.
25366—31-1-906</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>OUR LONDON LETTER.
( From Our Correspondent .)
London, May 11.
The most serious factor in the neutrality
question is the growing anger of Japan at the
help which Fruneo seems to be giving Admiral
Rodjestvensky, or allowing him to take. Our
allies, as is perhaps not unnatural in the air
circumstances, have shown a certain inability ft)
appreciate the extreme delicacy of European
diplomacy. They were irritated because wo
did not speak more strongly to Russia. It is
not to be expected that they should preserve
their equanimity at the inaction of France.
Nor can France herself rest and be satisfied
much longer. She has an imperative duty to
perform. But the Japanese must not forget —
and their high official representatives no doubt
recognize the responsibility as clearly as any-
body that in protesting with undue vehe-
mence they will be playing Russia’s game. A
drastic policy against France might drawGreat
Britain also into the confliot, and then Russia’s
extreme difficulties would be over. Her face
would be saved. And what matter if other
people's countenances became downcast 1 We
believe Japan will proceed cautiously, and, on
the other hand, have equal faith that France
will see the situation in its proper light.
Europe has batter cause than over to be grate-
ful that M. Delcasse retained office. He is an
asset on the side of honesty and peace.
The fact that Japan is England’s ally is
not sufficient to account for English enthusiasm
over the victories of Togo and Oyama. There
are other reasons: among them the national
habit of being on the side of the “little chap,”
and natural pleasure of seeing a bluffing bully
brought to earth. Can it be, as Quida suggests
iu the “Fortnightly,” that we have allowed
sentiment to over balance judgment! The
prophetess foretells woe, and nothing bat woe,
as the consequence of Japan’s triumph. A
terrible fate is preparing for us while we are
congratulating the real foe. If the yellow
race is superior to the white, then must the
white go to the wall. If we think that, having
tasted blood and the joy of conquest, the
Japanese will return to the painting of
chrysanthemums and the making of tea-trays,
we are sadly mistaken. Quida says so, and
adds that the horizon is red with fire. She
believes in the Yellow Peril as strongly as the
old philosophers believed in the elixir of life. ,
But the forgets that there are yellow men and
yellow men, Obiuete and Koreans as well as <
Japanese; forgets also—what we are all in .
danger of forgetting—that iu the first shock i
ol surprise we have perhaps gilded the Japanese .
virtues with too much retiued gold. II—we say, i
if—the yellow mau were the sublime and i
superhuman genius which some zealots declare
him to be, Ouida’s foreboding would be
justified, aud the Yellow Peril might make ns
all Ilussophiles. But the yellow mau is only
man alter all, and none ol us are pure gold
throughout, though he is one of the best.
The Admiralty announcement as to the
postponement of the summer mana'uvrea is a
model of suppressed significance. The manoeu-
vres may cause inconvenience if carried out as
planned ; if not carried out as planned they
would serve no useful purpose. Rodjestvensky
and Togo hold the waters, and till they have
finished it will be safer for us not to play at
war in their neighbourhood. A
British squadron might be mistaken for a
fishing fleet—there is really no saying what
might happen—and in those circumstances no
international commission would be able to
avert horrible consequences. There is an irony
in the picture called np by the imagination of
the British Navy playing at sailors and coming
into unintentional oonflict with the Russian
and Japanese Davies. It will be far better not
to run the risk. Yet from one point of view we
cannot but regret the decision, sensible as it
is from all other points of view. There will be
bo much to be learned from the great fight, if
and when it comes off, that a British fleet might
have acted the part of ourions spectator with
advantage to itself and perhaps to other people.
It is said that the struggle between Lord
Kitchener and the civil authorities in India
turns upon a grandiose proposal of Lord Kit-
chener’s to plant a line of great military camps
along the Northern frontier. The proposal
would involve an expenditure of £10,000,000,
and is vehemently opposed by all the members
of Lord Cnrzon’s Council, including Lord
Curzon himself. The quarrel places the homo
Government in a very difficult position, for
Mr. Brodrick must know only too well that
Lord Kitchener’s best arguments for these
gigantic defensive measures against a possible
Russian attack can be drawn from Mr. Balfour’s
speeches. The Prime Minister may have to
pay dearly for bis various Russian scares. The
probability is that a compromise will be reach
ed and the peril of Lord Kitchener’s return
averted. At any rate the Government is likely
to make many efforts to prevent Lord Kit-
chener’s return to England ’ anmauled” on
the eve of a general election,
Prom a military standpoint, it is an exceed-
ingly grave matter that the plague should
have selected the Punjaubfor its most ter-
rible devastations in India. That usually
healthy province actually suffered a loss of a
quarter of a million of its inhabitants, out of
about twenty millions, in three months last
year, and since then, as the “Lancet" shows
from official statistics, the rate of plague mort-
ality has materially augmented. As the Land
of the Five Rivers supplies the native army
with its most efficient recruits, including those
born soldiers, the Sikhs, Lord Kitchener may
be forced to lessen his demands on its physi-
cal resources. Daring recent years the oon-
cinuons tendency of the Indian War Office has
been in the other direction, Madras and
Burmese troops being more and more stiffened
by recruiting in Northern India. But the
surge of Asia evidently declines to subscribe
to this racial re-arrangement; last week, while
the number of deaths from the disease in
Burmah was only 72, and in Madras 81, the
Punjanb suffered a shrinkage of over 19,000.
Odd to say, this extraordinary disparity of
plagae mortality between the hardier and less
hardy populations is manifest almost through-
out the peninsula. Whereas last week’s deaths
in the Central Provinces number Jover twenty-
three thousand, Bengal, with its enormous aud
physically inferior population, lost no more
than 9,703.</p>
<p>The Stonehenge ease has no doubt attract-
ed the attention of the public to the ancient
monuments which still exist in Great Britain,
and an article in the "Quarterly Review”
which deals with the subject of their preser-
vation is of more than passing interest The
writer points out that here in England we
take far less heed of the memorials of the
past than they do in other countries. France
takes official notice of over two thousand
monuments, and included in the list are
over three hundred dolmens. In Germany
the Ministers of Public Instruction and of
the Interior have charge of all ancient monu-
ments, and appoint official custodians to look
alter them. Even the smaller States show
anxiety to protect the monuments of their
past history, and all of them pay more offi-
cial attention to the subject than we do in
England. We have an Ancient Monuments
Act, but want of money causes it to remain
almost a dead letter. There is now no In-
spector of Ancient Monuments, and there is
no official machinery to deal with cases of
vandalism. The writer of tho article calls
attention to several instances which show
that many of our most valuable monuments
exist only by accident, and not because they
have been properly taken care of. The habit '
our ancestors had of building cottage with
Roman and prehistoric walls is largely re-
sponsible for the loss of many priceless relics, '
and it cannot be said that the danger of
this sort of vandalism is yet completely past.
A hundred years ago this week Schiller died
peacefully at Weimar after a life into which
much physical suffering was crowded, and
wherever the German language is spoken festi-
vities are held in memory of Germany’s greates'
poet. It is interesting to note that his last
direct descendant, Alexander, Freiherr von
Gleichen-Russwurm, the grandson of Schiller's
youngest daughter Emilie, is taking au active
part in several of the celebrations. On Saturday,
when Schiller’s birthplace was en fete, he was
at Morbacb, on Sunday at Stuttgart, and
yesterday he was the chief speaker at the
imposing festival at Cologne, while three weeks
ago he had officiated in the same capacity
amoDg the Germans at Rome. Freiherr von
Gleiohen-RuBswunn is forty years old, and
after leaving the German Army some years ago
he devoted himself entirely to literary pursuits,
and has had the satisfaction of seeing one of
his plays, "The Comedy of Conscience," per-
formed on the famous Weimar stage.
Discussing the part played by medicine in
colonization the "British Medical Journal”
says that to Laveran we owe the discovery
which marked the dawn of a new era in tro-
pical pathology and sanitation, and from this
idee mere of a parasitic origin of a disease
which has been a mystery sinoe the beginning
of civilisation has sprang, especially daring the
last fifteen years, a series of other discoveries
which have gone far to justify the statement
made by Sir Patrick Manson before the Royal
Geographical Society in 1898 that 99 per cent,
of tropical diseases were caused by germs.
Climate may cause discomfort and enerva-
tion, and may predispose to disease, bat the
real enemy of the white man in tropioal dimes
and the great obstacle to colonisation is the
wealth of parasitic life, whioh finds in him a
ready prey. In the discovery of means of de-
stroying these parasites or neutralizing their
power of mischief lies the secret of acclimatisa-
tion. The prosperity of our empire, perhaps
the existence of our country, depends to a
large extent on the successful development of
the material resources of oar Colonies, and this
in turn depends on the increased possibilities
of acclimatisation. This is the chief practical
' problem which the schools of tropioal medicine
have been brought into existence to solve.
At a conference organised by the Church
Association and National Protestant League
yesterday it was decided, the motion of Mr.
Ati'Ln T y'or, that a supreme effort should
be made to influence the candidates at the
aiming General Election, so that oidy staunch
Protestants xLould bes-nt to Pur i-iment,aince
tho grave and vital question of the Protestant-
ism of the Church of England would have to
be dctlt with aud decided by that Parliament,
and that a fund of not less than £30,000
should be appealed for to enable a vigorous
Protestant electoral campaign to be carried
out whenever a dissolution was announced.
Christ's College, Cambridge, which is cele-
brating 'ho 400th anniversary of tho re-fonoda-
tiou by Margaret Beaufort, was first founded
as "God's House" in 1448 by Henry VI. owing
to "a great scarcity of masters of grammar.”
It was the Alma Mater not only of John Milton
but of the famous if little read “Cambridge
Platonifcts." Mark Pattison’s theory that Milton
turned Puritan through antipathy to his
Laudian tutor Chappell, by whom be was
"whipt,” seems unconvincing; for the poet, in
the "Apology for Smectymnus,” refers to the
"courteous and learned Fellows" of his old
College. Including Milton, five poets are
claimed for Christ’s by Dr. Peile, the Master
and historian of the College, but that beloved
of bards, C. S. Calverley, is surely entitled to
a sixth place among the brotherhood.
The trustees of the British Museum have
decided to make an addition to their collection
of "human documents," which will be at onoe
unique, and of great interest They have
accepted the offer of some of the companies
which occupy themselves with the phono-
graphic reproduction of coal utterances to
supply them with a series of such records for
permanent preservation. The choice will be
carefully restricted, being confined, it is under-
stood, to speeches of real importance, and
they will be available “for posterity only,” in
no cose being at the service of contemporaries.
It is rosy to think how full of interest such a
collection must be. How many problems they
might solve! What would we not give, for
example, for an imperishable reproduction of
words which have become historio ? As it is,
we have to be content with the written reports
of historians, who may or may not have been
well-informed, and may or may not have been
biassed in their accounts.</p>
<p>There is a story of heroism from Dublin in
the London papers which deserves all the
prominence it can be given. Something went
wrong at a sewer manhole on the quays, and a
workman was sent down to investigate. As he
did not reappear, his two mates and the
engineer who was their superior successively
followed, likewise not to return. Then a police-
man, Constable Patrick Sheehan, was fetched
to the spot, and in spite of the overpowering
sewer gas that was issuing from the manhole,
he bravely went down into tho horrible trap,
and had sent np three of the four men fastened
to ropes before he was himself overcome. A
cab-driver and a fireman followed, and in time
an eager crowd of volunteers clamoured round
the hole for the privilege ol taking their turns
at the work of rescue. Man after man was
overpowuie-J, but it was cleared at last Un-
happily, I be original victim died in hospital,
and the brave policeman as he was being
conveyed thither. As the story of the Birken-
head was read by order to the regiments of
Prussia, so the tale of Constable Sheehan's
heroic death deserves to be read in every
police-station and from every pulpit and head-
master's desk in the United Kingdom.
In the face of agitation and common-sense,
it seems that we have got to have the cri-
noline, after all. News of the formation of an
Anti-Crinoline League leaves the autocratic
costumiers of France smiling but firm. The
return of the crinoline, it seems, is an inevit-
able consequence of the evolution of the shape
of the skiit. The more important question,
therefore, is—what are we to do with the
monster when we have got it ? Times have
changed, and a conformation that could be
endured carriage drives and gentle shop-
ping excursions is incompatible with hansoms
and hockey. The compact modern flat or
residence, too, is ill-anited to superfluity of
circumference. It almost seems as if a new
mode of feminine life would have to be evolved
to fit the new mode in garments. A simple life
it will have to be, involving the minimum of
complication in movement, and an outdoor
life, too, unless we are all prepared to rebuild
our drawing rooms. Wherefore it is to be hoped
that the crinoline, as it has to oome, may ar-
rive while the warm weaker is jet with us —
and depart before the leaves begin to fall.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>EGYPTIAN RAILWAY CONTRACTS.
According to the "Deutsche Bergwerks JJei-
tang,” the recent adjudication of the Egyptian
State Railway Administration has resulted in
the placing of an order with the North British
Looomotive Company for the supply of 32
locomotives, with the German firm of Hensohel
and Co., of Cassel, for 15 engines, the French
Ateliers de Cail for 10 looomotives and the
Socidtd Franoo-Belge for 6 engines. The order
for 105 passenger coaches has been entirely
placed with the Metropolitan Amalgamated
Railway Carriage and Wagon Company. The
Leeds Forge Company has secured the contract
for 100 thirty-ton goods wagons, and the Bel
gian firm of Baume and Marpents an order for
1,000 ten-ton wagons and 50 cattle trucks,
while 40 brake-vans are each to be supplied by
the Belgian firm of Misuse and Delane and the
SocidW Franoo-Belge,</p>
<div type="item"><p>The Standard Life Assurance Company.
K8TABUBirm> 1880.	1 J
ACCUMULATED FUWP8 AH,300,000
BONUS YEAR, 11IOB.
THE NEXT DIVISION OF PROFITS will be made -nougat participating Pol Idee In exigence atltth NoremborlW
AU IVitb Profit Polirioo ofooiod on or biforo Ikat Anto will bo onUUoA to aboro in IXo DioMon.
Tbe Company here already declared Bonne Addition, to Polldca to tbe amount of more than</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>SEVEN MILLIONS STERLING.
Head Office for Egypt: bharln Knwel-Nll, Cairo.
8 NAT8A,N, *, <;»•/,	. .	A. V. THOMSON,
______CW A/nil for Alerandna,	Secretary for Egyyt.
EGYPTIAN MINES EXPLORATION.
Mr. C. J. Alford has furnished the following ■
summary of the month’s operations.
ATALLAH MINE — April. 15th. — No. 1
shaft 260 ft. crosscut, total length 30 ft. (a
telegram has since been received from the mine
that the vein was cut 18 inches wide assaying
4 oza gold per ton)—170 ft level N.E.—10 ft
of vein averaged 3 inches wide with 6 oza 6
dwts gold—last 16 It averaged 4 inches with
3 dwts. No. 2 shaft, 195 ft level N.E., 142
ft, last 26 ft vein averaged 4 inches with a
little gold. 195 ft level S.W., 132 ft, last 20 ft
averaged 7 inches wide, 1 os 14 dwts gold per
ton. No. 2 Incline, 800 ft crosscut to vein, 52
ft in granite.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ER1DIA MINE—April 15th.—No. 1 shaft,
crosscut to vein at second level 14 ft, in
granite. No. 1 crosscut N drive 98 ft, last 6 ft
vein averaged 10 inches wide, 2 dwts gold, i
Winze down 82 ft, vein 18 inches, 1 dwt No.
2 crosscut N drive 108 ft, last 10 ft vein
averaged 18 inches wide, 16 dwts gold. 8 drive
99 ft, last 10 ft averaged 14 inohes wide, 5
dwts gold. No. 8 shaft 100 ft level N, 86 ft,
last 10 ft averaged 80 inohes wide, 12 dwts
gold per ton. 100 ft level 8, vein 30 inohes
wide, 18.5 dwts.</p>
<div type="item"><p>SEMNA MINE—Work suspended daring
summer months.
Cheap Prepaid Advertisements
Under this heading advertisements are in-
serted at the following rates :—
ONCE 3 TIMES 6 TIMES
15 words . . . P.T.	5	P.T.	10	P.T.	15
30 words ...	„	8	„	16	„	1A
Bvery 10 words, \	9	. R
beyond 30. . . / »	2	--	*	••	6
The address is connected. The advertisement
most appear on consecutive days for above
rates to be obtained. 50% extra is charged
for advertisements not appearing consecutively.
All such advertisements most be prepaid, and
to this rule no acception whatever will
be made. Letters in reply to advertise-
ments will be posted to any address if a
few stamps are sent by the advertiser to
cover postage.</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>HEALTH UTTERLY BROKEN.
ANiEMIA, NERVOUS BREAKDOWN,
INDIGESTION, RAPID WA8TING,
PALPITATIONS, INCIPIENT
CONSUMPTION.
CURED BY DR. WILLIAM8’
PINK PILLS.
Serrible breakdown,
iher^enlt of lade of
given by Mrs. Lux-
Anatnia led to a com- 
plication of disorders and tors 1 “u,!d find]
threatening Consumption, consulted, a s i d
Dr. Williams' Pink PUlsBha- t*oh of them
effected a complete cure. 8av® complaint
a different name, but my friends thought I was
in consumption.</p>
<p>So Weak and Frail had I become that I
could neither eat, sleep, nor work.
"For some time I had suffered very "badly
from indigeston and a nervous breakdown. 1
lost hope of ever being better, and never
thought I should get out again. I had palpita-
tions and severe pains in the chest. I fell away
to a shadow. All food was repugnant.
"The Consumption I was hastening to was
really due to lack of blood. Dr. Williams’ Pink
Pills gave me the blood I needed so badly, and
that is why they oured me when do ordinary
remedies could. Other medicine might brace
me np, but what I wanted was new blood.”
"How soon after beginning Dr. Williams’
Pink Pills did you feel a change ?”
"After I had taken two boxes I began to feel
a different woman. I took five or six boxes,
and by that time could eat my meals and en-
joy them. I have since taken Dr. Williams’
Pink Pills when I required a tonio, but my old
oomplaint has never returned."</p>
<p>Loss of appetite is a sign that food is not
digesting. Weakness and Bile naturally follow.
The splendid appetite which Dr. Williams’Pink
Pills give shows that they oure Indigestion at
once. They do it by making New Blood.
Mothers know why they and their daughters
need new blood more than men ; bnt men can
be Anwmio, too. The weak book, easy fatigue,
lack of interest in life, and general nervous
weakness which trouble both men and women,
need New Blood to cure them. Nerves that
need new blood to feed them show their need
in Neuralgia, fits, St Vitos' dance, eventually
Paralysis, locomotor ataxy and utter breakdown.
Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills for Pale People can
cure all these things: but only the genuine
pills. To avoid substitutes, purchasers should
take care to see the fall name, as above, on the
wrapper, before paying.
Sold in Egypt by all chemists at P.T. 13 per
box or P.T. 70 per 6 boxes. Can be bought at
the general depbt: Max Fischer, Cairo, Hotel
da Nil St (1st floor), and Alexandria, Rue
Stamboul, No. 8,</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>ADVERTISING AGENTS.—The bestpnblio
a Advertising sites in Alexandria belong to
G. Veetzi & Co., Advt Agents, St Cathenne's
Square. Special rates for permanent clients.
Moderate terms. Prompt despatch.
25642-31-12-905
A RABIC LESSONS given by an 1
•A*- tutor to Europeans. Apply M.
“Egyptian Gazette' offioee.
A PPLY for French, Italian, Arabic, German,
to the Berlitx Schools, Alexandria (26,
Rue de l’Eglise Copto) j Cairo Sharia Kamel),
Most rapid method Trial lesson free. Evening
classes at Alexandria, P.T. 60 per month.
23069-80-9A-905
"DUCK TYPEWRITERS, No. 5 £9, No. 7
A* £11. W.T. Emmons, 99 Rue Attarine,
Alexandria, Address, Poet Office Box 35.
30-6-905A
DORMAN & Co. have just received a new
X> supply of Tennis Balls, Rackets, and
Cricket Bats.	259806-2
DORMAN & Co.—Suits to measure from
D P.T. 250. Best English doth, latest fit
and style guaranteed.	25981-6-2
EXPERIENCED NURSE would take charge
A of infant for free passage to England
June, July. Apply, No. 25,949, "Egyptian
Gazette” Offioe.	26949-6-5
EOR SALE.—Cart, Donkey, and Harness.
A £25. Apply, No. 26,952, “ Egyptian
Gazette” Office.	25962-6-5
GENUINE PANAMA HATS for sales, very
u good quality, very cheap price. At Mal-
luk’B, Mousky, Cairo.	25959-12-4</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>DAVIES
BRYAN
& Co.
ContinentalHotelBuildings,
CAIRO,
St. David's Buildings,
ALEXANDRIA,
and 35 - 37 Noble Street
LONDON, E.O.
English Tailors
Drapers
and Outfitters.
Beg respectfully;to an-
nounce that they have
received their various
stocks in the latest
styles suitable for the
present Season.
utm:
A large assortment of
Blacks, Blues, Scotch,
Irish & Harris Tweeds.
All garments cut by ex-
perienced English Cut-
ters, fit and style gua-
ranteed.</p>
<p>A varied stock of
Ladies’ Blouses, Boas,
Skirts, Belts, &c.
Careful attention is
GOVERENERS CART, in good condition,
'J with pony, required. Apply to R.O.D.,
P.O.B. 686, Cairo.	25977-6-2
HOUSE TO LET, Summer months! Position
near sea. Apply No. 25,983, "Gazette’’
Office.	25983-6-1</p>
<div type="item"><p>MOUNTAIN CAMP, for
-DA iner holidays. Apply,
B.A., Headmaster, HnglTnh
CAMP, for boys during turn
lays. Apply, Peroival Mayali,
»r, English School, Cyprus.
25921-48-10
"VTURSE WANTED for two English children.
A" £24. Apply, No. 25,972, “ Egyptian
Gazette” offices.	25792-6-3
SINGING LESSONS recommended by the
famous tenor Jkam dr Reszke given by
I Herr B. Wechaler of Heiddberg University.
| Voice production systematic. Apply for trial
lesson, press extracts, Herr B. Weohaler, Post
Office, Cairo.	26929-12-9
J TO LET.—Furnished house with five rooms,
| A situated in the best quarter of Alexandria,
: to let for 8 months, July, August, and Septem-
ber. Apply to A. J. Venieri, P. 0. Box 349,
Alexandria.	26946-6-6</p>
<div type="item"><p>HALL’S “BOAR’S HEAD” BRND.
Guinness’s T-B-HALL Bass’s
Extra pjf . «SS£=5» .^0 Pale
e°ARs head e*
StOUt	Al<1'
LIGHT 8PARKLINO FALX ALL
T. bThALL&Co., Ltd. *^2SSE «-
Bole Importer for Egypt °"<i ikt Bu4an •
G. MARCUS & Go.
ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO sad TANIA. *M
TO LET, on very moderate terms, a Stable
at Bolkeley. Apply, Manager, Carlton
Hotel.	25970-3-3
TO I
i E
TO LET FURNISHED 2-3 rooms, Ismailieh.
A Klectrio light; bath. Independent en-
trance. Bnglish,Poste Restante,Cairo. 25965-6-8
TO LET at Alexandria, off Rosette-road, for
-L the summer, a large, airy, roomy, Fur-
nished House ; eight rooms ; garden ; terms
moderate- For particulars apply, Magasins
Victoria, Alexandria.	25963-6-3
House ; two flats; garden ; splendid situa-
tion. Apply, No. 25,854, "Egyptian Gazette”
Offioes.	25982-6-1</p></div>
<div type="item"><p>WANTED at Port Sudan, for Government
YV Works, a typewriting English Clerk,
salary L.R 15 per mensum. Applications in
writing to Aset. Director of Works, War
Offioe, Cairo.	25966-8
suitable for Tours up
the Nile.
GENTS’
OUTFITTING:
The latest novelties in Ties,
Collars, Shirts, Gloves, &c.
Hosiery in all the newest
makes, (Camel Hair brand
a speciality).
We are also making a special display
in the Drapery Department, con-
sisting of Household Linen, Blan-
kets, Calicoes, Eider-down Qnilts,
Cushions,&o.,Ao., which are mark-
ed at such figures aa to command
YY Works, an estimating Draughtsman,
salary L.E. 18 per mensum. Applications in
writing to Asst. Direotor of Works, War
Office, Cairo.	26967-8
Young English lady desires situation
Resident Governess, in Alexandria or
RAtnloh ; can teach music. Apply, No. 26,978
"Egyptian Gazette" offioe,	88978-3-3
Boots & Shoes in the latest
shapes, Bags, Trunks & all
Leather goods in great va-
riety.
AIbo a large assorted supply of the
following articles:—
HATS, CAPS, UMBRELLAS,
WALKING-STICKS, RUGS,
STUDS, BRUSHES AND ALL
TOILET REQUISITES, AC.
Davies Bryan & Co.
Cairo & Alexandria,</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

