<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-02">October 2, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-04">September 4, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7284] ALEXANDRIA, Monday, September 4, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 4, 1905</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PEACE TREATY. THE TSAR’S TELEGRAM. WAR STOPS JUST TOO SOON !</head>
                    <p>Portsmouth (N.H.), September 3.</p>
                    <p>It is expected that the treaty of peace will be signed on Monday.</p>
                    <p>The last disputed point has been arranged. Both parties agree not to fortify
                        Saghalien or La Perouse Strait. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Sr. Petersburg, September 3.</p>
                    <p>The Tsar telegraphed to General Linievitch on the 1st inst., and in notifying
                        him of the conclusion of the negotiations, he says: "The Army is now
                        prepared to inflict an important defeat on the enemy, but my duty to my
                        conscience and the people commands me not to expose my army to fresh and
                        endless horrors of war, for the sake of half a remote island." (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, September 3.</p>
                    <p>The Mikado in replying to President Roosevelt's congratulations warmly thanks
                        him for his unremitting effects in the interests of peace, and says that he
                        gratefully appreciates the part taken by him in its establishment, which is
                        so essential to the welfare of the Far East. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Portsmouth (U.S.A), September 2.</p>
                    <p>M. Witte and Baron Kamura have agreed not to fortify Saghalien. (Havas)</p>
                    <p>Paris, September 2.</p>
                    <p>The French press finds that the renewed Anglo Japanese alliance is more
                        reassuring than disturbing in view of the entente cordiale.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE POTEMKIN'S CREW. PARDONED BY THE TSAR</head>
                    <p>Bukharest, September 3.</p>
                    <p>Several of the Potemkin's crew are leaving Roumania voluntarily for Russia,
                        the Russian Consulate having assured them that they will encounter no harm,
                        the Tsar having pardoned the mutineers. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. DIFFERENCES DIMINISH.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 2.</p>
                    <p>M. Rouvier has banded Prince Radolin the French reply to the German Note of
                        the 26th of August. Each exchange of notes diminishes the differences
                        between the two Powers. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES SENSATION. LIQUIDATION APPOINTED.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 2.</p>
                    <p>In connection with the report of the possible liquidation of the Raffineries
                        d’Egypte as a result of the suicide of M.Cronier it is declared here that
                        the French Courts have no jurisdiction.</p>
                    <p>A liquidator has been appointed in the matter of Henry Say and Co.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SHAH IN RUSSIA. IMPRESSIVE RECEPTION.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, September 2.</p>
                    <p>The Shah has arrived on the Russian frontier. The finest troops in the Empire
                        have been concentrated at St Petersburg for the purpose of convincing the
                        Shah that Russia is the greatest power of the Middle East.</p>
                    <p>The Shah has arrived at Peterhoff. He was met at the station by the Tsar, the
                        Grand Dukes, Count Lamsdorff, and General Trepoff.(Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MACEDONIAN FINANCES. INTERNATIONAL CONTROL REJECTED.</head>
                    <p>Constantinople, September 2. The Porte rejects the scheme of the Ambasrador
                        for an international control of the finances of Macedonia, but the Powers
                        will insist. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SPREAD OF CHOLERA.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, September 2.</p>
                    <p>There have been 43 oases of cholera, of which 17 were fatal, officially
                        reported in Prussia.</p>
                    <p>The Hamburg police have stopped the oon-veyanco of Russian emigrants to that
                        city, on account of the reports that there is cholera in Russia.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Berlin, September 2.</p>
                    <p>Cholera has been notified on the Poland frontier. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                    <p>London, September 2. </p>
                    <p>Surrey v. Northamptonshire tie.</p>
                    <p>The Australians beat England XI. at Bour nemouth by one wicket Sussex beat
                        Essex by 163 runs. The match at Blackpool between England XI, and Lancashire
                        was drawn. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRANCE AND MOROCCO. THE ALGERIAN CHIEF. COMPLETE REPARATION DEMANDED.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 2.</p>
                    <p>M. Saint Rene Taillandier handed the Sultan on Thursday an ultimatum
                        demanding a complete reparation, and an apology in specified terms for the
                        imprisonment of the Algerian.(Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Tangier, September 2.</p>
                    <p>M. Saint Rene Taillandier has handed an ultimatum to the Maghzen demanding a
                        complete reparation. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FIRE AT ADRIANOPLE. FOUR QUARTERS DESTROYED.</head>
                    <p>Adrianople. September 4.</p>
                    <p>A fire has destroyed the Greek, Armenian, Bulgarian and Jewish quarters.
                        There are several victims. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Adrianople, September 3.</p>
                    <p>A fire has destroyed the Greek, Armenian, Israelite, and Bulgarian quarters.
                        (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BOMB EXPLOSION AT BARCELONA.</head>
                    <p>Barcelona, September 4.</p>
                    <p>Two persons have been killed and 20 injured by the explosion of a bomb on a
                        crowded promenade. ( Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Barcelona, September 3.</p>
                    <p>A bomb burst on the promenade. There are many victims. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lyons, September 3.</p>
                    <p>M. Combes, in a speech, advised the Government to maintain its foreign
                        policy. (H.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Paris, September 3.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has left lor Vienna. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>Paris, September 2.</p>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive has left for Vienna. (II.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Nile Valley Shares</head>
                        <p>The committee of the London Stock Exchange has fixed Sept 13 as a special
                            setting day in Nile Valley Block E, Limited, Further issue of 6,000
                            Shares of £1 each fully paid, Nos. 30,001 to 36,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>San Stefano Casiso</head>
                        <p>Saturday next is the occasion of the great night fete at San Stefano when
                            an orchestral concert will be given, and there will also bo a display of
                            fireworks. The fete commences at 9.30 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>13 vessels passed through the Canal on the 31st ult. of which eleven were
                            British, 1 German, 1 French. The day’s receipts were frs. 432,554.53,
                            making the total for the month of August fr. 9,489,079.27, from 370
                            ships. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cholera in Europe</head>
                        <p>A communication has been made to the president of the Quarantine Board by
                            the German Sanitary delegate that only one case of cholera has been
                            notified at Hamburg, viz, that of a Russian immigrant who arrived on the
                            27th August and died on the 29th of the same month in the Hamburg
                            hospital. It also adds that the general sanitary condition of the port
                            gives no cause for anxiety.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Cattle Plaque</head>
                        <p>We are glad to be able to inform our readers that as no case of bovine
                            typhus has been reported since the 14th ult., the weekly cattle plague
                            report will no longer be published. It is perhaps dangerous to "shout
                            before we are out of the wood,” but this time it really seems that the
                            disease has worked itself out. The first case was officially reported to
                            the Sanitary Department on July 11, 1903.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Khedivial Agricultural Society</head>
                        <p>A local agricultural exhibition will be held at Fayoum under the auspices
                            of the Khedivial Agricultural Society on the 14th, 15th, and 16th. inst.
                            The Society is distributing tickets which will entitle those attending
                            the exhibition to reduction of 50 % upon return tickets to Fayoum on the
                            State Railways lines. These tickets have been sent to all the members of
                            the society in Upper Egypt Members residing in Lower Eygyt can obtain
                            them on application to the secretary of the Society.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Bubonic Plague</head>
                        <p>During the week ending the 2nd inst thirteen cases of plague were
                            reported for the whole of Egypt, eleven at Alexandria, one at Damietta,
                            and one at Da-boud in the market and province of Assouan. Between
                            January 1 and September 2, 1905 246 cases of plague have been reported
                            against 786 during the corresponding period of the previous year.
                            Saturday’s bulletin reports two deaths at Alexandria, two native girls
                            of the same family succumbing in the Minet el Bassal district Sunday's
                            bulletin reports three admissions to hospital at Alexandria and one
                            death Port Said. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUGAR TRADE SENSATION. M. CRONIER'S TRAGIC SUICIDE.</head>
                    <p>(From our own Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>London, August 29.</p>
                    <p>The European bonnes and the London 8tock Exchange were yesterday staggered by
                        the sensational news of the sadden death of M. Cronier, the great sugar
                        magnate. The effect was felt more especially on the Paris and Hamburg
                        bonnes, where the chief dealings in sugar shares take place.</p>
                    <p>M. Ernest Cronier, Ingenieur Principal do Ponts et Chviriee, Officier de la
                        Legion d'hon-nenr, had enormous commitments in sugar, which, according to
                        report, showed differences of over £2,000,000. The exact amount of the
                        losses cannot be ascertained, however, until his accounts have been
                        liquidated, so that the above figures must be accepted with reserve.</p>
                    <p>M. Cronier has for years been more or less connected with the sugar interests
                        of Egypt and Egyptian finance. In 1892 he formed the societe Generale des
                        Sucreries et de la Raffi-nerio d'Egypte in conjuction with Messieurs'
                        Suares, and at the time of his death he was president of the company. Not
                        only was be president, but he was the ruling spirit of the concern. The
                        interests of both the Say and Suares families came under the direct control
                        of this very strong-willed man, who, like Langrand Dumonean in the sixties
                        and Bon-teux in the seventies, dealt with all his companies as if they wore
                        branches of his own estates. </p>
                    <p>In 1898 he, in conjunction with Sir Ernest Cassel, Messieurs Sanies and
                        Cattani, purchased the Daira Sanieh estates from the Egyptian Government,
                        and in 1902 he bought from the Daira Sanieh administration the various sugar
                        factories tor nearly £1,000,000 sterling. In order to carry out the
                        financing of this operation the Daira Sanieh Sugar Corporation was founded
                        with a total share and debenture c vital of £1,573,000, and was the go
                        between of the Daira Sanieh and the sucreries et Raffinerie Co.</p>
                    <p>The tragic suicide of M. Cronier (it appears he shot himself with a revolver
                        at his dwelling in the Rue de Lisbonne, Paris), caused a heavy fall in the
                        sugar shares on the Paris bourse. The Say Company's stock fell from 950
                        francs to 580 frances, and that of the Sucreries Raffinerie d’Egypt from 152
                        francs to 107 francs ; and although it is early yet to obtain accurate
                        information, there seems to be an opinion that this tragic event will
                        involve some form of reorganisation of the latter company. Daira Sanieh
                        deferred shares have also reacted several points and leave off this
                        afternoon at 178.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOULED OF ST. GEORGE.</head>
                    <p>(From our Minet-el-Kamh Correspondent.</p>
                    <p>The Mauled of St. George at Mit Damsis, Dakahlieh was largely attended by the
                        native population. All the river boats and feluccas were decorated, and
                        cafes and kiosques were erected on the decks of barges and dahabiehs. In
                        spite of the numerous delays at the locks and bridges great number of people
                        visited the mouled by river and canal. A journey that should take ten hours
                        was only performed in forty five, so many wore the halts on the way.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW TELEPHONE LINES.</head>
                    <p>The Government has decided upon gradually extending the telephone system
                        throughout all the provinces and bringing the villages in the different
                        districts into direct communication with the markazes, and through these
                        with the moudiriehs, with the view of the more effective prevention and
                        repression of crime.</p>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has, on behalf of the Ministry of the Interior,
                        authorised the creation of new lines in 31 villages in the markaz of Toukh,
                        27 villages in the markaz of Ka-lioub, and 4 villages in the Sambellawein
                        mar-kaz, Dakahlieh moudrireh. As before, these new lines are to be erected
                        by the Telephone Company of Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" element="esbekieh"><head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS THEATRE.</head>
                    <p>The French theatrical troupe, known as the Louis Gardet Operetta Company,
                        arrive here on Tuesday by the Messageries steamer from Marseilles, and will
                        begin a series of performances extending over two months, on Thursday next,
                        at the above theatre. This is the third season the troupe has visited Cairo,
                        where on previous occasions they were great favorites.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" element="esbekieh"><head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Lt. Col. C. J. Markham and officers, the band of the
                        lst Batt King's Royal Rifles will perform the following programme of music
                        at the Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow (Tuesday) evening, oom-mencing at 9
                        o’clock.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner Nitocris sailed yesterday afternoon for Liverpool, via Smyrna,
                        with general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes mail boat Niger, which left Marseilles on the 31st
                        ult passed the Straits of Messina on Saturday and is due here to-morrow.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>AQUATIC SPORTS.</head>
                    <p>From our Correspondent).</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Sunday.</p>
                    <p>The aquatic sports which were held close to the Congal in the backwater on
                        the east side of the harbor yesterday afternoon, passed off very well.
                        Almost the whole of the British community were present, and were conveyed to
                        and fro by steam launches kindly tent for the occasion.</p>
                    <p>Of the several events, obstacle races, ladies' rowing races, gondola race,
                        and a titling bout from punts, the last two caused most real amusement.
                        During the progress of the gondola race two of the craft (merely painting
                        punts converted for this occasion only) sunk, leaving their crews to swim to
                        the shore.</p>
                    <p>The prizes were given by Mrs. Brown from a large lighter tastefully decorated
                        and hung with bunting, on which also the refreshment table was arranged.</p>
                    <p>The follwing is the list of events and names of winners.</p>
                    <p>(1) Obstacle swimming race.</p>
                    <p>1. Thornton. 2 Norman.</p>
                    <p>(2) Ladies’ rowing race in native boats with gentlemen as coxswains.</p>
                    <p>Won by Mrs. Williams and Miss O'Connor steered by Mr. Ching.</p>
                    <p>(3) Dongola race. This was a most exciting race and caused much merriment, as
                        two of the punts filled and tank before reaching the goal</p>
                    <p>Winners:—Chesman, Wallis, Tunstall, and Thorton.</p>
                    <p>(4) Tilting match in punts.</p>
                    <p>Won by Norman—pant propelled by Chesman.</p>
                    <p>THE BISHOP OP PERTH W. A.</p>
                    <p>The P. &amp; 0. Britannia had on board, amongst her large number of
                        passengers, many notabi-lities, one being the well-known Bishop of Perth,
                        who, after a brief holiday in England proceeds to Sydney, whore his presence
                        is necessary at the convocation of the General Synod to be held early in
                        October.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesSuakin">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RAINS AND THE RAILWAY.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Suakin, August 23.</dateline>
                        <p>The weather here remains very hot and the sun it scorching. Two more
                            soldiers of the Railway battalion, have succumbed to sun-stroke, the
                            supply of ice, which might have saved their lives, having ran short
                            through a breakdown in the machine, Kaimakam Long field Bey, acting
                            director of Railways, has kindly altered the regulations as to the
                            working hours of the soldiers, none of whom are now allowed to work
                            between 10 a.m. and 8 pm. On the other hand heavy rains have done some
                            damage to the railway and will cause some delay in construction.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PUBLIC WORKS</head>
                        <p>The works at Port Sudan are making good progress. The contract for
                            building a large Government school has been secured by Mr. A. Pappas for
                            LE. 4,000. The quarantine buildings which were secured by Messrs. Frank
                            &amp; Co. are now nearing completion. Kaimakam Kennedy Bey, R.E.
                            Director of the Sudan Works Department has, left Port Sudan for
                            Egypt</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>H. I. M. the Sultan has been pleased to confer the rank of Mushir on H H.
                        Prince Mohamed Aly</p>
                    <p>Saba Pasha and Iskander Pasha Fehmi have arrived in Egypt from Europe.</p>
                    <p>Count Zogheb, Consul-General for Denmark, left for Europe by the Austrian
                        mail boat on Saturday. </p>

                    <p>Judge Royle is returning by the P. &amp; 0. Arabia, and will be in Cairo on
                        the 20th inst.</p>

                    <p>Major J. E. Pine-Coffin, D.S.O., M.I., has been granted leave of absence from
                        7th. inst. to December 15. </p>

                    <p>El Bimbashi A. M. Byng. 2nd battalion, has resigned his commission in the
                        Egyptian Army.</p>

                    <p>Mr. W. D. Roberts, surveyor of contracts of the second circle of irrigation,
                        has been grant ed three and a half months' leave of absence dating from the
                        29 th August.</p>

                    <p>Mr. A. P. Marson, who has been English master for five years at the Scotch
                        schools in Alexandria, has been appointed head master of one of the C.M.S.
                        schools in Cairo. His new duties oommenoe to-morrow.</p>

                    <p>Mr. J. W. Congdon arrived at Port Said this morning by the S.S. Assyria, and
                        has left for Cairo.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to learn that M. Antoine Vala-dier, of Alexandria, who has been
                        the agent of the Russian Navigation Company successively at Salon ice, and
                        Beyrout, and who has keen acting as agent of the fame company at Alexandria,
                        bas been definitely appointed to the latter post,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SOLAR ECLIPSE. FURTHER DETAILS.</head>
                    <p>Our special correspondent sends us the following further account of the solar
                        eclipse as viewed from the zone of totality which had been virtually turned
                        into a huge observatory: -The garden of the Savoy Hotel was the scene of
                        action, and there most of the instruments of the various commissions were
                        erected. At the north end of the garden Professor Turner of the English
                        contingent had taken up his position. He had erected two large cameras
                        fitted with two very fine reflectors, especially ground so as to give no
                        distortion ; the lenses of this instruments were made by 8ir Howard Grubb.
                        Professor Turner managed to take fourteen photographs of the eclipse. To the
                        west of the English contingent, the two Russian professors from St.
                        Petersburg had placed themselves. These scientists like wise used a large
                        reflecting telescope in connection with a very fine camera, and they
                        succeeding in obtaining four photographic records. The Russians had set op a
                        magnetic observation camp on the west bank of the Nile near Grenvell's tombs
                        and on the west side of the island the American observers had up their posts
                        under Professor Hussey of the Lick Observatory, and Professor West of the
                        American College at Beyrout. The members of this commission had erected two
                        cameras, one of. enormous length measuring forty feet With this instrument
                        Professor Hussey obtained ten exposures, which varied from half a second to
                        ten seconds, and one of sixty-four seconds. The second instrument consisted
                        of four lenses in one camera, so that four photographs might be taken of the
                        corona at the same time and at different parts; with this instrument eight
                        exposures were made. Here also Dr. Myer of Germany had set up a small but
                        powerful telescope, which bad been made by the great German optician, Carl
                        Leiss of Jena, and the lens of his camera was very rapid, the longest
                        exposure with this instrument being only ten seconds. Dr. Myer, who made ten
                        exposures, chiefly interested himself in photographing the extreme edge of
                        the corona.</p>
                    <p>At the railway station Mr. J. H. Reynolds of Birmingham had erected a huge
                        reflecting telescope 120 feet long. There were great difficulties in
                        erecting this instrument, but thanks to the kindness of the railway
                        authorities, it was eventually placed in position. Mr. Reynolds secured two
                        exposures. One incident occured which might have had a disastrous effect. As
                        the total eclipse was approaching, the train from Luxor was seen to be
                        coming in the distance, but loud and continued shooting happily succeeded in
                        bring-ing the train to standstill outside Assouan station, and a great
                        dilemma was averted.</p>
                    <p>Three magnetic stations had bean erected by the Egyptian Government, one at
                        Assouan station under Mr. Wade, another at Dakka, 70 miles south, another at
                        Edfu, 70 miles north.</p>
                    <p>The total eclipse started as follows, from Winnipeg Lake across the Atlantic
                        ocean to to Spain, then through the Balearic Isles, Algiers, Tunis, Tripoli,
                        Egypt, across the Red Sea, and ended in the south east of Arabia. The total
                        eclipse rone measured two degrees, and the longest time daring which it was
                        visible was at Burgos in Spain, where it lasted for about three minutes.</p>
                    <p>Most of the astronomers busied themselves with taking photographs of the
                        sun's corona, and doubtless when they have returned to their respective
                        countries, developed their photographs, and made their measurements, they
                        will give the scientific results to the world. Many of the professors were
                        in gnat hopes that at this eclipse, some new planet might be discovered, but
                        for this result we must wait with patience. In Egypt very few spectroscopic
                        observations were taken. Two perfectly constructed spectroscopes had been
                        made by Zeiss for the Spanish government, one of them to be used at Burgos
                        in an observatory, the other to be used from a balloon. The day here dawned
                        quite clear, not a vestige of a cloud was to be seen any where, and all the
                        astronomers were early astir, fingering their instruments lovingly, and
                        having full dress rehearsals. In the morning about thirty people turned up
                        to view the eclipse, and at lunch time, one might have imagined the season
                        had already begun. The first contact took place at 3 h. 26 m. p.m. exactly,
                        and all were at their respective stations. The roof of the hotel was crowded
                        with people, and the natives on the bank of the river beat furiously on
                        tom-toms. Totality commenced at 4 h. 33 m. 6 secs, but fifteen minutes
                        before this it had began to get quite dark, and the conditions reminded one
                        exactly of twilight Just before the totality began, the shadow of the moon
                        was seen moving across the hills on the east bank ; in an instant the sun
                        was obscured, and the rays of the corona shot out from all sides, one
                        extremely long stream being seen low down on the left Totality lasted
                        exactly two minutes twenty four seconds; directly the sun re- appeared the
                        natives beat their tom-toms more furiously than ever, and cries of delight
                        were heard on all sides.</p>
                    <p>The eclipse was a groat success ; no clouds, rendered observation difficult
                        though it was a little hazy. The corona sphere was brilliant and at least
                        two well-marked prominences, were seen. The outer corona was very faint,
                        considering that sun spots were at their maximum. There is much speculation
                        as to whether the largest streamers can be associated with the sun spots,
                        but this is moat difficult to ascertain by a momentary glance.</p>
                    <p>The longest streamer may have been over a sun spot, which has been recently
                        visible. The stars were distinctly visible, also the planet Mars, but
                        Mercury was not seen. The largest streamer noticed was about two diameters
                        of the sun in size. During the whole eclipse the wind was hardly noticeable,
                        and the temperature seemed to drop considerably.</p>
                    <p>Professor Turner and his colleagues wish to thank Captain Lyons and all the
                        other members of the Survey Department for their kind help, without which
                        they could not have secured such success. They are also exceedingly grateful
                        to the Railway Administration for the advantages granted them, and to Mr.
                        Hazel, of the Ministry of the Interior, for the excellent way in which the
                        grounds of the hotel ware policed. Mr. Reynolds alto wishes to express his
                        thanks to Mr. Kieling for his invaluable assistance. Last, but not least,
                        all the astronomers are unanimous in expressing their satisfaction at the
                        way in which the Savoy Hotel placed everything at their disposal; the
                        basement was turned into a dark room, the garden into an observatory, and on
                        the day of the eclipse they stopped their steam water pump from working.</p>
                    <p>The following is a list of the different commissions who took
                        observations</p>
                    <p>England—ProfesrorTurner and Mr. Bellamy.</p>
                    <p>Russia.—Mr. Okulitach, Mr. Baikof, and M. Dubinsky.</p>
                    <p>America. Professor West, Professor and Mrs. Hussey, end Mr. Joy.</p>
                    <p>Germany.—Dr. Myer and Herr Elck</p>
                    <p>Survey Department—Captain Lyons, Mr. Kieling, and Mr. Dickinson.</p>
                    <p>Amongst the spectators I noticed Mr. Mitchell Innes Herr Anton Graf
                        Hackinicksi (Austrian attache) Mr. H. G. Shepherd, Mr. Schreibar, Mr.
                        Clifton, Mr. A.C. de Cosson, Amin Bey Sami. Dr. Garner, Mr. Weston, Rev.
                        Burns, Mr. Weigall, Mr. Quibella.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>
                        <head>THE ABOUKIR RACE.</head>
                        <p>One of the most popular races of the season took place yesterday. The
                            course was to Aboukir, (round "Nelson's Island") and back, a total
                            distance of nearly 50 miles, constituting the longest open sea race that
                            baa ever been bald under the auspices of the Yacht Club.</p>
                        <p>Eight boats started at 10.30 a.m. from the Club House at Ras el Tin, and
                            presented a very pretty spectacle as they all crossed the line together.
                            Six of them finished ; of the other two, Leman returned, as, being a
                            small boat, she was unable to do the distance in the heavy sea which was
                            running. The other boat, Jenny, apparently bad enough of the run down
                            and dropped anchor in the shelter of Aboukir Bay to wait a more
                            favorable opportunity of returning to Alexandria. The order of the six
                            arrivals was as follows.</p>
                        <p>Although the boats finished in the above order, the Ironie won the
                            handsome cup given by his Highness Prince Aziz on her time allowance, as
                            will be seen by consulting the handicap published in lest Saturday’s
                            "Gazette."</p>
                        <p>The Beltia sailed the wrong course so that her time cannot be taken as
                            indicating her speed.</p>
                        <p>The handicap was a very good one, the difference between the Ironie and
                            Tantah being only 11 minutes, and between the Tantah and Masr 40 seconds
                            only, on the 8 hours course.</p>
                        <p>The speed of the Masr, the first boat in, averaged about 8 knots, which
                            is exceedingly fast for a boat of her type and size, and would be beaten
                            with difficulty if at all by a European built boat of the same rating,
                            and great credit to due to the native builder.</p>
                        <p>After the race Prince Asia was “at home” to the Club members. Lady
                            Blomfield kindly presented the prise to the winner.</p>
                        <p>The race is a record one in every way inasmuch as throughout the whole of
                            the long distance and amongst all the boats not a single accident of any
                            kind occurred ; all the boats reaching port safely. Snob a contingency
                            was, however, carefully provided against by the kind offer of a tug boat
                            to follow the race by Admiral Blomfield, the posting of one of Prince
                            Aziz boats at Aboukir itself, and the loan by Mr. Sergeant of an ample
                            number of life belts, so that no one in the race was without one.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>The members met on Saturday last for the usual weekly sports.</p>
                        <p>Some high diving was witnessed, and the success attained by some members
                            was a proof of the improvement they had made since they joined the
                            club.</p>
                        <p>The diving exhibited by the juniors also showed a decided and vast
                            improvement</p>
                        <p>In a few days the date of fixture for the 3rd annual aquatic sports will
                            be announced, and also a list of the events.</p>
                        <p>Members' times for the 60 yards club hand-icap will be taken on the 23rd
                            instant</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB (ALEX.)</head>
                        <p>Members are reminded that the last spoon competition of the season will
                            take place on Saturday next at Mustapha rifle range. Shooting will
                            commence at 3 p.m.. There will also be a target for practice.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
