<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Charlie Rymer</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-03</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">Monday, August 22, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="item" n="1">
                    <h1>THE TSAR’S MANIFESTO.</h1>
                    <h2>INDIFFERENCE OF THE
                        PEOPLE</h2>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>EDUCATED CLASSES
                            DISQUALIFIED.</h2>
                        <h3>Sr. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>The complete absence of enthusiasm is the
                            most striking feature of the Russian press
                            comments regarding the Assembly project.
                            There are no signs of rejoicing anywhere. The
                            high rental qualification of the town voters
                            excludes the majority of the educated classes.
                            Only 5,000 inhabitants in St Petersburg are
                            qualified.
                            Rioting took place at Kichineff following
                            the publication of the project Several thou-
                            sand demonstrators were dispersed by the
                            mounted police.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>The Tsar’s manifesto has been greeted with
                            indifference.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>IS IT PEACE?</h2>
                        <h2>FURTHER CONCESSIONS IMPOSSIBLE.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>According to a telegram received yesterday
                            evening from Portsmouth (N.H.), the "Times”
                            learns that the Tsar held a Council at which it
                            was finally decided that no further concessions
                            can be made.	(Reuter)</p>
                        
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>WARSAW AND LODZ STRIKE.</h2>
                        <h2>THE POPULACE INDIGNANT.</h2>
                        <p>Warsaw, August 21.
                            A general strike has been proclaimed here
                            owing to the indignation caused by the pro-
                            cedure in connection with the elections, which
                            will treat the Poles in a similar manner to the
                            Asiatic nomade.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>A general strike at Warsaw and Lodz is
                            reported.	(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                     <div type="section">
                        <h2>RUSSIAN LIBERALS ARRESTED.</h2>
                        <h3>St. Petersburg, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>Professor Milioskow and ten other well-
                            known liberals have been arrested. (Havas)</p>
                     </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>INDIA'S NEW VICEROY.</h2>
                        <h2>FROM CANADA TO INDIA.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>(Official). Lord Minto will sucoeed Visoount
                            Curzon.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <p>The new Vioeroy of India is son of the third
                            Earl of Minto. Born on July 9,1847, he was
                            educated at Eton and Trinity College, Cam-
                            bridge. An ensign in the Scots Guards in 1867,
                            he saw active service with the Turkish Army
                            in 1877, and in the second Afghan war in
                            1879. He acted as private secretary to Lord
                            Roberts during the latter’s brief visit to the
                            Cape in 1881, volunteered for the Egyptian
                            campaign in 1885, and was military secretary
                            to the Marquis of Lansdowne while the present
                            Foreign Minister was Governor General of
                            Canada in 1883-85. In 1885 he was chief of
                            the staff during the hard fought little campaign
                            against the rebellious Indians and half-breds
                            in the north-west of the Dominion. He con-
                            tested Hexham in 1886, and in 1891 succeeded
                            to the title. He was created G.C.M.G. in 1898,
                            in which year he was appointed Governor-
                            General of Canada, a post which he filled with
                            consistent sucoess till 1904, when he was suc-
                            ceeded by Earl Grey. Lord Minto married, in
                            1885, Mary, daughter of General the Hon.
                            Charles Grey.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</h2>
                        <h2>NO FURTHER REDUCTION.</h2>
                        <h3>London, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>It is notified that the Army Council does
                            not intend to carry out any further reduction
                            of the British garrison in Egypt. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE EAST AFRICAN RISING.</h2>
                        <h2>GERMANY SENDS TROOPS.</h2>
                        <h3>Berlin, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>Owing to the rising in East Africa, the
                            Government is despatching 160 marines, to-
                            gether with machine guns and two small
                            cruisers.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>YELLOW FEVER ABATING.</h2>
                        <h3>New Orleans, August 21.</h3>
                        <p>Owing to rigorous preventive measures, the
                            yellow fever is abating.	(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="2">
                    <h1>LOCAL AND GENERAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <p>Quarantine — Arrivals from Adalia are now
                        subjected to a medical visit only.</p>
                        
                        <p>Greek Philharmonic Society.—A concert
                        will be given by this society to-morrow evening,
                        commencing at 9 p.m.</p>
                        
                        <p>Delta Barrage —A building for models is
                        to be constructed at the Delta Barrage in the
                        near future.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Post Office at Sennar is now op-
                        ened to foreign ordinary, inland ordinary,
                        and telegraphic money service.</p>
                        
                        <p>Commercial Treaties.—It is hoped that
                        the commercial treaty between Egypt and Italy
                        will be signed in November.</p>
                        
                        <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
                        Imam distriot of Cairo during to-morrow night
                        and at dawn of the 23rd inst. will be poisoned
                        by the police.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Plague.—Yesterday’s plague bulletin
                        reoords one now admission to hospital at Port
                        Baid, and the recovery of the solitary case at</p>
                        
                        <p>Suez Canal.— 16 vessels passed through the
                        Canal on the 18th inst., 11 of whioh wereBritish,
                        1 German, 2 French, 1 Turkish, 1 Austrian.
                        The day's reoeipts were frs. 424,603.23 making
                        the total from the 1st inst frs. 5,580,764.21.</p>
                        
                        <p>Injured by a Buffalo.—A startled buffalo
                        cow ran down a man and woman on Sonday in
                        Moharrem Bey quarter. The woman was
                        severely injured and requires fifteen days
                        treatment The man came cff comparatively
                        lightly.</p>
                        
                        <p>A Brutal Husband.—On Sunday a certain
                        Hassan Aisa Ali hurled a lighted lamp at his
                        wife Zanouba, who had asked him for some
                        money for household expenses, irflicting
                        serious burns on the poor woman, who has bad
                        to be removed to hospital.</p>
                        
                        <p>Killed by Scorpions.—Two more deaths
                        from the stings of scorpions are reported from
                        Cairo, a child having died from this cause in
                        the Darb el Ahmar quarter, and another in
                        Old Cairo, where such fatalities have been
                        comparatively common of late.</p>
                        
                        <p>Injured at Play.—A lad' named Ismail
                        Abd el Moneim, 11 years of age, was flying his
                        kite from the roof of a house at El Halwagi,
                        near the Customs, on Sunday, when he made a
                        false step, and fell into the attest, sustaining
                        injuries that necessitate ten days’ medical
                        treatment.</p>
                        
                        <p>Attempted Murder.—A Cairene butcher
                        named Ahmed el Habashi recently quarrelled
                        in the course of an argument with Hafzallah
                        Mankarius and stabbed him in the abdomen.
                        The polioe of the Khalifa kism have sinoe
                        arrested the would-be murderer, whose victim
                        has been taken to hospital.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Sarkis Affair.—We are glad to hear
                        that the Armenian community of Alexandria
                        has decided to send the two yoonggirls concern-
                        ed in this painful affair to an Armenian oonvent
                        for orphans at Constantinople. The "decision
                        does great credit to the humanity andoommon
                        sense of our Armenian fellow oitizens.</p>
                        
                        <p>The Alhambra Theatre.—To-morrow night
                        the Della Guardia Dramatic Company will
                        present Le Pillole cCErcole at this theatre.
                        Lorde'a drama La Dormiente will be given
                        very shortly and the oompany also bills Pam-
                        ela Marchande de Frivolitfi to appear soon.
                        Subscription tiokets may be obtained at the
                        box-office of the theatre.</p>
                        
                        <p>Hashish Seizures.—Six turbos of hashish
                        were found in a sack of flower by the Customs
                        authorities yesterday, whilst on Saturday two
                        women named Luisa Moretti and Elena Cassa-
                        pido while returning from the 8.8. Imperator
                        Nioolai were arrested by the quay polioe. The
                        female searcher emp'oyed discovered eight
                        turbas of hashish oonoealed in their skirts.</p>
                        
                        <p>Tne Liege Exhibition.—Among the mem-
                        bers of the Jury of the International Exhibition
                        at liege we notioe the name of Mr. Collonge,
                        director general of Berlitz Sohools. This official
                        nomination is still another homage rendered
                        to a celebrated institution, and to a system
                        whioh has rendered possible such progress in
                        the study of modem languages. 26347-1</p>
                        
                        <p>British Chamber of Commerce.—We would
                        draw the attention of manufacturers and mer-
                        chants to the work of the British Chamber of
                        Commerce of Bgypt, which was formed in
                        1896 with the sole object of assisting British
                        trade in this country. The services of the
                        Chamber are always at the disposal of any
                        member desiring information on trade matters
                        generally, including the question of appoint-
                        ing suitable agents. As no fee is oharged for I
                        such advice, it is obviously in the interests of j
                        all British traders here to beoome members,
                        especially when it is remembered that the
                        annual subecription is merely the nominal one •
                        £1. The latter payment also includes a oopy |
                        of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber j
                        Home enquirers oan obtain farther particulars
                        from oar London offioe, 86, New Broad-street
                        which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="3">
                    <h1>THE SULTAN’S ACCESSION</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>DINNER AT RAS EL TIN.</h2>
                        <p>Invitations will be issued this week by the
                            Cabinet of the Grand Master of Ceremonies
                            for the banquet whioh will be given by the
                            Acting Regent at Ras el Tin Palace on Sep-
                            tember 1st Among the guests will be the
                            ministers, advisers and under-secretaries of
                            state, the Diplomatic Agents of the Domains
                            Administration, and the Caisse de la Dette,
                            the State Railways and other Administrations,
                            General Bullock, the Acting Governor of
                            Alexandria, and the Consuls of the Powers
                            at Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                            <h2>THE YEMEN RISING.</h2>
                        <p>In his report on the reoent action at Sebk-el-
                            Hamis, Marshal Ahmed Faizi Pasha, Com-
                            mander of the Ottoman forces in the Yemen,
                            states that the action lasted from 8 a.m. to
                            midday, and that the retreating rebels left
                            many dead behind them. Tarkish authority
                            is re-established at Menakhkha.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE COTTON-WORM.</h2>
                        <p>Thif bulletin issued by the Ministry of the
                            Interior for the week ending last Saturday
                            again shows a very considerable decrease in
                            the area of land in whioh the ootton-worm still
                            exists. The following are the reports from the
                            four affected provinces.
                            Gharbieh :—825 fed dans, belonging to 68
                            proprietors, have been affested by the worm,
                            and 811 of these have been cleared by 718
                            ohildren.
                            Behera :—2,396 feddans, belonging to 48
                            proprietors, have been affected, and 2,804 have
                            been cleared by 6,641 children.
                            Dakahlieh :—109 feddans, belonging to 45
                            proprietors, have been affected, and 102 cleared
                            by 810 children.
                            Damietta :—9} feddans, belonging to 9
                            proprietors, have been affected, and have all
                            been cleared by 61 children.
                            Comparing the above with the report of last
                            week, we find that the number of affeoted
                            provinces is roduoed by one, Kalionbieh being
                            nowontire'y free from the worm.In theGharbieh
                            province tho number of affeoted feddans shows
                            a decrease of 814, in Dakahlieh a decrease of
                            13, in Damietta a decrease of 11}, and in
                            Behora an inorease of 1,141 feddans. The
                            ii orease in the number of feddans attacked in
                            the Behera provinoe must in no way be taken
                            to indicate a general increase, for it must be
                            remembered that this provinoe has suffered
                            much more severely, not only during the
                            present year,but also in former ones, than any
                            other, and in the reports ofeaoh week we have
                            noted a considerable numerical difference
                            between the areas attacked and those cleared.
                            It is obvious that the insect is much more
                            strongly established in this province than in any
                            other. Those who know the Prodenia littoralit
                            find it one of tho commonest of the moths
                            whioh fly round lamps or eleotrio lights at
                            night in Alexandria and the neighbourhood.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>SUMMER LEAVES.</h2>
                        <p>Leave of absence has been granted to the
                            following officials of the Sudan Government
                            and Army Officers until the undermentioned
                            dates :—
                            El Kaimakam Carter Bey, officer command-
                            ing 9th Sudanese, until 29th September ; El
                            g.;m»Viun Cameron Bey, senior inspector of
                            the Sennar provinoe until 1st October; El
                            Bimbashi Arden, 4th battalion, until 29th
                            September ; El Bimbashi Elderton, deputy
                            assistant financial recretary until 15th Septem-
                            ber ; El Bimbashi Mayne, D.S.O.. 18th Sudan-
                            eie, until 2nd October; El Bimbashi Cox,
                            3rd battalion, until 2nd Ootober ; El Bim-
                            bashi Rawson, 15th Sudanese, until 29th
                            October.
                            Leave in extension has been granted to
                            El Kaimakam Garsia Bey, D.S.O., department
                            of supplies, until 20th September ; to El
                            Bimbashi Dale, deputy assistant director of
                            posts and telegraphs, until 29th October ; and
                            to El Bimbashi Heath, Camel Corps, until
                            4th Ootober.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE LATE MENSHAWI PASHA.</h2>
                        <p>Dissensions and disputes having arisen
                            of late between the heirs to the immense
                            properties left by Ahmed Menshawi Pasha, the
                            wealthy landed proprietor who died suddenly
                            in Cairo some months ago, three native nota-
                            bles have been appointed arbitrators by the
                            Meglis El Haaby.They are Ismail Pasha Abaza,
                            Hassan Pasha Rassim and Saad Bey Zsglool.
                            The heirs are the lady Fatma Amen,the widow,
                            daughter of the late Abdalla Pasha Inglisi,
                            an Englishman, a daughter, and two sons, one
                            of whom is at Tourah serving a long term of
                            imprisonment on a charge of murder. The late
                            Menshawi Pasha left properties whioh give, it
                            is reported, an annual income of £40,000
                            at least, but a portion of his large estates were
                            handed over to the Wekfs for the benefit of
                            the poor and certain mosques. Itisoertain
                            clauses in his will that have been the oause of
                            the dissensions between the members of his
                            family, who are seeking to set aside some of
                            them. The son, who is now in prison was, it
                            appeals, disinherited, and he is also disputing
                            the will, but it is hoped and expeoted that the
                            arbitrators reoently named will be able to settle
                            the difference that have arisen and satisfy all
                            the interested parties.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="4">
                    <h1>CAIRO TRAMWAYS.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>CONDITIONS OF CONCESSION.</h2>
                        <p>Monday’s 'Official Journal' oontains the text
                            of the oonoession granted to the Cairo Tram-
                            ways Company by the Egyptian Government
                            We have already described the routes to be
                            followed by the new lines, and will oonfine
                            ourselves to mentioning the principal condi-
                            tions imposed by the Government whioh are
                            of considerable interest
                            The Tramways Company undertakes to use
                            ao rails in the future but those of the
                            •Ph«nix’ type of 68 kilogrammes per metre,
                            and to replace the rails at present in use
                            by the above mentioned type by Deoember
                            81,1990, at latest The Pyramids Une,however,
                            will form an exoeption to this rule, for the
                            rails of the "Vignol” type will be retained in
                            use between Kasrel Nil and Mena House. Of
                            the tramways the Saptieh and Shoubra lines
                            are to be completed and working within two
                            Cof the signature of the oonoession (i.e.
                            July 18, 1906), the Sahel (Rod el Fang)
                            line within five yean, and the Ghamrah and
                            Abattoirs lines within one year from the
                            abora date. The doubling of the old Cairo line
                            is to be completed by the end of this month,
                            greatly to the relief, we imagine, of all who
                            live near the Kasr el Aini Road.
                            The line from Foum el Khalig to the
                            Southern bridge over the small branch of the
                            Nile will be constructed oonourrently with
                            the widening of the road by the Tan rim.
                            The Ghizeh line across Rodah Island and
                            the new bridges will be completed as soon
                            as the bridges are open to heavy traffic, and
                            the Imam-el-Shaffdi line is to be completed
                            within fifteen yean from the 18th ult. The
                            minimum radius of all ourves is fixed at 25
                            metres, exospt in special cases which the
                            Ministry of Publio Works will determine.
                            The speed of the trams is not to exceed
                            twelve kilometres an hour and must be reduced
                            at all points where the Ministry of Publio
                            Works oonsiden a lower speed neoessary in
                            the interests of publio safety. The new and
                            the previous oonoessions expire simultaneously,
                            viz. on Deoember 6, 1951, when the whole of
                            the properties of the Tramways Company will
                            fall to the Government</p>
                            
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>MENA HOUSE.</h2>
                        <p>There -have been persistent rumours for some
                            time in Cairo that the Mena House Hotel and
                            the surrounding property of some 100 feddans,
                            belonging to Mrs. Locke-King, widow of the late
                            owner, had been acquired by, or were under
                            option to, the Nnngovioh Hotels Company,
                            but we are informed that snob is not the fact
                            The foots of the oase are that an offer of pur-
                            chase for £>20,000 was reoently made by the
                            representatives of an English syndicate to the
                            lady’s agent, bat was refuted, and sinoe then
                            it was pffered to the above oompany at a
                            slightly higher prioe, whioh offer was not, bow-
                            The original hotel bnildings and the different
                            additions and improvements made sinoe have,
                            it is said, cost from first to last £80,000. The
                            hotel is held by Mr. E. Weokel, the present
                            proprietor manager, on a ten yean’ lease, of
                            which about seven years are expired, at an
                            annoal rental of £4,000. There is no like-
                            lihood of there being any immediate ohange,
                            however, in the ownership of the property, as
                            Mr. Weokel, who is now at Luoerne, has just
                            sent out orders for all the repairs neoessary for
                            the reopening of the hotel on the 1st November
                            to be proceeded with at once.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>THE COMING ECLIPSE.</h2>
                        <p>The Survey Department has issued through
                            the Preea Bureau in Cairo the following in-
                            teresting particulars regarding the ooming
                            eclipse of the sun.
                            The oentral line of the total eclipse of August
                            80 will pass near the railway station of Kbat-
                            tara, about 12 kilometres north of Assouan ;
                            the phenomena will be visible as a total eolipee
                            from near Bdfn to near the village of Dakka,
                            aouth of Assouan ; north and south of this
                            area the eolipee will be partial, and at Cairo
                            about nine-tenths of the enn’s disc will be
                            oovered.
                            The eolipee will oommenoe in Cairo at fonr
                            minutes past three, at thirteen minutes past
                            four it will have reaohed its middle, and the
                            end will be at fifteen minutes past five. The
                            time will not differ greatly in the Nila Valley
                            localities.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>EGYPTIAN GOVERNMENT
                            TELEGRAPHS.</h2>
                        <p>After several postponements occasioned by
                            delay in the completion of the premises, the
                            oentral Government telegraph offioe in Cairo is
                            to be transferred on the 1st September to the
                            new bnildings in the 8haria Boulak belonging
                            to the Daira Khasea, whioh have been
                            taken on a ten yean’ lrase at a rental of LE.
                            500 per annum. The new offices will oooupy
                            part of the ground floor and are an immense
                            improvement on the old ones, whioh had
                            become much too small for the great
                            inorease of bosioess especially sinoe the open-
                            ing of the Cairo bonne two years ago.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                        <div type="advertisement"></div>
     
                    </div>
                <div type="item" n="5">
                    <h1>STAMPED PAPER.</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>A CASH FOR REFORM.</h2>
                        <p>Whenever boe turns to the “Official Gazette"
                            for information ra tenders, sales of public laud
                            etc. etc., the formula-tenders must be sub-
                            mitted on stamped paper* appears in every
                            notice. Under these dreams tonoee it —»m« to
                            unobtainable at the Gonvernorat of Alexandria
                            except in quantities of 1,000 or more sheets at
                            a time. For smaller quantities the buyer mast
                            go to the Post Offioe, or to a small shop in the
                            Tarkish market quite half-an-honr's walk from
                            the Gonvernorat We oannot help thinking that
                            the oonvenienoe of the publio would be better
                            served, if the indispensible sheets of “papier
                            timbed" were procurable at the Gonvernorat.
                            Alexandria, be it remembered, is a town of
                            long distances, and the foot that stamped paper
                            is obtainable in the Souk-el-Turki and at
                            the Post Offioe is not very comforting to
                            persons who are equidistant from both these
                            places, and, when applying to the Gouvernorat,
                            are informed that,their needs cannot be served
                            unless they oare to take a thousand sheets,
                            —more than enough to last the ordinary man
                            for a lifetime.</p>
                        <h2>S.S. GIBRALTAR AGAIN ON FIRE.</h2>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.)
                            Suez, Monday.
                            The cargo of the S.S. Gibraltar whioh was
                            on fire at Suez lest Thursday afternoon,
                            suddenly took fire again on Saturday after
                            noon, and again yesterday.
                            Thanks to prompt assistance, the fire was
                            soon extinguished by flooding the bold, and
                            the vessel is now discharging the damaged
                            oargo in lighten, in order to avoid similar
                            probable outbreaks.</p>
                        <h2>A NEW MOSS LINER.</h2>
                        <p>Messrs. Archibald M’Millan and Son, limit-
                            ed, shipbuilders, Dumbarton, laanohed on the
                            8th inst the steel screw steamer Menepthah,
                            whioh they have built to the order of the Moss
                            Steamship Co., Liverpool (Messrs. James Moss
                            and Co.) for their Mediterranean trade. The
                            vessel, whioh has been built to Lloyd’s highest
                            class, is of the following dimensions Length
                            315 feet, breadth 44 feet 6 inches, depth
                            moulded 25 feet 5 inches, and is fitted with
                            all the latest improvements for the rapid and
                            efficient working of cargo. Large and airy state
                            rooms have been fitted amidships for the
                            accommodation of first-class passengers, for
                            whom also is provided cm the bridge deck a
                            handsomely fitted entranoe hall louDge, and
                            smokeroom. Over these is fitted a large pro-
                            menade deck, on whioh is plaoed the captain’s
                            accommodation and chart-room. The aeoond-
                            olass passengers are aooommodated aft in the
                            poop, and the offioen and engineers’ rooms are
                            fitted under the bridge deck The vessel is
                            lighted by electricity throughout, and ample
                            refrigerating chambers have been fitted for the
                            preservation of provisions. The machinery is of
                            the triplo-explanaion type. The vessel and
                            machinery have been superintended during
                            construction by Messrs. William Bsplen and
                            Son, Liverpool, and the christening oeremony
                            was performed by Miss Harding, of Stanton,
                            Bebington, Cheshire.</p>
                        <h2>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</h2>
                        <p>Hie Moss liner Nitocris arrived yesterday
                            morning from Glasgow with passengers, mails
                            and general cargo.
                            The Khedivial Mail Steamship Assouan will
                            leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on Saturday and
                            Port Said at 4 p.m. on Sunday for Beyrouth,
                            Tripoli, Mersina, Alexandre tta, Larnaoa, Li-
                            massol, Cai'ffa and Jaffa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>PASSENGER LIST.</h2>
                        <h3>ARRIVALS.</h3>
                        <p>Le pequebot-poste Congo, des Messageries
                            Mari times anrivf aojourd’hui de Marseille
                            avait k bord:—
                            M. R G. 0. Moss, M. K. Fuller, M. Bartlett,
                            M. Eynard, M. et Mme Barker, M. et Mme
                            Mirles, M. Chidiao. M. Osman Rifki, M. Rodo-
                            oanaobi, M. Douglas Dunlop, M. Morris, M.
                            Ivor, M. Hussein et Hasson Mahmoud, R. P.
                            Tilhard, Tissot, Verny, 7 Frtres des Booles
                            Chritiennee, Dr. Elis Grad, M. et Mme Por-
                            gnary, M. W. Bonis, Mile Piauoe, M. Moham-
                            med el Dil, M. G. Salibi, M. Piorananti
                            Chinery, M. Q. Roffield, Mme Faro et enfant,
                            M. Marini, M. de Koningh, Mile Cl. Verneuil,
                            Mme Chariton, fomille Nuquimoti, et 89 pas-
                            tagera de 3me et 4me olasses.
                            Lea pa wagers su:vanta sont arrives oe matin
                            par le paquebot Khedivial ‘ Priuoe Abbas” de
                            Constantinople, Dardanelles, Mlielin, Smyrna
                            et Pirde.
                            M.M. Pains, & Cololthis, B. Coidonis,
                            Hassan Abdon GhaH et fils, G. Kyriaooponlos,
                            Ahmed effendi Selim, A. Pavre, Ahmed Bey
                            Assaad, A. Nathan et oompegnon, A.R. Robin
                            sou, Abdul Weteh Bff, Ali Eff. Kamel, P.
                            Stavridis, M. et Mme A. Misnhi et fomille,
                            D. a OylerfD. Pardo, M. Millet, D. Valentis,
                            A. Vafiadia, N. Candopoulos, D.P.T. Kitroeff,
                            J. Coyopoulos, A. Trevlos, B. Calpoyannia,
                            M. Hafiz. 0. Poppa, Panageta, B. Antomopou-
                            loa. N. Mereati, Mme. Dr. Is* Pacha, Finney,
                            Tennant, Yamaha et femffle, Kirakoff, & La-
                            banahkra et so fills, ainsi que 162 t-ffn da
                            port.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" n="6">
                    <h1>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</h1>
                    <div type="section">
                        <p>Sir Francis O’Calteghan, who, after leaf
                        railway eervioe in indie, beoame merging
                        director of the Uganda Railway, it oomi^ oat
                        in Ootober to Cairo on hie way to Uganda.</p>
                        
                        <p>Lieutenant W. F. Johnson, Army Service
                        Corpe, has beeo grouted leave of absence until
                        January 4, 1906.</p>
                        
                        <p>We regret to team that Mr. Wallioh, lame-
                        tor General of the Governmwt Telegraph
                        Department, who left Cairo on tho 15th July
                        on nek leave, haa not benefited by his stay at
                        the bathe of Salsomeggiore in Italy.</p>
                        
                        <p>We regret to announoe the death, whioh
                        occurred on Saturday at Cairo, of V-i—v—
                        Khalaf Bey Khairy, aide-decamp to the
                        Khedive.</p>
                        
                        <p>Bimbashi Mohamed Amin, commandant of
                        Police of Keneh district, has been granted
                        leave for two months from 1st proximo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>SPORT AND PLAY.</h2>
                        <h2>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</h2>
                        <h3>REGATTA</h3>
                        <p>The handicap for tomorrow’s race will be
                            the same as test week.
                            Class I. Course P.
                            Class IL Coarse Q.</p>
                        <h2>BRITISH RIFLE CLUB</h2>
                        <p>We are asked to remind members that then
                            will be a practice on Saturday next at Mostepha
                            range, omnmanning at 8 p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <h2>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</h2>
                        <p>We do not hold ourselves responisble for the opinions expressed
                            by our correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play
                            to all, to permit - within certain necessary limits - free
                            discounts.</p>
                        <h2>THE NICOSIA CHURCH.</h2>
                        <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gaxhte.
                            Sir,—I was glad to read in a reoent Dumber
                            of your esteemed journal that the little
                            Anglican Church, at Niooaia, Cyprus, haa been
                            greatly improved, as regards deoorations. It
                            is a nioe little church and what puzzles me,
                            is why no steps have ever been tafan to
                            organise a proper choir. Probably they have
                            one by now, but when I was these last-nr
                            no snoh thing existed. On my enquiring why
                            they did not have one, I was told that then
                            were not enough people, or some such excuse.
                            Surely there must be four gentlemen and four
                            or five ladies in Niooaia who oan zing 1
                            If they were to pnetioe onoe a week, as is ifong
                            at the English Churoh here, I believe they
                            would be able to oonduot the servioe chorally,
                            whioh is always nioe, and I am sore the dwp-
                            lain would prefer it Very often the choir at
                            St. Mark’s only numbers about six pessons,
                            and yet they are able to oonduot tho servioe
                            very well I do not therefore see why no steps
                            should be taken to furnish the ohurok at
                            Nioosia with a choir. The late Ven. Archdaaoon
                            8penoer, very often mentioned that it was a
                            pity no ohoir existed—only it seems he did
                            not try to get one np. The climate is very
                            healthy, and I am surprised to find snoh a
                            comparatively small British oommunity. I am
                            told that nothing goes ahead in Cyprus, and
                            that all who have from time to time establish-
                            ed businesses there had to sell np and leave.
                            I am always interested in anything that deals
                            with Cyprus.
                            1 am, Sir, etc,
                            A Well-Wisher of Cyprus.
                            Alexandria, August 16.</p>
                        <h2>CREDIT FONCIER SHARES.</h2>
                        <p>Te the Editor of the Egyptian Qaam.
                            Sir,—As there may be soma holders of Credit
                            Foncier Egyptian thane here whom it interests,
                            I would oall attention to a very oariont feature
                            in the quotations of their shares reoently
                            issued in Paris. There appears to be an attempt
                            to lower their prioe until after the new issue.
                            Within the test ten days Paris quotation
                            was frs. 815. An order sent to eight brokers in
                            Paris to buy at 8l8gaveno execution, but the
                            prioe row to 822, than on no order being sent
                            prioe was redwood to 816.
                            An order was sent to bay at 819, and a few
                            shares wertf given and prioe was raised to 821,
                            again no order was sent and prioe went np to
                            816, orders sent at 818 but no shares sold, and
                            we dose at 891. A Haves rumour rays a great
                            financier is striving to make the Credit Fonder
                            shareholders abstain from tbs new issue, ao
                            that the Daira 8anieh shareholders may get a
                            big interest in the Credit Fonder, and thow
                            who had Daira interest may retain an interest
                            in Egyptian affaire, instead being paid off in
                            otah. Henoe this oonstant marking down of
                            prioes without sales.
                            Perhaps this note may save a Credit Fonder
                            shareholder.	I ass, Sir, etc.,
                            Lux.
                            Alexandria, August 22.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advertisement"></div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>