<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE. FRIDAY, JANUARY 13, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section"><head>TO-DAY’S TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>PORT ARTHUR.</head>
                        <head type="sub">SURRENDER COMPLETE.</head>
                            <p>Port Arthur, January 12. </p>
                            <p>General Nogi reports that 546 guns were captured at Port Arthur, together 82,670 shells, 30,000 kilogrammes of powder, and 2,266,800 rounds of rifle ammunition. (R.)</p>
                            <p>Port Arthur, January 12.</p>
                            <p>The surrender of the place has been completed. It comprises 59 forts and 546 guns.
                                (Havas.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>GENERAL KUROPATKlN</head>
                        <head type="sub">RUMOUR OF RECALL.</head>
                            <p>St. Petersburg, January 12.</p>
                            <p>It is rumoured that General Kuropatkin will
                                be recalled.	(Havas.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>NEW RUSSIAN LOAN.</head>
                        <p>BERLIN, January 12.</p>
                        <p>The subscription for new Russian Loan opened here and closed immediately. The applications were unusually large.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>ORENBURG-TASHKENT RAILWAY.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, January 12.</p>
                            <p>The provisional running of trains on the Orenburg-Tashkent Railway will commence on the 14th inst. (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY COMMISSION.</head>
                        <head type="sub">RULES OF PROCEDURE</head>
                            <p>Paris, January 12.</p>
                            <p>The Commission of Enquiry has completed its rules of procedure. The agents' statements will be read at the first public sitting, which will take place on the 19th inst. The examination of the witnesses, the presentation of the agents' conclusions, and the final announcement of the Commission's decisions, will also be made at public sittings, whereas the Commissioners will deliberate in secret. (Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>HOME POLITICS.</head>
                        <head type="sub">GENERAL ELECTION PROSPECTS.</head>
                            <p>London, January 12.</p>
                            <p>Mr. Anold Foster, speaking at Croydon, said he thought there would be swing of the pendulum at the next General Election. He .it Til., next General Election. • lie ur.e.i	electors I" make the Collar-"</p>
                            <p>At Mt-;	-upe: Aiaie, .Mi Walter Long
                                aun.ltu- 1 111..I it alls possible the COUIItiy in .tr Temjit.iaMl) -Mr [ ,i lioVeriinielit Irym</p>
                            <p>-j.easi .. .it 1‘re-T- i . -Mr Vliaui nerlam said
                                n.at..- ’ - he ii«. wed trial It tie- Ills intetltioll ■ , saw s-ttori.	(/Irater.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>MEETING OF PARLIAMENT</head>
                        <head type="sub">PROBABLE DISSOLUTION IN MARCH</head>
                            <p>LONDON, January 12.</p>
                            <p>Parliament will meet on the 14th February Persistent reports are current in parliamentary circles that the dissolution will take place in March.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
                        <head type="sub">PRESIDENT OF SENATE ELECTED</head>
                            <p>Paris, January 12.</p>
                            <p>Chamber of Deputies.—M. Doumer, the President, delivered a speech of conciliation amidst the hisses of the Extreme Left.</p>
                                <p>Senate. M. Falieres has been re-elected President.	(Havas.)</p>
                                <p>Paris, January 12.</p>
                                <p>M. Falieres has been re-elected President of the Senate.	(Reuter.)</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>RECOVERY OF SIGNOR TITTONl.</head>
                        <p>Rome, January 12.</p>
                        <p>Signor Tittoni has recovered.	(Reuter.)</p></div></div>
                <div type="section"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Charity Ball, which was to have been given to-morrow by the Germania Lodge, has been postponed owing to the death of Mr. Blum.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Alhambra Theatre.—A ball will be given at this theatre tomorrow and another on Sunday, on the occasion of the Orthodox Now-Year.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>American Mission.—The Rev. H. P. Reid, of Alexandria, will conduct the English service at the American Mission in Tantah next Sabbath</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Seamen 's Home. The New Year’s treat given by the Ramleh ladies to the sailors frequenting the port of Alexandria has been fixed for the 26th inst.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>The Pilgrimage. We hear that the total number of pilgrims this year amounts at present to 3,610 ; 2,000 of whom are going at their own expense.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Abdeen district of Cairo during the night of Saturday and morning of Sunday will be poisoned by the police.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Cairo Gambling Hells Raided.--Early yesterday  morning the Cairo police raided two gambling hells, one in El Roui street, the other opposite the new Bazaar.
                        H.H.S. “Aida” returned to Alexandria this morning from Suakin, where she had gone with Sir Win. Garstin, G.C.M.G., Adviser to the Ministry of Public Works.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Authorisations.—Messrs. W. M. Thorey, Farid Abela, Hassan Zaki, Djemil Choukry, and Nassim Haddad, doctors, and Jean Doila, chemist, have been authorised to exercise their profession in Egypt.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Um Rus Gold Mines. — Application has been made to the London Stock Exchange Committee to appoint a special settling day Um Rus Gold Mines in Egypt 90,000 Vendors' Shares of £1 each, fully paid, Nos. 1 to 90,000.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>SUEZ Canal.—On the 9th inst. 12 vessels passed through the Canal, the receipts for the day being frs. 2« 1,007.99. a of the ships were bntisb, 1 Norwegian, 1 French, 2 German, 2 Dutch, 1 Danish. The total receipts from 1st to 9th inst. were frs. 3,242,002.35.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>A Scientific Mission.—Dr. Arloing, of the Academy of Medicine, Parts, of the French Institute, and Director of the Veterinary School at Lyons, who was here last year in order to study bovine typhus, is paying another visit to Egypt to complete his observations.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>A.L.M. and D.S.—As members of the choral union and amateur orchestra experience great difficulty in finding Rudolph s Asile, it may be useful to inform them that the best route thither is to take Averoff-street, and then the 4th turning to the lett (opposite the Windsor Hotel brings one at once to the side gate alongside of the Armenian Chapel.</p></div>
                    
                    <div type="item"><p>The Abbassieh Murder.— The Cairo police and the Native Parquet are still engaged in unravelling the murder of a native girl at Abbassieh. The first intimation of the crime reached the police through the father of the victim, a fairly well-to-do native ol Abbassieh, Mustapha Effeudi Ezab by name, who went to the police station at Wally two days ago and stated that his daughter Amna, a girl of 5 years, who had left home to play with some children of her own age, had mysteriously disappeared. The  police have discovered that the child was kidnapped by a servant named Hamad, who stole the child s earrings and then threw her into a pit, where she expired. The woman on being arrested accused her husband of the murder.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Timely Charity.—A very interesting ceremony took place on Wednesday at the Greek-Catholic Church, Alexandria, when a number of Syrian ladies made what is a bi-annual distribution of clothing to about one hundred indigent children of both sexes. The articles distributed were the result of the industry and philanthropy of the ladies themselves, among whom we noticed Mesdames George Bey Zananiri, Michel Bey Ayoub, Wadi Gabali, Habib Autonios, and others. The children, besides being provided with suitable winter wearing apparel, were regaled with refreshments, and the expressions of joy which filled their countenances must have been sufficient recompense for the charitableness of their fair benefactors.</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Egyptian Cigarettes.—The Cleopatra Cigarette Company, which was founded a few mouths ago by Nungovich Bey and Mr. Constantine Meimarachi, is making great strides in captivating the popular taste for a good Egyptian cigarette at a moderate price. Owing to the company being under the auspices of the managing-director of the Nungovich Hotels Company and of Walker and Meimarachi, Ltd., those cigarettes are strongly backed and are on sale at all the Nungovich hotels, as well as at the branches of Walker and Meimarachi at Cairo and Alexandria, and the principal hotels in Europe and America. The cigarettes are beautifully got up in artistic boxes, the trademark being the bead of the Egyptian queen from whom the cigarettes take their name.</p></div></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE RUSSIAN SQUADRON.</head>     
                    <head type="sub">DEPARTURE FROM SUEZ.</head><p>
                        (From Our Own Correspondent)</p>
                    <p>Suez, Thursday.</p>
                    <p>The Russian squadron, consisting of four cruisers, “Dnieper," “Rion," “Oleg," and “Izumrud,” and three torpedo-destroyers, “Gromki,” “Gosni," and “Riezvy,” under Admiral Botrovosky, entered the Canal yesterday forenoon. The destroyers reached Ismailia shortly after 4 p.m., when they anchored for the night, and resumed their voyage at 6 30 this morning. The cruisers, having searchlights, came through without stopping, and arrived at Suez at 5 o'clock this morning, anchoring in the Bay. At 10 a.m. the three destroyers came out of the Canal and anchored near the remainder of the squadron.</p>
                    <p>All the ships are fitted with wireless telegraphy apparatus and quick-firing guns. The “Dnieper” and “Rion” (ex “Petersburg" and “Smolensk" respectively), as well as the destroyers, are painted slate colour, while the two other cruisers have the usual Russian naval colour.</p>
                    <p>At this end of the canal they did not take on any coal, but were allowed to take a certain quantity of provisions and live-stock. During their stay they did not communicate with the shore owing to the plague at Suez, and wore flying the voluntary quarantine flags, in order to receive free pratique at Djibouti, where they intend coaling.</p>
                    <p>Several police and Coast Guard launches were patrolling the harbour, and almost similar precautions were taken as before, when the first division passed through.</p>
                    <p>Thanks to the arrangements of the Suez Canal Company, no steamer in the canal was detained, in spite of the large traffic.</p>
                    <p>The Russian Squadron intends sailing tonight, or at daybreak to-morrow, for Djibouti.</p>
                    <p>Suez, Friday.</p>
                    <p>Admiral Botrovosky’s squadron sailed at 5.40 this morning for Djibouti.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head><p>
                    Yesterday morning, the Khedive received Mazloum Pasha, who presented Mr. J. Wells, the new Inspector of Mines ; M. Alexandre de Zogheb, Portuguese Diplomatic Agent, who presented the Viscount de Faira, and M. Maskens, who presented M. Ed. Empain.</p>
                    <p>In the atternoon his Highness received the Prince d'Arenberg and MM. X. Charmes, Verge, and Mirabeaud, of the Suez Canal Company, M. Bonnet, M. Quellenec, and Harari Pasha.</p>
                        <p>It is stated that his Highness will very probably start on an excursion of three weeks' duration in the Libyan desert about the 25th inst.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>COAST GUARDS ADMINISTRATION.</head><p>
                    Lewa Hunter Pasha, Director-General of tbe Coast Guards Administration, and Mrs. Hunter and friends have gone for a trip down the Red Sea to Suakin and district. They hope to have a very pleasant trip, as the climatic conditions in those parts at this time of the year are excellent.</p>	
                    <p>The ostensible and official reason for this trip is that the Director-General of the administration has gone on a camel purchasing expedition, and Kaimakam Dumreicher Bey is accompanying the expedition in order to give his advice. These constant pleasure trjps of the highest officials of the Coast Guards Administration are always taken on the flimsiest excuse, for it is perfectly obvious that the presence of the Director-General of the administration is not necessary in order to buy camels, which any responsible subordinate officer could undertake. At present it is the busiest season of the year, and there is more opportunity for smuggling when the Customs officials are overworked, owing to the pressure their time due to the great influx of trade at this season, and the absence of Lewa Hunter Pasha on a pleasure excursion has aroused much comment, especially among the native officials in this administration</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head><p>
                    Yesterday's bulletin records three fresh cases at Suez (two fatal) and a death in hospital.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head><p>
                    The Messageries Maritimes S.S. “Congo" arrived at Marseilles from Alexandria at 11 p.m. yesterday.</p>	
                    <p>The Moss liner “Seti” sailed from Malta yesterday evening, and is due here on Monday morning at daybreak, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail S.S. "Mariout" will leave Alexandria on Saturday for Jaffa, Caiffa, Beyrout, Tripoli, Mersina, Alexandretta and Port Said.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. "Spartan Prince,” from Antwerp and London, and the S.S. “Cyprian Prince,” from Manchester, left Malta on Thursday and are due here on Monday next, with passengers and general cargo.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>CARLTON HOTEL.
                    Baikal*?, Ramleh.
                    Ten minstea from Alaxtndrfe. Hr«t-OU« la mrjr rmpaot. Very moderate rheryee. Imlkeley Is the tashto—Me WucUah
                    MtWII !■—	0, A9CTUHA.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN DELTA LAND.</head>
                    <head>INCREASE OF CAPITAL.</head><p>
                        An extraordinary general meeting of the Egyptian Delta Land and investment Company, Limited, was held in London on Wednesday, 11th inst.</p>
                    <p>The object for which the meeting was called was in regard to the increase of the capital of the company to £260,000. The resolution to effect was passed.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>NEW RAILWAY LINES.</head><p>
                    We hear that the construction of new lines to Zifta and from Ashmoun to the Delta Barrage has been decided upon.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>HELOUAN RAILWAY.</head>
                    <head type="sub">NEW TIME-TABLE.</head><p>
                        We understand that the Delta Light Railway Company intends to introduce a new timetable on the Helouan branch as from the 20th instant. The trains between Babel-Look and Helouan will leave about the same times at present and the time of most of them will be reduced to minutes. Six new trains will be run between Babel-Look and Tourah, to relieve the through trains and provide more facilities for the growing local traffic between these places. Persons wishing to take baths will be able to leave Cairo at 9.10 a.m., stay more that two hours at Helouan, and return in ample time for lunch.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>SALT AND SODA CO.</head><p>
                    We are informed that at yesterday's meeting of the Salt and Soda Company in London, the proposals put to the shareholders were carried unanimously.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>ZINZINIA THEATRE.</head><p>
                    The last performance of the Italian opera  company took place yesterday evening, when “Rigoletto” was successfully staged. The company leaves to-day tor Cairo, where it wilt make its debut to-morrow evening.</p>
                    <p>The French comedy company which terminated its Cairo season at the Khedivial Opera House last night arrived at Alexandria to-day and will open at the Zizinia to-morrow evening.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><head>CERCLE ARTISTIQUE.</head><p>
                    A concert will be given at the Cercle Artistique, Cairo. at 5.30 p.m. on Sunday next. The programme includes:</p>
                    <p>Air by Sinding and Chanson Napolitaine by Liszt.—M. Valentino.</p>
                    <p>Romance and finale of Wienawski's 2nd concerto.—M. Serato.</p>
                    <p>Air from “Aida.”—Mme. Bracale.</p>
                    <p>Adagio from Bruck’s 2nd concerto.</p>
                    <p>Song by Ambrosio and Ziugaresca. — M. Serato.</p></div>
                <div type="section"><head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>FOOTBALL.</head><p> 
                        "C." Co. R. Berks. v. St. Andrews.</p>
                        <p>These teams met on the parade-ground, Mustapha, on Saturday last, when an interesting game was witnessed by a fair turn-out of spectators. Saint Andrews kicked off against the wind, and some nice exchanges came the way of both sides. The homesters were showing the better combination, and the visitors' defence had their work cut out to keep them from getting through. Success came their way eventually, Walmer taking up the ball from a well placed corner kick, and screwing it in in a most masterly fashion, giving the Saints’ custodian no chance to save. Half-time arrived with the score 1-0. The “Saints” in the second half tried hard to equalise, but, although both ends were visited in turn, no further scoring took place, “C" Company thus retiring victors by 1-0. The following were the teams :—</p>
                        <p>"C" Company:—Muilard, Beile, Dovey, Young, Dovey, Ryan, Clark, Neble, Walmer, Prior and Finnes.</p>
                        <p>Saint Andrews:—A. N. Other, Dawson, Fitzgerald, Sweet, Nixon, Bright, Saunderson, Jones, Murphy, Cowie, Hutchins.</p></div></div>
                <div type="item"><head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Singapore” de la Cie Florio Rubattino parti hier pour Genes avait a bord : </p>
                    <p>MM. M. Jacob, Livio Mario, V. Sarti, E. Isnardi, Comite de Mexicains (12), Mme J. Ungar, M. et Mme Artom, Stenger, Heinrich Genund, Toselli, Branche, Bezaut et 25 passagers de 3me classe.</p></div>
                <div type="item"><p>CAIRO BRAND HAMWUM.
                    TURKISH SATM^~ " x hay». ** ELECTfclC URHT BATHS-
                    ■ iHSiGV a (LKCTUO-HTDBOriTBIC B1TH-. if-	Dr. Prof««r rtnuarlo* Dr. It 1UW</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>Grand Hotel Bonnard</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL
                        CAIRO.
                        Open till the year rtmnd,
                        flWTRtO HURT. - lift. ~</p></div>
                    <div type="section"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                        <div type="item"><p>Prince Aziz Hassan has returned to Cairo from his round-the-world trip.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Lord G. Cholmondeley and the Earl of Londesborough have arrived at Khartoum, where they will make a short stay.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Sir Colin and Lady Scott-Moncrieff, the Misses Scott-Moncrieff, and party arrived by the Orient Line steamer "Ortona,” and are staying at the Hotel d’Angleterre, Cairo.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Dr. Rucker-Jenisch, German Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General Cairo, was married to Countess Thyra de Grete at-Berlin on Tuesday. Dr. and Mrs. Rucker Jenisch are expected to arrive at Cairo via Part Said on the 23rd inst.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The German Consul-General’s bride was born at Varchentin, in Mecklenburg-Schwerin, in 1881. She is the daughter of Count Adolf de Grote, formerly Hanoverian Minister at Madrid. Her brother, Count Gernud Grote, is Marshal of the Court, and his brother-in-law is chamberlain and private secretary to Duke Ernest Augustus of Cumberland.</p></div>
                        
                        <div type="item"><p>Mr. A F. Home, of the 11th Hussars, who married Miss Violet D’Arcy, daughter of Mr. W. K. D'Arcy, some few years ago, and who is well known in Cairo, has just obtained his troop in that regiment. He has been waiting for his captaincy for about seven years, and has now obtained it owing to Captain Kenrick having boon made adjutant of the Lanarkshire Yeomanry.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Mr. and Mrs. Bradley Martin had arranged
                            to leave London on Sunday last for Paris and Egypt. It was expected that Lord And Lady
                            Craven would accompany them.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Comtesse de Roydeville is shortly coming to Egypt from Beaulieu, France.</p></div>
                        
                        <div type="item"><p>M. Randone, the statistical expert of the Customs Administration, is leaving Alexandria for Cairo at the end of this month in order
                            to occupy a high position in the Statistical Office of the Finance Ministry.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The funeral of Mahdly Bey Ahmed, chief cashier of the Public Debt Commission, took place at Cairo yesterday Afternoon.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Savoy Hotel is filling very rapidly, many large parties having arrived this week, amongst
                            whom are Mme. de Weerth, Master de Weerth, and Miss Hammer, of Paris ;
                            Mr. Luzarche d’Azay, Paris Mr. and Mrs. Walter L. Mackintosh, Pittsburg
                            ; Mr. Ignace Zakrewsky and the Misses Zakrewsky, St. Petersburg; Mr. and
                            Mrs. F. B. Joel, Mr. R.C. Coode and Miss W. A. Coode, London ; Mts. and
                            Miss Smallman, Canada; Mrs. Weldon and Miss Cope, Miss von Villeneuve,
                            London ; Mr. Max Henraux, Mr. Jean Lefevre, Paris ; Mr. Mr. Hugh Cayley,
                            London ; Dr. H. Goldschmidt, Berlin; Mr. and Mrs. Bradley Martin, Jun.,
                            New York; Mr. W. M. Postlethwaite and the Misses Postlethwaite,
                            Washington ; Mr. E. W. Halliday, Mrs. E.H. Rodgers and party, U.S.A ;
                            Mr. and Mrs. A.S. Heidelbach, New York ; M. and Mme Trinkaus,
                            Duesseldorf; and Miss Trill.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Savoy Restaurant is full every evening. Amongst those dining there on Wednesday evening we noticed : Count de Vauvineux and party, including Izzet Pasha and Mr. Lozardhe d’Azay ; Mrs. Mainwairing And party, including Sir John and Lady Rogers Pasha, Capt. LeWin; the Rev. Mr. Ryan and party, including Col. Mackenzie, Mr. and Mrs. Fitzgerald, Rav. and Mrs. Smith, and Mr. Donegan ; Mr. and Mrs. Paraviclni, etc.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The dances at the Savoy Hotel have been exceptionally successful this year. Next Saturday's dance promises to be the best attended. The restaurant is likely to be very full, as many large dinners have already been ordered for the evening. The Bracale Orchestra will play daring dinner.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. H. S. Martin, Mr. M. Duckstein, Mr. A. R. Bulman, Mrs. G. Milward, Col. Smith, Lt.-Col. Grattan, Mr. and Mrs. W. S. Powell.</p></div>
                        
                        <div type="item"><p>We learn that, with the exception of a few good rooms, which are still available, the Tewfik Palace Hotel is “au complet" Everything tends to show that a bumper season is in store for this and all the other hotels end pensions in Helouan. The arrivals this week at the Tewfik have been considerable, and amongst those expected within the next few days are Mr. and Mrs. Cooke Taylor, Mr. and Mrs. M.M. Miller, Mrs. J. M. Mackenzie, Mrs. Chas. Eyles, Mrs. E. H. Grogan, Mr. and Mrs. A. H. Payton, Mrs. Daman, Mrs. H. Finch, Mr. E. G. Owlee, Mr. Wilson, and the Misses Turner. The management of this hotel have now made their own 9-hole golf links, and all golfers, visitors and residents alike, can make use of them at all times, free Of charge. The arrangements of the P.T. 12 'Reclame" lunch are still in operation, and a first rate orchestra has been engaged to cheer the hearts of the guests during lunch end tea on Thursday and Sunday.</p></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><head>LE BUDGET MUNICIPAL</head>
                        <head type="sub">Le Fouctionaarisme</head>
                        <p>l*s recettes municipales qui étaient «MM modestes à l’origine de l'iastitettoo, ee sont aooruee rapidement eUnjourd’hei »*rebudget atteint une «estime de près de 900,000 irâra. Malheureusement les facultés administratives d'absorption se sont dév^oppéas avec non moins de rapidité et le muphte des naèttes disparaît toujonre avec une extrême facilité dans le gouffre des dépenses.</p>
                            <p>L'année passée déjà, nos bhégérira— mnni-eipaux approuvèrent avoua difficulté A disposer intégralement d'on total de «èafttre de lfttOOO livras. Cette année les 16,000 livres d'augmentation de revenu lie leur ont apnaé aucun embarras. La somme intégrale a été- inscrite aux dépenses.</p>
                            <p>Dans de telles conditions, en supposant que l’augmentation oootinue graduellement et que les téoettes de 1906 dépassent 900,000 fines, on peut s'attendra à ee que oette tomme soit aagloatie de la “-“tra «vif in</p>
                            <p>Ce qui surprend davantage dans le budget de 1905, c’est que l'augmentation des dépensa ne provient pas d'une pin forte somma de travail aooempU par l'administration, puis presque uniquement d'une majoration, de traita mente du penonoaL II n’est pas are» intérêt à ce propos de rechercher la proportion qei «date entra le travail fourni par la Municipalité et Us émoluments qu’elle distribue à ara employés pour voir s’il y avait lieu d’opéwr cette majoration d’appointementei</p>
                            <p>Aéet effet «ma dirieértms Ira dfpMauü en quatre catégories : V sommés payé» par la oaisao municipale, 9’ traitements do-peneraiel, 3* travaux d’utilité publique et 4" dépenses diverses. </p>
                            <p>Ia première catégorie oeraprend toutes les sommes payées à des administrations privées, distinotes de l'Administration Municipale, allouées à des sociétés de bieofaisanoes et autres et enfin toutes sommes payées directement par la Caisse et oh le personnel n’entra pour rien. La Ole du Gaz figura dans oette catégorie pour 92,050 L.B, d'éclairage la Oie des Baux pour 6,460 LK d’eau (190 pour F Administration Centrale, 500 pour le curage des égouts, 5,000 pour le nettoiement, 600 pour les para et plantations, 240 pour l'abattoir \ la pompions pour 4,950 LK, la sociétés de bien-faisanoes et eutraepoar 5,040 L.K, le fonds de prévojranoe du personne pour 9,400 LE, le servioe de l'emprunt pour 90,250 LE., fos frais judiciaires pour 125 LE., la expropriations pour 4,000 L.B., la polioe municipale pour 565 L.E., la réserve pour 3,700 LE.— Soit un total de près de 70,000 L.E.—Cette somme ne représente aucun travail fourni par la Municipalité et doit donc fitre mise de oôté pour la proportion qne nous voulons établir.</p>
                            <p>La traitements du . personnel classé, non olassé et hors cadre atteignent environ 50,000 ivres, y compris 5 à 6,000 livra de frais divers' (bureau etc.). Dans oette catégorie entrent l’Administration Centrale pour 8„170 LE., le sérvice des recettes pour 12,460, la services techniques pour 4,130, le bureau technique pour 3,140, la voirie pour 4,720, le nettoiement pour 2,268, les services sanitaires pour 6,360, l’abattoir pour 2,205, le mnsée et la Biliothèque pour 1,859. B est iaportent de foire remarquer ici que la joornalfets sont compris b part et entrent dans là catégorie suivante comme foff ririssRht un travail distinct da la comptabilité.</p>
                            <p>La troisième catégorie représente le trtriail accompli sous la direction Ct la surveillance da la Municipalité : entretien du pavagfe LE. 16,850, entretien da routa madachtmiséa</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>ONE NIGHT ONLY.
                        Saturday, January 14, at 9.80.
                        KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.
                        tfndet the distinguished Patronage, and in the presonoe of: R B. GOULD, Esq., I.S.O., H.B.M.’s Consul-General; Brio.-Genrral G. M. BULLOCK, C.B., and Admiral Sir. MASSIE and Ladt BLOMFIELD.
                        H. SCOTTLESLIE
                        (Th. wtll-Ynown Whion InUfUlner I aacnteiW WH1 (fire a HutnoroM A Ntutel
                        BElCITAIs
                        Hnppen«l by Hr. DAVID n. WOKTOH.
                            Phniat fOoroa'a Hall, lohdoo).	I
                            Hmnoroa* loap.	I Hnmoratu Sketch*..
                            ADMISSION P.V. 20.
                            Tickets may be had of Davies Bryan  Co.
                            iHttt</p></div>
                    <div type="item"><p>“AU DE ftOUGE.”
                        •CRdMl MAKRY EtTMlMMCm.
                        (Oeutral TMimwwy ratntUm),
                        O A i It o .
                        P. PL	UNKi
                        PROPRIXTOB.
                        DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITlSfe AND IRISH TEXTILE lANyFXCTURES.
                        Ladles’ Fancy Silk Blonses and Skirts, and Fancy Material for Bvening Wear, Also Fans, Fancy Pins, Art ficial Flowers,Pearl M«ck-lets, and Gblfftons.
                        Ladles' and Oent*’ Pocket Hand-</p></div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>


