<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Hannah Sain</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-09">December 9, 2016</date><gloss>1</gloss></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-09-07/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-07">Thursday, September 7, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent></bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/mode/1up">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7287] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1. </head>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/page/n1/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div> 
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 9, 1905</head><div type="section" feature="wire">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PEACE. Excitement at Portsmouth. SPEECHES BY PLENIPOTENTIARIES. Demonstration at tokio.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>Portsmouth (N.H.), September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>A volley of guns announced the signing of the peace treaty at 8.47 p.m. The
                        church bells at Portsmouth and Newcastle were rang, and flags were hung out
                        everywhere.</p>
                    <p>After the treaty had been signed, M. Rosen and M. Komura delivered cordial
                        speeches, expressing the wish that the two countries would remain good
                        friends. The representatives of the two nations shook hands. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                    <dateline>Portsmouth (N.H.), September 6.</dateline><p>M. Maartens, in an interview after the signa-ture of peace, said that Russia
                        will not brood over the past, but will gather all her forces a new struggle,
                        not on the battlefield, but in the fields of social and political progress.
                        (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                    <dateline>Portsmouth (U.S.A.), September 6.</dateline><p>The town is decorated with flags in honor of the signing of the peace
                        treaty.The Japanese plenipotentiaries have left (Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                    <dateline>Tokio, September 6.</dateline><p>A meeting held here yesterday protested against the terms of peace, and
                        attacked the offices of the Government organ "Kokumin." Several people were
                        injured and a number of arrests have been made. (Reuter)</p></div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMENIANS IN ATHENS. BOMB DEPOTS DISCOVERED.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>Athens, September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>The police have discovered several large depots of bombs, rifles, and
                        cartridges, notably the cellar of the Armenian Church. An investigation
                        leads to the belief that a widespread Armenian plot to induce the
                        intervention of Europe in favor of Armenia has been unearthed. The object of
                        this plot seems to have been to terrorise the Turks. Twelve Armenians have
                        been arrested. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                    <dateline>Athens, September 6.</dateline><p>An important Armenian organisation has been discovered, which desires to
                        induce European intervention in Turkish affairs. (H.)</p></div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TARTARS IN THE CAUCASUS. A REIGN OF TERROR.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>Baku, September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>Bands of Tartars are devastating the south-east. of the Caucasus province,
                        assassinating and pillaging everywhere. Official reports admit that 200
                        people have been killed and wounded in the fights at Shusha, which is now on
                        fire. The quarter where the factories and petrol refinery are situated is
                        also on fire. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="cable">
                    <dateline>Tiflis, September 6.</dateline><p>The Tartars are terrorising the south-east of Transcaucasia. (Havas)</p></div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHOLERA EPIDEMIC. 90 CASES, 26 DEATHS.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>Berlin, September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>The official bulletin notifies ninety cases of cholera and twenty-six deaths.
                        (Havas)</p></div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CHANNEL SQUADRON.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>Dantzig, September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>The Channel Squadron has sailed. (Reuter)</p></div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME CRICKET.</head>
                    <div type="cable"><dateline>London, September 6.</dateline>
                    <p>Players beat Gentlemen by an innings and 196 runs. The rest of the matches
                        for this date were drawn. (Reuter)</p></div>
                </div></div>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plaque</head>
                        <p>Yesterday a bulletin reports the death of a native street cleaner of the
                            Labban quarter.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Child Discovered</head>
                        <p>A newborn child, alive and apparently healthy, was found last night in
                            the Rue dee Soeurs and has been taken to hospital.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p>found in — Ismailieh quarter of Cairo during to morrow might and at dawn
                            of the 9th inst will poisoned by the police.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Counterfeit Marks</head>
                        <p>A goldsmith named Khalil Zeitoun was arrested yesterday on the charge of
                            counterfeiting the Government hallmarks on gold and silver articles.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ex-Empoye sentenced</head>
                        <p>The Gizeh native Court has condemned Moh. Ragbeb, ex-caretaker of the
                            Maadi station, to six months imprisonment and L.E. 60 fine for
                            embezzlement.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez canal</head>
                        <p>13 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th inst, 8 of which were
                            British, 3 German, 1 French, 1 Dutch. The day's receipts were frs.
                            432,393.75, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 1,150,561.83.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Gambling Hell Raided</head>
                        <p>On Monday evening the police made a successful descent on a a gambling
                            hell kept by a native in the Boulac quarter. The usual proces-verbal has
                            been drawn up and the roulette board, etc. seized.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Legislative Council</head>
                        <p>A meeting of the Legislative Council will be held on October 1, udner the
                            presidency of Abdul Hamid Pasha Sadik, when the questions connected with
                            the Armenian Church in Egypt will be discussed.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A Father's Cruelty</head>
                        <p>A native, named Mustapha Hassan, of Minet el Bassal, yesterday inflicted
                            such a severe flogging on his son, who is barely four years of age, that
                            the child fainted and had to be taken to hospital The unnatural parent
                            has been arrested.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Departure of the Royal Berkshire regt</head>
                        <p>We learn that the A C.C. is giving an at home at the Cricket Club to the
                            officers of the 2nd Royal Berkshire Regt, on Friday, the 15th inst., on
                            the occasion of cricket match between the regiment and the club.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Sudan Irrigation</head>
                        <p>The "Nineteenth Century and After" for September contains a long and most
                            interesting article by Sir William Garstin on the Irrigation of the
                            Sudan and the new engineering schemes for the Upper Nile which are now
                            being examined and discussed. We hope to give our readers the fall text
                            of the most important article in the near future.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Harmful soap</head>
                        <p>One of our Cairo contem-poraries states that the sanitary administration
                            has decided to take vigorous measures to prevent the sale of soaps
                            containing salicylate of soda, which remove dirt from the skin and after
                            a while remove the skin as well. All manufacturers of these poisonous
                            soaps will be prosecuted and the soap seised.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Delivery of Mails at Akhmin</head>
                        <p>Much disatisfaction is expressed at the late hoar at which the mails
                            arrive at Akhmin. The usual time at which they arrive is 8.30 am. but
                            there is no reason why they should not be here an hoar earlier and be
                            ready for distribution at 8 am. It is to be hoped that the notice of the
                            Postal authorities will be drawn to this, and that they will arrange for
                            an advanced hour of delivery.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fraudulent Broker</head>
                        <p>Taking a leaf out of the books of the Mariout Bedouin, a native broker
                            recently sold a plot of land at Ibrahim-ieh, which he asserted to be his
                            property, to a confiding client named El Bayed Mohamed El Gayar, who
                            paid L.E 438.70 for what he probably imagined would be an excellent
                            site. On discovering the fraud the victim complained to the authorities.
                            A proces-verbal has been drawn up against the broker and handed over to
                            the Parquet.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Abdul Halim Pasha Assim has returned to Alexandria, after presiding ovar the
                        meeting of the Superior Council of the Wakfa Administration, which met at
                        Cairo on Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>The Russian Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General left Alexandria for Cairo
                        yesterday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>We are authorised to contradict the rumour that Mr. Trevithick, chief of the
                        Locomotive Department of the State Railways, is about to retire from the
                        service on pension.</p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. Richmond</persName>, of the Ministry of Public Works, has arrived at Alexandria from
                        Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Ibrahim Bey Ali arrived here this morning.</p>
                    <p><persName>General Sir E. Forestier-Walker</persName>, the newly-appointed Governor of Gibraltar,
                        left London for that place last Friday by the P. and O. teamship
                        Mongolia.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="khedive">
                    <head>H. H. THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <head>WILL PROBABLY VISIT SUDAN.</head>
                    <p>Several of our native contemporaries state that H.H. the Khedive will visit
                        the Sudan in the middle of February next to preside over the opening of the
                        new Nile-Red Sea railway between Berber and Port Sudan.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SULTAN'S ACCESSION ANNIVERSARY.</head>
                    <p>Othman Pasha Ghalil, president of the committee of the Sultan's accession
                        fetes' has received a letter from Nouri Bey, secretary to Mukhtar Pasha el
                        Ghazi, Ottoman Commissioner, tendering H.I.M. the Sultan's thanks for the
                        loyal manner in which the committee undertook the organisation of the fetes
                        in celebration of the anniversary of his accession to the throne of
                        Turkey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CORPORATION OF WESTERN EGYPT, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>The order for goods wagons for use on the Nile-Khargeh Railway, now in course
                        of construction under the supervision of Messre. Kincaid, Waller, Manville
                        and Dawson, the consulting engineers to the Corporation, has been placed
                        with the Metropolitan Amalgamated Railway Carriage and Wagon Co., Ltd., who
                        tendered for the supply.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SOLAR ECLIP8E.</head>
                    <p>The "Times" gives the following account of the solar eclipse as viewed from
                        Assouan</p>
                    <p>The eclipse was successfully observed here in a normal clear sky. The British
                        party, with invaluable assistance from Captain Lyons and the officers of the
                        Survey Department, obtained five ordinary exposures with an astrographic
                        telescope, besides one with a green colour screen and one enlargement, six
                        photographs polarized by reflection in a horizontal plane, and two in a
                        vertical plane. Mr. Gunther, of Magdalen College, Oxford, obtained six
                        plates with a Goerz lens for comparison with similar plates taken in
                        Lahrador.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Reynolds's 120ft reflector was mounted under unforeseen difficulties, at
                        short notice, with the able assistance of Mr. Keeling, of the survey, who
                        has helped all the expeditions from the first. The local fire brigade kindly
                        flooded the ground under the tube to check radiation. All the photographs
                        will be developed shortly in Cairo in the Survey Department.</p>
                    <p>There was no opportunity to organise observations at the north and south
                        limits, or on the shadow bauds, but the Survey Department took six-hour
                        magnetic readings according to the international scheme and a register of
                        solar radiation.</p>
                    <p>The Lick Observatory party, under Professor Hussey, carried out their full
                        programme, obtaining eight plates with a 40ft. lens, eight plates for
                        intra-Mercurial planets with a composite battery of four telescopes, and one
                        plate of the general coronal spectrum. The Russian party took four plates of
                        the corona and a photographic register of magnetic elements.</p>
                    <p>The change of temperature was very slight, and a dead calm prevailed.</p>
                    <p>Tha corona was of the distinctly maximum type, with the longest streamer to
                        the southeast, about two diameters at most, probably less, and three others
                        shorter. Query, was the longest streamer over the recent sun spot. The
                        corona seemed small to the eye, perhaps owing to haze or dust and the low
                        sun. There was no sign of Mercury to the eye, nor was the moon seen at
                        sunrise here.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER SUICIDE.</head>
                    <p>At about 6.30 p.m. yesterday a young European girl, who is believed to have
                        been a servant, threw herself into the sea opposite the "Cafe du Quai." The
                        waves carried the body to a point opposite the "Cafe Falerne" where it was
                        seen by a number of persons who had collected there. The coast guards had
                        already telephoned to the police of the Menchieh caracol, who for some time
                        did nothing, and, according to the official report could not recover the
                        corpse till about 11. p.m. Bye witnesses inform os that the body was
                        perfectly visible and might have been recovered with little difficulty, and
                        that the efforts made by the police on the spot were so feeble that it was
                        not till after 4 am. this morning that it was finally brought to shore.</p>
                    <p>The discrepancy between the statement made by the police and that of eye
                        witnesses is so great that we venture to call the attention of the
                        authorities to it If the corpse could have been recovered between 9 and 10
                        p.m.,as our informants asseverate, it would surely have shown better feeling
                        had the police risked a wetting. The idea that a dead body should be allowed
                        to drift about within a few yards of the shore for hours is so repugnant,
                        that we prefer to suppose that our informants did not take into account the
                        roughness of the water near the new quay. In any case the affair seems to
                        require further explanation.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="bandPerformance"><head>ESBEKIEH GARDENS.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Lt-Col C. J. Markham and off, the band of the 1st Batt
                        King's Royal Rifles will perform the following programme of music at the
                        Esbekieh Gardens tomorrow (Friday) evening, commencing at 9 o'clock.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE STATE RAILWAYS. THE SUPERIOR COUNCIL. RETURN TICKETS.</head>
                    <p>As we announced in our issue of the 36th June last the present board of
                        administration of the State Railways will shortly be replaced by a Superior
                        Council, which will be presided over by Mustapha Pasha Fehmi, Prime
                        Minister. We understand that the constitution of the council as reported by
                        us on that date is correct. The date for the formation of the council will
                        not be decided upon until the return of Lord Cromer and the chief Government
                        officials.</p>
                    <p>M. Imblon, secretary to the board, will retire on pension as soon as the
                        change is effected, and will be replaced by Mr. Spiers, who was lately
                        engaged in England. Mr. Spiers, who possesses the necessary technical
                        knowledge for the post will draw a salary of £1,000 a year.</p>
                    <p>The question of the re-issue of return tickets on the State Railways has been
                        for some time under consideration, but as there is a divergence of opinion
                        on this point between the members of the Railway Board, the matter will
                        remain in abeyance for the present It is, however, no indiscretion to state
                        that the return tickets will most probably be introduced with the new year,
                        but then only on the principal lines, such as Cairo and Alexandria, Cairo
                        and Port Said, and possibly also on the Suez line. Measures will be taken to
                        prevent the recurrence of the frauds that were formerly practised on the
                        railway administration, and that wore the cause of the abolition of return
                        tickets, these frauds having been committed with the connivance of some of
                        the petty employes.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO TRAMWAYS CO.</head>
                    <p>The Cairo tramway company are expecting next month from Europe a consignment
                        of fifty cars of a new and improved pattern. These bars contain a special
                        compartment for first-class passengers, with eight seats, which is situated
                        at one end, and a similar compartment for ladies at the other, whilst the
                        centre will be for the second class passengers. They will be put on the
                        principal lines at as early a date as possible after the cars have had the
                        motors fitted at Boulao.</p>
                    <p>We gave a short time back a detailed list of the several extensions and new
                        lines the company are going to add to their present system. The first two to
                        be taken in hand will be the prolongation of the Khalig line from the
                        present terminus at Daher to the avenue Abbas, ending at the Gamrah bridge,
                        and the extension in the opposite direction of the same Line as far as the
                        abattoirs.</p>
                    <p>For the prolongation of the Boulao line from its present terminal point at
                        the landing stage of the Ghezireh Palace ferry to the railway workshops, it
                        will be necessary, in consequence of the narrowness of some of the streets
                        in that locality, to construct a river embankment which will be 150 metres
                        in length and 30 metres wide, which is estimated to cost £6,000.</p>
                    <p>According to the new concession granted by the Government these three
                        extensions will have to be ready for traffic in one year from the 23rd July
                        next</p>
                    <p>The company has paid the Ministry of Public Works the sum of' £3,500 towards
                        the expense of widening the road from Foum El Khalig to the point where the
                        new bridge to Rodah Island is being constructed,and £50,000 is the amount
                        agreed upon to be paid by the company for the privilege of crossing the
                        island from Old Cairo to Ghizeh when the new bridges</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A NEW BIBBY LINER.</head>
                    <p>There was launched on the 31st August at Messrs. Harland and Wolff's Yard,
                        Belfast, the twin-screw steamer Herefordshire (a sister ship to the
                        Worcestershire), with the advent of which the well-known Lancashire and
                        Yorkshire disappear from this service, single screw boats being now
                        recognised as obsolete for first-class passenger traffic. The fortnightly
                        service of the Bibby line will therefore be conducted entirely with
                        twin-screw steamers of high power and the latest type.</p>
                    <p>Of oourse the Bibby patent tandem cabin is in fall evidence, for it has been
                        so generally appreciated that practically all the leading mail lines,
                        whether going east or west, are adopting the system for their new
                        tonnage.</p>
                    <p>The Herefordshire is intended to sail on her maiden voyage early in the
                        spring, and will thus be available for the busy homeward pas-</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner Tabor sailed from Malta yesterday morning and is due at
                        Alexandria on Saturday afternoon with passengers, mails, and general
                        cargo.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Belgravia left Malta yesterday morning and is expected to arrive at
                        Alexandria on Saturday evening with passengers and mails.</p>
                    <p>The Russian mail steamer Tsarita will leave Alexandria on Wednesday next at
                        10 a.m. for Piraeus, Smyrna, the Dardanelles, Constantinople, and Odessa,
                        and will connect with the mail steamers of the tame company for Sebastopool
                        and Anatolian, Caucasian, Crimean, and Sea of Azov ports.</p>
                    <p>The M. M. mail steamer Congo, which left Alexandria on Friday, arrived at
                        Marseilles at 6 a.m.. yesterday.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Sailor Prince left Manchester on Tuesday with passengers and general
                        Cargo and is expected to arrive at Alexandria on or about the 21st inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="notesPortSaid">
                    <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                    <head>SHIP ON FIRE IN THE CANAL.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <p>Port Said, Wednesday.</p>
                    <p>From various sources I learn the following details of an accident which
                        occurred between kil. <measure>13</measure> and kil. <measure>34</measure> daring last night. It appears that the
                        S.S. Chatham, having some <measure>70</measure> odd tons of dynamite on board, which entered
                        the Canal here early last evening, was' tying up to permit the passage north
                        of the S.S. Clan Camming. Before the manceuvre was quite completed the Chan
                        collided with her, and in so doing, it is alleged, knocked down a lamp which
                        was suspended in the Chatham's forecastle. The whole of that part of the
                        vessel was soon in flames, and the proximity of such a large quantity of
                        explosives decided; the crew of the ship to at once leave her ; two or three
                        have since arrived here.</p>
                    <p>The chiefs of the Suez Canal Company, with characteristic energy, made a11
                        preparations for what might easily prove to be one of the most dreadful
                        accidents on record The ex-plosion from whatever cause of such an enor mous
                        quantity of dynamite would, of course completely destroy the canal for a
                        great distance on either side, and the removal of debris would have entailed
                        the work of weeks in all likelihood. All the powerful tuge and boats were at
                        once sent down to the scene or the disaster, and both M. Reynold and M.
                        Schmidt, the chiefs at Ismailia end Port Said, respectively, proceeded at a
                        lata hour to the</p>
                    <p>All train service was suspended, and fresh water canal sluices were closed in
                        case an explosion should oocur, and both from north and south ,Canal
                        navigation was stopped. There are now some sixteen ships tied up in the
                        canal and several others at either end awaiting passage.</p>
                    <p>After going carefully into the matter it was finally decided to make a dart
                        at the ship with all the available pumps, with the idea of flooding the hold
                        in which the explosives Were stored,—the fact of the crew having left the
                        ship to herself making it more difficult.</p>
                    <p>The fire Was seen to diminish early this morning, but shortly after took a
                        fresh hold and as I write the full power of the pumps is being employed to
                        flood the ship.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANOTHER BIG TOW.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. Berlin which left here today with three blades of her propellers
                        gone was taken tow of the Altona when she reached the the open sea. She is
                        being towed the whole voyage, but probably will use her one blade.</p>
                    <p>The tow lines consist of heavy wires at each end, which suspend between the
                        two vessel a length of chain cable, this last giving a decided spring to the
                        otherwise practically rigid wires.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ELDORADO THEATRE.</head>
                    <p>The Giuseppe Gray dramatic troupe are giving a saries of performances at the
                        Eldorado Theatre which is proving very successful, and attracts nightly a
                        considerable number of theatre-goers. Amongst the most popular pieces they
                        have given have been Pillole d' Ecole, Il Foranito di Venezia, and Romeo and
                        Juliet.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LIST.</head>
                    <p>Arrivals.</p>
                    <p>Arrived at Port Said by P. and O. S.S. Mol-davia from Singapore on Tuesday :
                        —</p>
                    <p><persName>Capt. Anley</persName>, <persName>Mr. M. Stewart</persName>, <persName>Mr. E.R. Carlos</persName>.</p>
                    <p>Arrived at Port Said from London by P. and O. S.S Arcadia on Tuesday :—</p>
                    <p><persName>Hassan Abdel </persName>, <persName>Mr. H. O. Bennett</persName>, <persName>Mrs. L. Holeman and infant</persName>, <persName>Capt M. J. Hamilton</persName>, <persName>Mr. E Murchland</persName>, <persName>Mr. B. Hornsley </persName> ; from Marseilles :<persName> Mr. Sharpe</persName>, <persName>Mr. B J. H. Ottley</persName>, <persName>Mr. E Teller</persName>, <persName>Mr. Hopkins</persName>, <persName>Mr. Rumbold</persName>, <persName>Col. J. R. P. Lord</persName>, <persName>Mr. and Mrs. Marksad</persName>, <persName>Mrs. W. Chaplin</persName>, <persName>Miss Margerison</persName>, <persName>Mrs. R. P.
                        Gallimore</persName>, <persName>Mr. G. H. Morrison</persName>, <persName>Mr. P. G. Barnard</persName>, <persName>Mr. C. J. Flower</persName>, <persName>Mr. R H
                        Armine</persName>.</p>
                    <p>Arrived at Port Said from Brindisi by P. and O. S.S Isis yesterday :</p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. and
                        Mrs. S. Cookson</persName>.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot <name>Prince Abbas</name> de la Khedivial Mail, parti hier apres-midi pour le Piree, <placeName>Smyrne</placeName>, <persName>Metelin</persName>, Dardanelles et Constantinople avait h bord :</p>
                    <p><persName>M.M. Stephan Cohidan</persName>, <persName>Georges Rini Bey</persName>, <persName>N. Donnison</persName>, <persName>T. Corotaili</persName>, <persName>N. Nanopoulos</persName>, <persName>E Drakos Alecco Bereketti</persName>, <persName>Dr. J. Tammis</persName>, <persName>D. Malaccas</persName>, <persName>C. Cangos</persName>, <persName>Hassan Bey Rassim</persName>, <persName>Bey Rassih</persName>, <persName>A. D. Taxousai</persName>, <persName>Michel Zottos</persName>, <persName>D. Chrissoverghis</persName>, <persName>Stephan Frudachis</persName>, <persName>B. Schual</persName>, <persName>M et Mme E Tirman</persName>, <persName>M. et Mme
                        Jacques S</persName>, <persName>Alguadich et famille</persName>, <persName>M. et Mae Nikitas Petilos et famille</persName>, <persName>Mmes Sultana Agnantiadon</persName>, <persName>M. Oregon</persName>, <persName>M. Young</persName>, <persName>G. Min-ohenson</persName>, ainai que 111
                        passagers de pont.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="shareMarket"><head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our Correspondent)</byline>
                    <dateline>London, September 1.</dateline>
                    <p>The view taken by the Stock Exchange of the signing of the peace treaty
                        between Russia and Japan was naturally one of general satis-faction and
                        shares of all descriptions was immediately started, and a good deal of
                        excitement unsued during which prices steadily rose all around. Of the
                        stocks of the two belligerent nations, Russia seemed to forge ahead mors
                        than the Japs Now, after the first excitement is over, busi-ness seems to be
                        steadying down again, and in some quarters 'disappointment is expressed that
                        the rise did not continue. This, however, does not apply to the Russian and
                        Japanese stocks, the former of which have been bought in Paris, on the
                        belief that the Russian Fours trill before long be quoted at 100 again.
                        Japanese stock closes firm at 105 and the new loan at 95.</p>
                    <p>It is reported to-day that the arrangements are nearly completed in America
                        for the issue of a farther Russian loan, and in view of this, Russian
                        securities will be kept up. If the statement is correct that Japan will not
                        issue a new loan, we shall see a further steady and permanent rise in their
                        securities.</p>
                    <p>The markets close quiet and almost dull the effect of the Cronier failure
                        still being felt. Consols have not kept up to the highest and they close
                        to-day at 90. Other gilt-edged securities remain steady with a firm The
                        firming up of money is no doubt due in a certain measure to the fear that
                        the final financing of the war expenditure in the far East will tend to
                        affect the rates in Paris, Berlin, eta</p>
                    <p>Egyptian stocks and shares are still influenc-ed to some extent by the
                        Cronier fiasco, and even National and Agricultural fallen. We understand
                        that a meeting of the directors of the Societe das Sucreries d'Egypt was
                        held in Paris two days ago, at which the affairs of the Company were fully
                        discussed. No definite news as to what took place has yet transpired, but in
                        as much as the legal advisor of the Company in Egypt was present, it is
                        supposed that measures are being taken to strengthen the future position of
                        the concern. The action that it is said is about to be taken by the several
                        banks and bankers who discounted M. Cronier's bills and those drawn on the
                        Societe Sucraries d'Egypt and the Raffi-nerie Say may have very serious
                        these concerns, as they may be held res-ponsible for the signatures given by
                        their late director. Daira Sanieh stock finished today at and Daira Sugar 4
                        1/2 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian mines remain quiet with a slightly easier tendency, although Nile
                        Valleys have risen to over £l per share since our last, thus justifying our
                        remark that holders wotdBprohíba prohíba do well to average at the low price
                        which they touched last week. Um Rus are easy at 7/8 ; New Egyptians are
                        firm at 1 1/2, and Egyptian mines at 13.9. The recent rise in Nile Valleys
                        has been attributed to a belief that the company has successfully made
                        arrangements for the taking up of the 47,000 reserve shares that Mr.
                        Robinson refused under his option, but the "Financial Times" states to-day
                        that it is informed that no arrangement has yet been concluded as to the
                        placing of the balance the company's unissued shares, bet that shareholders
                        will at once be informed whenever anything definite is arrived at Neither
                        was anything known by the officials to confirm the various rumours in
                        circulation in the market as to favourable developments on the com-pany's
                        concession. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LONDON COMMERCIAL REPORT.</head>
                    <p>Gum Arabic —Of 57 packages 15 sold, Aus-tralian fair frosted part rather
                        Woody at 26' 6d, block at 15s ; remainder withdrawn of bought in, including
                        picked Trieste peas at 8a. Gum Benjamin.—31 oases bought in.</p>
                    <p>Gum Elemi- 29 packages bought in.</p>
                    <p>Gum Edphorbium.—20 bags bought in.</p>
                    <p>Gum Kino.—6 cases' bought in.</p>
                    <p>Gum Myrrh.—Ot 53 packages 5 sold, Aden part blocky at 92s. 6d.</p>
                    <p>Gum Olibanum. — 23 cases sold, without reserve, garblings and sifting at 20s
                        to 20s 6d, blocky garblings at 10s 6d.</p>
                    <p>Gum Saudrac.----- 10 cases, bought in, Mogador pickings at 40s.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB. </head>
                        <p>REGATTA.</p>
                        <p>The following is the result of yesterday's races for the Commodore's cups
                            :--- </p>
                        <p>The wind was moderate from the N.W. and a close finish in both classes
                            was witnessed.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/page/n3/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/page/n4/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-09-07/page/n5/mode/1up"><cb n="1"/><div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
          <head> EXPORT
            MANIFESTS. </head>
          <p>Pour PORT-SAID et ODESSA, par le bateau russe "Reine Olga," parti le 30 août
   :</p>
          <p>Divers, 450 sacs riz, 66 sacs noix de galle, 44 colis palmes, 8 colis divers</p>
          <p>For HULL, by the S.S. "Ymer," sailed on the 30th August :</p>
          <p>Barker &amp; Co., 891 tons cotton seed</p>
          <p>T. Ghirghis, 2,710 tons cotton seed</p>
          <p>For PIRÆUS and CONSTANTINOPLE, by the S.S. "El-Kahira," sailed on the 30th
   August :</p>
          <p>Various, 1,701 bags rice, 80 bags henna, 180 bags sugar, 21 packages skins,
   157 packages sundries</p>
          <p>Pour LIVOURNE, par le bateau ital. "Luigi," parti le 30 août :</p>
          <p>Panelli, 290 tonnes vieux fer</p>
          <p>Pour LA SYRIE, par le bateau fr. "Sénégal," parti le 31 août :</p>
          <p>Divers, 136 colis divers</p>
          <p>Poor' MESSINE et GENES, par le bateau italien "Sirio," parti le 31 août :</p>
          <p>POUR DESTINATIONS DIVERSES</p>
          <p>M. Amin, 20 sacs riz (Tripoli)</p>
          <p>Trabelsi, 8 colis manufactures (Dernah)</p>
          <p>Griva fr., 300 cais. gomme (New-York)</p>
          <p>Mafalda, 16 balles papier</p>
          <p>Divers, 41 colis divers</p>
          <p>POUR GENES</p>
          <p>Bacco, 1 malle chapeaux</p>
          <p>G. Brach, 40 balles gomme</p>
          <p>J. Planta &amp; Co., 184 balles coton</p>
          <p>Peel &amp; Co., 132 „ „</p>
          <p>Choromi, Benachi &amp; Co., 15 „ „</p>
          <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 31 „ „</p>
          <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 123 „ „</p>
          <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 60 „ „</p>
          <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 31 „ „</p>
          <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 120 „ „</p>
          <p>696 balles coton</p>
          <p>Pour BRINDISI et VENISE, par le batesa italien "Bosforo," parti le 1er
   septembre :</p>
          <p>POUR DESTINATIONS DIVERSES</p>
          <p>Divers, 245 tūts vidas. 20 colis divers</p>
          <p>J. Soschino, 211 cais. effets de théâtre (Bari)</p>
          <p>POUR VENISE</p>
          <p>L. Cerasso, 20 fardes gomme</p>
          <p>Gallois, 3 cais. photograpbies</p>
          <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 20 balles coton</p>
          <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 35 „ „</p>
          <p>J. Planta &amp; Co., 100 „ „</p>
          <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 75 „ „</p>
          <p>280 balles coton</p>
          <p>Pour CANDIB, par le bateau grec "Athènes," parti le 1er septembre : -</p>
          <p>Divers, 1,430 sacs rir, 75 Baca latron, 200 barils vides, 11 colis peaux,
   837 colis divers</p>
          <p>For SYRIA, by the S.S. "Minieh," sailed on the 2nd September :</p>
          <p>Various, 493 bags rice, 7 cases cigarettes, 20 packages vegetables, 29
   packages skins, 1,084 packages sundries</p>
        </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
