<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Brandon Barrett</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-25"> September 25, 2016 </date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-11"> February 11, 1905 </date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239 ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 11, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
              <div type="item">
<head>THE RUSSIAN STRIKES</head>
<head>TROOPS FIRE ON WORKERS</head>
<head>FRESH DISORDERS FEARED</head>
<p>Warsaw, February 10
One thousand, five hundred strikers of
Sosnowice, seeing the catherine works illuminated,
thought that work was proceeding.
They started towards the building, when the
soldiers fired from the windows, hitting many
of the strikers.  (Reuter.)</p>
<p>St. Petersburg, February 10
The men of the putiloff and franco russian
works here have started an eight hours day on
their own account.  As the employers have
refused to countenance the movement, the
strike was renewed today, 12,000 men being
out.  The troops are in readiness to prevent 
the strike spreading.
Five thousand strikers have paraded here
today.  They induced four other factories to
join them, but dispersed quietly on encountering
the troops.
At the instance of the governors, the manufacturers
of warsaw and the mine owners at sosnowice are
conferring with a view to making concessions.  (Reuter.)</p>
<p>Warsaw, February 10
There was a fresh collision at sosnowice last
night with the troops.  The latter fired on the
moh as the strikers were extinguishing the
smelting furnace.  One hundred persons were
killed or wounded.  (Reuter.)</p>
<p>St. Petersburg, February 10
A strike has been declared in the Putiloff
works.  Fresh disorders are feared.  (Havas.)</p>                  
</div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MANCHERIA</head>
                    <head>JAPANESE ATTACK REPULSED</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, February 10
                    General Kuropatkin repulsed an attack on
                    his left flank on the 9th inst.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL ELECTION PROSPECTS</head>   
                    <head>LIBERALS GETTING READY</head>
                    <p>London, February 10
                    Mr. Herbert Gladstone, the chief liberal
                    whip, was warned the liveral agents to
                    complete immediately all arrangements for a
                    general election.  He expects the dissolution
                    may take place at any moment after the opening
                    of parliament on the 14th inst. (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A LIBERAL MANIFESTO</head>
                    <head>ISSUED BY LORD SPENCER</head>
                    <p>London, February 10
                    Lord Spencer has issued a manifesto in the 
                    name of the liveral leaders.  He dwells upon
                    the feed, incensing, and education questions.
                    He has not mention the japanese aliance but
                    approves of teh abomination treaties.  He 
                    advocates a fully representative and responsible
                    government for the transvaul and orange
                    river colony.  The imperial government must
                    promote the real interest of teh south aftican
                    colonies without continuing beyond the obligations
                    of existing contracts, any system of trade.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHURCH AND STATE IN FRANCE</head>
                    <head>SEPERATION TO BE VOTED.</head>
                    <p>The chamber of deputies has decided to 
                    vote the seperation of the churches from the 
                    state after voting the budget and the military
                    law.  (Havas.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>H.M.S. PYLADES AGROUND</head>
                    <p>Sidney, February 10
                    H.M.S. pylades is aground on the peel 
                    reef but is not seriously damaged.  (Reuter.)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The legislative council met at cairo 
                    today.</p>
                    <p>The plague- yesterdays bulletin records
                    a recovery at suez.</p>
                    <p>Quarantin restrictions on arrivals in egyptian
                    ports from the porbandar and yodia (india)
                    have been removed.</p>
                    <p>Council of ministers- The next meeting 
                    of the council of ministers will probably take
                    place on the 20th inst.</p>
                    <p>The steam yacht argonaut arrived at
                    alexandria from jaffa yesterday with a large
                    number of tourists, who proceeded to cairo.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Salt and Soda company- The
                    monthly retrun of sales of salt during january
                    shows a total of L.E. 23,301.698, as against
                    L.E. 24,806.081 in January 1903.</p>
                    <p>Very severe weather is reported between
                    crete and alexandria.  The S.S. Prince 
                    Abbas, which arrived this morning from the 
                    constantinople, bore traces of having weathered
                    a storm.</p>
                    <p>The Freres Case- The court of appeal at 
                    aix on thursday confirmed in its entirety the
                    judgement of teh french consular court given
                    against M.L. Yayou for livel against the
                    christian brothers.</p>
                    <p>The cairo tradesmens ball is to be given 
                    on the 17th inst. at the verdi theatre.  This is 
                    the second annual ball of this character, and
                    it should become a regular yearly fixtrue.  The 
                    ball was a great success last year.</p>
                    <p>Suez canal- 16 vessels passed through the 
                        canal on the 8th inst., of which 9 were
                    british, 1 dutch, 3 german, 1 austrian, 2 italian.
                    the days receipts were frs. 494,248.62,
                    making the total since 1st inst. frs. 3,057,940.69</p>
                    <p>The pirates of penzance- we learn
                    that the performance in cairo of gilbert and
                    sullivans opera has been antedated to the
                    17th inst. as H.R.H. the Duke of Connaught
                    has sighted his intention of honoring the 
                    performance with his presence</p>
                    <p>White Nile Exploration- one of the chief
                    contributions to the geographical journal
                    vol XXIV, containing the proceedings of
                    the royal geographical society during the
                    past half year, is an interesting article by
                    captain liddell on his exploration of the
                    white nile.</p>
                    <p>The Inniskilling Fusiliers held their 
                    regimental sports at mena house yesterday.  Some
                    of teh events were held before and some after
                    lunch.  In spite of the cold weather, the sports
                    went off well, there being a very large number of events.
                    About 150 to 200 guests had been invited by officers.</p>
                    <p>The electrification of teh ramleh railway
                    has inspired imitators in cairo, and it is
                    stated that the cairo tramway company is
                    negotiating with the failway administration
                    for an electric tram service on the matarich.
                    The company proposes to run one hundred and
                    sixty trams per day.</p>
                    <p>Coal imports- from 1st january to 9th inst.
                    the quantity of coal imported was 50,662 tons.
                    During the corresponding period of last year 76,848
                    tons, welsh districts
                    33,661, scotch districts 5,854, yorkshire 4,687,
                    and other districts 627 tons.</p>
                    <p>Abbas helmy theatre- This evening, 
                    Signora Bedincioni will appear in Massents 
                    Manon.  Tomorrow a matinee performance of 
                    La boheme will be given, and in the evening
                    Luena di lammermoor, with signora svicher.
                    Carmen is to be produced on monday, when 
                    Signora bellincioni will again appear.</p>
                    <p>Cheap houses at alexandria- a meeting 
                    of capitalists interested in the question of cheap houses
                    at alexandria for the working classes,
                    will be held shortly, when the statutes
                    of the societa anonima di case economiche
                    will be considered.  If the statutes are approved
                    the company will be difinitely formed.</p>
                    <p>H.M. transport soudan (capt S. de B. lockyer) reached 
                    port said on thursday night, outward bound from 
                    southampton and entered the canal yesterday morning
                    en route for bombay.  The troops on board numbered
                    1,313 of all ranks.  The officer commanding
                    is Lt. Col.M.G. Jackson, 1st devonshire
                    regiment.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial geographical society.  Dr. L de
                    Castro, who is the doctor attached to the 
                    italian legislation in abyssinia, will read a paper
                    before the khedivial geographical society,
                    entitled le patriarchisme et le feudalisme en
                    abyssinie, on monday.  Dr. de castro has spent
                    three years in Meneliks country, and his paper should 
                    be of great interest.</p>
                    <p>Alhambra theatre- a ball will be given
                    at this theatre this evening and tomorrow
                    evening, after the usual variety performance, 
                    which is still as attractive as ever.  A new ballet
                    is to be produced at a matinee performance tomorrow.  
                    Four performances are shortly to be given by the old chansonniers 
                    of the famous chat noir.  The company which is being brought here 
                    by M.C. Baret, has the celebrated jules moy at its head.</p>
                    <p>Helouan sporting club- a very successful
                    performance was given yesterday afternoon 
                    by the boys bands of tourah prison, which is 
                    composed of the sons of negro warders.  The boys, 
                    who were very smartly uniformed in blue 
                    and white, played from 3 to 5pm in the
                    enclosure of teh Helouan sporting club, next
                    to the tewfik palace hotel, and also gave a 
                    display of physical drill, which was greatly 
                    appreciated.</p>
                    <p>Still they come- Next week large numbers of tourists
                    are due at alexandria on the 13th inst. by the north german 
                    lloyds S.S. Hohenzoilern and on the 15th inst. by the 
                    white star liner romantic.  Three hundred and fifty
                    tourists are due here on the 27th inst. by the
                    hamburg american S.S. Moltke.  The passengers
                    will remain in egypt for 6.5 or 12.5 days,
                    as they may desire.  The moltke leaves
                    alexandria on march 5 for beyrout and
                    returns here on march 11, leaving shortly
                    after for Jaffa.</p>
                    <p>Retail trade combination- We have recieved a copy of 
                    the publication, entitled the retail merchants Journal
                    of canada, which seems to ba a first rate medium for
                    bringing together manufacturer and retailer.
                    Like our american cousins, canadian traders
                    have an excellent idea of looking after the 
                    main chance, and are well aware of the advantages
                    of combination for the advancement of
                    their mercantile interests.  The secretary and
                    editor is E.M. Trowern, 21, Richmond street, west
                    toronto, and the subscription $2 per annum.</p>
                    <p>Khedivial club-the annual general meeting
                    of the khedivial club, alexandria, was 
                    held this week, when the following gentlemen
                    were elected as officers of the club for the
                    current year: president, robert J. Moss;
                    vice presidents, Mr. Adv. R. Giro and hassan
                    pahsa mohsen; auditor, mr a bimsenstein;
                    members, messrs. J. R. Aghion, H.R.C. blagden,
                    av. clemente castro, p. cavafay, a.
                    cesana, av. m. colucci, e. friedheim, h.
                    b. greathead, f.c. haseiden, lt. col. lucas,
                    c.b.r.a.m.c., w.b. rees, j.r. reeves, av.
                    m. romano, dr. m.a. ruffer, a. sorokine, em.
                    stross, and av. alfred tilche.  The following 
                    members of the outgoing house committee
                    were re elected unanimously: mr adv r giro,
                    mr p cavaty, hassan pahsa mohsen,
                    mr. a cesana, and mr a sorokine.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lord and lady cromer and lady beatrice
                    thynne are expected to arrive at assouan on 
                    tuesday.</p>
                    <p>the following passengers left cairo yesterday
                    by the P.S. Hatasoo for the nile trip:
                    General and Mrs. Lance, Mr. Gilbert Elliot,
                    Rev. S. and Mrs. Campbell, Mr. aud Mrs. A.
                    Baillierc, Capt. and Mrs. Ueopcke, Mr. Josel
                    Hicbaum, Lt. aud Mrs. von Meyer iu Kuouow,
                    .Mr. J. Buckley Jonas, Mr. E. Hughes Jones,
                    Mr. E. C. Morris, Mr. Otto Kohou, Miss L. D.
                    Shephard, Miss Sara Nicholson, Mrs. Hogg,
                    .\IiM .v. G. Morris, Mr. J. P. Brady, Mr. W. J.
                    Biaily, Judge lloyle, Mr. Geo. Hoyle, Mr. S. H.
                    buerley, Mr. E. Foster Bruok, Mrs. Brierley,
                    Miss A. W. Shaw, Admiral aud Miss Dale,
                    Mis. Uundiu, Mr. Heibert Wallis, Miss A. B.
                    Hyde, Mias M. E. Crouse, Mr. E. Sas.</p>
                    <p>No official statement has yet been made 
                        confirming the rumour that mr. russell is to be
                        appointed director of the treasury.</p>
                    <p>The marriage arranged between mr. charles
                    o.borman and eumeline beatrice hewgill,
                    youngest daughter of mr. John hewgill, 
                    mex, will take place at st. marks church on
                    tuesday next, 14th inst.</p>
                    <p>Amongst the latest arrivals at the Eastern
                        Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. J. A.
                        Kuutli, Capt. P. W. North, Mrs. B. H. Jossen,
                        Mr. B. Mansfield, Mr. and Mrs. B. Firth, Mr.
                        Alex. Firth, Miss Wrightiuan, Mr. E Edwards,
                        Alj. and Mrs. R. Walker, Mr. and Mrs. Craw-
                        shay, Mr. P. R. Box well, Mr. E. L. Botham,
                        Mr. F. G. Davidson, Dr. W. M. Aden, Mr.
                        and Mrs. O. B. Butler, Mr. and Mrs. Wykoff,
                        Ur. and Mrs. Dunlop, Mr. and Mrs. MacNutt,
                        Mrs. J. Grundy, Mrs. M. Lucas, and Kauial
                        Bey.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY</head>
                    <head>RESIGNATION OF MR. ALDERSON</head>
                    <p>Mr. Geo. B. Alderson has resigned his position
                    on the alexandria municipality, and we have
                    been requested by him to publish the following
                    copy of a communication addressed by him today
                    to mr. chataway-
                    To the administrator of alexandria municipality.
                    Dear sir- I have now been one year a member of 
                    your honorable assembly and feel that, not having 
                    been invited to sit on the delegation, i am useless
                    for the public good, and beg to offer you my 
                    resignation. -yours obediently, Geo B Alderson
                    Bulkeley, February 11th.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PORT SAID COLLISION</head>
                    <head>FULLER DETAILS</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.)
                        Port Said, Friday.
                        As already reported, a serious collision
                        occurred in Port Said harbour on Thursday
                        afternoon between the Harrison liner, "Crafts-
                        man," of Liverpool, a vessel of some 8,000
                        tons, and the Norwegian collier, "Congal,” of
                        Sandefjord, bound for Hong Kong with coal.
                        The "Congal,” ready to enter the Canal, was
                        moored fore-and-aft at her berth, but having
                        no breast line out aft,jhad drifted slightly into
                        tbe fairway. Tbe “Craftsman," from the Canal,
                        in proceeding to her allotted berth, abreast of
                        the Suez Canal Company's offices—which was
                        directly eastern of that of the "Congal,"—passed
                        too near, with the result that a side collision
                        was inevitable, the smaller vessel's msin
                        rigging being touched by the high counter of
                        the "Craftsman,” and the stanchions on the
                        poop bent. The main damage, however, was
                        caused by the propeller blades (three of which
                        are reported to be broken) ripping the plates on
                        the port side of tho “Cougal" below the water
                        line, and causing the vessel to begin to settle
                        down.
                        Tbe Canal authorities, realizing the situa-
                        tion, at once sent tugs to tow the "Congal”
                        in-shore if possible, but the operations were
                        only half completed when she sank at the stem,
                        and the water rushing in, one bulkhead after
                        another gave way till the whole hull was
                        submerged. She now lies in the Bassin Cherif
                        with bridge and boats amidships, a small part
                        of the forecastle deck, and the mast and
                        funnel visible. The crow were able to save most
                        of their effects.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR W. WILLCOCKS EXPEDITION</head>
                    <p>As we announced a few days ago, Sir William
                         Willcocks has returned to Cairo from his
                        important expedition to the Euphrates and the
                        Tigris. He has kindly given us the following 
                        statement of the conclusions he has arrived
                        at:
                        The Tigris and Euphrates have apparently 
                        enough water to allow of the perennial irriga-
                        tion of 5 million acres and of keeping naviga-
                        tion open to the sea. The hydraulic problems
                        are not so hard as those on the Nile ; but
                        comprehensive projects must be taken up to 
                        secure the canals against obliteration by silt,
                        which has often ruined Babylonia. I saw the 
                        Tigris in places only 140 feet wide and 6 feet 
                        deep,mid the Euphrates 40 feet wide and 3 feet
                        deep, though I measured the water entering
                        Babylonia and found it 50,000 cubic feet per
                        second for tho Tigris, and 25,000 cubic feet per
                        second for tho Euphrates. All the existing 
                        canals in the Bagdad Pasbalio were ditcharg-
                        ing 500 cubic feet per second between them. 
                        The first work needed would be an irrigation 
                        and navigation canal some 150 foot wide, join-
                        ing the Tigris and Euphrates at Bagdad. This
                        would be easy, as th3 Euphrates is about 15
                        feet higher than the Tigris.
                        The Hindia Barrage on the Euphrates has 
                        so far been a failure, because they have made 
                        the same mistake as was made on the Cairo 
                        Barrage. I tried to persuade tho engineer (a 
                        Son of Mougel Bey, who built the Cairo Bar- 
                        race) to act as I acted in Egypt, but he con- 
                        sidered the risk too great.	
                        Some 100 specimens of soils and building 
                        materials and water have been collected by me.
                        When the agricultural experts and chemists 
                        have sent in their reports I shall be in a posi- 
                        tion to frame estimates.	</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRICE OF MEAT</head>
                    <p>As some misapprehension appears to prevail 
                        in regard to tbe subject of the price of meat e
                        and the cold storage system, we may state that 
                        in spite of the extra freight for meat landed 
                        at Port Said (it actually costs less to send 
                        frozen meat from Australia to London than 
                        from Australia to Port Said) and for railway car-
                        riage by fast trains, which is absolutely 
                        necessary unless the meat is to deteriorate,
                        also for duties, the Nile Cold Storage Com-
                        pany’s prices average only 1d. per lb. more
                        than those given in the London Army and
                        Navy Stores catalogue for 1904. And this
                        though the charges mentioned make the
                        cost of transport nearly 1.5d. per lb. higher,
                        the additional freight charge coming to about
                        a halfpenny per lb. more, while railway
                        charges add an extra .5d. in the lb. and
                        Customs about .3d. As for the retail prices of
                        the butchers in Cairo, they average 12% dearer
                        than those quoted by the Nile Cold Storage
                        Company. Here is an example—for lamb
                        (18 months old as a rule) four Cairo retailers
                        charge P.T. 14, 14, 13, and 11 per oke respect-
                        ively, while the company charges for genuine
                        lamb P.T. 12 for legs or loins, and P.T. 11 for
                        other parts. In beef, motton, and hams the
                        difference is even more marked.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The moss liner tabor sailed from liverpool
                    yesterday afternoon and is due here about
                    the 24th inst., with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL LEVEE</head>
                    <head>ORDER OF RECEPTION</head>
                    <p>On the occasion of the feast of kourban
                    beyram, the khedive will hold a reception at
                    abdeed palace on tuesday next, when visitors
                    will be recieved in the following order-
                    At 8 a.m. the ulema; the general
                    assembly and legislative council; the governor
                    of cairo and the moudir of ghizeh, the officers
                    of the army and navy, from the rank of 
                    bimbashi upwards.
                    At 8.30 a.m. the officials of the following 
                    administrations: council of ministers, ministry 
                    of the interior, board of health, prisons
                    inspectorate, slave trade repression department, 
                    cairo gouvernorat, Ghizeh mondirieh,
                    finance ministry, postal administration, the
                    coast guards, public debt commission, daira
                    sanieh, state domains administration, administration
                    of railways, telegraphs and the
                    port of alexandria, public works ministry,
                    ministry of justice, ministry of public instruction,
                    ministry of war, foreign office, wakfs administration.
                    At 9 a.m. the princess of the khedivial family;
                    the presidnet of the council of ministers
                    and the ministers; the financial adviser, 
                    the judicial adviser, and the adviser
                    at the ministry of the interior and of public
                    works; the under secretaries of state.
                    At 9.30 a.m. the former presidents of the 
                    council of ministers, the former ministers,
                    presidents of the legislative council, sirdars,
                    grand masters of ceremonies, heads of the khedivial 
                    cabinet, chief aides de camp, 
                    directors of the khedivial khassa, directors
                    general of wakfs, under secretaries of state;
                    directors general of the daira sanieh, 
                    administratiors of the state domains and 
                    administrators of the railways, telegraphs, and
                    port of alexandria; unofficial military and
                    civil personages having the rank of lewa or
                    oula sinf sani and upwards the officers of the army
                    and navy unattached and on the 
                    retired list having the rank of kaimakam or
                    miralai; the unofficial civil beys, having the 
                    rank of moutemaiz or sanieh and upwards.
                    At 10 am the diplomatic and consular corps.
                    At 10.15 am the directors commissioners 
                    of the public debt commission; the director 
                    general and the controllers of the daira
                    sanieh; the state domains administrators; 
                    the administrators of railways, telegraphs, 
                    and the port of alexandria.
                    At 10.45 am the field officers of the army 
                    of occupation; the clergy; the mixed magistracy
                    ; the native magistracy.
                    At 11.15 am the khedivial counsellors;
                    native notables; european notables; the 
                    officials of the military and civil housholds
                    of H.H. the khedive and those of the khedivial 
                    khassa.
                    The khediviah will also hold a reception on
                    tuesday at abdeen palace.  The princesses of
                    the khedivial family and native ladies will be
                    recieved from 3 to 3.30 pm, european ladies
                    from 3.40 to 4.40 pm and the wives of members
                    of the diplomatic corps at 4.45 pm</p>
                    <p>The khedive is leaving montazah for
                       cairo this afternoon.
                    The motor car which his highness bought
                    during his recent visit to paris has arrived
                    from europe this week.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT</head>
                    <p>Sir william garstin, mr. webb, and mr. clowes
                    left cairo last night for assouan, where
                    they will meet the duke and dechess of
                    connaught on the occasion of their royal
                    highness's visit to the assouan reservoir.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZIZINIA THEATRE</head>
                    <p>Last night’s performance at the Zizinia 
                        Theatre in aid of the El Orwa El-Woska 
                        benevolent society was a brilliant success. H.H.
                        the Khedive arrived punctually at 9 p.m. and
                        was received by .H. E. the Governor and the 
                        members of the committee of the society. His 
                        Highness occupied Baron de Monasoe’s box in
                        company with the Governor, Baron Alfred de
                        Menasce, and several members of tho committee. 
                        The appearance of the theatre was magnificent, I
                        the whole of fashionable Alexandria being pre-
                        sent,and the aspect was further enlivened by the 
                        band of the society in their brilliant and becom-
                        ing uniforms. The Khedive on several occasions 
                        applauded the playing of the young bandsmen. 
                        During the intervals his Highness received 
                        many European and native notabilities and 
                        also all the French comedy artists, who 
                        kindly lent their services in aid of the society’s 
                        funds. The play, Le monde ou ion sennui, 
                        a sparkling comedy by Pailleron, was very 
                        ably rendered and is certainly one of the best ,
                        performances of the company this season. Mme.
                        Pamy, l’atry, Lily and M1 le.Georgo to Loyer were 
                        particularly good. The latter, in the amusing ,
                        part of Suzanne de Villiers, was much ap
                        preciated, and was applauded more than once 
                        by H.H. the Khedive. Messrs. Cooper and ,
                        Laurent also deserve special mention.
                        The net receipts amount to about £300, ,
                        and we sincerely hope that it will help to
                        enhance the good this sodety is doing .in
                        the education and moral improvement of the
                        poorer classes of native boys. At present more
                        than 2,000 boys receive instruction at its
                        hands.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ARMY AND NAVY</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent)
                        London, February 8.
                        The appointment of P. M. 0. in Egypt will
                        be filled by the posting of Surgeon-Lieutenant
                        Colonel James Magill, C. B., senior medical
                        officer of the Coldstream Guards. lieutenant
                        Colonel Magill entered the medical depart-
                        ment in 1885, and reached his present rank
                        in May, 1896. He is no stranger in Egypt, for
                        he accompanied the Guards Camel Corps in
                        the Nile Expedition 1884-85 and was severely
                        wounded in the fierce action at Abou Klea,
                        near where Colonel Fred Burnaby fell fighting.
                        He was mentioned in despatches, received the
                        medal with two clasps and bronze star. He
                        was with the Coldstreams in tee Boer War,
                        and was present at the actions of Belmont,
                        Easlin, Modder River, Magersfontein, Poplar
                        Grove, Driefontein, Vet River, Zand River,
                        Johannesburg, Pretoria, Diamond Hill, Belfast,
                        and Komati Poort, and the succeeding cam-
                        paign. For his services he was mentioned in
                        despatches, awarded the C. B., medal with six
                        clasps, and King’s medal with two clasps.</p>
                    <p>The army council, despite much hostile
                        criticism, has determined to withdraw the 56th
                        battery R.F.A. and No. 4 mountain battery 
                        from egypt.  The field battery will return home
                        in march.  The army council is pushing 
                        retrenchment to the very verge of safety.</p>
                    <p>We have the authority of Mr. Arnold-
                        Forster for stating that 120 of the new 18.5
                        pounder field guns—just sofficient to arm 20.
                        batteries—are now ready and that 500 more
                        will be delivered in 1906. That is a great
                        hiatus. If 120 guns can be produced for India
                        in a few weeks, why wait newly two years for
                        the balance? The haste in providing guns for
                        India is based on Mr. Balfour's now historic
                        statement that "the problem of the British
                        Army is the problem of tee defence of
                        Afghanistan."</p>
                    <p>The battleship “Illustrious" has arrived at
                        Portsmouth to have one of her 12-inch bar-
                        bette guns replaced by a new one.</p>
                    <p>One of the objections to the late distribu-
                        tion of the fleet was that in a great number of
                        foreign countries the tremendous naval power
                        of Great Britain was not fully enough realised.
                        On many shores a small cruiser or obsolete
                        gunboat represented —or rather misrepresented
                        —the premier naval power. That will now be
                        all changed. The second cruiser squadron, -
                        which consists of eight powerful 24-knot ar-
                        moured cruisers under the command of Rear-
                        Admiral Prince Louie of Battenberg—who has
                        just hoisted his flag on the swiftest cruiser
                        afloat, the “Drake”—has been detailed for a
                        seven months’ cruise along tbe coast line of
                        North and South America. Every port of
                        importance will be visited, and the naval might
                        of the Empire practically demonstrated. The
                        selection of the “Drake” as flagship was a
                        happy one, perpetuating as it does the name
                        of that grim old sea dog who was the terror of
                        our enemies on the "Spanish main."</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROYAL MALTA ARTILLERY</head>
                    <p>The news that the company at Alexaxdria
                        and the detachment at Cairo of the Royal
                        Malta Artillery are leaving Egypt for their
                        native isle has been received with much
                        regret, as during the five years the
                        R.M. A. have been in Egypt they have
                        made themselves very popular. They came
                        here in January, 1900, two companies having
                        been raised in Malta for service abroad, and
                        one was sent to Egypt.
                        Nothing is known as to the future of the
                        company now in Egypt, and it is doubtful
                        whether they are to be stationed permanently
                        in Malta, or to be posted to some foreign
                        station. Since the R. M. A. came to Egypt
                        they have been under tbe command of Major
                        Balbi. The troops are leaving on the 4th
                        proxo. by the “Di wara.”</p></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN HOTELS LIMITED</head>
                    <p>A great many people appear to be quite
                        unaware of the position of the Egyptian Hotels,
                        imited, which company owns the Ghezireh
                        Palace and Shepheard’s Hotel. We are
                        authorised to state that this company, as
                        it present constituted, is an English company
                        and is registered under the Companies Acts.
                        its board is composed as follows. Chairman :
                        Lord Claude Hamilton, the Chairman of the
                        Treat Eastern Railway Company ; members of
                        die board: Sir Robert Herbert, Mr. Emmanuel
                        J. Zervudacchi, Mr. E. A. Harrison (general
                        manager of Messrs. Thos. Cook and 800, Limit-
                        ed), and Mr. J. J. Hug, of Cairo. The London
                        offices of the company are at 3, Lothbury, EC.
                        Up to last spring the Compagnie Interna-
                        tionale des' Grands Hotels was the largest
                        shareholder in the Egyptian Hotels Company.
                        The former company was bought out entirely
                        by .Mr. Charles Baehler, who is backed by a
                        powerful financial syndicate. He therefore is
                        now in control of the destinies of the company,
                        and with the assistance of his board, some of
                        whose members have great local experience, 
                        he should make the company, under its new
                        conditions, even more successful than it was
                        before.
                       Owing to the rise in the price of land,
                        especially for building purposes in the neigh-
                        bourhood of Cairo, the property belonging to
                        this company at Ghezireh has become a very
                        valuable asset, The company intend to develop
                        the Ghezireh estate into one of the finest
                        residential quarters of Cairo. Already thirty-
                        two villas have been built and some very high
                        offers have been recently made for suites at
                        Ghezireh.
                       The fashionable neighbourhood of this estate,
                        and its proximity to the Ghezireh Palace
                        Hotel, with its beautiful park and the Khedi-
                        vial Spotting Club, already combine to make
                        It a much aought after spot for residences.</p>
               </div> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
