<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Brooklyn Vincent--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- 2016-10-17 --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- 1905-10-17 --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> 
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, OCTOBER 17 1905</head>
<div type = "item"> 
    <head>FRANCE AND ENGLAND.</head>
<head>ENGLAND PREPARED TO FIGHT.</head>
<head>NOTIFICATION TO GERMANY</head>
<p>Paris, October 16.</p>
<p>The "Echo De Paris" learns from Berlin
from a semi-official source that Lord Lansdowne
informed Germany in June, that though no
Anglo-French alliance had been concluded or
promised, yet Great Britain would take part
with France, if war should break out through
Germany's fault	(Reuter)</p>
    
<p>Cologne October 16.</p>
<p>The "Koelnische Zeitung" says that Ger-
many asked no explanation either of France or
England regarding tho recent revelations (H.)</p>
</div>
         
                <div type = "item">        
<p>THE "ENTENTE MUNICIPALE."</p>
<head>FRENCH COUNCILLORS GO TO LONDON</head>
<p>Paris, October 16.</p>
<p>60 members oF the Municipality have start-
ed for their visit to London, there there will
be all sorts of festivities. They will be received
by the King to-morrow.	(Reuter) </p>

<p>Paris, October 16.</p>
<p>Sixty Municipal councillors have left on a
visit to London.(Havas)</p> </div>
                    
    
                <div type = "item">              
<head>THE PROPITIATION OF,FINLAND. </head>
<head>RUSSIAN TROOPS REPATRIATED.'</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, October 16.</p>
<p>The Russian troops in Finland are being
sent back to Russia. This is considered as
indicating a reversion to the policy of the
propitiation of Finland.	(Reuter)</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head>SITUATION IN THE CAUCASUS </head>
<head>MOBILISATION OF RESERVES. </head>
<p>St. Petersburg, October 16. </p>
<p>The reserves throughout the Caucasus are
being mobilised owing to the continued cri-
tical situation.	(Reuter) </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head>EVACUATION OF MANCHURIA.</head>
<head>COMPLETED IN SIX MONTHS.</head>
<p>Tokio. October 16.</p>
<p>Japan is preparing to begin the evacuation
of Manchuria at once It is expected that it
will be completed in six months.	(Reuter) </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> HARON KOMURA'S HOMECOMING </head>
<head> MIKADO'S MARKS OF FAVOR. </head>
<p> Tokio, October 16. </p>
<p>Baron Komura has returned and has been
received with special marks of favor by the
Emperor, who expressed his pleasure at the
conclusion of a satisfactory peace.	(Renter)</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head>MARRIED AND-DISGRACED.</head>
<head>GRAND DUKE CYRILS FATE-</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, October 16. </p>
<p>The Grand Duke Cyril has been dismissed
from the Army, deprived of all honors, and
excluded from Russia, for marrying the divorc-
ed Grand Duchess of Hesse.	(Reuter)</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> AMERICAN SHIP SEIZED BY JAPS. </head>
<p> Tokio, October 16. </p>
<p> Tho Japanese have seized the American
steamer Centennial in Soya Strait - (Reuter) </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> PRINCE FERDINAND IN PARIS. </head>
<p> Paris, October 16. </p>
<p>Tho Prince of Bulgaria has arrived here on
an official visit.	(Havas) </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> Calendar of Coming Events.</head>
<head>ALEXANDRIA. </head>
 <p>October.Tues. 17 </p>
<p>Mex. Prince’s Restaurant dee Bains
Roumanian orchestra, every after
noon. Sundays, morning.
0ld Bourse Palace Bar. Orchestra
nightly. 8 p.m.
Windsor Hotel. Orchestra
11.30 pm. everyday.
New Masonic Hall. Albert Edward
Lodge, No. 707, Meeting. 
8 pm.
Zinnia Theatre. Selvin. in Otells.
9 p.m
Alhambra. Italian company in Le
Pillole d Ercole ,9.15 p.m.
Crown Casino. Ibrabimieh. 9.30 p.m. </p>

<p>Sat 21 Tues. 24</p>
<p>A.S.C. October Skye Meeting.
Raa-el-Tin I alace. Khedive’s Fare-
well Reception. 9 a.m.
CAIRO.</p>
                    
<p> October Tues 17 </p> 
<p>Esbekieh Theatre. French Operetta
Company. 9.15 p.m.
Theatre dee Nouveautes. 9.30 p.m. 
Alcazar Parisien. 9.80 p.m. </p>
<p> Thurs. 26 </p>
<p>Khedivial Opera House. Cairo
Musical and Dramatic Society's
Concert in aid of Calabrian Victims,
under Patronage of H.H. the
Khedive.</p>
                </div>


                <div type = "item">
<head> LOCAL AND GENERAL' </head>
<p>Suez Canal—155 vessels passed through
the Canal from the 6th to the 13th inst., the
dues from which amounted to frs. 4,100,485.74. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>The Brindisi Mail will be leaving Port
Said every Sunday, instead of Monday, for
the next six months or so.</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>A.C.C.—The Squash court will be closed
from to-day to allow of painting walls,
stretching wire-netting, etc. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p> Zizinia Theatre — Cavalreto Salvini make
his first appearance at the Zizinia this evening
in Shakespeare's tragedy Othello. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Militarv Hospital. Cairo.—Lieut.Col. O
Todd, R.A.M C., having returned from leave of
absence has resumed charge of the Military
Hospital, Cairo.</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Stray Dogs.— Stray and ownerless dogs
found in the Waijy district of Cairo during
tho night of Wednesday will be poisoned by
the police. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Hedjaz Railway. — On Sunday last, in
honor of the 65th birthday of H.I.M the
Sultan, the Deraa-Haifa branch of the above
railway was formally opened to traffic. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Khkdivial Reception.— On tho occasion
of his departure from. Alexandria for Cairo,
his Highness will hold a reception at Rasel Tin
Palace on Tuesday, 24th inst., commencing at
9 a.m. </p> </div>
                
                <div type = "item">               
<p> Cairo Scientific Society. — A meeting of
tho society will take place at the School of
Medicine, Cairo, on Saturday, 21st inst, at
4.15 p.m. Mr. A. Lucas will read a paper on
“The Blackened Rocks of the Nile Cataract,"
and Mr. P. S. Barlow a "Note on tin Construc-
tion of Osmotic Cells.” </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p> School of Medicine.—On Sunday the
result of the examination of the students of
the third and fourth years was made public.
Sixteen competitors obtained their diploma,
and twenty students of the third year were
entitled to enter upon the fourth years come. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Fire at Menshieh. Fire broke out at
about 11 p.m. yesterday in the shop of an
Italian grocer in the Menshieh. Tho Fire
Brigade arrived promptly with the engine and
pumps, and after an hour's labour the tire
was extinguished. The damage has not yet
been estimated. </p> </div>
                
                <div type = "item">               
<p>San Stefano Casino. ,-The Bracsle orehos-
tra will continue giving the usual concerts
until Sunday next, the 22nd inst. We are
informed that on Saturday next, at 9.30 p.m.,
the celebrated telepathic "phenomenon,"Count
E. Bellini, will give a final seance of auto-
suggestion, which promises to be very interest-
ing. Admission will be P.T.5, and for this
occasion the season tickets will be suspended. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Emigration .from Syria —Owing to scarcity
of work in Syria, the natives of the country
are emigrating in large numbers. Last week,
abou 1,000 emigrants embarked on the Mea-
sageries steamer for America. Three of these,
on their arrival at Alexandria, had a dispute,
in the coarse of which one of them, named
Abdallah, was seriously injured and had to be
taken to hospital. The other two were arrested.  </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Transports. -There are now three trans-
ports in the Canal—the Plassy and Africa,
outward bound, and the Assaye, homeward
Details for embarkation in the transport Aessye
to-day left Cairo by the 6.15 p.m. train yes-
terday. Those from Alexandria left by the 3.40
p.m. train yesterday, changing at Benba and
joining the train which leaves that station at
7.1 p.m </p> </div>
                
                <div type = "item">                
<p> Field Firino in Cairo. — The British
Mounted Infantry will carry out field firing
daily (Sunday, 22nd inst, excepted), from
Monday, 16th, to Tuesday, 24th inst., in Cairo,
commencing each day at.S.SO a.m., and ter-
minating at 8.30 a.m., except on Tuesday,
24th inst., when the hours will be from 5.30
a.m. to 12 noon. The Commandant, Abbassieh.
has made the necessary arrangements for the
safety of the troops and public. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p> Fatal Fire in Cairo.—The Cairo City Fire
Brigade were called out at half past eleven
yesterday morning to an outbreak of fire which
occurred in a big laundry in the Mamnvheh
district. When they arrived on the scene it
appeared as if the outbreak were serious, but
happily it was extinguished in a short time,
and before very much material damage was
done, though one room was destroyed and
some machinery was badly damaged. Unfortun-
ately a native man was burnt to death. The
cause of the fire is not known, but it is supposed
to have originated in a stock of benzine and
petroleum which was kept on the premises.
Probably the amount of the damages will not
be found to exceed £'0. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEEP
BREMEN. </head>
<head> Fears so honest competition for quality </head>
<p>-Inferior Brands now being offered Men ages of certain good careless </p> </div>
 



                <div type = "item">
<head> PREMIER NOT TO RESIGN. </head>
<head> A BASELESS RUMOUR. </head>
<p> We aro authorised to state that the reports
of the approaching resignation of H.E. Musta-
jha Pasha Fehmy from the Prime Ministership,
which have appeared in the colomns of one
of our contemporaries, are absolutely without
frondation. </p> </div>
  
                <div type = "item">  
<head> EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
<head> HOWARD BEY'S RETIREMENT. </head>
<p> El MirJai F. J. L Howard Bey Las retired
from the Egyptian Army. In expressing his
regret at the retirement of E! Miralai Howard
Bey from his Highness the Khedive's Army,
the Sirdar, in an Army Order, places on
record his appreciation of tho services rendered
by this officer during the last ten years.
Daring this period El Miralai Howard Bey
has taken part in the following campaigns
and actions Expedition to Dongola, 1896 ;
Ni'e Expedition, 1897 ; Nile Expedition,
1898.—Battle of "Khartoum Nile Expedi-
tion, 1899.—Final defeat of the Khalifa. He
has held the appointments of Staff Officer
lor Supplies, and Governor and Commandant,
Suakia Province and District, in which the
excellence of his work has' been very con-
spicuous. The Sirdar, on behalf of-the Egyp-
tian Army, wishes El Miralai Howard Bey
every success in his future career.
Leave of absence, on private affairs, has
been granted to El Bimbashi Moore, Junior
Inspector, Kasala Province, and El Bimba-
ahi Ferrar, 15th Sudanese. </p> </div>
                
                <div type = "item">                
<head> MINISTRY OF JUSTICE. </head>
<p> Sir Malcolm Mcllwraith was received in
private audience by the,Khedive yesterday at
Ras el-Tin Palace, The Financial Adviser left
to-day On a tour of inspection of some of the
provincial tribunals, beginning at Port Said,
and will return to Cairo at the end of the week. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND
ALLOTMENT CO. </head>
<p>The "acte d'association" of the above com-
pany was signed yesterday at the mixed
Tribunals in Cairo, when a copy,of the statute
was deposited at the Greffe. It is non expected
that the new company will be floated in the
coarse of the next fortnight through the Hb Anglo-
Egyptian Bank, but only shall portion of the
capital, as we mentioned a few days Back, will
be offered to the public, as the rest has already
been privately subscribed. It has not yet been
decided who will be the third British member
of the board, as the gentleman to whom the
post was offered, although authorised to
accept it by his directors, has not yet done so.
The company has rented the offices formerly
occupied by the Daira Sanieh Co. in the
Sharia Kasr-el-Nil. </p>
<p>Wo have been asked to mention that, in
conformity with the Code, the shareholders
will be entitled to a dividend of 5 per cent,
before any distribution is made to the holders
of founders' shares, instead of 4 per cent, as
we were informed, and which we stated was
tho rate in our previous article. </p>
<p>According to the statutes the company is
constituted with the object of acquiring land
in Egypt and the Sudan, on purchase or on
lease, ameliorating the same, and re-selling or
letting it to cultivators in small lots and on
the most favorable conditions. The company
will likewise undertake irrigation or any other
works relating to agriculture in this country
or in tho Sadan, as well as making advances to
the fellaheen on security of land or crops. In
fact it will fulfil all the conditions of an enter-
prise which Lord Cromer in his last report has
strongly urged upon native capitalists to
turn their attention to, and we have no doubt
that the Anglo-Egyptian Allotment Company
will be hailed by the small cultivators as a
benefactor. </p>
<p>Besides the share capital of LE. 500,000,
divided into £195,000 shares of LE. 4 each,
the board is authorised to raise a like sum on
debentures if found necessary, and on condi-
tions to be determined later. The company
also reserves to itself the right of opening
branches or agencies throughout the country
whenever it considers this course advissable. </p>
<p> The net profits, after deduction of all ex
penses, internet on loans, and remuneration of
the board of directors, will be apportioned as
follows:—five per cent. to a reserve fond, and
five per cent to the shareholders ; of the sur-
plus, ten per cent, will be allotted to the
directors, and of the remaining balanoe 70
per cent will be paid to the shareholders and
30 per cent to the holders of founders'
shares. </p>
<p>The utmost credit is, we are told, due to
Yoassef Bey Sadik, formerly judge of the
Native Tribunals, in having brought the first
venture of this kind to a successful issue. He
proceeded to London and Paris at his own
expense during the summer, and there com-
pleted the arrangements for bringing out the
company. In our issue of the 22nd  September we
gave the names of the five native members of
the board, all of whom are well-known through-
out the country. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant </head>
<p>Table t'Hote Luncheons & Dinners
Served on the Terrace </p>
<p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
<p> delightful situation. sea numbers </p>
<head>CALENDAR OP THE WEEK. </head> </div>





                <div type = "item">
<head> COMING ROYAL VISIT. </head>
<head> PORT SAID ARRANGEMENTS. </head>
<head> PRINCE TO VISIT CAIRO. </head>
<head> (From our Correspondant). </head>
<p> Port-Said, Sunday. </p>
<p> The inhabitants of Port Said are already
beginning to prepare for the forthcoming visit
of the Prince and Princess of Wales, and to
all appearances local Britishers are determined
to give their Royal Highnesses a fitting wel-
come. </p>
<p> The arrangements which have so far been
made for the Royal trip are as follows. Their
Royal Highnesses will leave London on the
19th inst. and proceed to Ganos, where they
will embark on the 21st on H.M.S Renown.
This warship will be accompanied by H.M S.
Terrible, Suffolk, and Lancashire as far as
Port Said, where they are expected to arrive
at midday on the 26th inst. All four vessels
will be moored in the Dutch Basin, which is
being specially reserved for them. </p>
<p> The Royal party will probably proceed to
Cairo on the evening of their arrival, or, at the
latest, on the following morning, spending a
day or two in the Capital. They will afterwards
return to Port Said and re-embark on the
Renown, which, on resuming her voyage, will
be aocompanied by the Terrible—the other
two ships remaining here for station orders.
In the Red Sea the two ships will probably be
met and escorted by a detachment of the East
Indian Squadron to Aden before their final
departure for India. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> THE REFLOATED DREDGER. </head>
<p> As reported in yesterday's issue, the large
dredger Pharaon, which was sunk some five
months ago in the Dutcb Basin, was success-
fully refloated on Friday afternoon, after great
efforts by M. Dornoy and his staff. Oa being
examined it was found that the vessel was
absolutely full of mud and sand, besides being
covered with seaweed. She will probably
be partially sunk again, when the pumps will
be used to try and pump the mud and sand
out of her. At present she is so heavy with
the accumulation of sand and mud that she
cannot be lifted sufficiently high to allow of
her entering the floating dock. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> MALTA FEVER PREVALENT. </head>
<p> Malta fever ia very prevalent in Port-Said at
present. Several British residents are more
or less seriously ill, and there have been a few
deaths this week. The doctor at the Govern
ment Hospital iv very ill, and has been in
a critical condition all the week. This morning
however, a slight improvement was reported.
Dr. Betts, of Cairo, acts as locum tenens. </p> </div>
                
                <div type = "item">
<head> TOR LIGHTHOUSE. </head>
<p>Tor lighthouse is now in course of construc-
tion. One of Bell’s Asia Minor steamers, the
Fortuna, has already passed through the Canal
with a complete cargo of building material
The construction of the lighthouse is in the
hands of a French firm, and I understand that
the cost of building,exclusive of the cost of the
light and lens, is 75,000 frs. There were German
competitors tendering, and at a rate which
was slightly lower than the accepted oontract
The building is to be completed within two
years.</p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> PASSENGER LIST.</head>
<head> ARRIVALS. </head>
<p> Per Moss S.S. Moeris, arrived at Alexandria
yesterday : Mr. and Mrs. Bone, Mr. Soutar
and servant, and 2 deck passengers.
Le paquebot “Congo" dee Messageries Mari-
times arrive ce matin de Marseille avait a
bord:M.Ormad. Grant van Horne,M.Dimitraki
M. J. B. Caffari, Mlle Petit, Dr et Mme Hei
dan Bey, M.Fuad Greti Bey, M Touch Gaston
M.S.C. DUmm, M. H. Roose, Mme Bernard
Mlle Vernin, M et Mme Littlewood, 2 enfants
1 gonvernante, Mme Lequien, Mme de Balle-
garde, M.H Chamouleau, M. Boinet, M. et
Mme Simond Bey et enfant, M Ah. Bay Dara-
mally, M. Adanatis, M. D. Blake, Mlle Kem-
ber, Famille Sepsi, M. Autran, M. et Mme de
Sousa, M. et Mme V. Teissere, famille Zag-
doum, famille Riques, famille Banoum, famille
Suares, famille Vercamer, famille Goar, M. Le
Barry, M. et Mme Blum, famille Nicole, M. I
M. Rofe, Mme Delhaye, Mme de Chamber-
laine et 2 enfants, M. S. Tureidini, Mme Mil-
laire et I enfant. Mlle Casamart, Mme M.
Seljan, M. Delavigne, M.H.H. Borrison. M.
et Mme L Keel, M. A. Leakle, famille Chama,
famille Abbas Hilmi Bey, M. et Mme Gagnaire,
M. et Mme Sourmann, Mme H. Rosenzweig,
Mlle A. Morcier, M. Lautrey, M. Tronilley,
famille Mirguet, famille Neuville, Mme Colani,
Mlle Rousseau, M. Zahar, Mme B. Stramben,
famille Servin, Mme Baccus, famille Dick, M.
et Mme Maura, M. Schlinker, M. Seon, Mlle
Laura Marsheard, M. et Mme Cafeta et 3 en-
fants, M. et Mme Playonlt, M. Prnnibres, famill
Porol, M. Lacan, M. Comanos, M. Selim
Karem, M. Rene Nioole, Mme Piha et fils, M.
Leon, Sobame, Leon Jacob, Martynan, de
Gironde, famille Galassopoulo, Mme Arghiridis
et 1 bebe M. et Mme Hubin, M. et Mme
Levy, M. C. Adamidis, M. Clay, M. Levys,
Mme Lalyon et 74 passagers de 8me et 4me
classes. </p> </div>






                <div type = "item">
<head> LORD CROMER’S RETURN. </head>
<head> NATIVE PRESS COMMENTS. </head>
<p> "Al-Express," under the heeding of “Wel-
come to the Reformer," makes the following (
remarks on Lord Cromer’s return “The
comer is one whom Egyptians love, not as
the British Diplomatic Agent working, as he
must, for his own Government.... but as a
gentleman and a man of honor who has spent
two thirds of his life in Egypt Had it not been
for his diplomatic office Lord Cromer would 
have won the right to be elected as its minister
by the nation. He has studied the Egyptian
character, has associated with the Egyptian
people, and in his relations with them has
a1 ways proved the benevolent European who
likes the peasant aids the weak, and opposes a
determined resistance to the oppression which
he hates. Lord Cromer's policy has two aims :
to extend British influence in Egypt and to
increase the wealth, commerce, and culture of
Egypt and the freedom of every degree and
rank of the people...." </p> 
<p>The writer then discusses the appointment 
of a successor to the late Sheikh Mohammed
Abdou, and is certain that the now Grand
Mufti will have the support of Lord Cromer,
and confidently hopes that he will "confess no
influence above that of the law and no judge-
ment above that of God." </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> SPORT AND PLAY. </head>
<head> ALEXANDRIA SWIMMING CLUB. </head>
<p>On Saturday last, the Junior and Senior
Championships were swum off at the Gabbari
graving dock before a very numerous attend-
ance. The hon. secretary, Mr. H. S. Martin,
acted as starter, and sent the Juniors off for
their 60 yards swim to a good start, the follow-
ing competing: Harry Eisworth, H. Mit-
chinson, W. H. Talbot, M. L. Delanoy and
C. E. L Randall. A very even race ensued
but “little" Elsworth was too ambitious and
got ahead by himself and was exhausted before
he could be recalled to make a fresh start
with the other competitors. Randall soon show-
ed his superiority, and swimming well throughout
won somewhat easily by about 10 yards, Talbot
and Delanoy being second and third respect-
ively within a yard of each other. The silver
challenge cup for this race was presented by
Messrs. Borman & Co., and the three prizes by
the club. Master Randall has now won the cup
two years in succession, and should he be suc-
essful next year the cup becomes his own
property. </p>
<p> After this followed the event of the year,
viz, the 110 yards seniors championship for a
handsome silver challenge cup presented by
Mr. H. P. Kingham. There were 9 starters
and but for the absence of the E.T.C. staff at
Saez there would have been a far larger entry.
The following started, viz, Messrs. J. Bros-
comb, A. B. Collier, E. A. Darton. A. A. Boole-
stone, G. D. Lovell, N. Lupton, W. 0. Mace,
W G. B. Webb and W.Wood. The race was
well contested, and until the last 80 yards there
was no choice between Collier and Ecclestone
who were swimming neck and neck, they both
took too much notice of each other, and in the
meantime Darton, who had been swimming
steadily throughout, gradually overtook them
and won a sp'oodid race by a yard and a half,
and this in spite of the fact that he had recent-
ly undergone an operation for a poisoned foot.
Last year he was fifth in the same race, and the
present result speaks volumes for the progress
he has made. Collier was seoond and Boole-
stone third, barely a foot dividing the two.
After these events a polo match was p'ayed
between the dab and a team from H. H. 8.
Alla, represente 1 by the following : A.8.C.—
Messrs Darton, Ecclestone, Lovell, Lepton,
Randall,Webb andWood.H.H.8. Aida—Messrs
Ames, Bright, Haroty, Irvin,8auuders,Winter,
and Watt. The olnb at once deserted authority,
and before thegame was three miriutesold Darton
secured the ball from a neat pass by Lovell
and placed the ball into the oorner of the net,
! Winter having no chanoe of getting at tbe ball.
After this reverse Lieut. Watt (captain for the
. H.H.8. Alia) would have pat his side on equal
terms had Webh(who oaptained the dub seven)
not oonoeded a oorner throw. Notwithstanding
that the members had swam in the previous
contests,the faotmadtno difference to their ex-
odlent paseingflpeed and all round play, and
their superiority was very apparent from the
tart,with thewetult that before half-time Wood
sonred another goal. </p>
<p> Daring the interval the hon. sec. gave ons
of his usual exhibitions to tbe delight of thorn
t present On resuming the match even play was
witnessed until doee on time, when three more
goals, were soured by the dob through Darton,
' Ecclestone and Wood. We may add that for
' H.M.8. Aida Messrs. Watt Irvin and Winter
^ played exoellently, and but for the grand goal-
keeping of the latter the soore mast have
been far larger. </p>
<p>After this the prizes (given by the dub)
were presented to the suooesaful competitor*
by Mr. Wal'er P. Sujeant, (ohairman), who
made a short but appropriate speech to each.
Thus ended the third aud most snooessfnl
season of the A9.C, aid there is no donbt
that the dub has been established on a firm
footing in Alexandria. </p>
<p> Sir Massie and Lady Blomfidd have offered
a prize for next year’s sports, and H.H. Prinoe
Ad* Hainan Paths has expressed his desire to
' make his Challenge Cop an annual contribution. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head> KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLDB. </head>
<head> REGATTA.  </head>
<p> The handicap for to-morrow's race is the
,same as last Wednesday,
Class L Course D.
Class IL Course M. </p> </div>








                <div type = "item">
<head> GYMKHANA AT GHIRGEH. </head>
<head> (From a Correspondent). </head>
<p>It occurred to Mr. Harisborne, tho popular
and energetic agent of the Agricultural Bank
of Egypt at Ghirgeb, that the time was come
when some effort should be made to aireliorate
the lot of the unfortunate beasts of burden in
the moadirieh. In this idea he is by no means
alone, but his sympathy is of that active cha-
racter which is not content with theory, but
must find vent in practice.' He, therefore,
approached the Society for the Prevention of
Cruelty to Animals, which welcomed most
cordially the effort which he proposed to make.
The next step was to interest the community—
a matter of some difficulty, the idea being so
far without parallel in the district. To do this
it was thought that a gathering of the inha-
bitants would afford an excellent opportunity
to explain the object in view, and that no
method of convencing the people would prove
so effective as a gymkhana. The result was
that on Sunday last 7,000 people assembled on
the course at Ghirgeh. These included a large
proportion of the notables of the province,
headed by the sub-mundir, who, since the very
commencement of the movement, has exhibited
a close interest and given his hearty support
The programme was carefully arranged to
provide interest for the varying tastes of the
spectators. Perhaps the most popular item on
the programme was the handicap for men over
60, which was won by a hale old veteran of 76
summers, who crossed the line' but little in
front of a venerable old gentleman whose com-
mand of language elicited unstinted praise and
some laughter, when, on being awarded the
second prize of P.T. 50, he protested that a
sovereign would be little recompense enough
for his unwanted exertions. </p>
<p>A novel item was the contest between
village "champions." Unexpected difficulty was
experienced in bringing the competitors to the
mark, and it ultimately transpired that a
rumour was current that the winners of this
event would be required for military service.
None the less, representatives of 16 villages
started, and after an exciting contest, the
village of Owlad Yehia Bahri, represented by
Tevrfik, was declared winner; and the omdeh
was presented with a silver watch in comme-
moration of the event </p>
<p>Among those present in the grandstand
we noticed the sub-mondir, Hussein Bey
Waasif, Director of Irrigation, Fakry Abdel
Noor, German Consular Agent Kamil Eff.
Butrus, Salim Butrus, Bishai Malach, George
Mishrigi, Labib Abdel Noor, Nimr Abdel
Malack, mahoun and mulhir of police, the
postmaster, the station-master, Dr. Zaki, Mo-
hamed Namani Bey, and very many others.
At the close of the proceeedings the sub-
moudir presented the prizes and set forth the
objects of the gathering in a few well-chosen
words which were listened to with the greatast
interest. </p>
<p>Any acounnt would be incomplete which
did not pay a tribute to the mamonr el markas,
for the arrangements made for tho cont ol
of the crowd, and the orderliness of the spect-
ators, whose nunmbers far exceeded estimates,
and consequently reparations, so that some
discomfort was unavailable,but was none the
less born with imperturbable good humour. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
<p>The Sirdar, Mr. Machell Sir M. Mcllwraith,
and Sir Elwin Palmer have returned to Cairo. </p> </div>

                <div type = "item">
<p>Mr. Borchgrevink, Procureur General to the
Mixed Tribunals, returned by the S.S. Cleo-
patry yesterday.</p>

                    <div type = "item">
<p>Judge Sanders has also returned from
Europe.	</p> </div>
     
                    <div type = "item">
<p>Sir John Rogers will arrive at Port Said
on the 23rd inst.	,
Tho death is reported at New York of Mrs
Catherine Penfield, wife of Mr. Frederick
Courtland Penefield, former American Consul-
General in Egypt. </p> </div>
	
                    <div type = "item">
<p>Mr. Harold Harris, F. C. S., left Port Said
yesterday for Europe. </p> </div>

                    <div type = "item">
<p>Liett. C. G. R. Sydney-Turner, A.S.C., has
been granted leave of absence, on private
affairs, to January 31, 1906. Sister M.
Worthington, Q.A.I.M.N.S., is granted leave
of absence, on urgent private affairs, to
January 27, 1906. </p> </div>

                    <div type = "item">
<p>M. A. de Pauliny and family were amongst
the passengers by the S.S. Iraunaddy, which
arrived at Port Said on Sunday from Mar-
seilles. M. de Pauliny is returning to Cairo
to resume his duties as chief engineer of
the new works on the Egyptian State Rail
ways, after a well-earned rest of tome months,
having for years past refused to avail himself
of his annual leave in order to devote all
his energies to the completion of the new
line from ismailia Port Said, in connec-
tion with which he received a reocognition of
his services in the Farrer Commission's report.
Another passenger by the same vessel was
Saweeria Eff. Basta, (eldest son of the late
Basta Bey, a well-known Copto philanthropist
of Sohag.) This gentleman has been staying
in England for some months for the benefits of
his health, which, we are glad to hear, is now
fully restored. </p> </div>
 
            </div>







                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
