<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2021-01-21">January 21, 2021</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1905-02-14/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-02-14">Tuesday, February 14, 1905</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/mode/1up"
                status="incomplete">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-ad-etc02"> The Eastern
                                Telegraph Company, Limited.<lb/> Le réseau de cable télégraphiques
                                sous-marins de cette compagnie<lb/> constitue le moyen de
                                communication le plus<lb/> direct et le plus rapide d'Egypte pour
                                l'Europe, l'Amérique<lb/> du Nord et du Sud, L,Afrique orientale,
                                méridionale<lb/> et occidentale, les Indes, l'Australie, la
                                Nouvelle-Zélande, la<lb/> Chine et le Japon.<lb/> Pour assurer une
                                transmission rapide, les télégrammes<lb/> doivent porter
                                l'indication <hi rend="bold">Viâ Eastern</hi>.<lb/> Voir le temps
                                moyen de transmission le plus récent jusqu'à<lb/> Londres au
                                belletin journalier publié dans ce journal.<lb/> STATIONS EN EGYPTE.
                                Alexandrie, le Caire, Suez,<lb/> Port-Tewfik, Port-Said, Suakin.
                                Bureau principal à Londres.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7123">7,123</measure>]</cell>
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 14, 1905.</cell>
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="5"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n1/mode/1up"
                status="incomplete">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item"/>
                <!-- weather -->
                <div type="template" xml:id="deg-el-egsa03">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</head>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS.– Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including
                        delivery in Alexandria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231½ per
                        annum, P.T. 116 for six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries
                        in the Postal Union P.T. 273 (£2.16s.) per annum.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.– P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages,
                        or Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20, every additional line P.T.
                        10. Notices in news columns P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for
                        standing advertisements.</p>
                    <p>N.B.– Subscriptions commence from the 1st or 16th of any month.</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS are due in advance. P.O. Orders and Cheques
                        to be made payable to the Editor and Manager, Rowland Snelling,
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>London Offices: 86, New Broad-street, E.C.</p>
                    <p>THE "EGYPTIAN GAZETTE” IS PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE
                        LONDON PAPER MILLS Co., LIMITED (SALES OFFICE: 27, CANNON STREET, E.C.)
                            <measure type="indexNo">36-4</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="imprint" xml:id="deg-el-egpi01">
                    <head>The Egyptian Gazette</head>
                    <p>An English Daily Newspaper, Established in 1880.</p>
                    <p>Editor &amp; Manager: R. Snelling.</p>
                    <p>Price: One Piastre Tariff.</p>
                    <p><date when="1905-02-14">TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 14, 1905</date>.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="leader">
                    <head>EGYPT-OR UTOPIA.</head>
                    <p>While we cordially welcome the interest which is now being taken at home in
                        Egypt and things Egyptian, it must be confessed that there are certain
                        drawbacks to this attitude, especially when it tends to interference in
                        matters which can only be competently dealt with by those who have gained a
                        profound local knowledge of the country and its people. Egypt is far more
                        liable than any other Oriental country to arouse the platonic passions of
                        that class of busybody whose characteristics <cb n="6"/> have been embodied
                        by Mr. Kipling in "Padgett M. P." And as Cairo develops more and more into
                        an Oriental Brighton during the winter months, there, must necessarily be a
                        growing number of estimable persons, who, inspired by only a superficial
                        acquaintance with the conditions of Egyptian life, return to England.
                        determined to air their pet panaceas for the. betterment of the land in
                        Parliament or the Press. However well-intentioned they may be, their efforts
                        must, in many cases, do positive harm by stirring up that considerable
                        section of the population of the British Isles who belong to the genus
                        "crank" to make mis chievous attempts to hamper the work of Anglo-Egyptian
                        Administration. A suggestive sample of these tactics occurred in a recent
                        issue of the "Manchester Guardian," a correspondent of which paper in Vairo
                        ventilated a number of Egyptian grievances, con-- cluding with the following
                        sentence:- "When it is no longer possible to see Arabic children in Cairo
                        raking the rubbish heaps in the streets for their daily food, then it will
                        be time to declare that British officialism in Egypt is imbued with those
                        high aims, the absence of which called from the lips of an English 'bishop
                        the reproach against Cairo as being the grave of the soul."</p>
                    <p>The statements of this gentleman called forth an article from the editor of
                        the "Guar dian," who indulged in these remarks with all the sententiousness
                        befitting the occasion - "Now, that we have shaken off some of the
                        internationaal fetters on our rule, our respon sibility for these things has
                        become more direct and individual. It cannot be too clearly understood that
                        no administrative clockwork has yet been invented that will go for ever. It
                        cannot be wound up once and for all; there must be steady and continuous
                        interest in the mechanism of government if disaster is to be avoided.
                        English people have never, since the fighting stopped, taken a direct
                        interest in Egyptian affairs in that way, and still less in the welfare of
                        the Egyptian. Our correspondent points out some of the dangers of this
                        indiffe rence. When self-government is conceded the danger is reduced to a
                        minimum, and the policy of non-interference becomes political virtue. But we
                        have not provided ourselves with that safeguard. The machinery of government
                        in Egypt is still almost entirely. English, and if anything goes wrong with
                        it England will suffer the consequences."</p>
                    <p>The sentiments conveyed in this passage. are so excellent as to partake of
                        the nature of truisms, but they are entirely vitiated by the underlying
                        fallacy that Egypt can be benefited by interference from England. What can
                        parliamentary or official interference from home do to prevent "Arab
                        children in Cairo raking the rubbish heaps in the streets for their daily
                        bread " If the views of such persons as the correspondeht of our Manchester
                        contemporary gained acceptance, the grumblers would soon find out to their
                        cost that the distant and illinformed King Stork was much worse to deal with
                        than the local King Log, whatever the faults of the latter may be. If such a
                        policy is pursued to its logical conclusion, and the faddists obtain a
                        hearing through their im portunity and the weakness of the houte
                        authorities, the result will be as disastrous: as was "la politique des
                        rattachements" to Algeria, where the powers of the Governor- General were
                        utterly undermined by interference from Paris. As long as Lord Cromer
                        remains this tendency will be counteracted, but it may become a really
                        serious danger to Egypt in the future. Egyptian development should, and
                        must, proceed on the lines of local, by which we mean not only native but
                        resi dent. European, self government, and all attempts to invoke
                        interference from England as a "Deus ex machina" to bring about a Nilotic
                        Utopia must be most strenuously resisted, for it is a mischievous and
                        unstatesmanlike policy, and runs counter to the entire system on which. the
                        substantial fabric of British influence has been everywhere built up.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n2/mode/1up"
                status="verified">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE WAR<lb/>RUSSIANS REPULSE INFANTRY ATTACK</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Sr. PETRUSBURG, February 13 </dateline>
                            <p>General Kurpaktin seposta dmi 300 Japanese cavalry bitücked the
                                railway bridge al t urg on the 12instaud dainaged una of the live.
                                Traffic was subsequently tel. The Japanese, on the 11th iul,
                                brianded the Russim. pušitions with sient 1. The Japanese i fantry
                                attack was</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STATE OF SIEGE IN VLADHOSTOK.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>CSI L'ETERSBURO, February 13, </dateline>
                            <p>It is atidance bere that a state of siena isbyen pauclusimed at
                                Viadin stuk. Part of le intrabitants have lurriedly left the
                                town.</p>
                            <p>(llente</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THIRD BALTIC FLEET.<lb/>INSUBORDINATION AMONG MEN.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, February 13 A </dateline>
                            <p>certajer'amount of insubordination prevails mount the men of the
                                thiril Baltic Fleet A milor was shot on Saturday for stabbing a
                                lieutenant.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COLLIERS REFUSED JSTLUM.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>1: 143703. BA S ta), February 13.</dateline>
                            <p>The German ar Bulgariak" wid the Briti-l cuisi t osi'arived here.
                                "The ich athutties blete them to Batavia, where there to be lauded
                                and sold.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCOMOTIES FOR JAPAN.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>LADON, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The Japewe. Government has placed an irgent order in Glasgow for 30
                                locomotiven. (leuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NORTH SEA ENQUIRY. SITTINGS RESUMED.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Paris, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The North Sea Commissioners resumed their sittings today. The parties
                                submitted their coriclusions, both strougly adhering to their
                                original statements. (Reuter.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>PARIS, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The North Sea Commission of Enquiry has heard the conclusions of
                                counsel for England and for Russia</p>
                            <p>The conclusions of the English counsel maintain the absence of
                                torpe-to-boats and declan the Russian fire to have been
                                unjustified.</p>
                            <p>The conclusions of the Russian counsel deciure that military reasons
                                justified the fin of the Russian ships. Russia, however, agree to
                                pay an indemnity, which would be fixed by the Hague Tribunal.
                                ...</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>"DOWN WITH THE AUTOCRACY." DEMONSTRATION AT A THEATRE.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>SA PETERSBURG, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>There was # demonstration in the Mal Theatre bere last night, men
                                crying "Down with the autocracy and making use of persona învectives
                                against the Tur. The demonstrators were finally ejected, and the
                                performance i continued.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AMERICAN ARBITRATION. THE PRESIDENT AND SENATE.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>WASItingtox, February 13. - </dateline>
                            <p>President Roosevelt and the Senate have reached ad acute state of
                                disagreement concerning the arbitration treaties which Mr. Hay has
                                laboriously concluded with Japan, Great Britain, and syemal other
                                European Powers. In spite of strong pressure on the part of Mr.
                                Rooreveit, the Senate inserted an amendment in the treaties Securg
                                to it the right to intervene belore any question is submittest w
                                arbitration. In consequence, Mr. Roosevelt has resolved to drop the
                                treaties altogether,</p>
                            <p>Public opinion, apparently, endorsey the action of the Suuate.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS. AN HISTORICAL EVENT:</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>Vissa, Pebruary 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The Emperor yesterday received Herr Kos. suth in connection with the
                                Hungarian crisis. It was a notable bistorical event as it was his
                                first entrance to the Palace to my homage to the Emperor who bad
                                condemned his father to death. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GERMANY AND ABYSSINIA. MISSION AT ADIS ABEBA.</head>
                        <div type="cable">
                            <dateline>BERLIN, February 13. </dateline>
                            <p>The German mission, mentioned on the 6th December, has been received
                                by the Emperor Menelik at Adis Abeba. The mission will remain there
                                for 20 days. .. (Renter.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Tux AMERICAN STEAM </head>
                        <p>Yacur "Aloedo," lir. G. W. C. Drexel, owner, has arrived from</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FIELD DAY-- </head>
                        <p>A tactical field day will be held at ibhussieh for the Cairo garrison on
                            Thurs next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The KHEDIVE'- </head>
                        <p>Yacht the "Mahroussa," which arrived in the Clyde a firtnight ago, i. uw
                            moored close to. Meurs. Inglis' yard at Penthouse, where the alterations
                            will be carried out.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ALEXANDRIA SCANDAL. -</head>
                        <p>The Italian Consular Court of Alexandria pronounced judgment yesterday in
                            the divorce proceedings instituted by Mr. Ninci. Particulars will be
                            found on page 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The POWELL-COTON EXPEDITION </head>
                        <p>has left the Nile and arrived at the Zubesi. Accurd. Jing to the latest
                            advices received from Major</p>
                        <p>Powell Cotton he has started for an unexplored section of the Congo Stata
                            in -carch of the wlata rhinoceros.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PHE AMERICAN COLLEGE, BEYROUT. — </head>
                        <p>"An Eye witness" sends us details of some strange events, which are
                            alleged to have transpired at the American College at Beyrout on the 7th
                            and sth inst. As our orrespondent is anony mous we cannot publish his
                            statements.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAQUE.. </head>
                        <p>During the week ending Satunlay last, 7 deaths from bovine typhus were
                            reported throughout Egypt. During the corresponding week in 1904 5,949
                            deaths were notified. Since the beginning of the epidemic the total
                            number of deaths is 146 710.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW CATHEDRAL FOR CAIRO.- </head>
                        <p>The scheme for the erection of a Maronite Cathedral at Cairo bas taken
                            definite shape and L E. 10,000 has already been subscribed. Mgr. Darian,
                            the Maronite Archbish p. Chakour Pasha, Abdullah Bey Sfer, and many
                            other Syrian notables, are heartily supporting the scheme.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="letters">
                    <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                    <p>We do not had our strax for the responsable opinions expreso 1 ty car
                        correspondessta, lant wa wimb, spirit of fair pla to all, to purit - within
                        a scary limita fres d ansion.</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A RACE OF ARTIS IS.<lb/>TO THE EDITOR OF THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.</head>
                        <p>Sir, I send a few of the smaller stones from the desert, which I think
                            you have not seen, and for which I hope I may claim your adiniration.
                            What, sir, would not gott or I give for that touch of hand and truth of
                            eye ! Look at the wonderful skill with I which they have been carved,
                            repeating again</p>
                        <p>and again the same idea, but almost always with the distinctive touch of
                            the individual worker,--just as in the pretty attractive cloth I word of
                            the Kabyle women, the pattern is not copied or mechanically repeated,
                            but each worker follows an instinct of her own. And so it was with this
                            old stone race. With some exceptions, some types ronghly
                            executed-perhaps of the earlier time, for it! was over an immense space
                            of time that they worked, -- and some few that merely repro dnced the
                            conventional pattern, the mass of the stones bear constant witness to
                            the free play of band and imagination. What gifts this desert people bad
                            i One may donbt--and I am not forgetting the story of Greece, which wa-
                            different in its kind if the world has ever yet produced a race with
                            such an artistic sense 1-o widely distributed--perhaps in Japan 'you
                            have had the nearest approach to it. In the artistic fancies of both
                            ruces - the love of the quaint and grotesque-the mixture of human and
                            demon-yet with a certain self-restraint, the half extravagance kept
                            within the limits of sobriety--you feel as if there were common
                            elements--as if the two races had shared some of the same gifts. I
                            should like to send a tow examples to Tokio for our Japanese friends to
                            pass judgment upon.</p>
                        <p>And now, sir, how goes it with my friends, the learned babes 1 Have they
                            mended their little wayward fashions, and grown in wisdom and stature!
                            Or is A.B.C. still the same sal trial, as it was, to their rebel souls 1
                            Do they Ixtill pont and sulk in their eyrtier? Do they still cry "can't,
                            shan't, won't” while the little fists are doubled up in the little eyes
                            and the little</p>
                        <p>feet stawp upon the flxer? Was there ever sich Ja hullabaloo and piece of
                            work in the nursery</p>
                        <p>all about learning A.B.C., which sooner or later must be learned. There
                            is no prissible escape from it. No amount of shan't and won't</p>
                        <p>can help them. Their fate is inexorably I written. And never was there a
                            prettier, pleasanter, more attractive A.B.C. for a babe to learn--an
                            A.B.C. that sh-uld never have cost a tear oz a whimper! And as soon as
                            they once humble the haughty little souls- just a touch wanted of the
                            penitent's redeeming grace--and set themselves with goodwill to the
                            task, what delight they will find in it, what revelations are waiting
                            for them! But I must not take up too much of your space. At</p>
                        <p>Rome, Trieste, Athens, and again at AlexJandria, I found after some
                            little hunting plenty</p>
                        <p>of traces of the same race. The stone was I much less favorable, ant the
                            work consequently much rougher ; but the lealing types were the same.
                            Some day we ought to be able to trace with considerable exnotness the
                            march of this great people--for really great they | were. You cannot
                            live amongst their work, and with hold your admiration from them.I am,
                            eto,</p>
                        <byline>AUBEBON HERBERT. </byline>
                        <dateline>Tewfik Palace Hotel, Helouan,</dateline>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROYAL VISIT TO KHARTOUM.<lb/>REVIEW OF TROOPS.</head>
                    <byline>(From our CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Khartoum, February 4. </dateline>
                    <p>A review of all the troops in the station I was held this morning on the
                        parade ground at| Khartoum. At 8 o'clock H.R.H. the Duchess of Connanght,
                        with the Princesses, accompanied by Lady Wingate, arrived ina landau at the
                        Royal| stand. A few minntes later H.R. H. the Duke, | accompanied by H.E.
                        the Sirlar and Governor| General, General Sir J. Maxwell, and the staff,
                        followed on the parade-ground, and the Royal Standard was at once boisted
                        near the enclosure. | After the inspection, the troops began to file past
                        his H.R.H., performing the various evolutions, the Rifle Brigade being
                        specially smart and showing they had marched over Sudan sands once before.
                        The cavalry, and notably the artillery, appear to bave been I quite up to
                        the mark, and H.R.H. was pleased to express his entire satisfaction with the
                        bearing of the troops and the evolutions effected.</p>
                    <p>I learn that the Duke of Connaught expressed the opinion that trousers for
                        the native troups, shaped Zouave fashion, would perhaps be more suitable for
                        this climate than the ordinary trou-ers now in use.</p>
                    <p>In the after on, the Royal party, accompanied by the whole staff, crossed
                        over on a visit to Omdurman.</p>
                    <p>In the evening there was a military tattoo in front of Government baildings,
                        at which the Royal party were present. Bimbashi Franklin, director of mu-io,
                        was bonored with a few words of thanks from H. R. H. for his services on the
                        occasion. ROYAL PARTY AT DIVINE SERVICE.</p>
                    <p>Khartoum, February 5. </p>
                    <p>The Royal party attended divine service this morning in the temporary church
                        room in the Palace.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VISIT TO GORDON COLLEGE.</head>
                    <dateline>Khartoum, February 6. </dateline>
                    <p>T. R. H. the Duke and Duchess of Con. naught, with the Princesses, and
                        accompanied by H. E. the Governor General, Lady Wingate, and snite, visited
                        Gordon College to-day and then drove round the town of Khartoum. The natives
                        turned out and gave the Royal party a hearty greeting. The annual regatta
                        took | place in the afternoon in front of the Palace, and at 10.30 p.m. the
                        Royal party left for the North. I may mention that the police arrange ments
                        throughout the Royal visit were perfect.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASSOUAN DAM VISITED.</head>
                    <dateline>Assouan, Tuesday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Dake and Duchess of Connaught arriv. ed at Assouan this moruing and will
                        visit the dam in the afternoon accompanied by Sir Willinn Garstin, Mr. A. L.
                        Webb, Mr. Clowes, and Mr. Macdonald.</p>
                    <p>The R val party will leave Luxor on Thursday by a special train leaving at
                        6.50 p.m. which will bring them to Cairo at 9.10 a.m. ou Friday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>Today H. H. the Khedive visited the Mosque at Koubbeh for prayer on the
                        opening of Kourban Beyram. Salvoes of 21 guns were fired from the Citadel
                        and at Abbassieh on the arrival and departure of his Highness.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon, his Highness received Ally Pasha Yaghen, Governor of
                        Cairo, and all the principal functionaries or notables who received
                        promotion or decorations on the occasion of the anniversary of H. H.'s
                        accession.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GENERAL STOESSEL AT SUEZ.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Messageries Maritimes S.S. "Australien," by which Gen. Stoessel is a
                        passenger, is due to arrive at Suez to-morrow at 10 a.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PLAGUE ON STEAMER.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Saez, Monday. </dateline>
                    <p>The Austrian Lloyd 8.S. "Imperator," from Bombay, arrived at Suez yesterday.
                        Owing to her having landed a case of plagne at Aden, she was put in
                        quarantine at this port, and after being disinfected entered the Canal in
                        quarantine. Passengers for Suez were conveyed to Moses' Wells to purge two
                        days' quarantine</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXPORT OF GUM ARABIC.</head>
                    <p>Daring the month of December last, 1,031,614 kilus of gum arabic, valued at
                        LE.23,217, were exported from Egypt. In the same month of 1903 the experts
                        were 574,359 kilos, of the value of L.E.12,967, showing an increase in 1904
                        of 457,255 kilos, value LE 10,250.</p>
                    <p>During the year 1904, the exports show increases of 1,989,571 kilos in weight
                        and of LE. 11,394 in amount as compared with 1903, the respective figures
                        being as follows:- 1904, 10,402,054 kilos, value L.E.234,060 ; 1903,
                        8.412,483 kilos, value L.E.192,666.</p>
                    <p>Of the above, the export to England and her Mediterranean possessions was
                        2.220,528 kilos, valno LE 49,960; Germany, 1,740,096 kilos, value LE. 39,159
                        ; Austria-Hungary, 702,815 kilos, value L.E.15,810 ; France and Algeria,
                        2,711,811 kilos, value L.B. 60,990; Italy, 286,086 kilos, value LE 6,424 ;
                        Turkey, 12,303 kilos, value L.E.269; America, 1,438, 424 kilos, value
                        L.E.32,364, and to other countries 1,290,992 kilos, value L.E.29,084,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CROMER'S TRIP.<lb/>VISIT TO KENEH.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</byline>
                    <p>Keneh, Saturday. . Lord and Lady Cromer, accompanied by Lady Beatrice Thyone,
                        arrived at keneh by steamer at 1 p.m, to-day. Among those awaiting their
                        arrival were the Moudir, the SubMoudir, all the heads of the Government de
                        partments, the consular agents, omdehs, sheikhs, and a guard of honor.</p>
                    <p>As the steamer accosted the landing stage, I Lord Cromer stepped out and
                        sbook hands with the Moudir, who introduced a number of those present to his
                        lordship. On Lord Cromer asking if anyone could speak English, the SubMoudir
                        replied in the affirmative, and his lordship proceeded to thank the
                        gathering for their reception, the Sub-Moudir acting as interpreter. Lord
                        Cromer said he regretted he bad no time to visit the town, as he was in al
                        burry to leave for the South</p>
                    <p>The steamer remained at the landing stage for some time ooaling and at 3.30
                        sailed for Kous, where the party will stop for the night. On the following
                        morning (Sunday) the steamer will leave at 6 o'olook for Mataang direct and
                        will make another stay there for the night. Erom Mataana the distinguished
                        party proceed to Silwa, from which place they will go to Kom Orabo, where
                        they will remain three hours. Leaving Kom Ombo they will reach Assouan on
                        the afternoon of Tuesday, the 14th | inst. Lord and Lady Cromer expect to be
                        back in Cairo on the 22nd inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE JUDGE KEILEY.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of the late Judge A. M. Kelley, formerly judge of the Mixed
                        Courts of Egypt, who was accidentally killed in the streets of Paris, took
                        place at Notre-Dame on Saturday, February 4. The American Consul-General was
                        present.</p>
                    <p>Owing to illness, neither the judge's son-inlaw, Captain Hall, nor his
                        daughter were able to be present, but the family was represented by Mr.
                        Arnold Hall and Miss Hall, who came | from England to assist at the
                        ceremony. -</p>
                    <p>A correspondent writes as followa to the "New York Herald” (Paris) :-I feel
                        that the death of so well- known an American as Judge A. M. Keiley deserves
                        a record. In your edition of Saturday, January 28, I found a short
                        paragraph, ovpied from a French paper, stating that a well-dressed man,
                        about sixty years of age, had been knocked down by a delivery van in the
                        place de la Concorde the day before, and had been carried to the hospital,
                        where he died that night. In his pocket was found a card bearing the name
                        and address of Judge Keiley, 49, Dover-street, Piccadilly-nothing more,</p>
                    <p>Jndge Keiley was a man well known at home and abroad. He had at various times
                        Atted several publio offices in his native city, vit., Louisville, Ky, and
                        for many years had represented the United States in the Mixed Courts of
                        Egypt. He lived in Alexandria until his wife died, two or three years ago,
                        when he resigned his position and went to London, to be near a married
                        daughter</p>
                    <p>Judge Keiley was a man of unusual attainments; he knew the classies as he did
                        the alphabet ; not only spoke half a dozen modern languages, but know their
                        literature as well. He know all good things and loved them. He could tell a
                        story better than the next man, let him tell it never so well, and what is
                        more, could appreciate the point of the other fellow's story. He was
                        liberal, broad-minded, tenderhearted, full of sympathy for suffering :
                        genial and warm-hearted. He was a loyal, staunch friend, and I, who only
                        knew him casually, as it were, feel that I shall not soon look upon his like
                        again.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A PROPOS DE L'EAU.</head>
                    <p>Monsieur le Directeur</p>
                    <p>de "l'Egyptian Gazette." On fait grand bruit en ce moment, touchant la
                        pollution des eaux que nous vend fort cher "T'Alexandria Water Company
                        Limited" et ce n'est point la première fois que l'on crie que l'eau est
                        contaminée.</p>
                    <p>Après constatation des faits les services 88nitaires ne préconisent aucun
                        système pour stériliser les conduita et assurer enfin une enu moins chargée
                        de microbes.</p>
                    <p>Si les dits services poulaient prendre la peine d'analyser l'eau du
                        Mahmoudieh chaque jour et si le résultat de ce petit travail était
                        communiqué au public, celui-ci serait fort surpris d'apprendre quelle
                        quantité considé. rable de microbes il absorbe quotidiennement,</p>
                    <p>Quant au canal de dérivation qui alimente la Compagnie des Eaux, il est
                        installé dans toutes les conditions requises pour être contaminé en son
                        entier parcours.</p>
                    <p>En effet, dans tous les alentours du dit canal, il n'y a pas une fosse
                        d'aisances qui soit imperméable et cimentée conformément aux règlements
                        sanitaires.</p>
                    <p>D'autre part, le service Maritime et Quarantenaire ne fait aucune objection
                        quant à la fourniture de cette eau pour l'approvisionnement des navires et
                        ne prend aucune mesure pour leur procurer de l'eau saine. Le dernier congrès
                        sanitaire de Venise s'est pourtant 00enpé un tantinet de cette question
                        primordiale mais ici, au pays nilotique, la consigne est et sera encore
                        longtemps de dire : Malesch.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>De SaixT BONNET. Alexandrie, le 13 février 1905.</p>
                    <p>SIVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</p>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Manage ment Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerta twice daily.</p>
                    <p>#1941-18 PronuOM I Xornal &amp; Mannannt</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONDITION. OF HELOUAN. NO GOVERNMENT SUPPORT.</head>
                    <byline>(From Our CORRESPONDENT). ..</byline>
                    <p>* Helouan, February 12. An important meeting of the Municipal Commissioners
                        of Helouan has been held at the Gouvernorat under the presidency of H. E.
                        the Governor of Cairo. There were present the Tanzim delegate, Mr. Cartis,
                        the Sanitary Department delegate, Dr. Dryer, and the four elected
                        representative members of the town, M. Felix Suares, Hussein Bey Youssef,
                        Mahmoud Fehmy Pasha, and Dr. A. J. M.| Bentley. | The question of the
                        condition and wanta of the town of Helouan came before the meeting, After
                        some remarks from M. Suares, Hussein Bey Youssef, and Mahmoud Febmy Pasha,
                        on the unsatisfactory condition of the town and the miserable financial dole
                        voted to the Commission, Dr. Bentley addressed the Council as</p>
                    <p>follows. | Your Excellency, - You may remember that at our last meeting I
                        presented you with &amp; petition from the inhabitants of the town of
                        Helouen aoking that it might be read and considered by th: Council hefore
                        presenting it to the Government for their consideration. This your
                        Excellency did not see fit? to do, and the only course open to the
                        inhabitants was to go with it direct to the chiefs of the Ministries
                        interested, which petition was later on published in several of the
                        newspapers of Bgypt. This petition, I hear on good authority, was not
                        unfavorably received by the heads of tho various departments concerned. The
                        petition, I may call to your mind, dealt with the following points :(i). The
                        railway service ; (ü). The state of the roads and condition of the water
                        supplied for drinking ; (iii). The constitution of the Local Commission ;
                        (iv). The expenditure of the revenue derived from local taxation.--The
                        Railway (i) is now in the possession of the Delta Light Railway Company and
                        they have promised to carry out certain and, we believe, efficient reforms.
                        The matter of the drinking water and the roads (ii) concerns the Tanzim
                        Department. The allocation of the revenue (iv) derived from Helonan is a
                        financial matter and concerns the Ministry of Finance. The carrying out of
                        (ü), which is so urgently required, is</p>
                    <p>large matter, and it is absolutely impossible to deal with it satisfactorily
                        with the small amount of money allowed to this Commission. (iii The
                        constitution of the Commission is essentially an anomaly s elected partly by
                        public vote to carry out reforms, ithasabsolutely no power to accomplish
                        them. If suggestions are made to the Commission and they are not carried
                        out, the publie regard the failure as being due to its not having the power
                        to im prove, it still has to bear the blame. I propose, therefore, that in
                        the best interests of Helouan. and with a due regard to the dignity of this
                        Council, that the Municipal affairs of the town be placed again in the hands
                        of the Goverament, which alone is able to carry out those reforms so
                        necessary for the well-being of the town. This Commission has doubtless done
                        excellent work in its time, the Tanzim officials connected with it have
                        always been willing to do what they could for the improvement of the town,
                        but owing to the rapidly increasing importance of Helouan and its neigh
                        bourhood, and the urgent and large reforma needed, it is time that the
                        present system, with its very limited powers, should be abolished, and that
                        the municipal affairs should be placed in the hands of the Government, which
                        alone has the power to efficiently carry them out I appeal to your sense of
                        duty not to place any obstacle in the way, but rather to sink all
                        differences and personal feelings for the wellbeing of the town of Helovan,
                        and I further beg to suggest that to facilitate matters this Council should
                        delegate three or more of its members to consult with the Government to
                        ascertain ita views on this matter.</p>
                    <p>The president, in replying, stated that he had received official information
                        that the Finance Ministry had refused to sanction any further aid to Helovan
                        or to grant money to allow more water for the roads and trees. The tour
                        elected representative members there upon tendered their resignation in a
                        body, as a protest against the Government decision. * Later on they were,
                        however, induced by the president to withdraw their resignations
                        conditionally on his Excellenoy på mising to bring their protest before the
                        proper authorities. They, however, expressed very decided views to his
                        Excellency on the uselessness of holding | further meetings under existing
                        circum stances.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHEPHEARD'S SMALL DANCE.</head>
                    <p>Last night's small dance at Shepheard's met with the usual success. The
                        restaurant was quite fullat dinner time. Among many others dining there we
                        noticed Mr. and Mrs. Geo. W. | Drexel and party, Mr. B. Johnson and party,
                        including Mr. and Mrs. Thos Walsh and Miss Walsh, Baron von Oppenheim, Baron
                        Tiede mann-Seeheim and family, Mr. Pembroke Jones and family, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Fiedler, Mr. and Mrs. Granville Alexander, Mr. and Mrs. Enn. C. Zervudachi
                        and party, Mr. J. W. Mellor and Miss Mellor, Major Pirie and party, includ
                        ing Major Kenny Herbert, Mr. Carter Wilson and Major Harold ; Baron,
                        Baroness and Miss de Peteghem, Marquis de Corea and Comte Gabriel de Zogheh,
                        Mr. and Mrs. G.T. Rafferty and the Misses Rafferty, Mr. Mrs. and Misses
                        Abbott, Mrs. and the Misses Gelshenen, Prince Lichtenstein, Comte
                        Trautmannsdorf, General and Mrs. von Haewardt, General and Mrs. von Diest,
                        Baron Te-sin, Baron Vogel de Falkenstein, Mrs. Marion Spring and party, Mr.,
                        Mrs. and Miss Moss, Mr. and Mrs. Brsley and Mr. Horley, Mr., Mrs., and Miss
                        Pinkerton and Miss Bessie Jordan, Mr. and Mrs. Robinson, eto,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item" feature="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <p>"HBLOUAN THIRD WINTER</p>
                    <p>MEETING</p>
                    <p>The following are the entries for the above meeting, to be held at flelouah
                        on Priday, 17th inst, at 2.80 pm. :</p>
                    <p>FIRST RACE, 2.80 p.. Mapex Poxy RAÇe. Value PT. 2,500, 2nd borse to receive
                        P.L. 300, and 3rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Arab ponies, chat
                        have never won a race of any desoription. Weight for ago and inches Distance
                        1 for longa : - Saleh Bey. Yughan's ide, 10.7. Moharrem Pasha Chebin'a Vali,
                        9.18. Ibrahima Bey Cherif's Amour, 10.7. • Ishak Boy Hansein and Hassan. Bey
                        Kheir el-Din's Rais, 10.7, Saleh Bey. Chérits Ragan, 10.7. ...</p>
                    <p>SECOND RACE, 3 p.m.. MAIDEX GAILOMAX. Valús P.T. 2,500,-And borse to receive
                        P.T. 300, and 3rd P.I. out of the stake For Arabs, Weight for Age and
                        incben. Distande about mila-badi Bey Cherifs Arabi, 10.7, and Panda, 9.18.
                        Saleh Bey Yaghen's Munir, 9,18, and Sibame: 9.13. Mobarrem Pasha Chahin's
                        Bibioo, 8.7. Omar Bey Sultan' and Ahmed Bey Belai's Sayad II., 10.8. ME N.
                        Sogaja and Kaapel Effendi Maber's Social Life, 10.3.3</p>
                    <p>THIRD RACE, 3.30 p.m. The ARAB HANDICAP. ValueP.T. 2,500, And horse to
                        receive P.T. 300, and 3rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For all Arabe.
                        Distance 1 1 mile.--Soleh Bey. Yaghen's London and Mashkour II., Mobatrem,
                        Pasha Chelvin's Mizzaud, Mr. P. W. Stout's Shewiman, ishek Bey. Hussein's
                        Rapid, Omar Bey Balian and Ahmed . Bay el Bakri's Rachid... E FOURTH RACE, 4
                        «p.m...</p>
                    <p>TRIAL PLATE. Value P.T. 2,500, 9nd horse to receive P.T. 300, and 3rd horae
                        P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Amb horses, that have never won a race of
                        any description (Gymkhanas excepted). Weight for age. Distance mile.-Ibrahim
                        Bey Cherif s· Arabi, 10.7, Moharrem Pasha Chetin's 'The Prince, 10:0, Capt.
                        G. B. Byme's Chinaman, 10.7, Ishak Bey Hussein's Fargh, 10.0, Mr. N.
                        Yoanovitch's Napo, 10.7.</p>
                    <p>FIFTH RACE, 1.30 p.m. THE PONY HANDICAP. Value P.T. 2,800, 2nd horse to
                        receive P.T. 800, and 3rd horse P.T. 200, out of the stakes. For Arab
                        ponies.. Distance 7 furlongs.-Ishak Bey Hussein's and Hassan Bey
                        Kheir-el-Din's Rais, Moharrem Pasba Chehin's Bibico, Saleh. Bey Inghen's
                        Ide.</p>
                    <p>. SIXTH RACE, 5 p.m., 3 BEDOUIN STAKES. Value P.T. 2,500, 2nd horse to
                        receive P. T. 300 and &amp;rd horse P.T. 200 out of the stakes. For Arabs
                        that have never won a race of any description. Open to all members and
                        non-members wbo do not keep maging horses. Catch weights over 10st | 7lbs.
                        for Horses, rost. for Galloways and 9st 7lbs. for Ponies. Those previously
                        placed in any race to carry 7lbs. extra. Distance 1 mile. Nouridin Effendi's
                        Nasseeb (late Peacock), Daoud Sultan's Murseel, Soliman Sultan's Hattem,
                        Mahboul Khourdar's Said and Sewiteo, Kharkour Elia's Kattarchorak, Moh.
                        Abdel Kalik Ramsi's Farhan (late Ayanit), Humberto Carrozzo'sGigia, Padgan
                        al-Dabawi's Minsbar and Yakzan..</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL SPORTING CLUB.</p>
                    <p>3rd WINTER MBETING. - The Kasr, al-Nil Steeplechase will be a Handicap and
                        not as advertised.</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</p>
                    <p>The annual general meeting of the Khedi: vial Yacht Club will be held at the
                        Khedivial Club, Alexandra, ou the 27th inst</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The King has been pleseed to give and grant unto Robert Lang Anderson, Faq.,
                        Manager of the Aboukir Landa Reclamation Company, His Majesty's Royal
                        licence and authority that he may accept and wear the Insignia of the Third
                        Class of the Imperial | Ottoman Order of the Osmanish, conferred | upon him
                        by H.H. the Khedive of Bgypt, authorised by H.I.M. the Sultan of Turkey, in
                        recognition of valuable services rendered by him to His Highness.</p>
                    <p>Colonel and Mrs. C. Roadew Barn have left for Egypt, and will join the yacht
                        "Miranda" at the end of March. They do not expect to returú till May.</p>
                    <p>Baron Angust Twickl is leaving Rome this week for Egypt.</p>
                    <p>The marriage arranged between M. Henry Thierrard and Mélita, danghter of M.
                        and Mme. S. Caffari, will take place at St. Catherine's Cathedral,
                        Alexandria, on Saturday, 18th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to J. ELEURENT, I. MIGALLE Bolo Arant;</p>
                    <p>WINDSOR HOTEL:</p>
                    <p>Largest 1st Class and most comfortablo Hotel iz Alexandr fach Come position.
                        Onder Anglia 11-11-24</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n3/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOCIETE ANONYME DES MAISONS ECONOMIQUES </head>
                    <p>Le Comité de défense des intérêts des loca taires vient de publier les
                        statuts financiers de la future société anonyme des maisons éconc miques. En
                        voici les principales dispositions:--</p>
                    <p>La Società Anonima delle Case Economiche sura son siège à Alexandrie. La
                        durée de l Société est fixés à trente ans, mais cette pé riode pourra être
                        renouvelée.</p>
                    <p>Le capital social sera de 200,000 L.B. divisées en 50,000 actions de 4 L.B.
                        chacune. L'émission se fera par souscription publique et au pair. Ce capital
                        pourra être augmenté par décision de l'assemblée générale.</p>
                    <p>Les titres ne deviendront transmissibles et au porteur qu'après leur paiement
                        intégral. La responsabilité de chaque actionnaire est limitée à la valeur
                        nominale des titres dont il est porteur.</p>
                    <p>Opérations de la société : Construction de maisons économiqus pour les
                        ouvriers et les employés, à quelque nationalité ou religion. qu'ils
                        appartiennent. Ces maisons devront être construites dans l'enceinte actuelle
                        de la ville.</p>
                    <p>Le conseil d'administration sera composé de 9 membres élus par l'assemblée
                        générale pour - une période de 3 ans: Ces membres seront ré- éligibles à
                        l'expiration de leur mandat. Chaque année on procédera au renouvellement
                        d'un tiers du conseil. Pour les deux premières années les sortants seront
                        fixés par le sort et les années suivantes par rang d'ancienneté. Chaque
                        administrateur devra mettre en dépôt dans la caisse de la société au moins
                        50 actions. Pour que le conseil puisse valablement délibérer, cinq membres
                        au moins devront être présents. Les décisions seront prises à la majorité
                        absolue des voix et en cas d'égalité de suffrages, la voix du président sera
                        prépondérante. Le conseil d'administration jouira des pouvoirs les plus
                        étendus: il nommera les employés, fixera leurs salaires, les révoquera,
                        établira les règle ments intérieurs, autorisera les contrats, los
                        transactions de toute sorte et les poursuites judiciaires, étudiera toutes
                        les propositions faits à la société, conférera des procurations et établira
                        le bilan. Bien que les membres du conseil ne contractent du fait de leur
                        gestion aucune obligation personnelle, ils seront, toutefois, responsables
                        de l'exécution du mand t qu'ils auront assumé.</p>
                    <p>Chaque mois le Conseil d'Administration nommera dans son sein un
                        administrateur dé légué chargé de l'expédition des affaires courantes et de
                        l'exécution des décisions prises par le conseil. Il représenters, en outre,
                        la société vis à vis des tiers et en justice.</p>
                    <p>Le Gouvernement Egyptien aura la faculté de nommer un commissaire
                        gouvernemental pour faire partie du Conseil d'Administration et exercer sur
                        les comptes un contrôle minutieux. De plus le Ministre des Finances pourra
                        nommer tous les ans un délégué pour vérifier le bilan et la comptabilité et
                        dresser un rap. port détaillé qui sera soumis aux actionnaires à l'assemblée
                        générale.</p>
                    <p>Une assemblée générale aura lieu chaque année et toutes les fois que le
                        conseil d'Administration le jugera nécessaire. Tout actionnaite porteur de
                        10 actions aura droit à un seal vote jusqu'à un maximum de 10 voix. Ce
                        chiffre ne pourra jamais être dépassé, quelque soit le nombre de titres dont
                        l'actionnaire est détenteur.</p>
                    <p>Le prix de location ne devra en aucun cas dépasser le 7% du coût de
                        l'immeuble. Le 7% sera donel'intérêt brut accordéaux actionnaires De ce taux
                        il faudra déduire les frais d'adminis tration et du fonds de réserve. Dans
                        le cas où les appartements ne suffiraient pas à la demande,un comité formé
                        du président du conseil ou d'un administrateur délégué et du commissaire
                        gouvernemental feront choix des personnes les plus dignes d'intérêt. En cas
                        de conflit le conseil se prononcera en dernier ressort Les locataires et le
                        conseil d'administration devront pour tous différends, avant de recourir aux
                        tribunaux, s'en référér à l'arbitrage du commissaire gouvernemental.</p>
                    <p>La répartition des bénéfices se fera de la manière suivante: 1° impôts et
                        frais d'administration, 2 Entretien des immeubles, 3 Après les deux
                        prélèvements ci-dessus, 5% pour le fonds de réserve. 4° 5% au conseil
                        d'administration. 5 émoluments du cominissaire gouvernemental et du délégué
                        du Ministre des Finances à fixer par le Conseil d'Ad ministration. Après
                        libération des cinq charges qui viennent d'être énumérées, les bénéfices
                        restants formeront le dividende net des actionnaires.</p>
                    <p>La fonds de réserve sera capitalisé au fur et à mesure et consacré à la
                        construction de nouvelles maisons économiques dont l'intérêt sera versé aux
                        actionnaires. En cas de liquidation. de la société, le capital du fonds de
                        réserve fera retour aux actionnaires, après extinction des dettes de la
                        "Società Anonima delle Case Economiche."</p>
                    <p>Si pour une cause on pour une autre, le fonds de réserve venait à être épuisé
                        et le capital versé réduit aux 3/4, l'assemblée généralo serait
                        immédiatement convoquée pour voir s'il. y a lieu de liquider la société ou
                        d'en modifier les statuts. Les seuls tribunaux compétents en cas de conflit
                        seront les tribunaux mixtes. Le conseil d'administration actuel restera en
                        fonction jusqu'à l'assemblée générale de 1906. qui procèdera au
                        renouvellement de 4 membres.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER</head>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>PEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY N.B.-Inferior Brands now being
                        offered to Mar star of ourmin good coreles. Beware of evilly disposed
                        competitors running down this very BUPERIOR BRAND OF Bean</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer,</p>
                    <p>&amp; HOTEL COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF COEDS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO Three Sallings
                        a-Wook.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:-</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LO.</p>
                    <p>81.10 904</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LE SCANDALE ALEXANDRIN.</head>
                    <p>Le Tribunal Consulaire d'Italie de notre ville a rendu le 13 et. son jugement
                        dans le procès en séparation intenté par M. A. Ninci à sa femme, Mme Olga
                        Constantinidis, pour, adultère avec le juge Constantin Dimaras, ex-président
                        du Tribunal Consulaire et de la Cour d'Assi ses helléniques
                        d'Alexandrie.</p>
                    <p>Hatons-nous de dire que ce jugement donne à M. Ninci l'entière et légitime
                        satisfaction à laquelle il avait droit.</p>
                    <p>Le Tribunal a prononcé la séparation aux torts de Mme Olga Constantinidis
                        pour adultère; il a fixé à P.T. 25 par jour la pension alimentaire à
                        laquelle avait droit la défenderesse et a condamné cette dernière à tous les
                        dépens, y compris les honoraires de Me Mario Colucci,avocat de M. Ninci.</p>
                    <p>Nous publierons prochainement le jugement in-extenso.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <p>Municipalit Alexandri</p>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p>La Municipalité met en adjudication les travaux de dallage des rues
                        Moussaferkana, El Helal et Sidi Daoud, et de deux ruelles près: du
                        Mawazini.</p>
                    <p>Le cautionnement est fixé à LE 40.</p>
                    <p>Le cahier des charges est déposé au bureau de la Voirie où il peut être
                        consulté par les intéressés tous les jours de 9 h. à midi, les jours fériés
                        exceptés.</p>
                    <p>Les offres devront être adressées sous pli cacheté à Monsieur
                        l'Administrateur de la Municipalité avant le 28 courant.</p>
                    <p>Elles pourront également être déposées en séance de la Délégation le même
                        jour à 5b.p.m. L'enveloppe devra porter en outre la mention: "Soumission
                        pour dallage rues Moussaferkana eto."</p>
                    <p>Le cautionnement ou le reçu d'une Banque, d'après les conditions du cahier
                        des charges, devra être remis au Service de la Comptabilité avant
                        l'ouverture des offres et au plus tard le 28 février à midi.</p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur, (Signé) W. P. CHATAWAY</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 11 février 1905.</p>
                    <p>25435-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AVIS</head>

                    <p>Le Mardi 21 février courant de 11 h. a.m. à 1 h. p.m. et de 3h. au coucher du
                        soleil, la Municipalité procèdera à la vente aux enchères publiques près des
                        cimetières européens, sis à la Porte Kosette, d'une quantité de 2000 m3.
                        environ des pierres extraites des terrains des fortifications divisée en
                        lots de 40 à 100 m3.</p>
                    <p>Les acheteurs devront payer le droit d'enchère de 1% et déposer le 10% de la
                        valeur de la marchandise achetée au moment de la vente et effectuer le
                        paiement intégral à la Caisse Municipale le lendemain du jour de
                        l'adjudication.</p>
                    <p>Ils auront à supporter les droits de carrière au profit de la Ville et
                        devront enlever les pierres achetées dans un délai de dix jours, sous peine
                        de folle euchère pour compte de l'adjudicataire.</p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur, (Signé) W. P. CHATAWAY</p>
                    <p>Alexandrie, le 11 février 1905.</p>
                    <p>25436-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Metropolitan &amp; Cairo-Helouan Railway.</p>
                    <p>NOTICE is hereby given to the holders of the above shares that they may now
                        be exchanged for 5% Cumulative Preference Shares of the Egyptian Delta Light
                        Railways in the ratio of:</p>
                    <p>Two Preference Shares of the Egyptian Delta Light Railways for One Share of
                        the Cairo-Helouan Railway.</p>
                    <p>and Two Preference Shares of the Egyptian Delta Light Railways for 5 "Actions
                        de Jouissance" of the Cairo-Helouan Railway. Coupon H for arrears of
                        interest will be delivered along with the new shares. Holders of the
                        Cairo-Helouan Railway Co. shares are requested to lodge their Bearer
                        Warrants with the National Bank of Egypt, Cairo or Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>25441-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="shippingMovements">
                    <head>MOUVEMENT MARITIME</head>
                    <p>DU PORT D'ALEXANDRIE</p>
                    <p>ARRIVEES</p>
                    <p>13 février</p>
                    <p>Trieste et Brindisi ; 60 h., vap. autr. Cleopatra,</p>
                    <p>cap. Jochich, ton. 2,132, au Lloyd Autr. Liverpool et Malte; 3 j. 3/4, vap.
                        ang. City of Cambridge, cap, Walke, ton. 2,481, à Barker &amp; Co.
                        Trébizonde et Pirée; 2 j. 1/2, vap. ottoman Alexandros, cap. Pittas, tou.
                        717, à Ismiridi, Larnaque et Port-Saïd ; 20 h., vap. ang. Bear, cap.
                        MacMahon, ton. 363, à Minotto. Trieste et Port-Saïd; 19 h., vap. autrichien
                        Carniolia, cap. Marassi, ton. 1,731, au Lloyd</p>
                    <p>Autrichien.</p>
                    <p>Syrie et Port-Said; 20 h., vap. ital. Nina, cap.</p>
                    <p>Vicari, ton. 791, à Diab.</p>
                    <p>Marseille et Naples; 67 h., vap. all. Hohen zollern, cap. Pesvh, ton. 3,320,
                        à Schoeller. Syrie et Port Said: 20 h., vap. ott. Garcia, cap. Botterini,
                        ton. 751, à M. Sono. Bengasi et Dernah; 2j, vap. ang. Dundee, cap. Ruggier,
                        ton. 304, à Miladi.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTS</p>
                    <p>13 février</p>
                    <p>Port-Said et Odessa; vap. autr. Styria, cap.</p>
                    <p>Burgstaller. Malte et Liverpool; vap. ang. Menes, capitaine Angleterre; vap.
                        ang. Barcelona, cap. Arnold.</p>
                    <p>P. Crook.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item" feature="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <p>ARRIVALS.</p>
                    <p>Per 8.8. "Hohenzollern", arrived at Alexandria yesterday from Marseilles and
                        Naples:-</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Chas. I. Ackermann, Mr. S. Agvadias, Mr. W. Baumann, Mr. J.
                        Burnaby- Atkins, Baron Bassus, Mlle Sophia Curtis, Mr. Cotta, Mrs. E. David,
                        Miss A. M. Field, Mr. de Gobbart, Mr. and Mme Morris Meyerfeld, Mlle Leslie
                        Meyerfeld, Mr. and Mme P. Mouchot, Mr. and Mme Du Moncean, Mr. and Mme
                        Oppenheim, Mlle Oppenhein, Mr. C. H. Olirerson, Mr. and Mrs. O. Ochs, Mr.
                        Paine, Mrs. Pennington, Mr. H. Roger, Miss Agnes Shaw, Mme 8. B. Schloss,
                        Consul Léopold Stoube, Mlle Marguerite Stoube, Mr. and Mme Schneider, Comte
                        and Comtesse Gustave Salles, Baron Oscar de Tessin, Mme Denard and son, Mr.
                        Achille Edom, Mr. L. Wattecamps, Mr., Mme and Mlle Schrempp, Mr. and Mme
                        Consul Schriever, Mr. and Mme von Schaumburg, Mr. Walker, Mr. and Mrs. Hall,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Gramhalgh, Rittm. Freiherr v. Meyera-Hobenberg, Com.-Rath and
                        Mme Richter, Mr. Butler, Mlle Durand, Mr. Atkinson, Mrs. Underwood, Miss
                        Lyell, Rev. C. Bourke, Mr. Thompson, Miss E. Law, Mme Bertha Meyer Miss R.
                        Maddon, Mr. H. H. Eliel, Mr. and Mme H. Sutermeister, Mr. and Mme A.
                        Pülvermann, Mr. and Mme L. Hausmann and son, Mr. Johannes Ruperti, Mr. Cav.
                        P. Picardo, Consul Dr. Edm. Rhomberg.</p>
                    <p>Per Moss 8.8. "Rameses," arrived on Saturday from Liverpool, via Gibraltar
                        and Malta: Mr. and Mrs. H. McLaren, Mrs. Davenport, Mr. J. Eastwood, Mr. W.
                        Graham, Mrs. Hopkinson, Miss G. C. Trotter, Mr. J. Hartley, Count De Berims,
                        Mrs. Reid, Miss Symington, Mr. Swanson, Mr. A. B. Mee, Mr. F. Feller, Miss
                        Feller, Mr. I. Sadoch, Miss Mac Master, Mrs. Baker, Corpl. Crook, Mr.
                        Robso.</p>
                    <p>Per S.S. "City of Cambridge," arrived yester day from Liverpool:-</p>
                    <p>Dr. J. St. Clair Boyd, Dr. E. Purdow, Mrs. Bell and son, Mr. and Mrs.
                        Hargreaves, Mrs. Colver, Mr. F. E. Thew, Mr. A. Lamplough, Mr. A. Ireatön,
                        Mr. T. Taylor, Mr. J. Tonge, Mr. J. Butterworth, Mr. W. Brierley, Mr. W.
                        Cunliffe, Mr. J. Smith, Mr. J. G. Wagstaff, Mr. W. V. Thompson, Mr. J.
                        Mitchell, Mr. C. Smith, Mr. W. Graesbeck, Mr. R. Nessler, Mr. C. Gregs.</p>
                    <p>Le paq. "Cleopatra" du Lloyd Autrichien arrivé hier de Trieste avait à
                        bord:</p>
                    <p>MM. Agosti, M. et Mme Walter, Mme Pergy, M. et Mme Schoen, M. et Mme Van de
                        Velde, Laredo, M. et Mme A. Dresing, Chivalla, Knobloch, Douglas Cox et 2
                        comp., de Colle et sa sœur, M. et Mme Baeckel, Wildberg, Hocholkoch,
                        Liebermann, Bredt, Brendel et son fils, MmeWagner, M. et Mme Lansay, Mme
                        Neef, Mme Stocker, M. et Mme Thorsch, M. et Mme Taussig, M. Schaffer, M. le
                        comte Solnes, M. et Mme Litten, prot. Frankel, M. et Mme Kalkreuth, M. et
                        Mme Progler, de Sebestyan, Dr. Neubeck et Mile Neubeck, Mandel, Steger, M.
                        et Mme Subak, Tauschinski, M. et Mme Schonka, M. et Mme Bushbeck, M et Mme
                        Paterson, M. et Mme Young, le prince Ottinger, Kendel, Mme Henke, Kaderarek,
                        Agopian et 36 passagers de 3e classe.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Perseo" de la Cie. Florio Rubattino arrivé hier de Gênes avait à
                        bord : MM. De Castello et famille, F. Allen, D. O'Callaghan, N. Murphy, J.
                        Mosterson, Feeling, Razdwill, Mendescky, Baja, Aritzia et fam., C. Cooson,
                        Uddembrig, A. Tusan, E. Borsa, Littert, M. et Mme Edwin Schmidt Robillior,
                        Mlle Kaethe Roth, Kiamil, Ulrich, Walter et 22 passagers de 3e classe.</p>
                    <p>Le paquebot "Sénégal" des Messageries Maritimes arrivé ce matin de Marseille,
                        avait à bord:</p>
                    <p>M. John Fullock, Mme Givoy, M. Fontaine, M. A. Waddington, Mme Berry, Rév.
                        Berry, Cte et Ctesse de Giroudi, Mme N. Kalouniris, M. Kalouniris, Mr.
                        Lavielle, M. Andony, M. Salomon, M. Duval, Mme Guetand, M. de la Grondière,
                        M. Harbotte, Sir Walter Mieville, MM. Tavernier et Balmont, M. Grillaut des
                        Fontaines, M. Gottlself, M. John Oxford Donorand, M. Antomarchi, Mlle Liane
                        de Volney, Mme Gérard, M. Miconnet, Mme Barthet, M. Dewail, M. Wallet, R. P.
                        Sullivan et Daull, et 11 passagers de 3e et 4e classes.</p>
                    <p>DEPARTURES.</p>
                    <p>Le paq. "Semiramis" du Lloyd Autrichien parti samedi pour Trieste avait à
                        bord. MM. W. de Nikorovitch, T. de Florkowski, A. Frey, M. et Mme Peters,
                        Girardelli, W. F. Fuld, von Hemert, Dr. Kuffler, Mme Ida de Farkas, chev. de
                        Rappord, Col. Gratton, N. Smulders, baronne Reinlein, A. Philipp, Knopt, Mme
                        Prieste, M. et Mme H. Quandt, Dr. A. Pregel, E. Bonnet et son fils, M. et
                        Mme Dib, F. Kohn, M. et Mme Isacievicz, Maria Ton, Mlle M. Zinatelli, M.
                        Mertens, Mme R. Zerneck, David Schild, Mlle Schild, Oscar Rausch, Benvaidt,
                        J. Kredens, Antonietta Vittoria et 7 passagers de 3e classe.</p>
                    <p>Per Moss S.S. "Menes," sailed yesterday for Malta and Liverpool :-</p>
                    <p>Mr. MacPhail, Mr. and Mrs. J. R. Mandsley, Mr. J. Adamson, Miss M. Adamson,
                        Mr. A. Adamson, Miss Lunn, Mr. J. Hewison, Mr. N, Giovanni, Mr. P.
                        Skevofilaks, Mr. A. Zammit, and 6 deck passengers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Menes" sailed yesterday</p>
                    <p>afternoon for Liverpool, via Malta, with passengers, mails, and general
                        cargo, including 4,850 bales cotton.</p>
                    <p>The Ellerman 8.8. "Anatolia" arrived at Liverpool from Alexandhia on Friday
                        morning. The Westcott S.S." Perim" arrived here on Sunday evening from
                        Antwerp, London, and Malta, with general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The Westcott 8.8. "Barcelona" sailed yester day evening hence direct for
                        England with full cargo of cottonseed.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item" feature="comingEvents">
                    <p>Calendar of Coming Events</p>
                    <p>February.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Tues. 14 New Masonic Hall. Zetland Lodge</p>
                    <p>1157 E.C. Installation. 7.30 p.m. Zizinia Theatre. French Comedy Company in
                        Les Trois Anabap tistes. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 15 Moharrem Bey Common. New Ground. St. Andrew Football</p>
                    <p>Club v. Band 2nd R. Berks.Kickoff 3 p.m.</p>
                    <p>New Masonic Hall. Zetland Lodge 1157 B.C. Emergency Meeting. 7.30 p.m.
                        followed by banquet. Khedivial Club. General meeting of A.S.C. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Abbas Helmy Theatre.</p>
                    <p>Italian</p>
                    <p>Opera Company in The Barber</p>
                    <p>of Seville. 9.15 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 16 H. M.'s Consulate. Ordinary An-</p>
                    <p>Fri. 17</p>
                    <p>Sat. 18</p>
                    <p>Fri. 24</p>
                    <p>Sat. 25</p>
                    <p>February.</p>
                    <p>nual General Meeting St. Mark's Church Voters. 5 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Alderson's Garden. Variety Entertainment. 4 p.m.</p>
                    <p>New Khedivial Hotel. Recital by Fitzner Quatuor. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Monferrato's Hall. Germania Lodge's Charity Ball. 9 p.m.. New Khedivial
                        Hotel. Recital by Fitzner Quatuor. 9 p.m. Cercle Mohamed Aly. Ball. 10
                        p.m.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Tues. 14 GhezirehAgricultural Show. Khedivial Opera House. Italian Opera
                        Company in Gioconda.</p>
                    <p>Wed. 15</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 16</p>
                    <p>9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Verdi Theatre. Italian Operetta Company. 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Theatre des Nouveautés. Variety Entertainment. 9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Trocadero. Variety Entertainment.</p>
                    <p>9.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Military Tournament.</p>
                    <p>Railway Institute. Opening of Foot-</p>
                    <p>ball Competition.</p>
                    <p>Mena House. Gymkhana.</p>
                    <p>Ghezireh. Cricket. Cairo . Alex-</p>
                    <p>andria.</p>
                    <p>Ghezireh Palace Hotel. Small</p>
                    <p>Dance 10 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Fri. 17</p>
                    <p>Helouan. Third Winter Race</p>
                    <p>Sat. 18</p>
                    <p>Meeting. 2.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Zoological Gardens. Performance by Ghizeh Boys' Band in afternoon. Khedivial
                        Opera House. "Pirates of Penzance." 9 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Verdi Theatre. Tradesmen's Ball.</p>
                    <p>10 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Ghezireh. K.S.C. Horse Show. Shepheard's Hotel. Band Royal Inniskilling
                        Fusiliers. 4 to 6 p.m. Savoy Hotel. Small Dance. 10 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Mon. 20 Agricultural Bank. Annual general</p>
                    <p>Tues. 21</p>
                    <p>Wed. 22</p>
                    <p>Fri. 24</p>
                    <p>meeting. 3 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Shepheard's Hotel. Small Dance. Savoy Hotel. Austro-Hungarian</p>
                    <p>Ball.</p>
                    <p>K.S.C. Third Winter Race Meeting.</p>
                    <p>Thurs. 23 Ghezireh Casino. Grand Ball. K.S.C. Third Winter Race Meeting.
                        Shoubra. Trials of Steam-ploughing Machines.</p>
                    <p>Tues. 28</p>
                    <p>March..</p>
                    <p>Esbekieh Garden. French Benevolent Society's Ball.</p>
                    <p>Y.W.C.A. Rooms. Concert under the patronage of Lady Cromer.</p>
                    <p>3.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Tues. 7 Savoy Hotel, Bal Poudré et Cos-</p>
                    <p>tumé.</p>
                    <p>Ghezireh Casino. Bal Poudré et Costumé.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>BRITISH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE-We would call the attention of persons interested
                        in: Egyptian trade to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt,
                        whose office in Alexandria gives information as to standings, trade,
                        &amp;c., to its members, and whose monthly publication reviews our commerce.
                        The annual subscription is £1 and all British traders should become members.
                        Our London office, 36, New Broad-street EC., acts as London agency to the
                        Chamber.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>TENDERS are invited for supplying GROCERIES to the Garrison Institute,
                        Citadel, for a period of six months commencing 1st April, 1905. All tenders
                        and samples to be delivered to the President, Garrison Institute, Citadel,
                        by 12 noon the 15th of March. Tender forms can be obtained on application to
                        the President. 25423-3-3</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SALE OF MULES.</head>
                    <p>Messrs. Mieli &amp; Della Torre, Auctioneers, have been instructed to sell by
                        Public Auction 50 mules the property of the Army of Occupa tion. The Sale
                        will be held at Sharia Bab-el-Khalk, near the Egyptian Gouvernorat on
                        Thursday the 16th inst. commencing at 9 a.m.</p>
                    <p>By order, ARTHUR COLVILLE, Colonel, Chief Staff Officer.</p>
                    <p>Cairo, 11 February 1905.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE.</head>
                    <p>25432-3-2</p>
                    <p>THE CHAMBERS of Mr. J. Norton</p>
                    <p>Kyabe, Barrister-at-Law, are situated at Maison Spiro, first floor, opposite
                        the Savoy Hotel, Kaar-el-Nil, Cairo, 25346-6A-6</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GUNNY BAG MARKET.</head>
                    <p>SHVOR BROS. CALCUTTA MARKET REPORT</p>
                    <p>The e continues an absence of buying orders from the UK. and Continent at
                        current values, bu airly large basinc has a ga'n boen put the gh for the
                        Straits and China, as also for lol require nents, at full rates, and the
                        tendency of the market is still in favor of sellors.</p>
                    <p>Spenat rs have been confining their atten tiva to purchases for July/Decr.
                        deliveries, cusest values for which afford more room for a rice at with
                        quite stiff prices alrevly being aske 1 for loos jute for next season, wills
                        as a rule are against forward sales.</p>
                    <p>HESSIANS'are steady and higher prices have been paid for brau bags and whest
                        pockets Bleven.porter cloth in speculators hands is the only factor which
                        checks extensive buying tor later deliveries, and is apparently keeping
                        consumers back with their buying orders. The lighter texture is source and
                        in better demand. Privat: advices from Dundee point to a not unlikely
                        falling off in the pro luotion there for the next few months, values of
                        baled jute available, which will market.</p>
                    <p>We quote:-</p>
                    <p>consequent on the high and the small supplies doubtless react on this</p>
                    <p>Grain Sacks 60x 10 8x95lbs.</p>
                    <p>c.l.f. Sdes 20/ Freight. Feby/June</p>
                    <p>a.i.f-Port Said 234 Freight Feby June</p>
                    <p>Bagar Bag</p>
                    <p>TRAI</p>
                    <p>Onion Pockets</p>
                    <p>B. Twills 44x38) 1 lb.</p>
                    <p>Cotton Packs Px10 3lbs.</p>
                    <p>1 x 13.</p>
                    <p>Lo</p>
                    <p>630</p>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:id="deg-el-etcl01" status="templateDefault">
                    <head>EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO. LTD.</head>
                    <p>AVERAGE TIME occupied in transmission of Egyptian telegrams from England to
                        Alexandria on <date when="1905-07-11">Tuesday, 11th July, 1905</date>. </p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS.</p>
                    <p>Between the hours of 10 a.m. and 6 p.m. (Cairo time)</p>
                    <table rows="6" cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-etcl01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell rows="2">FROM</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">MESSAGES HANDED IN AT</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>The Company's Offices. H. M.</cell>
                            <cell>Postal Telegraph Offices. H. M.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>London</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Liverpool</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Manchester</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Glasgow</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Other Provincial Offices</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" feature="cottonContracts" xml:id="deg-el-ctns01"
                    status="templateDefault">
                    <head>COTONS</head>
                    <p>copie de la dépêche</p>
                    <p>DE L'ALEXANDRIA GENERAL PRODUCE ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>à la</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL COTTON ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khédiviale à 9h. 45 a.m.) </p>
                    <table rows="4" cols="4" xml:id="deg-ta-ctns01">
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 7/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Livraison</cell>
                            <cell>Juillet</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">15 3/16</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Août</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 23/32</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Novembre</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 5/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Janvier</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Marché ferme</p>
                    <p>Arrivages de ce jour, à Minet-el-Bassal, cantars <measure unit="cantar"
                            >1008</measure></p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khédiviale à 12h. 45 p.m.)</p>
                    <table rows="4" cols="4" xml:id="deg-ta-ctns02">
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 15/16</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Livraison</cell>
                            <cell>Juillet</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">15 1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Août</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 7/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Novembre</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 25/32</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell>Janvier</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Marché ferme </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CLOTURE</head>
                    <p>DE LA</p>
                    <p>BOURSE KHEDIVIALE</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS</p>
                    <p>Cours de l'Association des Courtiers en</p>
                    <p>Marchandises</p>
                    <p>Novembre...N.R. Tal. 11 13/16 à</p>
                    <p>6h. p.m.</p>
                    <p>27/32</p>
                    <p>Mars</p>
                    <p>22</p>
                    <p>Mai</p>
                    <p>33</p>
                    <p>12 25/32 .. 12 17/32</p>
                    <p>13/16</p>
                    <p>Juillet...</p>
                    <p>12 7/16</p>
                    <p>9/16 15/32</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton</p>
                    <p>N.-D.-J. ...N.R. P.T. 56 25/40 à</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Février Mars.</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>55 25/40</p>
                    <p>Avril ...</p>
                    <p>22</p>
                    <p>56 20/40</p>
                    <p>Mai</p>
                    <p>57. 10/40,</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>30/40 30/40 25/40 15/40</p>
                    <p>à 79</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>74</p>
                    <p>***</p>
                    <p>Feves-Saidi</p>
                    <p>Sept.-Oct, ...N.R. P.T. 78</p>
                    <p>Février Mars.</p>
                    <p>73</p>
                    <p>REMARQUES</p>
                    <p>Coton.-Nouvelle récolte: Très peu d'affaires dans l'après midi sur cette
                        échéance; toutefois,</p>
                    <p>le maintien n'est pas mauvais.</p>
                    <p>Récolte actuelle: Pas beaucoup d'entrain dans l'après-midi et clôture
                        légèrement faible. Les dispositious du marché sont pourtant tou jours
                        bonnes.</p>
                    <p>Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour mars tal. 13 1/32 à ; plus bas pour mar
                        12 3/4 à Dans l'après-midi prix plus haut pour mars 12 13/16 à--; plus bas
                        pour mars 12 3/4 à-- N.B.-Les autres livraisons avec reports
                        irréguliers.</p>
                    <p>Au moment de la clôture les nouvelles étaient les suivantes:</p>
                    <p>Liverpool coton égyptien disponible, Bearrés: 1/16 de hausse. Futurs mars: 6
                        31/64 8 point-</p>
                    <p>de hausse. Liverpool: coton américain: Futurs mar avril: 4.01 8 points de
                        hausse. Futurs mai juin: 4.06-9 points de hausse</p>
                    <p>New-York: cot. amér.: Futurs mars: Marché mai: fermé</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton.-Nouvelle récolte: Marché</p>
                    <p>très calme et affaires rares.</p>
                    <p>Récolte actuelle: Le marché a été faible dans l'après-midi et les cours
                        tendent à baisser davantage. Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour février</p>
                    <p>mars P.T. 56 20/40 à-/-; plus bas pour février-mars P.T. 55 25/40-1-. Dans
                        l'après-midi, prix plus haut février-mars P.T. 56-/-/-; plus bas pour
                        février mars</p>
                    <p>P.T. 55 25/40 -/- NB-Les autres livraisons avec reports irréguliers.
                        Foes-Saidi-Nouvelle récolte: Marché nul Récolte actuelle: Cours nominaux
                        Alexandrie, le 18 février 1905,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-el-mmeb01" status="templateDefault">
                    <head>MARCHE DE MINET-EL-BASSAL</head>
                    <dateline><date when="1905-02-14">14 février 1905</date>.—(11h.55
                        a.m.)</dateline>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Cotons</hi> —Clôture du marché du <date when="1905-07-11"
                            >13 février</date>: Marché sans affaires. </p>
                    <table cols="6" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="6">BEURRES</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">12 1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">5/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">13 1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14 1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">3/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">15 1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">3/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">16</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">3/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="6">HAUTE-EGYPTE ET FAYOUM</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">11</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">11 3/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">12 1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">13</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good,</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">13 3/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="6">ABASSI</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">14</measure> à <measure unit="tal">14
                                    1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good,</cell>
                            <cell>tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">15 1/2</measure> à <measure unit="tal"
                                    >16</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">3/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Extra,</cell>
                            <cell>tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">16 3/4</measure> à <measure unit="tal"
                                    >17</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">3/8</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="6">IANNOVICH</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fully Good Fair,</cell>
                            <cell>Tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">15 1/4</measure> à <measure unit="tal">15
                                    1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Good,</cell>
                            <cell>tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">16</measure> à <measure unit="tal">16
                                    1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Extra,</cell>
                            <cell>tal.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">17</measure> à <measure unit="tal">17
                                    1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>soit</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="tal">1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>de hausse</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-el-extr01" status="templateDefault">
                    <head>Exterieur</head>
                    <p>Dépêches particulières du <date when="1905-07-11">11 juillet 1905</date></p>
                    <p>PRODUITS EGYPTIENS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Coton: Etat du Marché</hi>.—Soutenu</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Disp</hi>..— F.G.F.: <measure unit="£">7 7/8</measure>
                        (sans changement)</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Futurs</hi> Juillet :<measure unit="£">7 52/64</measure>
                        (6/64 point de hausse)</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Graines de coton</hi>.—Soutenues</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Fèves</hi> — Fermes</p>
                    <p>HULL</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Graines de coton</hi>.—Calmes, sans changement</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Fèves</hi>.—Soutenues</p>
                    <p>LONDRES</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Graines de coton</hi>.— Sans changement</p>
                    <p>COTON AMÉRICAIN</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL</p>
                    <p>Futurs août-sept.: <measure unit="$">5.90</measure> (15 points de baisse)</p>
                    <p>" oct-nov.: <measure unit="$">5.92</measure> (13 points de baisse)</p>
                    <p>Disponible : <measure unit="$">6.12</measure> (11 points de hausse)</p>
                    <p>NEW-YORK</p>
                    <p>Middling Upland: <measure unit="$">11.00</measure> (30 points de hausse)</p>
                    <p>Futurs août: <measure unit="$">10.82</measure> (24 points de busse)</p>
                    <p>" oct. : <measure unit="$">10.96</measure> (24 points de baisse)</p>
                    <p>Arrivages du jour, balles <measure unit="balles">22,000</measure></p>
                    <p>Contre même jour, l'année dernière, balles <measure unit="balles"
                            >1,800</measure></p>
                </div>
                <!-- alex ramleh -->
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" feature="stocksShares" xml:id="deg-el-teha01"
                    status="templateDefault">
                    <head>TELEGRAMME HAVAS</head>
                    <dateline>BOURSE du <date when="1905-07-11">11 juillet 1905</date></dateline>
                    <p>COURS DES VALEURS A TERMS, CLOTURE</p>
                    <table cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-teha01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="3">PARIS</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rente Française 3 %</cell>
                            <cell>Fr.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">99 17</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Actions de Suez</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">4440 –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lots Turcs</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">132 5-</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Turc Unifié</cell>
                            <cell>" </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">89 20</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dette Egyptienne Unifié</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">107 40</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Daïra Sanieh</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">102 –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Crédit Foncier Egyptien</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">840 –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Extérieur espagnol</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">90 47</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Obl. Banque Nat. de Grèce</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">428 –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Banque d'Athènes, nouvelles actions</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">124 ½</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Métropolitain</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">– –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Russe consolidé</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">85 60</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sosnowice</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">– –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Change sur Londres</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">25 15 ½</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sucre No 3 disponible</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">– –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sucre No 3 livrable le 4 de mars</cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">– –</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="3">LONDRES</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Consolidés anglais</cell>
                            <cell>£</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="£">90 ¼</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Escomptes---Paris <measure>3</measure>, Londres <measure>2 ½</measure>,
                        Berlin <measure>3</measure>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" feature="cottonContracts" xml:id="deg-el-pdco01"
                    status="templateDefault">
                    <head>PRIMES DES CONTRATS</head>
                    <table cols="6" xml:id="deg-ta-pdco01">
                        <row>
                            <cell role="label" cols="6">"SIMPLE FACULTE"</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coton</cell>
                            <cell>Liv. Nov.</cell>
                            <cell>P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">16 1/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">17 1/2</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gr. de cot.</cell>
                            <cell>,, 3 mois</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">2 20/40</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">2 30/40</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell role="label" cols="6">"STELLAGE”</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coton</cell>
                            <cell>Liv. Nov.</cell>
                            <cell>P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">32 1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">35 —</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gr. de cot.</cell>
                            <cell>,, 3 mois</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">5 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">5 1/4</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell role="label" cols="6">"DOUBLE"</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coton</cell>
                            <cell>Liv. Nov.</cell>
                            <cell>P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">10 25/40</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">11 35/40</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gr. de cot.</cell>
                            <cell>,, 3 mois</cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">1 3/4</measure></cell>
                            <cell>,,</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">1 35/40</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <div type="template" xml:lang="fr" feature="cottonContracts" xml:id="deg-el-acms01"
                    status="templateDefault">
                    <head>ASSOCIATION DES COURTIERS EN MARCHANDISES</head>
                    <head type="sub">(Service spécial)</head>
                    <p>DÉPÊCHE D'OUVERTURE</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, 10h. a.m.</p>
                    <p>Américain</p>
                    <p>Futurs: août-sept. : <measure unit="$">5.85</measure></p>
                    <p>,, oct.-nov. : <measure unit="$">5.84</measure></p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n4/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>The Best Remedy for Delicate Children</p>
                    <p>It isreally wonderful how rapidly puny, delicate children gain in weight,
                        strength, and colour when they are given Angier's Emulsion systematically.
                        The reason is simple. By its effect upon nutrition, it enables the child to
                        get from his food all the good there is in it. It is therefore an ideal
                        "builder." The little ones all like the Emulsion and take it. with real
                        pleasure. Moreover it is perfectly simple and safe even for the most
                        delicate infants. Doctors préscribe, it for all wasting diseases of
                        children.</p>
                    <p>Ally LEUM WITH HYPOPHOSPHITES</p>
                    <p>In of themiss and Bazaars Avold imitations all of which ace made with
                        ordinary petroleum. Be sure to get Angier's. ANGIER CHEMICAL CO., LD.. 32
                        SNOW HILL, LONDON, ENG.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN MINISTERS.</head>
                    <p>Pharaoh" sends to the "Morning Post" from the Royal Societies Club the
                        following communication in favor of abolishing Egyp tian native, Ministers
                        and Under Secretaries of State</p>
                    <p>"Redde Caesari quae sunt Caesaris. Thanks to Great Britain, Egypt has entered
                        an era of prosperity aud wealth without precedent in her history. By the
                        improvement and by the development of the irrigation system tie fertility of
                        the Egyptian soil has been wonderfully increased, and large tracts of land
                        that a few years ago only could not be cultivated are now producing fine
                        crops. The railway system, which twenty years ago cousisted only in what was
                        deemed strictly necessary for the conveyance and the convenience of the
                        wealthier classes, covers now a considerable area, numer ous branch lines
                        have been laid, railway fares have been reduced, so that the transport by
                        rail has bee me easy, rapid, and cheap. With regard to trade, imports and
                        exports have attained a high figure, as shown by the customs revenues, which
                        are increasing from year to year. Companies have been formed for the working
                        of mines in Upper Egypt, other companies are busy with agriculture, others
                        are engaged in land speculations, foreign capital is pouring into the
                        country, business transactions are easy all over the land.</p>
                    <p>By mentioning thus the main and most striking features of the prosperity of
                        Egypt 1 merely intend to show the beneficial effects of the British
                        occupation; but the object of my letter comes hereafter. From the highest
                        official down to the humblest "fellah" every soul in the Nile Valley knows
                        that the Egyptian Government is practically and exclusively exercis ed by
                        the representativeut Great Britain, who is himself represented in each
                        department by a British off cial, and that official is absolutely the sole
                        effective head of the department. It des not require ich phraseology to
                        enhance the advantages and the soundness of this state of things. Suffice it
                        to say that no intelligent, honest, and straightforward Egyptian would ever
                        dream of its change, especially if h remembers the gloomy days of the past.
                        Under these circumstalices, and since the Egyptia affairs are managed in the
                        right way by Briti-li officials as to ensure the welfare of the country and
                        its population, one is at a loss to under: stand the reason for having
                        native Ministers and Under Secretaries of State, wh, of utility whatever,
                        are, as shown in the following list, a yearly burden to the Egyptian Budget
                        of £E.23,000.</p>
                    <p>The Minister of the Interior...... L.E. 3,500) The Minister of Finance...</p>
                    <p>The Minister of Justice</p>
                    <p>The Minister for War</p>
                    <p>The Minister for Public Works and Public</p>
                    <p>Instruction...</p>
                    <p>3,000</p>
                    <p>3,000</p>
                    <p>3,000</p>
                    <p>3,000</p>
                    <p>The Under Secretary of State (Interior) 1,500</p>
                    <p>The Under Secretary of State (Justice) 1,500</p>
                    <p>The Under Secretary of State (Foreign</p>
                    <p>1,500</p>
                    <p>Affairs).... The Under Secretary of the War Office 1,500 The Under Secretary
                        for the Ministry of</p>
                    <p>Public Instruction ...</p>
                    <p>1,500</p>
                    <p>L.E. 23,000.</p>
                    <p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs has not been mentioned in the above list,
                        being the effective head of his department, where there is no British
                        official:</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VAL-DE-TRAVERS COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>The Val de Travers Company has been established at Alexandria for the past
                        three years, and under the able management of Mr. Mr. Miard it has obtained
                        a large number of local contracts. As an instance of the succes of the
                        company we culi the following para graph from a Calcutta contemporary of the
                        10th ulto.:Yesterday afternoon the Viceroy visited the portion of the Strand
                        road.opposite the point where the Val-de-Travers Company are laying their
                        asphalte. The Hon. R. T Greer, Chairman of the Corporation, Mr. W.B. McCabe,
                        Mr. C. A. Giannacopuloy the repre sentative of Messrs. Glastone, Wyllie and
                        Co., and the expert of the Val-de-Travers Com pany, Mr. Collaud, were
                        present. Considering the suitability of asphalte pavement for a city like
                        Calcutta, especially such portions a Barra Bazaar, it is hoped that the
                        Viceroy's interest in the matter is evidence of a move ment in the direction
                        of extending its use."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>THE CROWN PRESERVED COAL CO.T</head>
                    <p>Works and Shipping Ports:</p>
                    <p>Liverpool, 1984 CARDIFF cago 11 Highest</p>
                    <p>Jamaica, 1001</p>
                    <p>oden</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>Port Talbot. Manufacturers and Shippers of "CROWN FUEL</p>
                    <p>USED BY</p>
                    <p>Warships, and State and Colonial Rail</p>
                    <p>Tel, Address: CROWN, CARDIFF</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO AGRICULTURAL SHOW.</head>
                    <p>OPENING DAY.</p>
                    <p>At 2.30 p.m. yesterday, H.H. the Khedive augurated the Khedivial Agricultural
                        Society's Stew, which was favored by warm and quietweather, a bright sun and
                        last but not least -a great number of visitors. Besides the Khedive who
                        stayed for some time and took great interest in the numerons exhibits-nearly
                        all the representatives of the Powers, the Governor of Cairo, and several of
                        the Ministers were present, and with them almost all the principal members
                        of the Khedivial Agricultural Society. Among other visitors to the show we
                        noticed Mr. and Mrs. Graham, Mr. Anthony, Mrs. Hunter, the Hon. A. and Mrs.
                        Davey, Sir William and Lady Wille cks, Dainos Pasha, Mr. Allen, Mr. G. B.
                        Alderson, Mr. Sibbald, Milhem Shaoour Bey and Miss Chacour.</p>
                    <p>The exhibition presented a very animated, not to say exciting scene. Messrs.
                        Orenstein and Koppel's locomotive was running on the circular line of light
                        railway laid down in front of the central hall, pulling a number of trucks
                        and arousing the interest of numerous experts -and non-experts. All the
                        machinery erected in the sheds was at work-pumps, grain clean. ers,
                        decorticators, and diggers of every typeand the Cooper digger was showing
                        its paces, turning in a marvellously short circle and runuing at a good
                        speed on the roadway in front or the old sheds. In the central hall were the
                        exhibits of cotton, cereals and poultry, admirably arranged and attractive
                        exhibits. Another interesting feature, which we do not remember to have seen
                        in previous shows, was Boniteau Bey's collection of insect pests and
                        beneficial insects, the latter including one of the chief enemies of the
                        locusts, a large black "Sphex" resembling a huge and hirsute wasp. A case
                        containing locusts of the 1904 swarms in all stages from two hours' age to
                        maturity was very interesting.</p>
                    <p>The exhibits of cotton and cereals were extremely good, the poultry-Beladi
                        for the most part-made a good show, and there were any well-known names
                        among the prizewinners. In our next issue we will publish the lists of the
                        prizes and winners.</p>
                    <p>EXHIBITS REVIEWED.</p>
                    <p>The following is a description of the exhibits of Messrs. Thos. Cook &amp;
                        Son (Egypt) Ltd:- A Tangye's gas engine with suction producer plant, of 23
                        maximum B. H. P. The well-known arrangement of engine and plant combines the
                        following advantages: No steam boiler or gas holder is required, so that
                        there is no liability of explosion. It does not need onstant supervision,
                        but requires to be attended to only for a few minutes every three or four
                        hours. It occupies only a small amount of floor space and requires no
                        foundation. The apparatus may be fixed indoors as there is no more danger
                        from fire than with an ordinary stove. There is no risk of gas escaping, as
                        it is generated by suction and below atmospheric pressure. There is great
                        economy of fuel as cheap anthracite "peas" are used in the generator. It can
                        be re-started, after being shut down for an hour or so, in a few minutes,
                        and, even from a cold condition, from 15 to 20 minutes. Gas is generated
                        only as it is required by the engine. No gas is blown or burnt twaste on
                        light loads. It is smokeless and tree from smell. The fuel used, known as
                        "anthracite peas," can be obtained easily in Alexandria at a very cheap
                        rate. The fuel consumption does not exceed 0.9 lb. per B. H. P. per hour. On
                        six hours' continuous test of Tangye's gas engine developing 22 B. H. P.
                        working in conjunction with a "D" suction producer, the consumption of
                        anthra cite peas was found to be as low as 0.785 per B. H. P. per hour.</p>
                    <p>One Tangye's 10 B.H.P. portable oil engine is bolted on steel girder frame
                        and mounted on four travelling wheels, the two front wheels being carried by
                        a swivelling carriage for convenience in moving about. The engine is fitted
                        with a balanced crank shaft, oil splash guard, pressure pump, and oil
                        reservoir for supplying the lamps, extended cowl for protecting the
                        vaporiser and lamps from the weather, and a water circulating pump. A tank
                        of large capauity for holding the cooling water is carried on the girder
                        frame, and the water is forced through the jacket of the engine cylinder by
                        the circulating pump to a cooling chamber, where it meets a current of cold
                        air and after wards returns to the opposite end of the tank. The carriage is
                        fitted with shafts, it has slipper and chain for use when travelling down
                        hills, and a set of checks for fixing it in position when the engine is at
                        work.</p>
                    <p>One seamless steel launch. Each side is made all of one plate pressed into
                        shape by hydraulic pressure; all the plates are after wards galvanised,
                        which will give them a very long life against the action of the sea water.
                        It is fitted with a 10 B.H.P. petroleum engine. One Cooper patent steam
                        digger No. 5. Thi is an invention for cultivating all kinds of soil by steam
                        power. Briefly described, it consists of a machine which travels over the
                        land at a rate of from one to two miles an hour, forking up and turning over
                        the soil as it travelby means of a series of forks fixed on a rotating crank
                        in the rear of the machine. The depth to which these forks will enter the
                        soil is regulated by two shoes, which slide over the ground and allow the
                        digging ear to rise or sink with the inequalities of the surface. The
                        diggers are the result of experience gained in actual work during many years
                        under greatly varying conditions and in all kinds of lands, from the hardest
                        sun baked soil of South Africa and Egypt to the heaviest clay or lightest
                        sand of England Under all circumstances, they are now justify <cb n="3"/>ing
                        their claim to be the most efficient cultivators ever made. The work done is
                        similar to the best manual digging, the soil being taken up and exposed to
                        the influence of the air, sun, or frost, in a manner which can only be
                        equalled by carefully digging over every inch of land. Where deeprooted
                        weeds abound, the diggers are the only machines which can suscessfully deal
                        with them, pulling them to the surface instead of cutting the roots under
                        ground and leaving them to grow again.</p>
                    <p>A distinctive and important feature of the Cooper digger lies in the fact
                        that the power exerted in driving the forks into the land and turning the
                        soil, is also useful in an equal degree in lifting the weight of the engine
                        from the ground and propelling it forward. In all other methods of
                        mechanical cultivation, this power is absolutely lost, and even tends to
                        impede the engine. This cir cumstance explains the fact that the Cooper
                        Digger will break up lands to any given degree of fiueness with half the
                        consumption of coal and water of any machine on the market.</p>
                    <p>One of the greatest difficulties which have been met with in cultivating the
                        land with a travelling engine is the length of time wasted in turning at the
                        headlands. In some cases the engines have to be disconnected, and hitched on
                        at the other end of the cultivator. Other machines have to back and
                        manoeuvre to get into the return position. The Cooper digger alone can turn
                        in its own length without stopping, the whole operation being completed in
                        thirty seconds.</p>
                    <p>Another exhibit is theCochran patent boiler. This is a vertical boiler, aud
                        in common with all vertical boilers, it possesses these most important
                        advantages: Economy of floor space. It does not require any brickwork
                        setting. Ali that is required is to set it on a hard level surface and it is
                        ready for work. In addition to these advantages, it has also the following:-
                        By its special arrangement of horizontal fine tubes, it has a large heating
                        surface, thereby combining the advantages of the vertical boiler with the
                        economy of the locomotive or multitubular boi er. At the same time it is
                        wholly accessible for cleaning and examining inside, an advantage not
                        usually possessed by other types of multitubular boilers. This is a point of
                        extreme importance when only impure water is obtainable.</p>
                    <p>The Cochran boiler can be kept thoroughly c'ean inside, and consequently its
                        efficiency is always maintained, and repairs seldom if ever necessary.
                        Experience leads to the confident assertion: (a) that it is more economical
                        than any other small boiler made; (b) that it is more durable and reliable
                        than any other boiler; (e) that it is the easiest boiler to set to work, and
                        the most economical to maintain; (d) that it is absolutely safe from
                        explosion; (e) that it is the cheapest and best made boiler in the
                        market.</p>
                    <p>Garrett's Engines. These engines are from the works of the well-known firm of
                        Messrs. Richard Garrett aud Sous, of Leiston, estab lished in 1778, who have
                        through five successive ge erations devoted themselves espe cially to the
                        perfection of their engines, and to the establishment of an almost
                        unequalled plant of labour-saving and other machinery if the highest class.
                        The engines are fitted. with Garrett's patent corrugated fire-boxes. These
                        fire-boxes are very elastic, which mean durable, and have about 22% more
                        heating surface than the flat-topped boxes, and it must be borne in mind
                        that experiments have proved that about half of the total evaporation of a
                        boiler is carried out in the immediate vicinity of the fire box.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>PERHAPS YOUR TROUBLE IS KIDNEY DISEASE.</head>
                    <p>Kidney disease comes on quietly-may have been in the system for years before
                        the patient suspected the real cause of his trouble.. There may have been
                        headaches, limb aches, neuralgia, sciatica, rheumatism, a nervous, irritable
                        feeling, or a generally weak, tired, feeling, weak heart, swelling of the
                        flesh, puffy eyes, etc.</p>
                    <p>He did not know that these were symptoms of kidney disease, and so he
                        doctored the symptoms, and not the kidneys,</p>
                    <p>Thus the trouble kept growing worse, until disturbances of the water
                        appeared, or there was gravel, or retention of urine, or backache -or some
                        such plain sign of kidney trouble that there could be no doubt.</p>
                    <p>Dean's backache kidney pills should be taken at the first sign of anything
                        wrong. There is no other safe way, because kidney diseases are the most
                        dangerous of all, except consumption. Doan's pills strengthen the kid neys
                        and help them to properly perform that most important of all functions-the
                        filtering of the blood-help them to flush off, and carry away with the
                        surplus water, all these impurities which the blood gathers up in its
                        circuit of the body. In no other way can you be well. Doan's backache kidney
                        pills are for sale by all chemists and druggists for P.T. 13 per box, or
                        P.T. 71 for 6 boxes; or they may be had by post from the general agent for
                        Egypt, Mr. Max Fischer, Hotel du Nil St., Mousky St., Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>ALD RSON'S GARD N, BULKELEY.</head>
                    <p>Friday, February 17 at p.m. GRAND VARIETY ENTERTAINMENT</p>
                    <p>BY THE POVAL TOOKEY PAMILY. Concluding with the Tang ab'e Sketch</p>
                    <p>"TH MYSTERIOUS YSTERY."</p>
                    <p>HOCKEY ON FRATES.</p>
                    <p>Return Patch: ET.C. e. Alderson's Garden. Dancing after the Concert.</p>
                    <p>writlab Garrison with their families and officers of market</p>
                    <p>marine to harbour and holders of permite are invited.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <!-- three adverts -->
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Thorough efficiency</p>
                    <p>is proved by the enormous sale of</p>
                    <p>CALVERT'S</p>
                    <p>CARBOLIC</p>
                    <p>Tooth Powder</p>
                    <p>Being antiseptic, its regular use keeps the teeth healthy as well as clean,
                        and also gives them the requisite polish without injuring the enamel. It is
                        at the same time most pleasant to use.</p>
                    <p>Calvert's Prickly-heat Soap</p>
                    <p>is very serviceable in hot climates as a preventive of prickly-heat and other
                        Irritation of the skin. It is pleasantly perfumed and captains 20% Crystal
                        Carbolle</p>
                    <p>F. C. CALVERT &amp; Co., Manchester, ENGLAND.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MARKET FOR EGYPTIAN COTTON.</head>
                    <p>Mr. Henry J. Monson writes to us from London:-Before again leaving England
                        for Egypt I have been making close enquiries into the business of Egyptian
                        cotton in Manchester as I did last year. It is of the greatest importance to
                        the cotton growers to know that it is very doubtful if the spindles recently
                        put on to American will revert to Egyptian again. The Egyptian market is
                        bad, the demand does not meet the increased production. If spindles are
                        reverted from American to Egyptian, a greater competition will set in than
                        ever before. The Federation of Master Cotton Spinners and the Bolton Master
                        Cotton Spinners Association have amalgamated, and will now control over 30
                        million spindles. The future prosperity of Egypt, and the maintenance of the
                        excessive high value put on land, depends on the move this association
                        makes. If the spindles are reverted, the value put on land at this moment
                        will prove to be entirely imaginary. I am of opinion that much of the land
                        that has been put under cotton will revert again to sugar cane culture.
                        Owing to the great development of cotton cultivation in other parts of the
                        world, Egypt must endeavour to keep to the front. It is useless any one
                        talking to spinners on the quality of Egyptian cotton surpassing all others,
                        expecting a ready purchase and a high price, because the answer given will
                        be a disappointment. I have visited the large wholesale houses in Nottingham
                        and London, The position now is, "that our market looks "like failing us,
                        and if not entirely then our "price obtained will be low owing to great
                        "competition."The sooner we agriculturista get together and discuss this
                        matter of endeavouring to enlarge the present market, seek other markets, or
                        create new markets, the better it will be for our future prosperity. An
                        Egyptian cotton growers' association should be formed at once. You, Sir,
                        would be doing a great service to the country if you would select the names
                        for a committee, with Alex andria as the central office.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item" feature="prepaidAdvertisements">
                    <head>CHEAP ADVERTISEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>(Prepaid.)</p>
                    <p>GARD'S INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES AND TRADE MARKS REGISTER. A urefol basiness
                        directory containing address of all important business fome of Great Pritain
                        the Continent, and Egypt. Circulating all over Europe and America Price-One
                        pound Sterling. Post Free. AGARD'S</p>
                    <p>INTERNATIONAL</p>
                    <p>HOTEL</p>
                    <p>GUIDE sent post free to all first clace Hotels throughout Europe, America,
                        the Colonies and Egypt The beat reference book for travellers. For
                        advertising space in both books apply to Mr. W. E Walton, Hotel du Nil,
                        Cairo,</p>
                    <p>APARTMENTS wanted by two Englishmen at Alexandria, one big furnished bedroom
                        with breakfast, in central position.. Apply, D.S.M., P.O. Box. No. 423.
                        25,414-3-3</p>
                    <p>F</p>
                    <p>Dr.</p>
                    <p>K.</p>
                    <p>respondent of the "Egyptian Gazette," iready to give any information, help, r
                        advice as to the Fayoum provine and the surrounding desert, lakes, etc., to
                        companis, banks, firms, merobante, I d loan banks, touriste, or others;
                        having a thorough knowledge of the country for the last fifteen years. Write
                        to the sbo e address 6-28</p>
                    <p>SINGING LESSONS recommended by the famous tenor JEAN DE RESZKE given by Herr
                        B. Wechsler of Heidelberg University. Voice production systematic. Apply for
                        trial lesson, press extracts. Post Office, Cairo. 25425-12-3</p>
                    <p>ILL ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEW8-68 value, up to 1902 well bound in good
                        condition, most y thick paser edition, for sale £8 May be seen as 8. Felice
                        Zgazig.</p>
                    <p>25418-5-4</p>
                    <p>LET. Furnished Room, with or without</p>
                    <p>Tboard, Sherif Paths Street, opposite Khedivial</p>
                    <p>Bourse, 2nd floor.</p>
                    <p>25402-12 7</p>
                    <p>ANTED, by a civil engineer returning</p>
                    <p>W from the Sudan, engagement in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Sound knowledge of surveying water works, and supply railway work and
                        sewerage work. Accustomed to control of large bodies of natives. Excellent
                        references and testimonials. Apply to No. 25,433, "Egyptian Gazette"
                        offices. 25433-3-2</p>
                    <p>WANTED for married childless couple well rooms</p>
                    <p>furnished rooms and board in respectable family within city. Apply No.
                        25,439, Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                    <p>25439-3-1</p>
                    <p>VOUNG MAN (22), having thorough know- Yledge ledge of the Egyptian Marketa
                        and foreign languages, English, Frenob, Arabic, and Italian, seeks
                        employment. Good references. Apply No. 25,440, Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                    <p>25440-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <p>Humber Cars &amp; Cycles</p>
                    <p>Beeston &amp; Coventry.</p>
                    <p>PAYMENT 416 and 81 PER MONTH</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN DEPOTI</p>
                    <p>C. LOUKAITIS &amp; Co. GOVERNMENT PURVEYORS,</p>
                    <p>Garage Beulas Street, Cairo,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <!-- davies bryan -->
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1905-02-14/page/n5/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>For HULL, by the S.S. "Kolpino", siled on the 3rd February </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd, 575 tons cotton seed </p>
                    <p>Carver Bros, &amp; Co. Lad, 521 </p>
                    <p>Barker &amp; Co, 430 </p>
                    <p>J. Gour &amp; Son, 483, </p>
                    <p>B.J. Conry &amp; Co., 408, </p>
                    <p>Tadros Ghirghis, 1,000 quarters beans </p>
                    <p>L. Heller, 50 barrels molasses </p>
                    <p>O. K. Levick, 1,198 bags onions </p>
                    <p>Crambani, 1 case cigarettes </p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 1 case cigarettes </p>
                    <p>H. Bindarnegal, 60 balas cotton </p>
                    <p>B. Bortolotti &amp; Co., 37 . </p>
                    <p>B. Mallison &amp; Co., 40</p>
                    <p>137 bales cotton - </p>
                    <p>Pour CANDIE, par le bateau hell. "Athènes", parti le 4 février : </p>
                    <p>Divers, 937 sacs riz, 401 saca sucre, 18 saas fèves, 25 balles coton, 518
                        barils vides, 228 colis peaux, 15 colis divers </p>
                    <p>For MALTA and LIVERPOOL, by the S.S. "Alexandria", sailed on the 4th February
                        : : </p>
                    <p>T. Ghirghis, 370 bales cotton </p>
                    <p>Mohr &amp; Fenderl, 125 , . </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Lank Ltd 76, </p>
                    <p>H. Bindernagel, 535 .</p>
                    <p>R. &amp;0. Lindemann, 660 </p>
                    <p>B. 3. Coury &amp; Co., 188</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co. 100</p>
                    <p>F. Andres, 85 </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 527 </p>
                    <p>J. Planta &amp; Co., 337</p>
                    <p>N. G. Casulli, 51</p>
                    <p>G. Pranger &amp; Co., 140</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Coy. Ltd, 1,367 </p>
                    <p>P. O. Baines &amp; Co., 100</p>
                    <p>Botton Bortolotti &amp; Co., 22</p>
                    <p>Ravelli &amp; Co., 20 </p>
                    <p>E. Toriel &amp; Son, 44</p>
                    <p>W. Getty &amp; Co. 10 .</p>
                    <p>4,757 bales cotton </p>
                    <p>Tadros Ghirghis, 1,000 quarters beans </p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egyptian Bank Ltd. 1,000 quarters beang, 810 tona cotton seed </p>
                    <p>G. Brach &amp; Co, 62 bags gum </p>
                    <p>L-Onofrio, 718 cases bones </p>
                    <p>Kyriazi fr. 3 cases cigarettes </p>
                    <p>Alex, Bonded Stores, 1 </p>
                    <p>Kevork Ipekian, 1 </p>
                    <p>M. G. Hagan, 80 casas eggs </p>
                    <p>Fix &amp; David, 164</p>
                    <p>L. Onofrio, 250 </p>
                    <p>A: Panzieri, 53</p>
                    <p>G. M. Ades, 150</p>
                    <p>R. Mortin, 96</p>
                    <p>Hadjès &amp; Co., 130 </p>
                    <p>"Bank of Egypt, 345 bags sugar </p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benachi &amp; Co., 13 canes furniture </p>
                    <p>E. Minotto, 6,941 cases oranges </p>
                    <p>Chorami, Benachi &amp; Co., 6 cases sweets </p>
                    <p>B. Tilobe &amp; Son, 270 cases bronze powder </p>
                    <p>A. Panzieri, 451 bags onions </p>
                    <p>B. Minotto, 88 cases onions, 106 begs dari seed, 25 bags acorns </p>
                    <p>Varions, 2 packages sundries </p>
                    <p>For PORT-SAID and SYRIA, by the S.S. "El-Kahira", sailed on the 4th February
                        : </p>
                    <p>Various, 1,360 bags rice, 925 begs sugar, 344 bags coffee, 100 baga natron,
                        83 bags cotton - seed, 12 bags henna, 61 packages vegetables, 10 packages
                        skins, 825 packages sundries</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
