<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> 
            THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER II 1905.
            <div type="item">
<head>THE HUNGARIAN CRISIS.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>DIET PROROGUED</head></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>OPPOSITION PROTEST STRONGLY.</head></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Budapest, October 10.
The Emperor has again prorogued the Hun-
garian Diet until the 19 h December by reason
of his non-success in forming a new Govern-
ment on the basis of securing the Parliament
against disorder.
In spite of the prorogation, M. Andrassy
moved a resolution protesting against the
crown's anti-constitutional procedure. This
resolution was adopted practically unopposed,
as the supporters of the Government abstained
from taking any part in the proceedings. ( R.)</p></div>
<div type='item'>
<p>Prague, October 10.
 The Diet has been Opened.  50,000 socialists
made a demonstration claiming universal
suffrage.	(Havas)</p></div>
<div type="item"> 
<p>Budapest, October 10.
Parliament has adjourned until December 19.
(Havas)</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>ENGLAND'S ALLEGED OFFER
TO FRANCE.</head></div>
<div type="item">
<head>GERMAN PRESS COMMENTS.</head></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Berlin, October 10.
In an inspired article the “Koelnisdhe
jjJLtntig" says that it does not believe that
England offered Franco any military assis-
tances and that judgment should be reserved
with reference to tho role, ascribed to Great
Britain until the, British press shall have
offered explanations.
The German newspapers in general demand
explanations from the British Government. (R.)</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>THE MOSCOW STRIKES</head></div>
<div type="item">
	<head>GRAVE DISORDER CONTINUES.</head></div>
                <div type="item">
 <p>Moscow, October 10.
The town is becoming quieter, and the
strikes seem to be partially subsiding, but
there was a sharp conflict yesterday between
the crowd and the Cossacks.
(Later). A crowd of strikers marching on
the boulevard with red flags, was dispersed by
the police. There are many injured. The
Russian newspapers report that the Cossacks
and police are behaving with savage brutality.</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>DISTRESS IN ITALY.</head></div>
<div type="item">
<head>HIGH RENTS TURN OUT FAMILIES</head></div>
<div type="item">
<p>Rome, October 10.
The lack of cheap housing accommodation
has produced a regular crisis. Hundreds of
families are camping in the porches of the
churches and in door ways of palaces and
houses. The landlords refuse to reduce the
rents.</p>
<p>The distress in the region devastated by the
earthquake continues to be severe and wide-
spread.	(Reuter)</p></div>
<div type="item">
<head>BRIGANDAGE AT SALONIKA</head></div>
<div type="item">           
<head>ENGLISHMAN'S EAR CUT OFF</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<p>Salonika, October 10.
Lately brigands captured an Englishman
named Wills, an employe of the Turkish
Tobacco Regie, and demanded a ransom.
They have now sent the Consul at Monastir
one of his ears, and threatened, to kill him
unless a ransom of £6,000 be paid by the
14th inst.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>THE KARLSTAD AGREEMENT.</head></div>
                <div type="item">               
<head>ADOPTED BY THE STORTHING</head></div>
                <div type="item">               
<p>Christiania, October 10.
The Stonthing has adopted the Karlstad
agreement by 101 votes to 16. (Havas)</p></div>
                <div type="item">                
<p>Christiania, October 10
The Storthing has approved the Karlstad
convention.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>THE SAY REFINERY.</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>RECONSTRUCTION OF CAPITAL.</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<p>Paris, October 10.
The shareholders of the Say Refinery have
lowered the old shares by 200 francs and
then voted the reconstruction of the capital
by an issue of 114,730 new shares of 200
francs.	 (Havas)</p></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>BRITISH SQUADRON LEAVES KOBE.</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<p>Tokio, October 8.
The British squadron has left Kobe for
Yokohama accompanied by the Japanese fleet.
During the visit there will be a special
service of trains between here and Yokohama.
(Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item">               
<head>EUROPE'S SUGAR OUTPUT.</head>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>London, October 10..
The output of sugar from Europe for 1905
is estimated at 6,625,000 tons. The production
of 1904 was 4,690,000 tons.	(Reuter)</p>
                        <div type="item">                        
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head></div>
<p>Stray, and Ownerless Does found in
Matarieh during to-morrow night and at dawn
of the 13th inst. will be poisoned by the police.</p></div>
                        <div type="item">                       
<p>Ramleh Book Club— From Friday, next
the Ramleh Book Club will be open for the
exchange of books from 3.45 p.m to 5 p.m. on
the usual days, viz Tuesdays and Fridays.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">                   
<p>The Brindish Mail is expected to arrive
at Alexandria at 3-5 this afternoon, in which
case letters will be distributed at the G.P.O. at
5 p.m. and newspapers, etc. at a later hour.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>The ELdorado Cafe.—A new cafe under
the name of the Eldorado will be opened to-
morrow in connection with the Alhambra
Theatre. The Tzigane orchestra will play selec-
tions from 5 to 8p.m. and from 9 p.m. to
r.30 aim. in the cafe. which is also provided
with English and French billiard tables.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>Affray Near  ssiout. -A s rious quarrel
arose the day before yesterday between two
men of Beni Feiz, which developed into a
general-affray, owing to the relatives and
friends of each disputant taking sides. Naboots
and other weapons were freely used and several
people badly hurt, six of whom were taken to
Assiout hospital in a precarious condition.
It was only with considerable difficulty that
the police were able to restore order.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>Cook’s Nile Tours. -We would draw the
attention of our readers who are resident in
Egypt to the advantageous terms which
Messrs Thomas Cook and Son offer them for
their Nile trips during the mouths of Novem-
ber and December. Specially reduced rates
are being offered to residents and many of
those who have spent the hottest months of
this trying summer in Egypt will take advant-
age of this offer to enjoy a short holiday.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>Salt and Soda Company -The returns of
the Egyptian Salt and Soda Co. for the month of
September show that the salt sales amounted to
L.E. 17,097.720m. as against L.E.16,881.002m.
during September 1904. From January 1 to
September 3 of the present year the total
salt sales amounted to L.E. 188.052.337m. as
against L.E. l86,091,342m. during the Cor-
responding period of last year. The increase in
sales in favor of the present year thus amounts
to L.E, 1,960.995 m.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>Crown Casino, Ibrahimieh. -A large num-
ber of people went to the Grand Crown Casino,
Ibrahimieh, last night to assist at the benefit
performance of Mille Brunette Abdelkader,
an Algerian artiste who has become a great
favorite on account of her Arabic songs and
dances. On this occasion' Mile. Abdolkader
oxcelled herself and had to answer to innu
merable encores. Vivacious Mille Mary Fleur
is still at this music-hall and as popular as
ever, and amongst others Mille Ivette Divanne
has taken a high place in the popular favor.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>Pure WATER FOR Pilgrims.—The water of
Jeddah,in the Heljaz, being naturally bad,
the thousands of pilgrims who visit the port
annually suffered greatly from the want of
drinkable water. Several years ago the Sultan
constructed a fountain, the pure water of
which was drawn from a distant spring, and
called it the Hamidieh fountain. The water
supply, however, proved very intermittent and
his Majesty recently issued an irade to the
effect that the fountain should be repaired as
soon as possible. A sum of L.T. 9,000 was
set aside for the scheme, and the work was
again energetically undertaken. It is hopel
that, before long, good water will be sup-
plied by the Hamdieh fountain to the satis-
faction of the Mohamedan pilgrims of the
whole world</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>British Chamber of Commerce.—We would
draw the attention of manufacturers and mer-
chants to the work of the British Chamber of
Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in
1896 with the sole object of assisting British
trade in this country. The services of the
Chamber are always at the disposal of any
member desiring information on trade matters
generally, including the question of appoint-
ing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for
such advice, it is obviously in the interests of
a British traders here to become members,
especially when it is remembered that the
annual subscription is merely the nominal one
of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy
of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber.
Home enquirers can obtain further particulars
from our London office; 36, New/Broad-street,
which acts as agents to the Chamber.</p></div>

<div type="item" scope="advertisement">
<p>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant. </p>
<p>Table d’Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
<p>ORCHESTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.30 P.M </p>
<p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION - SEA BREEZES.</p>
</div>  
 
<div type="item">
<p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company </p>
<p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
<p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
<p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
<p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
</div> 
<div type="item">                  
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>MESSAGE TO BRITISH
ASSOCIATION.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
 <p>On hearing of the impending visit of the
members of the British Association to Cairo,
H. H. the Khedive immediately sent his aide-
de-camp Major Watson, D.S.O. to meet the
scientists on their arrival,and to inform the
President that the Khedive wished to wel-
come him and the other members of the
Association to Egypt, and expressed the hope
that their stay would be most pleasant. H. H.
the Khedive was graciously pleased to put one
of his Nile steamers at the disposal of the
visitors on whoso behalf the President sent a
warm message of respect and thanks to his
Highness. </p></div>
<p>H. H. the Khedive granted an audience to
Field-Marshal Ghazi Ahmed Makhtar Pasha
at Ras el Tin Palace yesterday morning. The
interview was of a very cordial nature.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>SUICIDE OF A BRITISH SOLDIER.</head>
<p>The adjourned inquest into the cicum-
stances attending the death of Private Charles
Harris of the 2nd battalion of the Rifle Brigade,
by shooting himself in the head at the Citadel
barracks on Monday morning, was resumed
yesterday at the British Consulate.</p>
   <p>The first witness called was Sergeant Willian
Walker, who was on duty at the main quarter 
guard, and who related how he found the body
of the deceased as already mentioned in out
previous issue. He stated in answer to a ques-
ion that about sic months ago he noticed a
change in the demeanor of the man, who
seemed more than usually quiet and reserved.</p>
  <p>Four other witnesses were then examined,
but their evidence was of little importance.
The sixth witness was Private James Wood of
the same company who deposed that he had
known the deceased for three years and was
his best friend.  He met him last on Saturday
at the canteen and he seemed in his usual
spirits, but about two weeks ago, Harris
told him that he had quite enough of the 
troubles at home.  The deceased, however, did
not say of what nature, these troubles were. In
answer to a question from one of the jurors the
witness said that Private harris had never in
the cosafd of conversation led him to think
that he had any intention of taking his life.
The next who gave evidence was Colar
Sergeant Michael Josephy, who had inspected
the kit of the dead man and found a letter
addressed to his mother. This letter was opened
by the coroner and handed to the jury to read.
It was undated, and stated that the writer was 
quite tired of the troubles he had to go 
through. The witness added that the deceased
was a very dull man and backward in his drill.
In answer to a question from a juror Sergeant
Joseph said that he had never complained to
him about being annoyed by any of his
comrades.</p>
 <p> Captain Claude Kidd Morgan, of the R.A.M.C.,
was the last witness called. He deposed having 
been called at 6 o’clock on Monday morning
to examine the body, which was found near the 
tennis court with the rifle lying near it and
pointing upwards. The cause of death was a
rifle bullet, which had entered by the mouth
and come out the back of the head, lacerat-
ing the base of the brain and causing instan-
taaeous death. Witness had no doubt whatever
that the wound was self-inflicted, as he saw 
that deceased had attached one end of his boot
lace to his right foot and the other end to the
trigger of the rifle.</p>
  <p>The jury at 1.15 p.m., without retiring, gave 
a verdict of suicide whilst temporarily iusame.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>Death of Earl Fortescue</head></div>
                <div type="item">
<p>London, October 10.</p>
 <p>Earl Fortescue, the father-in-law of Sir
Michael Hicks Beach, is dead.     (Reuter)</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<p>Earl Hugh Fortescue, was the son of the 2nd
earl of that name and was born in 1818, succeed-
ing his father in 1861. In 1847 he married
Georgina, daughter of the Right Honorable
George Dawson Damer, who died in 1866. He
was educated at Harrow and passed from there 
into Trinity College, Cambridge. In 1840 he was
appointed private secretary to Viscount Mel-
bourne; he represented Plymouth in Parlis-
ment from 1841 to 1852 and Marlebone
from 1854 to 1859, when he resigned his 
seat owing to continued ill health, and 
was called to the House of Lords. During 
his membership of the House of Commons, he
held the appointments of Lord of the Treasurt
and Secretary to the Poor Law Board, the
former from 1846-7, the latter from 1849-51.
The deceased earl is succeeded by his son,
Viscount Ebrington, born 1854.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>Turkish Transport In Trouble</head>
                    <div type="item">
 <p>“Al Mokattam” states that a Turkish trans-
port from the Yemen has been lying off Tor
lately being unable to pay the canal does
Several underfed sick and wounded are on 
board, deaths have been frequent, and the
Quarantine Board have been obliged from
motives of humanity and in the interests of
public health, to order the sick and wounded to
be landed and a number of tents to be placed
at their disposal.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<head>Steamer Movements</head></div>
                    <div type="item">
<p>The Khedivial mail steamship Minieh will
leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on Saturday and
Port Said at 4 p.m. on Sunday for Beyroth,
Tripoli, Mersins, Alexandretta, Cliffs, and 
Jaffa.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<head>THE PRINCES’ CLAIM.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>DECISION TO MORROW.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>(From our Correspondent.)</head>
<head>(By Telephone).</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>This morning the first hearing of the ques-
tion arising from the claims of the Princes,
heirs of the late Ismail Pasha took place at
the Cairo Mixed Tribunals, before Judge Tuck,
the Juge de Refere. Maltre Molteni, Conten-
tieux to the Ministry of Finances, represented
the Government, Matre Carton de Wiart the
Credit Foncier and Daira Sanieh Companies,
while Maltre Count Petracchi watched over
the interests of the Daira Sanieb, in the
absence of Maltre Manusardi. Maltre Linant
was the advocate of the Princes.</p>
<p>The proceedings opened with an able expose
of the whole case by Me. Molteni on behalf of
the Egyptian Government Me. Linant replied
at some length, giving the views of his clients,
after which Me.Carton de Wiart, in an eloquent
speech, summed up the situation from the point
of view of the companies involved. The Court
then adjourned to consider its decision, and a
notice was shortly afterwards issued to the
Press announcing that the judgment would not
be communicated to tho public before 9 a.m.
to-morrow, Thursday.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">                     
<head>NEWSPAPER PROSECUTION.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>The tribunal of Saida Zenab which sat on
Monday found Ahmed Fouad, the proprietor
of the Cairo weekly paper called the "Thun
derer,” guilty of having published in his
paper a defamatory article concerning
Sheik Ali Yussef, proprietor and editor of the
"Moayad" and sentenced the accused to three
months imprisonment.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">
<head>SALE OF MENA HOUSE.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>A telegram has been received by the Nun-
govich Hotel Company, Cario, announcing the
purchase of the Mena House property from 
Mrs. Locke King. The conditions and the price
of purchase have not been mentioned in the 
telegram but will follow by the first mail. We 
understand that the lessee of Mena House,
Mr. Emil Weckel, intends to sever his con-
section with Egypt but it is not yet known
whether he will take over the management of
the hotel during the coming season or not. All
who know Mena House and Mr. Weckel will
join us in the hope that he will return for the 
season before finally bidding adieu to Egypt.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
 <head> PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head></div>                   
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>Mr. M. de C. Findlay, C.M.G., Acting British 
Diplomatic Agent and Mr. H. Rumblod, 2nd
Secretary to H.B.M.'s Agency, have returned
to Cairo. H.B.M.'s Agency at Cario reopens
officially to day.
    <div type="item">
<p>H.E. Ahmed Pasha Khairt left for Cairo
yesterday.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>It is reported that H.H. Prince Mohamed
Abdul Kader, second son of H.H. the 
Khedive is to be educated at the American
College, Beyrout, and has already left for
Syria in charge of Shawki Bey, the Egyp-
tian poet-laureate.</p></div>
    <div type="item">    
<p>El Kaimakam G. Gillison Bey, second in 
command of the Artillery and assistant Director
of Ordinance, has been appointed Commandany 
of the Artillery and Director of Ordinance. El
Kaimakam C.P. Roberts Bey, Artillery, has
been promoted to the two former posts.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>Lieutenant L.S. Coke, Irish Guards, has
arrived in Egypt and has been taken on the
strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank
of Bimbashi. He is posted to the 10th
Sudanese.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>El Bimbashi R.C. Bayldon, Sudan Govern-
ment, has resigned his commission in the
Egyptian Army.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>We are sorry to learn that the Rev. E
Ryan, senior chaplain (Roman Catholic) to
the forces, will not be able to return to Egypt
until the end of next January on account of
ill-health.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>Mr. Douglas W. Pollock has been appointed
to the Towns and Buildings service as archi-
tect and is posted to the Zagazig district.</p></div>
    <div type="item">
<p>Mr. Harold Harris leaves for Cairo this
afternoon and will leave Port Said on Monday
or Tuesday next by P. and O. boat for England.</p>
        <div type="item">        
<head>PASSENGER LIST</head></div>        
        <div type="item">
<p>Departures</p> 
<p>Le Paquebet Schlewsig, parti aujourd'hui
pour Naples et Marveille, avait a bord:</p>    
<p>MM. Jacques R. Aghion, Ernest Aghion,
Franz V. Plants, S. Schonchana, Herr Pro-
fessor K. Schmidt, Mme M. Gattabin, Mme
Dr. Gattavin, Herr Obermintorichter R
Loes, Dr. Warson, Herr et Frau R. Reinhold,
M. Gaston Montel, Mme B. Dupont.</p></div>        
        <div type="item">
<head>THE FINANCE MINISTRY.</head></div>
        <div type="item">        
<head>INSUFFICIENT SALARIES.</head></div>
        <div type="item">        
<p>Sir Vincent Corbett has received the follow-
ing letter from the native employes, of the
Ministry of Finance :—</p>
<p>Sir —We, the undersigned, employes of tho
Finance Ministry, joined last year in submit-
ting to you onr complaint of the inioffi-
ciency of onr pay to'meet the necessities
of life nnder the present financial circum-
stances of the country, beg to express o' r
pleasure at hearing of yoor return from leave
in perfectly good health.</p>
<p>We further request to be permitted to
declare our feelings cf thanks to you for
having given the said oomplaiut its due
share of consideration and trust that onr
hope will be realised by the beginning of
next year.
Signed:</p></div>
        <div type="item">
<head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
            <div type="item">            
<head>THE SS. NUBIA.</head>
                <div type="item">                
<p>(From our Correspondent).</p>
<p>Port Said, Toesday.</p>
M<p>r. Lawrence Brnoe, superintendent-en-
gineer to the Anchor line arrived here early
this morning by the S-8. Circassia, one of the
oompany’s largest passenger boats, alter having
been anchored outside for 20 hoars. Mr.
Bruoe has come oat fr'om Bog’and to.toe what
cm be done for the S.S. Nabia, which went
aibore in'the Red Soa some days ago. On his
arrival here he reoeived a telegram from 8oez
informing him that the Nabia had boon re-
floated, that she was very badly damaged, and
that she would proceed to Suez at once, and
asking him to oontinne on there immediately.
Aooordingly Mr. Brnoe went to Suez by this
morning’s train.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<p>HARBOUR NEWS.</p>
<p>The harbonr is still vary full and vessels are
arriving, ooaling. and leaving all day. Another
batch of fifteen boats left Port-Said to-d*y for
thaCanal and there are seven vessels outside
waiiiting for instructions to enter.</p></div>
                <div type="item">
<head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>MOUDIRIBH 8TAFF RETURNS.</head></div>
                <div type="item">                
<p>( From our Correspondent. )</p>
<p>Soakin September 29.</p>
<p>Mr. Kerr, acting moudir of 8uakin and the
whole of the moodirieh staff have arrived here
from Erkowit, where they have spent the aum-
mor. Fruit trees, a large consignment of whioh
recently arrived from Egypt, have been planted
et this hill sanatorium, and are reported to be
progressing very welL</p></div>
                <div type="item">                    
<head>RAILWAY NOTES.</head>
<p>The damage done to the line by the recent
washouts has been repaired in nearly.ev«fy
instance,aud if no fur heroloudburstatSoour the
lines should .lto joined about tbo iniddleof
October. Miralai Phipps Bey, secretary general
to the Sudan Government, arrive! here from
Khartoum on the 22nd inst. and succeed »d in,
making the greater part of hi* journey by train,
though he was ompell d to travel over the
gap between the railheads and thi damaged
portions of the line on camel back. After
in'peoting the moodirieh and the railways he
left for Port Sudan onThe 25th inst., and affor
au inspection of that port left fir Egypt by the
Khedivia! Mail S.S. Dakahlieh.</p></div>
                <div type="item">                
<head>ENGINEERING NOTES.</head>
<p>The mouditieh authorities recently reoeived
SbJiew plant from the iPolsometer Company,
Etlgland, by the>S.S. SHahristan which will he
erected-at the Sh£atali wells.' Mr. Boxall,
ohief engineer of the 8uakin condensers being
on. leave, the Govem->r of Suakin requested'
the Sudan Gove-umont 'Railways to lend him
the serrioes of an engjneqr to supervise its
ereotion and Mr. Bailey was accordingly de-
puted for the work.</p>
                    <div type="item">                  
<head>OFFICIAL NOTICE.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<p>Proposal to change a ship’s name. I.D-
Witt Gray, Secretary of-the Kbedivisl Mail
8teamship aud Graving Deck Company, Limit-
ed, of 71, Bishopsgate Street Within, in the
City of London, hereby give notioe that in
oonsequenoe of her name not being in con-
formity with those of the other vessels owned
by the Company, it is my intention to-apply to
tho BoaTcfof Trade, under "seotion' 47 of the
Merchant Shipping Act, 1894, ip resp&ot of
the steamer Inanda of Aberdeen, Official
Number 118,187,of Gross Tonnage 3,468Tons
of Register Tonnage 2,607, heretofore owned by
Messrs J. T. Rennie 1ft Son, Aberdeen, for
permission to change her name to Menzaleii
to be registered ih the said new nsmeatth"
Port of London, as owned by the' Khedivial
Mail 8taamahip. and Graying Dock Company,
Limited.</p>
<p>Any objections to tho proposed, ohange of
name must be sent- to the Assistant Secretary
Marine Department, Board of Trade, witftn
seven days from the appearance of this Adveri
Dote at London this 10th tjfiyofOotobeK
1905.</p>
<p>De Witt Gray,</p>
<p>Secretary.</p></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head></div>
                    <div type="item">                    
<head>CRICKET.</head>
                        <div type="item">                        
<p>E. T.C. v. MR. DAWSONS’ XI.</p>
<p>This match was commenced yesterday and
ended in a draw, a successful appeal being
made against the bad light at 5.30 p.m.
Scores : -</p>
<p>E.T.C</p>
<p>Mr. Stacey b. Mather ... ...	...	23</p>
<p>" Byrne b. Mather ............. ...	2</p>
<p> „Cheesman b. Graves ...	...	1</p>
<p>„Harrison st Scarth, b. Dawson...68</p>
<p>" L Mclean l.b.w. b. Mather...	8</p>
<p>„Hatley o. 8cartb, b. Graves..... 10</p>
<p>„Ash c. Guarino, b. Mather... ...  21</p>
<p>„ Blythman b. Dawson ...	5 </p>
<p>„Thurston not out ... ...	25</p>
<p>„Lees not out... ...	10</p>
<p>„Lester to bat........... ...</p>
<p>Extras .... ...	12</p>
<p>Total for 8 wkts. declared... ... 185</p>
<p>Bowling.</p>
          <p>   0.  M. R. W.</p>
<p>Mr. Dawson ....	9  1	30	2</p>
<p>„Mather	... ...	17	4	8)	4</p>
<p>"Graves	....... 17	2	63	2</p>
<p>Mr. Dawsons’ XI.</p>
<p>Mr. Graves b. R. B. McLean... ... ...	8</p>
<p>„ Mather not out ...	27</p>
<p>,,Freeman b. Byrne............. 11</p>
<p>„ Dowson c. Lees, b. Thurston ... 2</p>
<p>„ Dawson c. Henley, b. Byrne............ 5</p>
<p>„ Scarth not out ... ... ...	0</p>
<p>Capt Kirkwood</p>
<p>Mr. Corfield	</p>
<p>„ Gamage         Did not bat</p>	     
<p>Khalil Effendi	</p>
<p>Mr. Guarino </p>
<p>Extras.... ... ...6</p>                            
<p>Total for 4 wkts.... .. 59</p>
<p>Bowling. </p>
<p>                 O.  M.  R.  W.</p>                            
<p>Mr. Byrne... ... 10  5  15   2</p>
<p>„ R. McLean  ... 6   2  14   1 </p>
<p>„ Thurston ...   5   0  23   1 </p></div>
                        <div type="item">
<head>THE DAY OF ATONEMENT.</head>
                            <div type="item">                           
<p>While in all countries it is interesting to
note the observance of various religious festi-
vals and fasts, it becomes doubly so when,
as is the case in Alexandria, nationalities
too numerous to mention are gathered to-
gether under one roof to take part in the
service of the day. In the: “Referee,” four
years ago, Mr. G. R Sims (who writes as
"Dagonet” under the heading “Mustard and
Cress"), gave a very graphic account of
a visit he paid to the East London
Tabernacle in the Mile End road (which
had been lent to the Jews for the occa-
sion) on the Day of Atonement. Here, of
course, would be gathered together a vast
number of the foreign Jews who people White-
chapel and Bethnal Green, and Mr.Sims bore
testimony to the earnestness that marked the
demeanour of all present at this solemn service.
This was equally marked in the synagogue in
Rue Temple Menasce, where, under the gui-
dance of my friend Rudolph I attended the
service on Sunday evening last. We entered
the buildiug-abont 6 o’clock and fonod it crowd-
ed. Men, youths, and young boys, almost with-
out exception wearing white scarfs with coloured
ends, filled the synsgogaue to its utmost capacity,
the porch also being full. In the gallery high
up ladies were sitting, but as only the front
rows were visible from below,their numbers could
not be estimated. Shortly afterwards, the
Sanctuary was opened by the Chief Warden, Mr.
Joseph Gore, and the Scroll of the Law enclosed
in elaborately ornamented silver vessels, three
in number, was brought out. The Reader then,
from the steps of the Sanctuary, read the Grand
Prayer seven times, the congregation repeating
it after he had finished each recital.</p>
<p>The silver vessels containing the Scroll of
the Law were then carried round the building.
During the progress of the procession the
Chief Warden beckoned us to come to the
Sanctuary steps, and after he had restored the
scroll to its place an closed the Sanctuary
doors for another twelve months, kindly in-
vited os to accompany him to his seat. For
some time we sat and listened to the prayers
read from the marble desk in the centre of the
building by the Reader, which were attentively
followed and responded to by the congrega-
tion. We stayed till what is called "the silent
prayer," uttured in a very subdued tone by all
present, had been said, and then left the Syna-
gogue. I learned that the service would be
continued until about 10 o’clock, that the
building would remains open all night, and
that at an early hour on Monday morning
prayers would be resumed and continued all
day (with short intervals) terminating soon
after six o’clock, when the exhausting fast
won d be at an end. On the following day I
visited the synagogue for a short time in the
early afternoon, during an interval. A subdued
conversation was going on, but not of a character
calculated in the least to mar the solemnity of
the occasion, and no signs of exhaustion were
apparent. This I thought somewhat remarkable,
considering the strict nature of the fast as from
before sunset on the ninth day of the month
Tisri till after sunset on the tenth, no kind,
of food whatever must he eaten, nor even a
drop of water taken.</p>
<p>When one reflects on the regularity with
which this fast is observed year after year in all
countries—for there are few where the Jew is
not found—it is more easily understood how
the race has survived all the persecutions of
past centuries, and the possibility of their
reunion some day in a country of their own, if
not in Palestine. No more severe test of con-
formity to ancient laws and customs could be
found than the “Black Fast” of the Jews,
and few religions could be found now-a-days,
the professors of Which men, women, and
children—would go through the ordeal of 17
hours abstinence from food at a stretch, once
every year. The wonderful vitality of the
Jewish race remains as strong as ever. Efforts
to proselytise meet with scant success, and
indeed such methods as those exposed in
a letter written to the editor, of the “Ga-
zette” a few months ago—and allowed to
pass unchallenged—only go to show the im-
mense stability of the ancient religion of the
children of Israel, and the difficulty in the
way of those who would lessen its influences.</p>
<p>T.A.</p></div>                                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
