<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Hank Thompson --></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-15"><!-- Octber 15, 2016 --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-01"><!-- November 1, 1905 --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 1, 1905.</head></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>RUSSIA JUBILANT.</head>
                        <head>THE PEOPLE’S VICTORY.</head>
                        <head>EFFECT OF MANIFESTO.</head>
                        <head>THE TSAR CHEERED.</head>
                        <dateline>Lodz, October 31.</dateline>
                            <p>A company of troops bas been arrested for firing in the air. A similar incident bas taken place at Warsaw.	(Reuter)</p>
                            <div type="item"><dateline>Odessa, October 31.</dateline>
                            <p>There were 300 killed and wounded in the disturbances of Sunday.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, Ootober 31.</dateline>
                            <p>The Tsar’s manifesto declares that the prevalent troubles have filled his heart with great sorrow. These troubles may become a menace to the integrity of the Empire, and it is therefore his duty to efface himself, and to hasten their cessation. For this reason he recognises that the co-ordination of the powers of government is indispensable. Finally he directs the government to fulfil his will as follows :
                            (a)	To grant real inviolability of person and freedom of conscience, speech, union, and association.
                            (b)	Without deferring the elections for the National Assembly, to enable, as far as is possible on account of the shortness of the time, the classes at present deprived of electoral rights to participate in the elections, leaving the ultimate settlement of the franchise to the new legislative regime.
                            (c)	To establish as an unchangeable rule that no law shall come into force without the approval of the National Assembly, which is also to exercise real supervision of the legality of the acts of the authorities.
                            A general strike begins in Finland to-day, which will include the railways which have hitherto been unaffected.	(Reuter )</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 31.</dateline>
                            <p>The manifesto of the Tsar has been placarded throughout the City, and telegraphed to wherever the lines are working. It is believed here that the effect will be instantaneous. It created great popular rejoicing yesterday evening. The crowds in the streets cheered for liberty and the Tsar, singing the National Anthem instead of the ‘'Marseillaise," as lately.
                            The people surrounded the bewildered Cossacks, patting the horses and telling the men to go home as they were no more needed, since they had received their liberties.
                            The strike is at an end on the Moscow and St. Petersburg, Moscow-Kazan, and Moscow-Archangel  railways.
                            The jubilation caused by the first announcement that the Tsar had granted a constitution was succeeded to-day by demonstration in honor of the victory of the proletariat. A huge procession waving red flags and singing revolutionary songs paraded Nevsky Prospect. Hymns for the dead were sang at various points in memory of the victims of the 22nd January.
                            The processionists halted at the University, where workers and students joined in making speeches declaring that the manifesto showed the powerlessness of the autocracy.
                            The victory of the people has, been enthusiastically celebrated in the provincial centres by processions and thanksgiving services.
                            The Governor of Odessa appeared amidst the crowd in front of the palace, and congratulated them on their victory. The crowd demanded the release of political prisoners and the removal of the Cossacks. The Governor promised to comply.		(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><dateline>St. Petersburg, October 31</dateline>
                            <p>The Imperial manifesto has produced various effects. Whilst many people congratulate and thank the Tsar, numerous crowds in the cities have held demonstrations demanding greater concessions.
                            A monster demonstration of this description took place at St. Petersburg, and tumultuous and even sanguinary demonstrations have taken place at Odessa, Petrokoff, Lodz, Warsaw, and Sosnovice.	(Havas)</p></div></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>KAISER AND TSAR</head>
                            <dateline>Berlin, October 31.</dateline>
                                <p>In view of the interruption of the mail service between here and St Petersburg, the Emperor has placed two torpedo divisions at the Tsar’s disposal to convey official correspondence and despatches between Peterhoff and Memel. The Tsar has gratefully accepted the offer.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>FRENCH AMNESTY.</head>
                            <dateline>Paris, October 31.</dateline>
                                <p>The Chamber of Deputies has voted the amnesty, which was postponed in the last sitting of July.	(Reuter)</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>RACING.</head>
                            <dateline>London, October 31.</dateline>
                                <p>Cambridgeshire Stakes. Betting 6 to 1 against Velocity ; 13 to 2 Glenamoy; 9 to 1 lover Andover ;  100 to 8 Donnetta ; 100 to 7 Thunderbolt ; 100 to 7 Nirvanah (Reuter)</p></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Brindisi Mail will arrive at Alexandria at 3 p m. and will be distributed at the G.P.O. at 5 p.m.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>New Kuttabs—Thirty-five new kuttabs are to be built by public subscription in the markaz of Badari, Assiout province.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Suez Canal.—291 vessels passed through the Canal from the 6th to the 29th ult, the dues from which amounted to frs. 8,325,517.68.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Anglo Egyptian Land Allotment Co.—  Details of the subscription for the Anglo-Egyp-i tian Land Allotment Company will be found on page 6 of to-day’s issue.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Fatal House Collapse.—A house at Ard Khalaf, Boulac, collapsed on Monday evening. The owner of the hou e and six other persons were buried in the runis. The former and his son were killed.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Mansourah and Tantah Church Services.— By general desire the morning services (English Church) during November will be held at 11 o'clock, instead of 9.30 a.m., as announced in a previous number.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Royal Dublin Fusiliers. — Brig.-General Bullock, C.B., came down to Alexandria from Cairo this morning, and held an inspection of the Royal Dublin Fusiliers at Mastapha Pasha. He returns to the Capital this afternoon.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Execution — The execution of Rohaiem Youssef will take place at 9 a.m. to-morrow within the precincts of Hadra prison. The condemned man was sentenced to death for the murder of Abddalla Bey Fehmi on the 29th June last.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Sanitary Department.—Acting under the advice of the Director-General of the Sanitary Department, the Ministry of the Interior have authorised Doctors Outline Agheretos and John Michael Ormanian to practise their profession in Egypt</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>All’s Well that ends Well.—The proprietor of "Al Moayad”, whose marriage last year excited so much public interest, has had a new contract with Miss Safiah Saddat registered by Sheikh Radi at the Cairo Mehkemeh, and the young wife took up her abode with Sheikh Aly Youssef last week.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Moudirs’ Salaries. -The official salaries of the newly-appointed moudirs have been fixed as follows : —Ibrahim Bey Nahib, Mon-dir of Ghirgeh, LE 900 ; Mustapha Bey Maher, Moudir of Galioabieh, 840 ; Hassan Bey Hassib, Moudir of Assouan, 720 ; Khalif Bey Riad, Sub-Governor of the Suez Canal, 420.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouses — A circular informs us that Mr. E Pegna has been appointed sub-manager of the Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Company, in place of Mr. R Rosenberg, who has retired to take op some other business. Mr. Jacques 8. Mizrahi has been authorised to sign for the manager and the sub-manager.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Murderous Thieves. — Some burglars who were engaged in breaking into a house in the village of Atamineh, near Fayoum, were noticed by some natives who endeavoured to check them. Both parties exchanged shots, one man being killed and two ghaffirs slightly wounded. The Mondirieh authorities have held a careful enquiry into the circumstance of the incident</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>King’s Birthday Review. —The troops of the Army of Occupation now in Cairo, consisting of Military Mounted Police, Mounted Infantry, 2nd Company Royal Engineers, 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, and 1st Battalion King's Royal Rifle Brigade, will parade at Abbassieh in the Polygon at 10 a m. on the 3rd inst. to rehearse for the review on the 9th inst. in Abdeen Square.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Alexandria Station.—We are delighted to see that the Railway Administration has at last separated the third-class booking office from the first and second, at Alexandria station. Previously persons in want of tickets had to push, swear, and jostle amid a crowd of workmen, fellaheen, and others, whose idea of obtaining tickets was to shout at the fullest pitch of their lungs and push with all the force of their shoulders.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Murder.-A watchman, of Exbet el Shimi, near Balashoon, Mina el Kamh Markaz, was wandering around the farm on the 28th inst. when a bullet pierced his head and killed him on the spot. The shot was reported to have been fired from a spot near the ezbeh cottages. Next morning an inquest was held by the markaz authorities, and two ghaffirs of the same ezbeh were arrested, as each was suspected of having been the murderer.</p></div></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><p>Alhambra Theatre.—The Italian comedy company closed its stay at this theatre last night with Il Controllers del Vagoni-Lotti. To-morrow, the French comedy company whioh has been successfully performing in Cairo, will make its debut here with the amusing vaudeville Le File Surnaturel The manage ment inform us that, with a view to satisfying the demands of the public, they have lowered the price of admission to P.T. 5. In future, prices will be as follows : First reserved seats. P.T. 15 ; seoond reserved seats, P.T. 10; entrance P.T. 5. Boxes will be P.T. 80, not inclusive of entrance.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Post Office Notice.—Owing to the fact that former notices referring to clear direction of correspondence have been largely disregarded by the public, and that the general delivery has had to be delayed in consequence, it has been decided that from 1st February, 1906, correspondence for house-to-house delivery addressed only “Cairo" or "Alexandria" will be retarded and only sorted after the first delivery of each mail has left the post offices in those towns. After that date it will be no longer necessary to make special requests for house-to-house  delivery, as correspondence bearing the full address will be duly delivered.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>The Pro Calabria Benefit Concert. -In the account of the concert which was held last Thursday at the Khedivial Opera House under the auspices of the Cairo Musical and Dramatic society, for the benefit of the victims of the Calabrian earthquakes, the writer of the article inadvertently omitted to mention Sig. Valentino, who contributed in no slight measure towards the success of the concert by accompanying those who sang. Signor Valentino, besides being an excellent pianoforte soloist, has the invaluable gift of being able to accompany well. He adapts himself to the mood of the singer, to whom he affords great aid, and the accompaniment under his hands is always in sympathy with the air of the song Signor Valentino is well-known in Cairo and we hope to hear him many times during this season.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                            <div type="item"><p>The Viceroy of India and Lady Minto will sail from Marseilles by the P. and O. steamship Victoria on November 3, and are due to arrive at Bombay on November 17. Lord and Lady Carson will,acording to present arrangements, arrive at Marseilles on December 2. They have abandoned their intention of visiting Lord Cromer in Egypt on their way home.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>The Marquis de San Giuliano, ex-Minister of Agriculture at Rome, has arrived at Cairo from Asmari. Yesterday the Marquis, with Count Arrivabene Gonzaga, acting Italian Agent, visited Lord Cromer, Mastapha Pasha Fehmy, and other notables.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Adly Pasha Yeghen, Governor of Cairo, will return from leave about the end of next week.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>vice-admiral Sir William Fawkes, Vice-Admiral Montt, Sir H  Hill, Patterson Bey, Lieutenant A. E. Evans, Dr. Cutter, Mr. Davidson, and Mr. and Mrs. Bird are staying at Shepheard’s Hotel.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Dr. Zuckerkandl, the eminent Vienna surgeon, and Mme Zuokerkandl are paying a short visit to Cairo.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Mr. and Mrs. M. M. Mitchell Innes are among the passengers who are due to arrive at Port Said this week by the P AND O. steamer Syria.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>The Rev. Norman-Lee, S.C.F., Alexandria returned from leave yesterday. We are glad to hear that Mrs. Norman-Lee hopes to return to Alexandria about December next</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>M. and Mme Rene Veillard and M. and Mme Maes, who have been staying at Shepheard's  Hotel, left for Assouan yesterday on board their private dahabeah.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Sir Eldon Gorst is among the contributors to The Empire and the Century," edited by Mr. C. S. Goldman, which Mr. John Murray hopes to issue in a few days.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>It is stated that Mustapha Pasha Kamel, the proprietor of "Al Lewa," is endeavouring to find some German capitalists in Berlin, in order to form an agricultural company in Egypt under his management.</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Mr. J. A. Afriat has arrived at the New Khedivial Hotel, Alexandria,</p></div>
                            <div type="item"><p>Dr. and Mr Kalomiris have returned to Alexandria from Athens by the Russian Steamer</p></div></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>KHEDIVE AND THASOS.</head>
                        <head>EXPLOITATION OP THE ISLAND.</head>
                        <head>Our Constantinople Correspondent writes :</head>
                        <p>During the Khedive's recent visit to Constantinople his Highness had a conference with the Sultan on the subject of the Island of Thasos, which has unjustly been seized by the Sublime Porte. The,Sultan has recently instituted a Kaimakamat on the Island, whioh has since become the fourth Sandja’k of the vilayet of Salonica. To-day there is a mutassarifat, a tribunal, and an organised gendamerie on the Island. The Khedive has a chateau then and possesses various estates and farms on the Island, as well as large plantations. The forests are being exploited by a German-Jewish company. This German company want to exploit all the mines on the Island, and their application is under consideration.
                            The report that the Germans have been allowed to have a coal depot on the Island and to use it as a naval station is inexact. The Germans have not got so far, but the Sultan is getting more under the thumb of Germany every day, and the influence of the Germans is increasing in Constantinople enormously owing to the ellipse of prestige. The Sultan will soon be a mere tool in the hands of the Kaiser, whose clever policy in Turkey has done so much for the development of German trade and influence. </p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                            <p>The Khedive is considering a scheme for parcelling out his tefeiche at Koubbeh with a view to disposing of it for building purposes. His Highness spent yesterday at Koubbeh.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE MAHROUSSA.</head>
                            <p>The Khedivial yacht Mahroussa is now in the Govan dry-dock, where Messrs. Inglis are altering the stern for the turbine propellers. The turbine machinery and boilers are on board, the funnel is set up, and the mainmast in position. Workmen are busy laying the shade deck and erecting the other deck structures.
                                When our representative paid a visit to the vessel recently in Messrs. Inglis's yard, he found from 500 to 600 men busily employed on the yacht, with Mustapha Pasha Ibady and Mr. Taylor, the chief engineer, engaged in superintending the details of the work. The vessel, although not by any means nearly finished, had been completely changed, and was quite unrecognisable. There was, of course, no trace of the old paddles, and the old wooden bow had been replaced by a steel one. The new machinery takes up half the room previously unoccupied, and the space thus economised is being utilised for the erection of rooms for the Khedive’s suite. New deck houses are being erected, including a spacious dining saloon, captain’s room, and smoking room, while on the new boat deck there will be a room for his Highness and the chart room. It is expected that the Mahroussa will not leave the shipbuilders’ hands until the month of April or May next, as a good deal remains to be done in the way of fittings, etc. When put to sea again she will be capable of a speed of 17 knots.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>RAILWAY ESTIMATES.</head>
                            <p>The budgetary estimates of the Egyptian Railway Administration for the coming year will on the whole resemble the estimates for this year. The estimates allow for the increase of the salary of the chief controller of the Accounts Department from LE. 40 to LE. 60 per month, and that of the inspector of the same service from LE 40 to LE 50 per month.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>CAIRO ZOO.</head>
                            <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Zoological Gardens, Cairo, is an anaconda eighteen feet long, also some West African pythons, a warthog, a cassowary, and some monkeys.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE ALEXANDRIAN RAT.</head>
                            <p>The current number of the “Spectator" concludes an interesting article on the criminal rat with the following remarks on the Alexandrian variety:—
                                It is one of the curiosities of animal temperament that while the brown rat is so universally detested, the closely related Alexandrian rat—the white or piebald varieties are well known in this country—is almost a favourite. It is a very quiet, docile little animal, almost affectionate in its relations with man, and constantly kept as a pet by children. It is clean and very gentle, never by any chance offering to bite, and is as intent on storing up food, as if it had never forgotten the experience of its ancestors in the "lean years” when Joseph ruled under Pharaoh. It is the humblest of all domestic pets but often quite interesting in its ways, the only drawback to its company being the close resemblance in appearance to the criminal brown rat.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                            <p>The Ellerman S.S. City of Cambridge which left here on the 20th ult, arrived at Liverpool this morning, after a passage of 12 days. </p></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>EGYPT IN PARLIAMENT.</head>
                        <head>NATIVE PRESS OPINION.</head>
                        <p>“Al Moayad" reoently published an article of which the following is a summary.
                            “In his speech of last Jane Lord Cromer stated that Egyptian questions should always be kept distinct from the varying policies of the British political parties. Yet we have seen in the parliamentary reports of last August some comments on Lord Cromer's statement. Mr. H. Weston, M.P., asked the Under Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, on the 8th August last, whether the administration of Egypt by Lord Cromer would be taken under the control and responsibility of the British Minister for Foreign Affairs, to which Lord Percy replied that the administration of Egypt was entrusted to the Khedive and his Ministers, acting with the guidance and aid of Lord Cromer as the responsible Diplomatic Agent of H. M.’s Government In reply to another question Lord Percy said that the Egyptian Government most pay attention to Lord Cromer’s advice.
                            "The placing Egypt under the direct supervision of the British Parliament will have, as far as we see, to be freshly considered. As for ourselves, we should like our Government to be under parliamentary superintendence,provided, the latter is efficacious and unchangeable. The officials of the Occupation in that case would become very careful in their acts, and be obliged to give an account of them to their superiors. But it will be necessary for Parliament to obtain reports about Egypt from an Egyptian source, because the British reports will contain nothing against the Occupation, as is the case with Lord Cromer’s annual report.
                            "The Egyptians most understand their real position after 28 years of occupation, and after the occupying Power has come into close partnership with Egypt in possessing the Sudan, where England cares very little for her partner, and also after the Anglo-French Agreement Let us put aside the useless words “ocoupation" and “withdrawal" as all efforts in this direction of imagination and fancy will be in vain. Let us look at our present state and do our best to keep something of our station and strive for our possible advantage. We had better deal with the British authorities in our social questions and come with them to a useful understanding. If one requirements in some way could not be answered, we should do our best to bring the unsolved matters before Parliament. Now is the proper time for the communication. A member of Parliament itself opens a door for us to enter, and we must seize the opportunity in seeking a Parliamentary supervision over Egypt. Let us turn the demand into notion in good time, while we have such a straightforward representative as Lord Cromer, who possesses the necessary requirements and acts even if it is against himself. We had better do this before some other people put difficulties in our way."
                            This article having given rise to some misunderstanding, Sheikh Aly Youssef, proprietor of “Al Moayad," has informed “Al Mokattam" that it was not meant that Egypt should have any official relation with the British Parliament “Al Moayad" only wishes the Egyptians (says “Al Mokattam") to put before some M.P., who is or might be known to them, all the questions which they wish to come directly before Parliament.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                            <p>The recent inspection of the whole of Egypt north of Beni Sonef has proved satisfactory. The staff of cattle plague officers has been reduced by more than half, and the Sanitary Department is only awaiting a reply from the Quarantine Board to dispense with the remainder. It is hoped that by the 15th November cattle plague restrictions will be removed.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>THE MARONITE PATRIARCH.</head>
                            <p>The Maronite Patriarch has had a very cordial reception at Constantinople and has been most graciously treated by the Sultan. When in Paris the Patriarch obtained a renewal of the protection of France.
                                The Turkish newspapers have been ordered not to mention anything about the French protectorate over the Maronites, nor the Patriarch’s visits to Rome or Paris.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>EGYPTIAN COTTON IN RUSSIA.</head>
                            <p>The “Novosti” says that in the series of tariffs on the Russian railways there is a new standard for the carriage of Egyptian cotton, on condition of the same being certified as to origin The new tariff is very low as compared with the former one.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>AN ABYSSINIAN IN NEW YORK.</head>
                            <p>El Hadji Abdullahi, special envoy of King Menelik of Abyssinia, who has arrived in New York with a letter from King Menelik to Mr. Roosevelt, causes a stir wherever he goes because of his picturesque appearance.
                                He went to the United States ostensibly to arrange a commercial treaty, but, it is said, actually to pave the way for permanent diplomatic relations.
                                He has tried American cocktails and thinks they are grand, He has expressed amassment at the “skyscrapers." When informed that there was one “skyscraper" thirty-two stories high, he responded: “Take me there and I'll say my prayers on the roof of that house to-morrow</p></div></div>
                    <div type="item"><div type="item"><head>DSPORT AND PLAY</head></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>A. S. C. </head></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>GOLF COMPETITIONS.</head>
                            <p>We are requested by the Golf Steward 'o state that the “Alexandria Sporting Club Challenge Cap and G«-1I Medal.” which was played for for the first time last May-June, and won by Judge Percival, is now again to be competed for. Play, as before, will be by handicap, 18 holes. Entrance P.T. 20. Entries will close on Tuesday, 7th inst., at 6 p.m.
                            Members wishing to compete should write their names on the "golf notice" regarding the competition which has been posted up inside the club house building at the Sporting Club.
                            On the same date entries will close for the Mowing additional competitions ;(1). Handicap Match. Play 18 holes. Entrance P.T. 12. (2). Score competition 18 holes under Handicap. Entrance P.T. 12. (3). Handicap Four somes. Entrance P.T. 12. Entrance fees should be paid to the Golf Secretary.</p></div>
                    </div><div type="item"><head>FOOTBALL</head></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>BOULAC v. A. S. CORPS.</head>
                            <p>This match was played at Boulac on Friday last before some 200 spectators. Boulac won the toes and defended the Embabeh end. The play all through the match was very fast and Boulac supporters saw their team to the best advantage After a few minutes play, Boulac, by their forwards tricky conventions, scored their first goal with a fine shot of Mr. Barn's from a difficult angle. More goals were scored, and at half-time the soon stood at 3-0 in Boulac's favor. On the resumption of play the A. S. Corps started with great-dash and determination, and their forwards’ efforts were crowned with a goal, neatly shot by Williams. Gradually the home forwards began to regain their, for a short while, lost combination, which enabled them to register an additional 3 goals before the game concluded, and thus left Boulac victorious by 6-1 goals. The goal scorers for Boulac were C. J. Esau 2, Mahmud 1, W. Hayes 1, T. Smith 1, and G. Attwood 1, and for the losers, Williams, as already stated.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>CAIRO THEATRICAL SEASON.</head>
                            <p>In addition to the performances which M. Salvini and M. ALbert Lambert will give at the Khedivial Opera House, Cairo, M. Le Bardy, the secretary of the Comedie Francoise will give some performances in the coming season. The plays to be produced will be: Le Duel, le Dedale, le Marquis de Priola, le Reveil Gringoir, le Demi Monde, On ne badine pas avec l'amour, lautre danger. Il ne faut jurer de rien, I' Enigma et I' Etransgere </p></div>
                        <div type="item"><head>Passenger List.</head>
                            <head>ARRIVAL</head>
                            <p>Le paquebot “Niger” des Meengerisi Maritime arrive hier de Marseille avait à bord
                                Famille Ralli, MM, Doubre. Tambey.Cover Laolecbe, E. M. Word, Mae Walker, M. André Aghioo, Mlle flamant Fahmy, Mme Jaeqoet, M. Sohmidt, Mm Dmoiai, M. J.C. Mander Mme G. Wamnar, M C.Wamner,M. Maire* M. Vereri F. Canba, M. Fuek, Mme Boche* man, MM. Beyerié, P, Eodeok, Dr. Jf. G. flbed, Famille I. Ricard, Famille flofiog M. et Mme Àr t Khalil bey, M. et Mme Poîlay bey et Me, fil Hoeaein Blhaahab, Mme Dietrioh et 9 enj faute, M. et Mme Bianohi, Famille Galimbwti, Famille Matton,Mma Malaral, MM.ConlloDge, Raden, de Skgoyer, Berheim, Markeoi.Femuiti# M. Joodet, Mme K oaaelet et entant^ M. Bayera, Mlle Verion, famille Antofegei famille $aalt, M. et Mme Batel, Mlle Batel, famille fiébert Mme Saaanne Pin,Mme Barthe Dejeah, M. Wank, M. Gaiabet, Mme Belevoir Mme Haye et fillette, M. et Mme Rivolliet Min et Mlle Fleurent, Mrs. Deboanne, M. Bédouin, M. Abdallat flabat, Mmes D'Aeiae et Débemy, M. Tani, M. et Mme Moletix, Mlle Qoliger, M. André, M. Ootombani, M. Schéhadé, M. Poilay Bey, M. et Mme Gay, M. Prerisaiok et fila, M. et Mme Beyerle, Mme Vemlat, M. Reggio, Mlle Caneri. M. Blayden et 69 passagers de 3me et 4me classes.</p></div>
                        <div type="item"><p>Beck AND Co’s Pilsener Beer.
                            BREMEN.
                            IN CAIRO. ALSXiNDRIA AND THB SUDAN. Otherwise apply ts
                            L J. FLEURENT, F. MIGALLEF, sou a^
                            ---	u.1---— **	-
                            WINDSOR HOTEL
                            Table d'Hete Leaabaeae 4 Dlaeere tewtl aa tbe Terraee.
                            ORCHESTRA PLATS 6 TO 1U0 PJf
                            NUSTON AERATED WATERS
                            Guaranteed IMstUled.
                            t.Ba«.**** I</p></div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
