<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-11-26">November 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-12">12 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, JULY 12, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="international" source="wire">
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>JAPS AT SAGHALIEN.</head>
                        <head type="sub">CAPE NOTOKO OCCUPIED.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese have now occupied Cape Notoro, the southernmost point in
                                Saghalien. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese occupy Cape Notoro, south of Saghalien. (Havas.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>THE PEACE COMMISSION.</head>
                            <head type="sub">ITINERARY OF PLENIPOTENTIARIES.</head>
                            <dateline>Washington, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>The plenipotentiaries will assemble in the Government Navy Yard at
                                Portsmouth (N.H.), which is a cool and comfortable town. They will
                                first meet at New York and proceed in two cruisers to Oyster Bay, to
                                greet President Roosevelt, and thence by separate vessels to
                                Portsmouth. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>RUSSIAN UNREST.</head>
                            <head type="sub">MARTIAL LAW AT TIFLIS.</head>
                            <dateline>St. Petersburg, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>Martial law has been proclaimed at Tiflis, indicating the gravity of
                                the situation, but there is no news from that city. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>PREFECT OF MOSCOW KILLED</head>
                            <head type="sub">SHOT BY A PETITIONER.</head>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Moscow, July 11.</dateline>
                                <p>Count Schuvaloff, prefect of this city, was assassinated by a
                                    revolver shot while he was receiving petitions. The murderer has
                                    been arrested. (Reuter.) </p>
                            </div>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Moscow, July 11. </dateline>
                                <p>The prefect, M. Schuvaloff has been shot dead with a revolver by
                                    a visitor, who has been arrested. (Havas.) </p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>THE MOROCCAN AGREEMENT.</head>
                            <head type="sub">FRENCH PAPERS SATISFIED.</head>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Paris, July 11.</dateline>
                                <p>The French papers are satisfied with the agreement with regard to
                                    Morocco, as terminating the most serious crisis of the past 35
                                    years, but they do not attempt to blink at the fact that France
                                    has made heavy concessions. (Reuter.)</p>
                            </div>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>London, July 11.</dateline>
                                <p>House of Lords. — Lord Lansdowne announced that Great Britain
                                    will most certainly accept the proposal, which France will no
                                    doubt make, to join the Moroccan conference. (Reuter.)</p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>ELECTORAL REDISTRIBUTION</head>
                            <head type="sub">NOTICE OF MOTION IN HOUSE.</head>
                            <dateline>London, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>Mr. Balfour gave notice of a motion to make a redistribution of
                                constituencies on the basis of population. This redistribution will
                                give England seventeen more members, of which five for London and
                                six for the suburbs, Wales one more, Scotland four more, and Ireland
                                twenty-two less. (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>COLLIERY EXPLOSION IN WALES.</head>
                            <head type="sub">144 MEN ENTOMBED.</head>
                            <dateline>London, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>There has been a colliery explosion, which has entombed 144 men, at
                                Wattstown,Rhondda Valley. It is believed that all have perished.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>NORWAY.</head>
                            <head type="sub">PRINCE CHARLES PROPOSED AS KING.</head>
                            <dateline>Christiania, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>Prince Charles of Denmark has been proposed as King of Norway.
                                (Reuter.) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>DEATH OF SIR WILLIAM MUIR.</head>
                            <dateline>London, July 11.</dateline>
                            <p>Sir William Muir is dead. (Reuter.) </p>
                            <p>Sir Wm. Muir, K.C.S.I., LL.D., D.C.L., Ph. D., son of Mr. William
                                Muir, of Glasgow, was born in 1819. He was educated at the
                                Universities of Edinburgh and Glasgow; entered the Bengal Civil
                                Service in 1837 ; was Secretary to the Government of India in the
                                foreign department; was appointed Provisional Member of the Governor
                                General’s Council in India in Dec. 1867 and Lieutenant-Governor of
                                the North-West Provinces in 1868 ; was invested with the order of
                                the Star of India in 1867 ; appointed Financial Member of the
                                Council of the Governor General of India in 1874 ; and retired in
                                1876 ; Member of the Council of India, 1876 to 1885. In 1885 he was
                                appointed principal of the University of Edinburgh, in succession to
                                the late Sir Alexander Grant, and remained such until 1902, when he
                                retired. He was created an honorary D.C.L. of the University of
                                Oxford in 1882, and Ph. D. of Bologna in 1888. His works are : “The
                                Life of Mahomet and History of Islam, to the Era of the Hegira," 4
                                vols, Lond., 1858 61, third edit., 1 vol., 1894; "Annals of the
                                Early Caliphate,” 1883 ; “The Caliphate,” 2nd edit., 1893 ; “The
                                Korân, it Composition and teaching, and the Testimony it bears to
                                the Holy Scriptures,” 1878 ; “Extrcts from the Korân, with English
                                rendering, 1880 ; ‘‘The Apology of Al-Kinly,” 1881 and 1897 ; “The
                                Early Caliphate and Rise of Islam, being the Rede Lecture for 1881,
                                delivered before the University of Cambridge ; “Sweet First-Fruits,”
                                1893, etc. </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="section" scope="local">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Railway Accident. —</head>
                            <p>A Syrian was run over and killed by a Matarieh train yesterday. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>The Brindisi Mail</head>
                            <p> will be distributed at the G.P.O. Alexandria, at 9.30 p.m. to-day.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>The Plague.—</head>
                            <p>Yesterday’s bulletin records a fresh case and a recovery at
                                Damanhour, and a recovery at Alexandria. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>The Zizinia Theatre</head>
                            <p>and ground surrounding it have been sold to the Société d’Entreprises
                                Rurales for the sum of L.E. 88,000. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Beau-Rivage Hotel —</head>
                            <p>A small dance will be given at the Beau Rivage Hotel, Ramleh, on
                                Saturday next, and promises to be a great success.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                            <p>found in the Khalifa district of Cairo during the night of Friday and
                                at daylight on Saturday will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Suez Canal.—</head>
                            <p>18 vessels passed through the Canal on the 8th and 9th inst., 12 of
                                which were British, 2 French, 2 German, 2 Italian. The receipts for
                                the two days were frs. 515,555.45, making the total from the 1st
                                inst. frs. 2,641,724.34. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Salt and Soda Co.—</head>
                            <p>The sales of salt during June amounted to L.E. 20,546.472, as against
                                L.E. 20,791.393 in June, 1904; the total sales for the half year,
                                January to June, 1905, being L.E. 128,896.544, while in the
                                corresponding period of 1904 they were L.E. 131,929.225. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Ice Plant for Alexandria.—</head>
                            <p>We understand that an ice-making plant on a large scale has been
                                ordered by Messrs. R. Aspden &amp; Co., the well-known Alexandrian
                                ice manufacturers, from the British Engineering Co. of Egypt, Ltd.
                                The new plant is to be an addition to their already extensive
                                installation in Alexandria. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>San Stefano Casino.—</head>
                            <p>The management of the Casino has engaged the services of three
                                singers, two male and one female, from Milan for the summer season.
                                The artistes will sing on the terrace of the Casino, to the
                                accompaniment of the Bracale orchestra. Evidently, the Casino
                                management are leaving no stone unturned to make the resort as
                                attractive as possible. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>Association des Courtiers en Marchandises.—</head>
                            <p>The committee of the Association des Courtiers en Marchandises
                                informs us that Mr. Angelo O. Fiteni has been appointed secretary to
                                the association in place of the late E. C. Manuk, who had held that
                                post since its foundation. Mr. Fiteni is a man of wide business
                                experience, having been in the employment of Messrs. Barker and
                                Company for the last 23 years, and is eminently fitted to occupy the
                                post to which he has been appointed. </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>FRENCH FETE.</head>
                            <byline>( From our Correspondent. )</byline>
                            <dateline>Port Said, Tuesday.</dateline>
                            <p>The usual preparations for the French fête of the 14th July are now
                                well in hand and will be completed in good time. There will be a
                                number of races of various kinds in an enclosure which has been
                                prepared in front of the French Consulate, a gala performance at the
                                Eldorado, and the usual illuminations and firework display at night
                                in the harbour. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>BRITISH WARSHIPS.</head>
                            <p>H.M.S. Lancaster left here this morning for a cruise and firing
                                practice. She is to return at noon to-morrow. It is at present
                                intended that both British vessels in harbour shall leave about the
                                20th of the month. </p>
                            <p>H.M.S. Albion, Ocean, Vengeance, and Centurion are due here about
                                Sunday from China. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>GOING ON LEAVE.</head>
                            <p>By the Messageries S.S. Senegal, leaving to-morrow, M. and Mme
                                Perrichi are going to Marseilles. The former, who is port captain,
                                is being replaced while on leave by M. Cendres, the senior harbour
                                officer. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>THE CONGAL.</head>
                            <p>The famous Congal, empty, desolate-looking, covered with dried
                                sea-weed and rust, has been patched and towed away from the harbour
                                proper to the back of the coal islands, there to remain for probably
                                some time, as I understand hitches have again occurred in the
                                arrangements between those interested as regards her ultimate
                                disposal. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <head>THE MONSOON.</head>
                            <p>The P. and O. mail steamer Britannia has arrived some hours late. She
                                reports having experienced an extraordinarily heavy S. W. monsoon.
                                Her funnels are quite white with salt and she appears to have had a
                                bad voyage.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>DEATH OF GRAND MUFTI.</head>
                        <head type="sub">FUNERAL AT CAIRO TO-DAY.</head>
                        <p> We deeply regret to announce the death, which took place at Seffer,
                            Ramleh, at 5.15 p.m. yesterday, of Sheikh Mobamed Abdou, Grand Mufti of
                            Egypt. The deceased, who succumbed to cancer of the liver, had been
                            ailing for some considerable time past, but it was only within the past
                            week that fears were entertained of a fatal issue. Indeed, it was Sheikh
                            Mohamed Abdou's intention to have left a week or two ago on a voyage to
                            Europe and Morocco. However, “Man proposes and God disposes,’’ and the
                            sheikh who has done so much, and seemed destined to do so much more, for
                            the enlightenment of his co-religionists has passed away at the
                            comparatively early age of 57 years. His death will be deeply mourned,
                            not only by the Moslems in Egypt, and indeed throughout the East, but by
                            a large number of friends and admirers of other faiths. </p>
                        <p>The deceased’s body, which is to be interred at Cairo, was removed this
                            morning from Mohamed Bay Rasim’s house at Seffer station, where he died,
                            and conveyed by tram-car to the Ramleh Railway terminus, where it
                            arrived at 10 o’clock. On its arrival there the body was met by all the
                            notables who were able to be present, among whom we noticed the Acting
                            Regent, Hussein Pasha Fakhry, Riaz Pasha, Mazloum Pasha, Aziz Pasha
                            Izzet, Undersecretary of State for Foreign Affairs, Ibrahim Pasha
                            Neguib, Under-Secretary, Ministry of the Inferior, Mr. Mansfield de C.
                            Findlay, British Charge d’Affaires, the President of the Court of Appeal
                            and other judges of the various Courts, in their robes of office, the
                            Sub-Governor, Abdul Halim Pasha Assem, Mahmoud Pasha Fehmy, Mr. Ralli
                            and many other members of the Municipality, the Cadi of Alexandria and
                            the Mufti Nakib el Ashraf, El Said Abdul Rahitn el Dunerdachi, Mohamed
                            Shakir, Sheikh el Ulema, etc. Escorted by detachments of Cavalry,
                            Infantry, Police, and Coastguardsmen, the pupils of the Orwa el Woska
                            and Makarim el Akhlak Schools, and the Porters’ Benevolent Society, the
                            imposing procession started for Moharrem Bey station, where a special
                            train, which had been placed at the disposal of the family by the
                            Railway Administration, was in readiness to convey the body to Cairo. </p>
                        <p>This train left at 11 a.m. for Cairo, where it was due to arrive at 2
                            p.m. Among those who accompanied the mortal remains of the late Grand
                            Mufti to the Capital were Mohamed Shakir, Sheik el-Ulema, and the other
                            ulema of Alexandria, besides the family and relatives of the deceased,
                            who had come down from Cairo to be present with him at the end. On their
                            arrival at Cairo the remains will be taken to the Al Azhar Mosque for
                            the usual ceremony, after which the interment will take place at El
                            Megawreen Cemetery. </p>
                        <p>The late Sheikh Mohamed Abdou was born at Mehallet Nasr, Sheibrakhit
                            district, Behera, in 1848, his father being Sheikh Abdou, a cultivator.
                            He was educated at Al Azhar University and in the year 1295 A.H.
                            received the final certificate of the “Alimieh.” He was appointed editor
                            of the “Official Journal,” aud having been accused of being one of the
                            mutineers of the revolution, was exiled and condemned in 1882. Going to
                            Beyrout, he there married the daughter of Sheikh Hamada. At Beyrout he
                            engaged in religious and theological studies, and was finally pardoned
                            in 1892. Shortly after arriving in Egypt he became judge of the Court of
                            First Instance at Benha and afterwards at Zagazig. He was then promoted
                            to a judgeship in the Native Court of Appeal. In June, 1899, he was
                            appointed Grand Mufti of Egypt by H.H, the Khedive in place of Sheikh
                            Hassouna el Nawawi, and was a member of the Council of Administration of
                            Al Azhar from 1894 until his retirement recently. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>NILE BRIDGES.</head>
                        <p>We learn that no project for the construction of a bridge from Boulac to
                            Ghezireh has as yet been decided upon, but the question is receiving
                            full consideration at the hands of the officials of the Public Works
                            Department, who recognise the great advantage to be derived by direct
                            communication with Ghezireh by the continuation of Boulac road by means
                            of bridge. Soundings have been taken and various schemes have been
                            examined, but no decision can be arrived at until the return of the many
                            Government officials who are at present away on leave. We also learn
                            that an offer for the supply of funds has been made by a local
                            syndicate. We are unable to learn the terms upon which this offer was
                            made, but the acceptance of it is, we understand, very doubtful.</p>
                        <p>Before any such scheme can be finally fixed upon we anticipate seeing the
                            work of widening the Kasr el Nil Bridge started, and this will be a
                            great advantage for its present width makes it altogether inadequate for
                            the immense amount of traffic which passes over it. The work will, we
                            understand, be commenced before the completion of the bridge at present
                            in course of construction at Rodah, and therefore there will be no means
                            of decreasing the traffic, which will of necessity become much more
                            congested by the space which will be sacrificed to the work of widening.
                            Would it not be better to delay the alteration of the Kasr el Nil Bridge
                            until such time as there is another bridge to relieve the traffic to
                            some extent ?</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article" scope="advertisement">
                        <p>CARLTON HOTEL Bulkeley, Ramleh. Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Claas
                            in every respect. Very moderate charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable
                            English quarter. Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi Gabtr station. G.
                            Aquilina, proprietor.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>

                    <div type="article">
                        <head>THE COTTON WORM.</head>
                        <head type="sub">AN ARMY OF PICKERS.</head>
                        <p>The number of feddans of land under cotton cultivation in the Behera
                            attacked by the cotton worm amounted on the 8th inst. to no less than
                            40,443. The largest infected area is in the markazes of Teh el Baroud
                            and Kafr Dawar, and the number of boys available in these markazes
                            having been exhausted, reinforcements were drafted in from Sheibrakhit
                            and Damanhour. It having, however, been found that the total number of
                            corvéables in the whole province was no longer sufficient to cope with
                            the pest, the Ministry of the Interior authorised the importation of 800
                            boys from Gharbieh, and within 24 hours of the reception of the order
                            the whole number was despatched and placed at the disposal of the Moudir
                            of Behera. It is hoped that the total number now engaged in Behera
                            province, more than 50,273, will suffice to deal with the eggs as fast
                            as they are laid and avert the possibility of serious damage. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>RUSSIAN CRUISER AT SUEZ.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                        <dateline>Suez, Tuesday.</dateline>
                        <p>The Russian cruiser Rion arrived at 10.30 last night and entered the
                            Canal at four o’clock this morning. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>FIRE AT LUXOR STATION.</head>
                        <p>A telegram from our Keneh Correspondent states that a fire occurred
                            yesterday at 2 p.m. in Luxor station, burning 450 sacks of tibn and some
                            railway fencing. The conflagration lasted two hours. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head> A NEW STEAMSHIP LINE.</head>
                        <p>The Berlin Correspondent of “Commercial Intelligence” writes </p>
                        <p>German interest in North African ports is about to receive farther
                            expression by the inauguration of a new steamship line connecting them
                            with Hamburg. I understand that a Belgian shipping company will join the
                            projected concern. Particular attention is to be paid in the first place
                            to Egypt. There seems to be ground for assuming that the enterprise has
                            resulted from the extraordinary German mission to Abyssinia. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>CREDIT FONCIER EGYPTIAN.</head>
                        <p>At the extraordinary general meeting of the shareholders of the Credit
                            Foncier Egyptian the ratification of the convention between the Daira
                            Sanieh, Ltd., and this society was unanimously decided upon. The
                            liquidation of the Daira Sanieh will take place on October 1, 1905.</p>
                    </div>

                    <div type="article">
                        <head>A NEW EGYPTIAN COMPANY.</head>
                        <p>Egyptian Gold and Emerald Company, Limited.—Registered June 28th, by
                            Worthington, Evans, Dauney and Co., 27, Nicholas Lane, E. C. Capital
                            £300,000, in £1 shares. Objects : To acquire from the Sudan Finance
                            Syndicate, Limited, certain mining rights or concessions over lands in
                            Egypt ; to adopt an agreement with the above named syndicate, E. W.
                            Streeter and the Egyptian Gold and Gem Syndicate, Limited ; and to carry
                            on the business of miners, explorers, prospectors, winners and workers
                            of and dealers in precious stones, company promoters, financiers, etc.
                            The signatories are :— </p>
                        <table cols="4">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell/>
                                <cell>Shares</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>W. T. Johns,</cell>
                                <cell>68, Palmerston House, E.C.,</cell>
                                <cell>secretary</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>R. A. Fremantle,</cell>
                                <cell>9 Tokenhouse Yard, E.C.,</cell>
                                <cell>stockbroker</cell>
                                <cell>200</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Sir F. Frankland, Bart.,</cell>
                                <cell>2, Queen’s Gardens, Windsor</cell>
                                <cell>(by his agent, F. H. King)</cell>
                                <cell>200</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>S. Lee,</cell>
                                <cell>Langdale, Harrow,</cell>
                                <cell>director of United African Explorations, Limited (by his
                                    agent, C. F. Palmer)</cell>
                                <cell>200</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>J. Pasfield,</cell>
                                <cell>68, Palmerston House. E.C.,</cell>
                                <cell>secretary</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>F. T. Carter,</cell>
                                <cell>3a, Ramsden Road, Friern Barnet,</cell>
                                <cell>accountant</cell>
                                <cell>l</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. J. Pegg, 28,</cell>
                                <cell>Park Crescent, Clapham, S.W.,</cell>
                                <cell>clerk</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>H. H. Prockter,</cell>
                                <cell>Fox Hill, Upper Norwood, </cell>
                                <cell>registrar</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>A. P. Mack,</cell>
                                <cell>68, Palmerston House, E. C.,</cell>
                                <cell>managing director of the Nile Valley Company, Limited</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                        <p>Minimum cash subscription, £50,000. The directors may borrow up to the
                            amount of the nominal-capital without the sanction of a general meeting.
                            The number of directors is not to be less that two nor more than seven.
                            The first are : R. A. Fremantle, Sir F. Frankland, S. Lee, A. P. Mack
                            and E. W. Streeter, F.R.G.S., M.A.I., of 15 Buckingham Palace Gardens,
                            S.W. Qualification, 200 shares. Remuneration (except managing director),
                            £200 per annum (£50 extra for the chairman) and a share in the surplus
                            profits after 10 per cent, dividend is paid. The Egyptian Gold and Gem
                            Syndicate, Limited, has the right to nominate one director, the first
                            being the said E. W. Streeter. The said syndicate undertakes to pass a
                            resolution changing its name as soon as practicable. Registered office,
                            68-74, Palmerston House, Old Broad Street, E.C. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article" scope="advertisement">
                        <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; hotel company. RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS
                            BETVEEI ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO Three Sailings a-Week. Agents at
                            Alexandria— ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LD.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES</head>
                        <head type="sub">COMMERCIAL DEVELOPMENTS.</head>
                        <byline>(From our Correspondent).</byline>
                        <dateline>Constantinople, July 4.</dateline>
                        <p>The newly-founded financial establishment, the Orient Bank, will open its
                            branches in Cairo and Alexandria very shortly. Messrs. Frankoudi and
                            Rodocanachi have been appointed managers of these branches, the first at
                            Cairo and the other at Alexandria. </p>
                        <p>I hear that still another financial estahlishment is to be founded here,
                            with the object of increasing the commercial relations batween Egypt and
                            Turkey. The amount of the capital will be 250,000 Turkish pounds, and
                            its title will be “Société Financière pour le Commerce et l’lndustrie.”
                            The statutes of the company have been sent to the Grand Viziriete and
                            the Ottoman Ministry of Commerce. The project is signed by Emir Zadé,
                            Khalil Bey, and M. Tchimara. </p>
                        <p>It is announced that a group of Hellenes, natives of Volo, have decided
                            to create a Thessalian Steamship Company, with a regular service between
                            Egypt, Constantinople, and the ports of the Black Sea. The object of
                            this company is to facilitate the exportation of the products of
                            Thessaly to Egypt and Turkey. It is announced also that negotiations
                            have been opened for the purchase of three new steamers of 5,000 tons
                            each, with a speed of from 15 to 17 knots. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>THE MAKING OF THE SUDAN.</head>
                        <p>A little while ago a paragraph in “The African World” announced the fact
                            that the Suakin Railway would be completed early next year. Subsequent
                            advices show that the work of construction is being pushed ahead with
                            commendable energy. The value of the line to the Sudan and its
                            population cannot be over-estimated. It will carry goods from Khartoum
                            to the sea in twenty-four hours, where six days are now required for
                            transportation along the 1,500 miles of rail and river between the Sudan
                            and the Egyptian ports. The advantages of the new arrangement are so
                            manifest as hardly to need mention. It is safe to say that no single
                            factor will contribute so largely to the development of the great
                            territory won from the Mahdi. The Sudan is capable of great
                            fruitfulness. Cotton and grain it should produce in abundance. But
                            markets are essential. The Suakin Railway provides the shortest cut to
                            the markets, which, without that or another railway, might, so far as
                            the Sudan is concerned, as well be non-existent. ("African World") </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>A PORT SAID NUISANCE.</head>
                        <p>A Port Said correspondent writes:—One wonders how long the suffering
                            inhabitants of Port Said will pot up with the incessant whistling from
                            steamers and tugs. There is no reason for it, the signals are
                            meaningless and not in conformity with the International Code; they are
                            also misleading. The Germans are the worst offenders, but they cannot
                            take a ship in or out of port without music. Once upon a time a steamer
                            that whistled for her agent had to wait half-an-hour after the last
                            performance, but that good rule has dropped into abeyance. In Australia,
                            Japan, Hong Kong, etc., anybody can indulge in the luxury of waking the
                            town up with the whistle, but he has to pay a heavy fine for his fun,
                            and there is no reason why it should not be same at Port Said. Steamers
                            also leave their masthead and sidelights on when fast to the buoys in a
                            most casual manner, so that it is impossible to tell if they are under
                            weigh or not: this will lead to a serious accident some day. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section">
                        <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>A. S. C.</head>
                            <head type="sub">NOTICE TO OWNERS.</head>
                            <p>The committee have decided to consider the races for Earopean horses,
                                announced for next year, as sufficiently filled, and they will take
                                place as published subject as below. In consequence, however, of
                                these races not having received quite as much support as was hoped
                                they will all be left open until the 1st October next and other
                                subscriptions can be taken before that date. Existing subscriptions
                                will hold good. </p>
                            <p>Unless 20 subscriptions are received for the Continental Stakes, the
                                stakes will be reduced to L.E. 250, of which L.E. 30 to the 2nd and
                                L.E. 20 to the 3rd horse. Subscription L.E. 5 and nomination L.E. 5
                                on 1st December 1905. </p>
                            <p>The stakes in Lord of Rosna Stakes, Centenary Handicap, and
                                International Handicap will in any case remain as published. </p>
                            <p>The National Stakes for Arabs and E.C.B.’s, Class II., will also be
                                left open till 1st October, 1905, and if by that date at least 10
                                subscriptions have not been received the stakes will be slightly
                                altered, viz.: L.E. 100 to the 1st horse with a sweepstakesof L.E. 2
                                to go to 2nd horse. Subscriptions and nominations to remain as at
                                present. </p>
                            <p>All the remaining big races for 1906 will take place as published. </p>
                            <p>A. S. Preston, Hon. Secretary, A.S.C.</p>
                            <p>26232-1</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <p>EGLISH PENSION, ITALIAN RIVIERA. The best halfway home between Egypt and
                            England ii VLAXGOLO, Mar PtSA. Main line exp— stop. Pine woods, Sands,
                            Boa bathing •wild elimate, MugliMh Pmrtea. Villa Shallay. Inr heme
                            eemfort. Hwtrta light Modern Matatfca, huy fUMtel—to — and gardens.
                            P—Hfraia. IlfUSV ttllR</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>ON THE HEDJAZ RAILWAY.</head>
                        <byline> BY P. P. G.</byline>
                        <head type="sub">VIII.</head>
                        <p>While I walked about the slopes N. of Ma’ân and watched the trains
                            steaming out with railway material, sleepers, rails, ballast, and so
                            forth to carry on the line to the south, I suddenly noticed that it was
                            growing strangely dark and that a brutally cold wind had sprung up. I
                            next discovered that it was raining half a mile away and that the rain
                            was moving rapidly in my direction. There was no sort of shelter
                            anywhere near me : I was a good mile from the station, the nearest tents
                            were a good half-mile away, and it struck me that a European rushing
                            into a tent might cause considerable surprise and annoyance to its
                            occupants. In this I was mistaken for there were several Italian workmen
                            at Ma’ân, and soldiers were quite familiar with the sight of Europeans,
                            but had I thus sought refuge the chances were in favor of my getting
                            into a tent where Turkish women were quartered and causing a panic among
                            their spouses. One always does the wrong thing under such circumstances,
                            and after my experience with the tinned meat I had no desire to tempt
                            fortune any farther. </p>
                        <p>The rain arrived while I was looking aimlessly about me, preceded by a
                            violent gale that caught up all the dust in the desert for the rain
                            which followed it to lay again. Then came the rain and soaked me to the
                            skin but brought its recompense with it. While I ran down a gully
                            looking for some cleft or projecting rock where I could take cover, I
                            put up two gazelles which dashed like the wind across the wadi,
                            disappeared over a slope, and appeared again a moment later like two
                            brown flecks on the black plain that ran eastward. </p>
                        <p>When I got back to the station I found a Circassian, who was helping the
                            Greek station-master, and would no doubt become a station-master himself
                            one day. He frowned and made fearful grimaces, which were emphasised by
                            the rugged ferocity of his features, over what appeared to be a piece of
                            simple addition. M. Nikola, the station-master, turned to me from time
                            to time with a resigned gesture of amused contempt while his
                            subordinate, gripping the pen as if it were a dagger, made error after
                            error, which he corrected with the aid of sand and a stout penknife. M.
                            Nikola ordered tea with lemons (Ma’ân supplies no milk) and we drank,
                            the Circassian in particular disposing of several cups and dipping his
                            pen into ink or tea with a sublime indifference. </p>
                        <p>The station-master was called away, the Circassian put away his papers,
                            eyed me, and then said something ending in—orsun. I took it to mean “can
                            you speak Tarkish” and replied in my best kitchen Arabic, that splendid
                            language spoken by Englishmen to their Egyptian servants and learnt from
                            the industrious Berberin, who, as everyone knows has <hi rend="italic"
                                >such</hi> a good pronunciation of Arabic. To my joy the Tcherkess
                            answered me in equally bad and simple Arabic, and we conversed with
                            numerous pauses while we wrestled with the right phrases that refused to
                            be uttered or even remembered. A soldier from Aleppo grinned at our
                            Arabic solecisms and threw in a word now and again. </p>
                        <p>Yes ! I came from Egypt and Aziz Effendim from—well, I doubt if he knew
                            himself. He had been in Egypt, had seen the Zoological Gardens, where an
                            elephant had impressed him, and knew the Mousky quarter. He also had
                            been to a theatre in the Esbekieh. Fearing “startling disclosures” I
                            changed the subject and asked him how he liked Egypt . . but alas ! he
                            absolutely refused to puff the British Occupation or say a word for the
                            Agency. The utmost he would allow was that Lord Cromer was skilled in
                            “politika.” For him Egypt was a hopeless place where you could not ride
                            about after the manner of Hybrias the Cretan, armed and overbearing, and
                            where fighting was forbidden. His brother had been as far as Italy and
                            had fought a duel there. He himself had been to Aleppo, where the people
                            were like mules, bastards, neither Turk nor Arab (this to the address of
                            the Halebi soldier), and thieves. He had been at Diarbekir and Kharpat
                            in the time of the troubles, where he killed three Armenians with his
                            revolver while they ran, and “we destroyed all of them and burnt their
                            houses.” Inshallah, there would be a war with the Bulgarians soon. As
                            for the Ingliz, why did they wish to take Arabia and sell guns to the
                            rebels? This to my address.</p>
                        <p> (To be continued) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="section" scope="social">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>According to the “Tachydromos,” Mr. N. Scotides, Greek Consul
                                General, has been called to Athens by his Government, and leaves
                                to-day by the Khedivial mail steamer. His departure has given rise
                                to various conjectures. It is believed that he is going to settle
                                some pending questions corceming the Hellenic consular service and
                                interests in Egypt.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>Scander Pasha Fahmy and his two sons, Michel and Tewfik Fahmy, left
                                Cairo last night for Port Said, where they will embark to-day on the
                                Bibby S.S. Staffordshire for Marseilles. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>We regret to learn that M. G. Nagelmacker, director and founder of
                                the International Sleeping Car Co., died at Cannes on Monday evening
                                last.</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="item">
                            <p>Mr. Hood, chief engineer, Egyptian State Railways, and Mrs. Hood left
                                Egypt yesterday for England by the P. &amp; O. S.S. Britannia. </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
