<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Amber Fling</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">October 26, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">November 25, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7,335] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, November 25, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES
                    P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CABINET NOT TO RESIGN.</head>
                    <head type="sub">DISSOLUTION DEFERRED.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>London</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>It is understood that the Cabinet has decid- ed not to resign.</p>
                    <p>The meeting of the Cabinet lasted two hours. It is stated that the decision
                        of the Government was largely influenced by the knowledge that the Liberals
                        would not accept office prior to disoIution, and, therefore, until
                        Parliament meets again, it defers resigning or dissolving for a few weeks,
                        thus avoiding at the same time an election at Christmastide and the
                        neceisity of a shortlived interim government.</p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. Balfour</persName> has left town until Monday. He is not going
                        to Sandringham. The Cabinet will meet again on the 1st proximo. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOME RULE FOR IRELAND.</head>
                    <head type="sub">C.B.’s POLICY</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>London</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Speaking at Stirling, Sir Henry Campbell- Bannerman openly declared himself
                        as being in favor of Home Rule for Ireland, saying that his conviction on
                        this matter was stronger than ever. He advised the Nationalists, how- ever,
                        to accept any instalment of representative control that might be offered,
                        provided that it led up to a larger policy.</p>
                    <p>The newspapers continue to take Mr. Bal- four's resignation for granted. The
                        “Morning Post” says that Mr. Chamberlain and not Mr. Baltour will lead the
                        Unionists at the elections. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOST-FAVORED NATION CLAUSE.</head>
                    <head type="sub">BECOME OBSOLETE.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Liverpool</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Lord Lansdowne, speaking here, said that the most-favored nation clause has
                        become obsolete, and Great Britain must rely more upon contracts and
                        bargains in which her interests are specially provided for.</p>
                    <p>He gave as an instance the new treaty with Persia replacing the old
                        favored-nation arrange- ment. lf there should be any tampering with the
                        Persian tariff in future, Great Britain will have to be consulted first.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PORTE DEFIANT.</head>
                    <head type="sub">THREAT OF FANATICAL OUTBREAK.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Constantinople</placeName>, <date>November
                        24.</date></dateline>
                    <p>The Porte’s reply to the Powers is unusually defiant and closes with a veiled
                        threat of a Mussulman outbreak if the pressure of the Powers in favor of
                        Christians continues. (R.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR C. HARDINGE AT THE FOREIGN OFFICE.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>London</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p><persName>Sir C. Hardinge</persName>, Ambassador at <placeName>St. Peters-
                            burg</placeName>, replaces <persName>Sir Thomas Sanderson</persName>, of
                        the Foreign Office, who is retiring. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COURT.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>London</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>Queen Alexandra and the King of Greece will go to Sandrigham to-day, where
                        they will be joined by the King. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZEMSTVOS CONGRESS.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Moscow</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The congress of delegates of the Zemstvos has voted in favor of direct
                        suffrage. (Havas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ADMIRAL RODJESTVBNSKY.</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Nagasaki</placeName>, <date>November 24</date>.</dateline>
                    <p><persName>Admiral Rodjestvensky</persName> has left
                            <placeName>Vladivostok</placeName>.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Deschizeaux Beautifying Rooms</head>
                    <p>AMERICAN Graduate Masseuse treats wrin- kles, enlarged pores and all facial
                        blemishes permanently removed, face beautified and rejuvenated. Expert
                        manicure and skilful chy- ropody.</p>
                    <p>6 Rue Cherif Pacha.</p>
                    <p>26754-3 Telephone 89.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                    <head type="sub">235 BRANCHES.</head>
                    <p>French. German. Italian. Greek. Arabic, ate. Private Lessons, Residence
                        Lessons, taught by Native Masters.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA ; B6 Rue do l'Eglise Copto.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO : 1 Sharia Kamol.</p>
                    <p>TRIAL LESSON FREE.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JOSEPH COMAS,</head>
                    <head type="sub">TECHNICAL ENGINEER</head>
                    <p>Surveyor and Contractor in shipping. Takes charge of Engines and Boilers.
                        Undertakes repairs of same, guaranteeing success. First class references.
                        Address: Rue el Warsha, Maison Gabriel, ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>S66W-13A</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Khedivial Accession Fetes.</p>
                    <p>The third list of subscriptions to the fund for tho celebration of the
                        Khedive’s Accession Day brings the total up to L.E. 350.</p>
                    <p>New Khedivial Palace.</p>
                    <p>The Khassa Khedivial has purchased a palace in Cairo, belonging to Princess
                        Faikan Hanem, as a residence for the Khedive’s sons.</p>
                    <p>Erratum.</p>
                    <p>The list of inspectors assigned to the various provinces, appearing in our
                        issue of Thursday, should, of course, have been headed “Ministry of the
                        Interior."</p>
                    <p>Suez Canal.</p>
                    <p>Ten vessels passed through the Canal on the 21st inst., of which 7 were
                        British, 2 German, 1 French. The total receipts from the 1st to the 21st
                        inst. were frs. 7,177,394.61.</p>
                    <p>Charity Performance.</p>
                    <p>An entertainment for the benefit of the orphan school of the Sisters of St.
                        Vincent de Paul will be given to-morrow at the African Mission, Choubrah. M.
                        de la Bouliniere will preside and a very good programme is promised.</p>
                    <p>Egyptian Money Market.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. H. de Vries and Boutigny, stock and share brokers, Cairo, publish a
                        very detailed circular daily on the business of the stock market. This
                        circular, which contains also a great deal of financial information, is sent
                        gratis on application. [Advt.]</p>
                    <p>Coal Imports.</p>
                    <p>From the 1st of January to the 23rd of No- vember 974,918 tons of coal were
                        imported into Egypt. Wales sent 526,310. Newcastle 221,413, Scotland
                        118,203, Yorkshire 72,586, and other places 36,406 tons. During the cor-
                        responding period of 1904 954,081 tons were received.</p>
                    <p>American Diplomacy.</p>
                    <p>President Roosevelt has decided that in future Ambassadors, Ministers, and
                        attaches must know some other language besides English (see newspapers). A
                        knowledge of languages is indispensable in all careers. Berlitz Schools of
                        Languages: 26, Rue de l’Egliso Copte. Alexandria,and 1 ShariaKame’, Cairo.
                        [Advt.]</p>
                    <p>Big Fee for Suez Canal.</p>
                    <p>The Navy Department at Washington has learned that the Suez Canal Company
                        will charge from £4,000 to £5,000 for the passage of the Philippine dry
                        dock, now being built in Cheaspeake Bay. The deck will begin its voyage,
                        under tow, in December, and is ex- pected to reach the Philippines in four
                        months.</p>
                    <p>The Abbas Helmy Fire.</p>
                    <p>This morning the case of Monferrato and the Alexandria Gas Company came on
                        for hearing at the Mixed Tribunals, Alexandria. The case arose out of tho
                        circumstances connected with the fire at the Abbas Helmy Theatre last year.
                        Judgment will be given in a week’s time.</p>
                    <p>Distinguished American Visit.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Bryan, the American Democratic politi- cian, and at one time candidate
                        for the Pre- sidency, is probably, paying a visit to Egypt this season. An
                        American contemporary re- marks:—"Mr. Bryan should make a long and
                        contemplative study of the Sphinx in Egypt. It may give him a pointer on the
                        game in Democratio politics after his return.”</p>
                    <p>Moslem Fete.</p>
                    <p>The Moslem benevolent society will give a fete on Tuesday next at the
                        Esbekieh Gardens, Cairo, under the patronage of H.H. the Khedive. The
                        gardens will be open at 3 p.m. and we are promised a great display of fire-
                        works, with dances, singing, fireworks, and all kinds of music, till the
                        small hours of the morning, while an Arabic drama will be staged at the
                        Opera House at 8.30 p.m.</p>
                    <p>A Princess as Guardian.</p>
                    <p>A native contemporary states that the Princess Nazli Hanem has agreed to act
                        as guardian to her brother, Prince Aly Bey Fadel. Before accepting this post
                        her Highness stipulated that her brother should have nothing to do with the
                        management of his finances, and she has authorised M. R. Suares to deal with
                        his affairs together with Djaafar Bey, son of Fakhri Pasha, counsel to the
                        Princess’s Daira.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOTEL D’AMERIQUE.</head>
                    <p>This morning the case of Adda v. Rosins di Bella came on for hearing before
                        Judge Eeman in the Mixed Civil Court at Alexandria. This was an appeal
                        against the judgment of the Mixed Summary Court, which we published a few
                        weeks ago. The appellant has purchased the building and site known as the
                        Hotel d’Amerique at Alexandria from Mr. Selim Sabounghi, and brought an
                        action against Mrs. Rosina di Bella, the tenant, for resiliation of her
                        lease on the grounds that she had need the hotel for improper purposes
                        although it was specified in the contract that it should simply be need as
                        an hotel-restaurant.</p>
                    <p>Maltre Levi Cuzzer on behalf of Mr. Adda declared that the Hotel d’Amerique
                        was a public scandal, and protested against the judg- ment of the Summary
                        Court.</p>
                    <p>Maltre Guidotti, on behalf of Mrs. Rosina di Bella, declared that Mr. Adda
                        had asked £175 per annum from his client as a permit for her to renew the
                        contract for the hotel. The lady in question had agreed to pay £110 per
                        annum instead of £80, as arranged in the existing contract, which ends on
                        31st Jannary, 1907. But as she would not pay more than £110 the appellant
                        said he would oblige her to quit.</p>
                    <p>Judgment will be given shortly.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD CURZON AT SUEZ.</head>
                    <head type="sub">PROCEEDING TO CAIRO.</head>
                    <head type="sub">(From our Correspondent).</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Suez</placeName>, Saturday.</dateline>
                    <p>Lord and Lady Canon and suite are ex- pected to reach here this afternoon on
                        board the Royal Indian Marine steamer Dufferin. On arrival here they will
                        proceed to Cairo and join the S.S. Mongolia at Port Said later on for
                        Marseilles.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>On Thursday night H.H. the Khedive left Koubbeh for Cairo and was present at
                        the religious ceremony of tho Leilet El Kadr, in the Citadel mosque. With
                        his Highness were the Ministers and Under Secretaries of State, the Governor
                        of Cairo, Ghazi Mukhtar Pasha, Zeki Pasha and the civil and military mem-
                        bers of the Khedivial household, the director general of the Wakfs
                        Administration, the ulema, and numerous natives of high rank.The mosque was
                        most brilliantly illuminated.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday his Highness, with the Ministers, visited the mosque of Amr. On his
                        arrival the 3rd Battery fired the usual salvoes while the guard of honor
                        drawn from the 6th Battalion presented arms. The Khedive entered the mosque,
                        which had been decorated for the occasion, accompanied by the Grand Mufti on
                        his right and H.E. Abdel Halim Pasha Assem on his left. The usual military
                        honors were paid on the departure of his Highness.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday evening the Khedive, after giving several audiences, offered an
                        iftar to the merchants of Cairo.</p>
                    <p>To-day his Highness will preside over the Council of Ministers to be held at
                        Abdeen Palace at 3 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABBASSIEH LUNATIC ASYLUM.</head>
                    <p>Fresh sections are to be added to the Abbas- sieh Lunatic Asylum with a view
                        to increasing the accommodation of the building. A sum of LE. 16,0000 will
                        figure in the next Budget for these additions to the building, the construc-
                        tion of which will be carried out under the supervision of Mr. Price, of the
                        Public Health Department.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FREE STATE LANDS.</head>
                    <p>The cataloguing of Government Free Lands in the Fayoum province has begun.
                        The catalogue of the Menoufieh province will be finished by the end of tho
                        year. The catalogue of the Gharbieh province has just been com- pleted after
                        five months’ work. The catalogue is very detailed and will not be finished
                        for the whole of Egypt for four or five years.</p>
                    <p>Mr. J. T. Foxcroft, late of the Ministry of Public Instruction, has been
                        appointed Finance Inspector to the Free State Lands Depart- ment.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STATE DOMAIN BONDS.</head>
                    <p>Egyptian State Domain Mortgage Bonds to the amount of £29,300 nominal capital
                        have been drawn for payment at par on December 1. The drawing consists of
                        all bonds (not pre- viously cancelled by the operation of the sink- ing
                        fund) comprised in the series of numbers advertised.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN.</head>
                    <p>The Tewfik Palace Hotel, Helonan, is evidently doing very well, and more
                        people seem to appreciate the unique position of which this hotel has the
                        advantage. The gardens, the comfortably sheltered terraces, palmhouses and
                        grottoes make the place a veri- table paradise.</p>
                    <p>Amongst the many visitors now staying at the hotel aro Lord Robert Cecil,
                        Lord Edward Cecil, Lady Cecil, Miss Dickinson, Baron and Baroness de
                        Rosenwerth, Dr. Yeo- man, Dr. Hotchkiss, Mr. Parry, M. and Mrs. Greenwood,
                        Mrs. Parrer, Misses Clemens, Mr. and Mrs. Phillips, Mrs. Hopkins, Mr. Wylie,
                        M. Gazi, M. Hausch, Mrs. Lisener, Miss Uniake.</p>
                    <p>On Friday next an orchestra will perform during tea and dinner, for the
                        benefit of those availing themselves of the "Tewfik week-end."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN GOVERNMENT.</head>
                    <p>The Sudan Government has decided to create a new moudirieh called Mongola,
                        and L.E. 5,000 has been allotted for the purpose.</p>
                    <p>The Sudan Government has also decided to change the name of “Suakin
                        Gouvernorat" to "Red Sea Gouvernorat”</p>
                    <p>It has been further decided to establish a new sanitary administration, to be
                        called the “Local Provincial Service."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MARRIAGE AT MATARIEH.</head>
                    <p>The marriage of M. H. Parodi, professor at the Khedivieh School and chemist
                        to H.H. the Khedive, and MIle Mathilde Bernard, daughter of M. Alex. Bernard
                        Bey, Inspector to the Ministry of Public Instruction, and Mme Bernard, took
                        place at the Matarieh chapel at 3.30 p.m. on Wednesday. After the marriage
                        the parents of the bride gave a reception at their house at Matarieh, which
                        was largely attended by the many friends of the bride and bridegroom.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. City of Cambridge Bailed from Malta last night and is due here on
                        Tuesday at daybreak with passengers, mails, and general cargo.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. City of Khios sailed from Liverpool yesterday for Malta and
                        Alexandria with passengers and general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SALT MONOPOLY</head>
                    <head type="sub">THE NEW AGREEMENT.</head>
                    <p>When the Government decided on the abolition of the salt monopoly it became
                        neces- sary at the same time to settle the line of future policy in order to
                        assure a regular supply of the article. On the one hand, the Government was
                        desirous in the interests of all classes of the population and especially of
                        the poorest, to ma- terially reduce the price of salt to the consumer. On
                        the other hand it was reluctant to cause any unnecessary crisis in the
                        affairs of the Salt &amp; Soda Company, by the too abrupt termination of the
                        monopoly which it has hitherto enjoyed, more especially as it believed that
                        the com- pany, with its expenses and wide organisation, was in a position to
                        continue to supply the public better than any one else.</p>
                    <p>Under the agreement which has been arrived at, the company waives its right
                        to a six months' notice, and the monopoly ceases and determines on the 1st
                        January next, when the retail price of salt will be reduced from 5 milliemes
                        to 2 milliemes, while the Government on its part undertakes not to exploit
                        its own salines, or to let them to others, for the space of six years. The
                        poor will be free to piok np salt in the desert; but in order to avoid
                        abuses it may be necessary to guard the more important salines, which will
                        be done at the company’s expense.</p>
                    <p>By this arrangement it is hoped that not only will salt in Egypt be as cheap
                        as any- where else in the world, but that no material injury will be done to
                        the interests of the company whose shares are so largely held in this
                        country.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHIP ON FIRE IN PORT.</head>
                    <head type="sub">BEACHED NEAR BREAKWATER.</head>
                    <p>The S.S. Sardinia, of the Ellerman Line, which had just sent her redder
                        ashore for repairs by Messrs. Watson &amp; Co., was observed to be on fire
                        in her forehold, stowed with cotton and rice, soon after noon yesterday. No
                        flames were visible, but smoke was issuing from the port side through the
                        ventilator cowl.</p>
                    <p>The ship was at once towed to the qua- rantine anchorage in the outer
                        harbour, having the port steam fire-float , alongside. By 6 p.m., the smoke
                        had ceased to issue after two hours incessant pumping, and it was hoped that
                        the fire had been subdued. But, by 8 p.m. the smoke burst forth again and
                        the pomps were set to work.</p>
                    <p>At 10 a.m. to-day it was decided to put the ship ashore on the bank under the
                        breakwater, so that the hold might be filled with water without risk of the
                        ship going down or turn- ing over, as she had a great list to starboard and
                        her boiler fires were on the point of being extinguished. This was being
                        effected at 11a.m.</p>
                    <p>The cause of the fire is unknown.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
                    <p>The report of the experts, and especially their criticism of the proposals of
                        the con- trollers appointed under the concordat pre- ventif, has given rise
                        to considerable discussion. The opinion is held in some circles that from
                        the point of view of the shareholders a de- claration of bankruptcy will be
                        the best solu- tion of the difficulty. Experts take the line that to speak
                        of the financial reconstruction of the Sucreries is all very well in its
                        way, but that all must depend on the question whether the sugar industry can
                        in future be carried on at a profit. To sell the railways would only hasten
                        the catastrophe, for they are essential to the economic working of the
                        industry. The controllers have, no doubt, submitted their answer to the
                        criticism of the experts to the juge-commissaire, which should prove highly
                        interesting. Meantime the shareholders are about to meet this afternoon, and
                        what their attitude will be, after Thursday's meeting of creditors and the
                        reading of the reports of the experts, is a most interesting problem.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ACCIDENT TO M.M. STEAMER.</head>
                    <head type="sub">(From our Correspondent.)</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>Suez</placeName>, Friday.</dateline>
                    <p>The homeward bound Messageries Maritimes mail steamer Ofeanien arrived at
                        Suez on Wednesday with a broken shaft. She was moored shortly after in the
                        Port Ibrahim basin, in order to land the mails and passengers. The latter
                        left Suez at 8.30 yesterday evening by special train for Alexandria, where
                        they were transferred to the company's steamer at that port for conveyance
                        to Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>As the Caledonian is too long for the dry- dock at Suez she will be towed
                        to-morrow to Port Said by the Canal Company's tug Titan, and thence to
                        Marseilles by one of the com- pany’s steamers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES EROM THE SUDAN,</head>
                    <head type="sub">(From our Correspondent.)</head>
                    <dateline><placeName>El Obeid.</placeName>
                        <date>November 8</date>.</dateline>
                    <p>The weather here is still rather oppressive, although we get nice cool
                        nights.</p>
                    <p>Polo is in fall swing, and we can boast of one of the best grounds in the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>Kaimakam Hawker Bey, 0.C. of the Camel Corps here, left a few days ago for
                        Suakin, where he takes up his duties as moudir.</p>
                    <p>The 8th Sudanese Battalion is arriving here shortly relieve the half
                        battalion of the 12th Sudanese, which has left for Wan temporarily.</p>
                    <p>We have had large swarms of locusts lately passing over the town, and they
                        have done serious damage to the crops in the province.</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HAMBURG-AMERIKA LINE</head>
                    <head type="sub">AMALGAMATION WITH ANGLO-</head>
                    <head type="sub">AMERICAN.</head>
                    <p>The negotiations between the Anglo-Ameri- can Nile Steamer and Hotel Company
                        and the Hamburg-Amerika Steamships Company have ended satisfactorily, and
                        the contract has just been signed. The terms of the amalgamation are in
                        every way satisfactory to both parties concerned and this morning the shares
                        of the Anglo-American Company conse- quently advanced rapidly and closed at
                        5 7/8.</p>
                    <p>It is some time ago since Egypt learnt that the Hamburg-Amerika Steamship
                        Company was desirous of starting a Nile steamer ser- vice and at first it
                        was understood that the venture would be made independently of the companies
                        already established, notably Messrs. Thomas Cook and Son, and the company
                        with which they have just come to terms. Some agitation was evinced and the
                        opinion was expressed in some quarters that German en- terprise should not
                        be allowed the opportu- nity of ousting those companies which had a prior
                        right. The matter was taken np in London, and questions were asked in
                        Parlia- ment, hot, as is so often the case, no definite answer either
                        satisfactory or otherwise was vouchsafed.</p>
                    <p>Shortly afterwards it was rumoured that the conditions under which Nile
                        traffic is car- ried on were to be changed, and that the changes would in
                        all probability deter any would-be interloper from entering into competi-
                        tion with the established companies. Then we learnt that negotiations for
                        the amalgamation of the Hamburg-Amerika line with the Anglo- American were
                        pending,and later that arrange- ments bad been made for meetings between the
                        directors of the two companies at Paris or Berlin. We have more than once
                        prophesied the result of these negotiations, and our anti- cipations now
                        appear to have been well-founded.</p>
                    <p>The Anglo-American line is well-known and is yearly making rapid strides;
                        strengthened by the valuable support of the Hamburg- Amerika Company, with
                        the concomitant addition to its capital and consequent increase of its
                        fleet, it cannot fail to progress still more rapidly. What with the yearly
                        increase of Nile traffic there is plenty of scope for two such lines as
                        Messrs. Thomas Cook &amp; Son and the new amalgamation, and we have every
                        hope of seeing a continued improvement in the already excellent service,
                        without either party suffering from the inevitable but healthy competition
                        of its rival.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN ANTIQUITIES AT DUBLIN. </head>
                    <p>General Lord Grenfell daring his extended military service in Egypt, which
                        commenced in 1882 and ended with his command of the Egyptian forces in 1898,
                        made an interesting collection of antiquities. This collection he has now
                        lent to the Dahlia Museum. It includes a bronze head of the cat-headed
                        goddess Pasht, and a funeral likeness which illustrates the art of
                        portrait-painting twenty centuries ago.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOUR8E</head>
                    <p>(AejmrcCkui A midi et demie)</p>
                    <p>Una grande animation a tigni ce matin dans</p>
                    <p>la corbeille des valours. Toote la oote hausso et</p>
                    <p>la tendance est exoeptionnellement ferme.</p>
                    <p>Parmi lea gros titree, la National Bank gagne</p>
                    <p>1/4 k 25 3/4, l'Agrioolo 1/16 k 9 5/16, la Land</p>
                    <p>Bank 1/16 k 8 11/16, la Banqne d’Abyssinia</p>
                    <p>8/16 a 7'3/8, laBdbdra 1/2 k 38 1/2, la Nun-</p>
                    <p>govich 1/16 k 10 1/2, 1’Upper Egypt 1/8 k</p>
                    <p>5 3/16, 1'Anglo-Amerioan Nile 3/8 k 5 7/8,</p>
                    <p>i'Alexandria Water 1/16 k 14 5/8 et la Delta</p>
                    <p>Light 3/16 h 11 15/16.</p>
                    <p>Les valours moinB importantea solvent le</p>
                    <p>mCme mouvemont: la Delta Land remonta de</p>
                    <p>2 1/4 k 2 f /16, les E.tatea de 1 9/32 k 1 5/16,</p>
                    <p>la 8alt &amp; Soda de 28/9 h 24 et les Egyptian</p>
                    <p>Hotels de 2 1/2 k 2 8/1.</p>
                    <p>Par oontre, le Crddit Ponoier tombe de 782 k</p>
                    <p>778 et la Ramleh Railway de 7 k 6 15/16.</p>
                    <p>La han8se de 8/8 snr l’Anglo-American Nile</p>
                    <p>a dtd ddterminde par la signature d*nn accord</p>
                    <p>entre oetta socidtd et la Hambnrg-Amtrica.</p>
                    <p>On sait qne la Sooidtd des Markets exploits</p>
                    <p>depute qnelqne temps k titre d’essai, nn abat-</p>
                    <p>toir dont le bdndfice net devait litre partagd</p>
                    <p>aveo le gonvernement.</p>
                    <p>Le profit rdalisd de ce chef par la Socidtd au</p>
                    <p>boat d’nne anndo ayant atteint la somme de</p>
                    <p>1,000 livres, oellfroi vient d’accepter en prin-</p>
                    <p>cipe nne proposition tide avantagense do gon-</p>
                    <p>vemement, aux terniea de laqneile la Scoidtd</p>
                    <p>feonatruirait k sea fraia 40 abattoirs et lee. ex,-</p>
                    <p>ploitorait en payant augouven ement, lamoitid</p>
                    <p>des fcdndficoa hots.</p>
                    <p>Le gonvernement garantit k la Socidtd 5 0/</p>
                    <p>sur le oapjtal do 16,000 livres, qne ndeeseitora</p>
                    <p>-la construction de Oes abattoirs.</p>
                    <p>. Cairo, 24 Novembro.</p>
                    <p>Brillante matinde snr le marohd des valenrs.</p>
                    <p>La repriseqaonone faisiona prdvoir depnis qnel-</p>
                    <p>ques jonrs ddjk e’est prodnito oe matin ; elle a</p>
                    <p>dtd gdndrale.</p>
                    <p>La Banque gagne environ 5/8, l’Agrioolo</p>
                    <p>pids de 8/8, le.Crddit Ponoier ee oonsolido k</p>
                    <p>785, malgrd la baisse k Paris , hier; laBdbdra</p>
                    <p>regagne 1 li»re k 88 aohetenrs, la Banqne</p>
                    <p>d’Abysainie 8/16 k 7 1/8.</p>
                    <p>. Danale gtoope dw Hotels, lee Nnngovioh</p>
                    <p>rotronvent lo conrs do 10 1/2 et les Baehler,</p>
                    <p>■qui avaiont faibli k 9 1/4 hier, cctent de nou-</p>
                    <p>veau 9 1/2.</p>
                    <p>La Delta Land passe de 21/16 k 2 8/16—1/4</p>
                    <p>et les petitea valenrs en gdndral bdndficient de</p>
                    <p>la rapriie.</p>
                    <p>I Les transaotiorsfest-il heeoin de le dire; ont</p>
                    <p>d*d excessiveinent animdes et ellee ont poDd</p>
                    <p>snr nn hombre onnsiddrable de titres. La e.'0-</p>
                    <p>tnre a dtd nn | eu pics faibld ant la Banqne,</p>
                    <p>qai est revenue k 85 7/H snr de* rdeltotfon*</p>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Count A. Gorzaga and the Marehese di San Guilielmo, who recently visited the
                        Colonial Congress at Asmara, have left for Italy.</p>
                    <p>H. E. the Governor has left for Cairo to spend the Beyram holiday.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Rucker-Jenisch, German Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General, who has been
                        somewhat indisposed since his return from Europe, is now quite
                        convalescent.</p>
                    <p>The late British representative on the Public Debt Commission at Cairo is
                        finding his time folly oocupied in the Russian Capital, for while Sir
                        Charles Hardinge is absent from his post at St. Petersburg, for the
                        furtherance, it is sur- mised, of an understanding between En- gland and
                        Russia, Mr. Cecil Edward Spring- Rice, the First Secretary, in charge of
                        affairs in the Russian capital, has bean arranging for the protection of
                        British subjects there in the untoward event of civil commotion. Mr. Spring-
                        Rice may possibly find himself in charge dur- ing an exciting time. St.
                        Petersburg is, or shortly will be, closed to ships by ice, and till the
                        other day, the only line of railway that was working was the St.
                        Petersburg-Moscow line.</p>
                    <p>Mr Spring Rice is the grandson of the first Lord Monteagle, and was, last
                        year, married to Miss Lascelles, the daughter of Sir Prank, and the charming
                        maitresse de ceans of her father’s Embassy. Her mother was the daughter of
                        Sir James Olliffe, M.D., a practitioner very much in favor, and in fashion,
                        in the Paris of the Second Empire.</p>
                    <p>Major E. R. 0. Ludlow, D.A.A.G., and Mrs. . Ludlow will proceed on the 80th
                        inst. to Mena Home Hotel where they intend to pass the winter.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Glymenopoulo is arriving from Europe on the 5th prox. by the Messageries
                        Maritimes steamer. .</p>
                    <p>The Societe National d’Agriculture de France has made Bogbos Pasha Nubar a
                        foreign member for the mechanical and irri- gation section. Two years ago
                        the society awarded his Excellency its Gold Medal for his steam plough, an
                        award which was quite exceptional.</p>
                    <p>Mr, J. Bevan, one of the directors of the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Ltd., is
                        expected at Mona House on the 9th December.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Russell and Kerr, chartered account- ants, of Cairo and Alexandria,
                        announce that they have taken into partnership Mr. S. C. Wyatt, A.C.A., and
                        that the firm will be known in future as Russell, Kerr and Wyatt Messrs.
                        Russell and Kerr will continue to reside in Cairo and Alexandria
                        respectively, while Mr. Wyatt is opening a London office of the firm at
                        Moorgate Court, E.C.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are : Mr.
                        and Mrs. Colquhoun, Mr. M. King. Mr. D. Cuile, Mr. J. A. Keenly, Mr. Fred.
                        Latinew, Mr. and Mrs. G. Beaman, Mr. and Mrs. D. F. Basden, Mrs. W. I.
                        Luiette, Mr. W. Fretwell, Mr. J. Mc- Gown, Mr. Percy L. Smyth, Mr. J.
                        Pringh, Mr. W. J. Wayte, Mr. McKay, Mr. 0. Gantes, Mr. A. Barton Buckley,
                        Mr. A. L. Farwell, Mrs. C. E. Maltbs, Capt. R. R. Willis, Mr. B. Cavadia.
                        Mr. N. N. Tabet, Mr. L.- J. Eastwood, Mr. W. D. Blakes, Mrs. W. ft
                        Kingaford, Mr. Allen Joseph, Mr. Y. Reynolds, Mr. Anderson, Mr. W. Weber,
                        Mr. A. Stul- ken, Mr. P. Hindlay, Khalib Bey Riad, Sub- Governor of Port
                        Said, Mohamed Bey Rachid, Mr. G. Railston, Mr. S. W. Trafford, Mr. P. P.
                        Higgins. Mr. Littlewood, Mr. H. Cooper, Mrs. F. de Rougement, Miss Owen, Mr.
                        H. Smyth, Mr. J. S. Cowen, Mr. G. N. Malcolm, Mr. Crawley, Miss Dresser.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE TOURISTS.</head>
                    <p>The following passengers left Cairo by P.S. Nefertari yesterday, for the Nile
                        trip Mr. and Mrs. Sneath, Master and Miss Sneath Admiral and Miss F.E. Kane,
                        Miss Llewellyn, Misa Jean Greive, Mire D’Aubray, Count Max Marzani, Mr. A.
                        M. Cohen, Miss and Miss D. Rogers, Mr. Chas Royle, Mr. P.V. Davis, Mr. J.
                        Sloan, Mr. John L Low, Mrs. Low, Mr. H. M. Forster, Mr. Colin C. Macaulay,
                        Miss M.A H. Simpson, Misa A.A. Methley, Miss Harding, Miss Cowell, Lt Col.
                        Aberigh Meo- key, Mr. P.W. Early, Mia A. B. Bruce, Mia A. M. Dobie, Mr. and
                        Mr*. Vaughan Wild, Mr. H. E. Bowman, Dr. Grimolbey, Mr. Jos. Fray, Dr.
                        Allen, Mrs. Motley.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PASSENGER LIST</head>
                    <p>Departures</p>
                    <p>Per S.S Congo of the Messageries Maritimes sailed yesterday for
                        Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>M. and Mme Mimont M. Rizzo-Noris, M. Manzi. </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
