<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Olivia Evanoff</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">November 15,2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 7, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 6 190S.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN HORRORS JEWS BUTCHERED </head>
                    <head>REVOLTNG BARBARITES. FINLAND WINS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 4. The Amnesty is of the widest description,
                        Applying especially- to political offenders. There are no signs of Russia
                        becoming quieter. Great disturbances and bloodshed are reported daily from
                        fresh places. The latest reports show that the horrors at Odessa were not
                        exaggerated. Hooligans aided by the police slaughtered whole families of
                        Jews, with inconceivable brutality. It is impos- sible to estimate the
                        number of the killed, but there ate at present 5,500 wounded in. the
                        hospitals. 300 corpses have already been buried. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> London, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The “Times" learn from.St. Petersburg that Finland has won a manifesto of
                        freedom, embodying all the popular demands, which was submitted for the
                        Imperial signature yes- terday evening. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg,' November 4. </head>
                    <p>Warships have left Reval for Helsinugfors as a result of the continuance of
                        alarming reports. In reply to a representation from the British Government
                        regarding the safety of British subjects, especially in the south, the
                        Embassy has also informed that stringent orders have been sent to Odessa and
                        elsewhere to restore order. The other Embassies have made similar
                        representations. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A Petersburg, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The railway strike in Russia is ending. M. Witte has informed the strikers
                        that their demands have been granted. The police at Odessa have tardily
                        taken measures to put an end to the slaughter of the Jews. Bloodshed
                        continues elsewhere. A hundred were killed and six hundred wounded at Minsk.
                        The resignation of the' Minister of the Interior, M. Bouliguine, has been
                        accepted. A manifesto of the Tsar convokes the Finnish diet for the 28th
                        December, in view of the revision of electoral representation. It abolishes
                        the Dictatorship. Meanwhile four warships, convoying ten thousand troops,
                        have anchored at Helsiugfurs. , A great Socialist demonstration which had
                        been, arranged for to-day has been abandoned owing to the stem threat of
                        General Trepoff to repress disturbances rigorously. An official
                        communication declares that it is indispensable that all classes should
                        refrain from mutual friction in order to avoid'disturb- ances, which the
                        Government must repress for the protection of Russian citizens without
                        distinction. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Odessa, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Eight factories have been wrecked in the vicinity. The massacres were
                        accompanied by the most revolting barbarities ; eyes were gouged out,
                        tongues were torn ont with pincers, and n valids were burned alive. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 4.</head>
                    <p>Quiet prevailed to-day throughout Russia. The Tsar will grant the demands of
                        Finland. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The Minister Bouliguine has resigned. (H.) Odessa, November 5. A riot has
                        broken out. 300 people have been killed and 3,000 injured. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Tomsk, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The revolutionaries have set fire to a build- ing in which the reactionaries
                        had taken refuge, massacring those who attempted to escape. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WEI-HEI-WEI NOT TO BE ABANDONED. London, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The "Observer" states that Great Britain does not intend to abandon
                        Wei-hei-wei. (It) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL TOUR Aden, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The Renows left this afternoon. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN DEAD. London, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Sir Trevor Plowden is dead. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CELEBRATING INSPRUCK. Vienna, November 4.</head>
                    <p>Brawls took place between German and Italian students on tbe occasion of the
                        anni- versary of the Inspruck incidents. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>M'DEROULEDE IN PARIS. Paris, Novrmber 5. </head>
                    <p>M. Deroulede has arrived. He was oheered (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POWERS AND CRETE. INSURGENTS ACCEPT TEEMS. Canea, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The Cretan insurgents have agreed to accept tbe terms offered them by the
                        Powers, provided that the surrender of their arms be arranged in a manner
                        that will spare their susceptibilities. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRINCE LOUIS OF BATTENBERG. RECEPTION AT WASHINGTON. Washington, November
                        4.</head>
                    <p>Prince Louis of Batteuberg and tbe officers of tbe British aquadrou are
                        visiting this city for three days. They have been received by President
                        Roosevelt at White House with great ceremony and cordiality. Prince Louis of
                        Battenberg presented a personal message from the King. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>Washington, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Prince Louis of Battenberg has been enter- tained at a banquet by President
                        Roosevelt. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY AND AMERICA. TREATY OF COMMERCE. Washington, Novomber 5.</head>
                    <p>Negotiations for a Germano-American treaty of commerce have been opened.
                        {Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> GERMANY AND ABYSSINIA. APPOINTMENT OF MINISTER Berlin, November 5.</head>
                    <p>It is stated here that Germany intends to appoint a Minister in Abyssinia.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Um Rus Gold Mines of Egypt.— This com- pany has sold tbo September gold for
                        £1,552. (Mill ran 19 days.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Execution. — Beyioumi Bedawi, who was sentenced to death for murder, was
                        executed this morning in Tantah prison. Military Camp. — The 2nd Company of
                        Royal Engineers will move into camp on the Polygon. Abbassieh, on the 13tn
                        inst., for field works and musketry.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Theft in a Gouvernorat.— A sum of about L.E. 20 has been stolen from a safe
                        in tbe private enquiry department at the Cairo Gouvernorat. The safe
                        contained L.E. 66.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The “Egyptian Graphic."—We hear that our contemporary the "Egyptian Graphic"
                        will soon reappear for the season of 1905-06 under the editorship of Mr.
                        William Houghton.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Judges.—Tbe Egyptian Government is negotiating with the French and Greek
                        Governments for the appointment of two Mixed Court judges in place of Judges
                        Ruhland aud Boaphidis.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> Egyptian Land &amp; General Trust.—Mr. John Chini, of the firm of Messrs. P.
                        Glyme- nopoulos &amp; Co., has been appointed the agent of the Egyptian Land
                        &amp; General Trust, Limit- ed, in Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Seven at a Birth.—A native contemporary states that a poor woman of Damanhour
                        has given birth to seven children, four males and three lerooles. The mother
                        is doing well, but two of tbe boys and two of the girls died shortly after
                        birth.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Thefts at Alexandria —A local contem- porary persists in denying the
                        existence of a band of robbers at Alexandria, who have recently committed a
                        number of thefts. The statement can be proved by repairing to tbe scene of
                        their operations in Sisters-street and at the establishment of the Sisters
                        of St. Vincent de Paul.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Woman Strangled.—A native woman, 35 years of age, of the name of Aysha and
                        belong- ing to Jerza village, has been found dead in the Saida Zeynab
                        quarter of Cairo with a handkerchief bound tightly round her neck. The
                        medical examina ion shows that the poor woman was strangled, and that the
                        crime occurred only a few hours before its discovery.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Y.W.C.A., Cairo.—By kind permission of H.R.H. the Duchess of Connanght, in
                        remem- brance of her visit to the home last spring, the name “Connaught
                        House" will now be incorporated with that of Young Women’s Christian
                        Association. We are asked to state this to correct tbe impression that tbe
                        name of tbe institution has been changed. Miss Maclnnes, tbe acting
                        president, returned to Cairo last month.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MINISTRY OF FINANCE. A SECOND UNDER SECRETARY OF STATE.</head>
                    <p>Owing to tho greatly increased pressure of work at the Ministry of Finanoe,
                        it has been decided to appoint anothor Under-Secretary of State, and Lord
                        Edward Cecil Pasha has been selected to fill the new post. Great sa-
                        tisfaction is expressed both in British and native circles at his
                        appointment. During his career in the Sudan servioe Lord Edward Cecil has
                        displayed in a marked degreo the qualities of a good administrator. He is
                        thirty-eight, a brilliant soldier, and a man of business as well as of
                        affairs. The be- sieged in Mafeking owe him a large debt. They hod pretty
                        bad times there long before the siege was over, but had it not been for Lord
                        Edward Cecil they would have starved long before relief came. He took upon
                        himself the responsibility of providing the town with just four times the
                        quantity of food the military authorities found necessary, and when the
                        contractors hesitated to exeoote a seven thousand pound order on the young
                        major’s sole responsibility, Lord Edward promptly got Baden-Powell to back
                        the bilL. But Muafeking was only one incident in his career. He has served
                        in Egypt several times, accompanied the famous special mission to King
                        Menelik ot Abyssinis, gained two medals for his services with the Dougoia
                        Expedition, earned more fame at Atbara, and added to it at Omdurman the D.
                        S. O. and two clasps. The mission to Menelik, by the way, nearly put an end
                        to Lord Edward’s career. While the party was on its way uue of the camels
                        fell down a deep ravine, aud Lord Edward and Captain Swayne clambered down a
                        rope of puggarees with the idea of rescuing the animal. They could not roach
                        the camel, however, and one of the Abyssinians went down. A moment later two
                        shots rang out—one ot them came pretty near to hitting Sir Rennell Rodd—-and
                        the native caino up hand over hand in doable- quick time. He had found two
                        lions devour- ing tbe camel! Lord Edward, who is, of course, a younger
                        brother of tbe Marquess of Salis- bury, married in 1894 Miss Violet Maxse,
                        daughter of tbe late Admiral Maxse, and sister to the editor of the
                        “National Review." As a girl, Lady Edward Cecil sat for Millais' "Puss in
                        Boots,” and during the Boer war she did splendid work among the sick and
                        wounded. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will grant an audience to the newly-appointed Russian
                        Consul-General in Cairo next Thursday afternoon, when the Con- sul will
                        submit his credentials to his Highness.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN CONSULATE.</head>
                    <p>Baron von Humboldt-Dachroeden, German Consulat Alexandria, has been appointed
                        Consul- General at Capetown. He is expected at Alex- andria next week, on
                        his return from leave, and will take up his new post in the beginning of
                        December.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUNICIPAL ELECTIONS.</head>
                    <p>A preliminary meeting was held yesterday at the Alexandria Gonvernorat to
                        consider the new electoral list for tbe forthcoming munici- pal elections,
                        which will be held in March next </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AGRICULTURAL BANK OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The Committee of the London Stock Ex- change has fixed Wednesday, Nov. 15, as
                        a special settling day in Agricultural Bank of Egypt—Scrip certificates to
                        bearer, fully paid, for a further issue of 248,000 Ordinary shares of £5
                        each. (Nos. 375,001 to 623,000), and has ordered the same security to be
                        quoted in the offioial list. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN INSURANCE SCANDALS.</head>
                    <p>Our recent article on the American insurance scandals has been interpreted by
                        some persons here, whose knowledge of English is limited, as reflecting on
                        the agents in Egypt of the companies concerned. But the idea that the
                        article had any reference to anyone in Egypt is of coarse quite absurd, and
                        it will not bear that interpretation for a moment to anyone conversant with
                        the English language.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Messageries S.S. Dumbea, from Mar- seilles, passed the Straits of Messina
                        on Satur- day and is due at Alexandria to-morrow. The Moss liner Seti
                        arrived on Saturday morning from Liverpool, via Gibraltar and Malta, with
                        passengers, mails, and general cargo. The Ellerman S.S. Andalusian sailed
                        fran Malta ou Saturday afternoon and is due here on Tuesday night with
                        general cargo. The S.S City of Dundee (Westcott and Laurence Line) left
                        Malta on Saturday night and is due here on Wednesday, with general cargo
                        from London and coal from Newcastle.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE GRAND MDFTI. SUCCESSOR APPOINTED.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of the late Grand Mufti, Sheikh Mohamed Abd El Kader El Rafei,
                        took place early on Saturday afternoon. The Prime Min- ister, Mustapha Pasha
                        Fehmy, Fakhry Pasha, Fuad Pasha, tbe chiefs of the ulema, and the principal
                        dignitaries of the University of Al Azhar, Mr. Moberly, acting Commandant of
                        the Cairo Police, and a great number of notables and sheikhs were present.
                        The fu- neral service was bald at the Mosque of the Al Azhar University,
                        after which the foneral cortege moved on to the cemetery at El Me- gaonerin,
                        where the interment took place. The late Grand Mufti appears to have suc-
                        cumbed to heart failure while driving from the house of H. E. Boutros Pasha
                        Ghali to that of H.E. Ahmed Pasha Mazloum to con- clude a series ot official
                        visits which seem to have proved too fatiguing for his years. His friends
                        state that he showed no signs of illness when leaving his house in the late
                        afternoon. A successor to the Grand Mufti has already been found in Sheikh
                        Bakri Ashour, the acting Grand Cadi, who has aocepted the appointment.
                        Sheikh Bakri is reputed to be a learned theo- logian and bears a high
                        personal character.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FLOATING DOCK TO PASS THROUGH CANAL.</head>
                    <p>The Navy Department at Washington is negotiating for the passage through the
                        Suez Canal of three colliers and also a large steel floating drydock which
                        will be towed to tbe station of Olongapo, in the Philippines. No anxiety is
                        expressed over the voyage, which will be notable in many respects. The dock
                        will be the largest structure ever to pass through the Suez CanaL It is
                        estimated that the cost of taking the dock to Olongapo will be £250,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The Hon. Mr. Iddings, American Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General at Cairo,
                        arrives at Alexandria this afternoon by the North German Lloyd S.S.
                        Schleswig.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Archbishop Briante and the Marquis Soragna were among the passengers who
                        arrived yesterday by the Italian mail steamer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The new Under Seoietary of State for War is H. E. Ismail Sirhauk Pasha.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Sir Thomas Sutherland, Vice President of the Suez Canal Co., is giving a
                        dinner to his brother members of ths British section of the board of
                        directors, at the Elysee Palace Hotel London, on the 15th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lews Mansfield Pasha, Commandant of the Cairo City Police, arrived to-day by
                        the Austrian Lloyd steamer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, K.C.M.G. has arrived at Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Chitty Bey has arrived at Cairo from Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kaimakam Macaulay Bey left Cairo for Khartoum on Saturday night by the
                        sleeping car train to Loxor.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>We understand that Mrs. Sydney Farrar is rather indisposed, and is coming to
                        Egypt shortly. It is hoped that the mild climate of the Nile Valley will
                        greatly benefit her health.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. R. J. Moss and Miss Moss arrived here to-day by the Austrian
                        Lloyd S.S. Cleopatra.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. Reeves is expected at the Carlton early next week.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lieut. R. J. Cooke, Inspector of Army Schools, leaves Port Said for Malta on
                        the 9th inst. by the S.S. City of Corinth, on the conclusion of his
                        inspection in Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Naguib Bay Chikour, chief signalling en- gineer of the Egyptian Railway
                        Administra- tion, has retired with an indemnity of L.E 1,060.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the visitors now staying at the Carlton Hotel, Bulkeley, are Mr. J.C.
                        Clarke Mr. B. Nathan, Mr. Ch. Christian, Mr. F Nathan, England, Miss Mary B.
                        Moffat,U.S.A. Miss F. Clarke, U.S.A., Mr. C.H. Bernhard France, Mr. B.
                        Gorra, Syria, Dr. S. Schmeil Cairo, Mr. A. Mosseri and family, Cairo Mrs.
                        Bogdadli and family, Cairo, and Mr. E. L Edgar, England.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at tbe Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr.
                        C. R. Muratori. Mr. A. Macaulay, Mr. A. Benzinra Capt Moberly, Mr. P.
                        Cowlas, Mrs. E Macau lay, Mr. and Mrs. M. Summers, Mrs. H Mayne, Dr. E. H.
                        Ross, Mr. Batler. Mrs. C.E Malby, Mr. A. Nathan, Mr. P. Beohara, Mr. and
                        Mrs. A. Brown, Mr. James F. Waterlow M.C B.A., Mr. G. Geoman, Capt. Byarke,
                        Mr. RH. Parker, Mr. R. W. Wright Henderson Dr. and Mrs W.A. Hayes, Mr. and
                        Mrs. MoKay.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHRYSANTHEMUM. SHOWS. SUCCESSFUL EXHIBITS AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>The eighth of the Alexandria Horticultural Society’s Chrysanthemum Shows was
                        held in the San Stefano Casino on Saturday and Sunday last. It was the
                        largest yet held here, and was remarkable for the number of novel exhibits
                        it contained, this, evidently, being the result of according a oertain
                        number of points in tho programme for new varieties not hitherto exhibited
                        in Egypt. Every year brings one or two new exhibitors who show extra-
                        ordinarily good blossoms. Mr. Rolo surprised the public last year by his
                        beautiful cut flowers a in boxes, and this year Madame Salvago and Yehia
                        Bey, who never exhibited before, were able to carry off prizes in every
                        class for which , they (competed. The group of Mme Salvago, though small,
                        was quite charming, and the fine heads of flowers that Yehia Bey produced
                        were as good as any that have been seen at San Stefano. But to those who
                        really under- stand chrysanthemums and their culture, the great feature of
                        the show was undoubtedly the mass of pot plants in the centre of Mr.
                        Zervndachi’s gronp, which had been so culti- vated that while the plant
                        remained small, the bloom was as large as if the roots had not been touohed.
                        The ball-room of the Casino was completely filled by four large groups,
                        three of which were for competition, while the fourth was the exhibit of the
                        Municipality, which never com- petes. All showed great taste in arrangement,
                        and the harmony in colour in each was well thought out. The difficulty
                        consequently lay in judging the strength of the plant and in the value of
                        the new importations into Egypt Perhaps among all the exhibitors the
                        greatest stride has been made by the Municipality; the difference in the
                        grouping of their plants was greatly noticeable. The Municipality is now
                        taking great interest in the culture of flowers. The reading-room was also
                        quite full of plants; the blossoms were enormous and although most of the
                        prizes seemed to go to three or four (competitors, yet in every class there
                        was much competition. Cultivation of the chrysanthemum has become so general
                        in Alexandria, that it almost seems as if the committee might venture to
                        take a further step, and offer prizes for special classes suoh as Pompou,
                        Incurves, etc. We must not omit to mention the boxes of well-grown flowers
                        staged by General Bullock, nor the interesting exhibit of Mrs. Crafton,
                        consisting of the leaf, flower, and fruit of the Philodendron pertusum. It
                        is not generally known that the fruit, which tastes like pineapple, takes 18
                        months to ripen. There was a mass of vases arranged by natives, most of them
                        well thought oat, though perhaps the harmony of colour which generally
                        pleases the Earopean eye, was somewhat wanting. Asa trial the oommittee
                        offered prizes for collections of vegetables, salad, and fruit, without
                        speoifiying too varieties. These exhibits were a success, and showed the
                        pnblic several vegetables which they probably had no idea were at the
                        present time to be obtained in the market. We noticed, for instance, peas,
                        figs, and strawberry grapes. The attendance on the opening day showed a
                        marked increase on former years, while on Sunday the attraction of the
                        Armenian bend helped to swell the large number who were drawn to the show.
                        The following are the names of the judges :— Miss Borchgrevink, Mrs.
                        Crafton, Messrs. Ebell, Monfront, H Seffer, and Tramontins.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRIZE LIST. CHRYSANTHEMUMS.</head>
                    <p>Pot Plants. 1. Gronp of at least 200 plants.—Silver gilt medal, Mr. E. C.
                        Zervudachi; silver medal, Prince Omar Toussoun ; bronze medal, Mme Charlotte
                        Debbane. 2. Group of from 75 to 100 plants.—1. Mme - Salvago ; 2. Judge
                        S-ndars. 3. 18 plants, cultivated for large flowers ; 6 varieties at
                        least—1. Yehia Bey ; 2. Mr. Jacques Rolo. 4. 6 plants, cultivated for large
                        flowers.— No entry. 5. 6 plants, each at least 15 flowers.—1. Mr. E. C.
                        Zervudachi; 2. Yehia Bey. 6. 7, and 8.—No entry. Cut Flowers. 9. 24 Blooms,
                        12 varieties at least.—Silver medal, Prince Omar Toussoan ; bronze medal,
                        Mr. E. C. Zervudachi. 10. 12 Blooms, Mixed.—1. Yehia Bay; 2. Prince Omar
                        Toussoun. 11. 12 Blooms, one colour.—1. Prinoe Tous- soun ; 2. Mme Salvago.
                        12. 6 Blooms, mixed.—1. Yehia Bey; 2. Prinoe Omar Toussoun. 13. 6 Blooms,
                        one colour.—1. Prince Omar Toussoun ; 2. Yehia Bey. 14, 15, and 16.—No
                        entry. Floral Decorations, 17, 18, and 19.—No entry. 20. 1. Abdou Hassan ;
                        equal 2. Ibrahim Amer aod Shaban Ahmed. VEGETABLES AND FRUIT. 21. 1. Ahmed
                        Mohamed ; 2. Ali Said ; 3. Haffez Soliman. 22. 1. Daddour Mohamed ; 2. Ahmed
                        Mo- hamed. 23. Salad.—1. Ali Said; 2. Daddour Moha- med Best chrysanthemum
                        in the show. —Prince Omar Toussoun.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAIRO EXHIBITION. HIGH STANDARD Of EXHIBITS.</head>
                    <p>Saturday and Sunday's Chrysanthemum Show at Cairo was a thorough saocess from
                        the point of view of the judges, and the weather was delight- fully cool and
                        pleasant, with the result that the attendance was satisfactory and ths
                        visitors to the K. A.S building were content. The exhibits in nearly all
                        cases reached a very high standard, some of the groups being remarkably
                        beautiful, and the cut flowers attracting great attention. Mrs. Foaden, who
                        was by far tbe most successful exhibitor, secured no less than eleven first
                        prizes, her groups consisting of splendidly healthy blooms, and her other
                        exhibits being extremely tastefully arranged. Lord Cromer visited the Show
                        early on Satnrday afternoon, as did the Prime Minister and Husseith Fakhry
                        Pasha and many other well-known Cairo personalities, and there was a very
                        fair attendance on the second afternoon of the show. We need not say that
                        the arrangements were excellent, and that the excellent tea that was
                        provided and the music, for which we have to thank the C. O. of the 2nd
                        Royal Inniskilling Fosiliers, were heartily appreciated. The following were
                        the prize-winners in the various clasaes of exhibits:-</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMATEURS.</head>
                    <p>Flowers Cultivated in Pots. 1. Group of at least 25 pots of Cbrysanthe-
                        mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 1. Ahmed Bey Kho- loussi. 2. Group of at least 12
                        pots of Chrysanthe- mums and not exceeding 22 pots—1. Mrs. Foaden; 2. Ahmed
                        Bey Kholoussi. 3. Group of at leaat 6 pots of Chrysanthe- mums and qot
                        exceeding 12 pots.—1. Mrs. Foadon ; 2. Miss F. Curtis. 4. Group of at least
                        3 pots of Chrysanthe- mums grown for decorative purposes rather than for
                        large flowers. — 1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2 Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. 5. One specimen or
                        standard Chrysanthemum plant.—No exhibit 6. The best collection of at least
                        10 pots in flower other than Chrysanthemums.—2. Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. Cut
                        Flowers. 7. Collection of 48 blooms of Chrysanthe- mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ;
                        equal 2. Mrs. Mac- kenzie and Capt. Owen. 8. Collection of 24 blooms of
                        Chrysanthe- mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie. 9. Collection of 12
                        blooms of Chrysanthe- mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 9. Mrs. Mackenzie. 10 6 blooms
                        of Chrysanthemum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie. 11. Zinnias (one
                        box).—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2, Mackenzie. 12. Cannas (one box).—No award. 13.
                        Dahlias (one box).-1. M. Giliberti; 2. Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. 14. Collection
                        of Flowers not previously specified ; 2 boxes at least—1. M. Giliberti. 15.
                        Collection of Flowers not previously specified ; 1 box at leaat—1. M.
                        Giliberti. BASKETS AND VASES OF FLOWERS. 16. Basket of Chrysanthemums.—1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Butcher and Miss Crewe. 17. Vase of Chrysanthemums ;1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis. 18. Basket of Flowers (other than Chrysan-
                        themums).—No exhibits. 19. Vase of Flowers (other than Chrysaathe- mums).—1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis, - NURSERYMEN. 20. Group of pot
                        Chrysanthemums.—1. Moh. Said el Kebir; 2. Said Mohamad. 21. Best collection
                        of cut blooms of Chry- santhemums. 1. - Moh. Said el Bakri; 2. Said Mohamed.
                        Extra prizes for a basket of chrysanthemums and for buttonholes awarded to
                        Ahmed Mus- tapha. 22. Exhibits from Government Garden, Royal Horticultural
                        Society's S.G.M. and an Objet d'Art. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRBRIES COMPANY. MEETING OP DEBENTURE HOLDERS.</head>
                    <p>A meeting of tbe debenture-holders of the Egyptian Sugar Refineries was held
                        recently in Paris, at which, on tbe initiative of the French Council of
                        Foreign Bondholders, a committee was formod (the Paris correspondent of the
                        "Financial News" states) with the fullest powers to safeguard their
                        interests before the Cairo Tribunal of Commerce. The creditors of the
                        unfortunate concern have again been con- vened for November 17, after having
                        met on October 18 last, to receive the report of the experts.This
                        dcoament,the correspondent says, particularly incriminates the board of di-
                        rectors which up till last year distributed dividends, whilst the company’s
                        business never resulted in a single centime profit. On the contrary, for the
                        last five years the Egyptian Sugar Refineries constantly worked at a loss,
                        which did not appear in the obviously "doctored” balance-sheets. As to tbe
                        notorious Cronier bills which the managing directors aocepted, unknown to
                        their colleagues of the board, the experts declare they were duly entered in
                        the oompany's books; but the items reffering to that account were
                        subsequently omitted from the balance- sheets. Moreover, the bills once paid
                        by the company could not be found until they were discovered at the private
                        residence of a subor- dinate employe, who had staetd that he bad never seen
                        them. The debenture-holders will now await the meeting of November 17,when
                        the experts will read a supplementary report, whioh will also set forth the
                        exact state of the assets and liabilities of the company.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>