<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>  <TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Matthew Cooper</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-26">January 26, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7107 ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JANUARY 26, 1905. SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" element="social"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Owing to the large number of tourists who have arrived within the last few
                        days, Shepheard’s Hotel and Ghezireh Palace are completely full. Among those
                        staying at Shepheard’s we notice Prince Omar Toussoun, Baron Pidoll, Sir
                        Robert Pullar, Mr. Arthur Chamberlain, J.P., and family, Col. James Scott,
                        Count von Herder, Comte de Périgord and the Hon. Mrs. Sackville-West, Baron
                        Koenig, Baron Rudolf Drasch, Baron Dobe-zensky, Mr. and Mrs. Granville
                        Alexander, Kitter von Rapperd, Baroness F. de Fursten-werth, Mrs. von
                        Weydwiller, Mr. and Mrs. Eilw. Damgerfield and family, Mr. and Mrs. E.
                        Summerfield, Mr. and Mrs. F. G. Strim son, etc.</p>
                    <p>Among the names of the visitors staying at the Tewfik Palace Hotel we note
                        that of Mrs. Fanny Bullock Workman, F.R.S.G.S., who has travelled
                        extensively in almost every part of the world. In 1899 she made three first
                        record ascents for women in the Karakoram mountains, the highest of which
                        was Mount Koser Gunga, 21,000 feet, and has since accompanied her husband in
                        further exploring expeditions.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has been graciously pleased to grant to Mr. R. Carton de Wiart,
                        governor of Tourah prison, the commission of Kaimakam.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CATTLE IMPORTS.</head>
                    <p>The Sudan Government have published a order prohibiting the import of
                        Sudanese cattle into Egypt viâ Haifa, owing to the outbreak of cattle plague
                        in the Sudan. Cattle may still be imported into Egypt via Suakin and Suez if
                        the importers conform with the regulations as to quarantine applied to
                        cattle imported from Syria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Seti” sailed hence yesterday evening for Manchester, via
                        Malta, with passengers, mails, and general cargo, including 6,733 bales
                        cotton.</p>
                    <p>The Moss liner “Nitocris" sailed yesterday morning from Malta and is due here
                        on Sunday morning, with general cargo and coal from Glasgow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Aujourd’hui à midi et demie)</p>
                    <p>Les acheteurs se tenant sur la réserve, les cours restent à peu près
                        stationnaires.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DUKE OF CONNAUGHT. ARRIVAL AT ALEXANDRIA</head>
                    <p>This morning at about 10.30 o'clock, the 1st class cruiser "Essex," with the
                        Duke and Duchess of Connaught on board, was sighted approaching Alexandria
                        harbour. Soon afterwards Mr E. B. Gould, I.S.O., H.M. s Consul-General at
                        Alexandria, Brigadier General Bullook, C B , Rear Admiral Sir Massie
                        Blomfield Kilim, and Mahmoud Pasha Sidky, Go-vernor of Alexandria, embarked
                        on board a launch belonging to the Ports and Lighthouses Administration, and
                        proceeded to II. M. S. "Essex" to greet the Royal party.</p>
                    <p>The Duke and Duchess and their daughters, the Princesses Margaret and
                        Victoria, disembarked after lunch and landed at the Arsenal wharf shortly
                        after one o'clock.</p>
                    <p>The ram, which had been falling early in the morning, had ceased, and
                        although the sky was wintry and overcast, the climatic conditions were not
                        disagreeable at the time of the Royal party's disembarkation on Egyptian
                        soil. The Duke and Duchess lauded at the Arsenal wharf, close to the offices
                        of the Ports and Lighthouses Administration. The landing of the Royal party
                        was quite private, only a very limited number of persons being present
                        besides the high officials. The Arsenal wharf had been made to look quite
                        gay in honor of the occasion.</p>
                    <p>A guard of honor, consisting of one captain, two subalterns, and 100 rank and
                        file, with the King's colour and band, had been detailed by the
                        Brigadier-General commanding, from the 2nd Battalion of the Royal Berkshire
                        Regiment. Prom the wharf up to gate No. 4, the railway was lined by members
                        of the Alexandria City Police force and from No. 4 gate to Gabbari by the
                        Customs Guards.</p>
                    <p>Their Royal Highnesses wore received with the xxxxx honors on landing, and at
                        once proceeded to the train which was in waiting to receive them on the
                        wharf, by which they travelled to Cairo.</p>
                    <p>Their Royal Highnesses, with H H. the Khedive, will be present at the Cairo
                        races to-morrow.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive lias postponed his trip to the Lylnan Desert until the 22nd
                        proxo.</p>
                    <p>His Highness will preside at a meeting of the Council of Ministers to be held
                        at 10 a.m. on Saturday next at Abdeen Palace.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HOLY CARPET.</head>
                    <byline>FROM OUR CORRESPONDENTS</byline>
                    <dateline>Suez, Wednesday.</dateline>
                    <p>The Khedivial Mail steamer " Rahmanieh,' having on board the Mahmal, will
                        sail from Suez this afternoon for Jeddah.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAHMAL THEFT.</head>
                    <p>it is now believed on well informed circles that the theft of the 8,000 from
                        the Mahmal baggage train took place at Abbassieh. In the meantime, all
                        search for the culprits has xxxxxxx.</p>
                    <p>The men of the guard who accompanied the baggage tram have been placed under
                        arrest, pending the result of the enquiry which is now being conducted We
                        bear that the treasurer of the Mahmal caravan will be required as a witness
                        for the enquiry, and will very possibly be unable to accompany the Mahmal to
                        Mecca.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MR. SCOTT-LESLIE'S RECITAL.</head>
                    <p>The recital given at Monferrato’s Hall yesterday evening by Mr. H. Scott
                        Leslie, under the asspieces the Alexandria Literary, Musical and Dramatic
                        Society, was the great success which we had foreseen. There was a large
                        audience present, who were kept in the bested god humours for the space of
                        over two hours. The programme was of such a length that it would be
                        impossible for us to enumerate each item, but each and every one was
                        received with delight and enthusiasm. Mr. Scott-Leslie could have given no
                        better proof of his versatility than be did last night, when he appeared in
                        many characters. He has chosen primarily to follow in the path of Chevalier,
                        and his great natural gifts could find no better field for their display ;
                        while as a mirth provoking raconteur he has few equals. The mingled pathos
                        and humour of Chevalier are hard to emulate, but Mr. Scott Leslie succeeds
                        in his difficult task, and shows a delicacy and power, a mastery of
                        expression, and a subtle insight into character that places him very much on
                        a level with the great original, and enables him without apparent effort to
                        keep his hearers thoroughly amused and charmed during the course of a long
                        programme Mr. .Scott-Leslie was ably supported by Mr. David W. Norton, who
                        not only accompanied all the singers during tho even ing but contributed two
                        pianoforte solos, which he gave in a manner that demonstrated his absolute
                        mastery over the instrument.</p>
                    <p>Two of the most enjoyable items on the programme were a quartette from The
                        Cingalee, "True Love," and a glee. "The Old Norse Song.' The former was sung
                        by Lady Blom-field. Miss MunGavin, Mr. Bloomfield, and Mr. R M. Nixon, while
                        the following took part in the latter Lady Bloomfiel, Misses Cree, MunGavin,
                        Niell, and Talbot, Messrs. Blomfield, Byrne, Nixon, and Rees. Mr. Blom-field
                        was unexpectedly called upon to take the tenor part at the last moment. Miss
                        Mnn-Gavin gave an exquisite rendering of "Voices of the Past" (Greene) and
                        ol “Beloved, it is Morn” (Aylward), the violin obbligato being splendidly
                        played by Miss Gibson. Mr. R. M. Nixon sang two songs, "The Outpost’s Vigil”
                        and "Blow, blow, thou winter wind,” in his accustomed style and was much
                        applauded.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT AND THE EMPRESS EUGENIE REMINISCENCES.</head>
                    <p>The following is from the “Daily Telegraph" of Thursday last : —</p>
                    <p>To-morrow the Macedonia sails from Marseilles on her usual journey to Port
                        Said and the East. Among her passengers is an aged lady, whoso hair is white
                        with years and trouble. She is travelling incognito, and her identity may
                        not become known to her fellow-passengers, but she is none other than
                        Eugénie, ex-Empress of the French, who after an inter val of thirty five
                        years again leaves a French port on a trip to Egypt. But bow the
                        circumstances have altered ; what a changed world those it is for this
                        fallen Queen, and what memories must rise up before her eyes as she thinks
                        of then and now. The contrast is so dramatic and so poignant that we may
                        venture to recall events which may have slipped from the memory even of
                        those who are old enough to recall their impressions of the year 1869.</p>
                    <p>On Nov. 17,1859, the Suez Canal was opened with all the pomp and circumstance
                        which Ismail Pasha, the most recklessly lavish of all modern rulers, could
                        devise. And the Empress of the French, the Empress Eugénie, was the most
                        august personage in all that brilliant throng which assembled on the banks
                        of the Nile. Yet the Emperor of Austria was there in person; and the Crown
                        Prince of Prussia — afterwards the ill-fated Frederick the Noble — and the
                        Prince of Hollard. But thaïe passed almost unconsidered compared with tho
                        presence of the Empress of the French, the Consort of Napoleon III., then
                        the arbiter — or believed to be the arbiter—of the destinies of Europe.
                        Sedan lay in the future le»s than a year ahead— but who could foresee that.
                        Only a few sharp, eagle eyes at Berlin, who knew how destiny was shaping
                        itself, for they were helping her in her task. The Emperor of the French was
                        the great figure in Europe in the autumn of 1869, when the Empress embarked
                        “for the Orient" travelling slowly in the Imperial yacht, L'Aigle, and
                        calling at Venice and Constantinople on the way. It was highly appropriate
                        for yet another reason that the Empress Eugenie should be the guest of honor
                        in the land of the Pharaohs. For the canal was a French undertaking , the
                        engineer was a Frenchman and the idol of France . and Napoleon III. had
                        proclaimed bis faith in M. de Lesseps from start to finish, and had helped
                        his project by every means in his power. The ambitious visionary was right
                        where the practical English engineer Stephenson and the level-headed
                        Palmerston were wildly wrong. What Palmerston had denounced as “a bubble
                        scheme" became a reality, and, instead of English speculators, as he
                        confidently foretold, bemoaning lost money, the British Exchequer has
                        continued reason to bless Disraeli's shrewdness in purchasing Ismail’s
                        shares. It was but right, therefore, that the Empress of the French should
                        be the central personage during that amazing week when Ismail's borrowed
                        money was poured out like water in mad profusion.</p>
                    <p>The Empress was then in early middle-age, with beauty scarcely touched by
                        time, a queenly figure, possessed of every grace and charm. She was the
                        mistress of the fêtes of Compïègne of which all Europe was talking ; she was
                        the friend of Queen Victoria and of the Empress Elizabeth of Austria ; of
                        both she had been the hostess during their stay in France, while at the
                        Paris Exhibition of 1867 she had received the Emperors of Austria and
                        Russia, the King of Prussia, and the Prince of Wales. In 1869 the Empress
                        Eugénie was the most brilliant lady in Europe, whose slightest will was law.
                        At Constantinople the Sultan himself embarked on shipboard to greet her in
                        the Bosphorus, and conduct her to his palace of Bey1er Bey ; at Port Said it
                        was the French Imperial yacht that all eyes strained to see. There were
                        rumours at the last moment that she was not coming, that the Emperor had
                        taken offence at something, that some hitch had occurred. From first to last
                        people's thoughts were of Napoleon and Eugénie. Poor Ismail, who hoped to
                        show the world that a new Power had been born in Egypt, had built a palace
                        for her coming on the shores of Lake Tirnsah—a real Aladdin's Palace, where
                        for three days open tables wore kept fur ten thousand people, feasted with
                        the best and rarest that luxury could supply, and surrounded by a great city
                        of tents, where the Khedive's guests were housed. Someone told him that the
                        Empress was sure to desire to visit the Pyramids—at once he ordered a broad
                        road to be made, seven miles long, to be finished in six weeks. And finished
                        it was by the labour of ten thousand fellaheen working under the heavy lash.
                        The Empress of the French must be able to travel smoothly</p>
                    <p>The Empress came and saw and conquered anew, though her conquest was already
                        secure Her yacht arrived lost, just in time—a studied effect, no doubt — and
                        sailed slowly down the canal from Port Said, greeted with salvoes of cannon.
                        The procession of yachts was too slow to be very impressive, and the real
                        triumph of the Empress took place in a scene more suited to her sex and to
                        her charms — in the ball-room of the palace, where the State ball was held
                        to celebrate the opening of the new route between East and West Her Majesty
                        was the Queen of the Ball she and France triumphed. With her own hand she
                        decorated M. de Lesseps in the name of the Emperor with the Grand Cordon of
                        the Legion of Honor. "I can see her still in my mind’s eye," Mr. Edward
                        Dicey has written in a recent book, “as, covered with diamonds, she moved
                        like a goddess amidst the crowds who stood up to give her passage to the
                        dais, on which, surrounded by crowned heads and the heirs to Royal thrones,
                        she took her seat as, if I may use the phrase, the patroness of the ball. I
                        can still hear the strains</p>
                    <p>of 'Partant poor la Syrie,' which the hands played in her honor as she
                        embarked on the Imperial yacht on leaving the ball, and the salutes by which
                        her departure was proclaimed." It was her culminating triumph, thereafter
                        all was bitterness and disaster. The height she climbed was dizzy ; the fall
                        was terrible.</p>
                    <p>It is said that while the Empress Eugénie was in Egypt she wrote to the
                        Emperor, urging him to inaugurate a more Liberal regime. "I do not like
                        surprises," she wrote,- "and I am persuaded that a coup d'état cannot be
                        made twice in one reign.” Seven months later she said good-bye to husband
                        and son, as they left Paris for the frontier. A few more weeks and she was a
                        fugitive, hastily fleeing from Paris in a hackney coach, deserted by her
                        friends and almost alone. It was the prelude to Chislehurst Farn-borough,
                        the tragedy of Zululand—a succession of sorrows and shattered hopee.</p>
                    <p>Such were the circumstances under which the Empress of the French sailed, in
                        her Imperial beauty and power, for the Orient ! Now it is on aged lady who,
                        all unobserved, takes passage like an ordinary traveller for Port Said. It
                        is a brave journey, for it challenges memories as sad as ever oppressed a
                        Queen dethroned. Times are changed, indeed, and the Empress with them, and
                        Egypt too— changed beyond all recognition save for the Pyramids and the
                        Nile.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="notesHelouan">
                    <head>HELOUAN NOTES.</head> <div type="item"><head>RAILWAY DEVELOPMENTS.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</byline>
                    <dateline>Helouan, January 25.</dateline>
                    <p>The Delta Light Railway Company only took over the Helouan Railway towards
                        the end of last month, and already there are considerable signs of
                        improvement in the timetable and the general condition of the train service.
                        Six extra passenger trains have been put on. A great improvement has been
                        made in quickening the service from Bab-el-Louk to Helouan, by running a
                        purely local service of trams only as tar as Tourah,and thus enabling a
                        quick service of trains to be run from Cairo to Helouan in 35 minutes, with
                        only one stop at Tourah. The stations are being rendered spick and span by
                        lavish coats of paint, which they have not seen for ten years past.</p>
                    <p>Another development is the running of special trains. Fur example, on the day
                        of the Mahmal ceremony a special was run expressly fur the tourists at
                        Helouan to see the spectacle. The company wanted to run a special hack from
                        Cairo after the Khedive’s ball, but the residents could not muster up the
                        guarantee of £5 necessary for such an outlay.</p>
                    <p>Thu stone traffic to Lower Egypt could be very much developed if trucks were
                        obtainable from the Egyptian Railway Administration, but it is impossible to
                        obtain them.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN CASINO.</head>
                    <p>A powerful syndicate is being formed at this delightful winter resort for the
                        purpose of leasing and working the Helouan Casino and Gardens. A permanent
                        orchestra is to be installed, with all thee usual accessories of a
                        first-class Kursaal, such as exists at Homburg and other fashionable
                        watering-places on the Continent.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN LOTTERY.</head>
                    <p>The abolition of the Helouan Railway lottery was the result of the high moral
                        tone adopted by the Delta Railway Company, which, as an English company, did
                        not consider that it was “respectable" to run a lottery. The abolition of
                        the lottery is equivalent to a net annual loss of over £l,000, but I
                        understand that the Company expects to fully make up this deficiency by the
                        arival of free passes on the line. Tho former company used to bestow
                        numerous passes, and the only grumblers at the new order of things are the
                        persona who have been deprived of this privilege. The lottery, however, is
                        still being continued by the Helouan Sporting Club, and the revenue will be
                        used for the general improvement of Helouan, the inhabitants being forced to
                        use this means of improving the place owing to the stinginess of the
                        Government.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SOLDIERS GRAVES AT HELOUAN.</head>
                    <p>I am glad to hear that your remarks on the disgraceful state in which the
                        graves of the British soldiers at Helouan were kept up, have borne some
                        fruit and there is a talk of getting up a subscription for the purpose. All
                        soldiers' cemeteries ought to be looked after by the military authorities,
                        who have funds for the purpose. But as the authorities have treated our
                        soldiers' graves at Helouan with persistent neglect, we presume they regard
                        these last resting place of gallant men as of little or no account It is
                        therefore incumbent on civilians to maintain the two soldiers' cemeteries at
                        Helouan. Of course the funds at the disposal of the military authorities for
                        the proper maintenance of these cemeteries come originally from the taxes
                        the civilians pay, so to voluntarily give funds for the upkeep of these
                        graves, they are paying twice over. It is very noticeable that the
                        cemeteries of the foreign European communities at Helouan, which are in the
                        immediate neighbourhood of our neglected soldiers graves, are as spick and
                        span as could be expected in a desert spot and cast a silent but significant
                        reflection on our reverence for our gallant soldiers, who have passed
                        away.</p>
                </div></div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY HOTEL, LUXOR.</head>
                    <p>Best and most comfortable, unique for its position on Nile bank. Under German
                        Management. Moderate charges. Patronised by officer of Army of Occupation.
                        Concerts twice daily.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="sport"><head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <div type="item"><head>RACING.</head>
                    <head>CAIRO SECOND WINTER MEETING.</head>
                    <p>In spite of very cold and raw weather, there was quite a large attendance on
                        the first day of the Cairo 2nd Winter Meeting, though there were gaps which
                        the weather doubtless explained. Among those present we noticed H. R H.
                        Prince Gustav Adolf, H. H. Prince Omar Toussoun, Lady Cromer, Lady Beatrice
                        Thynne, the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire, Mr. A. L Webb, C.M.G.,
                        Major-Gen. Slade, C. B., and Mrs. Slade, Sir William Gamin, Coles Pasha,
                        Hassan Pasha Mohsen, Khalil Pasha Khayat, Ishak Bey Hussein, the Hon. F. O.
                        Lindley and Mrs. Lindley, Col. Aylmer, Mr. M. de C. Findlay, C.M.G., and
                        Mrs. Findlay, Lord Edward Cecil, Mr. P. Machell, Mr. H. Carter-Wilson, Mrs.
                        H. Delavoye, Mr. Astley Friend, Mr. and Mrs. Satow, Dr. Bentley, and many
                        other well-known residents and visitors.</p>
                    <p>The racing was good, the finishes being very close in the first and sixth
                        races, while the Eclipse Stakes was remarkable for the way in which the very
                        large field kept together all the way through. Latiff, who was much fancied,
                        was winner, and Khalil Pasha Khayat had another great day, getting no less
                        than three wins, one in the LE. 500 race and a third. In the Eclipse Stakes
                        Kendal and London were most fancied after Latiff, but Goga, who was third,
                        did not find much support in the place betting.</p>
                    <p>There were a couple of falls during the afternoon. In the second race Seagull
                        came down just in front of the grandstand, throwing Lillamaud, who was not
                        really hurt, while in the next race Emilius came down badly on the far side
                        of the course, giving Mr. René Carton de Wiart, who was riding, a nasty
                        fall, resulting in concussion of the brain. According to the latest reports,
                        no serious damage appears to have been done, and Mr. R. C. de Wiart will
                        probably be none the worse in a week's time.</p></div>
                
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE MAIDEN PLATE Value LE 25, 2nd horse to receive LE 3, if four or more
                        start, and 3rd horse LE 2, if six or more start, out of the stakes. For
                        maiden Arabs. Weight for age and inches. 14.1 to carry 11 st Distance 7
                        furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Ishak Bey Hussein's ch.a.h. El Tahawi, Stillwell. 10.13. 1</p>
                    <p>Mr. Tueni’s b.a.h. Caprice, Mathews. 10.6. 2 Ibrahim Bey Cherifs b.a.h. St.
                        Frusquin, Makhali. 10.6. 3</p>
                    <p>Hussein Bey Sioufi's b.a.h. Akid, 8.11. 0</p>
                    <p>Omar Bey Sultan and Bakri Bey's b.a.h.</p>
                    <p>Saiad II. 11.0. 0</p>
                    <p>Moharrem Pasha's b.a.h. Aeolus. 10.2 0</p>
                    <p>Kamel Eff. Maher’s g.a.h. Social Life, 10.8. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherifs g.a.h.
                        Sattame, 10.5. 0</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Branch and Mason's b.ab. Starboard Light, 11.0. 0</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Messrs. Rees and Barker's ga.h. Vandal, 10.6. 0 Aeolus led at the start but
                        was soon collared by Vandal and Caprice, *El Tahawi well up. Halfway El
                        Tahawi wont ahead and was soon up with Caprice. A very close race ensued,
                        Caprice being beaten by less than half-length. St. Frusquin was a moderate
                        third.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 55 on winner and P.T. 28, 32, and 117 for places.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE INTERNATIONAL STEEPLECHASE HANDICAP. Value LE 75, 2nd horse to receive LE
                        10, and 3rd LE 5, out of the stakes. For Arabs and Country Breds. Distance
                        about 2 and 1/2 miles.</p>
                    <p>Mr. E. Karam's g.a.h. Soutfi,11.0. Mr. Starkey. 1 Salen Bey Yaghen's b.a.h.
                        Mashkour II, 10.11.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Lockett 2</p>
                    <p>Ishak Bey Hussein’s g.a.h. Saber, 11.5. Bonser. 3 Captain Byrue's g.a.h.
                        Chinaman, 9.9. Bid Ali. 0 Mr. Schreiber’s g.a.h. Seagull, 9.12. Lella-maud,
                        0</p>
                    <p>Mr. E Boutros' ch.ah. Malgré Tout, 10.8. Elias. 0</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mashkour led at the start but was soon caught by Seagull, Chinaman being left
                        gaging at the first hurdle. Soutfi, Seagull, and Mashkour led with little
                        between them first time round, Malgié Tout and Saber together 10 or 12
                        lengths behind. Seagull then fell with his jockey and Soutfi leading for the
                        last 600 yards, won in a canter from Mashkour, while Saber came in a bad
                        third Totalisator paid P.T. 108 on winner and P.T. 30, 24, and 26 for
                        places. * THE UNITED SERVICE HURDLE HANDICAP.—Value LE 30, 2nd horse to
                        receive LE 7, and 3rd LB. 8, out of the stakes if six or more start Distance
                        2 miles over hurdles. For Arabs, the property of Officers of the Army of
                        Occupation, British Officers attached to the Egyptian Army, British
                        Civilians of the Egyptian Government and British Members of the K.S.C.
                        Captain Gillson's b.a.h. Mutmir, 10.5. Mr. Reid. 1</p>
                    <p>Mr. Starkey's g.a.g. Obeyan, 11.12. Owner. 2 Lockett’s ch.ah. Fitz, 12.7.
                        Owner. 8 „ Moberly's b.ah. Cherry, 10.12. Bonsor. 0 „ Hemp's b.a.h. Grand
                        Slam, 11.3. Owner. 0 Captain Byrne’s g.a.h. Emilius, 10.8. Mr. R. C. de
                        Wiart. </p>
                    <p>Obeyan and Cherry led, Fitz last, to begin with. Grand Slam then came up
                        followed by Mutmir and dispossessed Cherry and was in turn passed by Mutmir,
                        who went right ahead and won. Fitz, coming up at the last corner, was a good
                        third to Obeyan. Grand Slam was about 2 length behind.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 110 on winner, and P.T. 36, 27, and 27 for places.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE ECLIPSE STAKES. Value LE 500, 2nd horse to receive LE 100, and 3rd horse
                        LE 50, out of the stakes. For Maiden Arabs (Maidens at nomination). Weight
                        for age with penalties. Horses that have never run in Egypt prior to the
                        first Winter Meeting (December, 1904) allowed 7 lbs. Distance 1 and 1/2
                        miles.</p>
                    <p>Kalil Pasha Kayat's g.a.h. Latiff, 10.7. Jenkins. i Saleh Bey Yaghen’s
                        g.a.h.. London, 10.7. H. Suliman.</p>
                </div></div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
               
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
               
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
