<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexander Caliendo</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-26">October 26, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-04-15">April 15, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE WAR. RUSSIAN REVERSE. TROOPS GRADUALLY RETIRING.</head>
                    <p>Tokio, April 14. Oyama reports that 2,000 Russian cavalry and infantry were
                        encountered and defeated on the 12th inst. 30 miles to the east of Mukden.
                        The enemy retreated northeast to- wards Hailungcheng, fighting every step.
                        The Russians are gradually retiring along Kirin road. The positions are
                        otherwise un- changed. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 14. Linievitch reports that the Russian cavalry raided
                        the railway near Kaiyuan and demolish- ed the telegraphs. (Reuter.) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RIVAL FLEETS. REPORT OF FIGHTING DENIED. RUSSIANS GOING NORTH.</head>
                    <p>New York, April 14. A telegram from Manila has reached here. It states that
                        Admiral Train, commanding the American Squadron, has received news of the
                        arrival at Saigon yesterday morning of the Russian hospital-ship “Orel,"
                        having on board many wounded. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Tokio, April 14. An Imperial ordinance proclaims an imme- diate state of
                        siege over Maku Harbour, in the Pescadores Islands, which the Japanese are
                        believed to be using as a base. The report of fighting off Saigon is
                        officially denied. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Vienna, April 14. A state of siege has been proclaimed at Mako. (Havas.)</p>
                    <p>London, April 14. Naval experts believoethat Rodjestvensky will pass eastward
                        of Japan, in order to ap- proach Vladivostok from the east through the
                        islands. (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, April 14. (Official). The “Orel" had no wounded on board.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                    <p>Saigon, April 14. The Russian squadron is going towards the north.
                        (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTH SEA INCIDENT.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg April 14. Count Lamsdorff has just expressed to the
                        Scandinavian Legation his regret that Rodjest- vensky’s fleet fired on the
                        Norwegian S.S. "Aldebaran.” (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MOROCCO. THE ALGERIAN BOUNDARY.</head>
                    <p>Tangier, April 14. It is stated here that the Sultan of Morocco has replied
                        to the French Mission declaring that he has already signed an agreement with
                        France about the Algerian boundary. The other reforms must be referred to
                        the Powers which signed the Madrid Convention whereby he was bound.
                        (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FISCAL FIGHT. “MODUS VIVENDI" TO BE ARRANGED.</head>
                    <p>London, April 14. A meeting of Tariff Reform Members of Parliament, presided
                        over by Mr. Chamberlain, appointed a deputation, headed by Mr. Chamberlain,
                        to wait upon Mr. Balfour with a view to arranging a “modus vivendi.” It is
                        understood that Mr. Chamberlain has decided for the present to confine his
                        fiscal programme to the policy advocated by Mr. Balfour. The Duke of
                        Devonshire and his supporters are regarded as irreconcilables. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN REFORM.</head>
                    <p>Baku, April 14. The new Governor-General of the Caucasus has convened
                        representatives of all classes to confer with him with reference to judicial
                        administrative reforms. He held out the pros- pect od the allotment of
                        various Crown lands amongst the inhabitants. He announces that the Tsar has
                        ordered a revision of the Arme- nian Church property question. (Reuter.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MARSEILLES MUNICIPALITY.</head>
                    <p>Paris, April 14. The Council of State has validated the elections of 23
                        Municipal Councillors at Mar- seilles, among whom is M. Chanot, and has
                        cancelled 13. (Havas.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-aan02">
                    <p>Anglo-American Nile Steamer &amp; Hotel Company</p>
                    <p>River Transport of Good Between Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>Three Sailings a-Week.</p>
                    <p>Agents at Alexandria:</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Bonded Warehouse Co. Ld</p>
                    <p>1.10.904</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Council or Ministers will be held on Monday next, under the presidency
                            of H.H. the Khedive. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>H. M.’s First class Cruiser’ “Diadem" sailed from Suez yesterday bound to
                            Aden, en route to China. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Charity Bazaar</head>
                        <p>organised by M. and Mme M. Cattaoui, for the Israelite Hospital to be
                            built at Abbassieh, has brought in a profit. of about L.E. 200.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Attempted Murder</head>
                        <p>The Alexandria Na- tive Tribunal has sentenced Mohamed Hassan el Faleh to
                            5 years' hard labour for the attempted murder of a native of the Behera.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Land Purchase</head>
                        <p>We bear that MM. Rasponi and Abignente, members of the Italian Chamber
                            of Deputies, have bought Daoud Pasha's land at Ghezireh Tebadrak for
                            L.E. 15,000. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Execution</head>
                        <p>The first execution at Alexan- dria in the newly-erected execution
                            chamber at Hadra Prison will take place shortly, when the murderer
                            Basscouni will undergo the extreme penalty of the law.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>National Bank</head>
                        <p>The Committee of the London Stock Exchange has decided to allow the
                            following securities to be quoted in the Official List-National Bank of
                            Egypt, fur- ther issue of 50,000 shares of £10 each, fully paid, Nes.
                            200,001 to 250,000.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal</head>
                        <p>10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 12th Inst., of which 6 were
                            British, 1 German, 1 Dutch, 2 French. The day's receipts were frs.
                            324,586.42, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 3,896,862.52.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mariout</head>
                        <p>In the memory of the oldest inhabitants-and there are quite a number of
                            centenarians there--this year's barley crop in the Mariout district has
                            never been surpassed both for quantity and quality. The crops on the
                            Khedive’s estates at Mariout are exceptionally good.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ancient Egyptian Skulls</head>
                        <p>The Oxford Reader in Egyptology, Mr. Randall MacIver, has been examining
                            ancient Egyptian skulls with the result that he has discovered that the
                            Englishman has half as large a negroid element in his constitution as
                            the prehistoric Egyptian.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Egyptian Speculative Enterprise</head>
                        <p>“Spe- culative enterprise (remarks the “Financial Times" of the 4th
                            inst.) on the part of the Egyptians themselves has been on a heavy
                            scale,and so far the local demand for securities of all kinds shows no
                            signs of slackening. It is to be hoped that the pace will be pre- vented
                            from becoming too rapid.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Coal Imports.</head>
                        <p>From the 1st Jan. to 13th inst., 194,330 tons of coal were imported into
                            Egypt. For the corresponding period of last year the quantity was
                            324,589 tons. This year Newcastle sent 45,082 tons, the Welsh districts
                            102,954, the Scotch districts 22,749, Yorkshire 13,901, and other places
                            6,644 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Baldness a Egypt</head>
                        <p>An inscription has been discovered showing the antiquity of baldness in
                            Egypt Teta, King of Egypt some 3,500 years b.c., has left on record the
                            formula of a compound designed to promote the luxuriance of his
                            mother-in-law's hair. At this distance of time it is hard to say whether
                            he was honestly sympathetic in his efforts, or merely the ac- complice
                            of all ages in making sport of such unhappy victims.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>New Egyptian Co.</head>
                        <p>The article from the “Financier" in our issue of Wednesday last on the
                            position and prospects of the New Egyptian Company pointed out that,
                            whilst the nominal share capital was £500,000 and the debenture capital
                            £100,000, only £293,879 of the former and £55,000 of the latter had been
                            issued up to now. The debentures, however, were referred to as Four per
                            Cents. instead of Five per Cents., so that the yield is 1 per cent.
                            better than was made to appear. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Employes’ Federations</head>
                        <p>The societies lately ,ormed will undoubtedly render the greatest services
                            to this interesting class of workers. But the employes must themselves
                            be the authors of their own prosperity, and they will most assuredly
                            attain their object if they but apply themselves to acquiring the
                            principal languages spoken in Egypt:-English, French, German, Arabic,
                            Greek, Italian, etc. The Berlitz School, thanks to its unrivalled
                            system, will enable them to thus attain their end ; a trial lesson will
                            be sufficient to assure them of it. 25781-1</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The National Hotel,</head>
                        <p>in Soliman Pasha- street, Cairo, which has been in course of
                            construction for some time, is gradually nearing completion,and from
                            what may be seen so far, is sure to be a great favorite with our
                            visitors. The furniture has been ordered in England, and will be
                            completely installed before the 1st November, the opening day of this
                            new hotel. Both the dining-room and saloon will be sumptuously
                            decorated, the latter in Louis XII. style, and will offer all the
                            comfort and luxury money and modern appliances can supply. Mr. Chas.
                            Bauer, the well-known proprietor of the Bristol Hotel, has agreed to
                            take over the management of the National, and thus visitors may be
                            certain of being properly attended to. The position of the new hotel,
                            surrounded by mansions and villas, and in a quiet, aristocratic
                            neighbour- hood, will greatly enhance its valou, and the big verandah,
                            which is being constructed, is bound to be the meeting-place of many
                            resi- dents and tourists during the next season.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE HAHMAL'S RETURN. ESCORT ATTACKED BY BEDOUINS. A SHARP SKIRMISH.</head>
                    <p>The Emir el Hag telegraphs that the Mahmal, which left Yambo on the 4th
                        March, has reached Medina. Between Yambo and Medina the escort and pilgrims
                        were attacked by a band of Bedouins, who were successfully re- pulsed in a
                        sharp skirmish. The Emir adds that details will follow by post.</p>
                    <p>Ibrahim Pasha Neghib, who has returned to Cairo from Tor, states that the
                        enquiry which he opened as to the death of a Moor, who was supposed to have
                        been killed and buried by his fellow pilgrims, resulted in the discovery
                        that the Moor had died in alf apopletic fit. His friends, fearing that they
                        might be suspected of poisoning, buried his body with- out informing the
                        authorities.</p>
                    <p>The delegate of the Quarantine Board at the Hedjaz has sent a report on the
                        pilgrimage from Yambo in which he says that the general health of the
                        pilgrims has so far been good. Dysentery continues to prevail, while
                        smallpox is easily spread among the pilgrims in general, and is not fought
                        against at Yambo, where persons attacked by smallpox are dispersed
                        everywhere. The delegate says that he himself noticed a case of small pox
                        among the pilgrims with the Mahmal, and another was that of the wife of the
                        doctor who accom- panied the Egyptian caravan on behalf of the Sanitary
                        Administration.</p>
                    <p>Eight thousand pilgrims are ready to leave for Tor, five thousand of whom are
                        Egyptian. Their condition of health is satisfactory.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THURSDAY’S RAILWAY ACCIDENT.</head>
                    <p>The child to whom the unfortunate accident happened on the railway line which
                        we re- counted in our issue of yesterday, is the five- year-old daughter of
                        M. Debbane, Brazilian Consul-General. The injuries which she sustain- ed are
                        more serious than was at first believed, and as yet she cannot unfortunately
                        be pro- nounced out of danger. It appears that the child was not knocked out
                        of the carriage, but feel out owing to the door not being properly fastened. </p>
                    <p>Mme Debbane, who was in the carriage with her daughter, driven to despair,
                        was only pre- vented from throwing herself on the line, in a wild desire to
                        save her daughter, by a gentleman who happened to be in her company.</p>
                    <p>On the train being stopped, Prince Mohamed Ibrahim, Mohamed Bey Said, and
                        Mohamed Bey Rassehm joined the other passengers in the search for the girl
                        and gave every assistance in their power. The child had meantime been picked
                        up by a camel-driver, who brought her to Galioub station, where first aid
                        was admi- nistred.</p>
                    <p>The train was backed to Galioub and the child was then taken on and brought
                        to Alex- andria, where she now lies in a dangerous condition at her father’s
                        residence.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW TRAMWAY CONCESSION.</head>
                    <p>The Ministry of Public Works has given its approval to the scheme proposed by
                        Boghos Pasha Nubar and M. Empain for the construc- tion of a new tramway to
                        run along the Ismailieh Canal to the desert near Abbas- sieh. The terms of
                        the concession are now being studied.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABOUKIR COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>We understand that at the ordinary meeting of the Aboukir Company, Limited,
                        to be held in London next week, the directors will propose a dividend for
                        the year 1904 of 7 % on the ordinary shares, and also 7 % on the deferred
                        shares. The ordinary shares in January received a dividend of 11 % in
                        payment of balance of arrears of their 7 % cumulative dividend.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="khedive"><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>His Highness passed the day at Montazah Palace yesterday. He leaves for Cairo
                        this evening, after opening the Horticultural Show at San Stefano.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>
                    <p>The opening regatta of the season will be held on Wednesday afternoon next,
                        19th inst. Members are requested to send in the entries for their boatS at
                        onCe to the honorary secre- tary. The handicap Will be published in Tuesday
                        afternoon's "Gazette,” as usual. It has been decided to give the prizes
                        every four regattas instead of every three, the points to connt the same as
                        last year.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="steamerMovements"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss liner "Moeris” arrived this morn- ing from Liverpool, via Oran and
                        Malta, with passengers and mails.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE COLDEN GROSS LINE.</head>
                    <p>FOR CARDIFF AND BRISTOL DIRECT.</p>
                    <p>The fast steamer “Venedotian” will arrive on or about the 17th April and will
                        have room for about 1,400 tons of cargo.</p>
                    <p>For Freight and references, please apply to Alick Nimnim &amp; Son,</p>
                    <p>Marina, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>25780-3-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OPENING OF RACING SEASON. A. S. C. SKYE MEETING.</head>
                    <p>The racing season at Alexandria opened yesterday with the Alexandria Sporting
                        Club’s April Skye Meeting. Notwithstanding the very fine weather which
                        prevailed, there was not a very large turn out of the public, especially in
                        the early part of the meeting, when the grand stand bore a somewhat bare
                        appearance. Later, however, a number of ladies graced the enclosure with
                        their pre- sence, and more animation prevailed. In the racing the only
                        feature of interest was the five successive wins brought about by Khalil
                        Pasha Khayat's stable, and the owner is to be congratulated on his signal
                        success. Jenkins rode four of the five winning mounts, acquitting himself
                        very creditably. Though there were very good fields the finishes did not
                        afford any excitement, with the exceptin of the Pony Stakes, which was the
                        closest. The prettiest race of the day was the one for the Ladies’ Bracelet.
                        There were no less than 16 starters, and all were riding coming up the
                        straight. Pari Mutual yielded good returns, the favorites not coming up to
                        anticipations. The following are the results of the various events, the
                        enjoyment of which was considerably enhanced by the playing of the R. Berks.
                        Band :—</p>
                    <p>NOVICES’ RACE of P.T. 2,500, viz : P.T. 2,000 to winner and P.T. 500 to 2nd
                        horse. For Arabs that have never run in a race of any description, Amateur
                        races and Gymkhanas excepted. Horses 10.7, Galloways 10.3 and ponies 10.0.
                        Distance 5 furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Khayat's c.a.p. little Korosko, 10.0. Jenkins. 1 Mr. A. J.
                        Sursock’s g.a.p. Flying Dutchman, 10.7. Stillwell. 2 Mr. A. J. Sursock's
                        br.ap. Nigri, 10.3. Elias.3 Ibrahim Bey Cherifs g.a.h. Saclavie, 10.8. Ka-
                        mel Effendi. 0 Mr. M. Tueni's ch.a.h. Ajax, 10.7. Mr. G. H. Barker. 0 Mr.
                        Tueni's g.a.p. Hercule, 10.0. Matthews. 0 Saleh Bey Yaghen's g.a.h. Waasal,
                        10.7. Sha- kir. 0 Mr. K. Karam’s g.a.p. Bayard, 10.0. Michaeli- des, Jun. 0
                        Mr J. Hoyami’s g.a.h. Tonnerre, 10.7. Owner. 0 Mr. E. Bastros’ g.a.h. Moulk,
                        10.7. Fenwick. 0 Khalil Pasha Khayat’s b.a.h. Zariff III. 10.7. Whiteside. 0
                        Moh. Pasha Chehim’s g.a.p. Derwish, 10.0. Mr. A. J. Michaelides. 0</p>
                    <p>Despatched to a good start, little Korosko led nearly all the way and won
                        easily by two lengths. A length separated 2nd and 3rd. Time, 1.9. </p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 58 on winner and P.T. 27, 340, and 43 for places.
                        MAIDEN PONY PLATE of P.T. 2,500, viz: P.T. 2,000 to winner and P.T. 500 to
                        2nd horse. For Maiden Arab ponies. Weight for age and inches. Distance 1
                        mile.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Khayat's g.a.p. Au Revoir, 10.10. Jenkins. 1 Khalil Pasha
                        Khayat's g.a.p. Zeidan, 9.10. Whiteside. 2 Messrs. W. B. Rees and G. H.
                        Barker's g.a.p. India, 9.10. Mr. G. H. Barker. 3 Mohsen Pasha's g.a.p. Taib,
                        10.3. Mikhali. 0 Messrs. W. B. Rees and G. H. Barker's b.a.p. Firefly, 10.7.
                        Mr Ramsay. 0 Mr. E. Karam's g.a.p. Nimrod, 9.10. Mi- chaelides, Jun. 0 Saleh
                        Bey Yaghen’s b.ap. Spectre, 10.8. Bonser. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherifs g.a.p.
                        Sattam, lO.5 Kamel Effendi. 0 Ishak Bey Hussein and Hassan Bey Kheir el
                        Din's c.a.p. Rais, 10.7. Stillwell. 0</p>
                    <p>A good start, all keeping well together till they entered the cutting, when
                        Au Revoir took up the lead, followed by Taib, and Spectre. In the straight,
                        Zeidan came to the front but could not reach Au Revoir, who won easily by
                        about two lengths, India being a bad third. Time, 1.53 1/2. </p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 36 on winner, and P.T. 26, 41, and 43 for places.</p>
                    <p>TRIAL PLATE of P.T. 2,500, viz : P.T. 2,000 to winner and P.T. 500 to 2nd
                        horse. For Maiden Arabs. Weight for age. Distance 6 furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Khayat's c.a.p. Klondyke, 10.5. Jenkins. 1 Ishak Bey Hussein’s
                        ch.a.h. El Tahawi, 10.7. Stillwell. 2 Mr. M. Tueni's b.a.h. Caprice, 10.7.
                        Matthews. 3 Mohsen Pasha b.a.h. Gogo, 10.7. Mikhali. 0 Moharrem Pasha
                        Chehim’s g.a.h. Jupiter, 10.6. Mr. A. J. Michaelides. 0 Khalil Pasha
                        Khayat's g.a.p. Lonlou, 10.6. Whiteside 0 Capt. G. B. Byrne’s g.a.h.
                        Chinaman, 10.7. Moursi. 0 Messrs. W. B. Rees and G. H. Barker’s b.a.h. Ion,
                        10.7. Mr. G. H. Barker. 0 Ishak Bey Hussein’s g.a.h. Sir Visto, 10.8.
                        Fenwick. 0 </p>
                    <p>Klondyke made most of the running and won fairly easily by a length, the
                        others being close up. Time, 1.22 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 78 on winner, and P.T. 27, 28, and 45 for places. </p>
                    <p>PONY STAKES of P.T. 2,500. 2nd horse to receive P.T. 500 out of the Stakes.
                        For ' Arab ponies. Weight for age and inches with penalties. Distance 6
                        furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Khayat's g.ap. Kawkab, 9.6. Jenkins. 1 Ishak Bey Hussein and
                        Haasan Bey Kheir el Din’s b.a.p. Faik, 9.7. Stillwell 2 Messrs. W. B. Rees
                        and G. H. Barkers g.a.p. Vandal 10.0. Mr. G. H. Barker. 3 Ibrahim Bey
                        Cherif’s g.a.p. Amour, 9.3. Aly Hawass. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherifs g.a.p. Sattam.
                        9.6. Eliseo. 0 Moharrem Pasha Chehim’s g.a.p. Mamdouh, 9.2. Mr. A. J.
                        Michaelides. 0 Khalil Pasha Khayat's c.a.p. Suleik, 9.6. White- side. 0</p>
                    <p>Amour got the best of a headstart, Suleik being left at the post. Amour was
                        soon joined in the lead by Sattan, but on coming into the straight both
                        horses fell back and the rest was a close race between Kawkab and Faik, the
                        former winning by a length. Time, 1.25.</p>
                    <p>Totalizator paid P.T. 99 on winner, and P.T. 30,59, and 90 for places.</p>
                    <p>LADIES BRACELET of P.T. 2,000 present- ed by the Alexandria an Ramleh Railway
                        Company, viz: P.T. 1,000 to the nominator of the winner and P.T. 1,000 to
                        the owner together with P.T. 500 added to go to 2nd horse. For Arabs that
                        have never won a race except Gymkhanas. To be nominate by ladies. Horses
                        11.7, Ponies 10.11. Distance 6 furlongs.</p>
                    <p>Khalil Pasha Khayat's g.a.h. Sinounou, 11.7. Whiteside. 1 Mr. H. Eisler’s
                        g.a.h. Temsah, 10.11 Elias. 2 Mr. M. Tueni’s g.a.h. Faineant, 11.7 Mr. G. H.
                        Barker. 3 Mr. A. J. Sursock’s g.a.h. Flying Dutchman, 11.7. stillwell. 0
                        Khalil Pasha Khayat’s c.a.p. Doughan, 10.11. Jenkins. 0 Mr. E. Bustros'
                        g.a.h. Numir, 10.11. Fenwick. 0 Moharrem Pasha Chehim’s g.a.h. Jupiter,
                        11.7. Mr. A.J. Michaelidis. 0 Moh. Pasha Cdhehim;s g.a.p. Dervish, 10.11. 0
                        Mr. M. Tueni’s g.a.p. Hercule, 10.11. Matthews. 0 Mr. E. Karam’s’ g.a.h.
                        Boheme, 11.7. Michaeli- des Jun. 0 Sales Bey Yaghen’s g.a.h. Vassal, 11.7.
                        Shakir. 0 Sales Bey Yaghen’s b.a.p. Spectre, 10.11 Bonser. 0 Ibrahim Bey
                        Cherif’s g.a.h. Soulferino, 10.11. Eliseo. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s g.a.h.
                        Azize, 11.7. Aly Hawass. 0 Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s g.a.h. Saclavie, 11.7. Kamel
                        Effendi. 0</p>
                    <p>This was a very pretty race. The big field were despatched to a good start,
                        all the horses keeping together in a cluster until entering the straight,
                        when Temsah was seen to have gained slightly the advantage. In the straight
                        Sinounou came through his horses and shot ahead, Temsah at his heels. He was
                        never overtaken, however, and won by a couple of lengths. Nearing the post,
                        Faineant came with a rush and almost wrested 2nd place from Temsah, who only
                        got it by a head. Time, 1.24.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 247 on winner, and P.T. 75, 57, and 155 for places.</p>
                    <p>APRIL PLATE of P.T. 2,500. 2nd horse to receive P.T. 500 out of the Stakes.
                        For Arabs. Weight for age with penalties. Distance round the course.</p>
                    <p>Mr. A. J. Sursook’s g.a h. Boule de Neige, 9.4. Elias. 1 Mr. P. W. Stout’s
                        g.a.h. Showman, 9.7. Whiteside. 2 Khalil Pasha Khayat’s g.a.p. Au Revoir,
                        9.7. Jenkins. 3 Mr. Teuni’s b.a.p. Caprice, 9.7. Matthews. 0 Isak Bey
                        Hussein’s and hassan Bey Kheir el Din’s ch.a.p. Rais, 9.7. Stillwell. 0
                        Ibrahim Bey Cherif’s g.a.h. Royalist, 9.7. Kamel Effendi. 0 Mr. E. Karam’s
                        ch.a.h. Coeur de Lion, 9.7. Michaelides, Jun. 0 Messrs. W. B. Rees and G.
                        H.Barker’s ch.a.h. Shari, 9.7, Mr. G. H. Barker. 0</p>
                    <p>The horses got away to a good start, Mash- kour and Coeur de Lion leading.
                        When reaching the mile post, Coeur de Lion still maintained the premier
                        position, with Royalist in close attendance. On entering the cutting Boule
                        de Neige challenged the leader and was first into the straight, where all
                        were riding. Coeur de Lion was now done with and although Au Revoir at one
                        time looked like winning, Boule de Neige got first past the post by barely a
                        length, Au Revoir being some distance behind Shewiman. Time, 2.35.</p>
                    <p>Totalisator paid P.T. 48 on winner, and P.T. 27, 76, and 36 for places.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="passList">
                    <head>PASSENGER LISTS.</head>
                    <head>ARRIVALS.</head>
                    <p>Per Moss S.S. "Moeris,” arrived to-day from Liverpool :-Mr. H.B. Johnston,
                        Pte W. Salt, Pte W. Skillett, and 4 deck passengers.</p>
                    <p>Lo paquobot "Salaria" des Messageries Ma- ritimes parti hier pour Marseille
                        avait a bord. M. et Mme Beyram Bey et Mustafa Bayram Bey, M. et Mme Barbier,
                        M. et Mme Gutmann, M. Specht, Mme Hatter, M. le Dr Kenneth Scott, Mme
                        Kenneth Scott, Mme H. S. Gaze, Mlle Rich, M. et Mme G. Watson, M. le Dentu,
                        M. de Heredia, M. et Mme J. L. Baird, Cap. Cave, Mme Bernard, M. Appert, Mme
                        J. Roche, Mlle Teed, M. Bonhomme, M. Offen- tranger, M. Mowat, M. Paul
                        Honal, M. Benoit, Mme Favre, Clogstooun, M. et Mme Coutant, M. Emile
                        Claville, M. H. Mathews, Mme Susznna Valmont, M. J. Rapaport, Madame
                        Fillion, Madame Royet, M. Thomas, Mrs. G. R. et A. Huri et sa dame, Mlle
                        Kheror, Mme Myrthes, Mme Dorey, M. Constantopoulo, Mlle Florence Mellor, M.
                        Schehade, M. Lambert, M. Tennant, M. Halek Ismail, Miss Bourguer, M.
                        Bedouin, M. Af- frentangen, M Tarpinian, M. Essely, M.Copping, Mme Kamleh,
                        M. Darcier, M. et Mme Garnier, M. A. I. Larrat, M. Vallet, M. Oback, M. et
                        Mme Chiess, Mlle Hurully, Mme Besson, M. Fritz, M. Moray.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TYROL.</head>
                    <p>Weissentein Castle 3410 ft. First-class private hotel near Windisch Matroi ;
                        Station, Liens (reached from Venice or Trieate). Good mountaineering centre.
                        Tennis. Fishing, best June and September. Prospectuses and Pho- to graphs,
                        “Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>25365-48-28</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah01">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>Ten minutes from Alexandria. First-Class in every respect Very moderate
                        charges. Bulkeley is the fashionable English quarter. Visitors fron Cairo
                        alight at Sidi Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p>24480-24-5-905</p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" element="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Prince Mohamed Aly, brother of the Khedive, arrived at Constantinople on
                        Monday last. His Highness went straight to the Imperial Palace, and
                        afterward, to the Yali of the Khedivah Mother at Bebek, where he is at
                        present re- siding. </p>
                    <p>Prince Aziz Pasha Hassen and Zeky Pasha arrived at Alexandria from Cairo last
                        evening.</p>
                    <p>Abdul Halim Pasha Assem, Director-General of the Wakfs Administration, has
                        left for Cairo.</p>
                    <p>M. de la Bouliniere, French Diplomatic Agent, arrived from Cairo yesterday.
                        He is staying with M. P. Girard, French Consul at Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Councillor A. C. Cumbo leaves today for Brindisi by the "Semiramis." He
                        intends to spend the Easter holidays at Rome with his family and will be
                        back in Alexandria in three weeks.</p>
                    <p>The marriage arranged between Miss Mary Prior and Mr. William H. E. Quintana
                        will take place at St. Catherine's Cathedral Alex- andria, on Monday, 24th
                        inst., at 2 p.m.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death, which took place at Alexandria yesterday, of
                        M. Gregoire Mistrovachi. The funeral of deceased, who was a chevalier of the
                        Order of Francis- Joseph, took place this morning, at the Greek Orthodox
                        cemetery,</p>
                    <p>We have received P.T. 50 from Mme. Vve. H. Gantse and a like amount from Mr.
                        E. C. Manuk, for the St. Vincent de Paul charity, in memory of the late M.
                        Mistrovachi.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HOLY WEEK AND EASTER  SERVICES.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALL SAINTS’ CHURCH, CAIRO.</head>
                        <p>On Monday, Tueday, Wednesday, and Thurs- day, April 17th to 20th the
                            Services will be as follows:— 8.30 a.m. Holy Communion. 10.30 “ Morning
                            prayer. 6.30 p.m. Evensong and Address.</p>
                        <p>On Good Friday 8.30 a.m. Ante-Communion. 10.30 „ Morning Prayer and
                            Sermon. 2.— p.m. One hour Service. 6.- “ Evening Prayer and Sermon.</p>
                        <p>On Easter Eve Holy Communion 8.30 a.m. Morning Prayer 10.30 „</p>
                        <p>On EASTER DAY Holy Communion 6.30 a.m. 7.30 a.m. 8.30 a.m. and after
                            Morning Service. Other Servicee as on Sundays.</p>
                        <p>On Easter Monday and Tuesday Holy Communion 8.30 a.m.</p>
                        <p>Offertory on Good Friday will be devoted to  the Jerusalem and the East
                            Mission Fund.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ST. MARK'S, ALEXANDRIA. HOLY WEEK. </head>
                        <p>Monday to Thursday inclusive 8 a.m. Holy Communion. 11 a.m. Morning
                            Prayer and Address. 5.30 p.m. Evening Prayer and Address.</p>
                        <p>Good Friday. 8 am. Ante-Communion Service. 11 a.m. Morning Player,
                            Litany, and Sermon. 6.15 p.m. Evening Prayer and Address.</p>
                        <p>Easter Eve. 8 a.m. Ante-Communion Service</p>
                        <p>EASTER DAY. Three Celebrations of the Holy Com- munion, 7 a.m. 8 a.m. and
                            Noon. 11 a.m. Matins and Sermon. 6.15 a.m. Evensong and Sermon.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALL SAINTS’ RAMLEH. HOLY WEEK.</head>
                        <p>Monday to Thursday inclusive: 8 a.m. Holy Communion. 6 p.m. Evening
                            Prayer and Address.</p>
                        <p>Good Friday. 8 a.m. Ante-Communion Service. 11 a.m. Morning Prayer,
                            Litany, and Sermon. 6.30 p.m. Evening Prayer and Address.</p>
                        <p>EASTER DAY. The Holy Communion will be celebrated at 7.30 a.m., 8.30 am.
                            and at noon, in addition to the usual services at 11 am. 3.30 p.m. and
                            6.30. p.m.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" element="bulletinBourse"><head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <head>(Auiourd’hui a midi et demie)</head>
                    <p>Le marche en general se maintient dans les positions acquises. Certaines
                        valeurs accusent meme une hausse notable ; entre autres, la Daira et la
                        Crown Brewery. Quant aux transac- tions, elles ont ete assez nombreuses, en
                        parti- culier en Daira et en Salt and Soda.</p>
                    <p>La Daira debute a 27 3/8, et atteint 28 pour cloturer achetersn a 27 15/16
                        avec tendance marquee a la hausse.</p>
                    <p>De 210 la Crown Brewery passe en raison d’une forte demands a 220, prix
                        anquel elle cloture acheteurs.</p>
                    <p>De 38/8 al’ouverture la Salt and Soda a’eleve graduellement a 39/83 en
                        cloture avec beau- coup d’affaires. </p>
                    <p>Il y a du mieux aussi en Investment a 2 3/16, en Oasis a 1 838 et an
                        Privileglees Tram- ways a 147 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Par contre la Nungovich est plus fiable a 10 1/4 l’Anglo American Nile a 5
                        13/16, la Delta Light a 14 1/8 et la Ramleh Railway a 8 3/16.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
