<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10-10-16</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-06-30</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, JUNE 30, 1906.</head>
<div type="item">
<head>ODESSA IN FLAMES.</head>
<head>WORK OF MUTINEERS.</head>
<head>REIGN OF TERROR.</head>
<head>300 RIOTERS KILLED</head>
<head>HOSPITALS OVERFLOWING.</head>
    <dateline>London, June 29.</dateline>
<p>The ”Standard" learns from Odessa that
revolutionary mobs yesterday evening set fire
to the quarantine station, the warehouses and
other buildings of the harbour, and prevented
the firemen from extinguishing the Hemes.
The troops are terrorised by the guns of the
“Potemkin,” which late last night fired a
shell at a Cossack piquet, killing and wound-
ing 24. A torpedo-boat accompanying the
"Potemkin" entered the harbour and seized a
Russian steamer with a cargo of 2,000 tons of
coal.
The Governor has telegraphed to Sevastopol
for the fleet, but it is feared that the mutiny
will spread, as all the crews are disaffected,
and it is even reported that four battleships
have already mutinied, of which two are on
their way to Odessa. Grave anxiety is felt at
Lloyd’s, as there are many British ships in the
harbour.	(Reuter.)</p>
<dive type=“item”>
    <dateline>London, June 29.</dateline>
<p>The latest news from Odessa shows that
serious riots have taken place. Hundreds ol
people have been shot and the port is partially
destroyed by fire. Martial law has been pro-
claimed.	(Reuter.)</p>
<dive type=“item”>
    <dateline>Odessa, June 29.</dateline>
<p>It is confirmed that all the officers of the
“Potemkin” were murdered except three.
The sailors were prominent in yesterday's
street fighting.
A battleship and a cruiser left Sevastopol in
all haste for Odessa. Before burning the ware-
houses the mob carried off the goods. The
loss is estimated at 1,000,000 roubles. The
city is enveloped in smoke. All the shops are
shat and traffic is suspended. The troops hold
the main streets and the hospitals are over-
flowing.
There are not sufficient doctors to attend to
the wounded. Many inhabitants are leaving
the city. In several instances yesterday the
troops, who are mostly reservists, refused to
fire on the mob	(Reuter.)</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<head>DEATH OF ADMIRAL WALKER.</head>
    <dateline>London, June 29</dateline>
<p>Admiral Sir Baldwin Wake Walker is dead
	(Reuter.)
Rear Admiral Sir Baldwin Wake Walker.
2nd Baronet and Pasha of the Turkish Em-
pire, was bom st Siessa, Tuscany, on Sep torn
her 24, 1846, and succeeded to the title on
the death of his father in 1876. He entered
’be Royal Navy in 1859, was made lieutenant
in 1868, and commander in 1880 He served in
the Egyptian war of 1889, and was one of the
officers engage. 1 in the protection of the New-
foundland Fisheries, IR92. He was made C M 0
•n 1893 and C.V.O in the same year. He held
the command of the Mediterranean cruisers,
and was in Alexandria last year on the
occasion of the visit of the Mediterranean
Squadron.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
<p>The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O.,
Alexandria, at 8.30 a m. on Monday.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Stray and Ownerless Does found in the
Ghezireh district of Cairo during the night of
Sunday and at daylight on Monday will be
poisoned by the police.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>St. Andrew’s Church, Alexandria. — The
usual quarterly oclebration of the Lord’s Supper
will take place in this church on Sunday
next at 10.30 a.m. Visitors and strangers are
cordially invited.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Suez Canal —10 vessels passed through the
Canal on the 27th inst, 6 of which were
British. 1 German, 1 Dutch, 2 Italian. The
day’s receipts were frs. 275,422.47, making the
total from the 1st inst frs. 7.506,192.22</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Harmonia Club.—The “fete de tondation"
of this club will take place to-morrow evening,
commencing at 9 o’clock precisely, when a
very select concert programme will be gone
through, after which there will be a small
dance.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Fatal Pall from Building. — A native
workman engaged in limewashing the walls of
the third story of the new building belonging
to H.H. Prince Mohamed Ibrahim, in Moha-
med Aly-square, lost his balance yesterday and
fall into the street He died on being removed
to hospital</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>The Plague.—Yesterday's plague bulletin
records one fresh case at Alexandria, one
recovery at Port Said, one fresh case at Toukh,
and one death at Ashmoun. There are now
21 cases under treatment Dr. W. MacCarthy
Morroghy has been temporarily appointed to
plagne duty.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Lamp Explosion.—An accident which, for-
tunately, was not attended with serious conse-
quences, occurred yesterday to Mme. Myralda,
a medium of Prof. Lafontaiue, the hypnotist
While in the act of lighting a paraffin oil lamp
the latter exploded and the lady was soon in
flames. Thanks, however, to prompt assistance
all danger was averted. She merely sustained
a few slight bums.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Me.x Casino.—A grand open-air file will be
given at Mex Casino to-morrow evening by the
Margherita and Ernesto Rossi societies com-
bined. The first part of the programme will
consist of a dramatic entertainment and the
second of a ball, which latter will commence
at half-past midnight Tramcars will run
between Mex and the city during the whole
of the eight for the convenience of those
attending the fete.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Hotel Beau Rivage, Ramleh.—An excep-
tionally large number of visitors have patronis-
ed daring the early part of the season the
fashionable Bean-Rivage Hotel, which has been
full op every week since May. The restaurant
on the terrace facing the sea is now open, and
can accommodate 180 guests at small tables.
Meals in this open-air-restaurant are much
appreciated, and many banquets have been
given daring June. Afternoon tea in the
garden has become quite popular, it being such
a charming excursion from Alexandria to the
beau-Rivage The small dances which were
such a great success will soon be held regularly.</p>
<dive type=“item”>
<p>Carriage Accident.—Yesterday a carriage
accident that might have entailed serious con-
sequences took place at Cairo. Mohamed Bey
Seif el Nasr, of the Egyptian Army, had left
his dogcart in Kernel-street to purchase
some cigarettes when the horse took fright
and bolted with Miss Nasr, who was sitting in
the cart. The syce lost his head and dropped
the bridle at once and the horse rushed away.
Near the Continental Hotel the dogcart was
upset by a collison,and Miss Nasr was flung out.
She was immediately removed to the Con-
tinental Hotel where it proved that though
much shaken and frightened the had sustained</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Gardner-Brown Bioscope and Variety Co.
—This popular combination gave their opening
performance at the Mustapha Garrison Theatre
last night to a house packed to its utmost
capacity, and soured an unqualified success,
the audience showing their appreciation by
repeated calls for encores. Miss Annie Russell,
a dainty young soubrette, opened the show and
pleased every one by her clever rendering of a
couple of songs in lighter vein. Mr. Geo.
Gulliver, who followed, proved an excellent
ventriloquist, and caused roars of laughter with
the funny sayings and antics of his figures,
whioh so pleased the delighted audience that he
was compelled to respond to an encore. Miss
Lottie Walton, who next appeared, possesses a
very sweet and sympathetic voice, and her
rendering of the descriptive ballads was greatly
enjoyed, A series of animated pictures by the
Gardner Brown Bioscope followed ; these were
very clear and steady, snd were enthusiastically
received, especially the scene depicting an
incident at the Battle of the Yale. The Sisters
Romaine were very warmly received, their
singing and dancing, in addition to their youth
and graceful appearance, making them general
favorites. Mr. Leo. Montague, an exceptionally
clever comedian, hugely delighted the audience
with his songs with topical allusions, and had
to respond to an enthusiastic encore. Illustrated
songs by Mrs. Gardner Brown, and a wonderful
bioscopic production entitled The Poachers,”
brought to a conclusion a most bright and
sparkling entertainment during which there
was not a single doll moment The company
perform at Mustapha tonight and Saturday,
and will give a special performance at the
Railway Institute, Demanbour, on Sunday.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>THE “DNIEPER” AT SUEZ</head>
<head>“ST. HILDA'S” CREW ON BOARD.</head>
<head>BRITISH CRUISERS IN HER WAKE.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent).
    <dateline>Suez, Friday. 8 a.m.</dateline>
The Russian cruiser "Dnieper" has arrived
here. She is followed by a British battleship,
which is presumably H.M.S. "Goliath.” Parti-
culars will follow.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Suez Dock, Friday. 10.18a.m.
The "Dnieper " will enter the Canal to day.
The crew <-f the British steamer "St. Hilda"
are on board and will apparently land at Port
Said. I boarded the Russian cruiser bat the
officers absolutely refused to grant me an
interview or to allow me to see the British
prisoners of the “St. Kildas' The battleship
“Canopus" is entering the canal in the forenoon.
The battleship “Goliath" has been sighted.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>LOCAL BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
    <dateline>London, June 29.</dateline>
<p>Sir B. H. Vincent Corbett and Mr. Malcolm
Mollwraith have been created K.C.M.G. (R.)</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>RAILWAY COLLISION AT ASSIOUT.</head>
<p>(Prom our Correspondent).
Tahta, Wednesday.
The mail arrived yesterday five hours behind
time. The delay is due, I am informed by a
passenger from Assiout, to the negligence of
the pointsman there. The two up and down
trains that start regularly from Asaiout at 6
o’clock in the morning were maneuvering pre
vious to departure when the two engines col-
lided. The locomotives were not attached to
the carriages of the trains, and the drivers, see-
ing the danger they were in, jumped off and
thus save 1 their lives. The engines met with a
terrific impact and were both derailed, one
falling on the left of the line and the other on
the right. As the drivers had tailed to shut
off steam in their haste to save themselves, the
engines were still in motion and ploughed into
the ground. It was with great difficulty that
the drivers were eventually able to stop the
machinery.
Traffic was thus interrupted and the up and
down passengers had to be transferred from
one train to another until, 10 hours afterwards,
the line was cleared.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>ALEXANDRIA HARBOUR.</head>
<p>The breakwater in Alexandria harbour is
about to be lengthened, and the work htf
already been commenced. The new works will
extend from the red light on the end of the
breakwater to the pivot buoy (approx.)
A buoy has been laid down in 18 feet
(approx.) to mark the 8.E edge of the 13 feet
bank, which lies to the west of the breakwater
end.
Other buoys will be laid down from time to
time along the line of work between the end
of the breakwater and the pivot buoy, and
mariners are cautioned not to pass between
these points.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>THB GHIRGEH SCANDAL</head>
<head>ACCUSED FOUND GUILTY.</head>
<p>The Rifaa case came up before the Native
Court of Appeal at Cairo yesterday, the hearing
opening at 9 am. before the President of the
Court, Hasaem Bey Amin, and Aziz Bey Kahil
and Ahmed Bey Ziwar, who acted as assessors,
and Aly Bey Abu-el-Fetuk, publio prosecutor.
The morning was devoted to tho hearing of the
case for the prosecution. The Court adjourned at
1 p.m. for two hours.The defence of the accuse
was then heard,the pleadings lasting till 6 p.m.
The president then asked if they had anything
to add to the statements made by their counsel.
On their answering in the negative the Court
retired to consider the verdict.
At 7 p.m. the Court returned and the pro
didnt read out the verdict All the accused
were found guilty. The Mondir, the Cadi, and
the Wekil of the Daira Rifaa were sentenced
to two years' imprisonment with hard labour,
the young Rifaa to one year's imprisonment
wiw hard laboar, and the remainder of the
accused to six months' imprisonment. All the
culprits were condemned to pay a fine of LE.
50, with the costs of the case.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>TRADE OF EGYPT.</head>
<head>MAY CUSTOMS RETURNS.</head>
<p>The Customs Administration has published
its returns for the month of May. The value
of the imports to the fire ports of Egypt
(Alexandria, Port-Said, Suez, Damietta and
Kosseir) amounts to L.E. 1,533,679, against
LE. 1,451,949 in the corresponding month
of 1904, while the total for the first five months
of the year shows an advance of LE 722,072
on last year’s figures.
The export statistics for the past month
show a certain falling-off, the difference being
LE. 72,840 in favor of May 1904. The same
decrease is to be noticed in the figures for the
period January 1-May 31, 190^, the total
value of the goods exported daring that period
reaching LB. 8,293,341, as against LB.
10,057,661 in the corresponding period last
year.
British imports in May, 1905, amounted to
LE 506,385 and to LB. 2,653,06* for the first
five months of the year, against LB. 504,501
and LE 2,467,478 for the corresponding
periods last year. Exports to Great Britain
amounted to LE 617,439 in May, 1905,
against LE 581,581 in May, 1904, and
the first five months of the present year
show a total of LE. 4,244,697, against LR
4,989,264 in the corresponding period in 1904.
For the past month Turkey comes second to
Groat Britain among the importing countries.
Comparing the export statistics for May
1906, with those for May, 1804. we notice a
decrease in cotton exports representing a sum
of LE 232,674 and a slight (and very natural)
decrease in hides. The most remarkable
increase comes under the beading of rice
and amounts to LB. 87,999. Onion exports
(+86,909) and cane sugar (+40,112) also
show a gratifying increase, not for the past
month only, as in the case of rice, bat for the
five months. Among the imports the largest
increase comes under the beading of floor
(+49,700 for May and +122,789 for the first
five months of the year). Cotton goods and
iron articles also show an increase for the
latter period.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>A GREAT CAIRO SCANDAL</head>
<p>We would call the attention of the police
authorities to a grave public scandal that has
been allowed to exist for too long, and which is
a blot to the Capital that should no longer be
tolerated. We allude to the European houses
of ill-fame that are to be seen on all sides at
the very entrance to the city, at the commence-
ment of the Rue Kamel and within a stone's
throw of Cook's office and Shepbeard'a, one of
the most frequented parts of the metropolis.
Some three or four year ago, on the com
plaint of the management of the above hotel
and several of its prominent visitors, a stop
was put to the assembling nightly during the
winter season, on the pavements round about
this loyalty, of numbers of women from the
adjacent houses of bad repute, and it should
not therefore be difficult for the local police to
have the occupants of these houses removed to
a spot where they would not be such a public
scandal</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
<head>LOST—A TORPEDO.</head>
<p>(Prom our Correspondent.)
Port Said, Thursday.
H. M. 8. "Suffolk," while at «aa going
through the regular firing practice on Monday,
had the misfortune to lose a torpedo valued
at over £600, for which  a reward of £5 is
now being offered. She returned to harbour
after a successful day, at sunset</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>THB CHINA SQUADRON.</head>
<p>H.M. battleships "Goliath" and “Canopus,"
which wore at Aden on Friday last, are ex-
ported at Suez very shortly, to be followed
by the remaining six ships of the China Squa
dron daring the second week in July.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<had>CANAL COMPANY.</head>
<p>Comte de Serionne, accompanied by M.
Tillier, arrived at Port Said yesterday from
Cairo, and put up at the Canal Company's
"Residence.” They are to remain wily a
day or so.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>ENTERTAINMENT ON "LANCA8TBR.”</head>
<p>The crew of H. M. S. “Lancaster" are
giving an evening entertainment to-night to
those of the "Suffolk," in return for one given
by the latter at Malta. The programme will
consist of a sketch, a gymnastic display, and
variety show. The stage, which has bean
erected in Navy House by the crews them-
selves, will be lit, as will all the decorations
of the auditorium, by means of electricity
conveyed from the vessels through submarine
cables. Fairy lights and bunting will be the
base of the deporations.
(By Telegraph).
Port Said, Friday.
The "Lancaster's" entertainment last night
was a great success. The programme comprised
songs, sword and axe swinging, flying rings,
and a comic sketch entitled "Jaffin's Latchkey."
The ship's band performed during the evening.
The manager of the entertainment was Lieu-
tenant Wilton.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.</head>
<p>(Prom our Pimamoul Corrnsfondut)
London, June 28.
Had we bean writing our report yesterday
we should have been able to say that the
undertone in the Stock Exchange was stronger,
on the improved condition of affairs both as
regards the peace proposals and the Morocco
question, bat, alas, today the pessimists hare
again got the upper hand. Prices throughout
the general list are very "wobbly,” due to
a report that the German reply to the dig-
nified Preach note is not satisfactory.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Paris has been a busy seller of most of
her specialities dealt in in this market This
has in turn reacted on prices generally.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Consols closed at 90* after opening
90Ai a foil of | on the day, and there is
very little businees doing in gilt-edged secu-
rities generally, the tone /being rather in
favor of buyers than sellers. German I %,
which opened at 88 , close at 88 , and
French Rentes show a foil on the day of
J at 98.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>There is no feature of interest to report
in the market for Egyptian securities. Prices
show little or no change since oar lest report.
National Banks are slightly off and Mow at
25 J, and Agricultural Banks are particularly
firm at 18 |. In the mining section many of
the principal jobbers are absent owing to the
A soot races, which are being run is glorious
weather. Nile valleys closed at i A A,
Sudan Mines, Urn Eos 1, and Balt
and Soda 1.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL
We regret to learn of the death, which
Occurred yesterday, of Mr. Albert Bensilum,
manager for the 8alt and Soda Company, Limi-
ted, at Wadi Nation.
The marriage of M. Benvenuto Campos to
Mile Marcelle Aghion, daughter of M. and
Mme Benjamin Aghion, was celebrated at
Mme. Joseph Campos, near the Palace Station,
Ramleh. There was a very Urge and fashionable
attendance, which included many of the leading
representatives of Alexandrian society. A re-
ception was hdd after the religions ceremony
bed been performed, and the guests had time
to admire the wedding presents, many of which
were of exceptional beauty. The buffet was
much appreciated and the guests did not leave
till 8 p.m.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Kearsley and Cunningham's Weekly Report.
Liverpool, Jane 22.
Since the Market reopened after the holidays
Egyptian has been in active demand and
prices for the superior grades of Brown are
raised J per lb. , other descriptions are un-
changed. In Futures a fair business has been
done and the following are the dosing values:—
June 6.67 Aug. 6.58 Oct 156
July 6.68 Sep. 6.66 Nov. 6.63 Dee. 6.46
Americas Future* We did not issue any
report last week as the Market wee interrupted
owing to the Whitsuntide holidays. Sines our
last report there has been considers his activity,
and a further material advance in vainer, at
one time amounting to about 40 peseta. The
whole of the advance has been maintained,
but today's closing values are @ <8 points
higher then thaw of our last report on the
8th inst. The advance is chiefly due to extensive
“Ball" manipulation in the 8 merino markets,
based upon the scarcity of good grades, which
hare bean heavily sold for forward deli very, to
continued unsatisfactory reports of the condi-
tion of the Crop, which is aggravated by its
unusual lateness. It is possible that these
influences may compel higher prices, bat in
the neighbourhood of 5d. per lb. we cannot
recommend purchases, unless on sharp re-
actions. The following art the latest quota-
tions :—
Jane 4.86 8ep./Oot. 4.84 Jam/Feb. 4.84</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
<p>The 88. "Asriout," of the Westoott and
Laurence Line, left Malta on Wednesday and
is doe here Sanday afternoon or Moedey aton-
ing, with general cargo from Antwerp aad
London.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>PASSENGER LISTS</head>
<head>DEPARTURES.</head>
<p>Le paqoebot "Singapore" do la Cie Florio
Rubattino parti hiar pour Genes avait k bord :
MM. F. Dements, M. et Mme Levi, Carlo
Foret, Dr et Mme Oaetani, M. Simaika, Parag
Tiab, M. et M me Msggio, ProlNelli, Motzoli, W a
genovork. Prof. Ribooi, A.Rizzo et fom., Dorn.
Levi, P. Leguna, B. B. Charles, M. et Mme
Porto, P6re Agoetino, Mile Greglia, M. et Mme
Ch. Lipinas, Veeoova Va'destino et oompaguoo,
D. Tasso et eomp.. Mound Eff. et neveo, Milo
Mellonoini, Mile Roooatagliata, Hag Mohamed
Sellami. Baronne Fllix do Meoaaee ot dom ,
Mme Halifa Sachs et fillee, Mme Ida Tilehe et
fom., Dr Camerini, M. Piha et fom, Salome,
Dom. de la fom. Piha, Mme Rimediotti, Q.
Nestri. Mme Proli et * fils, M. et Mme Corelli,
U. Bocoia et fom., M Buries®, Mme Pilniato
vaska, Pavero, M. et Mme Mitris, K. 8torn,
A. Pardo et fom., G. Maruooo et fom., Mme
Moroni et file, Prof. Pasole, Mme De 8emo et
fil», Cap. di Maio, Dr Gataky, A. Finardi et
fom., Pfcre Borioo, Phro Cardano, dom. dames
Corelli, Mme Corelli et fils, J. Decern, G.
Stormiolo et 144 pemagerede 8me olasse.
ARRIVALS.
Par P. & 0. as. “Syria,” arrived yesterday
from London at Port Said —Mr. and Miss
Fletcher, from Malta :-Mre. Page.</p> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
