<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2022-09-09">September 9, 2022</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1906-01-27/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1906-01-27">Saturday, January 27, 1906</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="8">8</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01">The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.<lb/> This Company's system of submarine telegraph
                                <lb/>cables is the most direct and quickest means of
                                <lb/>communication from Egypt to Europe, North and <lb/>South
                                America, East, South and West Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New
                                Zealand, China and Japan.<lb/> To secure quick transmission,
                                telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi rend="italic">Via
                                Eastern</hi>.For latest average time to London, see daily
                                <lb/>bulletin in this paper.<lb/> STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria,
                                Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik, Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office.
                                London.</cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01">
                                <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7404">7,404</measure>]</cell>
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, JANUARY 27, 1906.</cell>
                            <cell> [EIGHT PAGES</cell>
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-pos05">
                    <head>Peninsular and Oriental S. N. Company.</head>
                    <p>Berths can be definitely engaged beforehand. Plans can be seen at the Offices
                        of the Company's Agents.</p>
                    <p>The through Steamers for Marseilles, Gibraltar, Plymouth and London are
                        Intended to leave Port Said after the arrival of the 11 a.m. train from
                        Cairo, every Monday. A steam tender will meet the train to convey passengers
                        to the ship.</p>
                    <p>The Brindisi Express Steamer leaves Port Said directly the Indian Mails
                        arrive. Passengers can go on board the evening before.</p>
                    <p>The express steamer usually reaches Brindisi on Wednesday afternoon, the
                        special train starting at 8 p.m. and arriving in London at the very
                        convenient hour of 4.56 p.m. on Friday.</p>
                    <p>The combined Sea and special train fare is £22.9.11 Port Said to London via
                        Brindisi or via Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>Passengers having paid fall fare in one direction are allowed an abatement of
                        25 per cent, on returning within 12 months.</p>
                    <p>In addition to the above regular weekly service there are sailings about
                        twice a fortnight of 5,000 to 7,000 tons steamers to London, calling at
                        Malta or Marseilles.</p>
                    <p>TO THE EAST.</p>
                    <p>The Mail Steamers leave Suez for Aden and Bombay every Wednesday, and for
                        Australia and China every alternate Wednesday. A steamer leaves for
                        Calcutta, fortnightly, and another for Japan. Passengers can embark at Port
                        Said.</p>
                    <p>For all further information apply to the Company's Agents,</p>
                    <p>Messrs. THOS. COOK &amp; SON (Egypt) Ltd. CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>GEORGE ROYLE, Esq. PORT-SAID.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. HABELDEN &amp; Co. ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>F. G. DAVIDSON, Superintendent P. &amp; O. S. N. Company in Egypt SUEZ.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">31-12-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-orm01">
                    <head>Orient-Royal Mail Line.</head>
                    <p>REDUCED SUMMER FARES FROM MAY TO OCTOBER INCLUSIVE.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD to AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p><name>R.M.S. "Oruba"</name> will leave Suez about <date when="1906-10-05"
                            >October 5</date></p>
                    <p><name>R.M.S "Ophir"</name> will leave Suez about <date when="1906-10-19"
                            >October 19</date>.</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD to NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTH, LONDON, TILBURY.</p>
                    <p><name>R.M.S. "Ortona"</name> will leave Port Said <date when="1906-10-23"
                            >October 23</date></p>
                    <p><name>R.M.S. "Oroya"</name> will leave Port Said <date when="1905-10-08"
                            >October 8</date></p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell rows="3">Summer Fares</cell>
                            <cell>Port-Said to Marseilles</cell>
                            <cell>1st Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 9.15.</cell>
                            <cell>2nd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 6.15.</cell>
                            <cell>3rd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 5.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port-Said to Plymouth or Tilbury</cell>
                            <cell>1st Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 14.5.</cell>
                            <cell>2nd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 9. 0.</cell>
                            <cell>3rd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 7.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port-Said to Naples</cell>
                            <cell>1st Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 8. 0.</cell>
                            <cell>2nd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 5.10.</cell>
                            <cell>3rd Class</cell>
                            <cell>£ 4.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Passengers returning by the Line obtain one-third rebate off the above fares
                        if leaving England before the end of October.</p>
                    <p>Agents. Cairo:—Thos. Cook &amp; Son. Alexandria : —R. J. Moss &amp; Co.—For
                        all particulars apply</p>
                    <p>Wm. STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, PORT SAID and PORT-TEWFIK (Suez). 31-12-906</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"><!-- page 2 contents --></div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" status="verified">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Fatal Accident</head>
                        <p>A native labourer was overwhelmed by an avalanche of earth and suffocated
                            at Bab Sharki, Alexandria, yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Connaught House Y.W.C.A.</head>
                        <p>On Thursday February 1, at 5 p.m., a lecture will be given at Connaught
                            House by Mrs. Lewis, LL D., D.D., on one of the earliest manrscripts of
                            the Gospels.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Kaiser's Birthday.</head>
                        <p>The German colonies at Alexandria and Cairo celebrated the anniversary of
                            the Kaiser's birthday with the loyalty and functions usual on this
                            occasion. The Kaiser was born on January 27, 1859. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Bourse.</head>
                        <p>The concessionnaire of the café of the Alexandria Bourse is now paying to
                            the Bourse Company a rent of £400 a year, but we hear that the committee
                            of the company have received an offer of £1,000 per annum for the café.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Tram Accident</head>
                        <p>A native boy, 9 years of age, was run over by a tram at Gabbari yesterday
                            afternoon. A lively scrimmage aftewards ensued, for the youth's friends
                            and relations besieged the tram and belaboured the tram-driver so
                            severely that he will be in the doctor's hands for some days to come.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A New Egyptian Company.</head>
                        <p>It is reported from Brussels, &amp; London contemporary states, that
                            shortly an Egyptian company will be promoted under the name of the Cairo
                            Metropolitan Electric Railway and Heliopolis Oasis Company, for the
                            purpose of working a concession granted to Boghos Pacha and M. Empain.
                            The capital of 15,000,000 f. will be supplied by a syndicate in which
                            Egyptian, English, and to a smaller extent, Belgian capitalists are
                            interested. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>P, W. D. Salaries.</head>
                        <p>There have been a large number of increases of salary among the officials
                            of the Irrigation Service of the Public Works Department. The following
                            are the recipients with the amounts to which their salaries have been
                            raised : Mr. John Langley and Ismail Pacha Sirry, L. E. 1,200 ; Hossein
                            Bey Wassif, L. E. 800 ; Mr. J. W. Waghorn, Abdalla Bey Wahbi, and Mr.
                            Mason, L. E. 600 ; Mr. E. W Buckley. Mr. J. F. Brooke, Mr. A. Morcom,
                            and Mr. R. C. Moser, L. E. 480. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Anglo-Egyptian Automatic Trading Co.</head>
                        <p>Last week, at the Mansion House, before Sir Horatio Davies, Stuart Dixon
                            Stubbs Ross, 38, of 18, Thicket-road, Anerley, and George Bertram Ross,
                            35, of the same address, general merchants, and brothers, were charged,
                            on remand, with combining together to acquire by false pretences moneys
                            and securities of such persons as should become shareholders in the
                            Anglo-Egyptian Automatic Trading Company (Limited), and in pursuance
                            thereof did obtain £525 17s 6d from Mr. J. G. Prentice. Stuart. D. S.
                            Ross was farther charged with obtaining by false pretences the sum of
                            £648 7s. 6d from Mr. John Edward Champneys. Defendants were again
                            remanded on bail, which was immediately forthcoming</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The Countess of Enniskillen left on Thursday to join Lord de Clifford's party
                        up the Nile. They are expected back again at the Savoy on February 8.</p>
                    <p>Lady Delamere left Cairo on Tharsday and is returning to England.</p>
                    <p>Sir Elwin Palmer passed an agitated night. His general condition is not as
                        good as yesterday, and his heart is weaker.</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Albert Blaschke are amongst the latest arrivals at Shepheard's.
                        Mr. Blaschke is a member of the firm of S. Bleichröder, the well-known
                        bankers of Berlin.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Constantine Meimarachi managing director of Walker and Meimarachi,
                        Limited, arrived last night from Cairo and will remain at Alexandria for
                        about three days.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has conferred the grade of Mutamaiz on Halil Bey Kamal, an
                        official in the Ministry of Finance, and the Sanieh on Girgis Bey Antoun, of
                        the Administration of State Railways.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah02">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria.)</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Patronized by the Elite.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day. Visitors fron Cairo alight at Sidi-Gaber Station.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">21440-24-5-905</measure></p>
                    <p>G. AQUILINA, Proprieter.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-eph01">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <p>NOTED FOR ITS EXCELLENT CUISINE.</p>
                    <p>ELECTRIC LIGHT. LIFT.</p>
                    <p>Special terms for officers of the Army of Occupation and Government Officials.
                       </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-whr01">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.</head>
                    <p>Table d'Hote Luncheons &amp; Dinners Served on the Terrace.</p>
                    <p>DELIGHTFUL SITUATION.</p>
                </div>
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OPENING OF THE NILE-RED SEA RAILWAY<lb/>TODAY'S CEREMONY - DETAILED DESCRIPTION<lb/>Interesting Speech by Lord Cromer.</head>
                    <byline>(FROM OUR SPECIAL CORRESPONDENT).</byline>
                    <dateline>Port SUDAN, Friday 11 40 a.m.</dateline>
                    <p>Arrival of the Dakahlieh.</p>
                    <p>The S.S. Dakahlieh arrived at Port Sudan with the official visitors and Press
                        representatives who are to attend the inauguration of the Nile Red Sea
                        Railway at 9.45 a.m. The weather is breezy and the Dakahlieh had a splendid
                        passage all the way. And here I wish to place on record the great
                        hospitality with which all on board were treated by the officials of the
                        Sudan Government and the officers of the Khedival Mail Line. The detachment
                        of the Royal Berkshire Regiment, which had been brought from Khrtoum, is
                        camped on the north side of the channel where H. M. S. Diana is anchored.
                        All the buildings in the town are covered with flags, and it is evident that
                        great preparations have been made for to-morrow's ceremony. The members of
                        the Legislative Council who are guests of the Sudan Government are all in
                        good health and spirits. </p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR SPECIAL CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                    <p>Port Sudan Friday, 3.40 p.m. </p>
                    <p>Viewing the Town,</p>
                    <p>This morning the members of the Legislative Council and the representatives
                        of the Press were taken over H. M. S. Diana. Afterwards the party landed and
                        went round the town in a steam train, visiting among other places the
                        Pulsometer Company's works, which supply water to the town. Though it mainly
                        consists of wooden houses, the town is obviously growing fast, and miles of
                        streets have been marked ont. The Gouvernorat, Quarantine, Customs, and
                        other official buildings are rapidly approaching completion.</p>
                    <p>The 2.45 train came in from Suakin full of natives, including many merchants.
                        A war dance will be given this evening.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer has not yet arrived, the train being late. H.E. the Sirdar and
                        Lady Wingate are already here,</p>
                    <p>The harbonr, though small, looks very good and is thought highly of by the
                        offisers of H.M. S. Diana. </p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR SPECIAL CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                    <p>Port Sudan, Friday, 7 p.m. </p>
                    <p>An Entertainment</p>
                    <p>The members of the Legislative Council and the Press representatives were
                        invited by Kaimakam Kennedy Bey and Bimbashi Kelly to tea in the engineers'
                        mess. H. E. the Sirdar, Lady Wingate, Sir R Slatin Pacha, and many others
                        were present. The great features of the afternoon were a camel race for
                        Hadendowa, which was won by a small boy, and Diluka and other tribal dances
                        performed by scores of Hadendowa blacks and Arabs. A most pleasant afternoon
                        was spent.</p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR SPECIAL CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                    <p>PORT SUDAN, Friday, 11 p.m. </p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer's Arrival,</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer's train steamed in some hours late, drawing up before the special
                        landing place, where a guard of honour consisting of three officers and 100
                        rank and file of the 6th Battalion E.A was drawn up with the Sudanese
                        Infantry band. The Egyptian Artillery fired a salute of 21 guns as Lord
                        Cromer left the train and was immediately greeted by the Governor General of
                        the Sudan. The guard of honour, which looked very smart and workmanlike,
                        presented arms, and the Sudanese band played the British National
                        Anthem.</p>
                    <p>The cause of the delay to the train by which Lord Cromer and party travelled
                        was over-heated bearings. The result was that the inspection of the port,
                        which was to have taken place place this afternoon, had to be postponed
                        until after the inauguration ceremony to-morrow.</p>
                    <p>Harbour Illuminated.</p>
                    <p>The official visitors and Press representatives returned on board the
                        Dakahlieh at nightfall, being accommodated on board for the night. All the
                        veseels in the harbor were illuminated, the display made by H. M. S. Diana
                        being remarkably fine. A display of fireworks also took place on the
                        Dakahlieh, and altogether the day proved most enjoyable and successful. </p>
                    <p>(From OUR SPECIAL CORRESPONDENT).</p>
                    <p>Port Sudan, Saturday, 10 a.m. </p>
                    <p>The Proceedings Begin.</p>
                    <p>At 7 o'clock this morning, Lord Cromer officially opened the Nile Red-Sea
                        Railway. His Lordship left his saloon in the train at 6.55 a.m. and
                        proceeded to the special enclosure, accompanied by Sir Vincent Corbett, Mr.
                        Higgins, and party. The Governor-General with the Captain and Commander of
                        H.M.S. Diana, the Director and Assistant Director of Railways, the Director
                        of Works and Lieut. Kelly, R.E., the Governor of the Red Sea Pronvince and
                        Inspector of Port Sudan, and members of the staff met Lord Cromer at the
                        entrance and conducted him into the enclosure. As Lord Cromer arrived in
                        front of the tents the flags were broken, the guards of honour presented
                        arms, and the band played the Royal and Khedivial Anthems. A salute of 21
                        guns was also fired by H.M.S. Diana on the signal of the flags breaking. The
                        guards of honour shouldered arms on the conclusion of the Khedivial Anthem,
                        and then Lord Cromer inspected the <cb n="3"/> guards of hononr, which were
                        furnished by H.M.S. Diana, the 6th Battalion Egyptian Army, and the Royal
                        Berkshire Regiment. The band in attendance was that of the Sudanese
                        Infantry. The British guards were drawn up on the north side of the special
                        enclosure and the Egyptian guard on the south side. The ground was kept by
                        other parties landed for the purpose from H M.S. Diana. </p>
                    <p>Governor-General's Speech,</p>
                    <p>The inaugaral proceedings began by the Governor General making the following
                        address :</p>
                    <p>My Lord,- It is with great pleasure that, on this auspicions occasion, I
                        welcome your lordship to the Sudan, both on my own behalf and on that of the
                        military and civil officials of the Sudan Government, and of the Ulema,
                        Sheikhs, notables, and people of this country. It is indeed, peculiarly
                        fitting that the opening ceremony of this railway, which connects the Red
                        Sea with the River Nile, should be performed by your lordship, representing
                        as you do, for that purpose, his Majesty King Edward VII. and his Highness
                        Abbas Helmy Pasha II., Khedive of Egypt. Since this country was first
                        reconquered, you have kept steadily in view the absolute necessity, if the
                        Sudan was ever to attain a high degree of prosperity, of establishing
                        communication with the outer world by means more rapid and less costly than
                        those afforded by the Nile. To this end, as we are all aware, you have
                        devoted much thought and many years of patient labour, and I am happy to be
                        able to congratulate you to-day on this visible sign of the success which
                        has attended your efforts. We heartily welcome also the presence of Sir
                        Vincent Corbett, the Financial Adviser to H.H. the Khedive, to whom and to
                        Sir William Garstin we owe so much for the valuable advice and assistance
                        they have always so readily accorded. The Sudan has indead every reason to
                        be grateful for the unfailing support extended to it by the high officials
                        of the Khedive's Government, and I would take this opportunity to tender to
                        his Highness--whose enforced absence from this ceremony is deeply regretted
                        by all--and to his Council of Ministers, my respectful thanks for the grest
                        interest which they have from the outset displayed in the construction of
                        the new line. Again, I desire to extend, on behalf of the Sudan Government,
                        a hearty welcome to those members of the Egyptian Legislative Council who
                        have honoured us with their presence here. We rejoice to see them in the
                        Sudan and they may rest assured that we shall do our utmost to make their
                        stay a pleasant one, and to show them, in the short time at their disposal,
                        the result of our efforts to carry out tbe work of civilisation and
                        progress. It only remains for me to bring to your lordship's notice the very
                        capable manner in which the construction of this new railway has been
                        planned and execated by Lieut-Col. Macauley, assisted by his staff. The
                        manner in which, under his able direction, the British, Egyptian, and
                        Sudanese officers and officials, the men of the Railway Battalion, and the
                        native labourers have performed their duties under very trying climatic
                        conditions, is beyond praise, and the work has been completed in a
                        considerably shorter time than was originally thought possible. I will call
                        upon Colonel Macauley to briefly describe the principal points of interest
                        in connection with the railway construction, and will also ask him to bring
                        offically to your lordship's notice the names of those officers and
                        officials who have rendered him special assistance in his difficult and
                        arduous tark, which names it has already been my pleasant daty to submit to
                        his Highness the Khedive. At the close of Col. Macauley's remarks I shall
                        have the honour to invite your lordship to declare the Red Sea-Nile Railway
                        open to traffic. </p>
                    <p>Macauley Bey's Speech.</p>
                    <p>Macauley Bey then addressed Lord Cromer in the following terms :</p>
                    <p>My Lord, --The new route from Khartoum to the sea by the Nile--Red Sea
                        Railway is 900 miles shorter than the old Nile route. The length of the line
                        from Sal-lom junction to Port Sudan is 21 miles, making a total of 331 miles
                        of main line. There are 25 miles of sidings. The cost of constructing the
                        line was L.E. 1,375 000. This figure includes the cost of bridging and some
                        other work which is not yet finished. The cost works out at L.E. 4,150 per
                        mile of main line. Work on the main line at Suakin began in August, 1904,
                        and railway communication between the Nile and the Red Sea was opened in
                        October, 1905. I am much indebted to Captain Midwinter and his staff for the
                        work done at the Atbara end under diffioult conditions. The line was laid on
                        the telescopic system. Owing to the insufficiency of the local water supply,
                        it has been necessary to obtain all water for working parties and most of
                        the water for bridges, buildings, and locomotives, by distilling sea water;
                        all water had to be carried up the line in special tank wagons. While a
                        temporary quay and some workshops, offices, etc., were being prepared at
                        Suakin, an experiment was made with some of the Arab tribes near Suakin to
                        see if they would do the earthwork for the line. They showed little
                        predilection for regular work however, and although a second attempt was
                        made when the actual construction of the main line began it was found
                        difficult to get them to do much earthwork. Men were accord<cb n="4"/>ingly
                        brought over from the Nile valley, and the men have worked very well. They
                        have been on piece-work. I desire to mention that I received very valuable
                        advice from Mr. Bakewell, C.E., regarding the general course and
                        construction of the line, and especially in the matter of bridging. I wish
                        to express my thanks to all the staff for the hard work they have done
                        during the construction of the line and I would specially mention : in
                        connection with the control of the Port at Suakin, Lieut. W. B. Dewry, Royal
                        Navy; in connection with the construction of the railway, El Miralai Mahmoud
                        Bey Kheirallah, Capt. W. E. Longfield, R.E.; Capt. M. E. Sowerby, R.E.,
                        Lieat. S. F. Newcombe, R. E., Lieut. P. C. Lord, R.E., Mr. C. E. Hickley,
                        the Hon. A. Pelham, Mr. R. W. Windham, El Saghkolaghasi Ali Eff. Shanki,
                        Sagh. Hussein Eff. Yasri, Yuzbashi Hassanein Eff. Rifat, and Yozbashi
                        Mohamed Eff. Ali. The following have also done excellent work in connection
                        with this railway but as they are, if anything, more closely identified with
                        the new railway from Abou Hamed to Kareima their names will again be brought
                        before his Excellency the Governor-General on the occasion of the opening of
                        that line : Capt. F. C. Midwinter, D.S.O, Royal Engineers; Mr. C. Hodgson,
                        Mr. G. B. Macpherson Grant, Mr. H. V. Hawkins, El Saghkolaghasi Mohamed Eff.
                        Fadil, and Ibrahim Eff. Es Sayyid. In conclusion, I beg to thank your
                        lordship, Sir Reginald Wingate, Sir William Garstin, and Sir Vincent Corbett
                        for all the help, kindness, and consideration which has been accorded to me
                        during the execution of the work.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer's Speech. </p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer made the following speech in reply :</p>
                    <p>Sir Reginald Wingate and Gentlemen, The first observation which I have to
                        make is, to express my great regret, - which I am sure is shared by all
                        present, - that his Highness the Khedive was unable to attend in order to
                        preside at the ceremony of to-day. I wish alsó to preface my remarks by one
                        further observation of personal character. The honours of to-day, Gentlemen,
                        belong to Colonel Macauley, and his very capable and efficient staff,
                        amongst whom I may especially mention the names of Captain Midwinter and
                        Capt. Longfield, of the Royal Engineers, as also Kaimakam Mehmoud Bey
                        Kheirallah. To have constructed 325 miles of railway in 14 months, under
                        such climatic conditions as those which obtain in the Sudan, is a very
                        remarkable achievement. I wish to take this opportunity, on behalf of the
                        British and of the Egyptian Governments, of expressing my very high
                        appreciation of the zeal and intelligence which have been shown in the
                        execution of this important work. I may add that the cost has been very
                        moderate. It has amounted to not more than L.E. 1,400,000. I now turn to the
                        more public aspects of the railway. Without doubt, of late years a great
                        deal has been done in the Sudan. Order and tranquillity everywhere prevail.
                        A fiscal system has been introduced which is adapted to the needs and
                        requirements of the country. Schools and law courts have been established.
                        It is, however, none the less true to say that the serious development of
                        the Sudan commences from today. So long as the country was separated from
                        the rest of the world by a waste of burning desert, and so long as
                        communication could only be kept up by a line of railway and river steamers
                        over a distance of 1,200 miles--for that is the distance from the mouth of
                        the Atbara to Alexandria--any very rapid progress was out of the question.
                        Colonel Macauley, in the note which we have just heard read, has explained
                        that the distance from Berber to the sea will now be shortened by nearly 900
                        mile. Fears have been occasionally expressed that the opening of this
                        railway might do harm to Egypt, and it has therefore been urged that the
                        resources of Egypt should not be employed in its construction. I am glad to
                        observe that these complaints are gradually dying out. It cannot be too
                        clearly understood that the construction of this railway will not divert any
                        existing trade to any considerable extent. It will create a trade, which,
                        unless the railway were made, could never exist. For the rest, I may observe
                        that the presence here to-day of several of the most distinguished members
                        of the Egyptian Legislative Council is in itself a sufficient proof that the
                        authorized representatives of the Egyptian people do not share the fears to
                        which I have alluded. My own opinion on this subject has always been very
                        clear, and has been frequently expressed. In the first place, I always
                        regard with a certain amount of suspicion any argument based upon the
                        necessity of keeping one locality--or perhaps in this case I should say a
                        whole continent--in a backward condition, in order that some other locality
                        should prosper. In the second place, more especially since the appearance of
                        Sir W. Garstin's epoch-making report, it has been demonstrated with
                        mathematical precision that the material prosperity of Egypt is intimately
                        bound up with that of the Sudan. It is the river Nile which connects them;
                        and it is certain that any large works undertaken in the future to benefit
                        Egypt must be constructed, not in Egypt proper, but in the upper regions of
                        the Nile Valley. This railway is, therefore, the first and preliminary step
                        in the gradual execution of a large scheme for the construction of works of
                        public utility. It is <cb n="5"/>the main artery of communication which will
                        open out the Sudan to the world. But before the country can gain the fall
                        advantages to be derived from this undertaking, further works must be
                        constructed. Some, indeed, have already commenced. The port at which I am
                        now speaking is springing into existence. Before many months have elapsed, I
                        hope that the railway from Kareima to Abu Hamed will be opened and will thus
                        put the wealthy province of Dongola in direct communication with the sea.
                        Irrigation works are about to be undertaken to utilise the waters of the
                        Gash, and thus fertilize the plains in the neighbourhood of Kassala, Borings
                        are about to be made with a view to the constructioa of a bridge over both
                        the Blue and White Niles at Khartoum. Railway surveys are being undertaken
                        with the ultimate object of bringing Kassala into communication with the
                        main line, of extending the railway up the left bank of the Blue Nile, and
                        of enabling the gum of Kordofan to fiad a ready market by bringing El Obeid
                        into direct communication with Omdurman. It is not to be supposed that all
                        these works will be at once remunerative. Undertakings of this sort, cannot
                        possibly pay in the first few years of their existence ; but that they will
                        ultimately prove remunerative I have not the smallest doubt. I can,
                        therefore, confidently recommend the taxpayers of Egypt to "Trust on, and
                        think to-morrow will repay." I need hardly say that the measures to which I
                        have alluded and which only form the preliminary steps to the execution of
                        Sir William Garstin's vast programme, will take years to accomplish. At my
                        time of life, I can only hope to stand on the top of an administrative Mount
                        Pisgah. I can scarcely hope to enter the promised land. I wish, however,
                        gentlemen, very strongly to impress upon you that the execution of this
                        programme--and I may add, both the general and local policy of the British
                        Government in Egypt and the Sudan--does not in the least depend upon the
                        individuals who have to carry it out. It will be found, I am well convinced,
                        wholly independent of ministerial changes in England, and of changes in the
                        executive on the spot. If I were to leave Bgypt—which I have not the least
                        intention of doing, so long as my health and strength endor--or if Sir
                        Reginald Wingate were to leave the Sudan--and I trust a very long time will
                        elapse before he does so--all that need be said would be, "Il n'y a qu'un
                        Anglais de moins." In conformity, not only with the Anglo-Eyptian Convention
                        of 1899, but also with the liberal policy persistently pursued by the
                        British Government in these matters, this port and railway will be open on
                        equal terms to the trade of all the world. There will be no differential
                        rates or duties to favour the trade of any one nation. But, gentlemen, it
                        has to be remembered, that though I do not doubt that, the opening up of the
                        Soudan will bring with it many of the blessings of civilization, there is an
                        inevitable risk that it will bring in its train some of the incidents which
                        appear to be the accompaniment, and are certainly the shame, of the
                        civilisation of the West. The railway will carry the legitimate trader, the
                        tourist, the scientist, and the philanthropist. It will also, possibly,
                        convey to the Soudan the drinkseller, the usurer, and the commercial
                        adventurer. I may say at once that I do not believe that any heroic or
                        arbitrary measures are at all desirable in order to keep this latter class
                        of society out of the country. But they may be combated by other means.
                        Sound agricultural banks may compete with the usurer. Wise legislation may
                        put some check on the excessive sale of drink. Care and judgment in the
                        disposal of Government lands may do a great deal to nullify any harm done by
                        the mere company-monger. I do not doubt that all these subjects will receive
                        the full attention of Sir Reginald Wingate, of whose past services to the
                        Sudan I cannot speak in terms of too high praise. There is yet one further
                        point to which I wish to allude. The transfer of the terminus of the railway
                        from Suakin to Port Sudan has, I am aware, been a disappointment to the
                        inhabitants of the former place. That their interests demand consideration
                        at the hands of the Government, I fully admit. Residents in Suakin will
                        therefore receive favourable treatment in the allotment of the lands for the
                        new town of Port Sudan, except, of course, those who have merely bought land
                        for speculative purposes. I cannot hold out any hope that this latter class
                        will be esceptionally treated. If they gamble in land, they must expect
                        occasionally to lose. Under the authority which I have received from his
                        Majesty King Edward VII. and his Highness the Khedive, I now declare the
                        railway from Port Sudan to Berber open.</p>
                    <p>Lord Cromer's speeeh was afterwards read out in Arabic by Shahin Bey Ghirgis
                        (Arabic Secretary) Sir Rudolph von Slatin Pacha then shortly explained in
                        simple vernacular to the assembled merchants, and to the omdehs and sheikhs
                        and people of nomad Arabs present, the effect the new railway will have in
                        improving their trade and local conditions, after which Lord Cromer formally
                        opened the line, the guards of honour presenting arms, and the band playing
                        the Royal and Khedivial Anthems.</p>
                    <p>Then followeł an eloquent speech by Charrarbi Pacha in Arabic. Your
                        correspondent is no judge of Arabic rhetoric, but qualified listeners spoke
                        most highly of the Pacha's speech.</p>
                    <p>The speeches over, the Governor-General presented to Lord Cromer the members
                        of the railway staff engaged in the construction of the new line</p>
                    <p>The proceedings then terminated. The guard of honour saluted as Lord Cromer
                        left the enclosure. The British and Egyptian flags were lowered, and on this
                        signal being given H. M. S. Diada fired a salute of 31 guns.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="specialCables">
                    <head>OUR SPECIAL CABLES.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ELECTIONS. DEFEAT OF MR. CROOKSHANK.</head>
                        <byline>(Gazette's Special Service.)</byline>
                        <dateline>London, Saturday, Jan. 27. </dateline>
                        <p>To-day's Liberal gains number seven, the Unionists' one. The Government
                            undergoes no change in ten constituencies and the Unionists in four. Mr.
                            Crookshank, brother of Crookshank Pacha, has been defeated by 262
                            votes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW APPEAL JUDGE.</head>
                        <byline>(Gazette's Special Service.)</byline>
                        <dateline>London, Saturday, Jan. 27. </dateline>
                        <p>Mr. J. Fletcher Moulton, K.C, F.R.S. the great anthority on patent law
                            and a well-known Liberal barrister, has been appointed a Lord Justice of
                            the Court of Appeal.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GRESHAM LIFE ASSURANCE CO. IMPORTANT JUDGMENT.</head>
                    <p>This morning the Mixed Court of 1st Instance at Cairo pronounced judgment in
                        the case brought by Mr. Otto Schmidt, late general agent of the Gresham Life
                        Assurance Society, Limited, at Alexandria, against that Society for rupture
                        of contract. The Court ordered the Gresham to pay an indemnity of LE. 1.000
                        plus commissions on business of which no account had been rendered by the
                        Society.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXTENSION OF PENNY POSTAGE</head>
                    <p>With effect from the 1st February next, the postage on letters for Malta and
                        Cyprus will be reduced and fixed at 5 milliomes for every 15 grammes or
                        fraction thereof.</p>
                    <p>Up to the present penny postage has been adopted with the United Kingdom, New
                        Zealand, British India (including Aden), the Straits Settlements, Malta, and
                        Cyprus.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONSULAR APPOINTMENTS.</head>
                    <p>Mr. George Pollard Davey, at present the British Consal at Jeddah, has been
                        appointed to be his Majesty's Consul at Damascus.</p>
                    <p>Mr. John Francis Jones has been appointed to be his Majesty's Consul for the
                        Eastern Coast of the Red Ses, to reside at Jeddah.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive is leaving Montazah for Cairo this evening.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DELTA CANALS.</head>
                    <p>In superression of the notice previously issued on the subject navigation
                        companies, and others interested, are invited to note that in the rules for
                        the regulation of navigation now being drawn up by the Public Works
                        Department, it is proposed to fix the limiting dimensions of craft plying on
                        the navigable canals in the Delta, as regards thair maximum length, maximum
                        beam, maximum draft, respectively: steam or motor barges, 35.00,6.8, 2.0 ;
                        cargo barges, 25.00, 6.0, 2.0; tugs, 20.00, 4.0, 2.0; country boats, 92.00,
                        6.0, 2.0.</p>
                    <p>The dimensions have been modified as above in order to meet the wishes of the
                        owners of barges so far as may be possible.</p>
                    <p>It is only the main canals such as :- the Rayah Menufia, the Bagouris, the
                        Mahmudia, the Rayah Tewfiki and the Mansuira, which are capable of passing
                        craft of the above dimensions.</p>
                    <p>Many of the locks on the other navigable canals are too small to accommodate
                        craft of this size, and, during summer, the depth of water in the tail
                        reaches, often falls much below 1 metres.</p>
                    <p>Even in the main canals a depth of 2.0 metres can by no means always be
                        depended on, and during seasons of low supply owners will run the risk of
                        grounding barges or boats if they lead them so as to make their draft reach
                        or nearly reach the limiting value of 2.0 metres.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="theatre">
                    <head>THEATRE ALHAMBRA</head>
                    <p>Dans la soirée donnée hier à l'Alhambra au bénéfice de Mlle Chantenay, cette
                        excellente artiste a obtenu un grand succès dans le rôle d'Irma da "Grand
                        Mogol." Elle y a été éblouissante de grâce et d'entrain. On pourrait en dire
                        autant de la princesse Bengaline, Mlle Nolba, qui a été surtout remarquée
                        dans la scène de la séduction. M. La Bany a été fort admiré dans le rôle de
                        Mignapour, ainsi que M. Crépy dans celui de Joquelet. La note comique était
                        donnée par MM. de la Freydière et Simon, le premier en Nicobar et le second
                        en Crakson.</p>
                    <p>Demain, à 4 h. p.m. 'La Fille de Mme Angot"; le soir "Le Grand Mogol."</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bsl01">
                    <head>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                    <p>236 BRANCHES.</p>
                    <p>French, German, Italian, Greek, Arabic, etc.</p>
                    <p>Private Lessons, Residence Lessons, taught by Native Masters </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 26 Rue Rosette (close to Zizinia Theatre.)</p>
                    <p>CAIRO : 1 Sharia Kamel. </p>
                    <p>TRIAL LESSONS FREE</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert"  xml:id="deg-ad-bcp02">
                    <head>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSENER BEER</head>
                    <p>BREMEN.</p>
                    <p>FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY.</p>
                    <p>N.B. -- Inferior Brands now being offered to Managers of certain good circles.</p>
                    <p>Beware of evilly disposed competitors running down this very Superior Brand of
                        Beer</p>
                    <p>SUPERIOR BRAND OF BEER.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"/>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"/>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                
                
                <div type="item" xml:id="deg-el-etcl01">
                    <head>EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO. LTD.</head>
                    <p>AVERAGE TIME occupied in transmission of Egyptian telegrams from England to
                        Alexandria on <date when="1906-01-26">Friday, 26th Jan., 1906</date>. </p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS.</p>
                    <p>Between the hours of 10 a.m. and 6 p.m. (Cairo time)</p>
                    <table rows="6" cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-etcl01">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell rows="2">FROM</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">MESSAGES HANDED IN AT</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>The Company's Offices. H. M.</cell>
                            <cell>Postal Telegraph Offices. H. M.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>London</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">17</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">32</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Liverpool</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">15</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">26</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Manchester</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">28</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Glasgow</placeName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">27</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Other Provincial Offices</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="min">35</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <div type="item" xml:id="deg-el-stsh01">
                <head>STOCKS AND SHARES</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="italic">Closing Prices, to-day at 1 p.m.</hi>
                </p>
                <table cols="4" xml:id="deg-ta-stsh01">
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell>Shares</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">
                            <hi rend="bold">BANKS.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>Debenture</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure type="currency" unit="£">26 5/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>National Bank of Egypt</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure type="currency" unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure type="currency" unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                            <cell>.. .. New</cell>
                            <cell><measure type="currency" unit="£">26 5/16</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">426 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell><orgName>National Bank of Greece</orgName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">815 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell><orgName>Credit Foncier Egyptian</orgName> Lottery Bonds</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="fcs">317</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lst.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="£">13 13/16</measure></cell>
                            <cell><orgName>Agricultural Bank</orgName></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="£">9 3/8</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>L.E.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="LE">— 1/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Banque Industrielle</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="LE">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">122 ½</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Bank of Athens</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">9 5/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Land Bank of Egypt</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">90</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell cols="4">
                            <hi rend="bold">LAND, &amp;c.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">1000 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Agric.-Indust. Egypt</orgName>...</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">520</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell>Fond.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">1050</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>L.E.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="LE">43 ¼</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Behera Company</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="LE">5 1/8</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">2 7/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Egypt. Delta Land Co.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">6 3/8</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Wardan Estate Coy.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">5</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">4 7/8</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Land &amp; Mortgage.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">28 1/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>New Daira Sanieh Fond.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">180</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Corporation of Western Egypt</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">15/16</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">34/ —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>New Egyptian Co.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell><orgName>Egypt. Estates Ltd.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">7/8</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell cols="4">
                            <hi rend="bold">COMMERCIAL INDUSTRIAL</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">30 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Alexand. Bonded Stores Pref.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">— 23/32</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Anglo-Egypt. Spinning Co.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">23 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Bourse Khédiviale</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">75 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell>pref. <orgName>Cairo Sewage Transport</orgName> Ord.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">60</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">200 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell>ex <orgName>Cr. Brewery Alex.</orgName> Fond.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">100</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">—</measure></cell>
                        <cell>do do 6 % Debs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">500</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">110</measure> —</cell>
                        <cell>do Cairo Fond.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">61</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Sh.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">5/3 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Egypt. Cotton Mills</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">22/9 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell>do Markets</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">100</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">34/9 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell>do Salt and Soda Fond.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="sh">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">70 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Ciments d'Egypte</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">15</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Egypt. Trust &amp; Invest.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">1 7/16</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">7 ¼</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Kafr-el-Zayat Cot. Coy.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">102 ½</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">9 7/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Nungovich Hotels</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">103 ¾</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">37 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Soc. Pressage et Dépôts</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">102</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">25 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Société Presses Libres</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">102</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell cols="4">
                            <hi rend="bold">NAVIGATION &amp; WATER WORKS.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">5 7/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell>ex <orgName>Anglo - American Nile &amp;c. Co.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">4 3/16</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Khedivial Mail S.S. &amp;c. Co.</orgName> Fonds.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">16/3</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">15</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Alex. Water Company</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">1115</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Cairo Water Coy. Fonds.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">1040</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">22 ½</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Tantah Water Co. Fonds.</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row role="label">
                        <cell cols="4">
                            <hi rend="bold">RAILWAYS &amp; TRAMWAYS.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">12 7/8</measure></cell>
                        <cell>ex <orgName>Delta Light</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">100</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Delta Light</orgName> Def</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">14</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">9 —</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Fayoum</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>"</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">26 ¾</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Keneh-Assouan</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fcs.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">165 ¼</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Alexandria Trams</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">480</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">—</measure></cell>
                        <cell>do " Fonds.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="fcs">340</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lst.</cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">7 1/8</measure></cell>
                        <cell><orgName>Ramleh Railway</orgName></cell>
                        <cell><measure unit="£">—</measure></cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <p>Furnished by <orgName>Reid &amp; Bernard</orgName> <placeName>10, St. Marks Buildings, Alexandria</placeName>, and <placeName>Sharia
                    Kasr-el-Nil, Cairo</placeName>, who undertake the sale and purchase of Stocks and Shares, on
                    the local Bourse and also on the <orgName>London Stock Exchange</orgName>.</p>
            </div>
                
            </div>
            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-01-27/page/n6/mode/1up" status="empty">
                
            </div>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8" 
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-01-27/page/n7/mode/1up" status="empty">
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
