<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Max Conway</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">10-10-15</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-06-29</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><head>THB EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, JUNE 29, 1905.</head>
<div type=“item”>
<head>MUTINY ON RUSSIAN</head>
<head>BATTLESHIP.</head>
<head>OFFICERS MURDERED.</head>
<head>EXCITEMENT IN ODESSA.</head>
<head>COILLISIONS WITH TROOPS.</head>
    <dateline>London, June 28.</dateline>
<p>Lloyd's reports from Odessa that all work in
the port is stopped. The crew of a battleship
in tho roads has mutinied and murdered the
officers It is reported that they threatened to
bombard the town.
(Later). The battleship was the "Knyaz
Potemkin Tavritcheski." The mutiny was due
to the commander having caused a sailor to be
shot for presenting a petition of the crew for
Better food. The crew thereupon attacked the
officers, and it is reported that they murdered
several. In the morning the sailors bore their
comrade's body ashore, where a bareheaded
crowd of strikers and others viewed the corpse,
amidst general interest and excitement The
police and Cossacks attempted to disperse the
crowd, which resisted, and some fighting en-
sued. The affair has greatly aggravated the
situation caused by the strike. Frequent colli-
sions are taking place between the strikers and
the troops. A workman threw a bomb at a
policeman, and both were killed by the
explosion.	(Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>
    <dateline>Odessa, June 28.</dateline>
<p>The crew of the battleship ' Potemkin" have
massacred their officers in order to avenge a
sailor who was killed by an officer owing to
his having complained about tho poor food.
(Havas.)</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
<p>The Plague—Yesterday's bulletin records
two new cases and two deaths in hospital at
Damanhour.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Cotton Pulling. —Thieves have destroyed
a cotton field belonging to the omdeh of
Nabtib, Belbeis markaz.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
Abdeen district of Cairo daring Saturday night
and at daylight on Sunday will be poisoned by
the police</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Rotations —The rotation programme now
in force in the 2nd Circle of Irrigation will be
extended up to July 24, when a modification
will probably be mode.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Suez Canal — a vessels passed through the
Canal on the 26th ii.st . of which 4 wore
British, 3 German, 2 French The receipts for
the day were frs. 265.411.13, making the total
from the 1st inst. frs. 7,230,769.75.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>LOWER STANDARD NOTED.</head>
<head>ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST.</head>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Fatal Accident.—A cigarette maker nam-
ed Ali B1 Said, while getting off a moving
train at Saida Zenab, caught his foot in the
wheel and had both legs drawn under and
crushed. The unfortunate man succumbed to
his injuries at the hospital.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>San Stefano Casino.—We are informed
that the Wagnerian concert at the Casino
next Sunday will commence at 10.30 a.m.
precisely. As it is likely to prove the most
enjoyable concert of the season, there is sure
to be a large attendance. The orchestra of
60 musicians will be conducted by Maestro
Bracale.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</head>
<head>HOPEFUL OUTLOOK.</head>
    <dateline>Paris, June 28.</dateline>
<p>Tb«- general feeling here is that the sting
has been taken out of the question of Morocco
by tho conciliatory tone of the German reply,
which, while pointing out that, as Morocco
and not Germany proposed the Conference, the
latter cannot limit the questions to be discuss-
ed at it, yet displays a disposition to utilize
the Moroccan dummy later on for the purpose
of meeting the views of France. (Reuter.)</p>
<div type=“item”>
    <dateline>Paris, June 28.</dateline>
<p>In consequence of exchanges of views eo
tween M Rouvier and Prince Radolin on the
Moroccan question is expected that a solu
tion will shortly be arrived at safeguarding
all interests	(Havas.)</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Victoria College.— We understand that
at the opening of the sealed tenders for the
purchase of the college site and buildings, in
accordance with the conditions announced in
our columns recently, no offer made was con-
sidered acceptable by the committee. The sale
will probably be adjourned to some future date
as there is no immediate necessity for carrying
it through.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Sexagenarian AttemptsScuicide.—A Greek,
named Costi Kerio, who is 60 years of age,
attempted to commit suicide yesterday by
throwing himself in front of a tram car between
Bacos and Seffer stations. It was impossible
to stop the car in time and the man s arms
and legs were crushed under tbe wheels, while
be sustained severe injuries in the head. He
now lies in the Greek Hospital in a precarious
condition. Papers found on the man showed
that be had contemplated taking his own life.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Prizes Given in Cairo. — M Buusquet,
French consul at Cairo, presided yesterday
over the prize-giving at the Jeanne d'Aro
School, Fagalla. The function was very pictur-
esque, the building and garden having been
tastefully decorated with French (lags, also the
stage, where some of the elder pupils gave an
excellent rendering of several scenes from
Moliere's /. .1 care. M. Bousquet paid a well
deserved compliment to Mile. Thibaud, the
head mistress of the College, in praising the
excellent French pronunciation of the pupils,
the majority of "horn are not of French origin.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>“Modern Society" says The Earl and
Countess of Londesborough gave a concert last
week in honour of the Khedive of Egypt at
Alington House, the fine mansion in South
Audley-street which was the scene of much
stately hospitality in the lifetime of the late
Lord Alington. The noble ballroom and spa
nous staircase and corridors make the house
an ideal one for entertaining on a large scale.
Lord and Lady Londesborough are personal
friends of His Egyptian Highness, as they spent
nearly the whole of the last winter in Cairo,
and saw a good deal of Abbas Pasha, who is
always on good terms with distinguished
English visitors to Egypt.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Sir William Garstin will leave Alexandria
for Cairo on Saturday next</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Mr A. Mitchell Innes returned to Cairo
yesterday from England.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>M. de la Boulinire, who will preside over
the prize-giving at the College des Freres,
Mousky, at 4.30 p.m. today, leaves Cairo
for Alexandria at 9.30 a.m. tomorrow to
embark for Europe.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>CAIRO MILITARY SCHOOL</head>
<head>LOWER STANDARD NOTED</head>
<p>In our issue of yesterday we gave a short
account of the prize distribution by El Miralai
Matchett Boy to the cadets of the Military
School, Abbassieh, and we now give farther
details with a list of prizes and the names of
those who have been granted commissions.
Mr. Brian, senior master, read his report on
tho year s work in which he remarks that he
considers the present standard of tire school
to be distinctly below the average, and that
neither could ho consider the results of the
recent examination to be altogether satisfac-
tory The fault however, does not lie with
either the instructors of the school or the
pupils themselves, but is due, Mr. Brian point-
ed out, to the contiuoed demand for officers,
which compelled them to commission men who
had only gone through a two-years' course of
instruction, whereas they should spend three
or even four years at the school before they
could be considered to be really ready tor a
commission. Out of the 84 cadets at present
on the school's lists only 24 had been present
at last June’s examination, and all of these,
with only one exception, were in the 3rd and
4th classes It was from these 24 that it had
been found necessary  to form the N.C.O.'s class
in January la»i Out of the 32 cadets of the
first class 24 had only joined last October, and
the remaining 8 of these had joined less than
six months ago.
Mr. Plunkett, in presenting his report on
the outdoor work it the school (football,
athletic sports, eta), remarked that he consi-
dered that the work done in this department
towards the physical training of the cadets
was fairly satisfactory, hut less time had been
devoted to it, so that here, too, a certain
falling-off was unavoidable. He suggested
that in future years the athletic sports
should be held in April as they had been this
year, as he considered it preferable to holding
them in March, as had been done in previous
years.
El Miralai Matchett Bey, Commandant,
after distributing the prizes to the successful
candidates, gave a short address to the cadets.
He greatly regretted the absence of their Ex-
cellencies the Minister of War and the Sirdar,
but the time of year at which the distribution
took place rendered their attendance impossible.
He was p.ui-ed to be able to express himself
as satisfied with the work which had been
done by them and with the general tone of
the school, and he was also glad to learn from
the report of the chief medical officer that
the health of the cadets was good. He agreed
with Mr. Brian that the standard of the school
was below that of former years, and said that
it was his intention to remark in his confiden-
tial reports on those who were to receive com-
missions that he considered that in some cases
they were hardly qualified to fulfil the duties
of officers owing to an insufficient period of
time having been devoted to their training.
He trusted, however, that the continual de-
mand upon tho school for officers would soon
cease and that they would then be able to
reattain their previous high standard, as the
cadets would thus be enabled to spend a mini-
mum period of three years in the school, which
was necessary for the sound and thorough
training in tho various branches of work with
which an officer must be acquainted.
It was then announced that H.H. the Khe-
dive had been most graciously pleased to
confer commissions on the following :—Moha-
n,ed Harden, Cavalry. Ahmed Atieh, Artillery;
Ahmed Fahmi Ouni, Artillery , Mohamed
H unmet, 7th Battalion , Hasaan Mohamed,
8th Battalion . Hassan Suliman, 7th Battalion;
Mohamed Onsi, 5th Battalion , Hassan Mah
moud, 1st Battalion , Hussein ol Maghraby,
3rd Battalion , Said Mustapha, 9 th Battalion.
The following is the list of those gaining
prizes Hoad of school (binoculars), Basil
Shawisb Mohd. Harden , 1st in 1st class
(Gladstone bag), Cadet Sabr el Tantawi , 1st
in 2nd class (atlas), Cadet Mohamed Awad ;
1st in 3rd class (dictionary), Cadet Moh. Abd
ol Nebi , 1st in 4th class (English dictionary',
Cadet Ahmed Moh. Mustafa , Military Exer-
cises (binoculars), Shawuh Ahmed Atieh ;
Mathematics (watch), Cadet Ahmed Said; Topo-
graphy (compass), Shawish Ahmed Fahmi ;
Fortification (watch), Cadet Sabr el Tautawi ,
Arabic (writing oase), Cadet Aziz Fahmi ;
English, 1st (watch). Cadet Kamel Lutfi ;
English, 2nd (atlas), Cadet Ahmed Moh. Mus
taia ; Geography (gazeteer), Bash Shawish
Moh. Harden ; R'ding (oandlestick), Bash
Shawish Moh. Harden . Gymnastics (cigarette
case), Cadet Moh. Ziki Fathi.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>GERMANY AND TURKEY</head<
<head>VERSUS</head>
<head>ENGLAND IN THE NEAR EAST</head>
<head>BY W.M.</head>
<head>THE DANGER.</head>
<p>The political shortsightedness that seems to
afflict the English people—which bears a repu-
tation second to none for a clear and precise
comprehension of the practicable—at certain
moments in its career, and notably, when
confronted with that critical phase in its
history, the outlines of which we propose to
trace, is one of the most remarkable pheno-
mena of contemporary history. Springing from
the union of carelessness and inattentiveness,
and from a combination of morbid causes and 1
effects, this political myopia grows more and
more serious. What oan be stranger or more
meloncholy than the torpor into which “watch- 
ful" Britain appears to be sinking when faced
by the danger that menaces her from every .
quarter of the horizon, a danger ubiquitous
and manifold, that may sot aim at the heart
of the empire which is guarded by the seas
but none the lees threatens to lop its members
in Africa end Asia and to sever its arteries 1
Germany prepares for the Titanic struggle of 
Empires that draws rapidly nearer, and with 
a science and sagacity only equalled by her
foresight, testa and examines every point in ,
the world wide armour of the British Empire; .
and like Prussia before Sedan or Japan before
Mukden she calculates and prepares die 
decisive blow. Meantime England, who recog-
nises the imminence of the stroke as thoroughly '
as her rival, concentratas her attention on
her rival and nothing else and falls asleep 
again as thoroughly satisfied that her head 
is safe as the proverbial ostrich, and as 1
careless of the rest The British refuse to !
recognise that they are still exposed, that
there are one or two points where an !
suomy’s blow will one day fall, points where
the essential parts of the Empire may
be separated from its brain-centre and the
whole body brought to ruin by their separa-
tion. They will learn too late that their terri-
ble armada will be of little value in the day 
of battle against the foresight and calculation 
of her opponent, whose armed forces will, that '
day, move unhindered against the British 1
Empire—on land.
It is strange and almost stupefying to note,
the one-sidedness and superficiality of the poli
tixal apperception of this people of sailors who
seem incapable of realising that Germany, the
00	on try of thinkers and calculators par excel
Lence, is doing her best to bring her continental
strength to bear on her foe should England
check the complete development of her strength '
on blue water. It is obvious that in case of
war she would keep her fleet in Kiel harbour
or up the channels, which no longer fear the
menace of the White Ensign based on Heligo-
land—the "Nasenklemmer” of the Elbe—and
would sow every channel, every strait and sea-
pass from Wilhelmshaven to the Belt and from
the Belt to the Konigsberg with the submarine
mines—sleeping but vigilant—to whose terrible
power the Russo-Japanese war bears witness,
while her torpedo flotillas and submarines
would emerge from the Jahde and the Bins,
from all the havens and creeks of the North
Sea and the Baltic, to harass the hostile fleets.
But can one even speak of coast attack by
fleets pitted alone against forts and mines after
the lessons taught by the Eastern war and the
Port Arthur campaign ! What fleet, ware it
four times as strong as the combined squadrons
of Britain, would dare assail unsupported the
coasts of the North Sea or the entrance to the
Baltic defended by all the organised might of
German genius It
The German Fleet once secures in its inacces
sible havens, what part is the British Navy to
play I It must confine itself to the observation
of the German coast and to attacks on German
commerce,—a species of warfare that is unlikely
to be attended by much glory or profit. Its
results would be practically nil. The German
merchant fleet would lie quietly immobilised in
home or neutral ports while Gorman commerce
would still be carried on under over of a
transfer to a neutral flag on every ocean. And
while England waits unable to grapple with
her elusive foe the main strength of Germany,
her continental strength, will come into play
perhaps without the employment it a single
Pomeranian Grenadier, against the crack in
Britain's armour whicb it will pierce like a
wedge.
It is with this end in view that Germany
has concluded tacit agreements and has—so to
say—added new members to her Empire to
which she is communicating her stark efficiency.
At the given moment she will have but to im-
press the given movement on these new wheels
of her military machine and they will tarn
irresistibly to fulfil her imperial designs.
It is the erstwhile "Sick Man” of Europe
rescued in his many death agonies by Eng
land’s active intervention, who trill be the prin-
cipal weapon, the steel wedge driven home by
German hands into the gaps of England's
weakened armour. Slowly, insidiously and
steadily Wilhelm II. has slipped through the
doors of the sublime Porte left open by his
rival enthusiastically bound for the Talley it
the Nile. Bash English step in retreat was
balanced by a German stop in advance, while
the Kaiser's policy was marked throughout by
consummate ingenuity and amazing discretion
and tact.
When England after Omdurman, showed her-
self vanquished by the attractions of the Dark
Continent, the last trace of Turkish sympathy
or confidence in her policy disappeared while
England, logically pursuing her policy of
expansion in African and in Mussulman —
territories did not hesitate to meet the surly
resentment of the 'Turk with defiance on the
Aden frontier and in the Arabian wastes.
: Then it was that Wilhemll. went in person
seal his pact with the shades of Ertoghrahl and
Saladin. For eight years his diplomatists had
prepared the completion and his officers had
ensured the utility of the treaty. Deaf to the
appeals of humanity horror-stricken by heca-
tombs of slaughtered Armenians, blind to the
stain on tho escutcheon of the German Empire,
he had eyes only for tho end of his polioy, the
creation of an Oamanli army that could serve
his ambition. Already imperfectly reorganised
by the great Moltke, the Turkish military
organisation had gone to rest again, and had
become an antiquated machine jarring and
creaking with every movement
But Moltke's work was taken in hand ones
more, this time with greater rigour, science,
and continuity, and above all with greater
freedom, greater secrecy, and a fuller apprecia-
tion of the military material of the Ottoman
Empire. Sober, teachable, sturdy, healthy,
fanatical with the desperation of those who
have all to lose, the Turkish troops possess
•very factor of brute force and only need the
coefficients of scientific leadership and organi-
sation to fulfil all the conditions imposed by
modern war. In the few years in which
Germany has applied herself to satisfy this
head all has bean renewed and reforged : the
military law, the general staff, commissariat,
communications, armament, fortifications, all
have been remodelled by Germans after the
German methods. In the midst of an unpro-
gressive Empire towers one great monument
of Progress—a new Tarldsh Army—and a part
of Germany’s armed strength.
Under the old organisation—or want of
organisation—what was most utterly lacking
and most urgently demanded by the military
reformer was a system of mobilisation and con-
centration dependent on strategic railway*
Under the pretext or economic or religions
needs Abdnl Hamid II. brought them into
being. In every province of his empire rail-
way construction began, confided to German
or at least to Continental companies, or
carried out at the expense of the Government
—as in the case of the Hedjaz line—and the
dames of the concessions in all that referred
to traffic or construction were drawn op by
the Turoo-German General Staff. Chemin de
for" spells “chemin de guerre" in the Ottoman
Empire and the most insignificant branch lines
have their value as means of concentration and
helpers in the scheme of attack.
In a series of articles appearing in the
"Egyptian Gazette" it has been shown dearly
enough (to those who read between the lines)
that the Hedjaz Railway is before everything,
not a line destined to serve the religious inter-
ests of Islam—as our credulous Moslems of
Egypt vainly believe—but a purely military
railway built to link the outlying provinces of
the Arab world with the Turkish centre, to
conjure thoughts of autonomy or independ-
ance in the turbulent provinces of the Hedjaz,
Aar, and Yemen, and to preserve the Black
stone of the Kaaba in the jewelled diadem of
the Imam of lstamboul.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Coles Pasha has had to put off his departure
for England till to-morrow.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>M G. Maspero, director of the Service of
Antiquities, will leave Egypt for a three months’
holiday on July 2$.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>We are glad to learn that the condition of
M- de Bcaupuis, the esteemed manager of the
Alexandria branch of the Bank of Rome, shows
s-'groat improvement.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Hassan Hasil Bey, Sub Governor of the Suez
CaDal, has been accorded 3J months' leave of
absence, from the 26th inst.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<p>Mohamed Bey Pehmy, inspector of towns
and buildings in Upper Egypt, will retire on
July 5- His poet is to be suppressed.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.h</head>
<head>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.</head>
<head>REGATTA.</head>
<p>The wind was rather fresh-from the N.W.by
W., which necessitated most of the boats
shortening sail considerably. The May and
Tier el Mina gave op early in the race and the
Banshee unfortunately carried away her peak
halyards and was towed home
Iu Class II., although the Jessica had on her
small suit of sails, she cams in first The
Akraba was disqualified through Mating the
Bog has Pass Mark buoy on je port hand
instead of the starboard hand : tilt St Georges
therefore takes third place, bringing her total
number of points up to 11, whereas the Jessica
had only 10.
The prize for June in Class L went to the
Sans Pareille and in (Bass IL to the St George.
Next week the handicap will be revised and a
special cup will be awarded in each class for
the winner of the one race. The cups have
been kindly given by the Khedivial Club.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>CRICKET.</head>
<head>“ALEXANDRIA” v. "CAIRO.”</head>
<p>The following will represent Alexandria in
the match to be played on Saturday next :—
H. B. Carver (captain), A. B. Banaohi, K. P.
Birley, H. P. Carver, S. Dawson, E Henley,
K. Maoaulay, A. Mustard, C. D. Stacey, A
Strange, H. Thurston. Mrs. 8. H. Carver has
kindly consented to give tea on the ground to
members and their friends</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>MYSTERY OF THE SEA.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent).
Suez, Wednesday.
The German steamer “Helene Rickmere,”
not being able to wait any longer for the
lighters which were left behind at Ras Gharib
laden with rice, entered the Canal this morning
at 3 o'clock. Up to now neither the tog which
was despatched to tow the lighters nor any
of the boats have returned to Suez, and their
whereabouts are unknown.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>A SCARE.</head>
<p>We are authorised to state that the rumour
that a case of cholera has occurred in the port
is absolutely unfounded. The cook of a new
vessel making her first trip from Bonder-
land appears to have celebrated the occasion
and to have taken advantage of his position to
such good purpose, that he was brought on
shore suffering from collapse due to over-
eating.</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>DAIRA SANIBH COMPANY</head>
<p>A special meeting of the above company 1
will be held in Cairo on the 8th July to ratify
the agreement entered into with the Credit
Foncier Egyptien. By the terms of the contract
the latter bays or takes over all the outstand
ing debts of the Daira Sanieh Company,
amounting to some eight millions sterling, by
the purchases of its lands payable by annual
installments extending over a certain fixed
period. The Credit Ponoier will, on its side,
charge interest at the rate of 5 per cent per
annum upon all sums repayable in fifteen years;
and in order to refund the £8,000,000 still due
to the company an arrangement has been
arrived at whereby the Credit Foncier will
augment its capital by a further issue of
debentures or shares. The balance has been
offered to be foind for the latter by a group,
with Sir Ernest Caasel at its head, in Paris and
London at 3  % annual interest plus 
commission, besides dividing between the
group and the Credit Foncier the 1 % represent-
ing the difference between the rate of interest
and commission of 4 % for the money to be
advanced, and the 5 % annual interest charged
by the latter, on sums repayable in 15 years,
the higher rate of 5  % for repayments
extending over 20 years not being taken into
account in the agreement.
The above terms for the liquidation of the
outstanding debts of the Daira Sanieh Company
are, we are given to understand, correct in
every detail and will be submitted, at the
extraordinary meeting of the shareholders of
the Credit Foncier Egyptian convoked for the
lame date, m, 8th proximo, for their approval</p>
<div type=“item”>
<head>ARRIVAL*.</head>
<p>Per P. & 0. S.S. "Oriental,'' arrived at Port
Said Tuesday from Londou Mr. W. John-
son, Capt. Bnsor. From Marseilles :—Mr. B
C. Paxton, Lt 3 Walpole, Capt G. Byrne,
Mr. N. Sims.
Per P. & 0. S3 "Isis," arrived from Brin-
disi yesterday : Mr. A. G. M. Dickson, Mr.
B. W. Echlin, Signor G. de Griffi, Mr. A.
Mitchell innee, Mr. H. Heemat, Mr. W. Starry,
Mr. N. White, Mr. B. M. Moeaevi.
departures.
Le paquebot "Ismailia" de la Khedivial Mail
parti hier aprts-midi pour le Pirie, Mdtelin,
Dardanelles et Constantinople arait k bord:
Aly Riza bey Yagha, Attah bey Husni,
Yousaef bey Fahmy, Mehemet Bey Tewfiok,
(Aide-de camp de S. M. I. le Sultan) H. Kbos-
raw bey Peyrea, Elias bey Tambay, Dr Moha-
med bey Kafrawi, M. M. Megalide* N. Sum-
mers, M. Nicolas Vatimbella, Geo. Spathis,
Sotiri G. Violara, Grigoire Vanvouris, William
Maltese, M. Antonopoulo, Nicola Cambourif,
Geo. Nioolaidee, Jules Catzeflis, Cb. Platon, D.
Lsondis, M. Bngleselly, J. L Capes, Theodore
Mihailides, K Arghiroglu, Isaac A boat, Geo.
Kyrisoopoulo, T. Leuoeei, M. Schweiasern, A.
Paulsen, Nicola Hadjikou, Henri Montaldo, D.
Mariannopoulos, J >hn A. Cholmis, C. Christo-
fides, Plorio Sullaii, Jean 8ootto, Blie Mizin,
D. Oardikas, A. Zonlia, Panayotti Soarlatini,
Haralla Agha, Ibrahim effendi Massoud, C.
Cooohopoulos, Moheldin effendi Belik, M. et
Luc J. Georgefendia et fomille, M. et Mme
M. Pankalos, Mme Louis F. Limpritis et
famille, M. et Mme Anastase Cbrissoverghis,
Mme Charlton et famille, M. et Mme Maz
Hesse et fomille, Mme Dr M. Kefrawi bey et
famille, Mme Djemal bey Sabit et famille, Dr
et Mme J. Herden bey, M. et Mme Geo. Ange-
lopouto et famille, Mme Calomiris et famille,
Mme Sauda Logory et famille, M. et Mme
Basil Anastassiades et famille, Mme Riza bey
Yeghsetfamille, Mme Ahmed bey Bminetfom.,
El Said Hussein el Rifai et fomille, Hassan
bey el Rifoi et firm., M. et Mme Xantopool'S
et fom.. M. et Mme G. de la Porta et fom., M.
et Mme Joeeph Benrrra, M. et Mme A. U-
chidis et fom., M. et Mme Demitrioua et fom.,
M. et Mme Abdnl Hamid et fom., M. et Mme
Abdel Ahad, Mme S. Stavri et fom., Mme
Louisa Conrath et fom., Riza hey et Sabit bey,
ElMeesik Abou Ahad, Mme decile Tamror,
S Msralto Sullan, Semi ram is, A. Casfiohi, He-
i lene Christen A. Coustantinidis, N. Coro-
, noos, Klfot Hanem Benina Hanem, Alliak
I Hanem, Melle* R Geer, A Papareskou, HflAne
; Dikeos, Lilian Gout, Stella Trangopoulos, M.
i et Mme A. Jaoob, Mme B.B. Avierinos, Marie
Despinas, Valet Mme Zimpritis, 16 bonnes, 6
i gouvernantes et 296 paaeegen de pont.
'“wSSS</p> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

