<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor role="primary">Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2024-03-26">March 26, 2024</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1906-11-03/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1906-11-03">Saturday, November 3, 1906</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="8">9</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/mode/1up">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                    Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7601">7,601</measure>]</cell>
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 11, 1906.</cell>
                            <cell> [EIGHT PAGES</cell>
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->

                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->

                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->

            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n1/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Jardin Francais.</p>
                        <p>The two last performances of the season at the Jardin Français will be
                            given to-night and</p>
                        <p>to morrow.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Plague.</p>
                        <p>Yesterday's plague bulletin recorded a fatal case at Alexand is, the
                            victim being a Berberee, who was found dead at his house in Moharrem
                            Bey.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Egyptian University.</p>
                        <p>A committee for the collection of subscriptions for the Egyptian
                            University has been formed by the students of the Khedivial Law
                            School.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Murder of Chaffir,</p>
                        <p>A ghafir has been murdered near Mataï, within a short distance of the
                            omdeh's house. The Parquet and the police have opened an enquiry.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Quarantine Board.</p>
                        <p>.3</p>
                        <p>The next meeting of the Quarantine Board will be held on Tuesday, when
                            special regulations concerning the passage of pilgrims will be
                            considered.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Late Mr. Rone Carton de Wlart.</p>
                        <p>A memorial service in memory of the late director of the Toursh prison,
                            Mr. Réné' Carton de Wiart, who died on the 17th ult., will be held at
                            St. Joseph's Church, Cairo, on Monday at 3.30 pm.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Bandmann Opera Company.</p>
                        <p>To-morrow evening the Bandmann Opera Company will give a special
                            performance of "The Geisha" at the Khedivial Opera House, the proceeds
                            of which will be devoted to the Abemla Jewish Charitable Society.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Boulac Bridge.</p>
                        <p>The Cairo Tramway Company has offered to subscribe L.E. 50,000 towards
                            the cost of construction of the new Nile bridge connecting Boulag with
                            Ghezireh, on condition that they are empowered to lay a double line
                            along the bridge, with a view to connecting Cairo directly by tramway
                            with the Pyramide.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>American Cruleer at Port Said.</p>
                        <p>The United States first-class cruiser Ohio has arrived at Port Said from
                            the Philippines. Yesterday several of the officers and crew went to
                            Cairo, where they spent their time visiting the most prominent places of
                            interest."</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Holouan Railway.</p>
                        <p>We would draw the attention of our Helonan readers to the new time-table
                            for November which has come into force on the Helonan branch of the
                            Delta Light Railway Company, and which is published on page 7.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Coal Importe</p>
                        <p>Between January 1 and November 1,, the imports of coal at this port
                            totalled 1,091,255 tons. Of this, 589.970 tons was Welsh, 190,642 tons
                            Newcastle, 99,029 tons Scotch, 159,135 tons Yorkshire, and 52:479 tons
                            other quali- ties. Daring the same period last year the total was
                            919,906 tons.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Zagazig Water Installation.</p>
                        <p>Tenders for the installation of a water plant at Zagazig are at present
                            being considered by the Government. Only three offers have been made,
                            namely, those of Messrs. Chartrain and Laroussie (LE. 29.765); Messrs.
                            Thos. Cook and Son (L.E. 31.837), and Fourneron and Mabagoli (LE.
                            34,000).</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Church of Scotland.</p>
                        <p>Rev. D. McClymont, of Aberdeen, will preach on Sunday at 10.30 a.m. and 6
                            pm. in St. Andrew's Charch (Church of Scotland), Cairo, next to British
                            Head Quarters, and will continue the services throughout the season." At
                            St. Andrew's Church, Alexandria, the evening services for the winter
                            months will be resumed to-morrow at 6 p. m.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Thief Caught</p>
                        <p>On Tuesday evening, at Medinet'el Fayoum, the Italian Consul, on retiring
                            to rest, about 11 pm., found a man hiding in one of the closets of his
                            house, evidently intending to attack him in his sleep. The man is now in
                            custody, and an enquiry has been opered by the movdir, as it is believed
                            that the ghaffirs were in league with the thief.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p> New Victoria Hotel, Ramich.</p>
                        <p>We are informed that this new and up-todate first class hotel will remain
                            open during the winter season. The management has decided to make
                            special arrangements for residents and officers wishing to take monthly
                            terms. Already, a number of residents are staying there. Among the
                            arrivals of last week we notice: Mr. James Watson, Mme G. Gorre, Miss Y.
                            Goirs,, Mr, N. Spathis, Mr. and Mrs. George- C. Khoury, Mr. M. Fondor,
                            Mr. Ch. Smith, Mr. N. Cavadias, and Miss M. Y. Gabriel.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St. Mark's Church, Alexandria.</p>
                        <p>The services at this church to-morrow will be as follows:-8 a.m., Holy
                            Communion; 11 a.m., Matins and sermon (Prescher Rev. W.. R. Livingstone,
                            M. A. Oxon and Melbourne, late Chaplain at Nicosia, Cyprus). Anthem: "No
                            shadowe yonder," from A. R. Gaul's "Holy City." Noon, Holy Communion.
                            6.15 p.m., Evensong and sermon (Preacher : Rev. A: H. Longley, B.A.).
                            "Magnificat" and "Nano Dimittis" (in B flat), by E. Vine Hall. Anthems:
                            Chorale from A. R. Gaul's sacred cantata Ruth," entitled "Nightfall." Ve
                            por bym Part in Peace." by H.H. Jefferiae. Collections for church
                            exper.see.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>MOTED FOR ITS EXCELLENT CUISINE.</p>
                    <p>ELECTRIO LIGHT, LIFT,</p>
                    <p>Special terms for officers of the Army of Occupation and Government
                        Oficials.</p>
                    <p>30-11-90</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLAND'S MUNICIPAL</head>
                    <p>GOVERNMENT.</p>
                    <p>THE TRIENNIAL ELECTIONS.</p>
                    <p>CONSERVATIVE VICTORY.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 2.</p>
                    <p>The elections for the Borough Councils in England took place yesterday. The
                        results are still incomplete, bat most surprising. The Progressive and
                        Labourite candidates were everywhere defeated. The fight was keenest in
                        London, where the Conservative element, selfstyled municipal reformers, has
                        been cam paigning most actively against the municipal trading tendencies.
                        (Router)</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November-2.</p>
                    <p>To-day's results of the elections for the borough councils accentuate the
                        sweeping victory of the Moderates. Here the Progressive and Labourite
                        candidates were everywhere ronted. A notable example was Westminster, where
                        one Progressive candidate was returned, compared with 17 in 1903. Up to the
                        present the Moderate party has gained 283 seats here. In the provinces they
                        have also scored big (Feuter)</p>
                    <p>successes.</p>
                    <p>The great triennial fight for Municipal ascendency in England has resulted,
                        as will be seen by the above telegrams, in the defeat of the Progressive and
                        Labour candidates.</p>
                    <p>This victory of the Municipal Reformers, as the Moderates have re-christened
                        themselves, is evidently due to the alarm aroused by the very collectivist
                        tendencies manifested by the Progressive majority on the Borough Councils
                        and by the disgust at the recent disclosures on local Government morality in
                        London. The air has been heavy with scandals for some time past, and the
                        gederal tone of the conduct of Municipal affairs has shown little signs of
                        improvement, especially since the recent revelations as to the lines on
                        which the Eastend Municipalities have been ran.</p>
                    <p>The Progressives have not been very confident, as they were fearful lest by
                        their policy of extravagance they might have courted the displeasure of
                        certain of the working-class districts upon which the Labour party had set
                        its eye. Of the 1,362 members of the new City Borough Councils only a small
                        minority were avowed champions of advanced Labourism. In the main the
                        struggle was between the Muni cipal Reformers and the Progressives. These
                        two parties had prior to the election on Thursday practically equal
                        representation in London. Out of twenty eight Borough Counoils, thirteen
                        were Moderate, and a like number Progressive, with two "doubtfals."</p>
                    <p>The members of the Borough Councils elected on the Ist inst. will remain in
                        office for a period of three years.</p>
                    <p>Possibly the real significance of the election results is mainly to be looked
                        for in the dislike of the average voter to the extraordinary wastefulness in
                        the various municipal industrial experiments. These experiments are part of
                        a great collectivist programme involving a com plete industrial revolution.
                        Municipal trading may become a recognised social fact in the fature, but on
                        this subject most people at home should say, in the words of Henry Sidgwick,
                        that they are patriotic enough to wish some other nation would try it
                        first.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE INNISKILLINGS MARCH.</head>
                    <p>AN INCIDENT.</p>
                    <p>Two days ago, in the course of their reconnaissance march through Menoufieh,
                        the Ioniskilling Dragoons had to pass through a maize plantation which was
                        considerably damaged by the passage of the equadron. The owners of the field
                        were naturally angered by the damage inflicted on their crop and immediately
                        approached the omdeh, seeking redress, The latter soon settled the question
                        by paying the fellaheen L.E. 8 which was their estimate of the damage.
                        Afterwards th3 omdah informed some of the men of the squadron that the field
                        of maize was theirs and that they could have the maize for their horses.</p>
                    <p>Having been asked by the commanding officer as to what he meant by the
                        statement. he had made to the men, the omdeh reported what had happened,
                        whereupon Major Pater- 80 thanked him for his action and ordered the L.E. 8
                        to be refunded to him.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MIXED COURTS.</head>
                    <p> The Alexandria Mixed Courts will shortly invite candidates for the posts of
                        huissier and commis greffier, who will be selected after examination.</p>
                    <p>Owing to so many financial concerns requir ing chefs du contentieux, the
                        Mixed Courts Are losing some valuable employés. A few days ago we announced
                        that M. Palladino, Greffier of Notarial Deeds at Cairo, had resigned in
                        order to accept the position of Director of the Legal Department of the
                        Crédit Foncier Egyptien, and now another official hea just resigned for a
                        similar reason Mr. Farid Bichara, advocate, secretary to the President of
                        the Mixed Tribunal at Alexandria and greffier of the Civil Mixed Court at
                        Alexandria, has sent in his resig ¡nation in order to take the control of
                        the legal department of the Land Bank.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HELOUAN AND CAIRO.</head>
                    <p>The inhabitants of Helonan have petitioned the Government to make a road
                        between Helonan and Cairo similar to that running to Ramleh from
                        Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>The Delta Light Railway Company have decided to ballast the line from Cairo
                        to Helonan so as to avoid as far as possible the great amount of dust raised
                        by the traine.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AN IMPERIAL CRISIS.</head>
                    <p>THE NEWFOUNDLAND AFFAIR.</p>
                    <p>A SERIOUS SITUATION.</p>
                    <p>LONDON, November 2.</p>
                    <p>Telegrams are being constantly exchanged between the Imperial Government and
                        the Governor of Newfoundland in connection with the modus vivendi. The
                        situation is serious. (Reuter)</p>
                    <p>The troubles of the present Government in its relations with various parts of
                        the Empire appear to be endless.</p>
                    <p>The present difficulty with Newfoundland does not, however, arise from any
                        fault of the Government, but is due to the inherently anworkable system of
                        our Empire, which has become quite as anachronistio as the political
                        machinery on which the United States is run. The crux of the difficulty is
                        seen in the reply s few days ago of the Under-Secretary for the Colonies to
                        a question as to the attitude of Newfoundland towards an agreement made with
                        a foreign Power on a matter profoundly affecting the interests of the
                        Colony, in which be made a statement which should force us to understand the
                        hopelessly anomalous position we now occupy. The Government has not been, he
                        said, so fortunate as to obtain the consent of the Newfoundland Government
                        to the arrangement, but as it is a question of a treaty with a foreign
                        Power, the Foreign Secretary is alone concerned, and neither the Colonial
                        Office, nor the Colony which is so vitally interested in the matter, has any
                        voice in it at all.</p>
                    <p>Is it possible to imagine anything more absurd The Colony has not even the
                        right to approach the Foreign Secretary on the subject, except indirectly,
                        and the statesman who has to decide it is in no way responsible to those
                        whose interests are principally involved. He is responsible to the
                        Parliament at Westminster alone, and so long as he pleases that assembly, he
                        is free to saorifice colonial interests to any extent he may think
                        convenient. It is quite possible that we may some day have a Foreign
                        Minister who would take a positive pleasure in doing so, and a House of
                        Commons which would heartily endorse his action.</p>
                    <p>No Empire could hold together permanently under such conditions, and they
                        must undergo a radical change if the great fabric is not to go to pieces
                        before our eyes. The only possible remedy is the establishment in some form
                        or other of an Imperial Council, chosen by and out of the whole Empire, to
                        which those Ministers who have charge of Imperial interests shall be
                        responsible. The House of Commons, would then be left free to deal with
                        local affairs in the same way as are the other Parliaments of the Empire,
                        and would cease to interfere in those foreign and colonial affairs which it
                        so deplorably misunderstands and mismanages now.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PUBLIC WORKS' REPORT.</head>
                    <p>ITS TARDY APPEARANCE.</p>
                    <p>The Report of the Ministry of Public Works on the progress of its various
                        departments daring 1905 has not yet made its appearance, and yet we are less
                        than two months from 1907. The report is the most important departmental
                        publication issued annually by the Egyptian Government, and should contain a
                        vast amount of invaluable local information. Year after year the report is
                        most tardy in making its appearance, and officials in the Public Works
                        Department confess that the question of the permanent postponement of its
                        publication absolutely depends on the good pleasure of the Adviser to that
                        Ministry.</p>
                    <p>As public opinion is as yet a very feeble institution in this country, and
                        Lord Cromer has many other matters of greater and equal importance to
                        supervise, it is very probable that these complaints will continue to be
                        reiterated year after year. In fact, for years past correspondents have
                        asked in our columns why this report should be published after such a lapse
                        of time as to render much of its contents practically valueless. No answer
                        has ever been vouchsafed to their just complaints, and the report this year
                        is as late, if not later than ever. There is no remedy for such a state of
                        things. Public opinion in Egypt 18 80 incoherent and timorons that it is a
                        simple thing to float it, and there the matter rests, until the same
                        complaints and protests come up next year to be treated with the same
                        indifference.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUEZ CANAL.</head>
                    <p>On the 31st October, 9 vessels transited the Canal, 3 being northward and 6
                        southward bound. Of these, 8 were British and 1.German. Daring the month 319
                        vessels went through, 205 northward and 114 southward bound. They carried a
                        total aggregate cargo of ,600,972 tons and 18,316 passengers, 16,716 being
                        adults, 952. children, and 648 steerage. The total revenue for the month was
                        Fr. 8,689,709.68.</p>
                    <p>The total receipts in passenger and transit toll between January 1 and
                        October 31, were Fr. 89,681,564.98, as against Fr. 94 632,490.50 for the
                        same period last year, a-falling-off of Fr. 4,950,925.52, due to the rebate
                        of 75 centimes off the tonnage duee.</p>
                    <p>From January 1 to October 31, 3,328 ships transited, 1,516 being northward
                        and 1,812 southward bound-155 ships less than for the same period last year.
                        This decrease is due to this year's shipping using the Canal being of larger
                        tonnage. On the 1st November, 12 vessels transited the canal, and paid for
                        transit and passenger toll Fr. 366,730.28. Of these, 9 were British, 2
                        Japanese and 1 American.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item" status="verified">
                    <head>CAIRO ASSAULT CASE.</head>
                    <p>WALDBERG v. BENNETT.</p>
                    <p>EXTRAORDINARY EVIDENCE.</p>
                    <p>An interesting case came before the British Consular Court at Cairo this
                        morning. The plaintiff is Captain Jorge Neilken y Waldberg, editor and
                        proprietor at "The Oriental Truth" a bilingual Cairo daily newspaper
                        published in French and Arabio.</p>
                    <p>The defendant is Mr. Bennett, an Englishman, private secretary to the
                        well-known Anglo- Belgian leader of the Cairo Bar, Maïtre Carton de
                        Wiart.</p>
                    <p>Captain Waldberg, in an article in his paper giving his version of the
                        affair, states that he was summoned to the offices of Maitre Carton de Wiart
                        by telephone and that when he arrived there the defendant and two other
                        individuals threw themselves on him, and maltreated him. In the scuffle the
                        Captain lost his gold-rimmed eye-glasses and £20 and none of these
                        belongings of his have been returned to him.</p>
                    <p>At the hearing of the case to-day Captain Waldberg, after having been sworn,
                        stated that he was the editor of "The Oriental Truth," a Latin-American by
                        birth, and a citizen of the United States. He said that on the 29th ulto.,
                        about noon, he received a communication at his office from one of the
                        members of his staff. In consequence of this he called at about 3.15 p.m. at
                        the offices of Maitre Carton de Wiart. After a time Mr. Bennett appeared and
                        told him to come into the office. Upon witness entering the office Mr.
                        Bennett made certain statements and afterwards made a felonious assault on
                        him. (By the Court: The assault was not felonious.) The defendant hit him in
                        the face and his eye-glasses fell down and were broken to pieces. There were
                        other persons in the room at the thime and, far as he could remember, Mr.
                        Bennett said nothing previous to the assault. Besides the eye glasses he
                        lost four five pound bank notes. Mr. Bennett "chucked" him out of the
                        office, saying, besides other things, that every English soldier would break
                        plaintiff's bones. The situation not being very pleasant he thought he had
                        better go away and left the building. He afterwards called on Maitre Carton
                        de Wiart.</p>
                    <p>CROSS EXAMINATION.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Le Breton, on behalf of defendant, afterwards cross examined plaintiff.
                        Witness stated that he did not try to stay in the office but went out as
                        soon as possible. He then proceeded to Maitre Carton de Wiart's house in a
                        carriage. He admitted asking the Maitre if he was cognisant of the assault.
                        The Maitre made a communication to him and the interview closed.</p>
                    <p>In answer to a question defendant admitted his responsibility for "Le Coucou
                        Egyptien" and also for certain articles, which were produced in Court.</p>
                    <p>Counsel for the defence: "Do you know that the Maitre is M. Empain's
                        advocate? Plaintiff objected to the question.</p>
                    <p>Do you generally extort money by blackmailing efforts ?</p>
                    <p>(Here there were voluble protests on the part of plaintiff, he declaring that
                        he would hold Mr. Le Breton answerable for it)..</p>
                    <p>The Court: Counsel is privileged.</p>
                    <p>(Further voluble and excited protests by plaintiff, who interlarded his
                        ejaculations with compliments to British justice).</p>
                    <p>M. Le Breton: Have you already tried to obtain subscribers to your paper in
                        your own words "par force" (More protests by defendant, who finally said
                        "No").</p>
                    <p>Do you know the Ecole des Freres ?-Yes. </p>
                    <p>Did you ever tell Father Belays that it would do much harm to publish certain
                        facts about the school and that you had over 800 subscribers, three-quarters
                        of whom were obtained by force?-This is untrue.</p>
                    <p>Is it also untrue that you told him you held some very compromising letters,
                        but would not publish them, if given £40 ?-Quite untrue. </p>
                    <p>In answer to a protest by plaintiff counsel for defence said he had liberty
                        to ask certain questions to prove his case, namely, that defendant was
                        simply a common blackmailer. </p>
                    <p>Do you known Mr. Kramer, of the Mousky?</p>
                    <p>-Yes.</p>
                    <p>Did you recently tell Mr. Kramer that you possessed compromising information
                        about him ?-No, this is a blackmailing affair. </p>
                    <p>Did you write an article, saying you were aware of certain matters re Mr.
                        Kramer requiring investigation, and did you publish this article?-Yes; I
                        published an article about Mr. Kramer but do not remember its exact
                        contents.</p>
                    <p>Do you know Mr. Empain, and did you.not till him that you had received many
                        complaints about the tramways, which you would publish unless the Tramway
                        Co. was more kind to you ?-No; I do not remember. </p>
                    <p>Have you published an article headed "Maitre Carton de Wiart ?"-eos. (The
                        article was produced).</p>
                    <p>When you went to the office did Mr. Bennett show you two papers with two
                        envelopes pinned to them ?-No.</p>
                    <p>Did you not deny that it was your handwriting, and was it not then that Mr.
                        Bennett pushed you out of the room ?- No, Sir. </p>
                    <p>Witness said he retired slowly backwards. He held a heavy stick but did not
                        use it. Mr. Bennett tried to take the stick away.</p>
                    <p>BITING ADMITTED.</p>
                    <p>Did you bite Mr. Bennett on the left arm ?-Yes; I had no other defence.</p>
                    <p>You never applied at the office for the £20 you say you lost?-No, I thought I
                        had better not. I thought the servant had picked them up.</p>
                    <cb n="5"/>
                    <p>As to your glasses. They were broken to pieces ?-Yes.</p>
                    <p>You stated so in your paper ?-Yes.</p>
                    <p>Ah, you mean they may have been broken in pieces? -Yes.</p>
                    <p>Well ! Here they are! (The glasses were handed to the Court unbroken!)</p>
                    <p>Further cross-examination followed.</p>
                    <p>There were other people in the room. He did not call them as witnesses as it
                        would be ridiculous, as one member of the office would not bear witness
                        against the another.</p>
                    <p>Witness protested to the Court against no place being found for his
                        reporter.</p>
                    <p>The Court replied that they had only room for the English papers.</p>
                    <p>Captain Waldberg then called on Maitre Carton de Wiart, who was sworn.</p>
                    <p>MAITRE CARTON DE WIART.</p>
                    <p>By plaintiff :</p>
                    <p>Did you call me by telephone to your office at 3.15?-"No, and I may add that
                        plaintiff must have known I was not at the office as he came to my house
                        directly after the alleged assault. He had no knowledge of plaintiff being
                        called to the office. On the morning of the 29th or the day before the
                        alleged assault be received envelopes containing marked passages from papers
                        which seemed to refer to himself. The envelopes were addressed to him in the
                        plaintiff's handwriting. He told Mr. Bennett he had better interview
                        plaintiff. It this sort of thing continued he would have to take strong
                        measures against the plaintiff, who was obviously trying to blackmail him.
                        Plaintiff was not to set foot in the office.</p>
                    <p>By plaintiff. Did you say you'd been blackmailed before ?-No, what I said was
                        that attempts had been made to blackmail me ; firstly, in the case of M.
                        Empain, whose advocate I am known to be, and secondly, in an article very
                        properly headed "Chantage." In this article it was stated we shall very
                        shortly publish a book giving a variety of details concerning persons whom I
                        gather were habitual companions of its author such as diplomatists,
                        financiers, and other notables.- Publication admitted by plaintiff.</p>
                    <p>By Plaintiff: Do you subscribe to "Oriental Truth" ? -Yes, I subscribe to
                        every paper in Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Where is the letter in my handwriting ?-Enclosed in the envelope I
                        received.</p>
                    <p>There was no such letter.-The envelopes of which you confessed yourself
                        ignorant just now bore your handwriting. (Plaintiff tried to explain himself
                        and became very involved.) </p>
                    <p>Did you try to get me, an American citizen, expelled from Egypt ? - I said I
                        would do my best to make you suffer and would ask Lord Cromer to help
                        me.</p>
                    <p>Did you ever give me any inside information ? -No, I never gave you an atom
                        of information, though you often came to my office.</p>
                    <p>CASE DISMISSED.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Alban, summing up, stated that, while the defendant admitted an assault
                        having been committed, the evidence produced by the defence made it very
                        probable that an attempt at blackmail had been committed and he would
                        therefore dismiss the charge.</p>
                    <p>No costs were allowed.</p>
                    <p>At the close of the case there were marked signs of approval at the decision
                        of Mr. Alban and Captain Waldberg disappeared with great velocity.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW HOTELS FOR EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>THE RITZ COMPANY.</p>
                    <p>A new hotel, under the auspices of the Ritz, Carlton, and Savoy Hotels of
                        London, is shortly to be built at Cairo, and Baron Pfiffer,
                        proprietor-manager of the National Hotel of Lucerne and director of the
                        hotels referred to, is himself coming to Cairo to organise the fitting up of
                        the Cairo hotel. The local administrators of the Ritz Hotels (Egypt).
                        Limited, about to be floated, are Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoun, Messrs, S.
                        H. Carver, E. Mosseri, and Charles Bacos, and those of London, Mr. H. V.
                        Higgins, M. I. Matesdorf, and Baron Pfifter.</p>
                    <p>The company is to be formed with a capital of £150,000, in preference shares
                        of £1 each, of which 50,000 are to be publicly subsoribed for through the
                        medium of the Anglo Egyptian Bank and Messrs. Coatts and Co., of London. The
                        company will have the right to issue 5% debentures to the amount of
                        £150,000. The profits will then be divided as follows:- 10% to the reserve
                        fand, 5% cumulative dividend to the shareholders, and of the rest, 30% to
                        holders of founders' shares, (there are to be 5,000 founders' shares at 1
                        shilling) and 70% to the privileged shareholders. The issue will probably be
                        made on the 26th November. The Ritz Hotel is to be constructed on the
                        property of the Garden City belonging to the Nile Land and Agricultural
                        Company. The principal façade will be upon the Nile at Kasr el-Doubara,
                        olose to the British Agency. The building will be commenced immediately
                        after the allotment and it is expected that it will be ready for the season
                        of 1907-1908.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CATTLE MARKETS.</head>
                    <p>It, is anticipated that the Department of Pablic Health will shortly
                        authorise the reopening of the provincial cattle markets, as Lower Egypt is
                        declared. free of the cattle plague, and last week only three cases were
                        notified in Upper Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Moss SS. Tabor sailed from Malta</p>
                    <p>last night, and is due here on Tuesday morning. The Norddeutscher Lloyd 8.8.
                        Hohenzollern left Naples yesterdayd is due at Alex andria about 9 a.m. on
                        Monday.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>WIRELESS TELEGRAPHY TREATY.</head>
                        <p>GREAT BRITAIN'S VICTORY.</p>
                        <p>BERLIN, November 9. The Wireless Telegraphy Treaty will be signed
                            to-morrow.</p>
                        <p>Great Britain has carried the day in conneotion with the contention over
                            article No. 3. She maintains a free hand to organize her own system and
                            has been loyally backed by France, Italy, and Japan.</p>
                        <p>The French delegates often supported her, even against their own
                            conviction.</p>
                        <p>Article No. 8 compels the coastal stations and ships to exchange messager
                            irrespective of the system. Great Britain carried an in-.. portant
                            amendment empowering each country to exempt stations at will.</p>
                        <p>(Router)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FANATICISM IN MOROCCO.</head>
                        <p>PROTECTION OF EUROPEANS.</p>
                        <p>TANGIER, November 2.</p>
                        <p>The Diplomatic Corps has protested against</p>
                        <p>the insufficient protection of Europeans by the</p>
                        <p>Shereefian authorities.</p>
                        <p>(Havas))</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DESTRUCTIVE TIDAL WAVE.</head>
                        <p>MEDITERRANEAN PORT DAMAGED.</p>
                        <p>PARIS, November 2.</p>
                        <p>Great damage has been done by a storm and tidal wave at the Riviera. Nine
                            torpedoboats have been wrecked at Toulon and the shipping has suffered
                            severely. (Reuter)</p>
                        <p>PARIS, November 9.</p>
                        <p>Considerable damage has been caused in various Mediterranean ports and at
                            Abbazia</p>
                        <p>by a tidal wave.</p>
                        <p>(Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RIOT IN GALWAY.</head>
                        <p>MANY SERIOUSLY INJURED.</p>
                        <p>DUBLIN, November 2.</p>
                        <p>A riot occurred in Galway owing to a collision between the supporters of
                            the Nationalist and Devolutionist candidates. Sticks and stones and
                            rotten fish were freely used. The police made repeated baton charges.
                            Forty persona were seriously injured. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>THE TSAR.</p>
                        <p>NOW AT TSARSKOE SELO.</p>
                        <p>ST. PETERSBURG, November 2.:</p>
                        <p>The Tear and his family have gone to</p>
                        <p>Tearskoe Selo.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>INTERNATIONAL FOOTBALL</head>
                        <p>ENGLAND BEATS FRANOE.</p>
                        <p>PARIS, November 2.</p>
                        <p>Association. England beat Frahos by 16</p>
                        <p>points to nil.</p>
                        <p>(Router)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>Lady Wingate arrived to-day from England.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Borton arrived at Port Said from Europe on Wednesday last and has
                        returned to Moharrem Bey, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>1.</p>
                    <p>Judge Bond, Vice President of the Native Court of Appeal, has arrived from
                        Cairo, and is staying at the New Victoria Hotel, Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>We greatly regret to learn of the serious illness of the eminent composer, M.
                        Camille Saint-Saëns, who is almost as well-known in Egypt as in his native
                        country. M. Saint- Saëns was crossing to New York on board the 8.8. Provence
                        to give a series of cohoer ta All will join us in the hope that in spite of
                        his advanced years the famous composer will be given strength to stem the
                        tide.</p>
                    <p>Rev. and Mrs. A. H. Ellaby have taken up quarters at the Carlton Hotel,
                        Balkeley,</p>
                    <p>Omar Bey Lutfy, the well-known lawyer, returned to Cairo from Europe
                        yesterday evening, via Port Said.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Harold Hall has arrived from England on his way to Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Dorling and family have returned from Europe.</p>
                    <p>Lient. A. Brodhurst-Hill, 1st Battalion</p>
                    <p>Royal Dublin Fusiliers, has been granted an extension of leave, on the
                        recommendation of a medical board, from October 31 to January 28..</p>
                    <p>Among the passengers for Marseilles by the Equateur on Saturday were Dr.
                        Lakah, M. Aicard, Mr. and Mme Maillard, Mr. Uokermann, Dr. Cooper, Mr.J
                        Glavany, M. and Mme Favre, M. and Mme Maitre, Mr. Pascal,</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n3/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n4/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n5/mode/1up"> </div>

            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n6/mode/1up"> </div>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8"
                facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1906-11-03/page/n7/mode/1up"
            > </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
