<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alexis Sharpe</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-09-09">January 24, 2020</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1906-10-31">Wednesday, October 31, 1906</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01">
                                <p>The Eastern Telegraph Company, Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01">
                                <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="advert" status="uncorrectedOCR">
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>This Companr's system of submarine telegraph mbles is the most direct and
                        quickest means of communication from Egypt to Europe, North and South
                        America, East, South and West Africa, India, Australia, New Zealand, China
                        and Japan.</p>
                    <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should be marked Via Eastern.</p>
                    <p>For latest average time to London, see daily bulletin in this paper.</p>
                    <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, Suez, Port-Tewfik, Port-Saïd, Suakin.
                        Head Office, London.</p>
                    <p>No. 7,598]</p>
                    <p>Peninsular and Oriental S. N. Company. </p>
                    <p>Commencing October let the through Steamers for Marseilles and London are
                        intended our to leave Port Said every Monday at 5 p.m.</p>
                    <p>The Brindisi Express Steamers leave Port Said directly the Indian. Mails
                        arrive. Passengers can go on board the evening before. Combined fare to
                        London by sea and train de uxe via Brindisi or via Marseilles £22 9.11. </p>
                    <p> For all further information apply to the Company's Agents. </p>
                    <p>* Massrs. Tłog. Cook &amp; Sou (Egypt) Ltd. GEORGE ROYLE, Esq.</p>
                    <p>*** *** *** *** *** ** CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>PORT SAID. Messrs. HASELDEN &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA. B.G. DAVIDSON, Superintendent P. &amp;0. S. N. Company in
                        Egypt</p>
                    <p>SUEZ.</p>
                    <p>ORIENT-ROYAL MAIL LINE.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARD TO AUSTRALIA.</p>
                    <p> R.M.S Omrah will leave Sues about November 2 R.M.S. Oroys will leave Suez
                        about November 16</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD to NAPLES, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR, PLYMOUTE, LONDON, TILBURY. B.M.B.
                        Ormaz will leave Port Said</p>
                    <p>November 5 | B.M.B. Orient will leave Port Said November 19 Pos to
                        Marseilles. ********* ..... 1st Olasa, &amp; 9.16. 2nd Olaus, &amp; 6.16.
                        3rd Class, &amp;$ Plymouth or Tilbury .........</p>
                    <p>. 14. 6.</p>
                    <p>9. 0. TABES. I no Naples...............</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">-8, 0.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Passengers returning by the Line obtain one-third rebate off the abovo fares
                        If leaving England before the end of October.</p>
                    <p>Agenta, CAIBO :-THOS. COOK &amp; SON. ALEXANDRIA -R. J. MOSS &amp; Co. - For
                        all particulars apply wm. STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, PORT Said and Port Tewdik
                        (Suez).</p>
                    <p>81-12-906</p>
                    <p>GIBBY LINE MAIL TWIN-SCREW STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>REDUCED SUMMER FARES MAY TO OCTOBER. </p>
                    <p>Port Sald to Tilbury £12.16.0 and Port Said to Marseilles £9.0.0. Passengers
                        returning by the Line will be granted a rebate of 33 % off the full fare i.e
                        Liverpool to Port Said £11.6,8 and Marseilles to Port Sald £8,0,0. </p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS to COLOMBO, TUTICORIN,RANGOON </p>
                    <p>Departure from Suez </p>
                    <p>S.S. Derbyshire, 6636 tons, Nov. 8</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARDS to MARSEILLES and LONDON.</p>
                    <p>Departure from Port Said .</p>
                    <p>S.S. Staffordshire 6,005 tons Nov, 12 </p>
                    <p>Agonta-Catro : THOS. COOK &amp; son, Suez &amp; Port Said , wm STAPLEDON
                        &amp; SONS 81-12-006</p>
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE.</p>
                    <p>FAST BRITISH PASSENGER STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Greece-Turkey Line. </p>
                    <p>Express steamers leave Alexandria every Wednesday at 4 p.m. for PIRÆUS,
                        SMYRNA, MITÝLENE, and CONSTANTINOPLE. In connection with Orient Express
                        train-de-luxe for Vienna, Paris, and London.. </p>
                    <p>Palestine-Syrla Line,</p>
                    <p>Fast steamers leave Alexandria every Saturday at 4 p.m., and Port Said every
                        Sunday at 6 pm., for JAPPA (for Jerusalem), CAIPPA (for Nezareth), BEYROUT
                        (for Damascus.) TRIPOLI, ALEXANDRETTA, MERSINE, coptinding in alternate
                        weeks to LARNACA and LIMASSOL (Cyprus.)</p>
                    <p>Red Sea Line, </p>
                    <p>Steamers leave Suez weekly on Wednesday at 6 p.m. for Port Badan and Suakin
                        direot returning from Buakin every Wednesday noon. Every Monday at 6 p.m.
                        &amp; steamer leaves Suez for Jeddah Pedas continuing every other week to
                        Saakin, Massowah, Hodeidah, Aden. Intermediate steamers do not proceed
                        beyond Jeddah bat call at Tor, (for Sinai) El Wedj and Yambo as required. </p>
                    <p>N.B.-Deck chairs provided for the use of passengers, excellent cuisine and
                        table wine free.Steamer plans may be seen and passages booked at the
                        Company's Agencies at Alexandria, Cairo, Port Said, and Suez, or at Thos.
                        Cook &amp; Son or other Tourist Agency. 81-12-906</p>
                    <p>The Moss S.S.Company,Ltd.</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL calling at MALTA (Mesere, JAMES MO88 &amp; Co., 31, James St.,
                        Liverpool, Managers:) </p>
                    <p>Amnete..............Tons 4,800 1 Shophren ....Tons 6,000 | Voorts
                        ..............Tons 7,600 | Eameno.......... Tons 8,900 Busin.. *</p>
                    <p>8,000 Mons. 1791 10.***... » 3,960 Phar ..------... 8,000
                        Seti................. 6,000 Kamak</p>
                    <p>6,000 Menopthab . 6,000 Philne... ..... * 6,008 | Tabor .............. 8,000
                        Becepd clue Second class accommodation only, unless specially reserved.
                        Fares: Alexandria to Liverpool, 1st £14 Single, £26 Return, 2nd, £9 Single,
                        £15 Return To Malte,1st £5 Single, £9 Return, 2nd, £3 Single, 26 Returp, --
                        Return tickets available for six months.</p>
                    <p>S.S. Pharos now on the berth, will sail on or about Wednesday, October 31st,
                        to be followed by S.S. Tabor. </p>
                    <p>S.S. Menon, in port, will load for Manchester, </p>
                    <p>Through freight rates on cotton, etc., to Lancashire inland towns, Boston,
                        New York and other U.S.A. towns, obtained on applian. tion. Cargo takon by
                        special agreement only, Passenger Tickets also issued inclusive of Railway
                        fare through to and from Cairo. 37-11-006 For particulars apply R. J. MOSS
                        &amp; Co., Alexandria Agente.</p>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO's LINE.</p>
                    <p>Steamers leave Suez and Port Said fortnightly for LONDON or LIVERPOOL direct.
                        Fare (home.) £10 Passengers returning by end October allowed 20% off outward
                        fare (£14). S.S. IRRAWADDY 7300 Tons will leave PORT SAID about ...</p>
                    <p>MANDALAY 6000 ..</p>
                    <p> PEGU5800…..</p>
                    <p> Due in LONDON or LIVERPOOL 12 days thereafter. - Apply WORMS &amp; Co., Port
                        Said and 082. THOS. COOK &amp; SON, (Karpt) LD., CAIBO C J. GRACE &amp; CO.,
                        ALEXANDRIA 31-12-906</p>
                    <p>ASIA MINOR STEAMSHIP Co., Ltd.</p>
                    <p>Regular weekly sailings to Cyprus and Coast of Syria. Steamer leaves
                        Alexandria every Tuesday afternoon for Limassol and Larnaca, returning viâ
                        Port Said. 1st Class Single Fare, Alex, to Cyprus £2 Sailings liable to
                        alteration owing to Quarantine, etc.</p>
                    <p>For further particulars apply : Manager, 3 St. Mark's-Street, Alexandria.
                        28478-31-12-06</p>
                    <p>THE PAPAYANNI LINE.</p>
                    <p>(The Ellerman Lines. Ltd.)</p>
                    <p>Frequent Sailings from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL, also Regular Services from
                        LIVERPOOL to ALEXANDRIA and to ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT, BLACK SEA, and other
                        Mediterranean ports</p>
                    <p>Excellent Passenger Accommodation. Stewardess carried. Liberal table and
                        Moderate Fares for single and return tickets. </p>
                    <p>The S.S. Avon now loading will leave for Liverpool on the 27th inst., and
                        will be followed by the S.S. AUSTRIAN.</p>
                    <p>CARGO taken by special agreement only. Through Freights quoted for the UNITED
                        STATES INLAND TOWNs in GREAT BRITAIN.</p>
                    <p>For passage or freight apply to the Agents, BARKER &amp; Co., Alexandria.
                        17-4-907</p>
                    <p>Navigation Générale Italienne,</p>
                    <p>Societos Reunios Florio-Rubattino. - Services Postaux. - Departs de
                        Novembre</p>
                    <p>Les JEUDIS 1, 8, 15, 22, et 29 à 3 h. p.m. direct pour Messine, Naples,
                        Livourne et Gènes </p>
                    <p>Les Jeudis 1 et 15 à 3 h. p.m. direct pour Brindisi, Bari, Ancône et Venise. </p>
                    <p>Les MERCREDIS 14 et 28 à 10 h. a.m. pour les escales de la Syrie at Larnaque. </p>
                    <p>Le LUNDI 12 à 4 b. p.m. pour Port-Saïd, Suez et Massawah. </p>
                    <p>Les MERCREDI 7 et JEUDI 22 à 5 h. p.m. pour Port-Said</p>
                    <p>31-12-906</p>
                    <p>THOS. COOK &amp; SON, (EGYPT) LTD</p>
                    <p>Head Office : LUDGATE CIRCUS, LONDON. CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE:- CAIRO, NEAR
                        SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Port Said, Suez, Luxor, Assuan, Halfa and Khartum. GENERAL
                        RAILWAY AND STEAMSHIP AGENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">BAGGAGE AND FORWARDING AGENTS. Officially appointed &amp;
                            Sole Agents in Cairo to the P, &amp;0, S, N. Co. par</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Large and Splendidly appointed steamers belonging to the Company leave Cairo
                        thrice weekly between November and March for Luxor, Assuan, and Halfa, in
                        connection with Trains de Luxe to Khartum.-Moderate Farēs.</p>
                    <p>Specially Reduced Rates for residents in Egypt by Tourist Services during
                        November and December. First sailing November 13th. WEEKLY FREIGHT SERVICE
                        FROM CAIRO TO ASSUAN AND HALFA.</p>
                    <p>Cook's Interpreters in uniform are present at principal Railway Stations and
                        m Landing-places in Europe to assist passengers holding their tickets.</p>
                    <p>Special Steamers and Dahabeahs for Private Parties, Special arrangements for
                        tour in Palestine, Syria, and the Desert; Lowest rates.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">BEST CAMP EQUIPMENT IN THE COUNTRY.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <!-- insert first ad here -->
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <p> British India S, N. Company, Limited. ended OUTWARD. </p>
                    <p> Fortnightly Service in connection with the Co.'s Indian Mall Lines.-Calling
                        st ADEN, GOLOMBO, MADRAG, and Calcutia Out, and MARSEILLeS (GENOA and
                        PLYMOUTH optional) Home. Sailings from Suex </p>
                    <p> OUTWARD.-S.S.Matiana Nov. 10 | HOMEWARD. — S.S. Golconda Nov. 7 </p>
                    <p> EAST AFRICAN LINE OF STEAMERS. </p>
                    <p> Calling at Aden, Mombasa, Zanzibar and Beira. Monthly service. S.S. Virawa
                        will sail from SUeZ on or about the 8th November. </p>
                    <p> Aden...*** </p>
                    <p>£19. 6 For</p>
                    <p> . 1 Colombo...... 225,15 I Calcutta... </p>
                    <p> 281. 01 First Class Fares from Suez to </p>
                    <p> £11. 8 </p>
                    <p> Madras....... 220.11 | Genon....... 21:10 | Marseilles....... £15.12 -
                        Bombay. </p>
                    <p> 831.10 14 Mombasa.... £26.10 | Zanzibar... </p>
                    <p> From Port Said £2 less Homeward, and £2 more Outward. Second Class, two
                        thirds of 1st Class Fares. PORT SAID Agents: Worms &amp; Co. and will &amp;
                        Co., Ltd. - CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA - Thos, Cook &amp; Bon, Ltd., and
                        AngloAmerican Hotel &amp; Steamer Co. For particulars apply G. BUX </p>
                    <p> 81-12-906 </p>
                    <p> ANCHOR LINE, LIMITED. </p>
                    <p> (HENDERSON BROTHERS,) LONDON, LIVERPOOL AND GLASGOW. </p>
                    <p> Booking Passengers and Cargo through to salung fortnightly from Suoz. </p>
                    <p> throngh to Porta in India, Europe and America First Class Passenger steamers
                        Salling fortnightly from Suex. </p>
                    <p> For MARSEILLES &amp; LIVERPOOL S.S. "Olympia" November 4 </p>
                    <p> For CALOUTTA. S.S. "Bavaria' November 26 </p>
                    <p> For LONDON S.S. "Assyria November 8 </p>
                    <p> For BOMBAY S.S. "Britannia" November 10 </p>
                    <p> Saloon Fares: from Port Faid to Gibraltar 20, Marseilles £9, London and
                        Liverpool £14, add ￡1 to above fare for passengers from Cairo, Ismailia, or
                        Suex, 5% reduction to families of three or more adults, 15% reduction on
                        return tickets within 6 months. Reduced rates on steamers not carrying
                        surgeon and stewardess. </p>
                    <p> (31-12-000] Agents: Cairo, THOS. COOK &amp; SON, Port-Said: CORY BROTHERS
                        &amp; Co. - For partloulars apply C. BEYTS &amp; Co., Suez. </p>
                    <p> Deutsche Levante-Linie </p>
                    <p> Mail and Passenger Steamships. Regular three-weekly Service from HAMBURG via
                        ANTWERP &amp; MALTA, to ALEXANDRIA and vice-vorså, admitting goods from all
                        chief German Railway Stations on direct Bill of Lading to ALEXANDRIA And all
                        chief ports of Egypt, Syria, eto., at favourable rates of DEUTSCHE VERKEHR
                        (traffio).-Steamers expected at Alexandria. </p>
                    <p> Nov. 16 S.S. WOGLINDE from Antwerp. </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">S.S. ANDROS, now in port loading, will sail for Rotterdam
                            &amp; Hamburg on the 31st inst. Por tarif, and particulars apply to
                            ADOLPHE STROSS, Alexandria Agent. 15-9-907</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> DEUTSCHE OST AFRIKA LINIE. </p>
                    <p> Regelmässiger Reichgpostdampferdienst. German E. African Line Imperial
                        Service. Departures from Port Said. (Approximate dates). OUT to Aden,
                        Zanzibar, Cape Town and intermediate ports : </p>
                    <p> S.S. Bürgermeister November 2 | S.S. Koenig November 18 | S.S. Prinzregent
                        November 30 HOME to Naples, Genoa, Marseilles, Algiers, Tangiers, Lisbon,
                        Dover, Flushing, Rotterdam &amp; Hamburg. S.S. Feldmarschal November 7 |
                        S.S. Markgraf November 24 </p>
                    <p> First class steamers fitted with latest improvements. Stewardesses and
                        doctors carried. Low passage rates. xe for </p>
                    <p> Splendid accommodation for passengers of all olasses. For particulars apply
                        to Fix &amp; David, CAIRO (Sharia Munsour Pacha, Telephone 865). </p>
                    <p> Messageries Maritimes </p>
                    <p> Sailing from Alexandria in October, 1906, anaing Tor Marnelle, diroot </p>
                    <p> Rates of DoodAGO no eddah ih Today 2 Nov, At 6 p.m. Rguateur Oapt.
                        Eschenauer </p>
                    <p> Inoluding table wine. Portugal Protot </p>
                    <p> Tora Alexandria or Port Sald Bamers </p>
                    <p> 5 &amp; 16 </p>
                    <p> Niger Bohmita </p>
                    <p> (directly or via Alexandria) Ist Oleg Ind OLL A Congo Baretgo To
                        Marsailles.. . " </p>
                    <p> 01. 2. 29.103 | 80 Equateur Kachenauer </p>
                    <p> Ost ne free. </p>
                    <p> Tor Port Said and Beyrouth Thursday 1 Nov. andria, Nm.m. Portugal Oapt.
                        Protot </p>
                    <p> to Port fald ... ... ... ... 1.16.10. 11.10 Oongo </p>
                    <p> Barotge 12-906 </p>
                    <p> Tor Port Saia, Jamh And Beyrouth Thursday 8 Nov. A i mrd. Nigor OnptBohmits
                        23 </p>
                    <p> . Equateur Eschenauer Through tickets for Paris (14 Marnelles trom
                        Alexandria) </p>
                    <p> 16.13. 1 . 10.12. 6 Through tickets for Paris (vis Marseilles) from Port
                        Bald (direct </p>
                    <p> V A nnars) </p>
                    <p> ... .. . 10. 5.12 . 13. 1. 61 sors) Throngh tickets for London (vis
                        Marseillon) (Olaia-Douvre from Indris or waria *** *** .. ... </p>
                    <p> * 10.12.10 1. 10. 9. &amp; cona 8,900 | Interchangeable return tickets with
                        the Austrian Lloyd Oy. (avallable ono way by Henri*** *** 35,000 Maritimes
                        and on return by Austrian Lloyd) (Via Triesto) ... ... ... ... ... </p>
                    <p> ,, 11.11.10 # 1611 3,000 </p>
                    <p> Sallings from Port Bald in October, 1908. 5 Roturn, </p>
                    <p> Probably on Thnrsday 11 Oct. Polynesien Oapt. Broc returning from Indian
                        Ocean months. </p>
                    <p> Wed, esday </p>
                    <p> Melbourne Lacarriero </p>
                    <p> Ohina Tor Marseillos Bunday </p>
                    <p> Bollior </p>
                    <p> Indian Oooan Diroot. # Sunday </p>
                    <p> Adour Rlquier </p>
                    <p> Ohin nappliana </p>
                    <p> Thursday </p>
                    <p> Salasie Allland </p>
                    <p> Australia om Oniro. </p>
                    <p> Sanings from Sues in October 1906. Thor Adon. Colombo, Singaporo, Baigon,
                        Hong-Kong, Bhans Friday 19 October Tonkin ghal, Kobo and Yokohama ...... </p>
                    <p> Ompt. Charbonnel Tor Djibouti, Colombo, Bingapore, Saigon, Hong Kong orahal,
                        kobo and Yokohama ** </p>
                    <p> Ernest Simone </p>
                    <p> Bourdon ** Tor Djibouti, Zansibar, Mutsamnda, Mayotte, M Norad-Bo, D.Buares,
                        Tamatavo, L. Réunion and Maurloos: Tuesday 16, Djemnal </p>
                    <p> Durrando For Djibouti, Aden, Mahe, Diogo Suares, Bto. Mari La Réunion and
                        Maurios ... .. *** </p>
                    <p> Wodnesday 91 .. Melbourne </p>
                    <p> Lacarrière For Aden, Bombay, Oolombo, Freemantle, Adelaide, Mol. bourno,
                        Sidney, And Noumen . .. ... ... ... Monday 29, Villa de la Ciotat Calro
                        Agency (Bhophoard's Hotel) </p>
                    <p>28-2-007</p>
                    <p> Boyroath </p>
                    <p>:21:1:: 3.5</p>
                    <p> St </p>
                    <p> Yarra </p>
                    <p> Friday </p>
                    <p> .. </p>
                    <p> PRINCE LINE. </p>
                    <p> 8,000 </p>
                    <p> 8,000 </p>
                    <p> 4,660 </p>
                    <p>prus £2</p>
                    <p>4,650 4,600</p>
                    <p> 3,050 </p>
                    <p>......</p>
                    <p>....</p>
                    <p> " </p>
                    <p> 10 </p>
                    <p> id and -12-906 Atrioon Prince............... Tons 8,000 Welsh
                        Prinoo.................. Tons 8,000 Algban Prinoo................. Tons
                        8,000 </p>
                    <p> Chineso Prince (bldg)...... 8,000 Japanese Prinoo (bldg)... 8,000 Burmese
                        Prince (bldg).... Korean Prince (bldg)..... </p>
                    <p> Arabian Prinoo (bldg)...... </p>
                    <p> 8,000 </p>
                    <p> Siamoso Prinoo (bldg)....... 8,000 d. Swedish Prince (bldg)...... </p>
                    <p> 8,000 Black Prince........... </p>
                    <p> 7,000 Saxon Prince.......... Tudor Prince........ </p>
                    <p> 7,000 </p>
                    <p> Norman Prince............ 6,000 Crown Prinoo................. ItAlan
                        Prince........ </p>
                    <p> 6,000 </p>
                    <p> Georgian Prince.............. 4,750 Trojan Prinos.................. 4,750
                        Tuesday Morohant Prince......... Sallor PH 06.....*.****** </p>
                    <p> Egyptian Prince............ 4,650 Soldier Prince.............. </p>
                    <p> 4,660 Russian Princo........ </p>
                    <p> Spartan Prince ......... </p>
                    <p> 4,476 Mexdoan Prince...... </p>
                    <p> 4,420 Highland Prince........ 3,860 Imperial Prince.......... </p>
                    <p> 3,760 31-12-06 Sioillan Prince....... 3,760 Napolitan Prince......... 3,760
                        Persian Prinoo......... </p>
                    <p> 3,250 British Prinoo...... </p>
                    <p> 3,180 Moorish Prince......... 3,180 Castillan Prinoo........ 3,100 Grecian
                        Prince... 3,076 Lastern Prince.......... </p>
                    <p> Asiatlo Prince........... 3,060 Creole Prince......... 3,050 Carib
                        Prince..... ******* </p>
                    <p> 3,060 KoMr Prinoo................. </p>
                    <p> 3,060 Syrian Princo........ </p>
                    <p> 2,960 Orange Prinoo........... 3,876 Cyprian. Prince.......... 2,760 Indian
                        Prince.......... </p>
                    <p> 2,780 Soottish Prinoo...... 2,660 Roman Princo........ </p>
                    <p> 3,880 Tuscan Prince................. 3,676 Odoan Prinoo...... </p>
                    <p> 2,400 Royal Prince....... </p>
                    <p> 12,400 ERPOOL </p>
                    <p> Good Accommodation for Passengers. </p>
                    <p> Sailings every 10 days from Manchester and Liverpool and fortnightly from
                        Antwerp and London to Alexandria and Syrian Coast. The dates are approximate </p>
                    <p> Creole Prince due from Antwerp &amp; London Oct. 27 | Persian Princo due
                        from Dunkirk &amp; London Nov. 9 </p>
                    <p> Cyprian Prince “” Manchester Nov. 3| British Prince “”Tyne Nov.10 </p>
                    <p> Moorish Prince “” Antwerp and London Nov. 6| Ocean Prince “” Manchester
                        Nov.10 </p>
                    <p> The S.S. Sailor Prince is now loading for Manchester, and will be followed
                        by the S.S. Carib Prince. </p>
                    <p> For terms of freight or passage apply to O. J. Graco &amp; Co., Alexandria,
                        Agente. 31.12.906 </p>
                    <p> The Ellerman Lines, Limited. </p>
                    <p> (Including Westcott &amp; Laurance Line.) </p>
                    <p> Regular sailings from Liverpool, Glasgow, Antwerp and London to Alexandria.
                        Frequent </p>
                    <p> sailings from Alexandria to Liverpool and London. Through freight rates to
                        Inland towns in Great Britain, also to the U. S. A. </p>
                    <p> Ellerman S.S. Arabian expected from Liverpool, Lisbon; Gibraltar &amp; Malta
                        about Oct. 31. Westcott S.S. Gulf of Suez expected from Antwerp, London
                        &amp; Malta about Nov. 4. Westcott S.S. Adalia expected from Antwerp, London
                        &amp; Malta about ........ </p>
                    <p> Ellerman S.S. Britannia expected from Liverpool, Gibraltar &amp; Malta about
                        ...... </p>
                    <p> The Ellerman S.S. Persian, now on the berth for Liverpool, will sail on the
                        31st inst. to be </p>
                    <p> followed by the S.S. City of Venice. PT) 20-2-907 </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">N. E.TAMVACO, Alexandria Agent.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> CUNARD LINE. 19-1-007 </p>
                    <p> Frequent sailings of cargo steamers from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL. Through
                        Bills of Lading to towns in the Interior and to the United States ports. </p>
                    <p> Sailings of ROYAL MAIL passenger steamers from LIVERPOOL to New-YORK and
                        BOSTON in Saturdays and Tuesdays. </p>
                    <p> Regular twin-screw passenger service between TRIESTE, FIUME, NAPLES and
                        New-YORK, </p>
                    <p> All passenger steamers fitted with Marconi's wireless telegraphy. For
                        through tickets from Egypt and particulars, apply to the Agents : </p>
                    <p> RODOCANACHI &amp; Co., Alexandria; NICOLAS KIRGIS, Cairo ; R. BROADBENT,
                        Port Said </p>
                    <p>Les Diamants “BERA" </p>
                    <p>La Meilleure Imitation du Monde</p>
                    <p> Afin de les faire rapidement connaitre au public, nous avons mis en vente un
                        nombre limité de ces merveilleuses et brillantes pierre montées sur de
                        superbes, Bagaes, Broobos, Boucles d'oreille, Epingles de cravate, Boutons
                        de manobette eto. etc., au prix de </p>
                    <p> P.T. la piece monture compriso </p>
                    <p> Catalogues gratis et franco sur demande BERA AMERICAN DIAMOND PALACE </p>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIE, CHERIF PACHA STREET 29. </p>
                    <!-- second column of ads -->
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <p> HAMBURG &amp; ANGLO-AMERICAN NILE Co. </p>
                    <p> Weekly departure during Winter Season by the Luxurious First Class Tourist
                        Steamers VICTORIA, PURITAN &amp; MAYFLOWER, </p>
                    <p> Regular weekly Departure to the SECOND CATARACT by the S.S. INDIANA. THROUGH
                        BOOKINGS TO KHARTOUM, GONDOKORO AND THE WHITE NILE. </p>
                    <p> Steamers and Dahabonha for private charter. SteamTugs and Steam Launches or
                        hire. FREIGHT SERVICE BY STEAM BARGES BETWEEN CAIRO AND ALEXANDRIA. </p>
                    <p> Working in conjunction and under special arrangement with the "Upper Egypt
                        Hotels Company." For details and illustrated programmes apply to "THE
                        HAMBURG and ANGLO-AMERICAN NILE COMPANY" </p>
                    <p> OFFICES IN CAIRO: Sharia Boulac, "Grand Continental Hotel Buildings."
                        Hamburg-Amerika Linie. Accelerated Service by S.Y, OCEANA of 8,000 Tons, 350
                        berths including 90 single cabins. </p>
                    <p>Greatest Comfort, Best Cuisine,</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">FARES : to NAPLES from £12, to Genoa from £15. </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Leaves Alexandria : </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">10 and 24 November</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">8 and 22 December</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">12,19 and 26 January</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">2, 9, 16, 23 February </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">2, 9, 16 23, 30 Marrch</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">6,13,27 April</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">11 May.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Arr, Naples :</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> 13 and 27 November </p>
                    <p> 11 and 25 December </p>
                    <p> 15, 22, and 29 January </p>
                    <p> 5, 12, 19, 26 February </p>
                    <p> 5, 12, 19, 26 March </p>
                    <p> 2, 9, 16, 30 April </p>
                    <p> 14 May </p>
                    <p> Arr. Genoa: </p>
                    <p> 14 and 23 November </p>
                    <p> 12 and 26 December </p>
                    <p> 17 April </p>
                    <p> 1 and 5 May </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">From Port Said to Naples &amp; Hamburg : Dec. 1, Jan. 12.
                            Feb. 9, March 9, April 20, May 4, June 16, July 13, Apply to:
                            HAMBURG-AMERICA LINIE, Continental Hotel, Cairo. C.), GRACE &amp; Co.,
                            ALEXANDRIA. DEUTSCHES KOHLEN DEPOT, PORT SAID &amp; SUEZ.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> 31-3-07 </p>
                    <p> NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD. </p>
                    <p> Weekly Service from ALEXANDRIA (Passenger and Freight) to NAPLES-MARSEILLEB.
                        Schleswig leaves Alexandria 3 p.m. 16 &amp; 28 November ; 12 December
                        Hohenzollern leaves Alexandria 3 pm, 7&amp;31 November ; 3 December. </p>
                    <p> Royal Roumanian Express Steamer Service from ALEXANDRIA to SMYRNA,
                        CONSTANTINOPLE and CONSTANZA. </p>
                    <p> Weekly departures from Alexandria every Wednesday at 6 p.m. with the new
                        twin screw steamers Regele Carol I., </p>
                    <p> Roumania, and Imperatul Trajan.The following steamers are Intended to leave.
                        PORT-SAID: HOWYWARD: for Bromonor Hamburg vla Naples, Glenon, (Gibraltar),
                        Southampton, Antwerp. </p>
                    <p> Gaoisenau 8091 Tons ... about 31 Oct | Prinx Ludwig 8000 Tons . ... about 16
                        Nov. </p>
                    <p> Gora 5006 “” . 16 Nov. | Prinx Alice 10911 30 </p>
                    <p> OUTWARD for CHINA and JAPAN VIA BURZ, ADIN, mburg. OOLOMBO, PINANG,
                        BINGAPORL TO </p>
                    <p> For AUSTRALIA VIA SUKK, ADIN, COLOMBO | Pr. Rog. Luitpold 6288 Tona </p>
                    <p> Aboat 29 Oot. Barbaros </p>
                    <p> 10916 Tons </p>
                    <p> we Aboal 10 Nov. ratos. Prins L. Friedrich 8866 </p>
                    <p> 13 Nov. Sobarnhorst </p>
                    <p> 10 Doo, </p>
                    <p> 35). </p>
                    <p> FOR FUBTRLA PARTIOULARS APPLY TO TI AGENTS OF TE NORDDEUTROFIE ILOYD at
                        Oatro, Alcarandria, Port Said and soon </p>
                    <p> TDIQ, Asant la Ontry, Open Square.. </p>
                    <p> a in Alendri Cleopatra Lang. 80-10-900 Mour. TEOS, OOOK SE </p>
                    <p> aromathorined to I Hatta OATRO and AL </p>
                    <p>4. DOLO 777</p>
                    <p> D M </p>
                    <p> Ps </p>
                    <p> Austrian Lloyd's Steam Navigation </p>
                    <p> Alexandria-Brindisi-Trieste (Venice ). </p>
                    <p> Weekly Express Mail Service. Steamers leave Alexandria every Saturday 4 p.m.
                        arrive Brindisi Tuesday 5 a.m. in time for Express to Milan, Lucerne, Paris,
                        Vienna, Berlin and London, leaving Brindisi at 7 am Arrival Trieste every
                        Wednesday about 11 a.m. in connection with Train de Luxe Trieste-Vienna
                        Ostendo. Passengers roach London every Friday 4.50 p.m. </p>
                    <p> Oct. 6 4 p.m. S.S. Semiramis Capt. Martinellob | Nov. 3 4 p.m. S.S.
                        Cleopatra Capt, Ivellieh </p>
                    <p> “ 13 “ “ Cleopatra “ Ivellieh “ 10 “ “ Habsburg “ Klausberger </p>
                    <p> “ 20 “ “ Habsburg “ Klausberger “ 17 “ “ Semiramis “ martinelick </p>
                    <p> “ 27 “ “ Semiramis “ Martinelich “ 24 “” Cleopatra “ Ivellich </p>
                    <p> Weekly Intermediate Service i Alexandria-Brindlal &amp; Trieste Line. </p>
                    <p> Steamers leave Alexandria every Wednesday at 4p.m. arrive Brindisi Sunday at
                        5 a.m. Trieste Tuesday 6 a.m; </p>
                    <p> Syrian-Cyprua Caramanlan|Lino, Steamer leaves Alexandria on or about 22
                        October, 5 and 19 November, 3, 17 and 31 December. </p>
                    <p>Syrian-Caramanlan Line. Steamer leaves Alexandria on or about 29 October, 12
                        and 26 November, 10 and 24 December.</p>
                    <p> Far East Lines. Departures from Port Said : To Suez, Aden, Bombay, Colombo,
                        Penan, Singapore, Hong-Kong, Shanghai, </p>
                    <p> Yokohama and Kobe, 3 November.. To Suez, Aden and Bombay accelerated service
                        about 8 Nov., 8 Deo. To Suez, Aden, Karachi, Colombo, Madras, Rangoon and
                        Calcutta about 19 Oct., 3, 19 Nov., 19 Deo, 4 p. To Suez, Aden, Karachi and
                        Bombay about 13 November, 1 December (Winter Lino). </p>
                    <p> East African Line. Departures from Port Said · To Suez, Adon, Mombassa,
                        Zanzibar, Beira, Delagoa-Bay and Durban </p>
                    <p> about 2 Nov., 3 December </p>
                    <p> For information apply to the Agents, Alexandria, Port Said and Suoz, Trog.
                        Coox &amp; Son, Leon HELLER, Cairo Agent, 24, Sharia Maghraby, (Telephone
                        192), Cairo ; F. TEDESCHI, Helovan. </p>
                    <p> special rates for Egyptan officials, members of Army of Occupation and their
                        families 8112-90 </p>
                    <p>RUSSIAN. STEAM NAVIGATION &amp; COMMERCIAL COMPANY</p>
                    <p> Postal Service Accelerated from the 1st June, 1906.. between Alexandris,
                        Piræus, Constantinople, and Odessa by the following recently built and
                        perfectly equipped vessels : n Emperor Aloolas 1.... *** *** 1010 tons |
                        Feari. H </p>
                    <p> Arrivals at Alexandria on Friday morning. Departures from Alexandria on
                        Tuesdays at 3 p.m. Circular route between Alexandria, Port Said, the Syrian
                        ports, Chio, Smyrna, Salonica, </p>
                    <p> Mount Athos, Dardanelles, Constantinople, and Odessa. Arrivals at Alexandria
                        every other </p>
                    <p> Saturday early in the morning. Departures from Alexandria same day in
                        afternoon at 4 p.m. 3,100 </p>
                    <p> ORIMEAN OR BESSARABIAN TABLE WINES FREE. </p>
                    <p> 38376-31-11-801 </p>
                    <p> Ellermans City Line </p>
                    <p> Ellermans City and Hall LIne </p>
                    <p> The undermentioned First Class Passenger Steamers will be dispatched from
                        Port Said on or about the following dates for </p>
                    <p> Malta and Londos S.S. CITY OF SPARTA Nov. 81 Marseilles &amp; Liverpool
                        Drorimsto Colombo &amp; Jaloutta.... S.S. CITY OF CORDITE Nov. 4 | Bombay
                        &amp; Karaoh ... S.S. CITY OR York November 11 Nov. 9 </p>
                    <p> Saloon Fares-Port Said to Malta ￡10.0.0 Marseilles, ￡12.12.0 London or
                        Liverpool, £12.13.0 Colombo, Oleathe Bombay or Karnahi, 436.0.0, Special
                        natos for stonmons not carrying Doctor of Btowarde Jor farther m ontan t </p>
                    <p> CORY BROS. &amp; Co., Ltd., Agents for Cry Line, Port Said ; W. STAPLEDON
                        &amp; Bon, Agente he S.S. HALL Line, Port Said ; or COOK &amp; Son (Bgypt),
                        Ltd., Cairo. </p>
                    <p> 28-3-907 12.906 </p>
                    <p> Egyptian State Railways. </p>
                    <p> .m </p>
                    <p> . </p>
                    <p> noon </p>
                    <p> Ep.m. </p>
                    <p> p.m. </p>
                    <p> p. me </p>
                    <p> p.ma, </p>
                    <p> 5.50 </p>
                    <p> 1.m, </p>
                    <p> p.m. </p>
                    <p> ed. THROUGH PASSENGER SERVICES. (Daily).-OCTOBER TIME-TABLE. </p>
                    <p> p.m. aquant Cairo ........ </p>
                    <p> DEP.1 7.801 9.30 1312.00+ | 18.1514 0 4.50 16.35 $11.30 was in </p>
                    <p> p.m. Tantah.......... ARR. 8.51 10.53 1 20. 2.80 5.28 </p>
                    <p> 18.1 Alexandria ... ARR. / 11.00 | 12.55 3.5 | </p>
                    <p> 7.35 7.50 10. 5 6 . O Doon p.m. 1 </p>
                    <p> pom Alexandria ... DEP. </p>
                    <p> It 12.001 2.10 3.40 </p>
                    <p> 01811.80 p.ma, </p>
                    <p> S . . to be Tantah... ARB. 8.59 10.58 1.40 5.24 5.40 </p>
                    <p> 7.61 8. 18 Cairo ... ARR. | 10.25 | 12.20 3.5 </p>
                    <p> 7.10 </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">9.20 6.0 gont.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> DEP. 7.0 11.01 f6.15 Port Said . DEP. </p>
                    <p> p.be Port Said </p>
                    <p> ARR. 12. 51 3.30 11. 0 Cairo ... ... ABR. I 1.25 -5.0 11.25 8-1-007 </p>
                    <p> A.m. p.m. co towns Cairo ... ... ... DEP. ||11.01 16.15 </p>
                    <p> DEP. I †11.0t | +6.15 For Sue Suez (Rue Colmar DEP. 7.89 [ 15.891 Vor Oslo </p>
                    <p> | change p.m. 1 p.m. </p>
                    <p> pom, Saez (Rae Colmar). ARB. 4.12 | 11.3 Iamailia I Cairo ...... ARR. 1.95
                        11.25 Lamellia </p>
                    <p>..... DEP. "Too</p>
                    <p>9.9.2017 12.001 | 1 To 5.70 | 21254 | Foo slirao</p>
                    <p> p.m. </p>
                    <p>... ARR.</p>
                    <p> 7.25 </p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p> 1 </p>
                    <p> m. </p>
                    <p> p.m </p>
                    <p> Cairo </p>
                    <p> - </p>
                    <p>5.10 117.80| +6.764</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">p.m.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p> p.m. </p>
                    <p> 1 </p>
                    <p> p.m. </p>
                    <p> TON </p>
                    <p> 0. </p>
                    <p> a.m. </p>
                    <p> Am. Am. 1 p.m. 1 p.m. </p>
                    <p> m: 1 Am. I pom ypt and Cairo ... ... DEP. | 7.45 11.30 2.40 5.25 Zagazig
                        DEP. 6. 08.4 </p>
                    <p> 11.4516 p.m. Zagazig.. ... ARR. | 9.44 1.40 4.45 7.27 Cairo. ARR. 8. 0 10.45
                        11.50 18.201 (Vis Bolbeis) </p>
                    <p> (Vis Belbeis) Am. 1 p.m. </p>
                    <p> p. Cairo... .. DEP. 8.30 - 8. o Laxor </p>
                    <p> DEP. </p>
                    <p> *5.80 </p>
                    <p> p.m. Wasta.. ... ... ... ... ARR. 9.55 9.30 Wasta ... ... ... ... ARR. 7.11
                        3.87 </p>
                    <p>p.m. am, Luxor.. ... ARR. (11.35 10. o| Cairo.. ... ... ...</p>
                    <p> | 8.46 7.8 6 1 Dining Oar. $ Bleeping Oar, First and Second Olass only, </p>
                    <p> Dining and Sleeping Uars are attached to these trains on the following
                        days:- From Cairo, every Monday, WedACHON And Saturday. From Luxor, overy
                        Tuosday, Thursday and Sunday : </p>
                    <p> G. B. MACAULEY • </p>
                    <p> Ganeral Manager. </p>
                    <p> le </p>
                    <p> GELLATLY, HANKEY &amp; CO. </p>
                    <p> monture </p>
                    <p> SHIPOWNERS, OF LONDON. BRANCHES ATPORT SUDAN, SUAKIN &amp; JEDDAH
                        Morobandise, furniture, baggage and personal effects forwarded, and
                        inspranoes effooted to all parts of the world. </p>
                    <p> 97876-88-8-907 </p>
                    <!-- third column of ads -->
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" status="verified">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Royal Insurance Co.</p>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE. Largest. Fire Office in the World. </p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria. 81-8-907</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.'. PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782); HASELDEN &amp; Co., Agents, Alexandria. FRED. OTT &amp;
                        CO., Sub-Agents, Cairo</p>
                    <p>THE PERFECTION OF QUALITY AND VALUE. --</p>
                    <p>In Sterling Silver, "Welbook” &amp; Silver Plated Goods</p>
                    <p>Provisions, Wines, Oigars, Brookery, Brushes, &amp;o., &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>"ECONOMICAL STORES” CAIRO AND ALEXAND?</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. CAFFARI'S</p>
                    <p>PRICE LIST ON APPLICATION.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Direction der Disconto-Gesellschaft</p>
                    <p>Berlin - Bremen - Frankfurt a. M. - London.</p>
                    <p>Capital (fully paid-up). M 170 000 000 . Reserve Fund ... M 57 600 000</p>
                    <p>Represented at Hamburg by the Norddeutsche Bank in Hamburg.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">The bank transacts general banking business of every
                            description and acts as</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>representative of the following foreign banks : Brasilianische Bank für
                        Deutschland of Hamburg, with branches at Rio de 7</p>
                    <p>Janeiro, Sao Paulo, Santos and Porto Alegre. Bank für Chile und Deutschland
                        of Hamborg, with branches at Valparaiso,</p>
                    <p>Santiago, Concepcion, Temuco, Antofagasta, La Paz and Oruro. Ernesto
                        Tornquist &amp; Co. Baenos Aires. Deutsch-Asiatische Bank of Shanghai, with
                        branches at Berlin, Calcutta, Han</p>
                    <p>kow, Hongkong, Kobe, Peking, Tientsin, Tsinanta, Tsingtan, Yokohama. Banoa
                        Generala Romana of Bakarest, with branches at Braila, Crajova and</p>
                    <p>Agencies at Constantza, Ploesti, Giurgiu. Kreditna Banka (Banque de Credit)
                        at Sofia, with a branch at Varna. Deutsche Afrika-Bank, Hamborg, with
                        brazches at Swakopmund, Windbuk and</p>
                    <p>Lüderitzbacht (South West Africa).</p>
                    <p>90798-1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Photographers. REISER &amp; BINDER Photographers</p>
                    <p>26848</p>
                    <p>Alexandria &amp; Cairo</p>
                    <p>4-12-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>N. SPATHIS.</head>
                    <p>CAIRO AND ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>N.B. - This Whisky is the same as supplied to the Red Cross Society London,
                        for use by the invalided troops, and hospitals in South Africa, to the of
                        House Lords and House of Commons</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>“AU DE ROUGE”</head>
                    <p>GENERAL DRAPERY ESTABLISHMENT. (CENTRAL TRAMWAY STATION, )</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Sudan Agent:- ANGELO CAPATO, Khartoum.</p>
                    <p>26985-21.12.90</p>
                    <p>P. PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTERS OF BRITISH AND IRISH</p>
                    <p>TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>NOW ON SALE Large assortment of plain and striped Flannelette, Oxfords, Nun's
                        veilings, Cashmeres, Meltons, and Woollen dress goods.</p>
                    <p>All Excellent Value.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPÉCIAL APPOINTMENT TO</p>
                    <p>HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT IN EGYPT AND SUDAN. NICOLA G. SABBAG,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>2, Rue de la Gare du Caire.</p>
                    <p>Telephone 559. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>What is Whisky? </p>
                    <p>“Sandy Macdonald” 10 years ols is the Finest Matured Scotch Malt</p>
                    <p>Whiskey Highest Awards</p>
                    <p>MACDONALD&amp;CO. Sharia El MaghraBY'</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>18-1-907</p>
                    <p>28398-31-8-90</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BRASS DOOR PLATES</head>
                    <p>WITH MAHOGANY BLOCK READY FOR FIXING TO DOOR, V WAL OR GATE J.MARGOSCHES
                        BULAC ROAD.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Draught Beer for the Home.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">KÜPPER'S BEER IN SIPHONS. 5 Litre Siphon per P.T. 20.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">10 Litre Siphons per P.T. 35 Delivered Free.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>'SOLE AGENTS : Walker &amp; Meimarachi, Ltd. THB EGYPTIAN SUPPLY STORES.</p>
                    <p>„Frisch vom Fass“.</p>
                    <p>36898-30.4.907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Eastern Exchange Hotel,</p>
                    <p>PORT SAID. FIRST CLASS HOTEL MODERN IN ALL RESPECTS.</p>
                    <p>Fire-proof, Drained to the sea, Lifts, Electric Light, English and French
                        Billiards, Fresh and Salt Water Baths. The Coolest Summer Residence in
                        Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Special terms to Cairo Residente and their families desirous of en. joying
                        the cool air and sea bathing during the summer months. Hotel Dragomans in
                        Onlfort meet all</p>
                    <p>Trains and Steamers.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HOTEL BEAU-RIVAGE.</head>
                    <p>RAMLEH.--Most charming Seaside Residence in Egypt 15 Minutes by Carriage or
                        "Palais"</p>
                    <p>tram from Sidi Gaber Station First Class Family Hotel with every Modern
                        Comfort. Unique situation on the Beach.</p>
                    <p>Lovely Garden. Lawn Tennis. Large Terrace, Electric Light. Own springs.
                        Perfect sanitary arrangements, tables for horses and carriage. 'Moderate
                        Oharges. - Special terms for Government Officials and Officers of the Army
                        of Occupation Telegraphic Address: BEAURIVAGE, Ramleh.--Telephone : 186,
                        Ramleh. G. &amp; M. RUNKEWITZ, Proprietor</p>
                    <p>16-1-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PORT SAID-SAVOY HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>NEW FIRST-CLASS HOTEL, OVERLOOKING THE HARBOUR &amp; OPPOSITE CUSTOM
                        HOUSE</p>
                    <p>Open all the year round. Well-appointed Bar. Electric Light. MODERATE
                        CHARGES. SPECIAL TERMS FOR RESIDENTS.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>First-class Hotel, Situated in Rosetta Avenue, the finest quarter in the
                        Town. Renovated Throughout. Two minutes from Railway Station. Close to
                        Consulates and Opera House. Electric Lift. Perfect Sanitary Arrangements.
                        Magnificent Ball, Reception, Reading, and Music Rooms. Bar and Smoking Room.
                        FINE TERRACE ON THE AVENUE. MOTOR BUS MEETS ALL TRAINS AND STEAMERS. MANAGER
                        FI REINSPERCER. 31-8-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEWAR'S WHISKY</head>
                    <p>18-12-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MCLAREN'S STEAM PLOUGHS</head>
                    <p>SUITABLE FOR EVERY DESCRIPTION OF SOIL AND OROP. KESTABLISHED</p>
                    <p>1876. IMPROVED COMPOUSD</p>
                    <p>ENGINES. Balance, Ploughs</p>
                    <p>Turning CULTIVATORS.</p>
                    <p>Harrows. Water Carts.</p>
                    <p>STEEL ROPES of very best quality CATALOGUES</p>
                    <p>POST FREE ON APPLICATION TO</p>
                    <p>J. &amp; H, MCLAREN MIDLAND ENGINE WORKS Codes used, A.B.C. 4th and 5th
                        editions, LIEBERS.</p>
                    <p>ENGLAND. Cable Address "McLAREN LEEDS".</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MODERN OFFICES ON THE SHANNON SYSTEM.</head>
                    <p>OPENING SHORTLY. NEW PREMISES in Sharia el Madabegh, Cairo (opposite
                        British</p>
                    <p>Consulate), also Warehouse in Alexandria. EXPERT ADVICE. – EXPERT PLANNING.
                        SPECIALITIES: Office Furniture.</p>
                    <p>Letter Filing Cabinets.</p>
                    <p>Couches and Chairs. COMPLETE EQUIPMENT ON MODERN LINES.</p>
                    <p>THE SHANNON LIMITED, P.O. Box 1078, CAIRO.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> Grands Magasins du Louvre, Paris.</p>
                    <p>L'Agence Generale d'Egypte a Alexandrie, Rue de la Porte Rosette No. 6, a
                        l'honneur de prévenir sa Clientèle d'Egypte qu'elle vient de recevoir les
                        échantillons et ca! alogues de la Saison d'Hiver qui sont
                        délivrés.gratuitecent on onvovés sans frais par la poste à toote personne
                        qni en fera la demande. Un très bel a38ortimeut de jupons, poignoirs,
                        corsages, bonneterio, fichue, parapluies, parfumerie et article de Paris est
                        également mis en vente por place.</p>
                    <p>Tous nos envois pour Alexindrie et le Caire sont expédiés franco de port,
                        quel qu'on soit | le montant, à l'exception des articles lourds et
                        encombrants qui ne sont expédiés franco quo jusqu'au port
                        d'embarquement.</p>
                    <p>Toutes nos marchandises sont marquées et facturées aux mêmes prix qu'à Paris.
                        Les N. droits de douane sont à ajouter aux prix irdiqnés.</p>
                    <p>28708-4*.3</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAPITALIST</head>
                    <p>wanted with £12,000 for Cigarette Factory, exporting approximately 12
                        millions of cigarettes a year. Yearly revenụe probably 20%, as per last
                        balance.</p>
                    <p>Please address letters F. D. S. c/o Egyptian | Gazette offices.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>YOST</head>
                    <p>THE TYPEWRITER PAR EXCELLENCE,</p>
                    <p>Illustrated Catalogue on application. </p>
                    <p>Machines on trial from:Sole Agents : Messrs. THOMAS HINSHELWOOD &amp;
                        Co..</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>CALLARD and BOWSERS</p>
                    <p>BUTTER - SCOTCH </p>
                    <p>(The Celebrated Sweet for Children)</p>
                    <p>This popular English Sweettreat can be obtained </p>
                    <p>Mr. OABONIS, ANGLO-Aamous Broms, Port-Bald.</p>
                    <p>DROITRIADES, Monori. TANOBID BONNICI &amp; Co., </p>
                    <p>The PATIBBIRI DI LA BOUBAR, Bue Oborti peab</p>
                    <p>Alexandrian. • Manntastory : London, England</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHOOTING SEASON 1906-1907.</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Salt &amp; Soda Co., Ltd. </p>
                    <p>HAS ON SALE A LARGE STOCK. OF </p>
                    <p>BEST ENGLISH LOADED SPORTING CARTRIDGES : </p>
                    <p>AMBERITE, SMOKELESS DIAMOND,</p>
                    <p>SCHULTZE, and E.C.</p>
                    <p>For all particulars apply to the Office of the evidence of awakening
                        interest. The Britisher Company, Boulak, Cairo. 28884-28-2-807 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="weather">
                    <head>DAILY WEATHER REPORT</head>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Kom-al-Nadoara Observatory.</p>
                    <p>Direction of wind ... … NE</p>
                    <p>Force of Anemometer ... </p>
                    <p>State of Sea..Calm</p>
                    <p>Barometer corrector..763.6</p>
                    <p>Evaporation. .. .. ..</p>
                    <p>State of Olondo ... ... ...clouded</p>
                    <p>Max. Temp. in the shade ...</p>
                    <p>Daring Min. do. do.</p>
                    <p>24 hours Humidity of the air ... ... ending &amp; a.m. Heat of the sun
                        ......</p>
                    <p>Rainfall in inches ...</p>
                    <p>Moon rises 6. p.m. O Bota 6.13 a.m.</p>
                    <p>REMARKS.</p>
                    <p>The weather remains cool and pleasant. A light N.E. breeze is blowing and the
                        barometer is steady.</p>
                    <p>OTHER STATIONS. OBSERVATIONS BY SURVEY DEPARTMENT.</p>
                    <p>For the 24 hours ending 8 a.m. yesterday.</p>
                    <p> Max. | Min.</p>
                    <p>Max.</p>
                    <p>Min. temp. temp. Stations.in the in the shade.</p>
                    <p>shado. shade.</p>
                    <p>t $ Port Said....... Merowe.......</p>
                    <p>Atbara.........</p>
                    <p>(Helouan.. Buskin ....</p>
                    <p>S | Ghizoh..... Khartoum.. </p>
                    <p> Ansioat ....... Wad Medan</p>
                    <p>Dueim.....</p>
                    <p>Wady Halfa .. 8017 </p>
                    <p> FOREIGN STATIONS.</p>
                    <p>Stations. Barom. Wind Topm, State of Sea</p>
                    <p>Triesto....</p>
                    <p>783.1</p>
                    <p>Almost 10 Calm Malta.........</p>
                    <p>767.8</p>
                    <p>Very Tel el Kebir.</p>
                    <p>rough Brindisi................. 781.4 Light</p>
                    <p>Athens ........</p>
                    <p>763.6 Fresh</p>
                    <p>Rather</p>
                    <p>rough Limassol 761.7 Calm 26</p>
                    <p>PHASES OF THE MOON. THE SUN.Rises a.m. Sets p.m.</p>
                    <p>Oct. Full Moon 3.48 p.m. 6.19 3.41 </p>
                    <p>0 Last Quarter 6.39 p.m. 6.83</p>
                    <p>6.31 </p>
                    <p>.. 18 New Moon 0.43 a.m. 6.50</p>
                    <p>, 34 First Quarter 3.60 p.m. 6.8</p>
                    <p>8.16 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUBSCRIPTIONS,</head>
                    <p>Alexandria, Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including delivery
                        in Alexandria postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231} per annum, P.T. 116
                        for six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries in the Postal
                        Union P.T. 273 (£2.168.) per annum. Six months P.T. 136} (£1.88.), three
                        months P.T. 95 (0.198.).</p>
                    <p>N.B.-Subscriptions commence, from the 1st or 18th of each month.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS. P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages or
                        Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20. Every additional line P.T. 10.
                        Notices in news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for standing </p>
                    <p> ADVERTISEMENTS and SUBSCRIPTIONS </p>
                    <p>are due in advance. P.O. Orders and Cheques to be made payable to the Editor
                        and Manager, ROWLAND SNELLING, Alexandria </p>
                    <p>London Corrospondent's Offices.-36, New Broad </p>
                    <p>Stroot, B.O. Cairo Offices. -No. Sharia Zervudachi. (opposite the
                        Agricultural Bank</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE IS PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE
                        LONDON PAPER MILLS Co., LIMITED SÅLES OTTICE: 87, CANNON STREET, LO,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette..</p>
                    <p>THE ENGLISH DAILY NEWSPAPER</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED 1880.</p>
                    <p>Editor and Manager ... R. SIELLIG </p>
                    <p>Price: ONE PIASTRE TARIFP. </p>
                    <p>WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 31, 1906 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LONDON PRESS ON EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>So great is the interest now being taken in Egypt by the home Press, that
                        certain London </p>
                    <p>papers have expressed their intention to send out special correspondents to
                        study the affairs of the country. Up to the present we have | always
                        considered that the average Britisher showed a remarkable ignorance of this
                        country, in spite of its importance both politically and commercially, and
                        we are glad to observe any : has for long been accused, and to a large
                        measure rightly, of lack of enterprise, and the business man of Egypt
                        especially grumbles at his hesitation co put British goods on the market
                        here and the restrictions with which he hedges round his would-be agents. On
                        every side we see foreign firms creeping in where we should have come in
                        first, and, though we hardly agree with the pessimists who prognosticate the
                        day when Great Britain will be a secondary or even tertiary commercial power
                        in Egypt, we fully agree with those who say that the Old Country fails to
                        realise what an enormous field is open to her song. The London journalists
                        who are about to visit this country have, therefore, a great and serious
                        opportunity before them, and we await the results of their visits with
                        interest and even with anxiety. The political and commercial affairs of
                        Egypt are not such as can be grasped by a cursory glance. Writers of
                        such</p>
                    <p>articles as we look forward to reading must, necessarily, generalise and this
                        entails doep study and searching inquiry among competent</p>
                    <p>men who know the country au fond, as far as that is possible. It is only in
                        such a way that in the articles can be made of real value..</p>
                    <p>We do not give this warning without reason.About a fortnight ago there
                        appeared in a prominent London paper an article of a column 2 and a half
                        purporting to deal with the future in Egypt. If the writer's idea was to
                        provide the reading public with facts which might indicate to them what the
                        future of Egypt is likely to be, he failed miserably. The article, in feed,
                        is chiefly remarkable for its verbosity, and a considerable part of it is
                        devoted to a picturesque description of a journey which he made to Zagazig
                        and a hardly more à propos</p>
                    <p>account of an interview which he had with an officer who served under Arabi
                        Pasha at the article there is much fault to be found, As an opening sentence
                        the writers says: "Ten</p>
                    <p>years ago Egypt was a country of the dead.”.All who have studied this country
                        must know that in 1896, during which year her revenues totalled L.E.
                        10,260,000, she was very much alive, and had already made a good stride
                        1towards her present-day prosperity. Ten years ago her imports showed an
                        increase over the previous year of L.E. 1,271,000 and her</p>
                    <p>exports an increase of L.E. 568,000. Ten years ago Egypt exported 4,008,000
                        cantars of cotton, an increase of 148,000 cantars over 1895. Ten years ago
                        the railway receipts amounted L.E. 1,822,000 and 9,864,000 passengers were
                        conveyed by the rail ways; telegraphic receipts</p>
                    <p>amounted to L.E. 53,000; 1,286 steamships cleared 1,943,000 tons of goods at
                        where the receipts of the port were L.E.141,000. And this from a country of
                        the dead!. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Commercial &amp; Financial Supplement </p>
                    <p>OF THE </p>
                    <p>"Egyptian Gazette," The Commercial and Financial Supplement of the “Egyptian
                        Gazette" is published at midday every Saturday in time for the Austrian
                        Lloyd's mail. The supplement contains exhaustive and important reviews of
                        the cotton, cotton seed, and stock and share markets, with all the latest
                        statistics up to the evening of the preceding day, complete tabular forms of
                        the various market fluctuations, and the oopiss of 'the official telegrams
                        of the Liverpool CottonAssociation, eto., etc. Subscription for one year
                        P.T. 100 (inclusive of postage in Egypt. for abroad the postage in P.T. 10
                        extra). For further particulars apply to the Manager the Egyptian
                        Gazette."</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" status="empty">
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" status="incomplete">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="wire">
                    <head>TELEGRAMS</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SITUATION IN MOROCCO.<lb/>FRENCH NAVAL PREPARATIONS <lb/>THE ALLEGED GERMAN LOAN. </head>
                     <div type="wireReport">   <dateline>PARIS, October 30. </dateline>
                        <p>There are various indications of naval preparations being made in
                            connection with the situation in Morocco. (Reuter)</p>
                        <p>TANGIER, October 30.</p><p> The French cruiser Jeanne d'Aro bash here to support
                            the Galilée in protecting French interests.</p>
                        <p>(Reuter)</p>
                        <p>LONDON October 30 </p>
                        <p>HOUSE OF COMMONS.-Sir E. Grey stated that, according to the latest
                            information, El Raizuli had restored order in Arzlia. It was not
                            proposed to send a man-of-war.</p>
                        <p>BERLIN, October 30.</p>
                        <p>The news is refuted here that the German Minister at Pez is negotiating a
                            small loan on behalf of the Moorish Government. He is acting entirely in
                            accord with the Algeciras Conference. (Reuter) </p>
                  </div>  </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FINAL BATTLE IN RUSSIA.<lb/>DESPOTISM TO FIND ITS GRAVE</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>ST. PETERSBURG, October 30 </dateline>
                        <p> 4,000 students and others assembled yesterday at the University and
                            adopted extreme revolutionary resolutions. A final battle is imminent,
                            they say, in which despotism will food ita grave. The University has
                            since been closed.</p>
                        <p>Eight men have been tried by drumhead court martial and executed in
                            connection with the bomb oatrage of the 27. (Reuter) </p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PRUSSIAN POLAND.<lb/>THE LANGUAGE QUESTION.</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>BERLIN, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Under instrüotions from their parents 45,000 Catholio children in
                            Pragsian Poland refuse to receive religious instruction in the German
                            language and are consistently punished. The Government approves of the
                            polishing.(Reuter)</p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EDUCATION BILL.<lb/>DISCUSSION IN HOUSE OF LORDS.</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>LONDON, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p>HOUSE OF LORDS.-A detailed discussion on the Bducation Bill was started.
                            Iatonas intere-t prevailed throughout. There was the largest attendance
                            of Peers since the last Home Rule Bill. The galleries were thronged with
                            Peeresses and Members of Parliament. Lord Heneage'</p>
                        <p>amendment, making religions instruction compulsory during school board,
                            was carried by 256 votes to 56, in spite of the opposition of the
                            Government (Router) </p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE FRENCH COLONIES.<lb/>NEW MINISTER'S RESOLUTION</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>PARIS, October 30</dateline>
                        <p> M. Eneroix, the now Minister of the Colonies, has declared that he is
                            resolved to administer the Colonies on business lines and to make them
                            pay by increasing the imports and exports. (Reuter) </p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE LUTIN DISASTER.<lb/>FUNERAL OF THE VICTIMS</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>BIZERTA, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p> The ongoity bold shows that the disaster to the Latin was not imputable
                            to her commandant, Leabemat Pépoux. The faperal of the victims took
                            place in the morning.(Havas)</p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PHILIPPINE ASSEMBLY.</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>WASHINGTON, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p>President Roosevelt has fixed the elections for the first Philippine
                            Assembly to take place in the Spring. (Reuter) </p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW GERMAN MINISTER AT CAIRO.</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>BERLIN, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p>Count Bernstorff, Congal General at Cairo, will start to-morrow for
                            Egypt. He dined with the Emperor and breakfast with Sir Frank Lascelles,
                            the British Ambassador.(Reuter)</p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RIFLE SHOOTING IN SCHOOLS.</head>
                        <div type="wireReport"><dateline>LONDON, October 30.</dateline>
                        <p>House of Commons. -Mr. Birrell explained that the rifle shooting
                            experiment would be confined to five schools. No farther permission
                            would be given., (Reuter)</p></div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>M. IZWOLSKY.</head><div type="wireReport"><dateline>BERLIN, October 30</dateline>
                        <p>The Booperor bas bertswed on M. Izwolsky the Grand Cross of the Red
                            Eagle. (Reuter)</p></div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="section" feature="sport">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY..</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FOOTBALL</head>
                        <p>K. S. C. o. R. INNISKILLING FUSILIERS.</p>
                        <p>This return fixture was played at Gbezireb on Saturday, 28th inst.
                            Several alterations were necessary in the composition of the home team,
                            and for a variety of reasons Barnard, Breretoa, and Carry gave way to
                            Fletcher, Ashcroft, and Lofton making a practically new forward line
                            from that which drow with the same team a fortnight ago. Stout won the
                            toss,and defended the pavilion goal. The advantage of the sun was
                            considerable at first and enabled the home team to immediately become
                            aggressive. Yates and Fletcher were early conspicuous, but found the
                            defence equal to all emergencies, and for the most part the game was io
                            midfield, where high kicking on the part of the defence deprived the
                            game of much interest, as the ball was too frequently in touch.” Several
                            useful runs were inaugurated by both forward lines, but each-Deeded
                            finish, and lack of shooting power was lamentably evident on both sides.
                            One effort however by the home forwarder deserved a better result.
                            Receiving from Btherington Smith, Yates in tarn transferred to Fletcher,
                            who, after taking it down the wing, went sorons a magnificent centre,
                            only to see the opportunity go begging, through the inside forward not
                            being op. A Second movement, however, carried oat on the same wing,
                            enabled Yates to give to Deacon, who after tricking the, backs had
                            little difficulty in placing the ball into the corner of the net,
                            Howlett having no chance.</p>
                        <p>At half-time the advantage of the odd goal still rested with the home
                            team. Bat on restarting the determination of the Inniskillings to get on
                            terms was soon evident, and the home defence experienced more than one
                            anxious moment. Welsh and Branagh, on the left, were always conspionour,
                            the former especially playing. * particularly a clever game. The
                            equalising goal came about ten minutes after the interval A clever run
                            by the visiting left, which the defence failed to stop, gave Welsh a
                            chance which he accepted, to send across a clever centre, and &amp;
                            misunderstanding between the back and goalkeeper left an absolutely open
                            goal to Percy, who made no mistake. The pace of the game was well
                            maintained to the end, but nothing further was stored and for the second
                            time this season the result was a drawn match.</p>
                        <p>From an artistic point of view the game can hardly be voted a success.
                            The pace of the ground and the light ball may have been responsible for
                            the somewhat ragged exhibition. There was far too much high kicking, and
                            combination was rather at a premium and good shooting entirely absent. A
                            little more practice, however, shoall make all the difference and once
                            together the home team should give a good account of themselves during
                            the coming season. In the military team there are distinct
                            possibilities: they pose as a c'ever left \wing, and Welsh was the best
                            forward on the field. Smyth, too, at left half, was as usual ubiquitous,
                            but the backs kick too hard and apparently without any consideration for
                            the forwards in front of them. </p>
                        <p>The following were the teams</p>
                        <p>K S.C. -Morrison, goal ; Stoot and Wyatt, backs ; Wesley, Rivers-Smith,
                            and Eherington Smith, half-backs ; Lofton, Ashcroft, Deacon,
                            forwards.</p>
                        <p>RI.P.-Bowlott, goal ; Pte Lyons and Pte Ward, bricks ; Cpl. Miller,
                            Sergt. Walker and Pte Smyth, half-backs : Ptes. Hatton; Percy,
                            Higginson, Branagh, and Welsh, forwards. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HELOUAN SPORTING CLUB.</head>
                        <p>The following is the racing programme for</p>
                        <p>1906-1907 : -</p>
                        <p>FIRST WINTER MEETING. -UTIN DISASTER. i</p>
                        <p> 28th December 1906. </p>
                        <p>TEWFIK PLATE: of P.T. 30,000, second horse to receive P.T. 3,000 and
                            third borso P.T.2,000, out of the stake. For Maiden (at nomination) Arab
                            ponies. Weight for age and nobles with penalties. Winners of a race of
                            P.T. 8,000 or more, at the Cairo First Winter Meeting 1906 will carry an
                            extra penalty in this race, of 7 lbs. Distance one mile. Botry by
                            subscription and nomination as follows :</p>
                        <p>Subscription on 1st June P.T. 600, with P.T. 500 on domination on 1st
                            November, and with a further charge of P.T. 400, if left in after the
                            1st of December 1906. </p>
                        <p>DESERT PLATE: of P.T. 6,500, second horse o receive P.T. 1,000, and third
                            borse P.T. 500, oat of the stakes. For Maiden (at nomination) Arabe.
                            Weight for age with penalties. Distance one mile. Entry by subscription
                            and nomination as follows:- .</p>
                        <p>Subscription on lot Jane P.T. 100, with P.T. 100 on nomination on 1st
                            November, and with a further charge of P.T. 100 if left in the 1st of
                            December 1906.</p>
                        <!-- Lipton limited advert -->
                        <cb n="3"/>
                        <p>SECOND WINTER MEETING.</p>
                        <p>1st February 1907. HELOUAN DERBY : of P.T. 30,000, second horse to
                            receive. P.T. 80,000 and third horse P.T. 2,000, out of the stakes. Por
                            Maiden (at nomination) Arabe. Weight for age with penalties. The winners
                            of the Jubilee Stakes or eclipse. Stakes, Cairo Second Winter Meeting
                            1907, will carry an extra penalty in this race, of 7 lbs. for either
                            win. Distance about one mile and a half. Battery by subscription and
                            nomination as follows: arry gave way to Fletcher, Subscription on 1st
                            Jane P.T. 500, with efton making a practically P.T. 600, on nomination
                            on 1st November, and with a further charge of P.T. 400, if left in after
                            the 1st of January 1907. </p>
                        <p>SAHARA STAKES : of P.T. 6,500, second horse to receive P.T. 1,000, and
                            third borte and enabled the home team P.T. 500, out of the stakes. For
                            Maiden (at nomination) Arab ponies. Weight for age and inches with
                            penalties. Wonders of the advertised value of P.T. 10,000 or more, will
                            carry an extra penalty in this race, of art of 7 lbs. Distance one mile.
                            Botry by subscription and nomination as follows : : </p>
                        <p>Subscription on 1st Jane P.T. 100, with P.T. 100 on nomination on 1st
                            November, and with a further charge of P.T. 100, if left in after the
                            1st of January 1907.</p>
                        <p>THIRD WINTER MEETING. </p>
                        <p>1st March 1907. </p>
                        <p>The Pony HANDICAP: of P.T. 10,000, second borte to receive P.T. 2,000,
                            and third horseP.T. 1,000, ost of the stake. For Arab ponies Top weight
                            not to exceed 11 stones, 7 Ibs. Distance about one mile and a half.
                            Entrance by subscription and nomination as follows :</p>
                        <p>Subscription on 1st June 1906, P.'T. 200, with P.T. 200 on nomination on
                            1st November and with a farther obarge of P.T. 100, if left in after 1st
                            February </p>
                        <p>THE ABAB HANDICAP : of P.T. 1:700, 2nd horse to receive P.T. 2,000, and
                            third horse P.T. 1,000, oath of the s'akos. For Arab horses.Top weight
                            not to exceed 11 st. 7 lbs. Distance about 2 miles. Katrande by
                            subscription and nomination as follows :ten minutes after the
                            interval.</p>
                        <p>Subscription on 1st Jan 1903, P.T. 200, on nomination on November 1st,
                            and farther charge of P.T. 100, if left in after 1st February 1907.</p>
                        <p>The possessor of two nominations in any of the above races has the right
                            to nominate also a third borge, op to the time that the was well
                            maintained to the entries close for all races of that meeting by paying
                            double entrance fee. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="comingEvents">
                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA. </p>
                    <p>October </p>
                    <p> Wed. 31 Zizipia Theatre. Grook company in</p>
                    <p>The Exile Othon. 9.</p>
                    <p>Alhambra Theatre Italian Dramatio company in Fiamme nell Ombra. 9.30. </p>
                    <p>Tour Eiffel Music Hall. Every evening 9 30.</p>
                    <p>French Garden. Varieties and Menagerie. 9.30.</p>
                    <p>November </p>
                    <p>Thars. 1 Alhambra Theatre. Tarkish Dramatic Company. 9.30. </p>
                    <p>Sat. 3 Mustapha Range. B R. O. Practice 2.30. </p>
                    <p>San Stefano Casino. A. H. S. Chrysanthemum Show. 8. </p>
                    <p>Round Point. Victoria School Pigeon Shooting Meeting </p>
                    <p>Sun. 4 Şap, Stefano Casino. Chrysanthemum Show.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Dotober.Wed. 31 Khedivial Opera House. Bandmann</p>
                    <p>Opora company in The Earl and <hi rend="italic">the Girl. 9.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Esbekieb Theatre French comedy<hi rend="italic">. 9. </hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Abbas Theatre. French comedy company. 9.</p>
                    <p>Théâtre des Nouveautés. 9.30</p>
                    <p>Champs Elysees. Cinematograph Entertainment.</p>
                    <p>November. </p>
                    <p>Pri. 2 Zoological Gardens. Concert by Ghizeh Boy's Band. Afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Sun. 4 Zoological Gardens. Concert by Ghizeb Boys' Band. Afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Pri. 30. Ghozirab. K.S.C. Skya Meetióg. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>MILITARY TAILOR.</head>
                    <p>EQYPTIAN ARMY OUTFITS A SPECIALITY</p>
                    <p>RIDING BREECHES. </p>
                    <p>F. Phillips and Co. </p>
                    <p>LADIES' TAILORS. (HIGH CLASS WORK ONLY).</p>
                    <p> CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA. <hi rend="italic">28067-91-5-07</hi></p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> WALKER &amp; MEIM ARACHI, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>SECOND NOTICE. </p>
                    <p>SHAREHOLDERS in the above Company who have not yet paid Calls or other movies
                        due in rospoot of shares allotted to them, are hereby required, in the terms
                        of the Company's Articles of Association, to pay the same within seven days
                        to the Bankers of the Company, the Apglo-Egyptian Bank, Cairo or Alexandria,
                        together with interest at the rate of 7% per annum, in accordance with the
                        notice published on September 10 h. </p>
                    <p>By order of the Board</p>
                    <p>WALKER &amp; MEIMARAOHI, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>Cairo, October 31st, 1906. 28768 4-1 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Peninsular &amp; Oriental Steam Navigation </p>
                    <p>COMPANY.</p>
                    <p> NOTICE. nation as follows :</p>
                    <p>The Peninsular and Oriental S.N. Company hereby give notice that the rates of
                        passage money from the lot November by their Mail Steamers from Egypt will
                        be as follows:</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">To First Second</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">London 19 13</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Marseilles 13 9</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Brindisi 9</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>These rates will be in force op to and including the 14th May next, and are
                        subject to, rebate of 25% off the above fares to passengers returning within
                        12 months of date of landing</p>
                    <p>28740 6-6</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Societe Genopole de Pressage et de Dépôts</p>
                    <p>AVIS </p>
                    <p>Messieurs les actionnaires sont informés que l'Assemblée Générale Ordinaire
                        de ce jour a fixé les intérêts et le dividende pour l'Exercice 1905-1906 </p>
                    <p>a 10%, solt $2 par sotion:</p>
                    <p> Un compte de £9.12. ayant été payé en Mai dernier, le solde, soit $1.88. par
                        action, sera payé à partir du Lundi 5 Novembre prochain par la Banque
                        Impériale Ottomane &amp; Alexandre contre remise du coupon No. 18.
                        Alexandra, lo 99 Octobre 1906. 28765-1 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Comptoir Financier et d'Egypte </p>
                    <p>Messibūrs les Actionnaires sont informés par décision de l'Assemblée générale
                        du 29 Octobre 1906, les dividendes ont été fixés à P.T. 28, 4/10 par action
                        ordinaire (lère émission) et à Latg. 2, par part de Fondateur. Ils sont
                        payables aux guichets du Comptoir Financier et Commercial d'Egypte à
                        Alexandrie et au Caire, à partir du 12 Novembre 1906, présentation du coupon
                        N. 1. </p>
                    <p>L'Administrateur Délégué,</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">ALRED CAMPOS</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Alexandrio, la 31 Ootobre 1906. - 38766-2x-1 0.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AVIS </head>
                    <p>MM. Youssef Boy Camel, Ragheb Eff, Camel,Toabia Bey Camel, Camel Bey Camel,
                        Consambra Theatre. Turkish Dra- tantin Bey Camel, Habib Bey Camel, Farid
                        Camel, Elias Camel, Tawfik Camel, Halim tapha Range. B R. O. Practice.
                        Camel, Gabriel Camel, Nabil Camel, Fayez Camel, Emile Camel, Charles Camel,
                        Pauzi Camel, Alfred Camel, ont l'honneur de vous informer qu'en conformité
                        d'un acte dressé le und Point. Victoria Soboul Pigeon 22 COUrant, sab. No.
                        147, aa Patriarcat Copte Catholique du Caire et donc un extraits été déposé
                        au Greffe des actes notariés du Tribunal ow.Mixte de l'aire lostanca de la
                        dite ville pour être conservé au rang de ses minutes suivant acte en date du
                        28 Octobre 1906 No. 85,082, ils ont ajouté à leur signature le nom TOURG le
                        nom originaire de leur famille étant CAMEL Toura</p>
                    <p>Le Caire, le 30 Octobre 1906. 28769-1 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Administration des Chemins de fer de l'Etat Égyptien. </p>
                    <p>AVIS </p>
                    <p>L'Administration des Chemins de Fer et des Télégraphes de l'Etat a l'honneur
                        de portes à la connaissance de Pablo qu'il ne sera délivré. Ja l'avenir sur
                        la ligne Sex-Docks que des cartes d'abonnement appelles aux prix actuels, et
                        qne les cartes d'abonnement pour 1, 3,6 &amp; 9 mois accordéons juego à
                        présent ne seront plus délivrées à l'avenir.</p>
                    <p>Le Caire, le 29 Octobre 1906. 28762 21</p>
                </div>
                <!-- Sanitas -->
                <cb n="5"/>
                <!-- missing adverts -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Photographic Stores O. DIRADOUR</p>
                    <p>PLACE DE L'OPERA DEPOT FOR KODAKS AND FILMS. AMATEUR WORK, CAMÉRA REPAIRS,
                        ETC.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Life Assurance Company.</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED 1825. fce :-3, George Street, Edinburgh. . .</p>
                    <p>......... . ... - 11.300.000</p>
                    <p>LOCAL BOARD FOR EGYPT: 5. COOKBON, Bøq., Manager, Anglo-kgyptian Bank,
                        Limited, Ontro. ERISON, Esq., General Manager, MoskS. Thomas Cook &amp; Bon,
                        (Egypt) Lul (14-11-000</p>
                    <p>oe tor Egypt: Standard Buildings, Cairo. BI &amp; Co., Oliat Agents for
                        Alexandria. A. V, THOMSON, sif el-Din Bey, Mohamed Aly Square</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Secretary for Egyption units”1</hi>
                    </p>
                    <!-- missing -->
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Tosh Whisky Established 1786,</p>
                    <p> Mackintosh &amp; C</p>
                    <p>INVERNESS.</p>
                    <p>AGENT</p>
                    <p>ERNEST THORON,</p>
                    <p>CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA </p>
                    <p>GENERAL DEPOT,</p>
                    <p>JOHN ROSS &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA </p>
                    <p>Retailers.</p>
                    <p>E. J. FLEURENT, RY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>Square Halim Pachs, CAIRO 196635 - 800-900</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASK FOR</head>
                    <p>And if not supplied to </p>
                    <p>APPLY TO</p>
                    <p> JOHN B. CAFFARI </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" status="verified">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PITH OF THE PRESS.</head>
                    <p>EXTRACTS FROM HOME PAPERS.</p>
                    <p> The Lords and the Education BIII. </p>
                    <p>The decision to recommend the postponement of the further consideration of
                        the Education Bill until a final judgment has been delivered in the West
                        Riding case is a naturals and indeed almost a necessary consequence of the
                        decision to appeal against the judgment of | 8 the majority of the Court of
                        Appeals. We have b already remarked that both good sense and good policy,
                        even in the narrower party sense | 8 of the term, pointed to the wisdom and
                        the expediency of having the appeal entered. The 8 game considerations
                        point, not-less conclusive-| I ly, to the wisdom and expediency of having it
                        | 6 determined before the House of Lords are invited to proceed with the
                        Education Bill. Until final judgment has been delivered upon the point
                        raised in the West Riding case, P Diether the supporters nor the opponents
                        of that mengare can debate it with any assurance that they rightly
                        understand the present situation of the education question. The Bill, no
                        doubt, zovers many other points besides that which is in controversy in the
                        West Riding casa; bat its main object, we have been con. stantly told, is to
                        remedy a grievance which the judgment of the Court of Appeal affirms to be a
                        non-existent grievance. The Government would clearly stand at a disadvantage
                        in pressing the House of Lords to legislate on the supposition that the
                        highest Court which has spoken on the subject is wrong, and that it may
                        hereafter be reversed when the case comes on, in ordinary course, before
                        that House as the Court of final appeal. (“Times.”) Parliament 1 A Waning
                        Attraction.</p>
                    <p>Parliament rassembles to-day, after a quiet And rather doll regas. Though
                        there are elements in the situation that promise, or threaten, 1 st a lively
                        time, it cannot be said that there sa is mach, if any, public excitement.
                        The fact of whether it is welcomed or deplored, is india- ne putable that
                        Parliamentary proceedings are I go fast losing their interest for a great
                        maps of Be people. The bare results of the day's sitting w are all that the
                        average man cares about, and fa the number of those who read even the
                        machcortailed reports of speeches is diminishing. There are advantages and
                        drawbacks in this growing indifference. At the present moment we are
                        inclined to think that th3 profit preponderates over the 1088.
                        ("Telegraph.") The Empire and the Navy.</p>
                    <p>One of the first matters with which Parlia- | a ment will deal with the
                        intended redaction of the Navy. As we have consistently maintained by
                        tained, it is above all things necessary that st this question, like all
                        questions affecting the as national and Imperial defences, should be
                        steadfastly treated as above all considerations TI of party politics. We
                        regard any Government of what political complexion soever, insofar 03 as
                        they fulfil their first date, which is the de dae and efficient maintenance
                        of the sea * and land defences of the Empire, as entitled op 1.on this head
                        to the gupport of every loyal</p>
                    <p>citizen. Conversely, we regard any Government. di ment, of wbat political
                        complexion soever, af who sacrifice the efficiency of the Services, cil no
                        matter what the pretext, as faithful th to their trust, and 28 no longer fit
                        to bolded the power and the insignia of their high led 'office. It is a
                        heavy indictment that the Govern.br ment will have to answer. If, we
                        sincerely 80 hope, they eleet te abandon their intention | ac of
                        disastrously crippling the efficiency of the Pleet, no one, as we have said,
                        will more heartily support their action than ourselves. Bot, even so, it is
                        idle to suppose that, however plausible the explanations presented, their
                        reputation has not been seriously, perhaps irreparably, injared. The great
                        body of the nation, although they may not be etirred to loud protest, are
                        profoundly, discontented and distrustful. It will need moeh - very mach--to
                        restore their confidence.</p>
                    <p>("Standard.") </p>
                    <p>France's Now Premier</p>
                    <p>M. Clemenceau will probably prove to be the cost original Premier whom France
                        bas bad since Gambetta. and the few facts known ás yet about his Ministry
                        stamp him as a man of courage and ideas. He proposes to F place at the bead
                        of the army his friend W General Picquart, who was op till Jaly a da colonel
                        "en retraite," broken for his gallant . deteros of Major Dreyfus, and even
                        expelled D from the Legion of Honour. General Picquart Pi bas 69. Mach
                        ability and a character of soch rare independence and moral courage that'
                        tio his promotion will be hailed abroad as a 0 striking act of reparation.
                        If the French pro<!-- Robinson's Barley ad --><cb n="2"/>duce a more
                        reckless, reactionary type that some other peoples, they alsó develop a
                        logic and &amp; virility among their radical which we can only envy and
                        admire. This choice will be sharply criticized, and it may be popular in the
                        army, though the army after General André's period of "purification” is no
                        longer what it was. ("Tribane”) </p>
                    <p> Zola's Editor, </p>
                    <p>What is to be said of M. Clemenceau bim self ? He also was a figure in the
                        great Dreyfa drama. He was Zola's Editor, one of those splendid statesmen
                        journalists of whom France has in her day produced so many. This is the man
                        who now steps up to the position of supreme executive power in France. Zola
                        is Gideon and the dead, else perhaps he also might have been summoned to
                        this astonishing Government. That it will work well we have every
                        confidence, and this emergence of absolute uncompromising honesty in public
                        affairs should stimulate English politicians to drop their wearisome
                        compromises, and adopt in their place a touch of real conviction.</p>
                    <p>("'Daily News.") </p>
                    <p> Unionists and Devolution in Ireland. </p>
                    <p>In his categorical repudiation of the late te besides that</p>
                    <p>Government in the so-called scheme of "dovlation,” Mr. Balfoar undoubtedly
                        doesn't have much to relieve the apprehensions of Unionists in Ireland as
                        well as in Great Britain. But whether be bas done enough to restore the
                        entire confidence which alone can ensure a solid resistance to the proposals
                        of the Liberal Government remains yet to be seen. Prima facie it would seem
                        that Unionists have a right to demand that their leaders should disclose the
                        scheme which was actually contemplated by the late Government in regard to
                        Ireland and which, therefore, may be offered as a constructive alternative
                        to the measure, which the present Extraction. Cabinet will sooner or later
                        introduce. That some alternative scheme was entertained is at least a fair
                        inference from Lord Lansdowne's se, or threaten, | statement at Nottingham
                        that even when he said that there saw the second "devolution" draft in the
                        bands bent. The fact, of Sir Antony MacDonnell did not think it necessary to
                        communicate the fact to his colleagues. So far from damaging the reputation
                        of Mr. great mass of Balfour and his Cabinet, sach a declaration day's
                        sitting would do more than anything else to ensure the 88 abont, and fall
                        restoration of the confidence which even ron the mach. I now have a bat
                        partially established. diminishing</p>
                    <p>("Morning Post.") </p>
                    <p> Federal Conference on Education. h3 profit pre </p>
                    <p>The League of the Empire has succeeded in perfecting &amp; scheme for holding
                        a Federal Conference on Education in London in May next. The Colonial Office
                        has, we understand, afforded valuable official encouragement in the matter,
                        and the League has been authorized by the Secretary of State for the
                        Colonies to necessary that state that the scheme bas bis sympathy and 1
                        affecting the assistance. The President of the English Board of Education
                        has also given his support. The Board will be fally represented at the
                        Conference, and Mr. Birrell will preside at the opening meeting. Invitations
                        have been dispatched by favour of Lord Elgin to the Colonial Education
                        Department, and the cooperation of the Indian Government has also been
                        requested. Educational authorities in different countries have expressed
                        their warm approval regarding the scheme, and the Council of the League of
                        the Empire h28 confidence, therefore, in carrying forward the Imperial
                        education work with which it has been entrusted, and asks the help of all
                        concerned in bringing it to a successful issue. That, we are sure, will be
                        readily accorded, for the object is an altogether excellent one. </p>
                    <p>("Westminster Gazette.") </p>
                    <p>Short-sighted Policy, </p>
                    <p>The machinery of the Empire is hopelessly out of gear, and is in need of
                        entire reconstruction. The inability of our present Ministers to see beyond
                        our own shores or to grasp the larger be interests of Empire is being daily
                        brought into greater prominence and greater prominence, and it is safa to
                        say that since their return to power more dissatisfaction and indignation
                        has been caused throughout our colonies than would have been conceived to be
                        possible in the time. ("Globe.")</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN GOVERNMENT.</head>
                    <p>Tenders will be received at the Office of the Financial Secretary to the
                        Sudan Government War Office, Cairo, ap to 12 noon on the 10th day of
                        November, 1906, for the supply of : 50,000 (fifty thousand) Maria Theresa
                        evan expelled Dollars to be delivered at the Ministry of Finance, Cairo.
                        People wishing to tender for this adjudication can consult the
                        specifications at the above Office any day from 9 a.m. to 1 p.me., except
                        Fridays and general holidays. 28767-6A-1</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item" status="uncorrectedOCR">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN FINANCES:</head>
                    <byline>BY MR. COPE WHITEHOUSE.</byline>
                    <p>The "Journal of Commerce and Commercial Bulletin” (New York) contains the
                        following</p>
                    <p>letter from Mr. Cope Whiteboase</p>
                    <p>Sir,- The Bank of Bngland recently sent £1,000,000 to Egypt, and attention
                        has been directed to the general condition of that country by &amp; special
                        Consular Report entitled "Progressive Egypt '' (Sept. 17). The conclusions
                        at which Consular Agent Pepper arrives point to the bursting of a number of
                        "speculative bubbles” founded on the familiar practice of converting
                        suburban acreage into toma lots, with a rise in "price," which is called an
                        enhanced "value." American manufacturers are, nevertheless, advised to
                        cultivate Egyptian trade, and cautioned against demanding cash on delivery,
                        or giving shorter oredit than three months. Lord Cromer in his last report
                        on Egypt (April) says that while so far as be is "able to forecast the
                        fatore, no sufficient ground exists for holding possitistic views," be
                        concedes that the great rise in the value of land, in the sadden rush which
                        has been made | to invest capital in various commercial undertakings, the
                        destruction of the sogar indāstry -as the result of dealing with the land
                        formerly planted with cane--and other causes have "tended to foster A
                        suspicion that Egypalatian affairs generally are QD8oond, and that a und
                        reaction, accompanied possibly by disastrous consequences, will probably
                        take place before long" (p. 17).</p>
                    <p>The financial disturbance in Egypt twenty five years ago had little effect
                        outside of three or four of the principal banking houses of the day and
                        their clients. The total unsecured debt at the time of the
                        British-vouupation (1882) es was about $250,000,000 ; and there were no
                        local financial corporations of the elightest international importance. This
                        is changed. A. flood, sach as those of 1861, 1868, 1874, and 1878, would
                        impair the ability of English, French and German banks of the highest
                        standing to hold American securities or assist in carrying out projected
                        enterprises. The Egyptian debt itself, deducting the amount realized by the
                        sale of collaterals, has not increased much over 70 por conta side the
                        British-ocsopation, with nothing to show for it as an asset, bat at least
                        $600,000,000 of "capital" has been placed there. As " imports, including
                        specie, ral have for two years exceeded the exports," Lord Cromer remarks
                        that "should this influx nd, of capital at any time dease or diminish, tha
                        Ebe external debt of Egypt will be increased by the amount due to the
                        foreign investor on the to capital now flowing into the country." In 1876,
                        and the exports were $67,806,425, and the mporta ish | $20,205,955. In 1886,
                        the exports had been reduced and the imports increased, leaving a bottle.
                        Port balance in favor of Egypt of about $12,725,000.</p>
                    <p>twenty five be In 1906 the imports exceeded the exports by</p>
                    <p>Those Jen $6,020,000. So far as Wall Street is concerned,</p>
                    <p>reply should be the only question is how far finance bills have</p>
                    <p>The to been placed by, or through, each banks as the</p>
                    <p>Crédit Lyonnais, the Deutsche Bank, the Banin que de Paris et de Pays Bas,
                        the Bank of i'm Abyssinia and other institutions which adver</p>
                    <p>tise for business in the Alexandrian and</p>
                    <p>Baropean papers. The parely Egyptian deposit Sept. 17, 1906. No. 2,68 ial
                        banks have increased their liabilities from Agent, Charles M. Pepper
                        Bt837,280,000 in 1901 to $98,020,000 in 1905. It will be seen from th in
                        Lord Cromer "cannot help thinking after that American manufacta</p>
                    <p>examining the balance sheets of the leading in exercising. caation. The
                        banke, that it is worth the attention of the lities offered the paroha
                        directors to consider whether the proportion of the liabilities, covered by
                        cash, by money at the apparently speedy. call or short notice, or by first
                        class securities, $500,000,000 of "Becurit should not be increased." la
                        National badke par, or even at a premium</p>
                    <p>here only "first-class” securities are regarded collaterals of the Europea to
                        as assets 1</p>
                    <p>• Ipete for Egyptian bills, A comparison of the obiet articles of export
                        effect on the money mi |--cotton, beans, wheat, onions and sogar-ip. the
                        Consular Report of the late Consul General Cardwell (1886), and the latest
                        statistics, fails to justify the title "Progressive Egypt '' of the report
                        of the Department of Commerce and Labour. The cotton exported in 1886 was,
                        it is true, only 563,000 bales ; but while more than Under this heading ac
                        balf of the population of the Delta was on-sorted at the following ra ployed
                        in its cultivation, all but three per cent.</p>
                    <p>of the Egyptians south of Cairo were engaged in 15 words... P.T. hal in corel
                        agriculture. It was a normal output, 1 80 words . .. fairly steady, like
                        that of gagar prior to 1896. 1 Bvory 10 words,</p>
                    <p>beyond 80. ). The cotton output in 1896-7 (before the The address Aggodan Dam
                        began), was 1,175,000 bales must appear on conseca of 500 pounds ; in
                        1899-1900, 1,301,000 bales;rates to be obtained. 50 | in 1905, in spite of
                        increased acreage and the ho advertisements not ap Aggodan reservoir, it
                        remained stationary. Bat.</p>
                    <p>Ansch advertisements the orop of 1905-6 was a "veritable disaster,"</p>
                    <p>to this rule no exc with a "deterioration in quality and quantity be made.
                        Letters in 30 percent." The acreage planted this year monts will be poste is
                        60,000 acres less than last year, with extreme low stamps are son mile high
                        prices on a rising market. Apart cover postage. from cotton, grow apparently
                        at a loss, it is difficult to see what Egypt offers in exchange for
                        $101,500,000 of imports, except finance GARD'S INTERNATIO bills for
                        "charities."In 1886, 4,528,400 burhela A AND TRADE MAI of beans were
                        exported, as against less than A useful business directory half a million
                        (469,275) in 1908, while it would all important business firms seem that in
                        1906 all but 30,925 bushels were Continent, and Egypt. Circ kept for home
                        consumption, and rice was and America. Prioa-One imported. Before 1886, the
                        exports of wheat Free. AGARD'S INTER averaged about 2,600,000 burbele. In
                        1908</p>
                    <p> QUID sont pont free to </p>
                    <p>throughout Europe, Ameri there was less than a thousand bachels (900). Egypt.
                        The best reference and in 1906 none at all. Even onions (grown largely for
                        export) fell from 793,973 boxes (1905) to 540,281 (1906).</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISER, Young The cultivation of tobacco, which flourished | 4. ont
                        Education, goo with a tax of $500 per acre, way long ago I address, at
                        present in En prohibited in European interests ; while eugar</p>
                    <p>to come to Egypt, Seeks h88 now also disappeared.</p>
                    <p>Confidential Clerk, or án Exports of cereals, vegetables, floor,</p>
                    <p>good post in Comraeroi</p>
                    <p>Experience of Secretaria etc ...........
                        ........................$13,652,285</p>
                    <p>Exceptional organising | Imports, do. ............................
                        13,963,100</p>
                    <p>Expert at accounts and Excess of importe...............$310,815</p>
                    <p>capable Correspondent. Colonial products, cane sugar, gum</p>
                    <p>Fome Spanish. Excellent |</p>
                    <p>Pinance, and Stock Exo</p>
                    <p>3,148,000 arabic, etc...... Imports,do......</p>
                    <p>4,667,535</p>
                    <p>Commercial Law. Fair appointed to a suitable</p>
                    <p>enthusiasm and energy Excess of importe................ $1,619.835</p>
                    <p>highest possible character</p>
                    <p>she (Daily Consular and Trade Reporta, Monday, "Egyptian Gazette," Ale</p>
                    <p>180</p>
                    <p>Cheap Prepaid A</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Sept. 17, 1906. No. 2,688. Special Consular Agent, Charles M. Pepper.)</p>
                    <p>It will be seen from these facts and figures that American manufacturers are
                        not far wrong in exercising caution. The local banking faci-: lities offered
                        by the profesor are more than ample. Bat the real importance lies in the
                        apparently speedy. elimination of over $500,000,000 of "Becurities" now
                        carried at par, or even at a premium, from the available collaterals of the
                        European bankers, who com: pete for Egyptian bills, with its consequent
                        effect on the money markets of the world.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="advert" colSpan="3">
                    <head>CATARRH, A NATIONAL SCOURGE</head>
                    <p>PE-RU-NA, A FAMILY NEED</p>
                    <p>A Heavy hand upon the land</p>
                    <p>CATARRH</p>
                    <p>PE-RU-NA THE CATARRH REMEDY.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">"Over half of the population of Canada suffer from some
                            form of catarrh during the course of the year. This demonstrates the
                            great need of Peruna in every home to protect the family against all
                            catarrhal diseases.”--S. B. HARTMAN, M. D.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>For special direotione everyone should read THE ILLs Or LITE '' copy of which
                        surrounds vuoh. bottle. Peruna is for sale by all chemists and druggists at
                        Ave billings per bottle or six bottles for twenty five shillings.</p>
                    <p>Those wishing direct correspondence with Dr. HARTMAN and joan wait the
                        necessary dolay in reifying * reply should address Dr. 8. B. HARTMAN,
                        Columbus, Ohio, U.S.A. The following wholesale druggist will supply the
                        retail drug trade in Alexandria, Egypt.</p>
                    <p>E. DEL MAR,</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Nigypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="prepaidAdvertisements">
                    <p>Cheap PrepaidAdvertisements.</p>
                    <p>Under this heading advertisements are inserted at the following rates :</p>
                    <p> ONCE 3 TIMES 6 TIMES </p>
                    <p>15 words .. . P.T. 5 P.T. 10 P.T. 15 </p>
                    <p>30 words ...., 8 , 16 , 24</p>
                    <p> Every 10 words, 2, 4. 6</p>
                    <p>beyond 30. </p>
                    <p>The address is slanted. The advertisement must appear on consecutive days for
                        the above ratos to be obtained. 50% extra is charged, bo advertisements not
                        appearing consecutively All we advertisements must be prepaid, and</p>
                    <p>to this rule no exception whatever will bo mado. Letters in reply to
                        advertisements will be poster to any address if a low stamp is sent by the
                        advertiser to cover postage.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">A GARD'S INTERNATIONAL INDUSTRIES</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>AND TRADEMARKS REGISTER. A useful business directory containing addresses of
                        all important business frms of Great Britain, the Continent, and Egypt,
                        Circulating all over Europe and America. Prica_One pound Sterling. Post
                        Froo. AGARD'S INTERNATIONAL HOTEL GUIDA sont post free to all first class
                        Hotels throughout Europe, America, the Colonies and Egypt. The best
                        reference book for travellers.</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISER, Young Gentleman of Excel. A ent Education, good status, and good
                        address, at present in England, but proposing to come to Egypt, Speke
                        Position as Secretary, Confidential Clerk, or any position of trust, or good
                        post in Commercial Firm. Wide Travel Experience of Secretarial work,
                        together with Exceptional organising and literary ability. Expert at
                        accounts and figures and highly capable Correspondent. French, Dotob, and
                        Home Spanish. Excellent knowledge of Banking, Pinance, and Stock Exobange
                        matters and of Commercial L w. Fair salary required, but if appointed to a
                        suitable post would work with enthusiasm and energy. References of the
                        highest possible character. Address E. 8. c/o. Egyptian Gazette,"
                        Alexandria. 28767-8-2</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <cb n="5"/>
                    <p>ASSOUAN.-Charming newly built Villa to A be let, unfurnished, for the season,
                        or yearly, on the riverfront, 15 minutes from station, standing in &amp;
                        bioe garden, amidst lovely scenery; containing, on ground floor, entrance
                        hall, dining, drawing, and sitting rooms, kitchen, pantry, and servants'
                        rooms in basement; upstairs, 3 bedrooms, dressing room, and maid's room.
                        Bath rooma, W.C., with perfect ap up-to-date sanitary arrangements. For
                        rents and particulars apply to G. Mit chell, Assouan. 28743 6-8</p>
                    <p>ARABIC TEACHER, years' experience, has A few hours free. Translations
                        English, Predcb. Private lessons pope's residence.Apply No. 28759, "Egyptian
                        Gazette" Offices. 28759 6-2</p>
                    <p>AUCTION SALE of Furniture and Household Eff-ots, on Friday, ind November
                        next. For catalogues and particulars apply to Messrs. Congdon &amp; Co.,
                        Coiro. 28729-6 6</p>
                    <p>ASSOUAN. - Mr. G. Mitchell, Batate Agent, A has several plots of land
                        editable for building in this rising district. Apply as above.
                        28744-30-6</p>
                    <p>ARABIYAS --Tip-wagons for Light Railway A tor sale, second, hand. LB. 400.
                        No. 28749, Egyptian Gazette" officer. 27849:6-8</p>
                    <p>PLICKENSDERFBR TYPEWRITERS. - D London Prices. Address to the Agent, Post
                        Office Box No. 35, Alexandria. 81.12-900</p>
                    <p>ENGLISH LADY, years' experience in teaching. L ing, certificates London,
                        wisbech to find pupils. Apply No. 28732, "Gazette" offices: 28782-6.6</p>
                    <p>FOR YOUR WINTER Suits and Overcoats Borman's now Cutter, from Ellis and Johns
                        London. 28737-6-5</p>
                    <p>FOR LADIES' Tailor-made Costumes try Borman's new Cutter from Ell'8 and
                        Jobne, London:</p>
                    <p>38738-6-6</p>
                    <p>FOR TROUSERS try Borman &amp; Co.'s new T Cotter, from Ellis and Jobu's,
                        London. Riding breeches a speciality. 28739.6-5</p>
                    <p>GENTLEMAN, experienced in office work, U knowing English, Frenoli, Greek,
                        Bookkeeping, regoiros situation. No. 38794| "Gazette '' offices.
                        28784-66</p>
                    <cb n="6"/>
                    <p>MRS. BOUCHER'S Narsing Institute, 3. 1 and 3a Pimlico Road, Londos. gapplies
                        (on receipt of fall particulars) Hanskarpers Secretaries, Governo8888, and
                        Nuros of all descriptions, including monthly and children's No fee till
                        saited. Also (without charge) good schools for both boys and girls. Only
                        those which are personally inspected placed on the list to</p>
                    <p>98631 98 93 </p>
                    <p>MOTOR BUS WANTED, for Alexandria 1. Hotel Write "B.," Égyptian Gazetto"
                        office. 88765-6-8</p>
                    <p>SMART OFFICE BOY WANTED in Alor. D andria. Most onderstand Boglish, Apply No.
                        28,735, "Egyptian Gazette" office. 28785-6-6</p>
                    <p>TO LET.-Large furnished bedroom in English family, 5 minutes from Bourso. No.
                        98,783 "Gazette" offices.98783-6-6 .</p>
                    <p>ZİTHER LESSONS given by experienced U lady teacher, at home or private
                        honses. Mias Stiefen hofer, 1, Rae Antoine, Alonndria.28745-64</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" feature="bureauPlacement">
                    <p>Societe Internationale des employo</p>
                    <p>D'ALEXANDRIE.</p>
                    <p>Siłoe Social Rue SIDI EL METWALLI NO. 80 ET RUE HAMMAM EL ZAHAB No. 1 AU 1ER
                        ÉTAGE</p>
                    <p>BUREAU DE PLACEMENT</p>
                    <p>Deux employés bons comptables disposant-da</p>
                    <p>quelques heures par jour demandait tans</p>
                    <p>livros de commerce. Bonnes références Professeur français diplomó, chorobo
                        locons &amp;</p>
                    <p>domicile, Un professeur d'arabe et de comptabilité d'une</p>
                    <p>des plus grande établissement d'instruction de la ville désire donner den
                        legona panti</p>
                    <p>golières. Un jeune homme de 80 ans demande place de • caissier. Une dame
                        connaissant la machine à dorure</p>
                    <p>et la comptabilité désire un emploi.</p>
                    <p>N.B.- Pour tous renseignements s'adresser au Siège social de la Société, Rno
                        Mosquée Attarine No. 21,</p>
                    <p>Le Secrétariat est ouvert tous les joun, a adopté les dimanches et jour de
                        fête, do 7b. 1/9 à 8 h. 1/2 du soir.. . Les insertions oi-dessus sont fajton
                        gratuitement par les soins de la Société et seuls les soci taires peuvent en
                        bénéficier.</p>
                    <p>Les personnes qui Adressent des demandes la la Société, sont priées de
                        joindre un diabro</p>
                    <p>pour la réponse."</p>
                    <p>·</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" status="uncorrectedOCR">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="bulletinBourse">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE</head>
                    <p>(Aujourd'hui à midi et demie.) La fermeté continue à régner, ainsi que
                        l'animation. Les échanges les plus importants ont été effectués en Union
                        Foncière, Comptoir, Estates, Trust, National Bank, Delta Land et Nile
                        Lund.</p>
                    <p>Des réalisations ont ramené la Behera de 45 * 44 1/2 et la Daïra de 16 15/16
                        4 16 7/8, mais les autres valeurs foncières sont généralement bien teņaes :
                        l'Union Foncière, de plus en plus recherchée, atteint. 69/16; la Delta Land
                        s'avance 808si de 4 1/32 à 4 1/16, la Nile Land de 16 13/6 &amp; 17 ; les
                        Estates sont un peu plus faibles à 2 3/16 et le Cheik Padl à 111.</p>
                    <p>La Privilégiée Bière d'Alexandrie réactionnel de 222 &amp; 210-220, tandis
                        que la Bière du Caire monte de 135 &amp; 136 la Privilégiée et de 72 3/4 " à
                        78 la Dividende. Les Cotton Mills s'avancent de 6/3 à 7, les Ninkovich
                        Hôtels. de 18 1/4 å 18 5/16, les Sucreries de 23 à 21.</p>
                    <p>De 147 les Lots Taros progressent à 149, tandis que la Cassa di Sconto
                        réactionnel de 238 8/4 à 238 l'ancienne et de 2331 à 233 la poubelle. On
                        offre la Land Bank à 9 et la Banque d'Orient à 134. Le Crédit Franco
                        Égyptien 8st demandé à 5 19/32.</p>
                    <p>Le rapport de Comptoir a produit une bonne impression : Action ancienne
                        remonte de 6 31/32 à 7 et la poubelle do 6 23/32 à 6 3/4, pendant que la
                        part de fondateur gagne de son côté anne domi-livre à 50 1/2.</p>
                    <p>Tout le reste de la côte demeure soutenu.</p>
                    <p>On voit par ce bref exposé que la situation de notre corbeille des valeurs
                        est exceptionnellement bonne pour la veille d'une liquidation. Celle-ci
                        d'ailleurs d'annonce de jnar en jour comme plat facile; il n'y a plus guère
                        de positions surchargées. Demain le marché reste fermé à l'occasion de la
                        Toussaint. Il n'y a done plus que deux jours pour liquider on reporter.</p>
                    <p>Un million de Livres sterling. sont arrivées avant-hier à Alexandrie par le
                        Cleopatra,” da Lloyd autrichien. Le Crédit Lyonnais a reçu 400,000 Livre',
                        l'Anglo Egyptian Bank 250,000 Livres, la Banque Impériale.Ottomane 200,000
                        Livres, la Deutsche Orient Back 60,000, le Comptoir Financier et Commercial
                        80,000 Liv. res et le reste pour d'autres établissements financiers
                        d'Egypte. .</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Circulaire 8. De Vries et Boutigny</p>
                    <p>NOTES ET CRITIQUES</p>
                    <p>Le Caire, Octobre 80. Le taux de l'escompte libre à Londres rasta à 5 7/8
                        pour rent. Au Stock Exchange, bier, le Consolide anglais a clôturé avarié à
                        86 118, de même gre l'Unifiée à 104. La National Bank est également demeurée
                        ipohangée &amp; 27 1/2, l'Agricole à 9.7/8 et la Daïra &amp; 17. Senle la
                        Delta Light a gagné 1/8 à 12 1/8.</p>
                    <p>A Paris, l'action Crédit Foncier Égyptien a olótaré en reprise de 3 francs à
                        783 et la Ban. que d'Athènes de 1 franc à 146.</p>
                    <p>Ici, nous avons eu, ce matin, une séance relativement calme, voire quelque
                        peu lourde, ce qui est an offset naturel de la liquidation de fin de moie.
                        Lo tassement a été, il est vrai, pea important, mais il n'est pas impossible
                        qu'il persiste et s'accentue même demain. C mouvement de réaction n'est
                        nullement inquiétant ; tout au contraire, il est plutôt rassurant, et il
                        faut le surveiller attentivement en ce Sens qu'il pourrait bien être le
                        prélude done proche poussée à la reprise. Celle-ci doit, en effet, forcément
                        se produire dans les premiers jours du mois prochain, aussitôt qae. l'argent
                        commencera à être plus abondant. Il y a done lieu de tirer parti des bas
                        coors qui pourraient être pratiqués pour profiter largement de la
                        baisse.</p>
                    <p>Dans le compartiment des Banques, la National a faibli &amp; 27 1/4-5/16 et
                        l'Agricole à 9 3/4 18/16. La Cassa di sconto s'est alourdie $ 210 l'action
                        ancienne et 235 la nouvelle. La Comptoir Financier gat revena à 6 15/16-7
                        l'action angine et 6 11/16 la nouvelle.</p>
                    <p>Le Crédit Foncier a été mieux tena à 7611 782. La Daïra s'est tassée à 16
                        7/8-15/16. La Bébéar a débuté à 46 pour atteindre 47 et actionner à 44 1/2.
                        L'Union Foncière s'est maintep ae 6 1/2-9/16. : La Nile Land s'est inscrite
                        à 16 11916-3/4. L'Immobilière a décliné à 380 381 ; la part de fondateur est
                        restée à 725-730. La part de fondateur Agricole du Nil a avancé à 9
                        5/8-11/16. L'Enterprise and Development a progressé à 18 7/8-15/16 ; la part
                        de fondateur a été traitée $ 22. Les Improvements ont perdu 1/8 8 6 3/16 1/4
                        et les Allotments 1/16 à 3 7/8-15/16 ; lear part de fondateur &amp; Ale hi à
                        163. Les parts de fondateur Gbarbieb Land, dont le prix de c! tore d'hier
                        était . passablement nominal, ont fiait aux abords de 2 1/2.</p>
                    <p>L'action Bat Reprises Immobilières et Travaux a été bien tepu? à 4 1/2-9/16;
                        la part de fondateur a oltaré &amp; 97.</p>
                    <p>Ici, nous avons eu, co matin, une séance relativement calme, voire quelque
                        peu lourde, oo gòi est og offert naturel de la liquidation de fin de moie.
                        Le tassement a été, il est vrai, peu important, mais il n'est pas impossible
                        qu'il persiste et s'accentue même demain. Cs mouvement de réaction n'est
                        nullement inquiétant; tout ça contraire, il est plutôt rassurant, et il faut
                        le surveiller attentivement en ce Sens qu'il pourrait bien être le prélude
                        d'une proche poussée à la reprise. Celle-ci doit, en effet, forcément se
                        produire dans les premiers jours du mois prochain, aussitôt que l'argent
                        commencera à être plus abondant. Il y a dopo lieu de tirer parti des bas
                        coors qui pourraient être pratiqués pour profiter largement de la
                        ba088e.</p>
                    <p>Dans le compartiment des Banques, la National a faibli &amp; 97 1/4-5/16 et
                        l'Agricole à 9 3/4 18/16. La Cassa di sconto s'est alourdie</p>
                    <p>210 l'action ancienne et 235 la nouvelle. Le Comptoir Financier et revenu à 6
                        15/16-7 l'action angine et 6 11/16 la nouvelle.</p>
                    <p>Le Crédit Foncier a été mieux tona à 761.) 782. LA D'airs s'est tassée à 16
                        7/8-15/16. Behera a débuté à 46 pour atteindre 47 et actionner à 44 1/2.
                        L'Union Foncière s'est mainte pao &amp; 6 1/2-9/16. : La Nile Land s'est
                        inscrite Å 16 11/16-3/4. L'Immobilière a décliné à 380 381 ; la part de
                        fondateur est restée à 725-730. La part de fon. dateur Agricole da Nil a
                        avancé à 9 5/8-11/16. L'Enterprise and Development a progressé à 12
                        7/8-15/16 ; la part de fondateur a été traitée $ 22. Les Ináprovements ont
                        perdu 1/8 8 6 3/16 1/4 et les Allotments 1/16 à 3 7/8-15/16 ; lear part de
                        fondateur &amp; flé bi à 163. Les parts de fondateur Gharbieh Land, dont le
                        prix de o! tare d'hier était . passablement nominal, ont fiait aux abords de
                        21/3.</p>
                    <p>L'action Bat Reprises Immobilières et Travaux a été bien tepu? à 4 1/2-9/16;
                        la part de fondateur &amp; olótaré &amp; 97.</p>
                    <p>L'action Brasserie des Pyramides, qui était depuis longtemps négligée, &amp;
                        avancé de 3 france à 135; la part de dividende a bénéficié de 7 francs à
                        75.</p>
                    <p>L'Express Nile a é é négocié à 4 1/8 et 18 part de fondateur $ 109 Los
                        Automobiles ont Mecbi à 6 1/8-3/16 et la part de fondateur 2 1.</p>
                    <p>Dans le groupe des valeurs hôtelières, les Manovich 36 sont alourdis à 18
                        8/8, les Egyptian á 75,16 318 et les Upper Egypt à 5 9/16-5/8. Les Excelsior
                        ont faibli à 4 7/16 et leur part de fondateur d 2 1/16. La part de fondateur
                        National Hotel &amp; éé cotée 82.</p>
                    <p>Parmi les petites valeurs, la Delta Land a été ramenée à 4 1/82 pour finir á
                        41/16, Port mouvement gar les Estates, qoi ont baissé à 2 3/16 par saite de
                        gros ventos; leur part de fondateur a filéobi à 15 5/16-3/8. Les New
                        Egyptian ont faibli &amp; 33 sh. 6, les Salt and Soda à 23 sh. 6, les
                        Constructions à 1 5/8 et le. Walker and Meizoaracbi &amp; 0 3/4. Les
                        Abdy</p>
                    <p>Ici, nous avons eu, co matin, une séance relativement calme, voire quelque
                        peu lourde, oo gòi est og offert naturel de la liquidation de fin de moie.
                        Le tassement a été, il est vrai, peu important, mais il n'est pas impossible
                        qu'il persiste et s'accentue même demain. Cs mouvement de réaction n'est
                        nullement inquiétant; tout ça contraire, il est plutôt rassurant, et il faut
                        le surveiller attentivement en ce Sens qu'il pourrait bien être le prélude
                        d'une proche poussée à la reprise. Celle-ci doit, en effet, forcément se
                        produire dans les premiers jours du mois prochain, aussitôt que l'argent
                        commencera à être plus abondant. Il y a dopo lieu de tirer parti des bas
                        coors qui pourraient être pratiqués pour profiter largement de la
                        ba088e.</p>
                    <p>Dans le compartiment des Banques, la National a faibli &amp; 97 1/4-5/16 et
                        l'Agricole à 9 3/4 18/16. La Cassa di sconto s'est alourdie</p>
                    <p>210 l'action ancienne et 235 la nouvelle. Le Comptoir Financier et revenu à 6
                        15/16-7 l'action angine et 6 11/16 la nouvelle.</p>
                    <p>Le Crédit Foncier a été mieux tona à 761.) 782. LA D'airs s'est tassée à 16
                        7/8-15/16. Behera a débuté à 46 pour atteindre 47 et actionner à 44 1/2.
                        L'Union Foncière s'est mainte pao &amp; 6 1/2-9/16. : La Nile Land s'est
                        inscrite Å 16 11/16-3/4. L'Immobilière a décliné à 380 381 ; la part de
                        fondateur est restée à 725-730. La part de fon. dateur Agricole da Nil a
                        avancé à 9 5/8-11/16. L'Enterprise and Development a progressé à 12
                        7/8-15/16 ; la part de fondateur a été traitée $ 22. Les Ináprovements ont
                        perdu 1/8 8 6 3/16 1/4 et les Allotments 1/16 à 3 7/8-15/16 ; lear part de
                        fondateur &amp; flé bi à 163. Les parts de fondateur Gharbieh Land, dont le
                        prix de o! tare d'hier était . passablement nominal, ont fiait aux abords de
                        21/3.</p>
                    <p>L'action Bat Reprises Immobilières et Travaux a été bien tepu? à 4 1/2-9/16;
                        la part de fondateur &amp; olótaré &amp; 97.</p>
                    <p>L'action Brasserie des Pyramides, qui était depuis longtemps négligée, &amp;
                        avancé de 3 france à 135; la part de dividende a bénéficié de 7 francs à
                        75.</p>
                    <p>L'Express Nile a é é négocié à 4 1/8 et 18 part de fondateur $ 109 Los
                        Automobiles ont Mecbi à 6 1/8-3/16 et la part de fondateur 2 1.</p>
                    <p>Dans le groupe des valeurs hôtelières, les Manovich 36 sont alourdis à 18
                        8/8, les Egyptian á 75,16 318 et les Upper Egypt à 5 9/16-5/8. Les Excelsior
                        ont faibli à 4 7/16 et leur part de fondateur d 2 1/16. La part de fondateur
                        National Hotel &amp; éé cotée 82.</p>
                    <p>Parmi les petites valeurs, la Delta Land a été ramenée à 4 1/82 pour finir á
                        41/16, Port mouvement gar les Estates, qoi ont baissé à 2 3/16 par saite de
                        gros ventos; leur part de fondateur a filéobi à 15 5/16-3/8. Les New
                        Egyptian ont faibli &amp; 33 sh. 6, les Salt and Soda à 23 sh. 6, les
                        Constructions à 1 5/8 et le. Walker and Meizoaracbi &amp; 0 3/4. Les Abdy
                            <cb n="2"/> se sont raffermis à 1 1/4-5/16, la Khedivial Mail à 36 sh.
                        et les Cotton Mille à 6 sh. 3. </p>
                    <p> Nous détachons d'ane lettre de Paris, en date da 23 Octobre, le passage
                        suivant: </p>
                    <p> "La situation monétaire générale continue être l'objet des préoccápations de
                        notre place. La nouvelle a coaro anjourd'hui que la Banque de France est
                        prête à mettre à la disposition de la Banqoe d'Angleterre 200 millions d'or,
                        ce qni permettrait au conseil de celle-ci de rameper l'escompte à 5 %. Dans
                        008 conditions, op soppose que la Banque de France ne serait pas obligée de
                        porter à 3 1/2 og 4 % le taux offi: ciel de l'escompte frauçuis, et cette
                        combinaison aurait la plus heureose influence ear le marché. </p>
                    <p> "La chose essentielle, toutefois, pour que la situation monétaire se détende
                        réellement, c'est que l'Amérique voie Cessar an état de pénurie qui se
                        répercate sur le marché international. A New-York, incontestablement, le
                        marché est gêné, mais M. Shaw a tout ce qu'il lui faut entre les mains pour
                        lai venir en aide, lorsqu'il sera décidé à le faire. Les autres facteurs
                        qu'il faudrait faira optrer en ligne de compte, cele que les demandes d'or
                        passagères de l’Egypte, sont beaucoup moins importants." </p>
                    <p> On annonce d'Alexandrie qu'a l'assemblée générale des actionnaires da
                        Comptoir Finan. cier d'Egypte, tenag bier soir, toates les propcsitions da
                        Conseil d'administration ont été approarées à l'unanimité. Le dividende
                        annoel qoi sera réparti pour l'exercice clos le 31 Jaillet 1906 sera de 12 %
                        pour les actions de capital et de 2 livres pour les parts de fondatear. </p>
                    <p> Les actionnaires de la Compagnie des Bateaux Omnibus sont convoqués-on
                        assemblée générale au Caire pour le 20 Novembro prochain. A l'ordre da jour
                        : Rapport de conseil d'administration sur l'exercice clos le 3 Sep. tembro
                        1906 ; présentation da bilan et do compte des profits et portes ;
                        répartition des bénéfices ; nominations Stato tairos. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="shippingMovements">
                    <head> SHIPPING MOVEMENTS. </head>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIA HARBOUR. </p>
                    <p> ARBIVALS. </p>
                    <p> October 80. Alep, Ott. 8. Capt. Cassar, Larnaca and Mer </p>
                    <p> sina, Viterbo. Memfi, Itál. e. Capt. Di Benedetto, Boyroatb </p>
                    <p> and Jaffa, Florio Rabattino. Birman, Brit. s. Capt. Hopkins, Port Said, </p>
                    <p> Barber &amp; Son. </p>
                    <p> DEPARTURES </p>
                    <p> October 30. Bana, Ital. s. Capt. Me:lo, Genoa. Emp. Nicolas, Raz. s. Capt.
                        Boarakoff, Piros </p>
                    <p> and Odesga. Löfkosia, Greek s. Capt. Eliadis, Cyprag. Bear, Brit. g. Capt.
                        Harris, Cyprus. Galaxidion, Greek 8. Capt. Merlas, Trebizonda. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests">
                    <head>EXPORT MANIFESTS.</head>
                    <p>Por Pont Sard, by the 8:8. Bosforo, sailed on the 22nd Ootober :</p>
                    <p>FOR BOMBAY Carver Broe. &amp; Co. Ltd, 70 bales cotton E Mallison &amp; Co.,
                        30, ,</p>
                    <p>100 bales cotton FOB VARIOUS PORTS Various, 7 packages sundries Por PrRÆUS
                        and ODESSA, by the 8.8. Reine</p>
                    <p>Olga, sailed on the 23rd October : Various, 20 bags cocoa nats, 2,016 cases
                        dates,</p>
                    <p>38 packages sundries E. Mallison &amp; Co.,' 300 bales cotton G. Praager
                        &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>100 G. Riecken &amp; Co., 100 .P.C. Baines &amp; Co., Choremi, Benachi &amp;
                        Co., R. &amp;0. Lindemann, Mohr &amp; Pender!, 65 Carver Bros. &amp; Co.
                        Ltd, 110</p>
                    <p>· 105</p>
                    <p>11</p>
                    <p>200</p>
                    <p>280</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>1,260 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>FOR BATOUM F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 50 bales cotton Por CYPRUB, by the 8.8.
                        Lefkossia, sailed in</p>
                    <p>the 23rd October : Various, 200 packages sondries : For ENGLAND, by the 8.8.
                        Vera, sailed on the | 23rd October : ' Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 2,850
                        tons cotton</p>
                    <p>seed For BRINDISI and TRIESTE, by the 8.8. Maria | Teresa, sailed on the 24th
                        October : :". G. Petracobi &amp; Co., 32 bales cotton F. Andres,</p>
                    <p>60</p>
                    <p>. 92 bales cotton</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Eastern Telegraph Co. Ltd. .</p>
                    <p>AVERAGE TIME occupied in transmission of Egypt</p>
                    <p>ian telegrams from England to Alexandria on the 30th October, 1906.</p>
                    <p>OUTWARDS.</p>
                    <p>Botwoon the hours of 10 a.m. and 6 p.m</p>
                    <p>(Calro timo)</p>
                    <p>MESSAGES HANDED IN ATFROM</p>
                    <p>The Company'sOfficer</p>
                    <p>Postal Telegraph Offices.</p>
                    <p>H.M. H.M. London... Liverpool Manchester ... Glasgow .. Other Provincial
                        Offices</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> Prix des sacs.</p>
                    <p> Qualits indiennd : A coton de 8 livres P.T. 5 1/2 Acero </p>
                    <p>" "</p>
                    <p>5 3/4 A Céréales , 2}</p>
                    <p>1 .2 8 10/40 · 37 · 3 85/40</p>
                    <p>. . 5 3/4</p>
                    <p>c.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Cloture de la Bourse Khediviale</p>
                    <p>CONTRATS Cours de l'Association des Courtiers en Marchandises Coton
                        F.O.F.Br.</p>
                    <p>6h. p.m. Novembre 1907 .. ... Tal. 16 25/32 4 - 13/16 Novembre... ... ... "
                        17 3/4 „ - 25/32 Janvier. ... ... ... ... . 18 - » - Mars ...</p>
                    <p>.........., 18 5/16 , - - Mai ... ... ... ... 18 23/32 ,,- - Juillet</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton Novembre Décembre-Jan. P.T. 67 20/40 à -25/40 Février Mars
                        ... ... ... , 69 15/40 ,- 20/40</p>
                    <p>Feves Saidi Novembre Décembre-Jan. P.T. 114 d 116 -</p>
                    <p>REMARQUES Colon.--Recolte actuelle.-La seance de l'après-midi a debute ferme
                        et en hausse, mais a cloture faible. Pas beaucoup d'affaires. L'Amérique n'a
                        pas repondu a l'attente des hausaiers.</p>
                    <p>Dans la matinee prix plus haut pour Novembre tallaris 17 27/32 à --; plus bas
                        pour novembre 1717/32 -1- Dans l'après-midi prix plus haut pour novembre 17
                        29/32 $ -; plus bas pour novembre 17 3/4 -</p>
                    <p>N.B.-Reports—Sans changement .</p>
                    <p>Au moment de la clôture, les nouvelles étaient les suivantes :</p>
                    <p>Liverpool, coton égyptien disponible : 9 10/16. Futurs octobre : 9 28/64.</p>
                    <p>Liverpool : coton américain : 'Futurs oct. nov.: 6.61. Futurs janvier-fevrier
                        : 5.57.. New-York : coton américain : Futurs : janvier: 10.28</p>
                    <p>mai: 10.55 Graines de coton.-Récolte actuelle.-Negligees mais bien
                        tenuse.</p>
                    <p>Dans la matinée prix plus haut pour 3 mois P.T. 67 6/40 8 -- ; plus bas pour
                        3 mois 66 25/40.- Dans l'après-midi, prix plus haut pour 3 mois 67 20/40 á
                        -- ; plus bas pour 3 mois 6710/40 8 ---- N,B.-Reports-Sans changement</p>
                    <p>Bateaux partis : Octobre</p>
                    <p>Destination Tonnes 18 Sylverton</p>
                    <p>Sharpness 3211 18 Anatolia</p>
                    <p>Rotterdam 400 19 Sardinia</p>
                    <p>Liverpool 458 20 Oity of Cambridge</p>
                    <p>Manchester 500 21 Menephtah</p>
                    <p>Liverpool 510 23 Vera</p>
                    <p>Bristol</p>
                    <p>2850 25 Dawlais</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>4215 25 Norwood</p>
                    <p>Bristol 2500 Bateaur sous chargement : Persian</p>
                    <p>Liverpool</p>
                    <p>800 Avon</p>
                    <p>Liverpool Craigendorn</p>
                    <p>Londres 3000 Hull</p>
                    <p>4000 Antonio</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>3200 Queensborough</p>
                    <p>Londres</p>
                    <p>4000 Royal Prince</p>
                    <p>Dunkerque 1000 Hartburn</p>
                    <p>U.K.</p>
                    <p>2500 Sailor Prince</p>
                    <p>Manchester 100 Treversa</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>3000 Andros</p>
                    <p>Hambourg</p>
                    <p>1100 Pharos</p>
                    <p>Liverpool</p>
                    <p>200 Assiout</p>
                    <p>Liverpool 100 Calvocoressi</p>
                    <p>Marseille 1700 Hesleyside</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>3000 Bateaux attendus : Birnam</p>
                    <p>Nantes</p>
                    <p>2500 Colenso</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>4000 Clio</p>
                    <p>Hull</p>
                    <p>2500 Hull</p>
                    <p>4500 Alexandrie, le 30 octobre 1906.</p>
                    <p>ToroVige</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>COTONS copie de la dépêche</p>
                    <p>DE L'ALEXANDBIA GENERAL PRODUOR A8SOCIATION</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL OOTTON ASSOCIATION</p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués hier soir à 5h. p.m. d la Bourse Khédiviale.) Tal. 17 27/32
                        Livraison Novembre » 18 1/32</p>
                    <p>Janvier , 18 3/8</p>
                    <p>. Mars 18 3/4 Marché ferme</p>
                    <p>Mai</p>
                    <p>(Cours clôture d'hier soir à 6h. p.m. affichés par Association des Courtiers
                        en Marchandises à la Bourse Khédiviale). Tel. 17 3/4 Livraison Novembre</p>
                    <p>Janvier , 18 5/16 ., Mars</p>
                    <p>, 18 2.3/32 , Mai Marché steady</p>
                    <p>.)</p>
                    <p>18</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>(Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khédiviale à Ph.45 m.) Tal. 17 21/32
                        Livraison Novembre 1 17 27/32 1 Janvier 18 6/32</p>
                    <p>Mars 18 17/32 , Mai Marché ferme Arrivages de ce jour, à Minet-el, Bassal,
                        can. 61.648</p>
                    <p>Cours pratiqués ce jour à la Bourse Khód. a 12h.45 p.m. Tal. 17 17/32
                        Livraison Novembre » 17 3/4</p>
                    <p>Janvier , 18 1/16</p>
                    <p>Mars , 18 15/32</p>
                    <p>Mai Marché quiet</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MARCHE DE MINET-EL-BASSAL</head>
                    <p>31 octobre 1906.-(114.55 a.m.) Colons.-Clôture du marché du 30 octobre :
                        Fermes.</p>
                    <p>BEURRES Fair. Fully Fair, Good Fair, Fully Good Fair et Good : Sans
                        changement</p>
                    <p>HAUTE-EGYPTE ET YAYOUM Fair, Fully Fair, Good Fair, Fully Good Fair et Good :
                        Sans changement</p>
                    <p>ABA891 Fully Good Fair, Good et Extra : Sans changement</p>
                    <p>JOANNOVICH Fully Good Fair, Good et Extra : Sans changement</p>
                    <p>Etat du marché de ce jour, cotons : Lourd et kaissant.</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages de ce jour se chiffrent par cantars 18923 contre même jour
                        l'année précédente san. 39127. Graines de coton.-Sans changement</p>
                    <p>Disponible</p>
                    <p>Ticket Mit-Afifi-65</p>
                    <p>Rien Haute-Egypte.--64</p>
                    <p>Rien Bida.-Fermes Qualite Saïdi.---Cond. Saha P.T. - --</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">, Behera : , , 105, 116 Fèves.--Marche nul Saïdi :
                            Disponible. Fayoum : Disponible. Qualile Saïdi. Cond. Saha P.T. 120
                            &amp; 125</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Behéru .. Lentilles.Fermes Disponible : Rien</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. 130 a 186 Orges.-Soutenues</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. 65 &amp; 68</p>
                    <cb n="4"/>
                    <p>Mais.-Soutenus Disponible : Rien.</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. 80 a 85</p>
                    <p>Exportation du 30 oct. Cotton Ball. 2266 Gr. de cot. Ard. 6171 Fèves</p>
                    <p>.</p>
                    <p>dep. le 26 oct.</p>
                    <p>Bal. 15323 Ard. 107851</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Exportations probables de la semaine</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>1906 1906 Coton - ... ... ... Bal. 35,000 27,700 Graines de coton ...
                        Ard.150,000 146,000 Fèves .........."</p>
                    <p>DOMAINES DE L'ETAT (Agence d'Alexandrie)</p>
                    <p>Arrivages Coton.-Balles 70—cantars 445-provenance Sakha Graines de
                        coton.-Ardennes 482-provenance Sakha</p>
                    <p>Les prix suivants ont été prati grito ce jour :</p>
                    <p>OOTON</p>
                    <p>O.X.B. (BABSZ-EGYPTE)</p>
                    <p>Province Béhéra Damanhour... ... ... ... De P.T. 336 346</p>
                    <p>Province Garbieh Kafr-Zayat ... ... ... ... De P.T. 355 360 | Tantah... ...
                        ... ... ... . 355 360 •</p>
                    <p>Province Menu fish Menon. ... ... ... ... De P.T. 340 4.365</p>
                    <p>(MOYENNE-EGYPTE)</p>
                    <p>Provinco Fayoum Fayoum.. ... ... ... ... De P.T: 300 – 312%</p>
                    <p>(HAUTE-EGYPTE) Beni Suef ... ... ... ... De P.T. 315 8 320 Bibeh ... ... ...
                        ... ...</p>
                    <p>- Minieh... ... ... ... ... "</p>
                    <p>SECTION DES GRAINES ET CÉRÉALES PRIX FRANOO.BTATION : DISPONIBLE TIOKET
                        Graines de coton Afifi... P.T. 65 - P.T. -</p>
                    <p>, Haute-Egypte..., 64 — , B16 Saidi.. ... Fèves-Saldi ...</p>
                    <p>Fayoumi .......</p>
                    <p>330</p>
                    <p>ARRIVAGES</p>
                    <p>du mercredi 31 octobre 1906 Documents de l'"Alexandria General Produce
                        A8A0G."</p>
                    <p>CHEMINS DE YER BARQUES Cotons ... ... ... ... S/B 6456 Graines de coton ...
                        ... sacs 24571 Blés Sardi...</p>
                    <p>230 Béhéra</p>
                    <p>43 Fèves Saidi</p>
                    <p>Behera ... ... ... Orge ... ... ... ... .. Mars ... ... ... ... ... Lentilles
                        ... · Colons-Total dos arrivages depuis le ler septembre 1906 jusqu'à ce
                        jour, cantars 1,617,784</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton.-Total des arrivages depuis le ler "septembre 1906 jusqu'à
                        ce jour Ard. 918,619. Contre mbime jour en 1906 :</p>
                    <p>DARQUES ET CHEMINS DE PER Coton ........... ..</p>
                    <p>... ... S/B 6713 Graines de coton....</p>
                    <p>... ... sacs 16699 | Bles Saidi ..........</p>
                    <p>12! T. Béhéra.. ... ...</p>
                    <p>""". ... ... ... ... 99 Fèves Saidi...</p>
                    <p>1 Behera ... ... Orge .. . " ** Mais ... ... ... Lentilles. ... ... ... ...
                        ... ... ...</p>
                    <p>Cotona.-Total dos arrivages depuis le ler septembre 1906 jusqu'à ce jour,
                        cantars 1,220,882%</p>
                    <p>Oraines de colon.-Total des arrivages depuis le ler septembre 1906 jusqu'à ce
                        jour, ardens 687,978.</p>
                    <p>268</p>
                    <p>18 /2</p>
                    <p>Cours de la Bourse de Minet-el-Bassa! Ooton F.G.F.Br.</p>
                    <p>Novembre 1907. ... ... Tal. 16 6/8 A 21/32 Novembre ... ... , 17 9/16
                        ,Janvier ... ... ... ... 17 3/4 - Mars... ... ... ....... 18 1/16 Mai...</p>
                    <p>Juillet ...... ... » 18 13/16 - Graines de coton</p>
                    <p>Nov.-Décembre Janvier.. P.T. 67 - -</p>
                    <p>Février Mars ... ... .. , 68 35/40 ,Fèves-Saïdi Nov.-Décembre Janvier.. P.T.
                        114 - „ 116</p>
                    <p>BENARQUES : Coton.-Récolte actuelle:--La faiblesse predomine et les cours
                        perdent graduellement du terrain. Premier cours novembre 17 21/32.</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton. ---Récolte actuello-Marche lourd et baissant. Prix
                        d'ouverture 67.</p>
                    <p>Pèves-Saidi.-Réoolte actuelle.—Marché nul,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BXTBRIBUR</head>
                    <p>Dépêches particulières du 30 octobre 1906 ..PRODUITS EGYPTIENS</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL Coton.--Etat du Marché. --Soutenu Disponible.-9 10/16
                        Futura.--octobre : 9 28/64 (8/64 de hausse)</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL Graines de coton.-Soutenues Fèves.-Néant</p>
                    <p>HULL Graines de colors.--Faibles Fèves.---Marché nul'</p>
                    <p>LONDRES Graines de colon. -Calmes</p>
                    <p>COTON AMERICAIN</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL Futurs oct. nov. : 5.61 (6 points de hausse)</p>
                    <p>. jan.-fév. : 5.69 (5 points de hausse) Disponible : 5.93 (8 points de
                        hausse)</p>
                    <p>NEW-YORK Middling Upland : 10.50 Futurs janvier : 10.15 (1 point de
                        baisse)</p>
                    <p>. mai: 10.43 (1 point de baisse) Arrivages du jour, balles 115,000 Contra
                        même jour, l'année dernière, balles 95,000</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>To-day's Exchange Quotations</p>
                    <p>Banks' selling 97 A 95</p>
                    <p>384.</p>
                    <p>385 %</p>
                    <p>381 %</p>
                    <p>382 %</p>
                    <p>*</p>
                    <p>Banks'</p>
                    <p>buying London cheque ... ... ... ... 96'</p>
                    <p>3m. bark paper ...... 96 X . , 3m. house paper</p>
                    <p>95 % Paris chaque ... ... ...</p>
                    <p>, 3m. bank paper ... ...</p>
                    <p>i Bun. house paper ...... Switzerland cheque .......</p>
                    <p>8m. bank paper ... Germany cheque ... ... .... 4 472 %</p>
                    <p>is 3m. bank paper ... ... Italian cheque ... ... ... ... 386 Vienna &amp;
                        Trieste cheque ... ... 402 Constantinople choque... ....... 88</p>
                    <p>"Leas one per mille brokerage,</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMLEH RAILWAY COMPANY</head>
                    <p>RECETTES du dimanche 21 octobre au samedi 27 oct. 1906</p>
                    <p>Carnets Billets Aboanements et divers Totaux</p>
                    <p>L.L. L.E. Année courante 788</p>
                    <p>14</p>
                    <p>187 989 „ dernière 733 11150 934 Augmentation 151 3</p>
                    <p>37</p>
                    <p>56</p>
                    <p>du ler octobre 1906 au samedi 27 octobre 1906</p>
                    <p>Carnets Billets Abonnements et divers Totaux</p>
                    <p>LE Année courante 3658 518</p>
                    <p>860</p>
                    <p>5036 . dernière 3360 290 620 4270 Augmentation 298</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">240 766</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>LE</p>
                    <p>209</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHARE LIST</head>
                    <p>(88UBD BY THE "ASSOCIATION DES COURTIERS</p>
                    <p>ET VALEURS D'ALEXANDRIE.”</p>
                    <p>es .</p>
                    <p>1</p>
                    <p>22</p>
                    <p>Cisture d'aujourd'hui à 12h.30 p.m.' Agric. Bank of Egypt ... ... Lat. 9
                        National Bank of Egypt ... 27 Ramleh Railway ... ....... 7 Egyptian Delta
                        Railways ..., Tramways d'Alex andrie ...</p>
                    <p>Fos. 1</p>
                    <p>Div.... Alexandria Water ... ... ... Lst. Eaux du Caire ... ... ... Fos.</p>
                    <p>. . Jouissance Dairs Sanieh ... ... ... ...</p>
                    <p>.. Lat. Béhéra ... ... ... ... ... L.E. Bourse Khediviale ... ... ... Lest.
                        Egyptian Markets ... ... ... Anglo-Egyptian Spinning ..., Bière d'Alexandrie
                        Privilégiées Fcs.</p>
                    <p>n . Dividendes Bière du Caire Privilégiées ...</p>
                    <p>' , Dividendes ..., Egyptian Cotton Mills ... ... Lest. Egyptian Salt &amp;
                        Suda ... ... Pressage ... ... ... ... ... » Presses Libres..." Oblig. Crédit
                        Foncier Egyp</p>
                    <p>tien. 3 % 1886.. ... ... ... Oblig. Credit Foncier Egyp</p>
                    <p>tien 3 % 1903., ........ Lots Turcs ... ... ... ... Banque Nationals de Grèce
                        ..., Cages di Sconto ....</p>
                    <p>- Nouvelle Anglo-American, Nile .... ... Banque d'Athènes.. ... ... . Fos. 14
                        Deferred Delta ... ... ... Lot. Nungovich Hotels ... ... ... Delta Land
                        .......... Nile Land... ... Suor. et. Raffinerie d'Egypto... Fos. Khedivial
                        Mail Preference ... .</p>
                    <p>Ordinary Egypt. Invest. &amp; Agency Ltd, Land Banks ... Land Investment ...
                        ... Trust.... ... ... ... *** Estates ... ... ... .. Splendid Hotels Cheik
                        Fadl ... Entreprises Urbaines ...... Lat. Comptoir Financier ......</p>
                    <p>parts de fondateurs, Building Lands ........... Delta and Upper Egypt.......
                        Union Foncière d'Egypt Bank of Abyssinis... ... ... Société Electrique de la
                        Basse.</p>
                    <p>Egypte......... ... - Banco di Roma ... ... ... Fos. 113 Orédit
                        Franco-Egyption.. ... Lst. 5 H. Banque d'Orient ... ... ... Fos. 133 -</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REUTERS' TELEGRAMS.</head>
                    <p>CLOSING REPORTS.</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, October 30, 12.50 p.m. Sales of the day ... ... ... ... ... ...
                        bales 7,000 Of which Egyptian ... ... ... ... ... 200 American new maize,
                        Spot per cental ... 4/4 % American futures (November December).. 5.69</p>
                    <p>» (March-April). ... ... 5.68 American middling ... ... ... ... ... 5.93
                        Egyptian fully good fair, delivery (October) 9 28/64</p>
                    <p>(November) 9 17/64</p>
                    <p>(January) 92/64</p>
                    <p>» (March) 9 2/64 Egyptian Brown fair (per lb. d.) ... ... ... 8 6/16</p>
                    <p>. good fair ... ... ... ... 8 14/16 ,</p>
                    <p>good ... ... .. ... ..10 3/16</p>
                    <p>fully good fair ... ... ... 9 10/16 Egyptian saidi beans (new por 480 lbs)
                        -|- . Arrivals from Egypt S.S. Pavia 3878 bales of cotton</p>
                    <p>New York, October 30. Spot Cotton ... ... ... ... ... ... ... ... 10.50
                        American Futures (November)............. 10.08</p>
                    <p>. (December)... ... ... ... 10.08</p>
                    <p>(March) ... ... ... ... 10.33</p>
                    <p>, (April)... ....... ... ... 10.37 Cable transfers ... ... ... ... ... ...
                        dol. 4.86% Cotton day's receipts at all U.S. Porta, ... bales 115,000</p>
                    <p>- New ORLEANS, October 30. Cotton Spot ... ... ... ... ... ... ... 106/16</p>
                    <p>: Futures December ... ... ... ... 10.10 . January .. ... ... ... ...
                        10.17</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL, October 30. American futures (November December) ... 5.56</p>
                    <p>LONDON, October 30. Par Silver (per oz d). ... ... ... ... ... 32 7/16
                        Private discount (3 month bills)... Consols (November)... Egyptian Unified
                        ...... Turkish Unified Rio Tinto ... . New Daira... ... ... ... Agricultural
                        Bank ... ... National Bank of Egypt... Rand Mines New ... ... ... Chartereds
                        of S. Africa ... ... ...</p>
                    <p>1 1832 Nile Valley Gold Mine ... ... ... New - 8/32 New Egyptians, ... ...
                        ... ...</p>
                    <p>1 21/32 The Western Oasis Corporation 10/32 premium Delta Light (Bearer
                        Sheres) ... Egyptian Railway ......</p>
                    <p>, Domain Ottoman Defence Italian Rents 4 0/0 ... ... .. Greek Monopoly ...
                        ... ... ... ... * Greek Bend 4 oso Ottoman Bank... ..</p>
                    <p>... ... ... 16 % Egyptian oot. seed to Hull (October) 6 13/16 sellers Jerman
                        Beet Sugar (October)... ... ... ... 8/8 % €140,000 were paid into the Bank
                        to-day</p>
                    <p>PARIS, October 30. Banque d'Athènes ...</p>
                    <p>... 146Crédit Foncier Egyptien ... Prédit Lyonnais . ... ... ... Comptoir
                        National d'Escompte ...... Land Bank of Egypt... ... Ottoman Bank ...</p>
                    <p>ote Turos ... ... ... ... *** Theque on London ...... ugar White No. 3
                        (October)...... Banque de Salonique ...</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">... 75</hi>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Telegramme Havas</p>
                    <p>4470.</p>
                    <p>BOURSE du 30 octobre 1906</p>
                    <p>QOURS DES VALEURS A TERME, CUTUBE - PARIS . . Rente Francaise 30% ...</p>
                    <p>Fr. 95 70 Dette Egyptienne Unifiée</p>
                    <p>106 30 Extérieur Espagnol.... ... ...</p>
                    <p>94 87 Russe consolidé..... .....</p>
                    <p>73 80 Actions de Suez... ... ... ... Crédit Foncier Egyptien Orédit Lyonnais
                        ...... Comptoir National d°Escompte Banque Ottomane .......... Land Bank of
                        Egypt ...... Banque d'Athènes ... ... ... ... Banque d'Abyssinie
                        ........</p>
                    <p>. 14 Crédit Franco-Bgyptien..... ....... 140 - Change sur Londres ... ... ...
                        ... 25 23</p>
                    <p>LONDRES Consolidés anglais ... ... ... ... ... £ 86 | Escomptes-Paris 3%.
                        Londres 6 0/0, Berlin 6.9%</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ASSOCIATION DES COURTIERS EN MARCHANDISES</head>
                    <p>(Service spécial) , DEPECHE D'OUVERTURE</p>
                    <p>LIVERPOOL 10h. 8.m. Américain Futurs : octobre novembre : - janvier-février :
                        5.47</p>
                    <p>Seconde Dépêche, 10.5 mm. Futurs : octobre novembre : - .. janvier-février :
                        5.50</p>
                    <p>Troisième Dépêche, 10b.10 a.m. Futurs : octobre novembre : 5.50
                        janvier-février : 5.48</p>
                    <p>Quatrième Depêche. 10h.15 a.m. Futurs : octobre-noverabre : 6.50</p>
                    <p>► janvier-fevrier : 6.51</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>DERNIERE HEURE (Clôture de la Bourse Khediviale 1 h. p.m.) Cours de
                        l'Association des Courtiers en Marchandises</p>
                    <p>Colon F.G.F.Br. Novembre 1907 ...N.R. Tal. 16 21/32 . - 11/16 Novembre... ...
                        ... ... ► 17 19/32 - 5/8 Janvier ............. 17 25/32 , - 13/16 Mars ...
                        ... ... ... ... 18 3/32 , - 1/8 Mai ................ 18 1/2 - 17/32
                        Juillet... ... ... ... ... , 18 25/32 , - --</p>
                    <p>Graines de coton Novembre Décembre-Jan. P.T. 67 5/40 4 - 10/40 Février Mars
                        ... ... ... , 69 -</p>
                    <p>Feves-Saïdi Novembre-Décembre-Jan. P.T. 114 – 116 -</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BOURSE DU CAIRE</head>
                    <p>Le Caire, le 30 Octobre 1906.</p>
                    <p>Banques</p>
                    <p>Actions Jouissances</p>
                    <p>Ooligations Fondateurs, Agricultural Bank of Egypt 6 9 X H 940 Banque
                        d'Athènes . ."'Fos. 145-146 National Bank of Egypt £ 27 X Cassa di
                        Soonto</p>
                    <p>Frs. 240 , Nouv. Emis. Frs. 235 - Land Bank</p>
                    <p>£ 9 - Comptoir Finano &amp; Comm. £ 61-7</p>
                    <p>Nouv. Emis. € 6 H Banque d'Aby winie £ 6 .tt Banque d'Orient</p>
                    <p>Fra: 133-131</p>
                    <p>Alex. &amp; Ramleh Railway 7%</p>
                    <p>oblig. 500 € 102 - Delta Light Railway</p>
                    <p>12-12 m Lots Turos obligations Frs. 149 --</p>
                    <p>· Societes des Eaux Alexandria Water Company £ . 13 Eaux du Caire part
                        capital Frs. 122.123 8 73-74 Eaux de Tantah . 8 km.</p>
                    <p>Societes Foncieres Daira Sanieh Nouvelle £ 16 74-14 100 Crédit Foncier
                        Egyptien Frs. 781-782 980 Crédit Fon. ob. 3o/o à Lots Fr. 336-337 Cr.
                        Foncierob. Nouv.Emis. Frs. 269-270 Cr. Foncier ob. 3/2 0% Frs. 500 - Sec.
                        Agricole &amp; Ind. 5.00 Frs. 975 - Société Agricole &amp; Ind. 4 0/0 Frs.
                        515 Caisse Hyp. d'Egypte Frs. 556 - Sociéte Anonyme du Behera L.E. 44% Ste
                        An. de Behera obligat. LE 5 - Societe Fonciere d'Egypte L.E.31 - Delta Land
                        Company Wardan Estate</p>
                    <p>£ 6 74-H 8 -9 Vile Land</p>
                    <p>£ 16 H- 4</p>
                    <p>80 n. Egyptian Estates Limited</p>
                    <p>2 to 15 H Union Fonciere</p>
                    <p>€ 6% 23. Anglo-Eg. Land Allotment L.E.3 7.4 P.T. 163 Gharbieh Land</p>
                    <p>L.E. 3 %-H LE. 2% Societes Immobilieres Cie. Immobilière d'Egypte Frs.
                        380-381 725-50 Agricole du Nil</p>
                    <p>Frs. 266 - 9H Improvements Corporation £ 6 A-X Enterprise and Development
                        LE.12 7-H Urbaines et Rurales . £ 6 .9. 15 Entreprises Im. et Traveux L.E.4
                        %-% P.T. 97</p>
                    <p>Societes Industrielles Anglo-Eg. Spinning : € 0% 2% Crown Brewery d'A·lex.
                        Frs: 227-228 130 Crown Brewery du Caire Frs. 136 Egyptian Cotton Mills</p>
                    <p>6/-6/3 Egyptian Salt and Soda £ 23/6-23/9 Ste dos Ciments d'Egypte. Frs.
                        70</p>
                    <p>12.18 Sucreries et Raffinerie Frs. 24-25 Ibrahimieh Ploughing Co. £ -- Port
                        Said Salt Association £ 16/6 Nile Cold Storage Egyptian Markets £
                        271-27-3</p>
                    <p>Navigation à Vapeur Anglo-American Nile £ 51.7% Khedivial Muil 9.9. £ 4.96
                        35/9-36 Menzaleh Canal &amp; Nav, Co. L.E. 4 - P.T. 108 Express Nile
                        Steamers Co.LE. 4% P.T, 109</p>
                    <p>- Hotels Nungovich Hotels</p>
                    <p>£ 18 % Nungovich Hotels Nouv. €. 18 % Egyptian Hotels</p>
                    <p>€ 7 A National Hotels</p>
                    <p>L.E. 4 % P.T. 82 Upper Egypt Hotels</p>
                    <p>L.E. 6%% Splendid Hotels</p>
                    <p>L.E. 4 Excelsior Hotels</p>
                    <p>L.E. 4, 2</p>
                    <p>Tramways Tramways d'Alexandrie Frs. 189 337 . Tramways du Caire try. 638 -
                        1035 .</p>
                    <p>i Valeurs diverses Bourse Khediviale du Caire £ 154 - 5 Egyptian Investment
                        Societe Egyp. d'Irrigation € 16 - Corporation of W. Egypt £ 1 New Egyptian
                        Company € 33/6 - Land &amp; General Trust Is A Egypt. Trust &amp; Investment
                        4 11% Soc. Frigorifique d'Egypte L.E.</p>
                    <p>4 td Walker &amp; Meimarachi</p>
                    <p>0% Automobiles du Caire</p>
                    <p>6 of 11 Egyptian Constructions € 1%</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <cb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7" status="empty">
            </div>
            <cb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8" status="empty">
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
