<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Alain Hernandez Corrales</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-10-17">October 17, 2019</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1906-12-27"><name>Thursday</name>, December 27,
                        1906</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="8">8</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <p> </p>
                <p>New Hospital</p>
                <p>Sbawarbi Pasha a Hospital, reo*otly built at Galioub, will be inaugurated on the
                    let proxo DsQprture o’ Tralnlng-thlp</p>
                <p>TheG*rman training ibipCharloHe left Alex andria abort1}- after noon today for
                    Beyrent.</p>
                <p>The eiaffua</p>
                <p>•» ter day a plague bulletin reoordi two fre«h oases and three death* in hospital
                    at Nag llsmadi.</p>
                <p>The eiigrimaga</p>
                <p>The number of pilgrims accompanying the Mahmal to Mecca and Medina now amounts to
                    1.686.</p>
                <p>I</p>
                <p>lift for Mixed Courts.</p>
                <p>The Mixed Courta at Alexandria are to be provided with an eleotrio lift, at a
                    cost of LB. 500.</p>
                <p>Abbaaelah Hospital</p>
                <p>The old irilitary hospital at Abbasaieh la a boat to be handed over by th*
                    Egyptian Army aothoritiea to the Sanitary Department aiixwd oaurta Cade*.</p>
                <p>The Mixed Courts Codes are to be re­printed next year, when the modifications
                    decided on by the international commission will be embodied</p>
                <p>The Brindisi Mall</p>
                <p>The mad from Bn rope, vii Briodiai, arrived late at Port Said, and will only
                    reach Alexandria at 3 p.m today, the diatribntiot at the G.P taking place at 4
                    80 p m</p>
                <p>Arrivals at the "loo ”</p>
                <p>The arrivals at the Zoological Gardena, Ghixoh, from the Sudan on Chriatmaa Day
                    ineluded three elephants, rn* bull giraffe, waterbuck and other ante^opea, two
                    female wild donkeya, etc</p>
                <p>Marohant teamen a Nome,</p>
                <p>Wo boar that Lady Blomfie'd ia giving a Xmas Tea for 200 seamen to-morrow, and
                    fneoda are arranging a concert on her behalf, the canal 'Xmas Feast being
                    unavoidably postponed ontil the 8th January</p>
                <p>Boni Beust ladwctrtal tehee).</p>
                <p>A delegation on dor the presidency of the Moudir of Beni Son of has been received
                    by H IL the Khedive, who showed most aym pathetic interest in the projected
                    industrial school which ia to be founded at that im­portant provincial
                    centre.</p>
                <p>Came etaallng.</p>
                <p>On Monday evening, between El Meesein and Bttehad stations on the Delta Railway a
                    gang of robbers attacked two cattle trucks on No 6 down train and stole three
                    animals, which, however, were recovered yesterday after a long search by the
                    authorities</p>
                <p>A Fatal Operation.</p>
                <p>A sad cans of death from misadventure occurred yesterday in the Attarin quarter
                    of Alexandria. A Greek from Pyrgoe, Angeles loglemi by name, was suffering from
                    a severe attach of neuralgia. He called in a doctor to ease his agonies, and the
                    latter injected morphia wi'h fatal results.</p>
                <p>■udan Broken,</p>
                <p>Native brokers in the Sudan are becoming as sharp as their brethren in Egypt. The
                    other day a Khartoum broker sold some land registered in a notable a name
                    without bia having been consulted about the transaction Not satisfied with the
                    proceeds of the first sale the broker sold the same land again to another
                    purchaser I</p>
                <p>U Orwa U week*</p>
                <p>M rears Davey, Paxman and Co., Ltd., of Colchester, England, have presented the
                    Orwa Bl Woaka Benevolent Society with £50 on having received an order from the
                    society for a fixed steam engine and boiler for the Mohamed Aly Industrial
                    School, through their agents, Merer* Haaaabo Mchamed and Co, the well known
                    native engineers of Alexandria.</p>
                <p>Auati a ■■ngarlan tell</p>
                <p>The Anatro-Hauganan Benevolent Society's annual ball will take place at the N*w
                    Kbedr vial Hotel on Batarday, February 9. Prepare lions for thia great eocsal
                    event are already in progress, and it ia expected to be, as u ual, a groat
                    success. Notwithstanding that he ia in mourning, Baron Allred do Meoasoo has
                    kindly offered hia assistance in the organisation of the function.</p>
                <p>riofia-Biateltino.</p>
                <p>Tbs FlorioHubattinu S B. Umbria will ar rive at Alexandria on Sunday next, and
                    will leave again on Thursday for Messina, Naples, Leghorn, and Genoa. The Umbria
                    la a splendid transatlantic liner ot 7,000 tons, launched id 1903, fitted with
                    the most modern improve­ments. Her cabins and saloons are Inxunouely furnished,
                    and she was considered one of the best vessels io ibe South American trade.</p>
                <p>Creak Assise Court</p>
                <p>Yesterday au interesting sa e was tried before the Greek Areize Court at
                    Alexandria It appears that a regular band if burglara and housebreakers
                    conducted a campaign in Alex andria last summer. Several oases of burglary came
                    to the notice of the police, and eventually two members uf the band, Antonio
                    Mikhailo vioh and Garifaloe Ganfalou, ware arrested, but the rest of the gang
                    have escaped Yesterday these two men were tried and sentenced to 92 and 24
                    mouths imprisonment respectively, the terms of imprisonment to run from the
                    begin­ning if their incarceration,</p>
                <p>An Unlikely Miracle</p>
                <p>The ecieotific papers predict that man may soon be brought to life scientifically
                    solely by mean* of chemistry 1 Thia seems a very unlike­ly miracle, but what is
                    really wonderful is bow iuiokly the Berlin Schools (Cairo I, Pharis Kamal ,
                    Alexandria, 12, rue Rosette) create polyglots Rasul tn are too convincing to be
                    (juestionod. [Advt]</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark15">QUESTIONS IN PARLIAMENT</hi>
                </p>
                <p>The question of the imports of drink into Egypt has beeu intere-ding some members
                    of the House rf Cemmons, and the following is the text of the questions that
                    have been recent­ly asked : —</p>
                <p>Dr. Rutherford (Middlesex, Brentford) 1 beg to ask the Secretary if State for
                    Foreign Affairs whether he will procure from the Egyp tian Government, for the
                    information of the House, a statement as to amounts and values of alcoholic
                    liquors imported into Egypt during each of the years 1400 to 1906, showing the
                    places of origin and destination and the natioa- alities of the consignors and
                    consignee* , also a statement of the number of distilleries and breweries for
                    the manufacture of alooholio liquors, showing in each case the towns and
                    provinces in which they are situated, and the amounts and values of the outputs
                    together with the nationalities if the proprietors for each of the years between
                    1900 and 1906.</p>
                <p>Sir Edward Grey : I will make inquiry and get as much of the information ssked
                    for as is obtainable.</p>
                <p>EGYPTIAN BREWERIES AND</p>
                <p> DISTILLERIES</p>
                <p>Mr JM Robertson (Northumberland, Tyne side) 1 beg to ask the Under Secretary of
                    State for Foreign Affairs whether in Egypt it is necessaiy that licences should
                    be obtained for the opening and working of breweries and die tillerie*, and, if
                    so, for what period such are granted; whether arrangements are in force for the
                    inspection and supervision of such Iraweriesand diitillerie*, and for testing
                    the quality and strength of the liquors produced, whether there is any law as to
                    a copy of the same being produced for the information of the House, together
                    with a statement as to the number of prosecutions, convictions, and repea’ed
                    convictions of offending brewer* and distillers under such law, showing their
                    nation alitiea ai d the penalties inflicted in each case during the years
                    between 1900 and 1906.</p>
                <p>Sir Edward Grey I will endeavour to obtain the information desired by the bon.
                    Member.</p>
                <p>RETAIL LIQUOR TRADE IN EGYPT</p>
                <p>Mr J. M. Robertson . I beg to ask the Secre­tary of State fur Foreign Affairs
                    whether he will procure for the information of the Hoose a copy of the licensing
                    law relating to the retail sale of alcoholic liquor in Egypt, together with a
                    statement a* to any modifications that may have been made therein, as to the
                    present number of licensed and unlicens­ed retailers, and details of
                    prosecutions and convictions of licensed and unlicensed re. tailers, and of
                    persons charged with drunken nasi in connection with thore establishment*, in
                    each of the year* te'w-ren 1900 and 1906 ; and whether the law, if any, relating
                    to the adulteration of a'ooholic liquors in Egypt applies to, and is enforced
                    against, retailers as well a&lt; manufacturers.</p>
                <p>Sir Edward Grey ; I will ask for as much of the information desired by the hon
                    Member as ii obtainable</p>
                <p>THB “EGYPTIAN STANDARD."</p>
                <p>“Al Lewa's" Paris correspondent telegraph* to bis paper that the London 'Times''
                    publish­ed on the 24th inst. a statement, written by Mnitapha Pasha Kamel, as
                    director of the "Egyptian Standard" company, contradicting the City paper's
                    statements regarding the com­pany. He defended hi* company'* integrity and noble
                    olj-cts, dtc'aring that the Khedive had no personal interest whatever in the
                    scheme.</p>
                <p>SALB OF THB ' FRBNCH MARKET."</p>
                <p>What is known generally at Alexandria as the • French Market," the property of
                    the Alexandria Market C impany, Limited, has been brought by Hanan Pa>ha Mohsen
                    and Mr. William Benwell Rees for £61,000 The area of the market is 3,580 square
                    metre*, and it is situated in the heart ot the town The share­holders of the
                    company will receive twenty pounds per » hare.</p>
                <p>ALEXANDRIA MUNICIPALITY.</p>
                <p>We understand that Mr Michel Salvago will propose next wsek^at the meeting of the
                    Muni oipal Commission that the local Press be admitted to the meetings of the
                    Alexandria Mui icipality</p>
                <p>Ismail Bey S dky, director uf the Admini* t-ative Service ot the Alexandria
                    Munici pahty and secretary to the Municipal Commission, has been nominated
                    secretary general of the Municipality at a salary of L B.8°0 per annum.</p>
                <p>The news of the appointment of Ismail B •y Sidky will be received w th pleasure
                    both by the municipal officials and the public at Alex andria,for during his
                    offiiial career he has won general esteem owing to his talent and cbarac tar;
                    and the progress of this capable young Egyptian in bis cffiiial career will be
                    watched with interest.</p>
                <p>p W I) CONTRACTS</p>
                <p>P. W D. contracts tor canal cleaning in the Bebera province, and the markates in
                    which 'he work is to be done, are as under</p>
                <p>Khatatba. L K 700, and Korn Hamada, L R 2.600 Neghib Madi, Teh el Baroud, L B
                    4.130, and Hoch Issa, LB 3 200, Attis El Sil; Cbebrakhit, Jbrahim Nagbib El
                    Diwaui, LB 3,00°; Dsmanhour, Assad Hanns, LE. 4 2’0; Kafr el Dawar, LR3 400. and
                    Alon Homos, L8 4.000, Mohamed Mgballawi , Rosetta, Khalil 8x1*, LR 2.070.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark18">CELEBRATION AT HELOL’AN.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Whatever may have been done in other parts of Egypt for the wvlfare and happiness
                    ot our guests during the 'X-na* holidays Helouan can at least take credit to
                    itself for having provided most seasonable enjoyments for its visitors. Ths
                    Grand Hote', besides providing a firstolaas dinner in all respects, commencing
                    with turtle soup and finishing with good old English plum padding, had also a
                    farther treat in store. One end of the large dining ball was illuminated by a
                    beautiful 'Xmas Tree tastefully decorated and lighted with electric lamps of
                    different colours. At the close of the dinner Dr. Hobson announced that the
                    management had provided a further entertainment in the form of a tombola, or
                    Italian lottery. Each guest bad a card given him containing certain numbers.
                        Ths<hi rend="underline">ma</hi>itre d’hfltel "Joseph then called out the
                    numbers from the tombola. As soon as the possessor of a card had a complete row
                    of five numbers as called out he then had the tight to select a prise from a
                    table covered with a collsctioo of beautiful presents all nicely oonooalsd in
                    appropriate wrappers. As there were over 100 priiM every guest had the privilege
                    of present­ing a winning card and making his selection accordingly.</p>
                <p>The collection of prizes was so numerous that space forbids our describing them
                    all, but we must congratulate Mr. Manuel on receiving a most beautiful ladies'
                    embroidered bolero. Lady Gilbert Parker was the early recipient of a beautiful
                    prize. Rev, Campbell and Mr Fildes vied with one another in their race to be
                    early at the tables, both receiving das rewards. Mrs Seligman and party were
                    very successful in their drawings. The members sf Countess Karolyi’s family
                    constantly appeared to be very del ghted with the amusement and were received
                    with cheers whilst going to re caive their prizes. Altogether a most enjoyable
                    evening was passed We bear that a grand ball will take place on the last day of
                    the year, to see the new year in and the old year out.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark21">CHRISTMAS SERVICES.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>ST MARK’S, ALEXANDRIA</p>
                <p>The services on Christmas Day were largely attended, the numbers at the 7 30 a m.
                    service being nearly double that of last year. At the 11am. service every seat
                    wax occupied, including about 60 chairs which were placed in the aisle and at
                    the west end ot the church. The choir sang the "Te Deum" to a setting by Rev E
                    Vine Hall. The anthem was “Behold, I bring," by the same composer. Two offertory
                    sentences were song and the first part of the service closed with the National
                    Anthem. The Communion service was a simple setting by the Rev. F A. Gore
                    Ouseley, though the time was by oo msans easy. The singing of the music was
                    excellent, and did the choir credit. The two soprano solos in the anthem taken
                    by Miss Callender, and the playing of the organ by Mr Heaton, were specially
                    worthy of note.</p>
                <p>The church and chapel were tastefully decor ated. Among those who sent offerings
                    of flowers were Mrs. Batobeller, Mrs. Callender, Mire Coates, Mr <hi
                        rend="italic">J.</hi> E Cornish, Mrs. Crafton, Mrs. Dickson, Mr B W. P.
                    Foster, Mr and Miss Morrison, Mr*. Binger, Mrs W T. Smith. Those responsible for
                    decorating the church were Mesdamrs Eyre, Roberts, and Algernon Ward, Misses
                    Barwell, Dodd, Morrison, and Talbot, and Mr Heaton.</p>
                <p>The collections throughout the day were for the fond for the poor and amounted to
                    P.T. 2,133 5 10.</p>
                <p>NOTES FROM SUEZ</p>
                <p>(FbOM OVK CoRRXflPOMDINT.)</p>
                <p>Suez, Wednesday.</p>
                <p>11 M 3. Fox entered the Canal this morning homeward bound, wbi'e her relief, H
                    M.S. Highflyer, is lying in the Suez roads, and will very likely sell to
                    morrow</p>
                <p>The B I. steamer Canara, from Bombay, having landed a suspected case of plague at
                    Moses' Wells, entered the Canal to day io quarantine after disinfection.</p>
                <p>CORPORATION OF WESTERN</p>
                <p> EGYPT.</p>
                <p>It has been brought to our notice that state­ments are being made to the effect
                    that the recent series of article* which we published on the present state if
                    the development of the concession of the Corporation of Western Egypt were
                    directly or irdir'ctly inspired by the company. Tbi* allegation is quite ui
                    true. The articles were the outcome of a trip to the Great Oasis made by the
                    writer, the editor of thi* newspaper, on hia own initiative, and not a single
                    one of the artiolei were revised by or subtfiitted to anyone interested in the
                    company prior to their publication in the 'Egyptian Gszette.” Our object was
                    merely to set before the Egyptian public a straightforward, matter of fact
                    statement of the beginnings of what is really the moat important land
                    development scheme that has ever been attempted in modern Egypt</p>
                <p>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</p>
                <p>The 8 3 R y»l Prinoe, with passengers and general cargo, left Malta on the 24th
                    inst., and ie due at Alexandru on the 28th.</p>
                <p>The 8.8. Persian Prince, with passengers and general cargo, left Manchester on
                    the 23'd inst., and is due to arrive at Alexandria UD or about the 8th
                    January</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark24">KHEDIVIAL OPERA HOUSE.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>“CARMEN."</p>
                <p>(From our Thxatrical Cdrrupundbnt.)</p>
                <p>1 came in rather late in the 2nd act, after hearing the singing at Sbepheard's
                    and I wish ed I had s'ayed at Shenheard's. “Carmen" was really just about as bad
                    as it could be. The only relieviag feature* were Ml'e Devilloy and M Fontaine.
                    M. Fontaine, for once, seemed to have freed his voice: it was clear and
                    resonant, and without effort in the lower register. Id fact, all his usual
                    faults were, for onee, absent. Mlle Devilloy was delightful, co sweet and true,
                    and with such a charm in every note, that she was encored, and we all wished
                    Mioae'a were a big part instead of being only secondary M&amp;ry as E*oamillo
                    seemed to me very apathetic , I was told the Toreador song was not by any mean*
                    wonder fol. Mme Chaix Bonheur, of whom 1 had heard so much, was most
                    disappointing, and far too melodramatic; her voice wasn't pleasing at all: it
                    was too coarse and masculine, as was indeed the whole of her interpretation. The
                    rest of the singers and the orcheatra were al! at sixes and leven*. quite
                    tuneless, out of time, often actually singing false. The orchestra was just
                    possible when by itself, but the moment any singing began everything went wrong.
                    I quite agree with “ L'Egypte'a ” proposal to change them radically and entirely
                    They evidently have no spontaneity or responsivene**, and they play badly, and
                    no amount of bard work will improve them The result is that only the fdw good
                    singers oan do anything, and that by forcing them selves and rest on to the
                    right note, or oom promising on the wrong note. The others and 'he chorus have
                    no chance against such discordant apathy</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark27">ZIZINIA THEATRE.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>“LA BOH EMR"</p>
                <p>To one who bad seen “Carmen' at Cairo last Monday night, any performance of any
                    opera might well have aeemed excellent. Buch was our case ; but even after
                    discounting this artificial autbesissm ore must admit that there were roally few
                    faults in last night's “Bohfcme ;” there were email, but annoying. In the first
                    place, the one performer whose voice should never be beard at all, the
                    con­ductor, to wit, talked much too loud and much too long , over tbs roller
                    an.I in the noisier passages h s rounded tones were au dible throughout the
                    house, now challeng­ing his orches'ra to further effort*, now al laying their
                    superfluous z*al. When the prompter sl*o gave tongue, deep answering to deep,
                    our last particle ot dramatu illusion wm lost. Then the horrible encore bsbit
                    reasserted I'self. On this evil it is nnneoes sary to dilate we can even pardon
                    it in the case of B. Carlo’s ' Veochia zimavra, senti,” a triumph t>f
                    i-ympathetic phrasing. Finally, wo would like to point out to the zealous
                    gentleman who managed the enow that, poor as ia the garret which (haltere these
                    Bohemians, it yet has a roof (which we nan see) whereby the heavy snowfall (Act
                    IV.) inside is ran dered a little ridiculous.</p>
                <p>With the singing and a> ting we must deal later, content'ng our e've* by hero
                    remarking that Mimi and Collino'e voioee gain enor­mously in softness by
                    contrast with Musette and Rodolfo, this with no imputation on these last
                    Orchestra admirable, ohoros-oo- prance inclined to fl i tn tea ; but why men
                    tion this I In Cairo it io two tones sharp</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="italic">( C"mu-unicati'>n Offnirllr)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Ia Commission Munioipates eat tei nie le 26 D6oembre 1906, X 4 h p.m sous la
                    providence de 8 R le Dr Bchiess Pacha.</p>
                <p>A roccasion de la communication des proems verbanx de la Deflation, one
                    observation de M. Rsctfher relative aux oom mao de* de tuyaux en grbs eat
                    renvoy^e X oe college poor 4tode.</p>
                <p>Communication e*t dont^a d une lettre de M Salvago demandant de porter a 1’ordre
                    jo jour d une dee plat prochame* *4anoee de la Commisaion one propoaition qn’il
                    oompte d4 velopper ter riant * I'admivaion de la Prease aux r6snoe* de
                    I'aasemblAe pldni£ra, sfin de donner a sea reunions la plus grande publicity, en
                    rai on de l extemion considerable dis affaires de la ville tt de l interlt
                    legitime qoe prend le public aux deliberations de la Commisaion.</p>
                <p>L'Assemblee en prend note et decide d'ina orire oette proposition a 1’ordre du
                    jour de la procbaine *4snoe</p>
                <p>Vu la lettre de Mr. Joseph et partageant entitlement lea ocncluaiona du rapport
                    prt*ente par Me Padoa Bey, Pitaident du Comitt du Contention*, au si jet de I*
                    demande de con oaesion d une j*t£e au Port Bet, la Commisaion considerant qu'one
                    concession de oette nature ne aaurait 4tre dt'aoht'e de la dttermination prtcise
                    de I'ceuvre a laqnelle elle doit a'sppli- qner, dtcide, avant touts rtwlution
                    dtfinitive, de demander a Mt. Joseph lea plan* et deasina devant faire, le oaa
                    tohtant, partie inttgrante de la oonoeaaion, plans quo dtter miners le service
                    technique et dont la produc­tion devra Atre (site par Mr Joseph dans nn dtlsi de
                    qaatre moia.</p>
                <p>La Commission aborde l examendu proiet de budget piur I'exeroioe 1907</p>
                <p>Mention eat faits k oet tgard de 1'envoi sox n.eiubrea du rapport de
                    I'Administrateur, dee dt'ibtration* de la Dtltgation et du rapport du Comitt des
                    Finances aur le dit projet de budget</p>
                <p>Aprte discussion, la Commission, conformt mei t k la proposition do ComitA des
                    Finances, arrtte les prtvision* dee Reoettea an ebiffre de L R 226 500</p>
                <p>Bur une observation de Buliman Bey Abani, il eat.dtjidt de oomprendre, poor oette
                    annte seulement dan* le budget ordinaire lea interfits sur les funds diaponiblee
                    ainsi qua lea interfits dfl* par lea acheteura de terrains dontlapte vision eat
                    fitablia k LR 7000,1a Commission se rtservantde atatuer, anufie par annte, sur
                    la declination tventuelle de oe* interfile. Les au treeobiffrM proposes par le
                    Comite, comma prt vision* de reoettee, root ado pit*</p>
                <p>Passant au chapitre de* Dfipenaea, la Com mission, aprfia one longue discussion,
                    adopts le rapport do Comitt apficitl des allocations, ainsi que la repartition
                    (site par oe Comite, et arrfite k LE 8131 le ohiffre dee diverse*
                    allocations.</p>
                <p>Elie epprouve lea segmentations proposes par la Delegation et le Comite de*
                    Finance*, en fsveor do haut personnel non claaae L'Ad- minis’rateur remerc e, X
                    oette orcas on, la Commission pour le ttmoiguage de bicnvail- lanoe qu'elle
                    vient de donner k oe personnel, ttmoignage qui eat de nature a stimuler l ardenr
                    des fonotionnaires et k les rncoorager d avoir tor jour* a cceur lea interfits
                    de 1'Ad miniatration.</p>
                <p>Sor la propoaition de la Dt'egation, elle decide 1’e'evation de Mr. hmail Bey
                    Sedky, Directear des Service* Adminiatratifa et do Contention!, au posts da
                    Secretaire General de la Municipalite aux appointemeuta de L E. 800 par an.</p>
                <p>Pour lea autre* chapitre* do budget de* dt penses, 1* Commisaion epprouve lee
                    propoai ticna de 1'administration, telle* qu'elles cot etd adoptees par la De
                    tgation et le Comite dea Finance* et adhtre aox observation* forma lees par cea
                    de«x oollkges, k 1'ocoasion de 1'examen de oe chapitre</p>
                <p>Bn oonetqnence, le Budget dea depenaee eat arrfite k L E 219786, laissant uno
                    rfiretve ordinaire de L.E. 6714</p>
                <p>Ao budget extraordinaire il eat decide de porter la provision du produit de la
                    rente dea terrains de* quais et entree, k LB 13658 , lea autre* chefs aont
                    inscrit* pour mfimoire, fitant donne lent oarset6re aieatoire et incertain.</p>
                <p>II a ete de ide, en outre, d inacme oomme dfipeme k pte'ever sor le mfime budget
                    LE. 650, poor surveillance de* travani de* quais et dea terraina a vendre et
                    5F30 LE poor achat et tranaport de nail I ease ; lea depensea tifioeaeairee poor
                    corfection dea noovellea routes, expropriationa et noovellea oanalisa tiens, k
                    ptelever »ur |e budget extraordinaire, aont inscritee pour mfimoire.</p>
                <p>La Commiasion epprouve I'fitat de virement* pour 1'ooverture dea erfidita
                    ■upplfimentaire* neoeaxaire* k la rfigolarisation des comptes de fin d'annfie du
                    budget ordinaire, r elevant k LB. 4,294</p>
                <p>Bor la propoaition de la Delegation, elle decide I’oovartore dea otedita solvents
                    k pre lever sor le budget extraordinaire</p>
                <p>lc LR 1480. poor ad'cation a divers em ploy4* a ('occasion de la cessation de
                    leurs functions, dont 1200 LE. k litre de gratifiia tion a Mr. Arooudaria.</p>
                <p>2° LB 840, pour la confection de* nou- vellea canalisation*, roe* Emam El Azsm et
                    BmsiIiou Bey k Kom El Chogafa.</p>
                <p>8° LK. 96, pour I'rngagenent de chalneor* pour le releve de* plans de* route* de
                    Rsmlrh.</p>
                <p>4‘ L.B. 4,100 pour le proIongement du dallsge de la route du Max.</p>
                <p>5° L.B 6 000 pour I'achfivement dei pare* k eteer sor l emplaremeut de* anciennea
                    fortifi cation* aitnfiea au Nord de la Porte Roaette.</p>
                <p>A I’ooceaioo de 1'apprcbation du erfidit oon oernant la route do Max, la
                    Commimion invito la D4 figation i fitudier nn projet de rfigleiren- tation de la
                    largeor de* jaate* de* rone* de* charrettea, 'e pen de largeor des roues fitant
                    one cause de deterioration de* voie* publiqne*.</p>
                <p>Vu i'bsore avanefie, lea autre* question* portfiea k I'ordre do jour aont
                    renvoyfies k nre prochaine sfianoe, tixfie au Msrcredi 2 Janvier pro chain.</p>
                <p>Lee interpellations de MM Kamel Bey Teymouret Salvago relative* k la oonfrotion
                    de la oornicbe et k I'fitat de* route* de la ville, viendront en tfite de
                    I'ordre du jour de la dite efiarce</p>
                <p>L* sfienoe eat levfie k 7 1/2 h. p.m.</p>
                <p>Mastapba Pasha Fehny, the Prime Minis­ter, who went to Mena House Hotel a little
                    time ago for a change of air, will remain in the hotel fur a month</p>
                <p>Prinoe Augustus d' Aren berg, chairman of the Board of Directors of the Suez Car
                    al Com pary, arrived at Port Bud on To&lt;wday last by the North German Lioyd ■
                    3 8. Gneisenau 1 be Prince was accompanied by M. Bonnet, secretary general, and
                    M Devin, administrator ot the company. He left for hmailia by the midday
                    train</p>
                <p>It is stated that Per k Ahmed Zeki Pasha, Grand Master of Ceremonies and A.DC. to
                    the Khedive, baa tendered hia re igeation to bn Highness.</p>
                <p>The Government ba* decided to make a grant to Ibrahim Fathi P«aha of L E. 1,200
                    in recognition <hi rend="italic">of</hi> the service* be rendered during the
                    Sinai crisis.</p>
                <p>The funeral <hi rend="italic">of</hi> M s* Cattaui A»lan. the daughter <hi
                        rend="italic">of</hi> Joseph Cattaui Bey, took place yesterday afternoon,
                    and was attend* I by the leading residents in Cairo. M aa Aslan, who was only
                    eigh'een yiar* old, succumbed to typhoid fever.</p>
                <p>Among thoae who are shortly expected at Gbezireb Palace are the Hon. Mr*.
                    Lawrence and party, who arrive on the 31*1 in t., and, after a ihtee weeks' stay
                    th«re, go op th* river, returning afterwards to Gbezireb for a pro­longed
                    visit.</p>
                <p>Mr. end Mr* Prank Cook arrived at Ghezirth yesterday.</p>
                <p>Mr- York and her two beautiful daughter* are due at Gheureb shortly, and Mrs K de
                    B. Carey, who passed the winter there two winters ago, has joat arrived.</p>
                <p>Mr N. A Morcou. has returned to Ghe* reh from Assouan</p>
                <p>Among the latest arrival* at the Savoy are Lady David V. Tennant, Lindon; Mr*.
                    Bnrde- kin and Mrs. A. Hay, the Mi sees Bnrdekin, Australia; Baroness de Gumbo
                    and two daughters, Alexandria; Covmendatore Gtnliu and Mme Malmusi, Italy; Mr.
                    J. and Mr. J W Kincaid, England; Major and Mrs T. Q. C. Reynolds, England;
                    Lisqt. Col. H. V. Ruseel, England, Mr. H W and Lady Monel Beckwith, Eugland,
                    Baron de Maruqnea, Paris, Capt Chandor Pool Ge'I, England; Mr C. Brier,
                    Manchester.</p>
                <p>GHEZ1REH PALACE</p>
                <p>Gb’r reh Palace Hotel is already in great vogo*. and the number uf visitors at
                    present staying there compares very favourably with that at the same time last
                    year The genera! manager, Mr. Muller, talks cheerfully of bright prospects and a
                    record season, an opinion which ie backed up by a pile ot advance book ing'.
                    Christmas was passed quiet'y at Ghsz reh, but the small danoaa will be
                    inaugurated thia evening, and the preliminary preparation* are already in
                    progress /or the great annual ball.</p>
                <p>MIL.ITARY TAILORS.</p>
                <p>EGYPTIAN ARMY OUTFITS A SPECIALITY.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark30">RIDING BREE0HE8.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>F. Phillips &amp; Co.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <p>TELEGRAMS.</p>
                <p>PERSIA</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark33">UPROAR IN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>London, December 26</p>
                <p>The "Daily Mui" leerni from Teheran that the Crown Prinos caused an eprosr id the
                    National Aseembly by proposing an amend ment to the letter's draft of a
                    oonetitntion, •atabliabing a Senate composed of SO official*, 80 members of the
                    Aseemb y, and 10 tepre tentative* of the Riyai tribe, to review the Assembly*
                    reform*, instead of the latter going direct to the Government fur acceptance and
                    enforcement. <hi rend="italic">{Reuter)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark36">MOROCCO</hi>
                </p>
                <p>EL RA18UU STILL ACTIVE</p>
                <p>Toulon, December 86</p>
                <p>The transport Nive has sailed for Morocco, t <hi rend="italic">Haw</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Tangier December 86</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Hl</hi> Baisnli oontianes to foment anti European</p>
                <p>agitations. &lt;</p>
                <p>DAMARALAND</p>
                <p>END OP WAR IN SIGHT</p>
                <p>Berlin, December 26.</p>
                <p>The Bonde r wart tribe ba* snrrendered in Damaraland and given up their weapons.
                    I be offi 31 si* here hope that th* war is nearly over. (Prefer)</p>
                <p>Berlin, December 26</p>
                <p>A sewn offioial note announce* a favourable torn of event* in Sooth Africa and
                    ’he snbmis ■ion of several tribes<hi rend="italic">{Haw)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark39">CHURCH AND STATE IN FRANCE</hi>
                </p>
                <p>SERIOUS SITUATION</p>
                <p>Pauls, December 26.</p>
                <p>The enforcement of the Separation Law i* greeting a serious situation in*l >wer
                    Brittany. Theolergy are preaching revolt against the law. Com mar os is at a
                    standstill and agrioul tural operation* are suspended in many district*. <hi
                        rend="italic">(Reuter)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark42">SNOWSTORMS IN THE UNITED KINGDOM</hi>
                </p>
                <p>London, December 86.</p>
                <p>A brilliant Christman Day was followed by heavy snowstorms in the evening all
                    ovei the United Kingdom The storms were especially severe on the sooth coast,
                    where tbe.bbuard is still raging Foor inches of snow fell here ( <hi
                        rend="italic">R</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark45">RACIAL CONFLICT IN MISSISSIPPI</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Niw York, December 26</p>
                <p>A racial conflict took place in Mississippi in oonseqnenco of a dispute with the
                    guard of a train. Fifteen persons were killed, mostly negroes Troops have been
                    ordered to the scene <hi rend="italic">(Reuter)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark48">ADMIRAL NEBOGATOFF</hi>
                </p>
                <p>St. Pmi'BCMa, December 26 The sentence on Admiral Nebogatoff has been commuted to
                    one of 10 years' imprison ment (//&lt;icw)</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark51">MR BRYCE RESIGNS</hi>
                </p>
                <p>London, December 26</p>
                <p>Mr. Bryce ha* resigned bis seat in tbs Hoose of Commons <hi rend="italic"
                        >(Reuter,</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark54">ANOTHER SPRINGBOK VICTORY</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark57">THE BUDGET.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>rixwni, advisers note.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="italic">(t' Htmu’-d)</hi>
                </p>
                <p>FOREIGN Trade</p>
                <p>The estimated figure* of the exports and imports of meroh ui'li** and «pecis for
                    the year 1906 are shown below together with the totals for the last six years,
                    as given by the Customs Returns</p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>The large increase in the exports for 1906 is, of course, lae to the abundant
                    cotton crop and the high pricas ruling The upward move moot in the import* is
                    b*rdly leas remarkable, raising their value as it does to a figure which ;* some
                    10 °; higher than that of 19o5 This notable progress appears by the customs
                    returns to be shared by nearly all classes nt the import trade, the most
                    prominent advance being in the category of me'ahand machinery, which alone
                    acooont* for 40 £ of the total increase</p>
                <p>In my Note last year I said "The fact that during the peat two years the imports
                    of mer ohandise and specie taken together have greatly outbalanced the exports,
                    notwithstanding the constant heavy charges for the servioe of the foreign debt,
                    oonstitutee a phenomenon that calls for reflection. A readjustment in the
                    direction of normal equilibrium must come sooner or later, and, if we are paying
                    for our imports with capital provided by tbe foreign investor, the operation,
                    though by no means unsound at present, cannot be indefluitely continued.1' These
                    remarks were somewhat severely criticised by a portion of the local Press, which
                    was inclined to accuse me of economic heresy and pessimistic fore bodings In tbe
                    passage quoted above I was far from desiring to formulate any economic theory,
                    beretioal or otherwise, but tbe fact that tbe total import* of merchandise and
                    specie in 1900 amounted to L E 18,200,000 as against L.E. 21,600,000 for
                    export*, leaving a balance of LE 3.400,(00 in favour of export a while in 1906
                    tbe figures are, imports LE. 31,900,000 and export* LE 2*.500 0 0, showing a
                    balance of over LB. 3 400000 in favour of import*, i* a phenomenon worthy of
                    attention and study Even if these figure* imply that Egypt has been paying for
                    her import* with funds advanced by tbe foreign capitalist, there is nothing
                    necessarily alarm ing in the fact, so long as tbe capital in qoes tion is
                    employed fur tbe purpose of remenera tive enterprise</p>
                <p>A special feature in tbe budget of last year wu the reduction of tbe import duty
                    on certain articles of first necessity from 8 ' to 4 <hi rend="italic">, ad
                        valorem</hi> Unfortunately, the oondi tions which have prevailed during the
                    past year ar* not such s« to furnish a fair basis on which to form a definite
                    opinion as to the precise effect of this reduction In tbe first place, there
                    were considerable accumulations of stocks to be disposed of before tbe consumers
                    could expect to benefit by tbe reduction, and secondly, foreign market prices
                    and freigb’e for most of tbe articles were higher tbia year</p>
                <p>Moreover, tbe state of tbj local market fur cattle and petroleum was abnormal,
                    owing to quarantine restriotions, and to the temporary atoppage of arrivals of
                    petroleum during the disturbances in Rneeia.</p>
                <p>Judging, however, from the data before me. I am ino'ined to think that, having
                    regard to tbe recent rapid advance of prosperity, a ledoo tion ol 4% on article*
                    of first necessity w 1! not be found, for the moment, to have affected the
                    consumption to any very great ex'enl, whatever the final re.nits may be If this
                    view proves to be correct, it may, at all event*, be claimed for the measure
                    taken last year that, while it benefits the consumers, it also furnishes tbe
                    Government with a fiaoal reserve which conld be made use of in oase of emergency
                    with the least pose ble disturbing effect upon trade</p>
                <p>The following is a comparative table of the articles on which the import duty was
                    last year reduced</p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>attention. With an ieoreased dsauand fjr those high cl um goods fir which
                    Egyptian oottons are extensively employed, there must naturally be a growing
                    demand for high grade oottons In this cioaeotion ths question of seed ae'ec tion
                    is one which requires every oousideration and attention.</p>
                <p>The out-turn in ginning in tbe early part of the season war not satisfacto'y,
                    and, though better result* were obtained later in the yea', yet the reault is
                    but moderate</p>
                <p>The past season has been fortunate in respect to insect attack*. The ootton worm
                    did pr*c tioally no harm, while the destructive boll worm appeared much later in
                    the season and io much diminished numbers.</p>
                <p>The cotton crop* since ths year 1997 have been as follows : —</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="italic">Total cropt (interior great weight}.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>1N97 189H ............... 6,543,128 kantars</p>
                <list type="ordered">
                    <item>1899 ....................... 5 589 314</item>
                    <item>19&lt;>O..._ ... 6,510,050</item>
                    <item>1901 ... ............. 5,427,388</item>
                    <item>1902........................ 6.371,643</item>
                </list>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark64">1</hi>908 1903........................... 6,838,090</p>
                <list type="ordered">
                    <item>1904 ....................... 6 508,947</item>
                    <item>1905 ....................... 6.351,879</item>
                    <item>1906. ............... 5,959,883</item>
                    <item>!9J7 (approximate) 6,750,000 „</item>
                </list>
                <p>Gold Demand of tub Egyptian M*ukt</p>
                <p>It may *ot be out of place here to offer •ome remarks on recent import* uf specie
                    to Egypt which have attracted some attention in the financial world.</p>
                <p>Gold ooiu is invariably mposted in conn derabls quantity in tbe autumn in order
                    to move the oollen wop, th* amount required depending oa the value of the orop
                    (quantity X price), the rapidity with wbii b it u brought <hi rend="italic"
                        >to</hi> market, aad the reserve* aiseady ssistieg in the imnds uf ib* banks
                    Tbe first of these is usually tbe predownnaUng iaoter. Io the proses t instance,
                    th* e* •aptional y large volume of th* erop and tbe hi|k pnoes it commanded
                    enupioi with th* tact that the cultivators took tbe opportunity of selling their
                    cotton earner than usual, brought itsAout tret the de*eand tsi gold mad* itself
                    felt with great suddend**a at th* beginning of October. The reserve* in ths
                    Banks were quickly exhausted, and a temporary financial stoingency ensued, which
                    was ultimately alienated by the arrival of gold from Eusope</p>
                <p>Tbe demand foigold in large quantities for Egypt, oonaUtutiag as it does a
                    phenomenon of annual occurrence, would probably have passed without comment bad
                    it not fallen, concentrated and sudden, upon a maike’ already short uf supplies.
                    The withdrawal of •ome four million! from tbe London money market for Egypt
                    during tbe mouth of October was doubtla s the principal o*um of tbs advance of
                    the Bank of B iglaud rate to 6 % It may be observed her* that no ns* in the rate
                    of interest will arrest a drain of gold to move the Egyptian cotton crop, for,
                    owing to tbe reluctance of tba native cultivator to accept anything bat actual
                    coin in payment of hi* cotton, a permanent cbeok to tbe snpplia* would stop the
                    entire commerce of tbe oountry and lead to the moat serious oonseqoenoa-.</p>
                <p>In view of the apprehension! which have found expression in some quarters, it is
                    the more necessary to lay emphasis un the fset that ths recent demand for gold
                    was a purely trade demand, aud was in no way connected with the financing of
                    speculative operations. Although it is incontestable, a* I bad occasion to point
                    out in my last Not*, that such opera tious hive been foatared to a ooasiderabl*
                    ax'ent of reo*nt years with the help of foreign capital, they should not be
                    confounded with tbe normal and legitimate commerce of the country. It is,
                    indeed, gratifying to learn, on the authority of the British Chamber of Com
                    merce, that ‘ speculation in stocks and lands wu reduced to it* lowest lim t
                    during the past faw month*" <hi rend="italic">'Bntirk Chamfer of Comtrurct of
                        Egypt Monthly Journal,</hi> November, I9C6, article on "Th* financial
                    8ti&lt;ugency in Egypt”).</p>
                <p>Egyptian Companiks</p>
                <p>It my last Budget Note, I drew attention to the fact th st the incorporation of
                    an Egyptian Cmpany by Khedivial Decree on y implies that tbe Company in question
                    has con formed to cerUin rules and regulations; tf &lt;4».&lt; <hi rend="italic"
                        >not imply that it tnjoyg the tupport, or erm the approval, of the Khedivial
                        G lemmnt.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>The system is an antiquated one modelled, I believe, on an old French law long
                    since repealed</p>
                <p>It is tbe cogtom cf tbe Khedivial Govern meut to authors* all companies which
                    con­form with tbe letter of ths regulations. Isut spring, however, it was
                    brengbt to tbe notice f th* Mini try of Fmai.co that tbe creation f ‘ Fusn ier*'
                    »hsre&lt; was being ueriied to an ahi’re eitm’, and, on 'bsadrire of tbe Ixgwl
                    Advie.-re tn Govenimeu’, it wm decided by tbs Coni ol Minuter* on June I to
                    limit ths creation (>f »uch ibe.to* in wh ch t)>&lt; y</p>
                <p>represent propury in ar invention, or a Go vemiumt cot c«■ ton if wh oh tbe value
                    is pr iblex-tic*1</p>
                <p>In foreign ooentne* the regulations laid down are often less stringent than those
                    which obtain in Egypt Th* result has been that companies wboae in corp > ration
                    in Egypt w g refused h»ve teen *uoceaaful y floated eleewber* This ba* notably
                    happened io the case of ooe Company which with a capita I of L E. 103,000 in
                    25,000 LK 4 sbates prop med to issue 100,COO Founders sharei. It ha«, I □
                    adoretarxi been registered a* a British oompany.</p>
                <p>Redution &lt; r Taxation</p>
                <p>Of late year* it ieeme to have been expected almiat as a mx’ter of course that,
                    a* December came round, •■im* rem lesion of texxtion in tbe succeed ng year
                    wculd bj announced Tbe limits within which snob remissions are ponibl* bar,
                    uoept as regards tbe reform of the Customs tar fl, now almost bean reached Had
                    tbs ooeditions of the past year been norma1, th* Gvvertmaot would ear</p>
                <p> tainly have eoosidesed tbe advisability of taking a farther step in tariff
                    reform. Uud*r the unfortunate oonditioos which marked tbe early part of the
                    year, and in view of tbe possible reenvdesrsnoe of -wasilar rtiffieobiei in tbe
                    future, accompanied by a corresponding increase in the demands on the national
                    purse, it ha* been deemed advisable to take no measure* calculated to diminish
                    th* financial resosreos of th* administration</p>
                <p>In defereooe, however, to the wishes expressed last year by the Legislative
                    Oewnct1, a small reform ba* boon adopted by the abo 11tion of ths Ayloola dur*
                    hitherto lenel by the Ministry of Fiaanoe When land is sold by heirs who bars
                    not prwwioosly acooreplxbed the formality of proving their title by means of a
                    deed mi the regular form, it is oustossary for the Modinoha to elaim payment of
                    tbe Ayloola does before transferring the property to the name <hi rend="italic"
                        >of</hi> tbe pnrobasev ie tbe Imnd tai Registers In each omo*. tbe dues will
                    not be demanded in fctnrr, bnt they will emrtinue to be levied in the Mrhkemebs
                    when a tithe ie applied foraed a Hod get Ayloola is delivered to prov* tbe same.
                    The loss bo tbe Treasury is estimated at L &amp; 18,0 0.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark69">LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>W&lt; du nM h&lt;4d rwpmatbU for th# »>0nl«Hie «■</p>
                <p>I r*a«»l by o>u ^rvte^MbdetiU •tab In a tjrirlt >(</p>
                <p>fair play lu all, lu permit*—within certain nawaaary 11 mi la - fwe Ueei— km</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark72">EGYPTIAN AND LONDON BOARDS.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>To TH* Rd ITO 1 or th* "EumuN Gaxxttx"</p>
                <p>8m,—la view of ths secular strife that is •ver being waged between th* local and
                    London board* of Bgyp’iau oampauia* I have a moat valuable suggestion to maka,
                    which I am ■ are would be most ireful. A large amount of friction might be
                    avoided if compasy pro­moters in Egypt,when stliciting British capital for their
                    enterprise*, were to state that after allotment the services of London board* of
                    directors would be dispensed with.—I am, ate.,</p>
                <p>"Financib*.”</p>
                <p>Cairo, Deocmbar 25</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark75">SULTAN S PRESTIGE IN EGYPT</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark78">To </hi>TBi Eorro* or THr "EormA’r Gabitti "</p>
                <p>Bit,—I notice that the Alexandria cor rerpondeot of the "Globe," writing from
                    that o>ty on the 1st in*t., give* an epitomise I aooonntofthe deecriptiou I sent
                    yoe of the reception at D*maeboor of Hhan Mchktai Pasha and oonolodes a* follows
                    . —</p>
                <p>In several particulars the aoDoent quoted is obviously overcharged, but it prove*
                    the enduring potency of the Bolters'• tnfluenes throughout Egypt, and that in
                    Islam Tcrkvy is never so vietonoos as when sbs fails.</p>
                <p>1 beg to reiffi m all I said, and to state thst the correspondent ot the
                    "Globo's" statement* as to my report having been exaggvrated is absolutely
                    untrue, a* tbe story I told was a plain and unvarnished account.</p>
                <p>YoVR CoBMfPONDBNT</p>
                <p>Damanhonr, December 85</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark81">THE PORT SAID AFFAIR</hi>
                </p>
                <p>To mt Editor of th* "Eoiitias Gazittb " 8:r,—In reference to tbe aarteipnndence
                    which has appeared on this subjtot, permit ms to say that what may have appeared
                    a heavy pnniih meut is net a* severe a* the writer himself would like to give
                    such people. It must be remembered that a number of people who unfortunately
                    sail them reives British subject* behave iu inch a manner that strong menure*
                    most be adopted in the attempt to suppress the*edisgracefnl ontbreak*of rowdyism
                    among *t hritishsr* abroad Bn oh min as th* on* in question, what may be termed
                    the "boll d >g style," are evidently under the Mupeereion that they can do and
                    act jut a* they think fit, and from personal knowleigs I congratulate onr worthy
                    Consul General on hi* eff >rte to bring snob unruly characters to thair proper
                    sense* I trust th»t 'mt example wi'l prov* * warning to othvs - I am, etc,</p>
                <p>JcSTlC*.</p>
                <p>Port Baid, December 25</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark84">SOLDIERS’ INTEMPERANCE</hi>
                </p>
                <p>To ths Editor uf th* "Egyptian Gaxktti "</p>
                <p>Sir,—Fating X-na* i* natural and indeed psoper. But is it neoas*ary for certain
                    scMieil of th* Army of 0 :enpariou to display lbs >e uhs of too much good cheer
                    quite as public ly I Two nights ago 1 ub eived an excellent man glurionUy intux
                    osted a»kmg a potz'e > »l>awiahtb* w*y to ibe E b*k eh wrhia 50y rd &lt; f
                    3bapbe*rd *. A group of K&lt;ypUans watoha t deruively till the aoldiet utubited
                    ova* ooe uf the Ta&lt; • m's ubatafiia tracks towards th Biwtol H »t«l Go tbe
                    sametveniug aevera other aigb'* uf iLa sort m *bt kava been seen I * I* glad to
                    admit that there is a great im provament io our Avu>y in th* matter of tempi
                    rauoe, but aomatbiug remains to be done, and in a ooantrybk* this tbe speotaol*
                    of a drank* •old'er does not improv* our preauga among Mosiemi —1 am, ate.,</p>
                <p>Caujufs.</p>
                <p>Cairo, December 96</p>
                <p>Qcalifiid English &lt; hbmift,speaking French fluently snd having some knowledge
                    cf Arabic, vented by a large London firm of pharma- oaotioal chemists to
                    represent 'hem in Egypt, th* Levant, etc Scotsman preferred, and one who has bad
                    previous experience in ths Near E**t Apply with usual paRicular*. stat ing age
                    salary required, etc., to ' Vaat," o/o West Bid Advtg Agency, Ltd., 195 Oxford
                    Street, London. W England. 89180-3* 8</p>
                <p>SHBPHBARI/8 HOTEL</p>
                <p>Latest Arrival*</p>
                <p>l>ec. 21. -Mr <hi rend="italic">J C</hi> Mackay, Mr* J i .Mackay, Hereford,
                    Admiral and Mr* WiMhington. Mr Jean de BovutniR a»l fan, y( AJexamirte, MiM
                    EwgenreBaak, Mia* A Back, Johannesburg, Mr. <hi rend="italic">V.</hi> J. F*aw*
                    York, Mr A. H Iiunnachia, Bootland, Mr * \f Brother*, Cape Colony, Mr. Bard, Mr
                    p. Bacot, Paris, Major Fox, Suex, Lieut. Hamilton, Huez, Mr McLaren, England,
                    Mr, Baiuev.i, Italy.</p>
                <p>iMc 22.—Mr. J. A. Naie, New York, Mr. and Mrs. John J. Aitken and family, Mr and
                    Mrs. Behrendt, Germany, M. and Madau. Ltonnet, Anvers, Mr and Mr*. Fran bent
                    Lal, N. Y. Mr» W. E. .dteaper, V. H. A., Mr II. F Koerner, Buffalo, Mr. H. N.
                    Rietiari^, Boston, Mr. S. N Hpencer, Buffalo, tbe Miws Judah, U M. A., Mr*.
                    Jewett, U. S A., Mr. and Mr* I>evter Leland, Mr and Mrs Andrea, Heidelberg Mr
                    and Mrs. Gordon, Dexte^ boaton, Mr Edward K. Ream, New York, Mr, and Mr* W. P
                    Stanton, Nre» Ywrtt, Mr aal Mr*, ttaonr, V S A., Mr. and Mr* Alfrwi Owteito, New
                    York, Mr <hi rend="italic">D.</hi> Ho4remr. U. H. A , Mr and Mn. M H. JarepK New
                    York Dr Julius Citron, Berlin, Mr. umd Mr*. <hi rend="italic">J.</hi> if.
                    Gillespie, Pittsburg, Mr M J. Forsyth, A., Monsieur Mackenna, Chili, Mr. and
                    Yin, Feigei, Wiesbaden, Mr. James Pam, Cuatrawi Elisabeth Mieeokuuske, CotnteMO
                    Ann* Je Skanyneke, Ponen, Mr H. P. Bose, N Y Mr-</p>
                <p>1 E. D Whaley. N Y. Mr E. OHIftage. Liver, pool, Mr Alfred Tweni. Mr L W
                    0>rrr,</p>
                <p>' Mr H 8. Hamilton, N Y. Mr and Mr* Lwu Higgimon, U. 8. A</p>
                <p>Dec. 23 —Saba Paaha, Mr C W Green, Mias L. Green, England, Mr. Aatoina Coma nua,
                    Maosuarah, Mr. and Mrs. Arthur J. Comer, BueSon, Gen. D. Farber, U. 8. A, Mr.
                    Jacques Holo, Misses Cruilin, Sao Fraocivo Mr. and Mr*. Hayes, Liverpool, Mass A
                    P, Westcott, Miss Annie H. Clark, Nev York, Baron arid Ban»n««v» de Menaace</p>
                <p>| I>ec. 24.—Mr Gserge H. Mel*srv«. Mr end Mrs. Oharlra Frtvwell, London, Mr.
                    George* Zervudacht, Mr G L Baity, Mr D. 8 Oorfett, England, Mr Howard, Mr. R D
                    Cooper Mr Geo H 8nowdon, New York, Mrs. Charles Anderson, Mr. Ernest Khvrpe,
                    Boston, Dr E. E. and Mr* Saties; Uam—h, Maa J. W. Coupee, Mrs* Hales Cooper,
                    UjKA-, Mr. D R.</p>
                <p>, Howe, England, Mr. W. Bsontch, Port Said, Mr Loransn I* Know, UJS.A. ; CoL and
                    Mr*. E. F. Hofmea, Mr. E. Pskar, Badapest ; Mr, C. Oteoesco, Mr. and Mrs. Fr.
                    Haspfner Karlsruhe, Mr. and Mrs. E. W. Pater*>u, Smyrna, Mr R.H. Wright, Miss
                    Lila Wnght, U.S A , Mr Haaa, Berlin.</p>
                <p>Calendar of Coming Events</p>
                <p>AuLEX ATTDBIA.</p>
                <p>■ ■</p>
                <p>I Dwoember.</p>
                <p>Tour 27 Zizmia lEeatre Itehaa Opesa Gim pany in LaArapr-ta. 9 Alhambra Theatre.
                    Javende Upeis</p>
                <p>Company in <hi rend="italic">La Eigeui dd Rey* mento</hi> 9</p>
                <p>Tour Eiffel Music Hall Varieties 9.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark87">January.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Tues. 1 British Ride Club. Club Match. 2. Tues 15 Khedivial Club. "At Hume.</p>
                <p>CA.IRO.</p>
                <p>Deossaber.</p>
                <p>Thur. 27 Ghezireh Palace. Saeail Danor.</p>
                <p>Khedivial Opera HoMwr Front a Opera. 9.</p>
                <p>Abbas Theatre. 9.</p>
                <p>Eabekieh Ganiena ThaatreL 9.</p>
                <p>Fn. 28. Halouaa Sport*og Club. 1st Wia’.er Meeting 2.</p>
                <p>Zoological Gardens. Ohiaeh Ryi Band Afternoon</p>
                <p>Sat. 29 Hbepheard * Hotel. Military Ba: I 4-6</p>
                <p>Mena House SrauLcb IjmIwi iOr­chestra. Afternoon.</p>
                <p>Savoy Hotel. Small Dance I'1</p>
                <p>Sun. 30 Zwfogical Garden* Ghtreh B"V*</p>
                <p>Bead Aftarwooo</p>
                <p>Mon 31 British Hairsatioa Club, Ball bbepheard ■ Hotel. Small Dance 1 .'.
                    January</p>
                <p>Tues. 1 aavoy Hotel, dsuall Dance. 10</p>
                <p>Fn. 4 K.S.C. &lt; iyaikbana</p>
                <p>Mon &lt; K.S.C Smash Rackets Tournaai'u* Tues 8 Xcceasion [>ay Parade.</p>
                <p>K S C England v dMStawd</p>
                <p>Fn. 11 K.S.C Mbye Meetate</p>
                <p>Thur 17 Sexmranu* Hotel. Inaugural Bali</p>
                <p>35 ed. 23 K.S.C. 2nd Winter Race Meetin,,’ Ghexiret Badrane. 5-a*ide Football T
                    >urnaineut.</p>
                <p>fn 25 K H C. <hi rend="italic">tnd</hi> Wmv- Hare M'*-' (*»d day).</p>
                <p>Man. 28 Shapkaard e Great Aaaaal Ba</p>
                <p>Fwbrwary</p>
                <p>Fn 1 ILdaaaa 8per**ng QuV fed V</p>
                <p>Meeting</p>
                <p>Sat 9 K. S. C Skye Meeting lues 12 Gheetreh Chssroo Bal PMdre</p>
                <p>March</p>
                <p>Fn 1 Huinoan Sporting Oleh 3rd Winter</p>
                <p>Hasten*</p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>
                    <hi xml:id="bookmark90">HOWIE*S BUTTER</hi>
                </p>
                <p>KowM sot 6*it te g+»e W s trial, feto'* thslr winter arrvngerean**</p>
                <p>Addroes 8«robrs feed, Cktox</p>
                <p/>
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"> 
                
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi xml:id="bookmark93">PICTURE POST CARDS.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>“Th* Egyptian Gazette" Series</p>
                            <p> it the moet artletlo collection to be found</p>
                            <p> In Egypt.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>TO OUR VISITORS.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Tlii EOPPttflllGdU’ttC han much pleasure Ui ) resenting to ita
                                HUhscnliere the acc&lt;*m]uinv jug of aotue of the many
                                interesting</p>
                            <p>r uJew by which they may travel homewards, (.rent care has been taken
                                to arrange them as n.-.urntely and concisely as posaible, and it
                                will lie found that none of them wre fraught with difficulty. In
                                clxxMiiig the rtiute home there are several things to la*
                                conxidercd. To leg m with there is the difference in climate letween
                                Egypt and the various points at which yAu may arrive in Euro]>e.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HOTELS EN ROUTE.,</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">SYRACUSE.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">GRAND HOTEL</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>PIAZZA MAZZINI, SYRACUSE (Si. ily)</p>
                            <p>First Hotel in the Town</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">SYRACUSE &lt; Sicily.!</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>WTIL DX3 173 Aits IDS.</p>
                            <p>"CASA POLITI.1</p>
                            <p>First cis*», Klectric Light, Lift Ontrsl Hnsting</p>
                            <p>Phi v *tx Baths. All Con roars</p>
                            <p>ENQELKE-ZUNKE.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Vade Mecum for the Homeward Bound.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>This d&lt;i>ends partly ii]m>h the month in whi&lt;h you leave
                                rlgypt, for Cairo in Januan ma* lie a little wanner than the
                                Riviera, and pissibly not -o waim as Sicily, bit in Mardi it vrill
                                Ire warmer than Rime, and more uni tormly warm than many other
                                place'in Europe. Many people leave Egvpt far t&lt;o early in the
                                \ear for as a rule the weather in April and May is {agrfect The
                                wannest place to g&lt; t&lt; on having Egypt is Sicily</p>
                            <p>Some will want to take into consideration the numlsT of days tc be
                                sjient at sea, and we therefore subjoin a list showing the time oc
                                copied on each of the various routes between Egypt and the I
                                ontinent of Eurujie</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>They are »• follows</p>
                            <p>The long sea routes from Port Said or Alexandria to Plymouth,
                                Southampton, Ixmdon</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>short ones are ax follows —</p>
                            <p>Port Said or Alexandria to Brindisi 3 days Alexandria to Messina
                                3</p>
                            <p>PortSaidor AlexandriatoMarseillex 5 „ Alexandria to Venice and
                                Trieste 3j ,,</p>
                            <p>Alexandria to Naples 3</p>
                            <p>Port Said to Genoa 5 ,,</p>
                            <p>Port Said Vi Naples 4</p>
                            <p>Alexandria to Constantinople ... 4 „ Alexandria to
                                Piraeus..................................................... 2</p>
                            <p>Port Said to Gibraltar........................... 7</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>The steamers of the P it G , North German Lloyd, Orient, and Message
                                riea Maritimes are the largest The Anchor, British India, Bibby and
                                Henderxon Line$ are also excellent, and their 'teamen are largely
                                jiatronised by travellers to Egypt</p>
                            <p>As regards the train journeys from Cairo the shortest is that to
                                Alexandria, without change 3 hours). That to Port Said can now be
                                made without change in 4 <hi rend="italic">k</hi> hours.</p>
                            <p>'Hie least expensive way to Elfgland is by the Mow, Papayanni,
                                Prince, and Westcott lines of steamer* from Alexandria to Liverpool.
                                The German Ijevant line has also g&lt;sxl steamers from Alexandria
                                to Hamburg.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">SICILY.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HOTELS EM ROUTE.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HOTELS EN ROUTE..</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>SYRACUSE.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi xml:id="bookmark96">PICTURE POST CARDS.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>“The Egyptian Gazette" Serlee</p>
                            <p>Is the meet artletlo collection to be found</p>
                            <p> In Egypt-</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>The quickest through Continental routes are by P X &lt;> Brindisi
                                express from Port Said, and the Austrian Lloyd Trieste Vienna
                                express from Alexandria</p>
                            <p>As regards heavy luggage it must Is? Ix.rne in mind that ver> little
                                luggage is allowtvl free on the railway^ of E’lrop*. but then- arc
                                several g&lt;ssl and res|>ons)hle forwarding agents in Egypt who
                                undertake at a fixed charge to deliver |su kages to any address in
                                Eurojie</p>
                            <p>The quickest manner of getting to Europe from Port Said is
                                undoubtedly by the fa>t Mail .Steamers “Osiris and “Isis” to
                                Brindisi. • fne of these leaves Port Said every week, as soon as
                                |s»ssible after receiving the Indian</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>mails from the great liner at rived fr>>rn B >ml>ay</p>
                            <p>1 iie«e small hut comfortable ships have enormously powerful engines,
                                and attain a vry high rate of s|s‘cd. Hiey are called the I erry
                                Ixwit.s, having Is-en qusially built to carry tho British mail from
                                Port Said to Brindisi. If you are going straight through to England
                                you will find the train waiting at Brindisi which will take you
                                to(«lais without changing. It has complete arrangements for sleeping
                                and eating on ls.ard, and you should arrive in Ix.ndon on the fifth
                                day from leaving Port Sind.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">TAORMINA.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>H£Tfl £)?()!.£.</p>
                            <p>First-Clan House. Beautiful Position German</p>
                            <p> Management</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Same Proprietor Hotel Grande Bretagne,
                                    Catania.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">Palermo’</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Villa loiea</p>
                            <p>6vanb IMel.</p>
                            <p>• CALAMTI,</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">SORRENTO</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>aevst. Yaoaavaat) Hotels Tramoatano 4 Tawi. 4 Hotel-Pension Syrtne.
                                Thaee aloeUMit Bdab, which ara situated in the beet part wbat la
                                warthily ruaod the Baaulv Mpot of Italy. era the anuuaJ retort of
                                the most &lt;Matia&lt;uiahwd English and Auisrlcan faiulltaa Ths
                                principal centra for eicuraioua El* trie light throughout. Tannic
                                Kngttah churth</p>
                            <p>Mr. O. Tbamuvtawo, Priipriutor A M»na&lt;«r</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">NAPLES</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL.</p>
                            <p>Unrivalled position. First Claw</p>
                            <p>■ Private Bathroomn. Steam Heating throughout.</p>
                            <p> Newest Sanitary arrangements.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">Havher &amp; DoRPFyKR,
                                Propre</hi>fheiioteliDaglioqi.</p>
                            <p> FIRST CLASS.</p>
                            <p>EVERY MODERN COMFORT</p>
                            <p>Branch Houmi HOTEL OTTALIE, BOLOCNA.</p>
                            <p>HoteiPHOLI,^^</p>
                            <p>LUNGARNO DELLA ZECGA.</p>
                            <p>Beautiful view of the surrounding hills.</p>
                            <p>First elass Hotel with Every Modern Comfort</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>The direct route to Sicily is by the Florio Rubattino Co s steamers,
                            which leave Alex andna wtstkly for MESSINA, where one takes train to
                            TAORMINA, one of the most charm ing ami [xipular places on the island
                                <hi rend="italic">(iiardint </hi>is the station at which to alight,
                            and the drive ui» to Taormina is moet delightful, occupying about one
                            hour. In and around the town is much to interest the visitor The theatre
                            is of Greek origin, but restored under the Romans. CATANIA is the
                            starting place for the ascent of Etna, and here also is a fine Cathedral
                            The Greek, Roman, and Saracenic remains that are found all over the
                            island, are an endless source of pleasure. SYRACUSE has an interesting
                            history, having been a Greek city, which w&amp;t designed by Demosthenes
                            in B.c 41.3, and taken by the Romans in n c 212, when Archimedes wa-
                            slain his tomb is to lie seen The cathedral was once an ancient pagan
                            temple. PALERMO, with about 300, (JOO inhabitants, is the capital of the
                            Island, and enjoys a dehgthful climate. Much of interest is to be found
                            in this fine city The <hi rend="italic">Palazw Kral*</hi> is of
                            Saracenic origin and close to it the church of .V z>va&lt;reinia <hi
                                rend="italic">degh Erimiti</hi> with its picturesque cloisters The
                            Cathedral, Museum, Botanic Gardens, Villa Giulia and Royal Park are also
                            worth a visit</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL VILLA POLITI.</p>
                            <p>NlWf.T KN’LARGKb and thoroughly r*fun»Uh«d. Efortrtc U&lt;ht
                                throughout C«titr»l HmIU^ in evary room UmutifuJ Gardena</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">NORTHERN ITALY </hi>
                                <hi rend="italic">IContlnuutT)</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>■ r.&lt;«</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">The ITALIAN LAKES..</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HOTELS EN ROUTE.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">TAORMINA.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">SAN DOMENICO</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">PALACE HOTEL.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS EVERY COMFORT.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>PALERMO</p>
                            <p>HOTEL DE FRANCE.</p>
                            <p>First Class Only Hotel in Palermo with Cent*al Heating Apparatus
                                throughout. Electric Ligiit. Lift. Winter Garden, loo Rooms, nearly
                                all sunny. Best and Healthiest"Situation.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>EVERY MOHERN COMFORT.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>DANIELL</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HOTEL BRITANNIA.</p>
                            <p>Flsst Cass Ketel !n the best pe.sltien with sapden</p>
                            <p> en the avand Canal.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HOTEL MILAN-BRISTOL.</p>
                            <p>In the name penitien tut mere meiewate.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL TRINACRIA =-</p>
                            <p>The ONLY Hotel In Palermo faoing the Sea Central Heating Electric
                                Lift and Light</p>
                            <p> Private and Public Bathroownc.</p>
                            <p>Roman Heyn Manager. Furtatrly at the Hotel Cecil</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">CENTRAL ITALY.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HOTEL</p>
                            <p>Florence Washington.</p>
                            <p>LUNGARNO.</p>
                            <p>Fimt Cam F»mily Hi>u»e. All Modern Comf.-rU</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Entirely Renovated.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>O. QOBBO,</p>
                            <p>"grand hotel</p>
                            <p>AND</p>
                            <p>HOTEL DE LONDRES.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>'Phe fine steamers of the North German Lloyd leave Alexandria every
                                Wednesday during the season for Naples, the voyage being only 3
                                days.</p>
                            <p>NAPLES is also reached in 10 hours from Palermo by the Florio
                                Ruliattino Co.’s steam ers, which leave daily. One cannot approach
                                Naples or leave it without wishing to explure some of its islands,
                                besides the lovely places on its bay—<hi rend="italic"
                                    >Cattdlamarr</hi> and ibrrMfo. The siyall steamer that takes you
                                to Sorrento [you can drive too] will take you on to <hi
                                    rend="italic">Gapri.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>From Naples to ROME is a train journey of but five hours All who can
                                will devote at least one week to visiting the many historical and
                                interesting portions of the Eternal City, whose charms and beauties
                                are too well known to need comment here</p>
                            <p>Ixiaving the Eternal City with much regret, a railway journey of five
                                hours brings you to FLORENCE, where another week can well l»e sjient
                                admiring the <hi rend="italic">City nf Elouerr</hi> and its
                                surrounding country. In Florunue itself the churches and galleries
                                are of absorbing inte rest, whilst the local promenades and
                                excur­sions should not lie omitted. <hi rend="italic">The
                                    (jaxine</hi> is the moat attractive and fashionable promenade in
                                Florence, whilst the <hi rend="italic">dei Colli,</hi> one of the
                                finest walks in Eunqie, otiened 35 yw ago, goes winding up through
                                the hills</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">PISA</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>The <hi rend="underline">only</hi> Hotel with Central Heating.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>RA<hi rend="underline">PALLO</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">GRAND HOTEL VERDI.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS. ALL UODfRI COMFORTS.</p>
                            <p> LAWN TENNIS.</p>
                            <p>P O. SAMPUTBO</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>ears</p>
                            <p>i a distance of four miles. The most delightful excursion outside
                                Florence is that to I <hi rend="italic">allam br&lt;*a,</hi> with
                                its <hi rend="italic">Mvnantevy</hi> 3,300 feet above the sea level.
                                This is made first by ordinary train from Florence to <hi
                                    rend="italic">St. Ell«r&lt;>.</hi> thence by cog wheel railway
                                to <hi rend="italic">Saltina</hi> The ascent through groves of oaks
                                takes an hour, and most striking i«noramas are unfolded to view.</p>
                            <p>PISA is easily reached from Florence in about 2 hours , here there is
                                a fine Cftthedial and the Leaning Tower A stay of at least one night
                                should if possible be made in order to enjoy the view from the
                                Canqiauile at sunset.</p>
                            <p>VIAREGGIO One of the most delightful places &lt;>n the Italian
                                Riviera near Pisa and on the main line from R une to Genoa. It Is a
                                very convenient half way house between Egypt ano England, and where
                                living is reasonable and the air and surroundings exceptionally
                                gms.1</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Pension Shelley.</p>
                            <p>VIAREGGIO.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">NORTHERN ITALY.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>GENOA (La Buperba). — The</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">GENOA</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>BRISTOL HOTEL.</p>
                            <p>L BERT--!</p>
                            <p>HOTEL CONTINENTAL.</p>
                            <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL.</p>
                            <p>Cuu. 1.</p>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL DE GENES.</p>
                            <p>IV MR.</p>
                            <p>HOTEL HELVETIA Mwiac rn«f> GRAND HOTEL ISOTTA.</p>
                            <p>KllNABT H- HV( aMI A Cu.</p>
                            <p>HOTEL DE LONDRES.,</p>
                            <p>MODERN HOTEL pGRAND HOTEL SAVOIE.</p>
                            <p>HOTEL SMITH.</p>
                            <p>HOTEL RESTAURANT RIGHI.</p>
                            <p>r &lt; H«rwtB«</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">SALSOMAGGIORE</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>HOTEL CENTRAL BAGNI</p>
                            <p>• r— , v V ></p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>GENOA (La Buperba). — The moxt picturex&lt;p'e and interesting city
                                in Italy, with the record of having one of the lowext death
                                average.': of Euro|>ean citiex and a phenomenally eipiabie
                                temiierature— warm m winter and deliuioimity oool breexea from the
                                xurroiiiiding mountains and the Mediterranean in summer X</p>
                            <p>The patriarchal home &lt;f Italy’s most an cient nobility, whose
                                palaces, gardena, ami famouH collection* of statuary, freacoex and
                                ]>aintings, are a constant delight to thousands of ’reveller’ who
                                annually sojourn in Genoa Then there are the superbly decorated
                                medie val churches containing exquirite marble calumns and
                                historical paintings, and the in comjiarahle (xuipc Santa filled
                                with its won­derful tombs.</p>
                            <p>From Genoa to Milan is a matter of only three hours by rail.</p>
                            <p>MILAN is a good centre for Northernlta ly la'fore making the tonr of
                                the lakes. The I’athedral is the principal attrai tioii, with its
                                la'autifiil windows illustrating the History of the Bible 'Hie
                                public gardens and the mono mental (emeb ry are also worth a
                                visit</p>
                            <p>P,etween Bologna and Milan ami only an hour and a half from Milan is
                                bAl*>OMA(l- G1ORE, a renowned health resort on account of its
                                thermal springs, change trains at <hi rend="italic">San
                                    Jlvminii</hi> and in half an hour you are at Salsomaggiore.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>NAPLES</p>
                            <p>SAiFU <hi rend="underline">LU CM</hi> HOHL.</p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS.</p>
                            <p>Kwery Modttrn Corrtfort</p>
                            <p>Central Meatlqg. Private JJatfys Etc</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">ROME</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Hotel Continental.</p>
                            <p>OPPOSITE THE STATION.</p>
                            <p>♦ FIRST CLASS.)---------------------------------- </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell cols="2">
                            <p>MAPI QD H0TEL 1)0 vesuve.</p>
                            <p>Ilfll LLO Fl R.ST CLASS. LATEST COMFORTS</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Le S<hi rend="underline">avoy.</hi> N<hi rend="underline">aples.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>First Class All Comforts. <hi rend="italic">R»»taurant. Winter
                                    Qardan.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>TELKPHGNK AUTO GARAGE.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Trlegmplli.- A'ldrr^</hi> ROSIAMICMO, Naples.</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>NAPLES.</p>
                            <p>GKflND HOTEL DE LONDRES.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">FIRST CLUSS CENTRAL.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Full South. Hpluudid view Hatha, Haaung. Parfard</p>
                            <p>OruinAgr all ita year round. A part man in with batlj</p>
                            <p>and UifleC.</p>
                            <p>DCLVITTfl, PMQIAMI, QAMFI0NI.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell rows="3">
                            <p>F HOTEL DE LA HILLE,</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">FLORENCE.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>/• life * \ °,>EN ALL 1HE YEAK ) STEAMHEATING</p>
                            <p>Electric Light Throughout</p>
                            <p>/s \ Wlnt.r O.rd.n,</p>
                            <p>COICEBT. MUERICIHi BH.</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>CONSTANCE (Germany )</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>INSEL HOTELS</p>
                            <p>M&lt;mt inUrrwtiug Hotel AtnJenL I ki mini can Cotivent now run
                                v«rt«d hit ■ Flnt Ciaaa Metal. iOn Heine Tennk Pishing Howimi.</p>
                            <p>M. B1UNNIR, Maea/ww</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Soiel Cafctafti,</p>
                            <p>ENGELDERG</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">GPAND HOTEL ROYAL................ </hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">.............. GRANDE. BRETAGNE.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>LUNGARNO, ACCIAOLI.</p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS. OPEN ALL THE YEAR.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">CHtOtTKl, Pner</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">BRUNNEN.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>giuji!) HmL SasMa</p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS SKumtlon .</p>
                            <p>ON THK LAKB</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell rows="2">
                            <p>THE MODERN HOTEL. lUNCAMO. FlORENCt.</p>
                            <p>APArrainn wtb mhjayi mw.</p>
                            <p>Ho« end raid runniua waver m erery room. Oenre) Healing AUTO-CARAOL
                                MODIRATI TIRMS.</p>
                            <p>D eli. a U as a it Sons, <hi rend="italic">Propr.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>THUN ( Lakx op Thun.)</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HKRXKHX OHKRI.ANl)</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">PENSION ITTEN.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>P1MT 0LAM FAMILY MtMJIl.</p>
                            <p>Hurruunded by W-wwU. Magnificent view uf the Jungfrau, Mociih, and
                                Eijrr NwtmCHur atta&lt; hed with prlxaU apart fuanta and Hatha Own
                                Farm</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>THUN (Lake of ThunJ.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>PEGLI.</p>
                            <p>HOTEL PttDITWHEE.</p>
                            <p>FIRST CLASS</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HOTEL BEAU-RIVAGE. Beautiful New Hotel.</p>
                            <p>Pint (Ta-ia Electric Light Central Heating and Every Modem
                                Comfort.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>MILAN</p>
                            <p>HOTEL CONTINENTAL FIRST CLASS.</p>
                            <p>FULL SOUTH.</p>
                            <p>CKTSTTRAL.</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">LAUTERBRUNNEN</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>hotel $teii)boek.</p>
                            <p>First Class.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">ALASSIO.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">irAutn mvitnn.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL MEDITERRANEE.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Fir»t Claau. On the Sea Shoro.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>SEA BATHING.</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">ALGIERS.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL ST. GEORGE.</p>
                            <p>Nustapha Superior. Firit-Class in every respect</p>
                            <p>■ OTKL DK LUXA</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>VENICE is a 5 hours jonrney by rail from Milan, and one of the most
                                delightful places imaginable to pass a quiet stay Th>* total absence
                                of vehicular traffic strikes one a* very strange , no horse, cart,
                                camage or bicycle is to be seen, and yet there is the sound of life
                                at every turn The approach the Venice from the Adriatic is unlike
                                that of any other sea |s>rt. The town seems to be gradually, like
                                Aphnslite, bom of the sea, no hills behind, no stretches of ruck,
                                but first the tops of Cum |>anilex appear above the horizon, then
                                slowly the whole ghtp-nng town rises like a fairy mirage out of the
                                calm lagoon.</p>
                            <p>Going northwards from <hi rend="italic">Milan</hi> you make the tour
                                of the beautiful Italian lakes.</p>
                            <p>( I'MO, the birthplace of the younger Pliny, is reached in oueand a
                                quarter hours by tram by way of Monza .</p>
                            <p>Boats leave Como frequently for the other towns on the lake, which is
                                very beautiful, and the scenery on either side going up the lake is
                                most enchanting. CERNOBBIO is a ehanning spot, then come <hi
                                    rend="italic">Tremezza, Cadrnaldna,</hi> and <hi rend="italic"
                                    >Mrnaggto</hi> with the prettily situated town of <hi
                                    rend="italic">Hellaggio</hi> opposite. The walk from 7’remeiso
                                along the shore of the lake to <hi rend="italic">Minaggio</hi> is
                                most enjoyable A steam tram runs from <hi rend="italic">Menaggio
                                </hi>to <hi rend="italic">Porlezzei</hi> on lake Lugano in three
                                quarters of an hour, then steamer to Lugano in two and 1 three
                                quarter hours</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">VENICE</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>LIDO (Venice);VENICE</p>
                            <p>Cmiwkwivmik«rt> ».</p>
                            <p>f.&lt; UM||.,uU</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>BAGNI LIDO (Venice) lUIr &lt; U... . • . • , .</p>
                            <p>CRAND HOTEL DES BAINS.</p>
                            <p>m Flr.t &lt;•!*». hot,,I with .1. ft</p>
                            <p>• -•'«> ■ -ft Kk,,r„ j,</p>
                            <p>... ***** w.iuS.t u.r</p>
                            <p>THE CRAND HOTEL, LIDO.</p>
                            <p>li t.I ,. .. ,... , ,, .l.lUt.t-</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>,u sesirrs sami, uh, vmmc, ivaiv.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">St MORITZ (Ewoaqi»«e) Switzerland</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Thu Grand Hoiel 81. IHoriiz.</p>
                            <p>A Niw Ffhjit Class Hotel</p>
                            <p>With evehy Modern Uonvknif.x* e. <hi rend="italic">AddreM all
                                    engutriee to THE MAN AH EH.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">LAKE OF COMO (Cermqbiq.)</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>grand hotel</p>
                            <p>VILLA D’ESTE</p>
                            <p>F1r.t I Uaa IIouh Flnwt on tho kkr I»..o>na«</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">LUGANO.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">SWITZERLAND..</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">HOTEL BEAU-REGARD and CONTINENTAL, </hi>FIRST
                                CLASS MODERN HOTEL a I'uk n i>i ■> ■■ i 1 u AK*r x N .</p>
                            <p>1. F HELMSHAUEK, <hi rend="italic">Prop.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">SwitzerLmd,</hi> the heart of Europe, has been
                                described as “A cluster of delights and grandeurs."</p>
                            <p>LUGANO is some 20 miles from Como, and reached by train in one-and a
                                hall hours. It has a population of 10,000 iieople and is charm ingly
                                situaUsl on the Ijake of Lugano, amidst lovely Italian scenery.
                                Around it rise M San Salvatore. M. de Caprino and M Generoeo.</p>
                            <p>LOCAKNtl may lie reached by rail from B*dlinzona in forty minutes
                                This pretty town, situated at the top of l&lt;ake Maggiore, has a
                                mild climate, and is an excellent winter resort. The church Madonna
                                del Sasso, situated above the town, is worth a visit, as it contains
                                interest­ing paintings, “Entombment," by Ciseri, and "'1 he Flight
                                into Egypt, by Bramantion.</p>
                            <p>LUCERNE—A sinking picture on the La! e of Lucerne facing the <hi
                                    rend="italic">Kigi</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Pilatun</hi> and
                                the snow-clad Alps</p>
                            <p>In and around the town the walks are charming, and the excursions to
                                be made from Lucerne by ls»at, rail, etc, are very numerous</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">The Eih of Lucerne</hi> abounds in delightful I
                                excursions, those to the <hi rend="italic">Kigi, Pilaf tu, Hurg. n
                                    »tock</hi> and <hi rend="italic">.Sunnenfawy</hi> needing a
                                special visit each Other excursions on the lake can be made by
                                steamer, and the ever&lt;hanging sitnery on the trip from <hi
                                    rend="italic">Lucerne to Eluden</hi> is a source of delight to
                                tlie lover of nature.</p>
                            <p>BRl’NNEN, charmingly situated on the most l>eautiful part of the I^ke
                                of Lucerne, commands magnificent views of lake and mountain scenery.
                                Along the lavke of I’ri from Brunnen to Fluelen runs the famous <hi
                                    rend="italic">A jenirasee</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Till N (on the Ixtke of Thun) half an hour from Berne and one hour
                                from Interlaken. Quiet and quaint , sheltered from winds , just the
                                place to rest and recnj»erate Beautiful walks, through w»l>, and
                                along the lake shore. Kursaal, Concerts, Casino, flares, Tennis,
                                Boating, etc</p>
                            <p>THE BERNICE OBERLAND. - INTER LAK EN.afavoarite summer resort,and the
                                best centre for making excursions in the Qberland, aliounding in
                                fine walks and views. There is a magnificent view of the <hi
                                    rend="italic">Jungfrau</hi> from the Hoheweg, a fine avenue of
                                walnut trees, the chief resort of visitors. Interlaken is also not
                                far from the famous waterfalls, <hi rend="italic">t.ieubach,
                                    Trummribach</hi> and <hi rend="italic">fifaubl>ach</hi> Then
                                also the glaciers of <hi rend="italic">(irinddwald</hi> ami view
                                from <hi rend="italic">Murr. n </hi>and the <hi rend="italic">hying?
                                    Platte</hi> are sights nut to l»* missed</p>
                            <p>( HATEAU D&lt;)EX 3,5&lt;xi ft. above the sea on the new Electric
                                Railway between Montreux and Interlaken, suarounded by magnificent
                                scenery, with pure dry air Much frequented by English jieople in
                                Summer and Winter.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">GREECE and IONIAN ISLES..</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">LUijANQ lari of Lugano)</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>GRAND HOTEL METROPOLE ET</p>
                            <p> MONOPOLE.</p>
                            <p>STRICTLY FIRST CLASS</p>
                            <p>A. Bbucca, Proprietor. <hi rend="underline">a|m| of the</hi> GRAND
                                HOTEL, LUGANO</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">LOCARNO.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>the grand hotel</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>LUGANO</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Hotel St. Gottljard apd</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Ternpnu§.</p>
                            <p>n..«t tlK Ukc Comfortable Family</p>
                            <p>l<hi rend="underline">l</hi>
                                <hi rend="underline">''luw’-</hi>___________________ <hi
                                    rend="underline">llaxdxy</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">LUGANO?</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>HOTEL DES ANGLAIS.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">THE ONLY HOTEL OH THE LUKE I</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Quite New. English Management.</p>
                            <p>_____________ <hi rend="underline">B. W. DOY</hi>LE, <hi
                                    rend="italic">Pop.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">Innsbruck (Tyrol)</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>CARL KAISER’S PENSION-HOTEL</p>
                            <p>NpleiMild eft nation TVrl^ki!^- river and valley. u ndad hy fruit,
                                conifer ainJ ruw ganieua. M dcru &lt;x.fuf..rta and humr like.
                                Library. Kngliali and A men. an |«prv« lUlha, Mana^ew g>.ud Tabla
                                and "mnitafy arran^amenla.</p>
                            <p>lady sulLahle for Uxmv resj'iintig re»t. quittneM, anr| OMUijfe <hi
                                    rend="italic">'Ji</hi> air CapitaJ I mud-piartara fx>r
                                e>mrvl&lt;«i)a Ivlagraph leh-photic, Iterk Ko&lt;»iu. Iirui»
                                iu>ak'rnt«.* tot either</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">INTERLAKEN</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>The Savoy Hotel.</p>
                            <p>QUITE NEW.</p>
                            <p> Splendid Situation.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">CHATEAU DQEX</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>THE GRAND HOTEL</p>
                            <p>The newe-t and most up iodate, th .roughly hirst CLiss and replete
                                with e'eii iti'.&lt;leru comfort.</p>
                            <p>ELtCTR'C UCHT, CrtttHUL HUI kt. PHUA - bAJHY</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HOTEL BERTHOD.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>The Most Comfortable First Class Family Hotel</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi xml:id="bookmark100">THE FOUR BEST</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>IN</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Hotki. NATIONAL — Hotel uk Lvxk with large park l>b» BEltyL’ES —
                                Family House.</p>
                            <p>METROPOLE First class Rouse with moderate charges. 1>U LAC — Central
                                poition Cooks Oipick in the Hotel</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>1 / hours from MILAN - ITALY ■ 6 hours from FLORENCE.</p>
                            <p> GRAND HOTEL DE THERMES.</p>
                            <p> FIRST CLASS EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Many people visitGreece after wintering in Egypt, as it is so easily
                                reached from Alex andna , the climate in April is charming. The best
                                steamers are those of the Khedivial Mail Co. and Russian Steam
                                Navigation Co</p>
                            <p>If |s«sible tourists should arrange to lie in Athens for the Orthodox
                                Easter in order to witness the Good Friday and Easter Eve
                                ceremonies, and to be present at the dancing on the Easter Tuesday
                                festival held at Megara. for which a special train is run from
                                Athens.</p>
                            <p>It is wortn while to sjiend a few days in CORFU on account of tlie
                                beauty of the scenery There is also good sni]>e and quail bixiting
                                to be had.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Bhhrilub BR0TitF.a\ <hi rend="italic">Pmiprutorf.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">TANGIERS</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>HOTEL CECIL</p>
                            <p> HOTEL DE FRANCE ‘</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">TUNIS</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">GRAND HOTEL DE PARIS.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Hotel de Loqdres.</p>
                            <p>CONSTANTINOPLE.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>SALSOMAGGIORE (Italy.)</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>A jlaaaantly xituatwd Tillage lyin&lt; in the Talley between Pia^enxa
                                and Parma rapidly becomlat lamoiu for ita waters which are Tery rich
                                in . &lt;n&lt;* 'odm*. and the richest in the world</p>
                            <p>*n lithium' atrontnun and ichthyoL and hare ■ncce«aftilly used in the
                                treatment of acrofula. tnbnrculoua affectiuua, ladies com F**
                                nY8,</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">Grand Hotel /Ailan.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">FIRST CLASS. EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <p> P., FERRARTO, Proprietor.</p>
            </div>
            
            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7">
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Expeditions</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>NOUS</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Graines de Coton do ler Septa mb re aa 3' Porta de destination</p>
                            <p>T 69 359</p>
                            <p> 31 196</p>
                            <p>.. 9 346</p>
                            <p>7.839 5,597</p>
                            <p> 7&lt;»0</p>
                            <p>6 381</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Novembre 1906, par Hall _</p>
                            <p>Lundraa</p>
                            <p>Liverpool Brutal</p>
                            <p>Southampton Lnth</p>
                            <p>Sharpnooe Glasgow</p>
                            <p>Greenock .............. </p>
                            <p>Avonmcutb...</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>8.909</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell cols="2">
                            <p>r&lt;xirteaui</p>
                            <p>t Hain** dr Mitos</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>Shga.</cell>
                        <cell>1/9 4 6/ .. 7/ ..</cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>-/ -/</p>
                            <p>-/</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>-/ ..</cell>
                        <cell>-/</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>LONDRIH</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1/9 4</cell>
                        <cell>-/</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Ttrtirtmani</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>6/6 .</cell>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">-1</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Grunt* de uoUxi</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>7/6 ..</cell>
                        <cell>_ /</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>HULL</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>&lt; htpiona</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>-/</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>King’t Lynn Dock* Boe too Dock* Rochester</p>
                            <p>Manohester</p>
                            <p>Marseille ___ </p>
                            <p>Havre.................. </p>
                            <p>Danker jae...</p>
                            <p>Nan tea</p>
                            <p>Brims Rotterdam</p>
                            <p>Ham bo arg . .</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Total</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <list type="ordered">
                                <item>950</item>
                            </list>
                            <p>9 795 3 415</p>
                            <p>950 3.040</p>
                            <list type="simple">
                                <item>6(X) 2 4 22 1 950</item>
                            </list>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>2 205</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>T. 161 637</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                            <p>GENERAL PRODUCE ASSOCIATION</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Les differences de Contnts de ooton 1 oomme tuit ;</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>,ni pour livraison »ur</p>
                            <p>oom bro out 6t4 fixf'cs</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>BBOWN</p>
                            <p>Entre Good Fair st F. G F ... P T 1 „ Pally Good Fair et Good „ 1
                                hauti mtpti rr payovm</p>
                            <p>Entre Good Fair et F G. F. . P.T 1 „ Fully Good Pair et Good ., I Lm
                                notons HabteBgypfe et Fayoi livrablea oontre oantrate Ddcembre, mo.
                                one bonification do P.T. 97j plus la plnalito do P.T 7 j.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>10 —</p>
                            <p>10 —</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>12 |</p>
                            <p>15 —</p>
                            <p>»&lt;im aont i, moyonnant</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>1,</cell>
                        <cell>B/B</cell>
                        <cell>1,443</cell>
                        <cell>Ard.</cell>
                        <cell>19,409</cell>
                        <cell>Sacs</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>1.</cell>
                        <cell>u</cell>
                        <cell>1,677</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>18,818</cell>
                        <cell>■*</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>1,</cell>
                        <cell>u</cell>
                        <cell>2,406</cell>
                        <cell>••</cell>
                        <cell>16000</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>4.</cell>
                        <cell>gl</cell>
                        <cell>3,960</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>17186</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>ft.</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>4,415</cell>
                        <cell>H</cell>
                        <cell>29,013</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>I.</cell>
                        <cell>ng</cell>
                        <cell>4,42ft</cell>
                        <cell>•1</cell>
                        <cell>98.565</cell>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">1.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>1M9</cell>
                        <cell>••</cell>
                        <cell>25,848</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>1HO</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>8.</cell>
                        <cell>■ a</cell>
                        <cell>7,452</cell>
                        <cell>H</cell>
                        <cell>85,260</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>».</cell>
                        <cell>U</cell>
                        <cell>4,483</cell>
                        <cell>If</cell>
                        <cell>23,040</cell>
                        <cell>M</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>10,</cell>
                        <cell>g|</cell>
                        <cell>5,87ft</cell>
                        <cell>H</cell>
                        <cell>18 673</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>50</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>11.</cell>
                        <cell>M</cell>
                        <cell>4,741</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>19,859</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>7,ft00</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>81,777</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>142</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>13,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>6,344</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>30 823</cell>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>14,</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>5,547</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>85,853</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>is.</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>5.993</cell>
                        <cell>• 1</cell>
                        <cell>32,804</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>H</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>ft,90 4</cell>
                        <cell>ae</cell>
                        <cell>80,932</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>183</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>17,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>4,880</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>29,833</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>18,</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>4,599</cell>
                        <cell>U</cell>
                        <cell>17,763</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>81</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>1*.</cell>
                        <cell>M</cell>
                        <cell>V92</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>22,061</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>174</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Xk</cell>
                        <cell>a a</cell>
                        <cell>4,34?</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>19 832</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>75</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>si.</cell>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>3,966</cell>
                        <cell>•I</cell>
                        <cell>17,791</cell>
                        <cell>a*</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>n.</cell>
                        <cell>g|</cell>
                        <cell>8,140</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>18 934</cell>
                        <cell>ea</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>>8,</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>4,896</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>I8,«9O</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>201</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>>4.</cell>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>8,489</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>17,847</cell>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>114</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>85,</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>4,118</cell>
                        <cell>ae</cell>
                        <cell>16 300</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>150</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>26,</cell>
                        <cell>U</cell>
                        <cell>4,242</cell>
                        <cell>||</cell>
                        <cell>16 252</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>131</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>27.</cell>
                        <cell>• 1</cell>
                        <cell>3,516</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>1ft 978</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>263</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>88,</cell>
                        <cell>U</cell>
                        <cell>4,481</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>25 348</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>120</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>29,</cell>
                        <cell>, |</cell>
                        <cell>4,359</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>19 724</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>=_</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>>0.</cell>
                        <cell>a.</cell>
                        <cell>4 291</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>30,210</cell>
                        <cell>•1</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>31,</cell>
                        <cell>• 9</cell>
                        <cell>4,837</cell>
                        <cell>91</cell>
                        <cell>24 738</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>260</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Da</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Ard.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>&lt;95,461 Sam</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>142,127</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>9,091</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Graines da ooton</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>ARR1VAGH8 A MINBTBL-B ASS A L da mon do Dtoambre 1905 Ooton</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>fl/B</p>
                            <p>NB — Cette lists art relev6o das Ragutraa</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>nous la publioDi afin qu'on peiaaa la comparer avec les amvagee dn
                            moi* ce d4oembro 1906</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Direction Generals</p>
                            <p> des DOUAIES EGYPHElHiES</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">Taatr D Exrorranow pour le mou de Deretn fare
                                1906</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>OBSIGNATION</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>VnlU</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Ooaoo</cell>
                        <cell>p</cell>
                        <cell>can tar</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>1J5</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Orainra d« Lotoo .</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>ard«b</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>too</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>„ Harun</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>ran tar</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>275</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>IU*a tteali «Bah*ra</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>ardeb</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>945</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Ftraa Saidi et IWhira</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>125</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>170</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Mau</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>820</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Org*-</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>520</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Pou vbx-lMa</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>500</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Pelita f»'U</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>200</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>„ „ oonraaaAa</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>400</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>H.lbt</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>500</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Rix (avec emb.)</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>toO</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Hu en peille</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>kilo</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Rn Jctui</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Farine No. 1 i 5 (90 vkra)</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>nat</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>900</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>8ucr» blanc (rn paina)</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>can bar</cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>5to</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>.. .. (jfrand morr i</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>500</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>(en poudrr) No. 1</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>rouge ' Farrhout I en paina</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>240</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>„ ,, „ rn poudrt</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>0</cell>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">zju</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>(oUxna Afnt4 rt ibeart pour</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Turqute</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>••</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>600</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Prix des</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">sacs.</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>— </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Qito/itJ indtmw</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell cols="2">A ooton do 8 livres P T</cell>
                        <cell>5 1 2</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>,. .. 3j</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>6 8,4</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>A C4r6nles „ 2 j</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>3 10,40</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>4 10,40</cell>
                        <cell>-</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>.. &amp;</cell>
                        <cell>»</cell>
                        <cell>5 3/4</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>GRAINRh de coton</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>906</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Le</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>P.T</cell>
                        <cell>65</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>PT 65</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>—■</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>44</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>.. &lt;5</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>a a</cell>
                        <cell>64</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>a «5</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>aa</cell>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>64</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>H</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>gg</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>44</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>M</cell>
                        <cell>>1</cell>
                        <cell>••</cell>
                        <cell>•ft</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fiix do dinponible do 15 Havtb Borm</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Grains dr ouUin.</p>
                            <p>&lt; '4r*to«a</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>LIVWFOOL</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>9/</p>
                            <p>1/9</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>4 10/</p>
                            <p>.. 2/</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>&lt; uUMI</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>ShKB.</cell>
                        <cell>11/</cell>
                        <cell>4 /</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>1 &lt; t ■ A ■ '</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1/6</cell>
                        <cell>.. /</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Tourtesui</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>9/</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Gr^inr- de outoo</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>oe</cell>
                        <cell>10/</cell>
                        <cell>. —/</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>(hjfnonfi _</cell>
                        <cell>M ..</cell>
                        <cell>eo</cell>
                        <cell>-/</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Gnunre de ooton (Ihmkerxue)</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Fr 12 4</p>
                            <p>12 ..</p>
                            <p>10 .,</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Ihgnuofl</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Le Havre</p>
                            <p>Dunkerque</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Hamburg St. Peteml'ourg</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Fr. 2-</p>
                            <p>. 2.56</p>
                            <p>.. 3 -</p>
                            <p>,. 2.50</p>
                            <p>.. i-</p>
                            <p>Fr. 20—4 22 50.</p>
                            <p>..25- I</p>
                            <p>.. 25 - i</p>
                            <p>.. 25 — <hi rend="italic">J</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>p&lt;r 100 kilog</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell cols="3">Arrivages de</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">la semaine</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Coton</cell>
                        <cell cols="3">U hain Fkvufi</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>Bal 6 677</cell>
                        <cell>Ard.</cell>
                        <cell>29 487 SacH</cell>
                        <cell>1 175</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>„ 5.839</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>87.140</cell>
                        <cell>602</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>„ 7 363</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>25 859</cell>
                        <cell>119</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>.. 7 440</cell>
                        <cell>..</cell>
                        <cell>29 008</cell>
                        <cell>163</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>„ 6 503</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>26 919</cell>
                        <cell>22</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>„ 56H5</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>27 135</cell>
                        <cell>183</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>21</cell>
                        <cell>„ 6 081</cell>
                        <cell>II</cell>
                        <cell>81.650</cell>
                        <cell>7</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell cols="3">ImvigN mem* Mmaine</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>1905</cell>
                        <cell>1904</cell>
                        <cell>1905</cell>
                        <cell>1904</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Bailes</cell>
                        <cell>Balle*</cell>
                        <cell>Ardebe</cell>
                        <cell>Ardebe</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell cols="2">ChTON</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">GxalNEB</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>5 993</cell>
                        <cell>2.785</cell>
                        <cell>32 804</cell>
                        <cell>13.881</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>5 904</cell>
                        <cell>5.648</cell>
                        <cell>20 932</cell>
                        <cell>18 638</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>4 880</cell>
                        <cell>4 169</cell>
                        <cell>29 233</cell>
                        <cell>19 100</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>4.599</cell>
                        <cell>5 079</cell>
                        <cell>17 763</cell>
                        <cell>16 894</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>19</cell>
                        <cell>4 892</cell>
                        <cell>4 324</cell>
                        <cell>22.061</cell>
                        <cell>16 041</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>80</cell>
                        <cell>4 347</cell>
                        <cell>4 267</cell>
                        <cell>19 332</cell>
                        <cell>27 504</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>21</cell>
                        <cell>3 866</cell>
                        <cell>4 369</cell>
                        <cell>17 791</cell>
                        <cell>18 951</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell cols="3">Arr.vtgfe semuit ultxeU</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>22</cell>
                        <cell>4 896</cell>
                        <cell>8 355</cell>
                        <cell>13 890</cell>
                        <cell>13 604</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>23</cell>
                        <cell>3 429</cell>
                        <cell>3 4-6</cell>
                        <cell>17 847</cell>
                        <cell>13 152</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>24</cell>
                        <cell>4 118</cell>
                        <cell>4 181</cell>
                        <cell>16.800</cell>
                        <cell>18.582</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>4 842</cell>
                        <cell>8 910</cell>
                        <cell>16.853</cell>
                        <cell>15.5( 9</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>16</cell>
                        <cell>3 516</cell>
                        <cell>8.883</cell>
                        <cell>15 978</cell>
                        <cell>13 517</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>27</cell>
                        <cell>4 461</cell>
                        <cell>4 962</cell>
                        <cell>25.348</cell>
                        <cell>18.463</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>88</cell>
                        <cell>4 859</cell>
                        <cell>4 190</cell>
                        <cell>19 724</cell>
                        <cell>24.081</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>H>m bey</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Aleiandne, le 19 decembre 1906.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>ADMINISTRATION</p>
                            <p> DBS DOMAINB8 DE L’BTAT</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Aoincx d’Aluandbh</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Lota</cell>
                        <cell cols="2">Ballas</cell>
                        <cell>Cantan</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Pnx</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>176,</cell>
                        <cell>Mdcir,</cell>
                        <cell>68</cell>
                        <cell>388</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>15/16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>180,</cell>
                        <cell>Ro winch.</cell>
                        <cell>81</cell>
                        <cell>479</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>7 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>182,</cell>
                        <cell>Bosh biohe,</cell>
                        <cell>59</cell>
                        <cell>347</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>1/16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>178,</cell>
                        <cell>D qtnlra,</cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>77</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7,16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>202</cell>
                        <cell>Beshbiche,</cell>
                        <cell>5</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>204,</cell>
                        <cell>Doqmlra,</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>206,</cell>
                        <cell>Mdcir,</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>60</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7 15</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>‘208,</cell>
                        <cell>Ro winch,</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>60</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7/16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>210,</cell>
                        <cell>Santa,</cell>
                        <cell>60</cell>
                        <cell>355</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>1 8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>211,</cell>
                        <cell>■ ■</cell>
                        <cell>60</cell>
                        <cell>370</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>7 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>2 2,</cell>
                        <cell>to</cell>
                        <cell>43</cell>
                        <cell>257</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>9 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>215,</cell>
                        <cell>.a</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>65</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>9 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>214,</cell>
                        <cell>■ a</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>98</cell>
                        <cell>17</cell>
                        <cell>r 16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>217,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>14</cell>
                        <cell>92</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>218,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>36</cell>
                        <cell>232</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>213,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>33</cell>
                        <cell>202</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>1,16</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>200,</cell>
                        <cell>Sakha,</cell>
                        <cell>8</cell>
                        <cell>46</cell>
                        <cell>18</cell>
                        <cell>5/8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>184,</cell>
                        <cell>Rowineb,</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>56</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>7/8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>185,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                        <cell>56</cell>
                        <cell>85</cell>
                        <cell>7/8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>186,</cell>
                        <cell>Sakha,</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>90</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>7 8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>187,</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>52</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>7/8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>189,</cell>
                        <cell>Reahbicbe,</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                        <cell>36</cell>
                        <cell>26</cell>
                        <cell>3 4</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>188,</cell>
                        <cell>Sakha,</cell>
                        <cell>11</cell>
                        <cell>66</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>l/«</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>190,</cell>
                        <cell>Bedibichs,</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>22</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>1 8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>191.</cell>
                        <cell>Rowineb,</cell>
                        <cell>42</cell>
                        <cell>235</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>7 8</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>193,</cell>
                        <cell>Sakha,</cell>
                        <cell>52</cell>
                        <cell>300</cell>
                        <cell>25</cell>
                        <cell>1/4</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>195,</cell>
                        <cell>Beabbiohe,</cell>
                        <cell>70</cell>
                        <cell>396</cell>
                        <cell>15</cell>
                        <cell>1 4</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>198,</cell>
                        <cell>Sakha,</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>52</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>199,</cell>
                        <cell>Rowineb,</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>9</cell>
                        <cell>20</cell>
                        <cell>—</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Enoberes de jeadi 90 d£o. 1906, t</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Uh.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>de qiahtd afifi, lei</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Lea 16 premiere aont aatrea de joanovich</p>
                            <p>Le toat a 6t6 adjagl k 1'Anglo Egyptian Bank, Limited</p>
                            <p>N B —A l’ia u» de I'ooobfcr*, il a procldl a la rente d'an lot de
                                oo’on scarto de 36</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Anglo Etfvphan Rank, L mi'ed.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>COALS</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell cols="3">
                            <hi rend="italic">Current pricea prr ton !rtt &lt;>n waym</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>Shga</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">CaBI</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>lle>t quality</cell>
                        <cell>26/</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>\ «wr K’</cell>
                        <cell>lin-t quality</cell>
                        <cell>25/ ..</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell>XiWCAWTLK</cell>
                        <cell>llolhal</cell>
                        <cell>20/6</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>-/</p>
                            <p>-/</p>
                            <p>21/</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>lleirde</p>
                            <p>Dunlop*</p>
                            <p>Heat Hamilum Ell Nluklifield liwt I-aiuanhirv</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <list type="simple">
                                <item>.. 21/</item>
                            </list>
                            <p>20 6 ., s21/ 20/6 .. 21/ 20/6 ., 21/ 19/6 20/3</p>
                            <p>19/6 ., 20/ 19/6 ., 20/ 19/6 .. 20/ 19/6 .. 20/</p>
                            <list type="simple">
                                <item>.. 2u/</item>
                            </list>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Anobur</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>at>, .. »/ ..</p>
                            <p>26/ .</p>
                            <p>26/ ..</p>
                            <p>26/ ..</p>
                            <p>26/</p>
                            <p>40/ .</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>-/</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE AGENTS FOR</p>
                            <p>Muhbh. HUSTON,</p>
                            <p>Fixed and Portable Steam and Oil Engines, Corn Mills</p>
                            <p> Patent Tib ben making Thraahing Machines.</p>
                            <p>.Mkbsm. PLATT BROTHKRS 4 CO., LIMITED, Oldham.</p>
                            <p>Cotton Ginning Machinery</p>
                            <p>Mrshbn. JOHN FOWLER 4 00., LIMITED, Lnidb.</p>
                            <p> Steam Ploughing Machinery and Sundries.</p>
                            <p> THE CENTRAL CYCLONE CO., LIMITED, London.</p>
                            <p> Grinding and Pulverising Machinery</p>
                            <p>Mi88H8. CAMMBLL, LAIRD 4 CO., LD., op Shipfibld,</p>
                            <p> Steel Ralls, springs, buffers, &amp;c. — Patent sand blast
                                files.</p>
                            <p>Mihhb8. MERRYWRATHKR 4 SONS, London.</p>
                            <p>Steam and Manual Fire Engines.</p>
                            <p>Mb88R8. F. REDDAWAY 4 CO., LD., Pbndlbton, MANOHrem.</p>
                            <p>The Camel Brand Belting, etc., etc.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>PROCTOR 4 OO., LIMITHD, Linoolm.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>THE ENGELBERG RICE HULLER</p>
                            <p>(,ilkea Vortex Turbine.</p>
                            <p>Menskrh. A. RANSOME Co., LIMITED, Nxwark or Tbrnt</p>
                            <p>Wood W .rking Machinery and Appliance*</p>
                            <p> MCCORMICK’S REAPERS &amp; MOWERS</p>
                            <p> PLANET JUNIOR AGRICULTURAL IMPLEMENTS</p>
                            <p> iLiffc, etc , wUj.</p>
                            <p>OLIVER PLOUGHS.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>W. H. ALLEN, San &amp; Co., Lid</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">QUEEN'S ENGINEERING WORKS.</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Bedford. England</p>
                            <p>Makers of the well-known</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CONQUEROR</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Centrifugal Pump &amp; PunipingEngines; also of <hi rend="underline"
                                >Dynamos </hi>and High-Speed Economical</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="underline">Steam-Engines</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>A large assortment of our pumps are kept in etock by our Agents, The
                            Midland Engineering Oo. of Rue de la Qare du Cairo, No. 2,
                            Alexandria.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Representative: F. C BEVAN,</p>
                            <p>8, Ibrahim Bey Wafa's Bail ling, 8h. Gama Cbarkasse,</p>
                            <p>28580- is-12-906 Cairo</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>ni</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>EVERY MODERN COMFORT</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CD</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Corso - Hotel.</p>
                            <p>Corso Vittorio Emanuele.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">opihid</hi>
                            <hi rend="italic"> i»on.</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Corso Restaurant Milan</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Rooma fot 1 600 Paraona. Oarlt*- Conear t a</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Caffe Riffli, Milan.</p>
                            <p>(.alien* Vittorio Knianuela.</p>
                            <p>OLD RtPUTATION INTIRILV RENOVATED</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Caffe Reataurant Concerta.</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Modern Hotel</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Corse Umberto I.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">RIMINI</hi> — Summrr rw.rt, Sv*fwthing Hotels.
                                R«-v*ur*aU KutmaI. ViIIm. Sports, &lt;-tc</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">
                                    <hi rend="underline">Proprutori</hi>
                                </hi>
                                <hi rend="underline"> tooleta Milanese Alberghl, Restaurants ed
                                    AfTInl. </hi>
                                <hi rend="underline">Main Office. </hi>
                                <hi rend="underline">MILAN</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CAIRO SEWAGE TRANSPORT Cr.‘, Ld.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>ENGRAIS NATUREL8 COMPL1TI</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>G. MA R C U S &amp; Co.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">HOLE AEtETB FOE EGYPT FOE</hi>MILNBR’S BAFK
                                COMPANY. LIMITED.</p>
                            <p> Transatlantic Fire Insurance Company, Limited</p>
                            <p> or HAMBUBQ. (OOY1XI ALSO BUBGLAXY BISKS.)</p>
                            <p>The National Assurance Coamaay ef Ireland</p>
                            <p>Now assumed by the Yorkshire Fire &lt;k Life uiaraaos Coy.
                                Established 1824 Fire Insurance Policies granted ou ail approved
                                Descriptions of Property, at moderate rates, ALEXANDRIA, Maiacn A.
                                N. Asm, Bue Constaolinople. CAIRO, Boafa</p>
                            <p>H I UM</p>
                            <p>STEINEMANN, MABABDI &amp; 0”</p>
                            <p>Ti*« ptlan HntflsiMMrtntf BSorae.</p>
                            <p>MERCHANTS, CONTRACTORS &amp; MACHINERY IMPORTERS, ALEXANDRU</p>
                            <p> 8oto AfBDts for Egypt, Aaia Minor and Syria lot</p>
                            <p>Meson. CLAYTONA SHUTTLEWORTH, Unooh. Portable A fixed bgtaes 4
                                Beilers, Con mils, Thrashing, Strawbraising 4 Cutting <hi
                                    rend="underline">Mach inis</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Maasra. GALUJWA YS, LTD., Manchester.—The Imrgest Boiler Works is ths
                                World. WALTER A. WOOD, Mowing ana Baaping Machine Co. Hoomeh
                                Pall&lt; NT (Amorim Reapers, Mowon, HarvsrtenFksLs</p>
                            <p>PIGUWT 4 Co., Lyons. — Prsnoh Ktanm Knginas AVKLING A PORI ER, LIMII
                                DI), Rw'hester.—Stenin Rollon and Steam Pl<hi rend="underline"
                                    >ou</hi>gh*</p>
                            <p>LIB TANNKR1K3 LYONNAI3R3. On Ilins (Rhdue).—Bmrt Leather Baiting.</p>
                            <p>8 3 HINDLEY, Burton, Dorost — Vertaoai Engines and Boden, ipeouJIy
                                designed for driving Eleotrio DynacMN 4 Centrifugal Pnmpo, etc.,
                                etc.</p>
                            <p>H1LLAIRET HUGUBOT, Paris.—Efootngians</p>
                            <p>L DUMONT, Paris.—Centrifugal prmpe.</p>
                            <p>AFAR TURNER, LTD., Ipowtah - Floor .Villa 11188-84 11 9CI</p>
                            <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son (Egypt), Ltd.</p>
                            <p>nmnama, neciaa, raram Hninau.</p>
                            <p>MECHANICAL AND ELECTRICAL RNG1NRER8, ALSO SHIPBUILDERS, RQ, AC Al!
                                alasaeo of engineering work sod supply of storm undertaken.</p>
                            <p>Pontoon Dock for raising voaseis <hi rend="italic">al</hi> the
                                largest rim</p>
                            <p>BOULAC ENGINE WORKS</p>
                            <p>Baa»na at Baanu BarKi. Hannm (CAIROJ, ALEXANDRIA AND KHARTUM iw
                                ron</p>
                            <p>8TOH WASSER ft WINTER PUTHB</p>
                            <p> LEGGING ft MILITARY IMdULFMENTB</p>
                            <p> CORPORATION LTD.</p>
                            <p>JMaM a (Ja. Otaa aeo ou M«w</p>
                            <p>CHUBB ft BUN’S LOCK ft SAFE CO LTD</p>
                            <p> UMrtMntaStfSaa kaaS, IS*</p>
                            <p> tf wamw ran aaaaf^M.</p>
                            <p>COCHRAN ft CO. ANNAN, LTD</p>
                            <p>Th* UNhma moms warn mim.</p>
                            <p>THE SEAMLESS STEEL BOAT 00, LTD</p>
                            <p>THE COOPER STEAM DIGGER CO LIT</p>
                            <p>niwei aaS* to mw Ma. a •> I aw4 11</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>isoiL.K m.encw'rm</p>
                            <p>RICHARD GARR1HT ft SONS. LTD</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>SHAND, MAEON ft CO.</p>
                            <p> reams mawa mS Maaaal Mn B^waa</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>NOBELS EXPLOSIVES 00., LTD</p>
                            <p> ewtaa'la S»«aMi ^_O«lay«, Simaaxaa^ aUaay ftwa. Ma.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>GEO. ANGUS ft CO., LTD</p>
                            <p> laZ'UHST* *“■ ***•</p>
                            <p>TANGY E8 LIMITED (BOLE V KN DORR</p>
                            <p>Maa*. 00 aaS Oaa mataaa «W0 FnSa** PlaM. Fama* *M</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Price 65 piastres Postage 3 piastres</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>ROBERTS, HUGHES &amp;Con</p>
                            <p>28913 Sharia Fl Manakh, CAIRO.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>The Brit-Ban Ventilated Shoes</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Blacl\ &amp; Taq</p>
                            <p>Clacc Kid</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>lUustnied</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>meet comfortable ft moat easy fitting shoe? made.</p>
                            <p>Ladies who appreciate comfort with elegance in footwear should give
                                these shoes a trial.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">
                                <hi rend="underline">ROME.</hi>
                            </hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>HOTEL ROYA</p>
                            <p>MOST MODERN HOTEL.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="underline">SPLENDID SITUATION. MODERATE PRICES</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">
                                    <hi rend="underline">FLORENCE (Italy).</hi>
                                </hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Luckrubaclfs Hotel................ </p>
                            <p>. . . . Metropole 4 Londres.</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>OpPOfllTl BHIPHIABO'a</p>
                            <p>for Books, Stationery Ntwtytptri, and *' Bgyptian Gazette" Picture
                                Poet Card*</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CAIRO.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>CROMPTON ft Oo., LTD.</p>
                            <p>Oyaaaaa ai*»M and iliMMi aamiaary or aU teartoaaa</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">KOPP£L</hi>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>ALEXANDRIA.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>CHARLES EVANS.</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Passenver, Shipping,</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">Cusfom House and Foruardiig Agent</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Ba* al POST BAID</p>
                            <p>Mrua peewoaj «Meai>..ri riuwi^L</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>PALERMO (Sicily.)</p>
                            <p>Frickep’s Savoy Hotel &amp; Pension.</p>
                            <p>THE OHLY HOUSE WITH MO Dll AH TERMS. I</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">OFFERINO FVIRr MODERN COMFORT</hi> I</p>
                            <p>BtcamheaUuc, Lift, etc. *>ote 24* <hi rend="italic">i</hi>
                            </p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>drnaiaur™ —TANGYB8' GAS ENGINES with Prodocm Plants, COOPER Pd TEN!
                                STEAM DIGGER spooially ruitahla foi &lt;mall landownon</p>
                            <p>rWsgvsp^ Addrass <hi rend="italic">"SNQINBSR. CAIRCT —4 "IINQINBBR,
                                    ALBIANDRIA</hi>
                            </p>
                            <p>Works Offce tn town, Ohara BaRKi Hedaed (Cano).</p>
                            <p>Alexandria Show Room*, Offioes and St. res, Rae do la Garo da Cairo
                                No. 1. Si-9 4</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Egyptian Delta Light Railways Co., Limited.</p>
                            <p>Connections mada with the moat important train* of the State Railway
                                in the Provino* <hi rend="italic">f</hi> Rebora. Gbarbioh, Dakahliab
                                liberties and Gulioubieb. FL-trngk mrears /or gauds between ■ lI
                                stations of tbe Company and -ww <hi rend="italic">10(1</hi> pno. <hi
                                    rend="italic">ipal itathau of ika </hi>/Wwt* AaUinsy in Upper
                                and .wer Egypt. flood* may also bo through-b>>->ked from or Io any
                                station on Helonas tail way. The Company has 9'» station* upened for
                                public Telegraph Service in conjunction with 11 ofloeu of the
                                Government Telegraph Depa- menu For temr taWos, fcwoft ■</p>
                            <p>pplyto the oWloea at Cairo Alexandria Dam*, boar. Tan tab, Eageaig or
                                Saida Zenab</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>Halouan Branch Time Tabla</p>
                            <p>Cain>ta»«. Uat&lt;/&lt;/> S.tiH |u9 It) IQlu ti.lu 1210 I |.»
                                I'exrah6.54 a to 0 <hi rend="italic">JU</hi> IU <hi rend="italic"
                                    >1»</hi> 11 <hi rend="italic">M ILM</hi> 111</p>
                            <p>Helouao urr 7 15 N 46 9 4,'a 10.47 11.47(1247 15'</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>from let Wovomber, 100 S.</p>
                            <p>210 I 10 4.10 t ilt 4 10 « w> 7 » t >> ia- ||»> I U</p>
                            <p>29 124 4 "9 5 <hi rend="italic">*9</hi> 8 34 S 59 7 40 X.54 10 19 II
                                49 I 1'</p>
                            <p>
                                <hi rend="italic">1</hi> 47 t 45 4 45 5.45 453 7.15 8. 5 9 U 10 35 U
                                5 I M</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>IfvluuUl fourth (torn.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <hi rend="italic">dtp.</hi> 6IO75OMIO 9 IO 10.10 11 l&lt;» 121" „ 6 31
                            —8 31 B 1'130 II Jh 12 *1 orr 6 55 &lt;4.20 S 53 9 45 10.47 11.45,12
                            47</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <p>1 15 210X10 4 10 5.10 6 10 7 3U 8.30 la-</p>
                            <p>I 33 2to 1 <hi rend="italic">M</hi> 4 JM 5 2| 8 33 7.4* XXi IO lb</p>
                            <p>I to 247 3 45 4 45 5 43 435 8 5 9 In 10 40</p>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CYPRUS,</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>II 4*</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>CYPRUS &lt; iOVr.<hi rend="underline">BXM KN</hi>T RAIEXVAYH</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>aa fol I"</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>(AibMlral (IMHM</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Fort .Said W«d 19ch</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>10</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>Telephone Company of Egypt, Limited</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>l. Oaatalli 4 Co. ; Ramlah, Coetnl Officm, Hao Stefano C<hi
                                rend="underline">toai</hi>nr.,</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p> </p>
            </div>
            
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8"> 
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

