<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Adam Hutson--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2018-02-05">Febuary 5, 2018<!-- Febuary 5, 2018 --></date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1907-01-07"><name>Monday</name>, January 7,
                        1907<!-- January 7, 1907 --></date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="masthead">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <!-- 7654, January 7, 1907, eight pages -->
                    <head type="sub">No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>] ALEXANDRIA,
                        THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="1"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ric01">
                    <head>Royal Insurance Coy</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE.</p>
                    <p>Largest Fire Office in the World.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; CO., Agents, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY, LIMITED.</p>
                    <p>(ESTABLISHED 1782);</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; CO., Agents, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">31-3-906</measure> FRED. OTT &amp; CO., Sub-Agents,
                        Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-abp01">
                    <head>THE ARTESIAN BORING AND PROSPECTING COMPANY.</head>
                    <p>(SOCIÉTÉ ANONYME)</p>
                    <p>CAIRO, 28, SHARIA-EL-MANAKH,<lb/> (OPPOSITE IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK).</p>
                    <p>I. —Installation of complete Water supplies for drinking, agricultural,
                        and<lb/> industrial purposes by means of artesian wells.</p>
                    <p>II. - Deep borings for prospecting purposes in all conditions of soil by
                        means of the<lb/> “Express Boring System."</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24,437-12-1-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="cps01">
                    <head>Cairo Photographic Stores</head>
                    <head>O. DIRADOUR</head>
                    <p>PLACE DEL'OPERA</p>
                    <p>SPECIAL DEPOT FOR KODAKS AND FILMS</p>
                    <p> Plates, printing paper and supplies of the best English, French and German
                        brands. </p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">530-18.3.907</measure></p>
                    <p>AMATEUR WORK, CAMERA REPAIRS, ETC.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-jes01">
                    <head>Joseph Evans &amp; Sons.</head>
                    <p>Culwell Works.</p>
                    <p>Wolverhampton.</p>
                    <p>Makers of PUMPS and Pumping Machinery For all Purposes.</p>
                    <p>Irrigation Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Mining Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Boiler &amp; Pumps Combined.</p>
                    <p>Centrifugal Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Household Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Telgrams: EVANS, Wolverhampton.</p>
                    <p>Write for List No. 9.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">2516</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cct01">
                    <head>Calvert's Carbolic Toilet Soap</head>
                    <p>Ensures a Clear, Soft Skin.</p>
                    <p>It is pure throughout, fragrantly perfumed, emollient, and antisceptic, (10%
                        crystal carbolic). It quickly removes dust and dirt, takes away the
                        unpleasant effects of perspiration, and leaves instead a delicious feeling
                        of thorough purification.</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Sold by local Chemists and Storekeepers.</hi></p>
                    <p>Made by F.C. Calvert &amp; Co., Manchester, Eng.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-adr01">
                    <head>“AU DE ROUGE."</head>
                    <p>GENERAL DRAPERY ETABLISHMENT.</p>
                    <p>(Central Tramway Station), CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>P. PLUNKETT, PROPRIETOR.</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTER OF BRITISH AND IRISH TEXTILE MANUFACTURES.</p>
                    <p>LADIES’ SUMMER STOCKINGS.</p>
                    <p> IN SPUN SILK at P.T. 20 per pair.</p>
                    <p>LISLE THREAD, in plain and lace open-work, in black, white, tan and usual
                        shades, to suit boots worn in Egypt, from P.T. 5 per pair.</p>
                    <p>Every pair is marked “Au De Rouge" which is a guarantee that the Color is
                        absolutely fast and stainless.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">24916-15-11-905</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-nfc01">
                    <head>The Nile Flotilla Co., Ld.</head>
                    <p>REGULAR AND FREQUENT TRANSPORT SERVICE ON RIVER AND CANAL</p>
                    <p>CUSTOMS-CLEARING &amp; FORWARDIG.</p>
                    <p>Offices - London, Cairo &amp; Alexandria</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">27154 17-1-907</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-tnh01">
                    <head>THE NATIONAL HOTEL, Cairo</head>
                    <p>One of the finest and most up-to-date Hotels in the Metropolis. Situated in
                        Sharia Soliman Pasha, the very centre of the healthiest and most fashionable
                        quarter. Stands in its own grounds with garden and lawn tennis grounds at
                        back. Over 350 rooms and 5 saloons. Magnificent salle à manger. Handsome
                        covered promenade verandah, 80 yards long. Highest class cuisine, electric
                        light throughout, and lifts. English comforts. Rooms and apartments at
                        prices to suit everyone. For further particulars apply to GENERAL MANAGER,
                        Cairo. </p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">26839—30-11-906</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ghk01">
                    <head>GRAND HOTEL KHARTOUM, SUDAN</head>
                    <p>SUDAN.</p>
                    <p>First Class. Open all the year round.</p>
                    <p>THOROUGHLY RENOVATED AND IMPROVED.</p>
                    <p>Standing in a magnificent position in its own extensive grounds on the banks
                        of the Blue Nile. Perfect climate, no mosquitoes, moder comfort, very
                        homely. Concerts twice a week on the verandah of the Hotel.</p>
                    <p>ENTIRELY NEW MANAGEMENT.</p>
                    <p>For accommodation please write or wire beforehand to Manager</p>
                    <p>G. OTTO BOCK, Manager.</p>
                    <p>Lake Holland House, New York.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">26836—31-3-906</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sph01">
                    <head>SAVOY PALACE HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>The Fashionable Hotel of Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>RESTAURANT AND ANGLO-AMERICAN BAR.</p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">29705-4-3-908</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="lip01">
                    <head>LIPTON , Limited.</head>
                    <p>NAVAL &amp; MILITARY CONTRACTORS.</p>
                    <p>Office and Stores : 31 Boulevard de Ramleh.</p>
                    <p>P. O. BOX 665 ; TELEPHONE, 1686.</p>
                    <p>TEA, PROVISION, WINE &amp; SPIRIT MERCHANTS.</p>
                    <p>TEA MERCHANTS TO THE KING OF ENGLAND.</p>
                    <p>BRANCHES THROUGHOUT THE WORLD.</p>
                    <p>Tea, Wine and Spirit Agents for all Egypt, P. BLESS &amp; Co, Rue Nubar
                        Pacha, Alexandria, and Ben-el-Suraein, Cairo — Head Office, City Road,
                        London <measure type="indexNo">28042 31-8-907</measure>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ccc01">
                    <head>The Cigarettes Manufactured by<lb/>The Cleopatra Cigarette Co.</head>
                    <p>G. NUNGOYICH</p>
                    <p>are on sale at the Company's establishment by Grand Contental Hotel, Cairo,
                        and at Walker &amp; Meimarschi's, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>Purveyors to H. H. the KHEDIVE.</p>
                    <p> Patronized by the Duke of Connaught and the Archduke Otto and all the High
                        Life of Egypt.<measure type="indexNo">35750 18-4-80</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-ddg01">
                    <head>Direction der Disconto-Gesellschaft</head>
                    <p>Berlin - Bremen - Frankfurt a. M. - London.</p>
                    <p>Capital (fully paid-up) M 170 000 000</p>
                    <p>Reserve Fund ... M 57 600 000</p>
                    <p>Represented at Hamburg by the Norddeutsche Bank in Hamburg.</p>
                    <p>The bank transacts general banking business of every description and acts as
                        representative of the following foreign banks: </p>
                    <p>Brasilianische Bank für Deutschland of Hamburg, with branches at Rio de
                        Janeiro, Sao Paulo, Santos and Porto Alegre. </p>
                    <p>Bank für Chile und Deutschland of Hamburg, with branches at Valparaiso,
                        Santiago, Concepcion, Temuco, Antofagasta, La Paz and Oruro. </p>
                    <p>Ernesto Tornquist &amp; Co. Buenos Aires. </p>
                    <p>Deutsch- Asiatische Bank of Shanghai, with branohes at Berlin, Calcutta,
                        Hankow, Hongkong, Kobe, Peking, Tientsin, Tsinanfu, Tsingtau, Yokohama. </p>
                    <p>Banca Generala Romana of Bakarest, with branches at Braila, Crajeva and an
                        Agency at Constantza. </p>
                    <p>Kreditna Banka (Banque de Credit) at Sofia </p>
                    <p>Damara- und Namaqua Handels-Gesellschaft, Banking Department, at Swakopmund,
                        Windhuk and Lüderitzbucht (South West Africa). </p>
                    <p><measure type="indexNo">72220-18-1907</measure></p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hct01">
                    <head>HIGH-CLASS TOOLS</head>
                    <p>For Miners, Contractors, and Agriculturists.</p>
                    <p>The “UNIVERSAL” PICKS.</p>
                    <p>Picks, Spades, Shovels, Forks, Axes, Hoes, Fasses, Hammers, Wedges, Crowbars,
                        etc. </p>
                    <p> HAND and POWER BORING MACHINES for Rock and Coal.</p>
                    <p>"HARDY" DRILL STEEL.</p>
                    <p>Hickory Handles.</p>
                    <p>THE HARDY PATENT PICK CO., LTD., SHEFFIELD, ENGLAND.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">


                    <p>TTvDaI Weisaenstein Castle (3401 Jf X Ule feet). Fireglass. Private Hotel/
                        near Windisch-Matrei station, T-i«nr ( Easily reached from Trieate or
                        Venice. ) Bracing air. Good mountaineering centre. Tennis. Fishing. Photos
                        and Prospectuses at “Egyptian Gazette” office, Cairo. 2921s—*o*-a-»o7</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>minary study, and consequently the interests of the varion* corporations will
                        , not be sufficiently taken intoXxrasideration. This is, however, quite
                        erroneous. The Egyptian Government has always made a point of consulting the
                        import and export trades of Alexandria before taking any measure that might
                        jeopardise thfiir interests. We have no doubt bat that the Government will
                        do so in the present case. As to the position of the Alexandria Municipality
                        in this matter,, we need merely state that the only step that has up to now
                        been taken has been the communication to that body of the project of the new
                        branch of the Canal. This scheme was submitted to the Municipality a few
                        months ago in order to be studied by the members of the Municipal
                        Commission. It was carefully drawn up by the able engineering authority* of
                        the Ports and Lighthouses-Administration, M. Malavel, who' may be called the
                        originator of the idea of the now branch. - The project has not yet been
                        brought officially to the cognizance of the members of the Municipal
                        Commission. One of the first conditions that the Municipality was prepared
                        to insist upon was that in no way should the free flow of the existing canal
                        be impeded lest in any case the purity of the present intake of the
                        Alexandria Water Company should vbe endangered by havtfig a stagnant body of
                        water existing below the site of the intake. Since then the question- has
                        remained in statu quo. The Government! has now1 to give a decision on the
                        matter, and will then doubtless consult the Municipality in order to take
                        its opinion as to the advisability of proceeding with the projeot. An
                        regards the Irrigation Department, trie scheme for a new maritime canal has
                        been brought'to the notice of the Inspector General of Irrigation for Lower
                        Egypt, • but as yet no definite steps have been taken. A new branch does not
                        offer any objection from the point of view of irrigation, as it does not
                        entail the Irrigation Department’s giving any more water, which is the main
                        consideration with that department.</p>
                    <p>The actual scheme is the construction of a new salt-water canal running at
                        ses level from Gabbari to Nouxha, where it would step up to the canal level
                        by means of locks. It is obvious that such a scheme has many advantages. It
                        prevents the silting up al the harbour, will improve the railway
                        comniunications, relieve the congestion on the Mahiuoudieh Canal, and
                        improve the sanitary condition of the port During the last four years the
                        number of boats passing through the Menoufieh head lock at ' the barrage has
                        more than quadrupled and the number of boats passing through the tail lock
                        of the Mahmou- dieh Canal shows a similar increase. In 1905 the number of
                        boats passing Kafr Da war up and down stream was 30,438, and annually 20,500
                        boats ply on the Nquxha*Mii«et-el- Bassal reach. The congestion grows worse
                        every day, and the construction of the new branch is imperative, for it is
                        the only solution out of the difficulty. Alexandria is growing rapidly, and
                        will inevitably become not only the great outlet tor Egypt's railway
                        traffic, but tor the greater part of Africa. The Cape-to Cairo Railway
                        scheme may yet be far from being a “fait accompli,” but there is sure to be
                        a complete system of communications between North and South Africa by rail,
                        river, and lake in a few years’ time, and the outlet for this traffic will
                        be at Alexandria. The growth of the town westward 'will In a few years’ time
                        lead to one uninterrupted mass of buildings stretchingJrora Gabbari to Mex
                        and occupying every available site between sea and lake. Unless, therefore,
                        a decision is arrived at soon the scheme will not be feasible without
                        enormous extra cost for expropriations. At the present time the land- owners
                        interested in the promotion of the project are prepared to cede to the
                        Egyptian Government free of any charge, the land necessary for making the
                        new branch and they are ready to construct the canal under the supervision
                        of the Government. They •further offer to give facilities for connecting tie
                        goods station at Gabbari through the Gabbari quarter with the new ways to
                        the west Under such favourable conditions .the new maritime canal could
                        easily be constructed, and it is to be hoped that the Government will not
                        lose the opportunity, for soon, owing to the rise in the value of the land
                        consequence on the development of the ffity westward, the canal will never
                        have a chance to be made without very great expense.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
