<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An Encoded Transcription</title>
                <editor>Celine Benedico</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-09-09">September 9, 2019</date><date>January 30th, 2020</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-13"><name>Thursday</name>, July 13,
                        1905</date><date>January 14, 1907</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01">
                                <p>The Eastern Telegraph Company, Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01">
                                <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <div type="item">
                    <!-- page 2 contents -->
                    <head>Royal Insurance Co.</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE: Largest Fire Once in the World.</p>
                    <p>HASELDEN &amp; co., Agents, Alexandria. 31-8-907</p>
                    <p>R. VITERBO &amp; Co., Agents, Cairo. </p>
                    <p>PHOENIX ASSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED. (ESTABLISHED 1782); HASELDEN &amp; Co.,
                        Agents, Alexandria, </p>
                    <p>PRED. OTT &amp; Co., Sub-Agents. Cairo</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IND, COOPE &amp; Co., Ltd.</head>
                    <p>BREWERS, BURTON-ON-TRENT AND ROMFORD, PALE ALE &amp; DOUBLE STOUT,</p>
                    <p>SPECIALLY BREWED FOR EXPORT. </p>
                    <p>Agents : MESSRS. JOHN ROSS &amp; Co.,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA &amp; CAIRO:</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> Cairo Photographic Stores</head>
                    <p>O. DIRADOUR</p>
                    <p>PLACE DE L'OPERA SPECIAL DEPOT FOR KODAKS AND FILMS Plates, printing paper
                        and supplies of the best English, French and German brands</p>
                    <p>AMATEUR WORK, CAMERA REPAIRS, ETC.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Calverts Carbolic Toilet Soap</head>
                    <p>Ensures a Clear, Soft Skin. </p>
                    <p>It is pure throughout, fragrantly perfumed, emollient, and antiseptic, (10%
                        crystal carbolic). It quickly removes dust and dirt, takes away the
                        unpleasant effects of perspiration, and leaves instead a delicious feeling
                        of thorough purification. </p>
                    <p>Sold by local Chemists and Storekeepers. Made by P.C.Calvert a Co.,
                        Manchester, Eng.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>“AU DE ROUGE”</head>
                    <p>CENTRAL DRAPERY ESTABLISHMENT. (CENTRAL TRAMWAY STATION)</p>
                    <p>CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>P. PLUNKETT,</p>
                    <p>(PROPRIETOR. )</p>
                    <p>DIRECT IMPORTERS OF BRITISH AND IRISH TEXTILE MANUFACTURES. </p>
                    <p>CAIRO AND ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>The ready made Ladies costumes and skirts for which costumes have been
                        waiting are now on sale. </p>
                    <p>EXCELLENT VALUE AS USUAL.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Macmillan's Guides.</head>
                    <p>EGYPT AND THE SOUDAN. </p>
                    <p>Including a Description of the Route through Uganda to Mombasa. With 35 Maps
                        &amp; Plans, 5s, net.</p>
                    <p>PALESTINE AND SYRIA. </p>
                    <p>With 18 Maps and Plans, 5s. net.</p>
                    <p>PALESTINE AND EGYPT. MINING PUMPS.</p>
                    <p>wah Maps and Plans.</p>
                    <p>To be bought of all Booksellers. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Tyrol. </head>
                    <p>Weissenstein Castle (3401 feet)</p>
                    <p>First-class. Private Hotel, near Windisch-Matrei station, Lienz, (Easily
                        reached from Trieste or Venice. ) Bracing air. Good mountaineering
                        centre.</p>
                    <p>Tennis. Fishing. Photos and Prospectuses at The Nile Flotilla Co., Ld.
                        "Egyptian Gazette" office, Cairo. 29218 —80 4-4-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Nile Flotilla Co., Ld.</head>
                    <p>REGULAR AND FREQUENT TRANSPORT, SERVICE ON RIVER AND CANAL </p>
                    <p>CUSTOMS-CLEARING &amp; FORWARDING</p>
                    <p>LONDON, CAIRO &amp; ALEXANDRIA</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTICE</head>
                    <p>Persons importing Egyptian Labourers to work in the Sudan are recommended to
                        enter into a written contract with them. This contract should be explained
                        and signed by the Labour era in presence of an official or other reliable
                        witness.</p>
                    <p>2-283A 30-10-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Residents</head>
                    <p>Returning from Europe and who have not hitherto used</p>
                    <p>HOWIE'S BUTTER</p>
                    <p> should not fail to give it a trial, before making their winter arrangements.
                        Address Shubra Road, Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>British Commercial Travellers</head>
                    <p> Visiting Cairo should arrange with “THE COMMERCIAL BUREAU.", Sharia
                        Madabegh, for introductions to Firms </p>
                    <p>37 62-31-1-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NATIONAL HOTEL, Cairo</head>
                    <p>One of the finest and most up-to-date Hotels in the Metropolis, Situated in
                        Sharia Soliman Pasha, the very centre of the healthiest and most fashionable
                        quarter, Stands in its own grounds with garden and lawn tennis grounds at
                        baok, Over 360 rooms and 5 saloons, Magnificent salle à manger. Handsome
                        covered promenade verandah, 80 yards long. Highest class cuisine, electric
                        light throughout, and lifts. English comforts. Booms and apartments at
                        prices to suit every one. For further particulars apply to GENERAL
                        MANAGER,Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The George Nungovich Hotels.</head>
                    <p>GRAND HOTEL, HELOUAN. - Finest and most luxurious Hotel near Cairo.
                        Patronised by Royalty. Moderate charges</p>
                    <p>Special terms for residents. HOTEL DES BAINS-Most comfortable hotel, opposite
                        the Baths. Pension from P.T. 4). Attached to the above hotels</p>
                    <p>and specially reserved for their clients are the Golt Links (18 holes) with
                        English Professional. Own Golf House in the desert SULPHUR BATH
                        ESTABLISHMENT.-Sulphur water stronger than any in Europe. Eight European
                        masters and massguses. Every modern improvement.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW VICTORIA HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>SAN STEFANO, Noar ALEXANDRIA.</p>
                    <p>Halt No. 2.</p>
                    <p>OPEN ALL THE YEAR ROUND. </p>
                    <p>Specially built in 1904 for a first class Hotel with every modern comfort.
                        Magnificent Dining room, Saloons, Smoking room, large Verandabs and Garden
                        Electric light. MODERATE CHARGES. Express Motor Cars meet trains from Cairo
                        at. Sidi Gaber and Alexandria Stations. The Management have also arranged
                        for the Motor Cars to meet all steamers. Special terms for Government
                        Officials and Officers of the Army of Occupation.</p>
                    <p>C. F. RAISIG, MANAGER. RESTAURANT AND BAR OPEN TO NON-RESIDENTS.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GHEZIREH PALACE HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>On the bank of the Nile. Formerty the Prison of the Khedive Ismail.
                        Transformed into a luxurious hotel.</p>
                    <p>Splendid Park. </p>
                    <p>Renowned for its afternoon-teas on the West Balcony overlooking the Park.
                        Excellent Tsigane Orchestra. Motor-car running to Sherheard's Hotel and vice
                        versa.</p>
                    <p>29030-31-9-7</p>
                    <p>CAIRO - SAVOY HOTEL Is Now Open</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Grand Hotel, Khartoum.</head>
                    <p>The only First Class Hotel at Khartoum, prettily situated in its extensive
                        Palm Gardens on the Banks of the Blue Nile, with commanding views from the
                        terrace of the Hotel over the Blue and White Nile, Omdurman, and the
                        Battlefields of Kerreri.</p>
                    <p>Entirely re-built, enlarged and refurnished in 1906 ; replete with all modern
                        Eur spean comforts.</p>
                    <p>Electric Light, Steam Laundry, Lawn Tennis, Stabling, Boating, own farm and
                        Dairy products Cosmopolitan Cuisine, European service.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">Terms --From P.T. 100 to 125 per person and per day.,
                            Special terms for a prolonged stay. R781-31-8-06</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>G. OTTO BOOK Manager</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GORDON HOTEL, KMARTOUM,</head>
                    <p>Open in November Most comfortable and best appointed Hotel in town. Central
                        situation, affording splendid view, No mosquitoes. Verandah, music and
                        varied amusements, Electric Light. Carriages at landing stage at tourists
                        disposal. Cellar renowned, BEST CUISINE. - OPEN ALL THE YEAR ROUND.</p>
                    <p>29113–31 3-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY PALACE HOTEL. THE HOTEL DE LUXE OF ALEXANDRIA. WILL BE OPEN
                        SHORTLY</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LIPTON, LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>NAVAL &amp; MILITARY CONTRACTORS. </p>
                    <p>Office &amp; Stores : 31 Boulevard de Ramleh, Alexandria,</p>
                    <p>P. O, BOX B6B; TELEPHONE, 1882 </p>
                    <p>TEA, PROVISION, WINE &amp; SPIRIT MERCHANTS</p>
                    <p>TEA MERCHANTS TO THE KING OF ENGLAND. </p>
                    <p>BRANCHES THROUGHOUT THE WORLD. </p>
                    <p>Tea, Wine and Spirit Agents for all Egypt, P. BLESS &amp; Co, Rue Nubar
                        Pacha, Alexandria, an</p>
                    <p>Ben-el-Suraein, Cairo – Head Office, City Road, London 38042-30-11-908</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Direction der Disconto-Gesellschaft</head>
                    <p>Berlin - Bremen - Frankfurt a. M. - London.</p>
                    <p>Capital (fully paid-up) M 170 000 000 Reserve Fund , , ; M 57 600 000</p>
                    <p>Represented at Hamburg by the Norddeutsche Bank in Hamburg.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">The bank transacts general banking business of every
                            description and acts as</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>representative of the following foreign banks : Brasilianische Bank für
                        Deutschland of Hamburg, with branches at Rio de</p>
                    <p>Janeir), 840 Paulo, Santos and Porto Alegre. Bank für Chile und Deutschland
                        of Hamborg, with branches at Valparaiso,</p>
                    <p>Santiago, Concepcion, Temuco, Antofagasta, La Paz and Oruro. Ernesto Torp
                        quist &amp; Co. Buenos Aires. Deutsch-Asiatische Bank of Shanghai, with
                        branches at Berlin, Calcutta, Han</p>
                    <p>kow, Hongkong, Kobe, Peking, Tientsin, Tsinantu, Tsingtao, Yokohama. Banca
                        Generala Romana of Bukarest, with branches at Braila, Crajova and</p>
                    <p>Agencies at Copstaptza, Ploesti, Giurgiu. Kreditna Banka (Banque de Credit)
                        at Sofia, with a branch at Varna. Deutsche Afrika-Bank, Hamburg, with
                        branches at Swakopmund, Windbak and</p>
                    <p>Lüderitzbucht (South West Africa).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HIGH-CLASS TOOLS</head>
                    <p> For Miners, Contractors, and Agriculturists.</p>
                    <p>The " UNIVERSAL" PICKS.</p>
                    <p>HAND and POWER BORING MACHINES for Rock and Coal.</p>
                    <p>Picks, Spades, Shovels, Forks, Axes, Hoes, Fasses, Hammers, Wedges, Crowbars,
                        etc.</p>
                    <p>" HARDY” DRILL STEEL.</p>
                    <p>Hickory Handles.</p>
                    <p>SPECIAL TOUCH MINERS DRILL STEEL.</p>
                    <p>THE HARDY PATENT PICK CO., LTD., SHEFFIELD ENGLAND</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PHTISIQUES. ESPÉREZ!</head>
                    <p>Le désespoir est dangereux ; aussi, réagissez et, pour vous y aider avec
                        proht, employez</p>
                    <p>l'Emulsion Scott qui, certainement, réussira a arrêter d'abord et puis à
                        vaincre votre cruelle et redoutable ennemie.</p>
                    <p>Sachez, en effet, que</p>
                    <p>l'Emulsion Scott </p>
                    <p>nourrit le sang, refait les muscles plus promptement et plus sûrement
                        qu'aucun autre aliment ou médicament ; elle régénère l'organisme affaibli
                        et, de la sorte, lui permet de repousser victorieusement</p>
                    <p>la PHTISIE. </p>
                    <p>Alors, vous êter guéris !</p>
                    <p>Crisert injur: Emulsion avec cette man : "le Preheur", marque du procédé
                        Scott!</p>
                    <p>EN VENTE CHEZ TOUS PHARMACIENS ET DROGUISTES.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Daily Weather Report</head>
                    <p>Alexandria/Kom-el-Nadours Observatory</p>
                    <p>Directions of Wind: N/A</p>
                    <p>Force of Anemometer: 10</p>
                    <p>State of Sea: Slight</p>
                    <p>Barometer corrected: 765.6</p>
                    <p>Evaporation: 3</p>
                    <p>State of Clouds: clouded</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian Gazette</head>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including delivery in
                        Alexandria</p>
                    <p>or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231; per annum, P.T. 116 for six
                        months,</p>
                    <p>P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries in the Postal Union P.T. 273
                        (£2.168.), per annum. Six months P.T. 136} (£1.8s.), three months P.T. 95
                        (0.19s.),</p>
                    <p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages or Deaths, not
                        exceeding three lines, P.T. 20. Every additional line P.T. 10. Notices in
                        news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for standing
                        advertisements.</p>
                    <p> ADVERTISEMENTS AND SUBSCRIPTIONS</p>
                    <p>Are due in advanice. P.O. Orders and Cheques to be made payable to the Editor
                        and Manager, ROWLAND SNELLING, Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>London Correspondert's Offices-36, New Broad Street, B.O.</p>
                    <p> Cairo Offices.--No. 1 Sharia Zervadachi. (opposite the Agricultural
                        Bank)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Financial Stringency in Egypt</head>
                    <p>The scarcity of gold which again made itself felt last month was not nearly
                        so acute as that experienced a few weeks previously, but, on the other hand,
                        was much more unexpected. An insufficency of gold for currency requirements
                        is no new phenomenon in this country and will, undoubtedly, continue to
                        occur from time to time owing to the fact that any sudden and unexpected
                        demand for gold can only be met by fresh inmports from Europe. The position
                        in October was declared by people who know the country well as being the
                        worst for many years, and the general opinion was that, after the heavy
                        importations of gold, a similar situation could not possibly occur again
                        this season. Events have proved the inaccuracy of these opinions, for during
                        December there was a renewed gold famine, much less acute than its predessor
                        it is true, but which at the same time made itself somewhat severely felt,
                        as the exchange quotations show. On Saturday the 1st December banks' buying
                        price of cheque on London was quoted at 97 to 97 whilst on the following
                        Monday it went down to 97 and later in the week to 96 the average of the
                        month being a shade under 97. Although other instances might be quoted, we
                        will content to ourselves by mentioning merely the case of a certain native
                        who, at the present moment, is reputed to have I.E. 20,000 (20,512) in
                        National Bank of Egypt notes hidden in his house in one of the villages. The
                        owner will not lend this money-more especially as it is against the
                        Mohamedan religion to receive interest-neither will he employ it in any way
                        until a favourable oppurtunity for the purchase of land occurs. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Military Tailors</head>
                    <p>Egyptian Army Outfits a Specialty.</p>
                    <p>Riding Breeches</p>
                    <p>F. Phillips and Co.</p>
                    <p>Ladies' Tailors</p>
                    <p>(High Class Work Only)</p>
                    <p>Cairo and Alexandria</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <cols n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Local and General</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> Penny Postage</p>
                    <p> The postage on letters for British North Borneo has been reduced and fixed
                        at 5 milliemes for every 15 grammes or fraction thereof.</p>
                    <p>A Love Tragedy</p>
                    <p>The Beni-Sogef Criminal Court has sentenced Awad Mohamed Mahdi to one year's
                        imprisonment for the murder of Assaad Eft. Saleh who had had clandestine
                        relations with Awad' fiancée.</p>
                    <p> The Plague</p>
                    <p>No fresh cases of plague are reported in to-day Yesterday's bulletin recorded
                        the admission into hospital of the daughter of a Greek baker who has a shop
                        in Haret Okelle Limoun. The case is bubonio. </p>
                    <p>Navigation on the Nile.</p>
                    <p>In connection with the Baneb Barrage works, a sadd is being constructed near
                        the western bank, about one kilometre north of the town of Esneb. Boats of
                        all kinds navigating the river should pass to the east of the red lights
                        fixed on the western side. </p>
                    <p>Railway Robbery.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday evening, while train No. 670, on the Delta Light Railway, was
                        between the stations of Borwah and Meballot Marhoom, a travelling cash case,
                        containing upwards of £200, was stolen from the van. The omdebs of the two
                        villages were advised and a search party of railway officials immediately
                        set out from Tantah.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL OPERA HOUSE.</head>
                    <p>( FROM OUR THEATRICAL CORRESPONDENT: )</p>
                    <p>"La Fille du Regiment” is as distinot a change as possible after two tew
                        Mazgènets, Meyerbeer, and the other productions we have had so far. It is
                        rather a delightful change, too; charming light must be known, and plenty of
                        dialogue and acting. Mlle Charpentier and M. Darand (the sergeant) were
                        quite good, always correct and with plenty of life as far as singing went;
                        and they acted extremely well, better than they sang, I confess: Mlle Char,
                        pentier looked enchantingly pretty, more so in her fashionable dress if
                        possible that as the Vivandière ; and the sergeant was finely made up. M.
                        Monteox had the part of Topio, and for once be sang in tone, but his voice
                        is most distasteful, hopelessly affected, and entirely falsetto in the high
                        notes.</p>
                    <p>The chorus were much as usual, but why do they look so deplorably stolid !
                        And do all French soldiers of the period wear those quaint American-striped
                        trousers ? I rather wished they would black their faces and try a "coon"
                        song. An elaborate ballet Wowed the opera, I confess I only ondored of it. I
                        don't profess to understand ballet. It seemed except for Mlle Deliny, to
                        consist in a species of swimming lessons--at least as far as the arms were
                        concerned. Doubtless every gesture has its cabalistio meaning for the
                        initiated. The music, by one Délibes, was rather pretty, with plenty of
                        violine, floter, and French bora (which made one think of togs from
                        Wagnerand that was nice).</p>
                    <p>With regard to fortbooming performances, "L'Afriesine" and "Messaline" are
                        being "studied”. I asked about places. That is always a ground of complaint
                        for those who do not buy seats for the season, and who really want to hear
                        opera, and not their neighbours' opinions on Bourse questions. Seats on
                        Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday are practically unobtainable, but on
                        Fridays there are plenty as the abonnement is only partial. When will the
                        worthy managers understand that the whole reality of the opera and theatre
                        is annihilated by that absurd "abonnement" system! It has no single saving
                        merit: even the regularity of the receipts is fatal to the acting and
                        singing, as no real effort or risk is involved : an empty house represents
                        as much money-and far less noise-than a full house. That is perhaps a merit
                        to a few keen listeners.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ZIZINIA THEATRE.</head>
                    <p>The opera season at the above theatre, thus far, has proved one of the best
                        for several years. Each production has been well staged, and the artistes
                        concerned are, for the most part, evenly balanced, --a very great assistance
                        to the general success of any theatrical representation, whether dramatic or
                        operatie. Saturday's performance of "Mefistofele" was certainly the most
                        perfect of this opera. Signor Carlo Walter was in fine form, and his
                        splendid voice was heard to great advantage. Sigoor Walter's histrioni
                        ability is well known, but his Mephisto undoubtedly one of his best, and at
                        the same time one of the most difficult roles. His impersonation is worthy
                        of more than a passing comment, showing, as it does, most careful study,
                        &amp; commendable attention to the minutest detaile, a perfect picture of
                        devilry and music, -a strange combination, perhaps, but one necessary in the
                        present instances; in fine, an artistio performance worthy of Signor
                        Walter.</p>
                    <p>Signor Agerbi as Paust appeared tired, and sang occasionally rather out of
                        tune. His performance, however, was an excellent one Signora De Lerms was in
                        perfect voice and sang admirably throughout the opera. We preferred her
                        appearance in the second part as a brunette; why do the powers that be
                        insist on a blonde Marguerite?</p>
                    <p>The other characters were well supported, and the orchestra worked
                        splendidly. By the way, can nothing be done to prevent the discordant
                        tootling and scraping indalgel in by the orchestra before each act ? Such
                        noises cannot be intended for tuning, and they most jar on the sensitive
                        ears of many patrons of the theatre.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>M.P's. PEREGRINATIONS.</head>
                    <p>MR. ROBERTSON VISITS DENISHWAI.</p>
                    <p>Mr. J. M. Robertson, M.P., has been touring in the Gharbieh province. On
                        Saturday night the M.P. was entertained by the Omdeb of Borwah. Our Shebin
                        el Kom Correspondent, telegraphing this morning, says :- Rumours are current
                        here that Mr. Robertson, M.P., paid a visit to the village of Denishwai
                        yesterday. He has also visited this town.</p>
                    <p>The journeys of Mr. Robertson are being followed with great interest by the
                        Nationalist Press, and with such detail that one might imagine that this
                        gentleman was being escorted throughout Egypt by a phalanx of Nationalist
                        journalists.</p>
                    <p>"Al Ahram" remarks: We are glad to see that Mr. Robertson is engaged in
                        inspecting many native localities and departments and taking down in his
                        note-book all that he can gather of the circumstances of the natives. This
                        may be useful to this country later on. We have been informed that this
                        member of Parliament refused to see some AngloEgyptian Government officials
                        and refrained from seeing some other persons, whose object was only to serve
                        the interests of the Occupation.</p>
                    <p>"Al Watan," the Coptic organ, remarks :The Islamic newepaper world has
                        welcomed Mr. J. MR bertson, M.P., with such enthusiasm that some of our
                        contemporaries seemed on the point of hailing him as the deliverer of Egypt
                        and the defender of Islam. Yet this gentleman's views are utterly divergent
                        from the native way of thinking. Mr. Robertson's friends in Egypt are
                        persons in favour of religious instructior, while he is well known to be
                        antagonistic to all creeds. He was a friend of Bradlaugh, the notorious
                        Atheist, and he assisted him in editing a journal whose object was the
                        promotion of Free Thought. He is one of the members of the committee of the
                        Rationalist Press Association together with Hoxley, Tyndall, and Haeckel,
                        who are among those European savants who deny revealed religion. He is the
                        author of many works dealing with liberty of thought, i.e., the denial of
                        taith and the fictions of religious peoples' belief. Yet the leaders of
                        Islam in Egypt have nevertheless chosen Mr. Robertson, of all people in the
                        world, as their sincere friend, for they consider him as the man with the
                        truest ideas! Is not this a carious anomaly? </p>
                    <p>"Al Lewa," of yesterday's date, gives the following account of Mr.
                        Robertson's progress in the provinces :-</p>
                    <p>News comes from the Bebera that Mr. J. "M. Robertson one of the commissions
                        composed of Liberal members of the British Parliament who are studying the
                        condition of Egypt, arrived at Itay-el-Baroud on Friday, where he was
                        welcomed by a number of omdehs and notables of the Mondirieh who happened to
                        be gathered at the station. The Markaz Mamoar introduced the best known
                        among them to Mr. Robertson, who shook hands with the natives and expressed
                        pleasure at meeting them. His object in coming, he said was to travel
                        through the provinces and study the manner of living of the fellaheen. Mr.
                        Robertson, who was accompanied by Abd ElHamid Ammar, proceeded to Nahiel
                        Biban, where he was received as a guest by the Ammar family. The natives
                        evince their I pleasure at seeing Mr. Robertson, knowing the object he has
                        in view.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                    <p>A special Cairo District Order states that "His Highness the Khedive bas been
                        mort graciously pleased to express to His Excellency the Sirdar his entire
                        satisfaction with the smart appearance of the troops and the manner in which
                        the various movements were carried out on the occasion of the review held in
                        honour of the anniversary of his accession."</p>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive has been most graciously pleased to conquer for the
                        following decorations upon the under-mentioned officers : 3rd Class O mani :
                        El Miralai E. E. Bon 1</p>
                    <p>Bey, D.S.O., Sudan Government. 3rd Class Mejidi: El Miralai H. D. Palmer,
                        Bey, Financial Secretary.</p>
                    <p>4th Class Osmania : El Bimbashi Khelil Effendi Fabmi, Department of Supplies;
                        El Sagbkolagbasi Abm ed Eff di Petin, 7th Battalion.</p>
                    <p>4th Class Mejidi : El Bimbashi A.A.C. Taylor, Sndan Government. · The Khedive
                        has been most graciosuely pleased to approve of the following promotions. To
                        date 1-1 07:</p>
                    <p>El Lewa Ibrahim Pasha Pathi, D.S.0., en pansior, to be Honorary Perik ; Local
                        Miralai E.B. Bond Bey, D.3.0., Sudan Government, to be Miralai ; El Bimbashi
                        B. J. P. Vaogban, Assistant Private Secretary and Deputy Assistant Aitjnta't
                        General, to be Kaimakam ; EI Yuz'a bi Emin Eff ndi Heiman, Aide de Camp to
                        His Ex ellenoy th: Sirdar, to be temporary Sagbkolagbasi.</p>
                    <p>The following officers are seconded for special service. To date 1.1 07: El
                        Kaimakam A.C. Parker Bey, BI Bimbashi H.D. Beamish, 12th Sudanese.</p>
                    <p>The following transfers and appointments have been approved, from dates
                        stated :1 E Miralsi E.C. M.twinter Bey, D.8 0. to be Commandant, Atbara D
                        strict, 1107, El Kai makım H H 3 Morant Bay,to ba Commandant, Halfa
                        District, 1107; El Kaimaksm A. C. Parker Boy, Sadan Government, to the Army,
                        1 107; E Bimbasbi J.LJ. Conry D.8.0., Upper Nile District, to 12h Sudanese,
                        1-1.07 : El Bimbasbi R C. Greenwood, 3rd Battalion, to Sudan Government, 1-1
                        07,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUSTAPHA KAMEL.</head>
                    <p>STILL ANOTHER INTERVIEW.</p>
                    <p>A Havas telegram from Paris states that Mastapha Kamel, in an interview with
                        a representative of the "Temps," said that Egypt was ripe for liberty and
                        not resigned to suffering.</p>
                    <p>"Al Lewa's" Paris correspondent telegraphs that the "Temps" published on
                        Saturday Mustapha Pasba Kamel's declarations in regard to British policy and
                        aims in Egypt. Kamel Pasba pointed out that no agreement was possible
                        between the Egyptians and the English so long as the latter adopted the same
                        policy.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TURKEY AND EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The statement contained in Constantinople telegrams to the Vienna Press that
                        the station in Egypt is causing preoccupation on the part of Yildiz Kiosk
                        and the Porte is unfounded. Such reports are spread by interested parties
                        who desire to disturb the relations of Great Britain and Turkey. Equally
                        mischievous is the further statement regarding British attacks on the
                        position of Mukhtar Pasha, the Porte's High Commissioner, whose status, as
                        is already known, the British and Egyptian Governments decline to recognise
                        officially.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA.</head>
                    <p>A persistent report is current in Cairo that Mr. MacGillivray, Governor of
                        the Bank of Abyssinia, will not return to Addis Abeba, but will shortly open
                        an important exchange business in the capital. We have reason to believe
                        that there is some truth in this report.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THỂ NEW CAIRO BOURSE.</head>
                    <p>A report is current to the effect that H. H. the Khedive has offered to lease
                        at a reasonable figure 1,000 metres of the land be has recently purobased
                        from the German community, opposite the Hotel d'Angleterre, Cairo, for the
                        purpose of the new Boarse, the cost of building which he is so willing to
                        defray and to charge a rent for the same.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN ESTATES.</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Estates, Limited, has under its agreement given formal notice to
                        Mr. Salamone Conegliano, the tenant of the Alhambhra Theatre at Alexandria,
                        to quit in six months' time. This step has been decided on owing to
                        important developments in property in that district of the city.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>L'EPARGNE IMMOBILIERE LIMITED</head>
                    <p>The statutory meeting of the above company was held on Saturday at their
                        offices, 24, Sbaris el Maghraby, Cairo, the president, Mr. Joseph Vaast,
                        presiding.</p>
                    <p>After the report had been read and approved, it was unanimously decided to
                        increase the capital of the company to £800,000 by the issue of 175,000 new
                        shares of £4 each, and full power was given to the directors to dispose of
                        this additional capital to the best interests of the company.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Boutigny gave a short resumé of the doings and intentions of the company,
                        and among other things, mentioned that the company bad bought 80,000 metres
                        of land on Ghezireb Island on very exceptional conditions, and this land
                        will be resold with facilities of payment, extending over 30 years. There
                        are 61 lots, and already 10 have been sold : it is expected that the
                        remainder will be disposed of in two months. This arrangement will prove
                        most advantageous for the buyers as well as for the company, who will make a
                        profit of about £160,000. The company have also concluded other transactions
                        from which large profits will be derived.</p>
                    <p>The company are buying land and paying for same in shares of the new issue,
                        and a large portion of this new issue has already been placed in this
                        manner.</p>
                    <p>The shareholders will certainly have every reason to congratulate themselves
                        at the end of the financial year.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LANGUAGE BOOKS</head>
                    <p>Egypt, Arabia, Turkey and Greece</p>
                    <p>Marlborough's SELF-TAUGHT Series</p>
                    <p>Of EUROPEAN &amp; ORIENTAL LANGUAGES</p>
                    <p>Contain Travel-Talk for Rallway, Steamboat, Custome Hotel, Post Office,
                        Conversations, Vocabularies, Elementary Grammar, Tables of Money, Weights
                        &amp; Measures, to with ENGLISH PHONETIC PRONUNCIATION</p>
                    <p>EGYPTIAN (Arabic), ARABIC (Syrian)</p>
                    <p>Self-Taught. TURKISH</p>
                    <p>Wrapper, 1- ea.; GREEK (Modern) Cloth, 2)6 Jach. FRENCH SELF-TAUGHT.
                        L'ANGLAIS SAN MAÎTRE.</p>
                    <p>Wrapper, 3)- the stench; Cloth, Wo eseh Ask for Complete List of "SXLP-TAUGHT
                        SERIES." OF ALL BOOKSELLERS &amp; TOURIST AGENTS. | condon: B. Marlborough
                        &amp; Co., 84, old Batley, E.C.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>50 MILLIONAIRES FOR EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>RECORD PASSENGER LISTS</p>
                    <p>The Cunard liner Caronia and the White Star liner Cardio. which left New York
                        on the 5th inst. for Alexandria, are bringing no less than fifty
                        millionaires to Egypt. They have only first class passengers on board from
                        nearly all the principal cities in the United States. None of the passengers
                        are paying less than £280 each for the trip</p>
                    <p>The Cedrio and Caronis have the largest number of persons on board bound for
                        Egypt that over lett New York at one time. In the office 28 of all the big
                        steamship companies in New York it was asserted that an anosgally largo
                        exodus to Egypt and Southern Italy is expected this winter. In the last few
                        years, Egypt has been making great inroads on the mid winter Italian tourist
                        traffic.</p>
                    <p>Among the prominent New Yorkers on board the Cedrio are: Mr. and Mrs. W. P.
                        Stafford, Mr, and Mrs. J. William Beekman, Dr. and Mrs. R. . Derby, Mr. and
                        Mrs. E. W. Potter, Professor Henry Fairfield Osborn, Mr. H. W. Cannon, Mr.
                        and Mrs. W. D. Guthrie, Mr. and Mrs. T. P. Pisko, Me. C. W. Leavitt, Jr.,
                        Mr. C. D. Paller, Captain H. J. Hoehler, U.S. A., and Mr. Hoebler, Mr. and
                        Mrs. George Gifford, Mr. Frederick Gebhardt, Mrs. Frederick Neilson, Mt. P.
                        N. Doubleday and Mr. Henry Clark.</p>
                    <p>On the Caronia are: Mr. Elwin C. Atkinson, Mr. and Mrs. James H. Aldrich, Dr.
                        Edward P: Brewer, Mr. George K. Baker, Mirg Helen Collamore, Mr. Aaron M.
                        Crane, Mr. W. F. Doty, Amerióan Consul at Tabriz, Persia ; Mr. Henry T.
                        Parrar, Mr. and Mrs. Hagh A. Marray, Mr. and Mrs. W. H. Moffitt, Dr. and
                        Mrs. M. Loeb, Mrs. Pierre Lorillard, Mr. and Mrs. Horace L. Hotohkiss, Mr.
                        Albert G. C. Hsbn, Mr. George A. Ganther, Mr. and Mrs. Alfred T. White, Mr.
                        Charles H. Werner, Mr, and Mrs. Robert A. Van Wyck and Mrs. James B.
                        Hendrick</p>
                    <p>The Caronia left Gibraltar yesterday on her way to Naples and Alexandria. Sbe
                        is due here on the 19th inst. and returns to New York on the 20th inst, via
                        Rome and Naples.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUEZ.</head>
                    <p>STEAMER AGROUND IN CANAL.</p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                    <p>Suez, Sunday The French steamer America, bound to Jeddab with Algerian
                        pilgrims, is aground in the Suez Canal, near the small lake, since early
                        this morning, and is stopping the traffic. The tog Titan has been despatched
                        to her assistance.</p>
                    <p>The 8.8. Tangistan, which was ashore at Saakin, arrived at Saez this morning,
                        and will go into drydock for repairs</p>
                    <p>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>(FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                    <p>Port Said Friday. The Italian praiser Marcatonis Cologne has has arrived here
                        and will await the arrival of H.R. H. the Duke of Udins, who is returning
                        from a tour round the world, and is expected early next week. : Last
                        Tuesday, Mr. Black, a young Boglishman who is making stay at Port Said,
                        commenced a 10 days' walk to Cairo and back. Yes. terday, at noon, he was
                        reported to have passed Ismailia, Mr. Black is a good all round sportsman';
                        he has played for Port Said, and op more than one occasion he has got them
                        out of a difficult at bookey, cricket, and football.</p>
                    <p>Port Said, Sonday, The commander of the Italian cruiser yesterday paid a
                        visit to the Governor, accompanied by the Italian Consol. In the afternoon
                        the Governor returned the visit. The cruiser left this morning for Suez.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IMPORTANT FIND AT LUXOR</head>
                    <p>Mr. Theodore M. Davis has discovered in the Valley of the Kings the tomb of
                        the great Queen Thi, wife of Amenhotep III. It contains ber mommy, coffin,
                        canopie jars, and numerous other beautiful and interesting objects. The
                        inspirations will be welcomed by all Egyptologists.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIYE.</head>
                    <p>H. H. the Khedive, who came down to Alexandria on Friday night, will spend a
                        few days inspecting his estates at Mariout.</p>
                    <p>After Kourban Beyram the Khedive intends to go on a trip to the desert.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EDINBURGH.</head>
                    <p>Post-Graduate Vacation Course in</p>
                    <p>Medicine. In connection with the UNIVERSITY</p>
                    <p>and ROYAL COLLEGES.</p>
                    <p> Courses will be held from the 2nd to the 28th September, 1907. For Syllabus
                        and further particulars apply,</p>
                    <p>Secretary, University New Buildings,</p>
                    <p>EDINBURG, 2911--2-w-1</p>
                    <p>Scotland.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                    <p>K. S. C.</p>
                    <p>JUNIOR CHAMPIONSHIP POLO</p>
                    <p>"JOURNAMENT. The cold windy weather, and the absence of a band no doubt
                        accounted for the small gathering assembled to witness these matches on
                        Saturday.</p>
                    <p>First MATCH E INNISKILLING DRAGOONS 6. K.8.C. Mr. Merriman I. Mr. Spier 1 Mr.
                        Nixon II Capt. Kennedy II. Mr. Holland III. Capt. Hadow III. Mr. Bowen,
                        back. ' Capt. Bartlett back.</p>
                    <p>The match began tamely, play being slow and rather interesting. In the second
                        chokker was brighter, both sides, however, missing easy shots at goal. In
                        the third chokker Capt. Bartlett, who bad been playing a good game
                        throughout, made a fine ron ap the ground, and Mr. Spier, bo!ding the
                        opposing back, soored a good goal. Soore : K.8.C. I goal to love. Mr. Bowen
                        shortly afterwards equalized. Play now became faster, Capt. Bartlett
                        especially being conspicuous. Capt. Hadow also seemed to find his game at
                        last, and scored a clever goal, bringing the score to 2 to 1 in favour of
                        the K.S.C., and in the last minute Capt. Bartlett added a third.</p>
                    <p>Final score: K.S.C., 3 goals. Inniskilling Dragoons, 1 goal.</p>
                    <p>'SECOND MATCH. TIGERS v. COLDSTREAM GUARDS No. I. TEAM. Capt. Sterling I. Mr.
                        Warde Aldom Mr. MacGillivray II. Mr. Beckwith Mr. Jepkinson III. Mr. Gibbs
                        Mr. Reid, back. Mr. Bentinck</p>
                    <p>These two sides had met twice before in practice games, each side winning a
                        match. This naturally added extra interest to the game. From the throw-in
                        Mr. Jenkinson came away, bat missed his shot, and some give-and take in the
                        middle of the ground followed. In the second chokker the play was keener and
                        faster than ever, Mr. Jenkinson doing great work for his side, bat be missed
                        an easy goal. We noticed a good deal of missing on both sides, but the
                        keenness of all the players made up for this. It was not until the fourth
                        and last chukker that Mr. Beckwith scored a goal for the Guards. This pat K.
                        8. C. on their metal, Captain Sterling equalizing. Shortly afterwards Mr.
                        Jenkinson added yet another, which brought the score to 2 to 1 in favour of
                        the K. 8. C. Bat the Guards were not done with, and made a most determined
                        attack on the goal of the K. 8. C., who, after saving their goal several
                        times, were at last besten in their detence. This brought the soore to 2
                        all. Ten seconds later the bell rang, 80 an extra ohakker bad to be played.
                        The Guards, who evidently were still fall of fight, soon settled matters, a
                        good run up the ground resulting in a goal. Final scores : Tigers, 2 goals ;
                        Coldstream Guards, 3 goals.</p>
                    <p>So ended a very keen, hard contested match. The next tie will be played off
                        on Tuesday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FAYOUM RACES.</head>
                    <p>The first winter meeting of the Fayoum Racing Club will be held at Payoum on
                        Friday next. There are five events on the card, aod entries must be made
                        before Thareday to the hops. secretaries, Mr. R. H. Way or Abmed Efendi
                        Fatbi, Fayoum. The Adviser to the Ministry of the Interior and Lady Victoria
                        Macbell are to be present. Any tourists wishing to attend this op-country
                        meeting should notify one of the hon. secretarie', who will arrange for
                        lanoh and arabias to the course at P.T. 30 a bead.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA MIXED COURT.</p>
                    <p>The following have been elected judgeassesors for commercial cases in the
                        Alexandria Mixed Court for the year 1907, with the number of votes obtained
                        by each :</p>
                    <p>Emmanuel Benachi, (36), P. Fenderl, "(30), G. Karam, (30) Micbel Sivadino,
                        (30), Georgia Zervudachi, (30), Eli Cozzioa, (30), A. G. M. Dickson, (29),
                        Paal Hahuloger, (29), H. P. Kingbam, (29), E. Mallison, (29). G. Rolo,
                        |(89), I. Bindernagel, (28) L'Escoffier. (28). Henri Nabman, (28), Dante
                        Rieti, (28), Emmanuel Stro-8, (78), Sidney Carver, (97),</p>
                    <p>A. Pirenay, (27), P. Hess, (27), 0. Rothacker, |(27), Luigi Stagni, (27).
                        Adolphe Struas, (27), H. Sobæller, (26), 8. Well Off, (26).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Papayanni leader Alexandria left for Malta on Saturday and is expected to
                        arrive here to-morrow afternoon with a sengers and mails.</p>
                    <p>. The Messageries Maritimes 8.8. Equateur, from Marseille, passed the Straits
                        of Messina I on Saturday, and is dae here tomorrow.</p>
                    <p>The Cunard S.8. Veria arrived at Liverpool on Saturday morning.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL </head>
                    <p>Facing the Sea on the New Quay of Alexandr</p>
                    <p>FIRST-CLASS HOTEL Lately Built' and Furnished.</p>
                    <p>TERMS P.T. 50 PER DAY. Special terms to Government Officials.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Prince Aziz Pasha Hassan came down to Alexandria yesterday from Cairo.</p>
                    <p>The Khedive has conferred the grade of Mirmiran on Monbeb Bey, Governor of
                        the Haez Canal, and Dr. Mohamed Bey Shukri, both of whom now become Pasb and
                        the Medjidie of the Yad class on De. Almy Pasba.</p>
                    <p>We regret to announce the death, which took place on Friday night in Cairo,
                        of Youssef Bey Sbawki, Counsellor to the Native Court of Appeal.</p>
                    <p>The French Government has conferred the Legion of Honour on Count Alexander
                        de Zogheb, the Portuguese Consul in Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>M. Empain, the Belgian capitalist, who is o largely interested in Egypt, has
                        been made Baron by the King of the Belgians.</p>
                    <p>Boghor Pasha Nabar is arriving from Eprope on the 15tb inst.</p>
                    <p>M. Nico'aos Thectokis, son of the Hellenio Premier, left on Saturday for
                        Cairo, and will have an audience of the Khedive.</p>
                    <p>Lient. Lord A. J. Percy, 3rd Battalion Grenadier Gaarde, has been selected
                        for employment with the Egyptian Army.</p>
                    <p>Sir Nowell and Lady Salmon will spend the next few weeks in Cairo, where Sir
                        William and Lady East have recently arrived.</p>
                    <p>We regret that Dean Butcher's condition is still such as to cause
                        considerable anxiety to his many friends.</p>
                    <p>Col. Hopkinson Bey, Commandant of the Alexandria City Police, left yesterday
                        for Cairo.</p>
                    <p>The following were that passengers by the train deluxe for Upper Egypt on
                        Friday night : Saad Pasha Zaghloul, Minister of Education ; Ahmed Effendi
                        Nagaib, Mr. Haar, Mr. 8 Halperin, Mrs. Hayes Saleen, Miss O'Meara, Miss J.
                        O'Mears, M. and Mme Schwein.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Schafer, of the Shannon, Limited, has arrived in Cairo and is stopping at
                        Shepheard's Hotel.</p>
                    <p>| Mr. and Mrs. Bland-Satton arrived in London last week from Syria.</p>
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice : Major
                        General Ballock, CB, Capt. Danbar, Lieut.-Col. Allfort, Mr. MacMillan and
                        party. Major Fryer, Major and Mrs. Churcb ward, Comtesse Tysokievicz, Graf
                        Børnsdorff, Major and Mrs. Hall, Baroneas Cambo, Miss B. Serhardt, Mr. S.
                        Rhodes, Mr. Sardoa Logan, Demirgien Bey, Dr. Frank, Mr. Bronner, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Chotzper, Mrs. Pell, Mr. and Mrs. L. Marshall, Miss Gorman, Miss
                        Gebhart, Mr. and Mrs. Sobwerin, Capt. Lysop, M. Petsaly. M. J. Grabam, Mr.
                        Munro Long. M. Knapp, M and Mme Menet, Mr. Williamson.</p>
                    <p>List of passengers by the P.8. Tewfik, which left Cairo on Friday: Miss and
                        Miss M. Burton, Dr. and Mrs. Adger Smyth, Mr. and Mrs. Bautier, Mr. and Mrs.
                        C. H. Winn, Mr. and Mrs. Albert Nathan, Mrs. H. M. Bevis, Mies Erskine Shaw,
                        Capt, and Mrs. Devenish, Miss A. Devenish, Mr. and Mrs. Arnold de Muller,
                        Miss M. Cross, Miss C. D., Ryan, Mr. and Mrs. Hoobfald, Mr. E. Lang. Baron
                        and Baroness de Crombragghe, Miss Renée Van de Poll, Dr. T. I. Patterson,
                        Miss R. Patterson, Mr. and Mrs. Maurice Christin, Miss S. R. Smyth, Miss
                        Grace Francis, Mrs. E. Bennett, Miss P. O. Bandett, Mr. I. Leykauf, Mr. Carl
                        Teofal, Mr. Giboney Honck, Mrs L. Houck, Miss R. Hoáck, Ms. R Dowdiag, Mr.
                        8. Dowding</p>
                    <p>List of passengers by the F.S. Hats 800, which lett Cairo on Friday -Miss A.
                        Reyr er, Miss M. Li vasay, Mr. Conadonris, Mc. and Mrs. Forgean, Major and
                        Mrs. Innes Taylor, Miss H. E. Innes 'T'aylor, Mrs. Joseph Dickson, Miss
                        Marion Ramsey. Miss Julia Rmsey, Pripoe de Braucon vào, Mr. H. L. Riseley,
                        Miss Riseley, Miss M. E. Jacques.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>New Khedivial Hotel,</head>
                    <p>CATRO Built in 1904, Between Shepherd's Hotel and the Railway</p>
                    <p>Station, Electric Light. Lift. Sentry arrangements up to date. Open all the
                        year round. Special terms for Government officials and Arthy of
                        Occupation</p>
                    <p>NEW MANAGEMENT. 20942-26-11-9075</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck &amp; Co's Pilsener Beer</head>
                    <p>BREMEN. Obtainable from every Reputable Firm IN CAIRO, ALEXANDRIA AND THX
                        BUDAN</p>
                    <p>Otherwise apply to EJ. FLEURENT, H, MICALLEF, Sole Agent</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                    <p>325 BRANCHES. </p>
                    <p>French, German, Italian, Greek, Arabic, etc. </p>
                    <p>Private Lessons, Residence Lessons, taught by Native Masters</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 12 Rue Rosette (close to Zizinia Theatre) </p>
                    <p>Cairo: 1 Sharia Kamel</p>
                    <p>Trial Lessons Free</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"/>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"/>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
