<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2018-02-14">February 14, 2018</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
                <idno type="URI">https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/1907-04-03/tei</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1907-04-03">Wednesday, April 3, 1907</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="8">8</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/mode/1up">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                    <head type="sub">No. <measure quantity="7726">7,726</measure>] ALEXANDRIA,
                        WEDNESDAY, APRIL 3, 1907. [EIGHT PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n1/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n2/mode/1up">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section" feature="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL. </head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Brindisi Mail.</head>
                        <p>The mail from Brindisi viâ Port Said will be distributed at Alexandria at
                            4.e0 p.m. to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Egyptlan University. </head>
                        <p>The total amount of subscriptions received up to date in aid of the
                            University's scheme now amounts to L.E. 25,774.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Holy Carpet in Quarantine.</head>
                        <p>Owing to the case of plague which occurred recently to one of the Mahmal
                            escort, the Holy Carpet will remain in quarantine for ten more days
                            dating from the 31st ult.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Wakfs Administration </head>
                        <p>The Superior Council of the Wakfs Administration has authorised the
                            expenditure of L.E. 2,000 as a fabric fund for several mosques
                            recognised as monuments of Arab art.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Rudolph Home. </head>
                        <p>The following have kindly sent contributions to the Rudolph Asylum in
                            memory of the late Mr. L.H Birch:—Société de la Bourse de Minet
                            el-Bassal £2, Alexandria General Produce Association £2, R. Yousri &amp;
                            Co. £2.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Irrigation Department </head>
                        <p>Out of the L.E. 9.000 which has been granted for the undertaking of new
                            irrigation works in Upper and Lower Egypt, L.E 5,000 is to be devoted to
                            the construction of a barrage on the Rosetta branch of the Nile at
                            Mahallet el Kebir.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>At Ahbassieh Asylum.</head>
                        <p>"Al Moayad" reports that two patients of the Abbassieh lunatic asylum,
                            who were seized with the hallucination that they were Mahdi and Prophet,
                            fought together, with the result that one man was killed by a heavy blow
                            with a log of wood</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>United Egyptian Lands</head>
                        <p>The Committee of the London Stock Exchange have fixed Thursday April 4th.
                            as a special settling day in United Egyptian Lands, Limited—396,100
                            Ordinary Shares of £1 each 10s. paid within Nos. 1 to 343,757 and
                            443,758 to 498,750. (Amended notice )</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Khartoum Railway Station</head>
                        <p>Much speculation has been indulged in of late in Khartoum, as to the
                            exact site of the future central railway station which will be erected
                            after the new bridge shall have been completed. According to the
                            origiual plans this station was to be to the South-West of the town, but
                            as these plans are subject to various modifications nothing can be
                            certain as to the exact site. One thing seems to be certain and that is
                            that for the new station a very large area will be railed in.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The English Bar In Egypt. </head>
                        <p>A question of some interest to the members of the English Bar practising
                            in Egypt is dealt with in the Bar Council's annual report. The Council
                            ruled during the past year that a member of the English Bar, who is also
                            a member of a legal firm in a Colony in which there is no distinction
                            between barristers and solicitors, ought not to practise as an English
                            barrister while he remains a member of the Colonial firm. Although
                            Colonies are only attended to in this ruling of the Council, it is to be
                            presumed that it would also apply to barristers practising in Egypt and
                            the Dominions of the Sublime Ottoman Porte</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Ulema Board of Alexandria. </head>
                        <p>Sheikh Mohamed Shaker, President of the Ulema Board of Alexandria, has
                            published his report for last year respecting the theological school
                            under his directorship. The report contains full details of the
                            religious studies and the latest arrangements adopted by the Ulema Board
                            for improving the schools in question. The number of the students of
                            those schools was 576 up to the end of last year. 531 of the number
                            offered themselves for the annual examination in which 429 students were
                            successful. Sheikh Shaker refers to the prosperity of the Ulema Board
                            Schools being due to the valuable assistance and encouragement given by
                            the Khedive. He asks the Mohamedans of Egypt not to disdain but to
                            support their religious education which they should consider as the
                            basis of enlightment and prosperity, and which would enable them as a
                            nation to vie with the civilised world</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Hotel Semlramle. Cairo. </head>
                        <p>Among the visitors staying at the Hotel Semiramis, Cairo, are the
                            following the Countess of Seblourne, Lady Gwendoline Cecil, Countess
                            Hahn Basedow, Countess Henckel Donnersmarck, Mr and Mrs Saul, Mr. and
                            Mrs. Blumgart, Mr. and Miss Corliss, Mr. and Mme Jacques Cattaui, Mr.
                            James Porter, Marquis J. de Freige, Mr. and Mrs W. Brodrich, Mr. de
                            Pourtalé, Mr. and Mrs. van Eghen, Mr. A. Burton Buchley, Graf von Moers,
                            General Oberarzt Dr. Keitel, Baron von der Schulenburg, Baron zu
                            Knyphausen, Mr and Mme Faid Sabit Bey, Mr. H.M. Digby, Miss Marg.
                            Reibold, Mr. J C. Black, Mr. W. Macdonald, Prince Putbus, Countess
                            Lottum, Mrs. and Miss Ulman, Mr. and Mrs. Gillett, Hassan Bey Rassem,
                            Baron von Salich, Mrs Emery Cahill, Mr. Cahill, Mrs. Frank Williams,
                            Mrs. and Miss Davis, Mme de Brissac, Mrs. Carew Gibson, Countess de
                            Montjoye, Mr. Vandeleur, Mr and Mrs. J E. Harvey, Mr. and Mrs. and Miss
                            Fraser, Mr. Robino, Mrs. and Miss Foster, Mr C.W. Thompson, Mr. and Mrs.
                            Edward Mears, Mr. Arthur Corbett, Mr. W.B. Hunt, Mr. F A Rothier, Mrs M.
                            Fisher, Mrs. and Miss Lescaille, Mr. and Mrs. Rahr, Mr. and Mrs. Andrew
                            Anderson, Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Hurd, Mr D M. Ramsey, Mr. and Mrs. Hall
                            Caine, Mr J.B Potter, Mr nad Mrs. Dickinson, Komm. Bath Landfried,
                            Fraulein von Heemskerck, Col. and Mrs. Markham, Mrs. P.M. Price,
                            Princess Carl zu Hanau Horowitz.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLAND IN EGYPT. YILDIZ INTERFERENCE. "DAILY TELEGRAPH" WARNING. </head>
                    <byline>( Gazette's Special Service. )</byline>
                    <dateline>London, Wednesday.</dateline>
                    <p>In the leading article of to-day's "Daily Telegraph" referring to Lord
                        Cromer's remarks anent the entente cordiale, the writer says that from the
                        date of the signing of the Anglo- French convention Sultan Abdul Hamid has
                        worked through Mussulman agencies to create what is called the "national
                        movement" in Egypt. He has had one warning of the daugers of this course and
                        he may yet require another. It may be that nothing short of the appearance
                        of a British fleet under the park walls of Yildiz will ever convince him of
                        the fatal folly of interfering with our position in Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAISSE DE LA DETTE. A USEFUL INNOVATION.</head>
                    <p>The National Bank of Egypt has come to an agreement with the Egyptian
                        Government and the Caisse de la Dette, whereby the receipts from the land
                        tax and other sources of revenue hypothecated to the Caisse de la Dette will
                        be henceforward paid to the local agents of the National Bank. As these sums
                        are paid in, the National Bank at Alexandria will pass that amount to the
                        Credit Lyonnais at Alexandria to the Credit of the Caisse de la Dette. This
                        new arrangement will have an important result, for it will cause the money
                        to circulate much more rapidly than has hitherto been practicable during the
                        busy cotton season, and should be of material assistance in helping to put
                        an end to one of the chief causes of the locking up of gold, such as was
                        experienced during the acute money famine, which raged with such intensity
                        and caused so much inconvenience throughout the whole country during the
                        past autumn.</p>
                    <p>At present the branches of the National Bank throughout the provinces are
                        constant buyers of cheque on Alexandria of the agents of the big cotton
                        buyers here. To provide funds for that, the branch of the National Bank at
                        Alexandria has to send specie to its provincial agencies. Under the system
                        recently inaugurated, by receiving this money from the Caisse de la Dette,
                        there will be no longer any necessity, to send up so much specie to the
                        provincial çentres, and this same money will perform the double
                        transaction.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NATIONAL BANK OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The following report will be presented to the seventh ordinary general
                        meeting of the shareholders of the National Bank of Egypt, which is to be
                        held in Cairo on the 11th inst. </p>
                    <p>The directors of the Narional Bank of Egypt submit to the shareholders the
                        annexed balance sheet and profit and loss account for the year ending the
                        31st December, 1906.</p>
                    <table cols="3">
                        <row>
                            <cell>A gross profit is shown of . </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 495 259. 7. 5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>of which £ 50 500, derived from special investments, are
                                exceptional profits.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deducting rebate of interest . </cell>
                            <cell>£ 18.178 5.10</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <p>and the current expenses </p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>„ 98 950.1. 4</cell>
                            <cell> „ 117.128. 7. 2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <p>there remains a net profit of</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>
                                <p>£ 378.131. -. 8</p>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <p>The following distribution is laid down by the statutes of the
                                    Bank :</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4% to the capital, or 8 - per share . </cell>
                            <cell>£ 120.000</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10% of the net profit to the ReserveFund. . </cell>
                            <cell>,, 37.813.2</cell>
                            <cell>„ 157813. 2—</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 220 317 18 3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10% to the directors .</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell> „ 22.031.15.10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Leaving a balance of</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 198 286. 2. 5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To which must be added the balance carried forward last year </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>„ 30.675 3. 4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>making a total of</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 228.961. 5. 9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>The directors recommend the paymentot a dividend of an additional
                                10/- per share which will absorb .</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>„ 150000.—.—</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>and leave</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 78.961. 5. 9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>They further recommend that a sum of ...</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 50.000.—.—</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <p>to be taken from the exceptional profits referred to above, be
                                    carried to a reserve fund to be employed specially for
                                    equalising future dividends</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>and that.......................</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>£ 28.961. 5 9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <p>be carried forward to profit and loss new account.</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Each share will thus be entitled to 18/-, equivalent to 9 per cent on the
                        Capital.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-cah03">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Bulkeley (near Alexandria) half way to San Stefano</p>
                    <p>Ramleh's Fashionable Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Full Pension P.T. 50 a day with Monthly Terms</p>
                    <p>Visitors from Cairo alight at Sidi Gaber.</p>
                    <p>Reclame Lunch, P.T. 16. – Dinner, P.T. 20.</p>
                    <p>Proprietor, C. AQUILINA, (Late of Thos Cook &amp; Sons)</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL VISIT. REVIEW AT ABBASSIEH. </head>
                    <p>Yesterday morning H.R.H. the Duke of Connaught reviewed the troops of the
                        Cairo British garrison on the parade ground at Abbassieh. Half past ten was
                        the time fixed for the review and some time before that hour the Abbassieh
                        road was crowded with people anxious to witness the parade. A postponement
                        of half an hour had been made, however, and at eleven o'clock the Duchess of
                        Connaught and Princess Patricia arrived, being accompanied by Lewa Watson
                        Pasha, and escorted by a bodyguard of Inniskilling Dragoons. On their
                        arrival the National Anthem was played by the massed bands.</p>
                    <p>Less than a quarter of an hour later the Duke of Connaught arrived on the
                        scene, the troops coming to "Present," and the bands again playing "God Save
                        the King."</p>
                    <p>When his Royal Highness had taken up his position at the saluting point, the
                        parade marched past in the following order: – Major General Bullock and
                        Staff, "U" Battery Royal Horse Artillery, 6th Inniskilling Dragoons (3
                        Squadrons), Mounted Infantry, Royal Engineers, 3rd Bn. Coldstream Guard (8
                        companies), 2nd Bn. Inniskilling Fusiliers (7 companies), 1st Bn. King's Own
                        Scottish Borderers. The Infantry Brigade under the Command of Col. Grenville
                        Smith (Coldstream Guards) marched past in quarter column and again in line
                        of quarter column. The Royal Horse Artillery gallopped past in splendid
                        line, followed by the 6th Inniskilling Dragoons at the "charge." The Parade
                        then reformed in extended line and advanced to within 30 yards and saluted,
                        while the massed bands under Bandmaster Watson Ramsey, Inniskilling
                        Fusiliers, played the National Anthem.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="khedive">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H.H. the Khedive received Miralai Matchett Bey in audience at Abdin Palace
                        yesterday morning.</p>
                    <p>To-morrow evening his Highness will give a banquet at Abdin Palace in honour
                        of the Duke of Connaught</p>
                    <p>His Highness is expected to come to Alexandria next week and has consented to
                        be present at the performance to be given at the Zizinia theatre on the 18th
                        inst for the benefit of the Orwa el Woska Society.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STRIKE AT PORT SAID. SERIOUS SITUATION.</head>
                    <byline>(From our own Correspondent )</byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, Tuesday.</dateline>
                    <p>As I wired you this morning the bunkering Arabs have come out on strike in
                        sympathy with the coal-discharging men who left work without notice on
                        Thursday night. Throughout yesterday things were looking black, the Arabs
                        taking from 1 to 4 hours to get from the Arab town to the ship, and when
                        they did arrive they were very slow in getting to work. Late last night they
                        refused to work, and there have been some 12 or 15 ships whose crews have
                        had to set to and coal for themselves.</p>
                    <p>It is reported that the sheikhs are having a much trouble as well as the
                        "blacklegs,''and last night the mounted police had to be called out to keep
                        order in the Arab town.</p>
                    <p>Everything in the European quarter is quiet and the police are ready to deal
                        with any disturbances which may arrive.</p>
                    <p>Colliers continue to arrive and the discharging basin is now full. Four
                        vessels with a total tonnage of over 21,000 tons have arrived within the
                        last two days.</p>
                    <p>I understand that the owners are trying to engage labour from Cyprus, but
                        that nothing has yet been fixed.</p>
                    <p>H.M.S "Minerva" has not yet been sighted.</p>
                    <p>Later.</p>
                    <p>The P. &amp; O mail S.S. Egypt has arrived and is coaling with her crew.
                        Large crowds of Arabs along the quay are watching the coaling
                        operations.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ENGLISH SAILOR'S SAD DEATH. </head>
                    <p>On Monday evening John Marshall, a seaman of the S.S. Aleppo, while returning
                        to his ship with a shipmate, stumbled and fell into the water. He was
                        speedily rescued and conveyed to the German Hospital, where it was found
                        that his state was precarious and he succumbed eight hours later. Marshall
                        was 31 years old and a native of Sheffiold ifa Yorkshire. The inquest was
                        held this morning, evidence being given by the captain of the ship, two
                        seamen, and a coastguardman.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="steamerMovements">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS. </head>
                    <p>The S.S Kaffir Prince, with passengers and general cargo, left Manchester
                        yesterday and is due to arrive at Alexandria about the 18th inst.</p>
                    <p>The S S. Alexandria of the Westcott and Laurence Line left Malta on Tuesday
                        night and is due here, via Tripoli, on the 6th inst with general cargo from
                        Antwerp and London</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert">
                    <head>Windsor Hotel</head>
                    <p>Facing the Sea on New Quay of Alexandria</p>
                    <p>FIRST-CLASS HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>Lately built and Furnished</p>
                    <p>Terms P.T. 50 per day.</p>
                    <p>Special Rates to Government Officials.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <div type="item" feature="egyptological">
                    <head>EGYPTOLOGICAL NOTES.</head>
                    <head>INTERESTING FINDS. </head>
                    <p>For many years past classical chronologists have been at loggerheads about
                        the exact date of the decisive battle of Chrysopolis (now Scutari) wherein
                        Constantine the Great defeated Licini s, the master of the East and thus
                        became sole ruler of the Empire. Some fragments of Greek papyri recently
                        discovered at Theadelphia near the Fayoum, and brought to the Cairo Museum,
                        have been found to fix the date of the battle at 324 of our era.</p>
                    <p>M Cledac, the partner of M. Clermont-Ganneau, in the excavation now
                        proceeding at Assouan, has discovered the site of the Necropolis of the rams
                        of Khnoum, the god of Elephantine. Fifteen of these gods have been brought
                        to light and the greater number are in good preservation. The mummies have
                        unfortunately very few inscriptions on them.</p>
                    <p>The inscriptions of the Greek and Roman eras discovered in Egypt, and
                        published during 1906 have been very few. Four come from the Fayoum, one
                        from Mahemdiat, and one from Tehneh. Three of the Fayoum ones, however, are
                        legal documents engrossed upon wax preserved in Roman writing tablets and
                        are of much importance for the theory of Roman law. Three of the Roman
                        Governors or Prefects are mentioned in the various new texts, T. Hateritis
                        Nepos Q Corvius Flaccus, and M. Petronius Honoratus.</p>
                    <p>WORK AT THEBES.</p>
                    <p>Mr. James Dennis, of Baltimore, an associate director of the work of
                        excavation in Egypt conducted by the Egyptian Exploration Fund, has sent a
                        letter to those interested in the work in Baltimore, under date of the 15th
                        ulto. from Luxor, setting forth what has recently been accomplished. In the
                        course of it he says :</p>
                    <p>"The work of the expedition this year has been confined chiefly to opening
                        the shaft found last year that was presumed to lead into the tomb of King
                        Mentu-Hotep, Ra Neb Hapet, of the eleventh dynasty (about 2700 B.C.), and to
                        clearing the western court of the temple built by that king at Der el Bahri,
                        on the west bank of the Nile, in old Thebes.</p>
                    <p>The opening and clearing of this shaft have now been completed. The shaft
                        itself consisted of a long, inclined passage way, cut through the solid
                        rock, extending for nearly six hundred feet into the cliffs surrounding Dier
                        el Bahri. For about one-third of the way the shaft is roofed by cyclopean
                        blocks of sandstone, meeting in an arch at the top. Beyond this shaft is a
                        chamber about twenty feet long, at the end of which a flight of shallow
                        steps leads to the tomb chamber, the entrance to which is faced with large
                        granite blocks.</p>
                    <p>The roof of the tomb chamber, which is about sixteen feet high and twelve or
                        fourteen feet square, consists of large slabs of granite, meeting in a point
                        at the top, and not curved, as in the shaft. Three fourths of this chamber
                        is occupied by a great shrine, in which the sarcophagus containing the body
                        was placed. This shrine is built entirely of large blocks of alabaster,
                        except the roof, which consists of a granite monolith overlaid with
                        alabaster ; the inner sides are pierced with numerous holes, to contain pegs
                        for holding the coffin lid, and its exterior is modelled after the style of
                        a temple pylon. In front of this shrine was a large quantity of mummy cloth,
                        mixed with which we found the bones of the king, some portions of the skull,
                        jawbone aud the larger leg and arm bones ; the rest had crumbled to dust
                        ages ago.</p>
                    <p>Besides these fragments of the body of King Mentu-Hotep we found a large
                        number of models of sacred boats, wooden statuettes, figures of persons
                        engaged in various occupations, many war bows and arrows, the latter being
                        of a type hitherto unknown in Egypt ; two large heads in wood that formed
                        the covers for canopic jars and one of the gilded sandals of the king, part
                        of a gilded sceptre, several parts of chairs and thrones, and many other
                        fragments too badly injured by their forty-six centuries of interment to be
                        valuable.</p>
                    <p>The greatest interest connected with this discovery lies in the fact that the
                        temple and tomb of Mentu-Hotep are older by about a thousand years than any
                        monument heretofore found on the site of ancient Thebes, while the finding
                        of a royal body in its tomb, though not unprecedented has occurred only
                        three times in the history of Egyptian exploration. The temple itself is
                        unique in its architecture, and represents a transition period between the
                        pyramid type of interment and that practised in later times.</p>
                    <p>Many statues of the King have been found lately in front of the temple, and
                        within a week we have found the remains of a finely paiuted shrine of
                        Rameses the Great, showing that from about 2700 BC. to 1200 B.C. the temple
                        was known and revered as the last resting place of the greatest that Egypt
                        has ever had.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CONTINENTAL HOTEL. </head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Major A. Fryer and Officers of the Inniskilling
                        Dragoons, the Band will play a programme of music on the terrace of Grand
                        Continental Hotel to-morrow from 4 to 6 p.m.</p>
                    <p>March— Our Am encan Belles—Liborate.</p>
                    <p>Incidental Music from Henry VIII— Sullivan.</p>
                    <p>Valse— Kuenstler-Lebenn—Strauss.</p>
                    <p>Selection—The Catch of the Season— Haines,</p>
                    <list type="ordered">
                        <item>Humoriske—Dvorak.</item>
                        <item>Aubade. Napolitaine —Aletter.</item>
                    </list>
                    <p>Morceau—Salut d'Amour—Elgar.</p>
                    <p>Selection - Carmen — Bazet </p>
                    <p>Mazurka (Norvegienne) La Scandivane—Ganne.</p>
                    <p>Regimental March—The Khedivial Anthem</p>
                    <p>"God save the King.''</p>
                    <p>J. Prosser, Bandmaster</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ITALIAN VESSEL WRECKED. FOUR MEN DROWNED. RESCUE BY A MOSS BOAT. </head>
                    <p>The Moss Liner Moeris Captain F. Dunnett), arrived from Glasgow, reports the
                        following incident:– </p>
                    <p>On the morning of the 17th March, off Cape Finisterre, she came up with the
                        Italian steamer Industria, (980 Tons, of Genoa) in a sinking condition,
                        bound from Falmouth to Buenos Ayres with a cargo of iron and coal.</p>
                    <p>Some of her crew had already left and were observed clinging to the bottom of
                        a capsized boat. A south-westerly gale was blowing at the time and the
                        Moeris promptly lowered one of her boats, which, in charge of the chief
                        officer, Mr. J. James, first rescued the men from the overturned boat and
                        then approached the sinking steamer, those who remained aboard having to
                        jump into the sea and be picked up by the salvors. Four men refused to leave
                        and were seen to go down with the unfortunate vessel, which broke in half
                        immediately afterwards. Fourteen men were saved, including the English
                        captain and chief engineer, and were landed at Gibraltar</p>
                    <p>Great credit is due to Captain Dunnett, officers and men for a smart rescue
                        under very difficult aud risky conditions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>T.R.H. the Duke and Duchess of Connaught and H H. the Khedive will attend the
                        gymkhana to be held at the K.S.C., Cairo, this afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Lady Cromer will not be "at home" on Saturday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>Lady Wingate and family are expected to arrive early in April at Stafford
                        House, Dunbar, from Cairo.</p>
                    <p><persName>Sir Frederick Adair</persName>, Bart., has left England on his way
                        to Egypt.</p>
                    <p>Count von Bernsdorff, the German Diplomatic Agent and Consul General, who
                        arrived at Alexandria from Europe by the S.S. Hohenzollern on Monday last,
                        has resumed his official duties at Cairo.</p>
                    <p><persName>Mr. Tottenham</persName>, Inspector of the Sudan Irrigation
                        Department, has been granted three months' leave dating from the 1st
                        proxo.</p>
                    <p>The successor of Dean Butcher will be the Rev. Molesworth, of Leicester.</p>
                    <p>The British officers of the Egyptian Army recently gave a farewell banquet to
                        El Lewa Henry Pasha at Shepheard's Hotel.</p>
                    <p><persName>Dr. Mauchamp</persName>, whose murder in Morocco has caused such a
                        crisis in the affairs of that country, was well known in Egypt and the
                        Levant. He had been for five years head of the French Hospital at Jerusalem
                        aud came in 1903 to Egypt during the cholera epidemic where he devoted
                        himself to combating the epidemic.</p>
                    <p><persName>M. Ferdinand Martini</persName>, formerly Governor of Erythrea, has
                        arrived at Cairo from Massawah and will leave Alexandria for Italy
                        tomorrow.</p>
                    <p>The Very Rev. the Haham, or "Wise Man," of the Sephardim, or Spanish and
                        Portuguese Jews, Dr. Moses Gaster is leaving England after Easter—that is to
                        say, the Jewish Feast of Pass over—on a prolonged visit to Egypt, Palestine,
                        and Asia Minor He is going entirely in a private capacity to study the
                        conditions under which the Jews live in those countries He will also visit
                        Rumania, from which country he was exiled many years ago, mainly through the
                        agency of the Rumanian Prime Minister. The Haham is by way of being a modern
                        Mezzofanti, as he speaks, so he has told the London correspondent of the
                        "Yorkshire Post," nearly every language in Europe, and has written books in
                        three or four of them.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-lau01">
                    <head>The world renowned Laurens Cigarettes.</head>
                    <p>"LE KHEDIVE" Company</p>
                    <p>can be obtained in their new artistic shop, Kasr-el-Nil street, opposite the
                        Savoy Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Also the best Havana Cigars specially selected for English and American
                        connoisseurs, and sold at New York and London prices.</p>
                    <p>The company are purveyors by appointment since many years to the Rgies of
                        France, Austria, Hungary, Italy, Spain, Tunis, etc., to their Majesties the
                        Kings of Italy and Spain, to the Household of H H. the Khedive, to H. R. H.
                        Prince Charles of Bavaria, etc.,etc.</p>
                    <p>London Address :— 17 Hanover Square W. Agencies and depots in all parts of
                        the world.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-bsl01">
                    <head>BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                    <p>236 BRANCHES.</p>
                    <p>French, German, Italian, Greek, Arabic, etc.</p>
                    <p>Private Lessons, Residence Lessons, taught by Native Masters </p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA: 26 Rue Rosette (close to Zizinia Theatre.)</p>
                    <p>CAIRO : 1 Sharia Kamel. </p>
                    <p>TRIAL LESSONS FREE</p>
                    <p>11, Rue Midan, Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="item" xml:lang="fr" feature="municipality">
                    <head>DELEGATION MUNICIPALE</head>
                    <p>(Communication Officielle)</p>
                    <p>La Délégation Municipale s'est réunie le 2 avril 1907 à 4 h. 1/2 p m. sons la
                        présidence de S.E. le Dr. Schiess Pacha.</p>
                    <p>Communication est donnée :</p>
                    <p>1° d'une lettre ministérielle suspendant la décision prise par la Commission
                        relative à la règlementation du contrôle des poids.</p>
                    <p>3° d'un projet de lettre à adresser au Ministère tendant à reserver à la
                        Municipalité les carrières du Mex, pour les besoins des divers travaux
                        projetés, sauf à mettre à la disposition des carriers les quantités
                        nécessaires à l'entreprise privée.</p>
                    <p>4. de deux lettres ministérielles confirmant les mesures prises pour
                        l'expédition au Caire de la viande de Serbie et du bétail destiné à
                        l'intérieur.</p>
                    <p>5. d'une lettre du Ministère des Travaux Publics regrettant de ne pouvoir
                        donner suite à la demande de la Municipalité pour l'abaissement de la ligne
                        du chemin de fer de Moharrem Bey, en raison de questions d'ordre technique.
                        Les talus devront être au contraire rehaussés d'un mètre et demi environ, ce
                        qui permettra, au besoin, l'établissement de ponts assez élevés pour
                        faciliter les communications.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation ajourne pour étude, le projet présenté par la société des
                        entreprises urbaines et rurales pour la confection de la route de la
                        corniche.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation, vu les offres présentées pour la fourniture des articles de
                        droguerie, de désinfection et autres nécessaires à la Municipalité pendant 3
                        années, décide de répartir cette fourniture entre les différents
                        soumissionnaires, suivant les indications données par l'Inspecteur
                        sanitaire, et d'après les offres les plus basses. Certains de ces articles
                        seront achetés au fur et à mesure des besoins, librement par les services,
                        en raison des prix élevés offerts par les soumissionnaires. Il sera de même
                        pour les articles pour lesquels aucune offre n'a été présentée.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation adjuge à M Miard, représentant la Val de Travers Asphalte
                        Paving Co. les travaux d'asphaltage de la partie de rue située devant le
                        palais municipal, au prix de P.T 92 le m c., à la condition que cet
                        entrepreneur accepte la clause de la responsabilité en cas d'affaissement
                        naturel du sous sol.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation décide d'étendre l'asphaltage dans diverses rues centrales
                        parées en dalles. D'ores et déjà elle décide de mettre en adjudication
                        l'asphaltage de toute la rue Rosette, sauf contribution de la part des
                        propriétaires riverains.</p>
                    <p>Les dalles retirées de cette rue serviront à la continuation de l'exécution
                        du dallage des diverses rues d'après le programme déjà arrêté par la
                        Délégation.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation regrette de ne pouvoir donner suité à une demande de la Cie des
                        téléphones tendant à la location d'une parcelle de terrain sur les quais
                        pour y établir un dépôt.</p>
                    <p>Elle decide de renvoyer à l'examen du Comité des travaux publics un projet
                        présenté par M. l'Ingénieur Gorra pour rétablissement d'une route, reliant
                        la route de la corniche au Canal Mahmoudieh.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation prend connaissance d'une lettre de l'Administration des Ports
                        et Phares au sujet de la concession de la jetée Joseph ainsi que d'une note
                        de l'ingénieur en chef de la Municipalité à cet égard.</p>
                    <p>Cette question est renvoyée à l'examen des comités compétents.</p>
                    <p>Sur la proposition de l'Administration des Douanes, la Délégation décide de
                        déclasser la rue Ramsès, qui entrera dans la zone de la Douane ; une ligne
                        de chemin de fer sera établie dans cette rue. Il est bien en entendu que
                        l'Administration des Douanes aura à rembourser à la Municipalité les frais
                        déboursés par la Municipalité pour la confection de cette rue.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation renvoie au Comité des travaux publics une demande présentée par
                        le Directeur de l'Abattoir pourr divers achats et aménagements à faire dans
                        cet établissement.</p>
                    <p>Elle émet un avis favorable à une proposition de l'Inspecteur sanitaire
                        tendant à l'élaboration d'un règlement relatif à la vaccination obligatoire
                        des personnes débarquant à Alexandrie et renvoie cette proposition à l'étude
                        du Comité du Contentieux.</p>
                    <p>La Délégation conformément à l'avis de l'Ingénieur en chef, décide d'adopter
                        pour les tramways le système en usage à Liverpool.</p>
                    <p>La séance est levée à 7 h 1/2 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="bulletinBourse">
                    <head>BULLETIN DE LA BOURSE </head>
                    <p>(Aujourdhui à midi et demie.)</p>
                    <p>Après un excellent début, la cote a partiellement fléchi en clôture. Une
                        reprise n'est guère possible avant la fin de la semaine, la liquidation ne
                        te terminant que vendredi prochain. Les reports sont rares, on préféré
                        liquider. La National remonte a 25 11/16, la Banque d'Athènes a fr. 125 1/2,
                        la Building a 4 7/8, la Port-Salt a 13/9, L'Uuion Foncière est ramassée
                        discrètement a 5 17/32. En hausse également la Nile Land a 30 3/8, la Bourse
                        and Banking a 1 5/8, le Crédit Franco-Egyptien a 5 11/16.</p>
                    <p>Par contre les Eaux du Caire reculent à fr.120, les Markets à 25, 1a Salt and
                        Soda à 19/3, la Cassa di Sconto à 207 et 209, le Comptoir à 6 ¼ l'action, et
                        6 ½ la part de fondateur, la Banque d'Orient à 125 ½ acheteurs et les Ritz à
                        4 1/8.</p>
                    <p>En baisse de 1 32 la Delta Land et l'Urbaine qui font 3 11/16 et 7 3/16
                        respectivement, La part de fondateur de l'Eg Land Investment and Building
                        dégringole à 4 1/8</p>
                    <p>Deux petites agences viennent encore de cesser leurs paiements, le passif est
                        cependant insignifiant.</p>
                    <p>Pour les réglement des différences résultant des compensations, le comité a
                        fixé, pour les valeurs non inscrites a la cote, les cours suivants : New
                        Egyptian 22/3, Sidi Salem (fondateur) £5, Ghesireh Mansions 3/4, Hooker
                        31/32, Karam 13/16.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n3/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n4/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n5/mode/1up" status="incomplete">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="item" feature="circulaire">
                    <head> Cipculaire H. De Vries et Boutigny </head>
                    <p> NOTES ET CRITIQUES </p>
                    <p> La Caire, Mardi 2 Avril 1907. Le taux de l'escompte libre à Londres est
                        retrmbé, jandi passé, de 1/8 à 6% Au Stock Exchange, le même jour, le
                        Consolidé anglais a haussé de 8/8 d 85 3/4. L'Uuifiée est re-tée invariée à
                        101 1/2. La National Bank a gagré 1/4 à 35 3/4. L'Agricole est demeurée
                        inchangée $ 8 7/8. La D Yra a rétrogradé de 1/4 &amp; 15 1/2 et la Delta
                        Light de 1/8 à 10 7/8. </p>
                    <p> A Paris, le Crédit Foncier Egyptien aurait regagné 10 franus à 735 d'après
                        certains télégrammes. La Banque d'Athènes s'est maintends à 129. </p>
                    <p> loi, on dépit da long chômage des fêtes de Pâques, la séance de ce matin n'a
                        guère brille par l'animation et l'activité. Il ext vrai qre o'était le jour
                        des règlements de la liquidation de fin de mois et qu'il importe de tenir
                        compte des difficultés monétaires dans les que les se debât la place. Il
                        faut également prendre en considération que la liquidation d'Alexandrie
                        commence demaio et qu'elle semble s'annoncer fort laborie 188. Tontos 008
                        Causos réunies jointes, à la baisse du cotor, enrayent. poor l'instant, la
                        reprise sérieuse que les nouvelleplus favorables d'Europe et des cours très
                        bas faisaient, à bon droit, entrevoir a bref delai. Neapmoins plasieas
                        titres enregistrent d'ores et déjà ade amelioration. </p>
                    <p> Dans le compartiment des Banques, la Na. tional, bien tenor, &amp; avancé à
                        25 3/4. L'Agricole &amp; progressé à 8 3/4 13/16. La Cassa di Sconto s'est
                        tassée à 218. Lo Comptoir Financier a Héchi à 6 31 6 et sa part à 6 7/8. </p>
                    <p> Le Crédit Foncier a été négligé à 726 727. La Nile Land est revenge à 233/8.
                        L'allotment a rétrogradé à 8 13/16; 88 part &amp; côturé à 106. L'Enterprise
                        and Development est rémontée à 11. </p>
                    <p> Bn bonde demande, les Entreprises Immobilières et Travaux, q10 nous avions
                        laissées jeudi passé à 9 1/2, ont atteint 11 3/8 poor olotarer à 11 8/16-1/4
                        ; leur part &amp; tormiré à 126 après 180. L'Epargne Immobilière est restée
                        à 3 1/16 et sa part à 128. L'Express Nile action nouvelle s'est maintenue à
                        5 1/4 5/16 et la part à 149. </p>
                    <p> L'action de ospital Eaux do Caire a été cotée 115 ex-coapon et les
                        Joaissances 251 ex-coupon également. </p>
                    <p> Dans le groupe des valeors hôtelières, les Nangovich sont demeurés à 27
                        11/16-3/4. Tree moavementes, les Egyptian ont atteint 11 1/4 pour
                        réactionner en ordre à 10,13/16-7/8. Le Upper Egypt, en bonde tendar of, ont
                        gagré 7/16 à 4 1/16 1/8. Les National ont rogresse à 3 1/4-5 16. L s
                        excelsior ont taibli à 9 3/16 5/8. Les Ritz H tels ont été tends à 3 1/4
                        5/16 ; il se confirme que cette société a acheté, a des conditions très
                        avantageuse", a la Nile Land 80,000 mètres a K281-el Donbara, on dehors da
                        terrain destiné a la construction d'on botel. </p>
                    <p> Parmi les petites valeurs, la Delta Land a été ramenée a 3 3/8. Los Eestates
                        ont également faibli a 1 3/4 13/16 et leur part a 17. La New Egyptian a
                        reéalé a 22 sh.' et les Construction, &amp; 0 7/8-16/16. </p>
                    <p>L'action H. de Vries and Boutigry L'd. &amp; été demandés a £3, soit avec une
                        prime de deox livres.</p>
                    <p> Les journaux de Loudres, arrivés par le opurrier d'hier, annoncent
                        l'enregist ement, à la date du 20 Mars dernier, de la Société ano. nyme " H.
                        de Vrieg and Bootigny Ltd. ”, aa capital de £ 300,000, dont nous avons en
                        Ocos. Bion de parler dans notre Circulaire de mor. credi et jeudi passés en
                        rendant compte de l'assemblée générale extraordinaire de la Socié'é
                        d'Estreprises Immobilières et de Travaux. </p>
                    <p> Une assemblée générale extraordinaire de l'Egyptian Delta Land and
                        lovestment Co. est convoquée à Londres pour le 16 Avril courant &amp;
                        l'effet d'adopter une série de résolations spé. ciales relatives aux
                        arrangements intervenus dernièrement au Caire. </p>
                    <p> A l'ordre do joor figurent également deos résolations ordinaires, l'ane
                        tendant à porter lo capital social de £ 250,000 &amp; £ 590,009, l'autre à
                        rétablir les rapports existant antérieurement entre la 8: c'été et
                        l'Ezyptian Delta Light Rilways Co. </p>
                    <p> L'assemblée générale ordinaire de la Société d'Entreprises Urbaines et
                        Rurales s'est tende samedi passé au siège social à Alexandrie. </p>
                    <p> Les comptes et bilan de l'exercice 1906 in 6! é approavés. Sar la
                        proposition da conseil d'administration, il a été décidé de payer, à partir
                        da 8 Avril courant, op dividende de P.B. 50 par antion et P.E. 134 1/2 par
                        part de fondatear. </p>
                    <p> La 80nscription publiqne $ 52,000 actions de la Cairo Baildings Co., Sociée
                        anonyme an capital de £ 151,000 représenté par 150,400 actions à £ 1 et
                        20,000 parts de fondateor à 1 shelling, a été ouverte ce matin chez MM.
                        Adolphe Cattaui et Cie. au Caire et sera olore samedi proobain. </p>
                    <p> Carnet de l'actionnaire. </p>
                    <p> Les actionnaires de la Snciété Anonyme Egyptienne de Pablicité sont
                        convoqnés an assemblée gérérale ordinaire, au siège social an Caire, pour le
                        15 Avrll coorant, à 4 b. p.m. A l'ordre da joar : rapport da conseil ;
                        approbation des comptes de l'exercice écoulé ; fixation do dividende. Le
                        dépôt des titres doit être effectoé an plus tard le 10 Avril au siège de la
                        Socié'. oa à l'Anglo-Egyptian Bank. </p>
                    <p> - L'assemb'de générale ordinaire de la Bailding Lands of Egypt Co. est
                        convoquée pour le 20 Avril soprant, ad siege social a Alexandrie. A l'ordre
                        da joar : rapport da conseil ; approbation des comptes de l'exercice 1906;
                        fixation da dividendo ; ratification et domination d'administratoon, </p>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <p> - L'assemblée générale ordinaire de l'U nion Funo è e d'Egypte, tenae
                        meroredi passé au sisge social à Aloxandrie, , a approuvé la distribution
                        d'an dividede de P.E. 22 par action, payable à partir da 8 Avril courant. </p>
                    <p> Los teosttes de la D-lča Light Rsilways Co. pour la semaine au 28 Mars 1907
                        se sont éle vées à L.E. 5,01 ) contr+ 3 948 en 1906, soit op augmentation de
                        L E. 1, 65. Les recatto: totales depois le ler Avi 1906 se chiffreat par L
                        E. 243,774 contre 209,868, soit en plasvalas de L.E. 33,906. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> AVIS INTERESSANT </head>
                    <p> La maison Spartali a l'avantage d'informer sa nombroase clientèle qu'elle
                        vient de rere. voir, commo deroier envoi de la saison, au riche assortiment
                        de tapie. </p>
                    <p> Nous conseillons vivement au pablio de Vonir visiter les deroières créations
                        de cette maison dans ses magasins sis à l'avenge Rogsetta, u se presse un
                        pablio aussi nombreux qa'élégant. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> Fayoum Light Railways Company. </head>
                    <p> Massienrs les Actionnaires sont convoqnés en Assemblée Générale
                        extraordinaire qui sera tepne an didge Social ao Caire, Standard Lite
                        Building, Sharin Kasr-el-Nil, Vendredi, 19 Avril 1907 à 11 heares da matin,
                        aux fins de délibérer sur l'ordre da jar suivant : 1° Modifications à
                        apporter one les Articles </p>
                    <p> 1, 6 et 7 de l'Acte de Concession. 2° Pouvoirs spéciaux à donner au Présider
                        t| </p>
                    <p> da Conseil d'Administration, relative </p>
                    <p> ment aux dites modifications. Pour assister l'aeremblée, il faudra se
                        trouver dans les conditions de i'irt cle 16 der Statate, le dépot de titres
                        devant avoir lieu avant le 16 ay ilan Siège social ou à l'AngloEgyptian Bank
                        (Caira-Alexandrie). </p>
                    <p> Poor le Conseil d'Administration 89935-1 </p>
                    <p> 8 DE BILINSKI. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="notice">
                    <head> Alexandria Central Buildings Company. </head>
                    <p>AVIS</p>
                    <p> Megsieurs les Actionnaires sont informe que | l'Assemblée Générale Ordinaire
                        d'hier a fixé à 5% (soit £0.5.0 par action) le dividende pour l'Exercice
                        1906 qui sera payé à partir de Lundi, 8 Avril curant, par l’Anglo Egyptian
                        Bank, Limited, à Alexandrie, contre remise du coupon N° 2. </p>
                    <p> Alexandrie, le 3 Avril 1907. 29941-1 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item" feature="exportManifests" status="verified">
                    <head> EXPORT MANIFESTS. </head>
                    <p>For Piræus and ODESSA, by the 3.8. Impera'o, Nicolas II, sailed on the 26th
                        March :</p>
                    <p>Varioos, 105 empty casks, 550 packages vegatables, 515 bege rice, 100
                        packagak sundries</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benacbi &amp; Co.,' 100 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 200</p>
                    <p>300 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>For Hull, by the S.S. Thorndals, sailed in i the 26 b Maroh :</p>
                    <p>Anglo-Egypt. Bank, 1,065 tons cotton seed</p>
                    <p>Egyptian lavest. &amp; Axency Ltd, 200 i . . .,</p>
                    <p>Ibrah. Duff, . 8,608 bags onions</p>
                    <p>Moh. H E Chariff, 1,650,</p>
                    <p>Gliver Hill &amp; Co, 273</p>
                    <p>D. G. Philipidis, 161</p>
                    <p>Bustros &amp; Huri, 2,001</p>
                    <p>Aly Moh. Salib, 600</p>
                    <p>Katr Ziyat Cotton Ltd, 7,280 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>Egypt. Salt &amp; Soda Co., 5,604 bags oil caka</p>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL, by the S.. Menez, sailed on the 26 h March :</p>
                    <p>Choremi, B-nachi &amp; Co. 845 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>Bastr 8 &amp; Hiri, 109</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baines &amp; Co., 25</p>
                    <p>W. Getty &amp; Co, 35</p>
                    <p>Cred + Fraico Egyptien 72</p>
                    <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemain, 20</p>
                    <p>G. Riecken, 233</p>
                    <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co.,284</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co., 148</p>
                    <p>G. Petracohi &amp; Co. 90</p>
                    <p>J. Planta &amp; Co.,. 50</p>
                    <p>Imp. Ottoman Bank, 116</p>
                    <p>O. A. Pringo, 55</p>
                    <p>W. Camilleri, 7</p>
                    <p>2,089 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>Bahrerd &amp; Co., 1,071 bags onions</p>
                    <p>L. Onofrio, 520</p>
                    <p>Bastion &amp; Hari, 2,600 ;</p>
                    <p>T. Gbirghis &amp; Son, 2,690</p>
                    <p>Ayoub Bey, 214</p>
                    <p>Barber &amp; Son, 1,000</p>
                    <p>Mob. Suleb, 500</p>
                    <p>M. H. E Cherif, 1,525</p>
                    <p>J. Davies, 250 ,</p>
                    <p>A. Par zieri, 400</p>
                    <p>Glover Hill &amp; Co., 3,856</p>
                    <p>B. J. Coary &amp; Co., 100 tons cotton seed</p>
                    <p>J. &amp; A. Abonobanab, 1,100 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>Asia Minor S.S. , 1,533 osses oranges</p>
                    <p>Khedivial Mail, 51 bags yellow berries</p>
                    <p>For MARSEILLES, by the S.S. Purtugal, sailer on the 29th March :</p>
                    <p>FOR MARSEILLES</p>
                    <p>Adee, 25 cases eggs</p>
                    <p>Babsgiar, 267 crates tomatoes</p>
                    <p>Seisun, 97</p>
                    <p>Dalia, 100</p>
                    <p>8. Luvy, 200</p>
                    <p>Bonded Warehouse, 7 CABOS cigarettes</p>
                    <p>Peel &amp; Co, 93 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>Carver Bros. &amp; Co. Ltd, 16</p>
                    <p>F. C. Baide, &amp; Co., 128</p>
                    <p>R. &amp; O. Lindemann, 30</p>
                    <p>Choremi, Benschi &amp; Co., 128</p>

                    <p>327 bales cotton</p>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <p>Behrend &amp; Co., 200 bags onions</p>
                    <p>Onofrio, 300 „ „</p>
                    <p>Rice Mills, 1000 bags rice</p>
                    <p>Salt &amp; Soda, 1072 bags oil cake</p>
                    <p>Various, 100 packages sundries</p>
                    <p>For Barcelona</p>
                    <p>Moursi, 25 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>For Le Havre</p>
                    <p>R. &amp; O Lindemann, 300 bales cotton</p>
                    <p>G. Frauger &amp; Co., 100 „ „</p>
                    <p>400 bales cotton</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section" xml:lang="fr" xml:id="deg-el-mmeb01">
                    <head>MARCHE DE MINET-EL-BASSAL</head>
                    <dateline><date when="1907-04-03">3 avril 1907</date>.—(11h.55 a.m.)</dateline>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Cotons</hi> —Clôture du marché du <date when="1907-04-02">2
                            avril</date>: Marche nul</p>
                    <p>Etat du marché de ce jour, cotons : Soutenu</p>
                    <p>Les arrivages de ce jour se chiffrent par cantars <measure unit="cantar"
                            >856</measure> contre même jour l'année précédente cantars <measure
                            unit="cantar">2738</measure>
                    </p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Grains de coton</hi>.—Sans changement</p>
                    <table xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb02">
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Disponible</cell>
                            <cell>Ticket</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mit-Afifi—</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">58</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Rien</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Haute-Egypte.—</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">56 1/2</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Rien</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Blés</hi>.—Très fermes</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Qualité Saïdi</hi>.—Cond. Saha P.T. <measure unit="pt"
                            >—</measure> à <measure unit="pt">—</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">" Béhéra</hi>: " " " <measure unit="pt">110</measure> à
                            <measure unit="pt">120</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Feves</hi>.—En baisse</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Saïdi</hi>
                        <measure unit="pt">95</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Fayoum</hi> : disponible : <measure unit="pt"
                        >94</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Qualitè Saïdi</hi>. Cond. Saha P.T. <measure unit="pt"
                            >108</measure> à <measure unit="pt">114</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Lentilles</hi>.—Très rares</p>
                    <p>Disponible: Rien</p>
                    <p>Cond. Saha P.T. <measure unit="pt">120</measure> à <measure unit="pt"
                            >130</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Orges</hi>.—Soutenues</p>
                    <p>" Cond.Saha P.T. <measure unit="pt">61</measure> à <measure unit="pt"
                            >63</measure></p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Maïs</hi>.—Sans changement</p>
                    <p>Disponible : Rien</p>
                    <p>" Cond. Saha P.T. <measure unit="pt">100</measure> à <measure unit="pt"
                            >110</measure></p>
                    <table rows="4" cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb03">
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>Exportation</cell>
                            <cell>du <date when="1905-07-11">11 juil.</date></cell>
                            <cell>depuis le <date when="1905-07-07">7 juil.</date></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coton</cell>
                            <cell>Bal. <measure unit="balles">616</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Bal. <measure unit="balles">10298</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gr. de cot.</cell>
                            <cell>Ard. <measure unit="ard">2962</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Ard. <measure unit="ard">8952</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fèves</cell>
                            <cell>" <measure unit="ard">6595</measure></cell>
                            <cell>" <measure unit="ard">7461</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table rows="4" cols="3" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb04">
                        <head>Exportations probables de la semaine:</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1905</cell>
                            <cell>1904</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coton</cell>
                            <cell>Bal. <measure unit="balles">15,000</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="balles">5,900</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Graines de coton</cell>
                            <cell>Ard. <measure unit="ard">25,000</measure></cell>
                            <cell>Ard. <measure unit="ard">34,000</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fèves</cell>
                            <cell>" <measure unit="ard">16,000</measure></cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="ard">2,000</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table cols="5" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb05">
                        <head>Les prix suivants ont été pratiqués ce jour</head>
                        <head>COTON C.M.E. (Basse-Egypte)</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="3"/>
                            <cell cols="2">par Cantar</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="5">Province Béhéra</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Damanhour</placeName>. </cell>
                            <cell>De P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">180</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">242 ½</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="5">Provience Garbieh</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Kafr-Zayat</placeName>. </cell>
                            <cell>De P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">265</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">295</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Tantah</placeName>. </cell>
                            <cell>" "</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">260</measure></cell>
                            <cell>"</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">295</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell cols="5">Province Menoufieh</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><placeName>Menouf</placeName>.</cell>
                            <cell> De P.T.</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">222 ½</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à</cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">277 ½</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table cols="5" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb06">
                        <head>SECTION DES GRAINES ET CEREALES</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell>PRIX FRANCO-STATION :</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">DISPONIBLE</cell>
                            <cell cols="2">TICKET</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Graines de coton Afifi</cell>
                            <cell>P.T. </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">58 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell>à P.T. </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>" Haute Egypte</cell>
                            <cell>" </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">56 ½</measure></cell>
                            <cell>" " </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fèves Saïdi</cell>
                            <cell>" </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">95 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell>" " </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>" Fayoumi</cell>
                            <cell>" </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">94 —</measure></cell>
                            <cell>" " </cell>
                            <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ARRIVAGES</head>
                        <dateline>de <date when="1905-07-12">mercredi 12 juillet
                            1905</date></dateline>
                        <p>Documents de l' "Alexandria General Produce Association."</p>
                        <table rows="9" cols="4" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb07">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell/>
                                <cell cols="2">CHEMINS DE FER</cell>
                                <cell>BARQUES</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cotons</cell>
                                <cell>S/B </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sb">53</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Graines de coton</cell>
                                <cell>sacs </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">1630</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Blés Saïdi </cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>" Béhéra</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">2033</measure></cell>
                                <cell>-</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fèves Saidi</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">1273</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>" Béhéra</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Orges</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Maïs</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                                <cell>—</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Lentilles</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                                <cell>-—</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Cotons</hi>.-Total des arrivages depuis le <date
                                when="1904-09-01">1er septembre 1904</date> jusqu'à ce jour, cantars
                                <measure unit="cantar">6,209,388</measure>.</p>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Grains de coton</hi>.—Total des arrivages depuis le
                                <date when="1904-09-01">1er septembre 1904</date> jusqu'à ce jour,
                            Ard. <measure unit="ard">3,503,332</measure></p>
                        <p>Contre même jour en 1904 :</p>
                        <table rows="9" cols="2" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb08">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell/>
                                <cell cols="2">BARQUES ET CHEMINS DE FER</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Cotons</cell>
                                <cell>S/B </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sb">-</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Graines de coton</cell>
                                <cell>sacs </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">-</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Blés Saïdi </cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>" Béhéra</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">894</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fèves Saidi</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">3506</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>" Béhéra</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Orges</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Maïs</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">250</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Lentilles</cell>
                                <cell>" </cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="sack">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Cotons</hi>.—Total des arrivages depuis le <date
                                when="1903-09-01">1er septembre 1903</date> jusqu'à ce jour, cantars
                                <measure unit="cantar">6,458,818</measure></p>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Graines de coton</hi>.—Total des arrivages depuis le
                                <date when="1903-09-01">1er septembre 1903</date> jusqu'à ce jour
                            Ard. <measure unit="ard">3,533,437</measure></p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CONTRATS, (11h.55 a.m.)</head>
                        <p>Cours de la Bourse de Minet-el-Bassal </p>
                        <table cols="5" xml:id="deg-ta-mmeb09">
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell><hi rend="italic">Coton F.G.F.Br.</hi></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Novembre</cell>
                                <cell>Tal.</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">14 15/16</measure></cell>
                                <cell>à</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Janvier</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">14 27/32</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mars</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">15 —</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Juillet</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">14 15/16</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Août</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">15 3/16</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="tal">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell><hi rend="italic">Grains de coton</hi></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>N.-D.-J.</cell>
                                <cell>P.T.</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">61 —</measure></cell>
                                <cell>à</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Juillet</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">58 20/40</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Août</cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">59 30/40</measure></cell>
                                <cell>"</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row role="label">
                                <cell><hi rend="italic">Fèves-Saïdi</hi></cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Sept.-Oct.</cell>
                                <cell>P.T.</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">95 —</measure></cell>
                                <cell>à</cell>
                                <cell><measure unit="pt">—</measure></cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                        <p>REMARQUES</p>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Cotons</hi>: Nouvelle récolte.—Le novembre a ouvert à
                            14 15/16 sous l'impression de la clôture d'Amérique et ne tarde même pas
                            à fléchir à 14 7/8, mais il se raffermit de nouveau. Affaires
                            claisemées.</p>
                        <p>Récolte actuelle. —Juillet a débuté à 14 5/16 et reste soutenu. Marché
                            peu animé.</p>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Grains de coton</hi>: Nouvelle récolte.— Sans affaires
                            importante; quand même les cours sont bien tenus.</p>
                        <p>Récolte actuelle.—Juillet a obtenu P.T. 58 ¾ à l'ouverture. </p>
                        <p><hi rend="italic">Fèves-Saidi</hi>: Nouvelle récolte.—Marché nul.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="7"/>
            <div type="page" n="7" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n6/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <div type="page" n="8" facs="https://archive.org/details/egyptian-gazette-1907-04-03/page/n7/mode/1up" status="empty"> </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
