<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Karl-Frederick Roche</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-09-17">September 17, 2019</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1907-12-16"><name>Monday</name>, December 16,
                        1907</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01"><p>The Eastern Telegraph Company,
                                Limited.</p>
                                <p>This Company's system of submarine telegraph <lb/>cables is the
                                    most direct and quickest means of <lb/>communication from Egypt
                                    to Europe, North and <lb/>South America, East, South and West
                                    Africa, <lb/>India, Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                    rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p></cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01"><p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                
                <cb n="2"/>
                <!-- second column of ads -->
                
                <cb n="3"/>
                <!-- third column of ads -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
                
            </div>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3"> 
               <p> LOCAL AND GENERAL. <lb/> —— Cholera at Meooa. <lb/> An_ isolated case of cholera
                    is reported from Mecca. <lb/> Now Quay Appointment. <lb/> » Mohamed Effendi
                    Khatta, Ministry of Just: ice, has been appointed Superintendent of the
                    Alexandria quays. <lb/> The Coldstream Cuarde. <lb/> The annual sports of the
                    3rd Battalion Coldstream Guards will be held on the Slade ground, Abbassia, on
                    Thursday next. </p>
                <p>Bubonie Plague. There aré now 19 cases of plagne under treatment, One case has
                    been discharged cured and one has ended fatally at: Alexandria.</p>
                <p> Hasheesh Smuggling. The Coast ‘Guards Administration -seized 106 kilos and 850
                    grammes of hasheesh in the Port Said’ harbour on the 12th inst. this being the
                    second seizure made at Port Said within the fortnight.</p>
                <p> Cairo Water Commission. A Council of Ministers will be heldthis week, and the
                    report of the special water commission will be one of the subjects submitted to
                    the Council. We understanéthat this report is in every way a favourable one. </p>
               <p> Savoy Hotel, Cairo. The first small dance of the Savoy Hotel, Cairo, will be held
                    next Saturday. Tables for dinner and supper should be booked early as numerous,
                    orders haye already been given. The Old Rugbeian Dinner will also be held at the
                    Savoy on the same evening. </p>
                <p>Cairo Scientific Society, Members Of the Cairo Scientific Society are invited to
                    inspect the Rodah Bridge by invita- tion of Mr. A. J: Knowles, on Thursday next.
                    A paper will be read before the Society by Mr. Knowles, at a later date,
                    describing * the construction of the Bridge. </p>
                <p>‘ Y. W. 6. A. Cairo. The sale of work of the Young Women’s Christian Association,
                    Cairo, which will be opened at 3.30 p.m. to-morrow by Lady Gorst at the
                    Semiramis Hotel, will be re-opened at the same hour on the following day by Lady
                    Blanche Smith at-Connaught House; </p>
                <p>Coal Imports. : Between January 1 and December 1.291,617 tons of coal were
                    imported into Egypt, of which 711,207 tons wete Welsh, 158,579 12 * Noweastle,
                    186,149 Yorkshire, 100,080 Scotch and 135,602 other qualities. During the
                    corres- ponding period of last year the imports totalled 1,217,384: </p>
                <p>Nativé Criminal Court. The Criminal Court of Alexandria which met-on the 14th
                    inst. under the presidency of Judge- Mohamed Bey Said, Councillor to the Court
                    of Appeal,.have sentenced Akeel Saad, Saad Ahmed, and *Abnbaker Massad, who
                    murdered the Omdeh of Zarka village, to im prisonment with hard labour for life. </p>
                <p>Bandmann’s Comedy Company. Maurice E. Bandmann has arranged for his London Comedy
                    Company.to appear for two weeks at the Khedivial Opera House, Cairo, in the
                    latter part of April and beginning of May next. The company has carried every-
                    thing before it during their eighteen months -tour in India and the Far East.
                    While in Cairo they will give the following popular London successes :—
                    “Raffles,” “His House in Order,” ‘The Walls of Jericho,’ “The Christ- ian.” ‘The
                    Morals of Marcus,” “John Glade's Honour,” “Che Admirable Crichton,” ‘Peter's
                    Mother,” “Old Heidelberg,” “Sherlock Holm- es,” “The Earl of Pawtucket,” and
                    “Sunday.” The repertoire is certainly an excellent one and seding that the
                    company 1s carrying some fifty tons of scenery we are likely to see each piece
                    staged in the same elaborate mauner as in London. </p>
                <p>ALEXANDRIA CONSERVATOIRE OF MUSIC. </p>
                <p>The fifth annual entertainment given by the } pupils of the above flourishing
                    institution took place on Saturday in the Lifontr concert hall, and’ attracted*a
                    large and’ fashionable “audience. Most ofthe items showed a dec idedl
                    improvement on last year's. pe ‘rformance, which was more particnlarly marked in
                    the individual numbers. The choruses might be much more forcibly. rendered.
                    appeared to be an absence of any attempt at accentuate the light and shade which
                    1s 80 necessary in order to produce the’ effects in- tended in such achorosas
                    Verdi's “I Profughi Scozzesi” trom Macbeth. </p>
                <p>The same remark applies to the chorus “‘La Primavera” in*the sécond part. The
                    soprano solo in this, Azzarelli, whose perfofmance was rather spoil- ed,
                    however, by an evident nervousness. In Mayerbeer’s romance “Sic Vendicata’ Prof,
                    Gianni Galletti put forward one -of his best pupils in Sig. D.Lambridis,who has
                    a fine yoice. of excellent.quality and his tasteful rendering was much
                    appreciated. Schumann’s duet “for soprano and tenor “La Danza” was pleasingly he
                    instrumental numbers. were particularly good. Sig. Perdichidis and ig. R..
                    Scinica gave violin, solos in @ manner which was most comméndable. Messtfs. Te:
                    and J. Papasian are worthy of more than passing notice: each worked hard and
                    contributed considerably to thé suecess of the enter- tainment. We congratulate.
                    Signore. Gianni Galletti. Lama, Colella, Romeo, and Onesti, on the excellent
                    progress made by the pupils. </p>
                <cb/>
                <p> COMPANIES IN EGYPT: SUPREME COURT'S DECISIONS. Judge:Cator in the Supreme
                    British Con- sular Court~delivered judgment this morning on the two appeals of
                    the Bourse and Banking Company Ltd against the judgments of the Consular Court
                    given on the 20th November last. The Appeal Court dismissed both appeals and
                    ordered the Bourse and Banking Company to pay the costs in the Court below and
                    on the appeals. </p>
                <p>These decision of the Supreme Court to up- hold the judgments of the lower Court,
                    given on the 20th ulto., are of great importance as all thie numérous limited
                    liabilities companies, registered under the companies Acts, «whose sphere of
                    operations are in Egypt, are now declared to be amenable to the jurisdiction of
                    the British Consular Courts, whether their boards are composed of subjects of
                    foreign Powers or not. In the one case an application was made by an English
                    shareholder of the Bourse and Banking Company of Egypt Limited, represented by
                    Mr. Gooding for the removal of the liquidator, appointed at the meeting of the
                    shareholders and the appointment of a liquidatornominated by the Court. Mr.
                    Devon- shire, who represented the company contended that the court had (4) no
                    jurisdiction onder section 12 of the Order in Council, (2) no jurisdiction in
                    that the circumstances do not admit of same under section 107 of the Order
                    unless, under section 167, the Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs should
                    make an order covering a case where the circumstances do not permit. </p>
                <p>The Court held that the question at issue fell Within jurisdiction as the
                    plaintiff isa British subject and the defendant compuny of the same
                    nationality,whereby the Mixed Courts could have no jurisdiction. Council for the
                    defence appealed to the Supreme Court, which has now decided that the Court had
                    jurisdiction. </p>
                <p>In the second case, the plaintiff, an English shareholder in the same company,
                    represented by Mr. Reginald Silley, brought an action on the tollowing grounds.
                    The plaintiff had been allotted 200 shares in the Company which he sold at a
                    premium of #5. Subsequently, on the announcement that the bearer warrants were
                    ready, plaintiff applied through the Anglo- Egyptian Bank for delivery of same.
                    He was requested by the company to sign a form in accordance with the
                    regulations of the Alexandria Bourse, or otherwise the company would not make
                    the delivery. The plaintiff filled up the form, expunging the words “according to the Alexandria Bourse require-
                    ments.” Mr. Silley sabmitted that such con-
                    dition in the form was unfair and interfered
                    with ‘the rights of private contract and,
                    therefore, the company is improperly retaining
                    the warrants. Mr. Devonshire, for the company
                    contended that art. 47 of the company’s sta-
                    tutes fully empowered the directors to de-
                    termine the conditions upon which* the bearer
                    warrants should be issued and to settle the
                    form of application for the same. The. lower
                    Court held that the directors were not justified
                    in attaching such condition and gaye judg-
                    ment for the plaintiff for the delivery
                    of the warrants or £200 and costs. The
                    Bourse and Banking Company, appealed
                    against this decision, but, as already announ-
                    ced, the Supreme Court dismissed the appeai.
                    
                    The full bearings of these decisions will be
                    considered in another issue.</p>
                <p>THE KHEDIVE </p>
                <p>Sir-Eldon Gorst was received in audience by the Khedive on Saturday morning and
                    his Highness also granted audicaces to Lemaire Bey. Crookshank Pasha, Mr.
                    Pacliano, Rouma- nian Consul General, Mr. Smyrnoff, Russian Diplomatic Agent,
                    ‘who introduced Prince Mi- chael Gortchacoff, Chevalier Serra, Italian acting
                    Diplomatic Agent, who introduced Mr, Pan] Brenna, Count Bernsdorff, German
                    Diplo- matic Agent, Dr. von Campe and Mattre Carton de Wiart.</p>
                <p> PILGRIMS AT BEYROU®P. </p>
                <p>‘DISTINGUISHED PASSENGERS. (FROM uUR OWN CORRESPONDENT. )</p>
                <p>                                                Beyrout, December 12. The
                    Khedivial Mailliner S.8. “Tantah’ arrived yesterday from Constantinople with a
                    contin- gent of pilgrims for Mecca among whom were the following distinguished
                    personages: the mother of the present Shah of Persia, Sultan Mobam- med Ali, and
                    his brother Prince Nasreddine Mirza, with a large retinue of Ulemas etc. The
                    Prince is only eleven~ years of age and is said to be endowed with remarkable
                    intelligence. After the official visits to the Seraglio and the Per- sian
                    Consulate General, his Highness stopped: with his mother as honoured guests at
                    the Vali’s residence for the night and then proceeded by the some boat next day
                    toCaiffa,where they are to take the Hedjaz Railway for the sacred towns. The S;.
                    “Tantah” took from Beyrout 315 pilgrims. </p>
                <cb/>
                <p>EGYPTIAN’ POLITICS. </p>
                <p>THE REPUBLICAN PARTY. </p>
                <p>The formation of an. Egyptian, Repebliean Nationalist party is still exciting a
                    good deal of discussion, for the demand for thé’ immedia te constitution of an’
                    antonomous’ automatic, and independent republic of Egypt has at- tracted a good
                    deal of notice. A vernacular contemporary remarks :— </p>
                <p>It appears now that. the leader of this. new movement is an editor. who acted as
                    assistant and counsellor to thesupposed leader. of the Egyptian Liberals. Well,
                    liberalism bas in many ¢éases led to republicanism and even to socialism, and we
                    are .in the same boat with other nations. But who is the candidate for the
                    presidency according to present arran- gements?</p>
                <p> THE COPTIC. PARTY </p>
                <p>“Al Watan,” the Coptic Cairo organ, in’a notice of the Coptic party, says :— ~
                    The coptic party was given® the death blow by the refusal of “Al-Watan” to”
                    work=for ite constructions; Yet some:individuals talk ofits coming formation and
                    say that it will not insiat upon the public useof the ancient Coptic language as
                    the basis-of its political mission.</p>
                <p> THE NATIONALIST EXTREMISTS.
                    
                    The general assembly of the active-members
                    of the National Party will take place atthe
                    “Lewa” office on Friday the 27th. inst) in
                    order to select. the committee of direction: and
                    to approve the statutes. “Our Direetor,” says
                    the “Egyptian Standard,” “will deliver-an im«
                    portant political discourse. on the-occasion.”
                    
                    PARTY OF THE PEOPLE.
                    
                    A Cairo correspondent writes :—
                    
                    Great indignation has been aroused among.
                    the various political parties in Cairo atthe,
                    news that Abdul Razik Pasha has had a mani-,
                    festo published in the London “Standard,”
                    outlining the aims of the Party of the People.
                    The other parties of “‘Nationalistic” proclivities,
                    recognise that the handful of political busy-
                    bodies in England, who take an interest.in,
                    Egypt, will soon be so confased as to the state
                    of affairs here that they will be quite unable to
                    know which ‘Party’ topatronise. The Moderate
                    Nationalists and the Egyptian Liberals have:}
                    each had various maniféstoes published in the,
                    London newspapers and now that the Party of
                    the People has secured a footing in the English;
                    Press, it will be difficult for the Radi¢als to.
                    distinguish one party from the other, especially
                    as they are all, collectively and individually,
                    anathematised by Mustapha Pasha Kamel. The
                    leader of the Nationalist Extremists is very,
                    much chagrined at Abdul Razik Pasha’s in
                    auguration of a forward policy in the London
                    Press, for not only hus he lost the’ patronage
                    of Mr. Robertson, M:P.~ and’ Aborigines Pro-
                    tection Society, but he has seen his influence
                    in England undermined by the Moderates and
                    the recent’ foundation of the party of the
                    Constitutional Reformers-has: still further in-
                    creased his vexation. NoW.even the Party of
                    the People, which he always affected to despise,
                    has gained a hearing. in Exgland and of eourse
                    every tresh party helps to diminish his in-
                    fluence as the sole and supreme head of the
                    National Movement.</p>
                <p> MIXED COURTS. a </p>
                <p>EGYPT'S TRADE ae _ NOVEMBER CUSTOMS RETURNS. | Daring: last modth the value of
                    goods.imm. ported into Egypt was L.E. 2,544,870, being LE. 373,909 more than,
                    November 1906, while for, the eleven. months’ period with: an import value of
                    L.E. 23,669,152 an increase of LE 2,818,004 is shown. Last. month the exports
                    totalled: L.E. 4,414,418 against L.E.8,944,994 during N
                    ovember:1906,-and:'since-the ist of January b. B:24;145, 178 against L.
                    E.20;587,162. ; Classitying ‘the various imports and exports we get. the
                    following figures for the eleven months :— Animals and animal foods—Imports L.E.
                    1,166:964"; Exports L.E. 110,853 Skins and works in skins. Imports L.E. 427,708
                    ; Exports L.E. 138,798. Other animal. products—Imports L E.84,929: Exports LE.
                    99,397. Cereals, vegetables, and corns. — Imports LE. 2,690,680 ; Ex
                    L.E..2,753,601, Colonial :roots..and drugs. — Imports L.E.. 681,5025 Exports
                    L.E. 106,278. Spirits, liquors, and oils, — Imports L.E. 1,031,402; Exports LE.
                    12,482. -Chiffons, papers, and books: — Imports LE. 867,628; Exports L.E.
                    18,129. Wood and coal, — Importa 2,984,045; Ex. ports of wood L.E.,16,489,
                    Stone,.earth,. vessels, glasses,,and crystals.— Imports 1.E.:702,022; Exports
                    L.E:'4,888. Tinetures and colours. — Imports LE. 250,599-; Exports L.B~21,728:
                    Chemical. and méditinal. products and per- fomes:— Imports LE: 708,841; Exports
                    L.E. 26;991. Textile industries. — Imports L.E. 6,409,373; Exports (cotton.
                    included) L.E. 20,398,829 Metals -and work in metal: — Imports -L.E. 3,652,154;
                    Exports L.E.' 3,416. Various ‘articles. — Imports L:E. 1,867,830; Exports
                    L.E..75,849. Taking the tota] imports and eaports for the principal countries
                    from January 1 to Novem- ber 30, 1907 we having the following figures: —.
                    England—Imported L E. 7,798,626, Export- ed L.E. 12,942,960. France-Imported LE
                    2,901,048.; Exported L.E. 1,188,704 Turkey-——Imported L.E..2,706,632; Exported
                    L.E. 316,171, Austro-Hungary-—Imported L.E. 1,916,211 ; Exported’ L.B.
                    1,185,920. Germany-—Imported ‘L.E. 1,270 ; Exported L.E. 2,027,512. :
                    Italy—Imported LE. 1,242,594; Exported L.E. 682,503. 5 Russia —Imported L.E.
                    589,756; Exported LE. 1,880,376. » Greece—Imported L. By 311,237 ; LE.
                    20,466,</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"> 
                
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"> 
                
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"> 
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
