<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor> Robert Klein</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-09-09"> January 30, 2020</date>
                    <gloss>1</gloss>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-02"><name>Tuesday</name>, September 02,
                        1907</date>
                    <extent><measure unit="pages" quantity="6">6</measure> pages</extent>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <div type="nameplate">
                    <table cols="6">
                        <row>
                            <!-- paste left top ad in first cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-etc01">
                                <p>The Eastern Telegraph Company, Limited.</p>
                                <p>To secure quick transmission, telegrams should <lb/>be marked <hi
                                        rend="italic">Via Eastern</hi>.</p>
                                <p>For latest average time to London, see daily <lb/>bulletin in
                                    this paper.</p>
                                <p>STATIONS IN EGYPT: Alexandria, Cairo, <lb/>Suez, Port-Tewfik,
                                    Port-Saïd, Suakin. Head <lb/>Office. London.</p>
                            </cell>
                            <cell cols="4">THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</cell>
                            <!-- paste right top ad in third cell -->
                            <cell rows="2" xml:id="deg-ad-nll01">
                                <p>NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</p>
                                <p>BREMEN.</p>
                                <p>EXPRESS MAIL STEAMERS<lb/>FROM<lb/>ALEXANDRIA, PORT SAID, AND
                                    SUEZ,<lb/>TO<lb/>NAPLES, MARSEILLES,<lb/>GENOA, SOUTHAMPTON,
                                    ANTWERP,<lb/>BREMEN, HAMBURG, AMERICA,<lb/>EASTERN ASIA,
                                    AUSTRALIA Etc.</p>
                                <p>For Particulars see Advertisement below.</p>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> No. <measure quantity="7239">7,239</measure>]</cell>
                            <!-- Enter issue number -->
                            <cell> ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905.</cell>
                            <!-- Enter date -->
                            <cell> [SIX PAGES</cell>
                            <!-- Enter number of pages -->
                            <cell> P.T. 1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <cols n="3"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <!-- insert first ad here -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head> ORIENT-ROYAL MAIL LINE.</head>
                    <p>OUTWARD 10 8.M.. Orotavu will leave Snes about September 67 Orontes will
                        leave Buck about September 70</p>
                    <p>HOMEWARD to NAPLER, MARSEILLES, GIBRALTAR PLYMOUTH. LONDON, TILBURY. R.M.R.
                        Mutlader will leave Port Said Sept 10 | R.M.A. Ortons will love Port
                        Said</p>
                    <p>Sept 24 Septal redwood rates turing sur mer season (12th May-15th September)
                        as follows: Puma Naples</p>
                    <p>Marcolina. Plymouth</p>
                    <p>or Tilbury. The summer fares are neté bnt passenger travel Ist Class
                        £7.14.0</p>
                    <p>£11.0. C</p>
                    <p>£ 15.8.0 ling at these rates, and returning within 6 months 5.10.0 7.14.0</p>
                    <p>9.18.01| at the winter rate, will obtain an abatement of 20 % ind</p>
                    <p>3.0.0 4.0.0</p>
                    <p>7.0.0 | off the first and second class winter rate. . Agente, Carso, THOMAS
                        COOK &amp; Son, Id. 3. ALBANDU: B.J. MOBB &amp; Co. For all information
                        apply to Wm. STAPLEDON &amp; Sons, Pont Sam a Pon Towns (free), 11-13-4</p>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BIBBY LINE TWIN-SCREW MAIL STEAMERS.</head>
                        <p>OUTWARDS to COLOMBO, TUTICORIN, oto., and RANGOON. 8.8 Choshino, 5,775
                            tons will leave Snez about September 12 b.</p>
                        <p>HOMEWARDS TO MARSEILLES Ad LONDON. 8.8 Herefordshin, 7,182 tode, will
                            leave Port Said about September 16th. IPEDIAR MEDVODE FARES DURING THE
                            SUMMER SLASON.</p>
                        <p>19-991 May 26th September 30th inclusive.. Fares from Port Said to
                            Marocillos £8.0.0; London £12.0.0 ; Colombo £32.10.0; Rangoon
                            £37.10.0</p>
                        <p>Fitted with Refrigerators, Electric Light, Electric Fans and all recent
                            improvements.</p>
                        <p>Agents in CAIRO: THOR. 000K &amp; Son, Ltd. For all partieulan apply to
                            Wm. STAPLEDON</p>
                        <p>Sono PORT SAID</p>
                        <p>PORT TOWER(Quer)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KHEDIVIAL MAIL LINE.</head>
                        <p>st British Passenger Steamers. GREECE-TURKEY MAIL SERVICE Express steamer
                            loave Alexandria wookly us under for PIRÆUS (Athone), SMYRNA, MITYLENE,
                            and CONSTANTINOPLE,</p>
                        <p>In conneotion with the Oriental Railway Express Service for VIENNA,
                            BERLIN, PARIS &amp; LONDON. S.S. Oomanleh,</p>
                        <p>Wednesday 4 p.m. July 17, 31, August 14 and 28. 8.8. Tomailla,</p>
                        <p>Wednesday 4 p.m. July 10, 24. August 7 and 21. PALESTINE-SYRIA MAIL
                            SERVICE.-The fast steamers Assouan, Minieh and Menzaleh leave Alexandria
                            alter.</p>
                        <p>unfortunately on Saturdays at 4.p.m. for Jaffa (for Jerusalem), Caitts
                            (for Nazareth), Beyrouth (for Damascus), Tripoli, Alexandretta, and
                            Mersina calling fortnightly at Larnaca (Cyprus) and continuing from
                            Beirut</p>
                        <p>in alternate weeks to Rhodes, Smyrna, Mitylene, Dardanelles, Gallipoli
                            and Constantinople. SUDAN DIRECT MAIL SERVICE.-The mail steamers
                            Dakahlia and Kosseir leave Suez alternately on Wednes</p>
                        <p>days at 6 p.m. for Port Sudan and Suakim in connection with the Sudan
                            Government Railways express</p>
                        <p>service to Khartoum. RED OLA COASTING MAIL SERVICE.-Mail steamers leave
                            Suez on Mondays at 5 p.m. for Tor (for' Sinai</p>
                        <p>Yambo and Jeddah, continuing in alternate weeks to Port Sudan, Suakim,
                            Maasowah, Hodeidah and Aden For further information refer to the Coi's
                            Agencies at Alexandria, Cairo, Port Said, Suer or to Thos. COOK</p>
                        <p>&amp; Son (Egypt) Ltd., HAMBURG-AMERIKA REISE-BUREAU or other Tourist
                            Agencies</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DEUTSCHE LEVANTE-LINIE.</head>
                        <p> Mail and Passenger Steamship. Regular Service fortnightly from HAMBURG ;
                            weekly from ANTWERP ; every 4 weeks from BORDEAUX direct to ALEXANDRIA;
                            homewards every 2 weeks from 'ALEXANDRIA for ROTTERDAM and HAMBURG.
                            Goods forwarded at through-rutos from all German Railway Stations on
                            direct Bills of Lading to ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, SYRIA, eto. Special
                            facilities for John</p>
                        <p>e of cotton, eto from Alexandria via Rotterdam and Hamburg to German
                            manufacturing towie.</p>
                        <p>Expected at Alexandria : September 6th 9.8. Rhodos from Hamburg, bound
                            for Rotterdam and Hamburg.</p>
                        <p>8.8. Samos, now in port discharging.</p>
                        <p>tarif and particulars apply to ADOLPHE STROSS, Alexandria Agent.*
                            15-9-907</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> Moss S.S.Company,Ltd.</head>
                    <p>For LIVERPOOL Calling at MALTA (Mouers, JAMES MOSS &amp; Co., 81, Jamer St.,
                        Liverpool, Managers.) Amata........ Tona 4,000 1 'Thephren ....... Tons
                        5,000 Muerte........... Tons 7,500 Bastris</p>
                    <p>* . * ,VODI NURO</p>
                    <p>,000 Boti................... Tons 5.000 Karak.. ***</p>
                    <p>Coneptha 6,000 Komed00 **</p>
                    <p>3,000 "Becend class accommodation only, unless specially reserved. Faree:
                        Alexandrin to Liverpool, lat £14 Bingle, R26 Return Ind, £9 Bingle, k16
                        Return,-To Msita, 1st, 26 Bingle, £9 Return. Ind, 23 Bingle, 26 Betar, --
                        Return tickets available for six months Through trett man on cotton, etc.,
                        to Lancashire inland towns, Boston, New York and other U.B.A. towns,
                        obtained on Applier tion. Cargo taken by special agreement only. Passenger
                        Tickets also issued inclusive of Railway fare through to and from Ostro.
                        11-11-000</p>
                    <p>For particulars apply R. J. MOSS &amp; Co. Alexandris Agenta.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>For particulars apply R. J. MOSS &amp; Co. Alexandris Agenta.</head>
                    <p>P. HENDERSON &amp; CO's LINE.</p>
                    <p>The Stormers of this Lane leave Suez and Port Said every fortnight for
                        Algiers and London ur Liverpool</p>
                    <p>Saloon Fare £12. Special Summer season rates £10 Port Said to Marseilles £7.
                        8.B, TENASSERIM Tons 7100 will leave PORT SAID about 1st September for Dover
                        » AMARAPOORA 6600</p>
                    <p>»</p>
                    <p>17th Sept for Dover Due In London or Liverpool in 13 days. The Saloon
                        accommodation is amidships, and the vessels are fitted throughout with
                        Electric Light and have all the latest improvements.</p>
                    <p>For further information apply to the Company's Agents, WORMS &amp; Co., Port
                        Sald and Suer. THOS. COOK &amp; SON (EGYPT) LD., Catro, G. J. GRACE &amp;
                        Co., Alexandria 81-12-906 </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EXPRESS NILE STEAMER Co.</head>
                    <p> Cairo-Luxor Tourist Service-Luxor-Assouan Express Service.</p>
                    <p>Quick Freight Service ALEXANDRIÀ - CAIRO. 062 For Bookings and Particulars
                        apply : CAIRO OFFICES, 19, CHAREH-EL MADABEGH.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Cunard Line</head>
                    <p>Sailings from LIVERPOOL to New York and Boston every Saturday and alternate
                        Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>Royal Mall Steamer LUCASIA and Campania fastest British steamers. Lusitania
                        and Mauretanin, 32500 tons, largest vessels in the world. CARONIA and
                        Carmania latest and most luxurious Hotels afloat.</p>
                    <p>Regular Sailings between TRIESTE, FIUME, NAPLES and NEW YORK by twin screw
                        steamers. Excellent passenger accommodation</p>
                    <p>Through tickets from Egypt delivered by Messrs, RODOCANACHI &amp; Co.,
                        Alexandria, General Agents ; NICOLAS KIRZIS, Cairo ; R. BROADBENT, Port Said
                        and all Offices of Messrs. THOS COOK &amp; SON 19-1-907</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANQUE DU CAIRE, LIMITED,</head>
                    <p>CAIRO,</p>
                    <p>CAPITAL: Latg. 600,000. The Banque du Caire Ltd., undertakes all banking
                        business such as : Advances on deeds and securities, discount, cheques
                        delivered at very best rates of exchange on all the principal towns of the
                        world, telegraphic transfers, purchase and sale of stock and shares in Egypt
                        and abroad, letters of credit issued, safe custody at a low charge, of
                        titles, deeds and securities, current accounts opened. Receives money on
                        deposit at sight at 3 % per annum.</p>
                    <p>30014-1444-908</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KHEDIVIAL HOTEL, ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>First-class Hotel, Situated in Rosetta Avenue, the finest quarter in the
                        Town. Renovated Throughout Two minutes from Railway Station. Close to
                        Consulates and Opera House, Electric Lift. Perfect Sanitary Arrangements.
                        Magnificent Ball, Reception, Reading, and Music Rooms. Bar and Smoking
                        Room.</p>
                    <p>FINE TERRACE ON THE AVENUE. MOTO MEETS ALL TRAINS AND STEAMERS. WANACER F.
                        REINSPERCER. 81-8"</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THOS. COOK &amp; SON (EGYPT) Lm</head>
                    <p>(EGYPT) LTD</p>
                    <p>Hond Oem.; LUDGATE CIRCUS, LONDON. CHIEF EGYPTIAN OFFICE:- CAIRO, NEAR
                        SHEPHEARD'S HOTEL</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Port Said, Suez, Luxor, Assuan, Halfa and Khartoum. CENTRAL
                        RAILWAY AND STEAMSHIP ACCENTS. BANKERS.</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">BAGGAGE AND FORWARDING AGENTS. Officially appointed &amp;
                            Sole Agents in Cairo to the P, &amp; 0,8, N. Co.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>RESIDENTS IN EGYPT proceeding to Europe for the summer are requested to apply
                        to our offices for information respecting their passages, where steamer
                        planı may be consulted, and Berths secured by all Lines of Steamers to all
                        parts of the Globe; arrangements can also be made for the collection and
                        forwarding of their baggage and clearance at port of arrival.</p>
                    <p>CIRCULAR NOTES issued payable at the current rate of exchange in all the
                        principal cities of Europe.</p>
                    <p>Cook's Interpreters in uniform are present at pripoipal Railway Stations and
                        Landing places in Europe to assist passengers bolding their tickets.</p>
                    <p># Large and splendidly appointed steamers belonging to the Company leave
                        Caire thrive weekly, between November and March, for Luxor, Assocan, and
                        Wady Halfa in connection with trains de Joxe to Kba:tonm. Moderate
                        fares.</p>
                    <p>FREIGHT SERVICE. Steamers leave Cairo overy Priday for Assopan and Half
                        Spoolal combined rail and steamer Nllo Tours at greatly reduced prloor.</p>
                    <p>Speelal Stormers and Dahabeahs for Private Parties, Special arrangements for
                        tours in Palestine, Syria, and the Desert, Lowest rated</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">BEST AWP EQUIPMENT IN TAI COUNTRY,</hi>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <!-- COLUMN ENDS HERE -->
                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>British
                        India.. N. Company, Limited.</head>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>Fortunately service in connotation with the Co's Indian Med</p>
                    <p>Olta st ADO, COLOMBO, MA ORAS, and ALOUATTA Out, and MARSEILLE (MOA ad
                        PisMOUTH optional) Home</p>
                    <p>from Bue OUTWARD. - Dunera September 14 | HOMBKARD. - Thilwara</p>
                    <p>September 9 EAST AFRIOAN LINE OF STEAMERS.. Calling at Adon, Mombaan, Sandhar
                        and Bein. Monthly service.</p>
                    <p>228, 6 Osleutta... 284. 21 Marseilles............. 817.. Piret Olie Pures
                        from Buen to Bombay...</p>
                    <p>22.13 depos....... 314.17 234.18 Women</p>
                    <p>London. ******</p>
                    <p>I Landhar...u Prom Port Bald n les Homeward, and</p>
                    <p>ond Okas, two thirds of Ist Class Pares. PORT SAID Agenta: Norma &amp;00. And
                        will do</p>
                    <p>EXAN OBTA - Tbos Cool &amp; Son, Lad., and AngloAmerican colo</p>
                    <p>r e pardoule</p>
                    <p>Oolombo</p>
                    <p>220.18</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANCHOR LINE,
                        LIMITED.</head>
                    <p>LONDON</p>
                    <p>(HENDERSON BOTTLES, LONDON, LIVERPOOL AND GLASGOW. Booking Padsongens nad
                        Part taronga to Porto in India, Europe and America</p>
                    <p>First Class Pesonge steamore Saling fortnightly from Sues, For MARINA LIAHOOL
                        1.1. Ciro Madla Bop 11 For CALCUTTA SS. "Assyria" Lept. September 18 ror
                        BOMBAY</p>
                    <p>Sept. 11 Summo atos up to the 31st October FARRS PROM : Port Said t Marseille
                        € 8. 10.6.- to London &amp; Liverpool 418.4 0 - Kad ei to shove fare for
                        passengers from Ogiro, Ismailin, or Buen. Redneed rate in stemmers not
                        carrying Surgeon And stewardess.</p>
                    <p>18-19-2007 Agente Claro, TNOS. COOK &amp; son, Fort-Bald: CORY BROTHERS &amp;
                        Co. - for particular apply CC. BEYTS &amp; Co., </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> DEUTSCHE OST
                        AFRIKA LINI E.</head>
                    <p>Regelmässiger Reichspost Dampflopst, German E. African Line. Imperial
                        Service. Departures from Port Said. (Approximate daten). OUT to den,
                        Zanzibar, Cape Town and intermediate ports - 8.8. Markgraf</p>
                    <p>ppt, 20 S.S. Panzessin</p>
                    <p>Sept. 11 HOME to Naples, Marseilles, Tangier Lisbon, Dover, Flushing,
                        Hamburg. 8.8. König</p>
                    <p>ept. 141</p>
                    <p>S.S. Burgermeister October 5 First class steamers fitted with latest
                        improvements. Stewardesses and doctors carried. Low passage raten.</p>
                    <p>Splendid accommodation for passengers of all classes. For particulars apply
                        to Fix &amp; David, Ciro Sharia Mansour Parha. Telephone 865).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Messageries
                        Maritimes</head>
                    <p>Trou Morandria</p>
                    <p>1 August 107 For Marolles ains</p>
                    <p>Rates of DAGING. mo. 9 August St 4 p.m.. Capt. Henrie</p>
                    <p>Including table wine August p.m.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Since from Alexandria airPort Brid 96 August at 6 p.m.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Casanova</p>
                    <p>(directly or vis Alexandris) lut Ola n d 29 August 34 p.m.</p>
                    <p>- Capt. Oonret</p>
                    <p>To Parallels.. * * * 30 August at 4 pm Congo O apt. Baretge Tor Port Said and
                        path</p>
                    <p>From Alexandria Thursday 8 Angrist at m.m. Portugal dept. Ons nova i to Port
                        EAA .. . . 1.16.10 11.10 Thursday 23 August 8 sm. Congo Capt. Baretge</p>
                    <p>For Port Said, van was Beyrouth Thursday 16 August ...m. Rywaten Capt.
                        Couret</p>
                    <p>To Beirut Thursday 29 August Wim. Oronoque Capt. Lansinoh brough title for
                        Parlia (v Marcellles from Alexander Through tickets for Paris (wie Manoila)
                        trom per directly or in Alexand</p>
                    <p>. . )</p>
                    <p>. . . . -</p>
                    <p>16.11 * 1. I Through tlacoyos for London (vio Martellen (</p>
                    <p>Onto Douvre from Alexandria or Purt skal (directly or via Alondra)</p>
                    <p>10.12.10 . 11. .. Interchangeable return tiekate with the Antrian Lloyd Cy.
                        (available one mwy by Kesagerie Maristan and on retain by ADACHAD Lloyd)
                        (vla Trieste)</p>
                    <p>2.11.10 . 16.11 Ballinn en Port Said to August, 1907 Probably on Thursday 1
                        Angnat Caledonien Uapt Compet earning from Indian Down Weldowane</p>
                    <p>Chins for Marseille</p>
                    <p>பெகம் -</p>
                    <p>Tutian Oost Direct.</p>
                    <p>Sunday 78</p>
                    <p>Dumbea . Beyor</p>
                    <p>blus Thursday</p>
                    <p>Adour Rechensur</p>
                    <p>A quatrain # Ibursday</p>
                    <p>Riquier Salling from Sues ta August 1907. For Aden, Colombo, Singapore,
                        salgon, Hong Kong. Bao-Saturday 28 August Nora</p>
                    <p>Ompt. Sebaita ghal. Kobe and Yokohama For Djibouti, Colombo, Singapore,
                        Saigon, Hong-Kong, Bhan-la</p>
                    <p>Saturday</p>
                    <p>. Hal, kobe and Yokohama ***</p>
                    <p>Veron * For Djibouti, Zansibar, Mantaman, Mayotte, Majang</p>
                    <p>Friday</p>
                    <p>Natal Nonstop-Bé, D.Bures, Tamatave, La Réunion and Mauries</p>
                    <p>Kachnster Por Djibouti, Aden, Mabe,Diogo-Buerote Marie, Tamatano) Want to</p>
                    <p>Melbourne</p>
                    <p>Lacarrière Réunion And Maurico . Por Aden, Bombay, Oolombo, Freemantle,
                        Adelaids,</p>
                    <p>Monedas Pennies</p>
                    <p>Magnen bourne, Sidney, and Noumen</p>
                    <p>Otro conoy (Shepheard's Hotel)</p>
                    <p>2,800</p>
                    <p>3,160</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Prince..
                    Calabrian Prince </head> <p> (bldg). Tons 11,000 Thonn Prince (bldg)... Tons 13,000
                        Flemish Prince (bldg)... Tons 10,28 Corsican Prince............ 10.250</p>
                    <p>aleb Prino. *************</p>
                    <p>Norse Prino...**** Afgban Prince..........</p>
                    <p>ok Prince...-******</p>
                    <p>Arriona Prince....</p>
                    <p>bA Tudor Prino,</p>
                    <p>row Prineo... .</p>
                    <p>Lazon Prince....*********** Norman Prinoo......*******</p>
                    <p>tesprian Prinoo *******</p>
                    <p>Itatan Prince... .** Verohant Prince..**.** Trojan Prince.. **********</p>
                    <p>Ballor P000..</p>
                    <p>ge Soldier Prince... Ruso Prinoo...*********</p>
                    <p>Georton Prince... Spartan Prince</p>
                    <p>4,860 Slollinn Prince.... **</p>
                    <p>Modern Prince..... Napolitan Prince......... 4,000 Moorish
                        Prince....--**-**.</p>
                    <p>hland Prince.... . Imperial Prince.........</p>
                    <p>3,760 CLStAllan Prince...********</p>
                    <p>3.100 Dritte Prino...Grecian Prinoo......</p>
                    <p>Creole Prince............</p>
                    <p>3,100 Carto Prince..***.* Eastern Prince.......</p>
                    <p>3,100 Alatio Prinde....*..***</p>
                    <p>Per dan Prince...... Kamr Prince...********** 3.650 prian
                        Prince....*********</p>
                    <p>2,760 Syrian Prince.... . Orange Prince.........</p>
                    <p>2,860 Roma Principe</p>
                    <p>Indian Prince.. Soottish Pride.</p>
                    <p>Royal Prince..... . Good passenger accommodation. – O. J. GRACE &amp; Co.,
                        Alexandria, Agents. Bailings every 10 days from Vanchester und Liverpool and
                        fortnightly from Antwerp and London to audria and Syrian Const the data
                        around approximate British Prince due from Manchester Sept : Syrian Prince
                        due from Manchester Sept: Fgyptian Prince die from Manchester Sept. 7 Indian
                        Prince die from Dunkirk &amp; Antwerp Sept. 2 Highland Prince due from
                        Antwerp &amp; London Sept. 16 Trojan Prince die from Antwerp &amp; London
                        Sept. 29</p>
                    <p>The 8.8. Persian Prince is now Loading for Manchester, and will be followed
                        by the 8.8 Asiatic Prince.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Asia Minor
                        S.S. Co. Ltd.</head> <p>SAILINGS TO CYPRUS AND SYRIAN COAST.
                    Especially LOW RATES. Fur particulars apply Manager, 3 St. Mark's-8t.,
                        Alexandria, or Messrs. Thos. Cook &amp; Son (Egypt) Ltd. Ellermane</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Ellerman's
                        CITY LINE </head><p>| The undermentioned First Class Passengeten mere will be
                        dispatched from Behind on or about the following date. London
                        ....................... 8.8. CITY OF ATHENS Sept. 10th ornare liverpool 8.8.
                        TRAFFORD HALL P .)
                    Oet. Ind Bombay Orloutta. ..................... 8.8, CITY OF CORINTH</p>
                    <p>Karaoke</p>
                    <p>8.8, OITT OY YORK Cot.</p>
                    <p>CITY &amp; HALL LINE</p>
                    <p>Bahay or Kamahl, £27 10,0 ponial furonore not carrying Doctor Newardesor for
                        keeping CORY BROB. &amp; Co., Ltd., Agents for City Line, Port Said : 1,
                        STAPLEDON &amp; Son, Agent or HALL Line, Port Baid ; or COOK &amp; Bow
                        (Egypt). Ltd., Owlro.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SUDAN
                        GOVERNMENT RAILWAYS.</head>
                    <p>SUMMER SERVICE FROM APRIL 1877 UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE Express 2 Blow</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">т</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>рговом о. 8an, and Wodn... Sat. and Tues</p>
                    <p>art Osiro</p>
                    <p>Bus. and Woda, 7.86 m Tues. ad Satur. 7.0 Mon. and Thun Bun. And Weds. 6.40
                        pm</p>
                    <p>Shells part Be And Tue 0.</p>
                    <p>4 m . Mon. and Prid. Mon. And Thurs. Bun. And Wedn. 7 p part Shell</p>
                    <p>arrive Bot and fuel. Ium. Mon. and Iris Wedn. and Bat. Wedn. and Bat. 11 cm .
                        Half</p>
                    <p>depart Thur. an ad Bun, about midnight Sat and Wed. Wednesdays and Saturdays
                        ... * p.</p>
                    <p>part Hata Ariya Thurays and Sundays</p>
                    <p>10.1 Thursdays and Sundays ... 1.10 m. part Abu Hamad depart Thursday and
                        Sundays</p>
                    <p>12. Thursdays and Bundayat... * .. .m. depart Atbans Jen. depart Thun day and
                        Sunday</p>
                    <p>S.10 p. Thursdays and Sundays .....30 pm Iyo Khartoum N. dopart Wedendayet
                        and Saturdays</p>
                    <p>1 Bleeping and Dining Cars. Nors.-Passengers leaving Balts by the rail
                        stormer in connection with wednesday night mail from Khartoum may remain on
                        board in order to travel by the Funday train from Bhe Lal with sleepippud
                        Dining Cor connection at Luxor. 164.00</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROYAL
                        EXCHANGE ASSURANCE.</head>
                    <p>INCORPORATED A. D. 1720. Chief Office: Royal Ohlins,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>London, ASSURANCE CORPERATION</head>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">FUNDS IN HAND EXCELD £4,600.000 - CLAIMS PAID £40,000,000
                            Alexandria ANGLO-EQVPTIAN RANK</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>MARINE</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Mr. J.LOAFTARI Oniro.... Mr. J. DAFTARI</p>
                    <p>Suez, .... Mr. QLO. MEINEKE 21-6-206 Londol</p>
                    <p>ce Corporation. Established 1720.</p>
                    <p>OF EGYPT. Limited</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Northern
                        Fire and Life Assurance Coy</head>
                    <p>The undersigned agents are antborided to issue policies on behalf of the
                        above Company at modanta mte</p>
                    <p>IMPERIAL OTTOMAN BANK, Alexandria. OTTO BTKRZING, Cairo. GEORGE MRINEOKE,
                        8nes.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NATIONAL
                        MUTUAL LIFE ASSOCIATION OF AUSTRALASIA, LTD. Ext. 1869 Funds exceed
                        84,000,000. 3</head>
                    <p>Annual Income exovideo 4700,000. ? S pecial privileges offered to British
                        Naval and Military Officers serving in Egypt or the Soudan. Example of whole
                        Polloy Life.--Age of proposar 30. Sum assured £1,000 with profits payable at
                        death. Annual premium covering war risk and foreign resident€28 : 6:8.</p>
                    <p>HRAD OYYIOR: CAIRO, KHEDIVIAL BXCHANGE COURT</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The
                        Cigaretto. Manufactured by</head>
                    <p>The Cleopatra Cigarette Co.</p>
                    <p>.G. NENOX ano on mon the Company's tablahmoni by mad Continental Hotel,
                        Online</p>
                    <p>PATRONISED by the Sea - OSRAMOT and the Am</p>
                    <p>at the old the</p>
                    <p>evol</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PORT
                        SAID-SAVOY HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>FIRST-CLA88 HOTEL, NRLOOKIN. THE HARBOUR &amp; OPROBITI CESTON HUB</p>
                    <p>Onon all tho your end. Woll-appointed Bar. Electro Light. :) MODERATE
                        CHARGES. SPECIAL TERMS FOR RESIDENTS.</p>
                </div>
                <!-- COLUMN 2 ENDS HERE -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>HAMBURG
                        &amp; ANGLO-AMERICAL, MILE Co.</head>
                    <p>Weekly departure during winter coupon by the LUXURIOUS FIRST CLASS TOURIST
                        STEAMERS." vietoma, Fourtan," and "Cema.</p>
                    <p>REGULAR WEEKLY DEPARTURES TO THE SECOND CATARACT BY THE 88. "NUBEA." THROUGH
                        BOOKINGS TO KHARTOUM, GONDOKORO AND THE WHITE NILI.</p>
                    <p>Steamers and Dahabonba for privata ebarter. Steam Tags and Steam Launch for
                        bin FREIGHT SERVICE BY STEAM BARGES BETWEEN CAIRO AND ALEXANDRIA. Working in
                        conjunction and under special arrangement with the "Upper Egypt Hotels
                        Company." For details and programmen apply to HEAD OTTICH : Sharia Boulaye,
                        Continental Hotel Buildings, CAIRO, </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Hamburg-Amerika Linie.</head>
                    <p>Leaves Port Said Maven Naples Arrives Hamburg 88. Silesia Aug. 10th Aug. 14th
                        Aug. 26th These steamers call also at Plymouth</p>
                    <p>
                        <hi rend="italic">if needed. 8.8. Scandia Sep 7th Sep. 11th Sep. 23rd FARRS:
                            1st class. &amp;rd elsas. 8.8. Habsburg Oct. 5th Oct. 9th Oct. 21At To
                            NAPLE $10.- €2.8.8. Rhenania Nov. 2nd Nov. 6th Nov, 18th To HAMBURO
                            €7.10</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Monthly connections from Port-Said to the ports of the Red Sex and the
                        Persian Gulf. Port Said to Colombo, China and Japan : August 3rd, 8.B.
                        RHENANIA ; Sep. 3rd, 8.8. HOHENSTAUFEN; Oet</p>
                    <p>4th 8.8. SILESIA Nov. 3rd 8.8. SCANDIA.</p>
                    <p>Also occasional sailings from Port-Said to Marseilles, Oran and London. Roomy
                        Cabins-Good Cuisine. Plonor Cruller to loveland, Spitsbergen, Norway,
                        Scotland, etc. during the Summer by the s.s. OORANA,</p>
                    <p>S.S. METEOR and the s.. KRONPRINCESSIN ORCI. VI</p>
                    <p>The 8.8. Oceana will resume the express service between Alexandria and the
                        Continent next October. Apply to: HÁNBURG-AMERICA LINIE, Continental Hotel
                        CAIRO, O.J. GRACE &amp; O... ALEXANDRIA, DEUTSCHES KOHLEN DEPOT, PORT RAID
                        &amp; SUEZ</p>
                    <p>31-11-07</p>
                    <p>during the Summer by the a.s. OORANA</p>
                    <p>The 8.8. Oceana till</p>
                    <p>KONFRINGESSIN ORCILAR. VI</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head
                        >NORDDEUTSCHER LLOYD</head>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA-NAPLES-MARSEILLES. Wookly Departure from ALEXANDRIA (3 p.</p>
                    <p>SONLESWIG : 4, 18 Sept. ; 2, 16, NO October</p>
                    <p>HOHENZOLLERN 35 Sept. 24 October 6 November The following 8.8. are intended
                        to leave PORT SAID R OMEWARD : for BREMEN or HAMBURG</p>
                    <p>via Naples, Canoe (gibraltar ) Southampton Antu Zleten</p>
                    <p>8000 Ton about 7 Sept,</p>
                    <p>1 Tuto Drieb 9000Tong .. about YOU 3 9 000</p>
                    <p>11 Nept Pr. Reg. Luitpold 6300</p>
                    <p>- 29 Sept. Prian Reinrich 6800 OUTWARD for ORINA and JAPAN VI BURZ, ADUN,
                        OUTWARD ; for AUSTRALIA VISUEZ, 4PRK, COLOMBO</p>
                    <p>COLOMBO, PINANG, SINGAPORE. Klolat 9000 Tons ... . about 3 Hept. I</p>
                    <p>8000 Tons ...... about % Sept. Room 8000 18 Sept. Dromen</p>
                    <p>11700 ,</p>
                    <p>18 Oct,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Service
                        Maritime Roumain</head>
                    <p>A</p>
                    <p>16 Rue Berontrie A Quarantine of five days having been imposed by Turkey
                        against animals from Egypt, no departures www take plans until further
                        Notice. Vor particulars apply to the Agents : OTTO STERZING Open Bunn,
                        CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>N MUUT Messrs. THOR, COOK &amp; Son (Egypt) Lid are that t ellu et in
                        DAERO</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WHITE STAR
                        LINE</head>
                    <p>NEW YORK AND BOSTON MEDITERRANEAN SERVICE. Regular sailings between
                        SOUTHAMPTON-HORROR and NEW YORK Vis Queel Weatboud) vis Plymouth (Eastbound)
                        LIVERPOOL and NEW YORK, via Queenstown, LIVERPOOL and BOSTON entown, OHIOA,
                        PALERMO, NAPLES, NEW YORK and BOSTON. Unsurpassed accommodation for all
                        classes of</p>
                    <p>ens, Form of stemmen, rates of page and full particulars, party to THIS. COOK
                        &amp; SON (Karrt) LAD., Oniro, Alexandr Luxor and Amouan; JOHN RONS &amp;
                        Co., Alexandria; WHITE STAR LINE, Vis Roma, Genon, and 21 Piazza della Bor
                        Naples</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PAPAYANNI
                        LINE (FLINEN LAN)</head>
                    <p>Frequent Sailings from ALEXANDRIA to LIVERPOOL. Regular Services from
                        LIVERPOOL to ALEXANDRIA, ALGERIA, MALTA, LEVANT, BLACK BRA, and other
                        Mediterranean ports. Excellent Pamenger Acco nodation. Stewardess carried.
                        Liberal table and Moderate Fares for single and return tickets.</p>
                    <p>CARGO taken by special agreement only. Through Freights quoted for the UNITED
                        STAT INLAND Towns and GREAT BRITAIN. For passage or freight apply BARKER
                        &amp; Co., Agente, Alexandria The 8.8. ALORRIAN now loading will leave for
                        Liverpool in a few days and will be followed by the SABARDINIA</p>
                    <p>174-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ELLERMAN
                        LINES LTD. (INCLUDING WAS</head>
                    <p>Regular sailings from Liverpool, Glasgow, Antwerp and London to Alexandria
                        Pregont milling</p>
                    <p>Ala Andris Liverpool and London. Through freight rates to Inland towns in
                        Great Britain leo to the U.LA</p>
                    <p>TAMVADO, ALEXANDRIA, Agent. Westeott 8.8. "Fabian" expected from Antwerp,
                        London &amp; Malta about 7th Inst, Ellerman S.S. "City of Oxford" expected
                        from Liverpool Gibraltar &amp; Malts about 14th inst. Westeott 8.8.
                        “Barcelona" expected from Antwerp, London and Malta about and in</p>
                    <p>The 8.8. "Avon", now londing for Liverpool will all for that port on 31st
                        Inat,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Russian
                        Steam Navigation Comp</head>
                    <p>Express Service by the following one, new steamers between ALEXANDRIA,
                        PIREUR, CONSTANTINOPIR and ODENSA</p>
                    <p>Emperor Nicola II. Reine Oiga, Tokethat Hof (TOTO tons uncle) and Tsariton
                        (6000 tons) Arrive Alexandris Friday noon, ler ve Alexandris Tuesday, 8 pm.
                        Circular route between Alexandria, Port Said, the Syrian porta, Chio,
                        Smyrna, Salonica, Mount Athos, Dardanelles, Constantinople, and Odessa.
                        Arrive Alexandria alternate Saturdays early morn leaving Alexandria same day
                        at 4p.m. CRIMEAN OR BESSARABIAN TABLE WINES FREE.</p>
                    <p>20876-31-6-60</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Navigation
                        Générale Italon • Sociétés Routes Florio-Rubattino - Services Postaux. -
                        Doparts de Juin.</head>
                    <p>Les JEUDIS 1, 8, 15, 22 et 29 3h p.m. direct pour Messine, Naples, Livourne
                        et Gênes, Les JEUDIS 1 et 158h. pm, direct pour Brindisi, Bari, Ancône et
                        Venise. Les MERCREDIS 7 et 11 10am pour les carales de la Syrie et
                        L'arnaque. Les LUNDIN 194 h. p.m. pour Port-Saïd, Suez et Massaouah. Les
                        Jeudi 1 et SAMEDI 225h. p.m. pour Port-Saïd.</p>
                    <p>31-19-906</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Sun Insurance Office,</head> <p> | LONDON. Founded 1710.- Total sam insured in 1909
                        £487,600,000 | General Agents : BEHREND &amp; Co., Aloxandria. Leon Moller,
                        Cairo Agent. e Lazzerint &amp; Bar, Suor Aceh </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Egyptian
                        Bonded Warehouses Company, Limited,</head>
                    <p>(SOCIÉTÉ DES ENTRECÔTE D'EGYPTE) Bonded Warehouses in Alexandria, Cairo, Port
                        Said and Suez. Special Departments for clearing, and forwarding and for
                        luggage and parool Express Service</p>
                    <p>" and</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Egyptian
                        State Railways</head>
                    <p>are prepared to adopt offers to exhibit FRAMED POSTERS, NOTICES, etc., In and
                        about their STATIONS, at the following rates :=</p>
                    <p>P.T. 60 per square metre per annum at 1st class stations , 40</p>
                    <p>2nd .. „ .15 .</p>
                    <p>Brd a miW (The above includes fixing in position).</p>
                    <p>Danes The stations are divided into three classes according to their value
                        from an advertising point of view.</p>
                    <p>For further information apply to the PUBLICITY SECTION, General Manager Dept.
                        Egyptian State Railways, Cairo.</p>
                    <p>G. B. MACAULEY. Cairo, June 1907,</p>
                    <p>GENERAL MANAGER,</p>
                    <p>907</p>
                </div>
                
         
                <cb n="3"/> <!-- END OF COLUMN 3  -->
            </div>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <div type="page" n="2">
                <!-- page 2 contents -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Royal Insurance Co.</head>
                    <p>FIRE AND LIFE. LARGEST FIRE OFFICE IN THE WORLD</p>
                    <p>d . Agonto, ALEXANDRIA - VITENDO &amp; Bo, Agents, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>Phoenix Assurance Co., Ltd. (Unram.com</p>
                    <p>u</p>
                    <p>l o, Agonite ALBATDRIA.</p>
                    <p>-</p>
                    <p>FRED. OTT &amp; Bo, Sub-Agents, CAIRO.</p>
                    <p>CAIRO,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>N.SPATHIS</head>
                    <p>bor Pacha-ol ALEXANDRIA,</p>
                    <p>Avorofi-et Bode Water, Lomonada, dingor Ale, Qingor Door, Tonie Water,
                        Pomegranate, Orangonde.</p>
                    <p>Ume Juice and Soda, Champagne Cider, Lemon Squash WATER GUARANTEED BY
                        CHAMBERLAINS FILTER (PASTEUR'S SYSTEM.) Inventor of WHISKY • SODA and BRANDY
                        &amp; SODA, bottled ready for use.</p>
                    <p>Sole Agent in Egypt and the Sudan for 4. Car &amp; Co...</p>
                    <p>Bordeaux Wine and Cognacs. Loon No .S.</p>
                    <p>Rheims</p>
                    <p>Champagnes ADOR ENOBI...</p>
                    <p>Wiesbaden Rhine and Moselle Wines. Mon &amp; Co.</p>
                    <p>Glasgow Lagavulin, White Horse Cellar and other Whiskies DOWS' &amp; Co.,
                        Ias.</p>
                    <p>Belfast</p>
                    <p>Old Irish Whiskies W. LANAKAN AND Box...</p>
                    <p>Baltimore Monongahola XXXX Whisky. COOL AND BORN IMAX Co.</p>
                    <p>New York *Old Valley" Whisky "Gold Lion" Cooktail O AND SON * ***</p>
                    <p>London Guinness Stout, Bass Pale Ale Ave MGTOW BRAUHAUS</p>
                    <p>In Peloneta Pilsener Beer ORD BALLON Co.</p>
                    <p>Torine</p>
                    <p>Vermouth, Cette</p>
                    <p>Vermouth and Aperitive MADONNA TE COMPANY, LAD</p>
                    <p>Tess HENDRRSON &amp; Co. CEYLON CORONA TEA. Broat, department of Wino.,
                        Spirito, Liqueurs, Toast of Nnoot brando</p>
                    <p>DRIVEN B</p>
                    <p>POR</p>
                    <p>FOR E</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BON-ACCORD Centrifugal Pumps</head>
                    <p>STEAM, ELECTRICITY, GAS, OIL OR BELT, IRRIGATION, DRAINAGES, DOCKS, etc. HIGH
                        SPEED ENGINES FOR ELECTRIC LIGHTING FAN ENGINES FOR FORORD DRAUGHT &amp;
                        VENTILATION High Lift and Rotary Pumps.</p>
                    <p>Apply in Egypt, Cairo and Alexandria, A. ABOAF &amp; Co. (whore a stock is
                        kopt.)</p>
                    <p>DRYSDALE &amp; Co. Bon - Accord Engine Works, Glasgow.</p>
                    <p>manufacturer,</p>
                    <p>CODES: ABC., LIEBERN, ENGINEERING TELEGRAPH. WRITE FOR CATALOGUE</p>
                    <p>Telephone 2005 NATIONAL YATO CORPORATION</p>
                    <p>E FOR</p>
                    <p>JOSEPH EVANS &amp; SONS</p>
                    <p>CULWELL WORKS. WOLVERHAMPTON,</p>
                    <p>MAKERS OF</p>
                    <p>PUMPS and Pumping Machinery</p>
                    <p>For all Purposes</p>
                    <p>IRRIGATION PUMPS. MINING PUMPS. BOILER &amp; PUMPS COMBINED. CENTRIFUGAL
                        PUMPS. HOUSEHOLD PUMPS. Telegrama: EVANS, Wolverhampton</p>
                    <p>Write for List No.&amp;</p>
                    <p>TRY Howie's Butter</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE FINEST IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>AND IF NOT SUPPLIED</p>
                    <p>APPLY TO JOHN B.OAFFARI</p>
                    <p>Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p>
                    <p>A real boon for BREAKFAST</p>
                    <p>during hot weather. ASK FOR IT, SEE YOU GET IT.</p>
                    <p>Address :-Shubra Road, Oniro.</p>
                    <p>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CARLTON HOTEL BULKELEY (near Alexandria) halfway to San Stefano</head>
                    <p>RAMLEH'S FASHIONABLE HOTEL Pull Pension P.T. 50 a day with Monthly Terms</p>
                    <p>Voltors from already slight at si Baher. Reclame Lunch, P.T. 16. - Dinner,
                        RT.2</p>
                    <p>Proprietor, C. AQUILINA, (late of the Cook Special terms to Government
                        Officials</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHAMPAGNE GEORGE GOULET.</head>
                    <p>BY SPRCIAL APPOINTMENT TO HIS MAJESTY THE KING.</p>
                    <p>REIMS.</p>
                    <p>SOLE AGENT. IN EGYPT AND SUDAN. NICOLA G. SABBAG,</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    <p>2, Rue de la Gare du Caire.</p>
                    <p>Telephone</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WINDSOR HOTEL</head>
                    <p>Pacing the Sea on the New Quay of Alexandria</p>
                    <p>FIRST-CLASS HOTEL. Lately Built and Furnished</p>
                    <p>M. PT. PER DAY.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TUR. EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, SEPTEMBER , 1907.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IND, COOPE &amp; Co., Ltd</head>
                    <p>BREWERS, BURTON-ON-TRENT AND ROMFORD. PALE ALE &amp; DOUBLE STOUT</p>
                    <p>SPECIALLY BREWED FOR EXPORT. Agents :</p>
                    <p>VESSRS JOHN ROSS &amp; Co..</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA OATBO:</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NATIONAL HOTEL, Cairo</head>
                    <p>One of the finest and most up-to-date Hotels in the Metropolis, situated in
                        Shar Soliman Pasha, the very centre of the healthiest and most fashionable
                        quarter. Stands in it own grounds with garden and lawn tennis ground st
                        back. Over 850 rooms and 5 saloon Magnificent salle à manger. Handsome
                        covered promenade verandah, 80 yards long. Higher laos cuisine, electric
                        light throughout, and lifta. English comforts, Booms and apartment at prices
                        to suit every one, More further particulars apply to GENERAL MANAGER,
                        Cala</p>
                    <p>9688980-11-9</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SAVOY PALACE HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA. Re-Open September 1st.</p>
                    <p>29705-4-3-908</p>
                    <p>FIRST CLASS HOTEL.</p>
                    <p>MODERN IN ALL RESPECTS.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EASTERN EXCHANGE HOTEL,</head>
                    <p>PORT SAID.</p>
                    <p>THE COOLEST SUMMER RESIDENCE IN EGYPT.</p>
                    <p>Fire-proof, Drafted to the Sea, Lifts, Electric Light. English and French</p>
                    <p>Billiards, Fresh and Salt-Water Baths.</p>
                    <p>HOTEL DRAGOMANS IN UNIFORM MEET ALL TRAINS AND STEAMERS.</p>
                    <p>Special forms to Outro Residents and their familie desirous of enjoying the
                        cool air and sem bathing during the summer months</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JOHN FOWLER &amp; Co., (LEEDS) LTD</head>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED 1850. THE OLDEST &amp; LARGEST MANUFACTURERS IN THE WORLD ON</p>
                    <p>STEAM PLOUGHING MACHINERY</p>
                    <p>OF EVERY DESCRIPTION AND FOR ALL SOILS.</p>
                    <p>Over 35 years experience IN ALL PARTS OP EGYPT where car steam ploughing
                        tackles are in constant use and giving the greatest satisfaction.</p>
                    <p>The only makers of steam ploughing machinery who manufacture their own STERI
                        WIRB ROPES</p>
                    <p>FOWLER'S STEAM PLOUGHING TACKLES are the strongest, best designed and best
                        proportioned in all their parte, therefore they are the most sconomionl.
                        Experience of over half a century in all parts of the world.</p>
                    <p>ALLEN, ALDERSON &amp; Co., Ltd</p>
                    <p>AGENTS. ALEXANDRIA - CAIRO - KHARTOUM. 99783-14-6-90</p>
                </div>
                <!-- NEW COLUMN -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian Lignolite &amp; Brick Co., Ld.,</head>
                    <p>Undertake and promptly and satisfactorily carry out paving and other kinds of
                        work, in connection with their LIGNOLITE patent process, as used by the War
                        Office, Public Works Department, the Administration of the Sanitary
                        Department, etc., etc.</p>
                    <p>Hygiene, waterproof, incombustible and jointless pavements can be executed in
                        different colours, with fancy borders, etc.</p>
                    <p>MANUFACTURE and SALE of patent H.H.B BRICKS in hydraulic lime and cement For
                        further particulars apply :AT ALEXANDRIA, TO</p>
                    <p>AND AT CAIRO, TO 19 RUE STAMBOUL, Telephone No. 1640, P.O.B. 8ST.</p>
                    <p>RUR RI, MAGHRABY, Telephone No. 808, P.O.B.937.</p>
                    <p>15-8-008</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Notices to Advertiser.</head>
                    <p>( NOTE PAPER WITH STAMPED</p>
                    <p>NISED ADDRESS,&amp;C.</p>
                    <p>COACHES BRASS PLATE ENGRAVER GENERAL SIGNWRITERS ANO LETTER MANUFACTURER</p>
                    <p>The "Egyptian Gazette" has given no advertising agency or company in Egypt
                        any monopoly or exclusive right to act as advertising Agents on its behalf.
                        Advertisements of every description are received at the offices of the
                        "Gazette" from advertisers direct.</p>
                    <p>BULAC ROAD</p>
                    <p>CAIRO</p>
                    <table rows="18" cols="18">
                        <head>NILE GAUGE READINGS</head>
                        <row role="label">
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <!-- made a chart for this section, not sure how to complete it except manually -->
                    <!-- column break -->
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DAILY WEATHER REPORT.</head>
                    <p>ALESSANDRIA</p>
                    <p>Komol-Nadoun Ohernatory</p>
                    <p>North</p>
                    <p>Blight 758.8</p>
                    <p>Direction of wind Force of Anemometer State of Be. Barometer corrected</p>
                    <p>rporation. Stoot Olonde</p>
                    <p>Max. Temp. FS the shade Daring</p>
                    <p>Min. do d o. bonne Humidity of these eding &amp; Am. Hos of the man - --
                        -</p>
                    <p>Clear</p>
                    <p>ria</p>
                    <p>Moon Fee 18.84 p.m. - cele 3.40 p.m.</p>
                    <p>REMARKS There is no change in the weather conditions. The morning opened
                        pleasant with light North bree and a steady barometer.</p>
                    <p>ita</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Calendar of Coming Events</head>
                    <p>d</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDRIA. September Mon. 2 Alhambra Theatre. French Comedy</p>
                    <p>Troupe. "Le Contrôleur des Wagons</p>
                    <p>Lits. San Stefano Casino Grand Symphony</p>
                    <p>Concert Every afternoon at 5.30 p.m Windsor Hotel, Open-Air Concert by the
                        Ladovie-Rivier orchestra 6 p.m. to midnight, Fronton "Jai Alai" Pelote
                        Basque</p>
                    <p>9.30 pm Urbanors Cinematographie Entertain</p>
                    <p>mente. 6,30 and 9.30 p.m. Cinemaphon Aziz and Dorès, old</p>
                    <p>Ramleh Station 6.30 &amp; 9.30. Pathé Cinematographie entertain ment. 6,30
                        and 9.30 p.m. Bains du Mex Balloon Ascents</p>
                    <p>every Thursday, Saturday, and Sunday. Two Orchestras, Last tram 1 a.m. Tour
                        Eiffel. Variety Entertainment</p>
                    <p>9.30. The Lifonti Concert Rooms, Grand</p>
                    <p>Evening Concert, 9.30 p.m. Sat. 7 Alexandria Swimming Club. Boat</p>
                    <p>leaves Marina, 3.15 p.m. Sun. 8 San Stefano Casino Classical Con</p>
                    <p>cert. Pigeon Shooting Club Cabbari.</p>
                    <p>2.30 p.m. Pigeon Shooting. Champs Elysée</p>
                    <p>2.30 p.m. Alhambra Theatre, Matinée. 4.30. Tour Eiffel. Matinée. 4.45.
                        Eldorado. Matinée. 4.30. Cinemaphon Aziz &amp; Dorès. Performances 4.5.30,
                        6.45</p>
                    <p>CAIRO. September Mon, 2 Ezbekieh Gardens Theatre, 6.30.</p>
                    <p>Theatre des Ambassadeurs. 9,30. Tues. 3 Ezbekieh Gardens, Military Band</p>
                    <p>9 to 11. Fri. 6 Ezbekieh Gardens. Military Band</p>
                    <p>9 to 11. Sun. 8 Zoological Gardens. Ghizeh Boys</p>
                    <p>Band. Afternoon.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian
                        Delta Light Railways Ltd.</head>
                    <p>Are prepared to accept tenders for the supply of General Stores during a
                        period of one year commencing from the 1st October 1907. A copy of the
                        schedule and Conditions of Tender can be obtained from the Chief Storekeeper
                        of the Company, Alexandria. Tenders must be received before the 20th.
                        September, 1907.</p>
                    <p>80848-3-3</p>
                    <p>OF THR</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Commercial
                        &amp; Financial Supplement</head>
                    <p>"Egyptian Gazette." The Commercial and Financial Supplement of the "Reyptian
                        Gazette" is published at midday every Saturday in time for the Anaten
                        Lloyd's mail. The supplement contains exhaust ive and important review of
                        the cotton, cotton seed, and stock and share markets, with all the latest
                        statistics up to the evening of the preceding day, complete tabular forms of
                        the various market flotations, and the copies of the official telegrams of
                        the Liverpool Cotton Association, eto, stor. Subscription for one year P.T.
                        100 (inclusive of postage in Egypt</p>
                    <p>). For Partner partial apply to the Manacor the "Reyptian Guetta</p>
                    <p>for abroad the</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>1. Soupoes
                        Krauchambrunnon D'Ems.</head>
                    <p>Are renowned throughout the world for their efficacy in colds and
                        hoarseness:</p>
                    <p>Also the SEL d'EMS and PASTILLES d'EMS taken from these waters.</p>
                    <p>Sent to all parts of the world by RUDOLPH EISFELLER, BAD-EMS.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TheEgyptian
                        Gazette</head>
                    <p>This</p>
                    <p>SUBSCRIPTIONS.</p>
                    <p>Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including delivery in
                        Alexandria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 231% per annum, P.T. 116
                        for six months, P.T. 80 for three months. To</p>
                    <p>there countries in the Postal Union PT. 273 (62.168.) per m x mouths P.T.
                        136) 1.8 l breek</p>
                    <p>P.T.9 019)</p>
                    <p>de mest ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>
                    <p>P.T. 4 per line. Minimum charge P.T. 20. Birthe, Marriage of Deaths, not
                        exceeding three lines, P.T. 20. Every additional line P.T. 10. Notices in
                        news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts etered into for standing</p>
                    <p>advertisements ADVERTISEMENTS and ..</p>
                    <p>. SUBSCRIPTIONS are due in advance. P.O. Orders and Cheques to be made
                        payable to the Editor and Manager, ROWLAND</p>
                    <p>SNELLING, Alexandria. London Correspondent's Offices:-36, New</p>
                    <p>Broad Street, B.O. Cairo Offices: - Telegraph Building Boulao Road (opposite
                        All Saints Church). P. O. B. No. &amp; Telephone</p>
                    <p>No. 878. Head Offices, Alexandria: The Old Bourse Palace (Palais de
                        l'Ancienne Bourse) 6 Rue du Télégraphe Anglais. Telephone Number 242.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>The Egyptian
                        Gazette</head>
                    <p>THE ENGLISH DAILY NEWSPAPER.</p>
                    <p>ESTABLISHED 1800. Editor and Manager - - R SIELLING</p>
                    <p>Price: ONE PIASTRE TARIPR.</p>
                    
                    <p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 2, 1907.</p>
                    
                    <p>THE SOCIALIST CONGRESS.</p>
                    <p>Nervous people who see before them an era ht, in which Socialism, and, by
                        consequence, a</p>
                    <p>grinding and remorseless tyranny, will be supreme, may take some comfort from
                        the proceedings at the Socialist Congress at Stutt: gart. Presumably, the
                        delegates there assembled know something of what Socialism means, or is
                        intended to mean, but it must strike the most casual observer that the
                        moment anyone of them attempts to define any portion of the theory, or to
                        suggest how it should be applied in practice, the rest fall upon him as
                        though he were a hare in a kennel of beagles. Upon such an elementary point
                        as the question whether the perfect Socialist ought to possess any
                        patriotism we have been favoured by Herr Bebel and M. Hervé with a spectacle
                        which certainly proves that some human passions have not been eliminated
                        from their breasts. Upon the question of the Colonial policy of the future,
                        the entire assemblage appears to have been reduced to inarticulate howls,
                        says the "Globe" and so great was the friction engen</p>
                    <p>dered that the very translators lose themselves and the amendment of the
                        French</p>
                    <p>delegates in the amazing confusion. This is no d new thing. It has been
                        characteristic of</p>
                    <p>every Socialist Congress since the Socialist Congresses began, and there is
                        not the smallest reason to suppose that it will not continue as long as they
                        do. Something is, perhaps, to be set down to the undoubted fact that the
                        average Socialist is an unbalanced and excitable person, but that does not
                        fully account for the phenomenon. The plain fact is that the moment an
                        attempt is made by sincere people--and most of the delegates are as sincere
                        as they are wrong headed-to apply the theory of Socialism to practical lite
                        its defects become so apparent that its defenders are at their wit's end to
                        save it. Each clearly perceived the fatal defect in the plans of the others,
                        and is consequently vociferous for his own equally futile panarea. Socialism
                        may be, and is, a serious danger, because of what it threatens to destroy,
                        but it can never be set up as a constructive policy in any civilised country
                        until its adherents can agree among themselves. That, so far, they have
                        shown themselves utterly unable to do.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BERLITZ
                        SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES</head>
                    <p>336 BRANCHES Anglish, French, Arable, Grook, Italien, oto. Private and Class
                        Lessons - Residence Lessons</p>
                    <p>NATIVE MASTERS ALEXANDRIA CAIRO,</p>
                    <p>12 Rue Mootte</p>
                    <p>1 Bear me SUMMER BRANCH. Men</p>
                    <p>TRIAL LESSON FREE.</p>
                </div>
                


            </div>
            
            
            <pb n="3"/>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <div type="item">                <head>LOCAL, AND
                    GENERAL.</head>
                <p>More Shoe Dinner.</p>
                <p>On Saturday the jockeys of the Alexandria Sporting Club and their friends held a
                    dinner at the Abbey hotel, which proved a most enjoyable and sociable meeting.
                    We are, however, compelled to hold over our account thereof until to-morrow as
                    the large amount of copy to hand more than exhausts the space at our disposal.
                    Lost City Found</p>
                <p>. Am Egyptian sun temple and a city that has been lost for 3,300 years have been
                    located by Prof. James H. Breasted of the University of Chicago. It is the
                    temple of Sesebi founded by Amenhotep IV. The city is situated in the heart of
                    the almost inaccessible district of Nubia, near the foot of the third cataract
                    on the Nile Earth Dentistry</p>
                <p>The art of dentistry was practiced among the Egyptians and Etruscans, and
                    there</p>
                <p>the treatment W e</p>
                <p>introduced into America by John Grepuwood, who established himself in New York in
                    1788. In 1790 and again in 1795 he carved in ivory an entire set of teeth for
                    General Washington. Shooting Apollent.</p>
                <p>Yesterday morning about 5 o'clock, a shooting accident took place at Ghémileh. A
                    young European man was shooting quail fired without taking precaution, with the
                    rent that Mr. Edward Vitali an official of the Port Said police, who was in
                    front of him received all the charge in his thigh. M Vitali was immediately
                    transported to the Egyptian hospital, and the imprudent author of the accident
                    placed under arrest to await, establishment of responsibility. The wound is
                    serious and may possibly necessitate amputation. Another Tramway Agoldent</p>
                <p>What might have been a nasty accident occurred this morning about 8.45, at the
                    tramway crossing between the Sporting Club and Camp de Caesar station. A tram,
                    proceeding towns the eity, came into contact with a two-horse arabesk which was
                    endeavouring to cross the line. The driver managed to clear his horses but in so
                    doing the arabia became wedged in between the car and the Tramway Company's
                    kiosk and there was an ominous rending and splitting of wood, the arabah
                    sustaining considerable damage before the car was brought to a standstill. The
                    near hind of one of the horses was twisted up in some of the wreckage and the
                    animal was extricated with difficulty, to all apparel Shops fortunately, not
                    much the worse. A Woman. Anger</p>
                <p>A woman of Russian nationality, paid a visit yesterday to the house of one of her
                    friends in the Rue Telephone, Cairo, where she was cordially welcomed. During
                    the course of their conversation someone knocked at the door, and three young
                    men, friends of the mistress of the house, entered. Middle. As gave visible
                    signs of her annoyance at this interference with her visit, and soon engaged in
                    bitter words with one of the young men, a Frenchman in the employ of the
                    Government. All at once Mlle. A. livid with anger seized a carafe full of water
                    and inflicted a terrible blow on the face of her companion. The friends of the
                    victim fetched a carringe and took him to the caracol, followed by a large
                    crowd. The doctor pronounced the wound serious enough to necessitate a months
                    treatment in hospital. The proces-verbal was communicated to the Consulate and
                    the woman was arrested. Brendful Fire Dane.</p>
                <p>Mt. C French engineer living with his with his wife and two children in the Copt
                    Market, Cairo, on Friday evening went to the French hospital in the company with
                    his wife, leaving the two children, both young, alone in the house. One of them
                    slept on the bed while the other played at its foot. No one knows exactly what
                    occurred, but the little girl was heard to give 'vent to heart rending cries and
                    ran down the stairs drying out that there was a fire in the house. A cab man was
                    the first to receive the news, and going up to the room opened the door. A
                    horrible right met his eyes, surrounded by flames, the boy, a child of 11 years,
                    we suffering frightful agonies. The cabman cours geously did what he could by
                    tearing off the burning clothes and rolling the unfortunate child on the
                    mattress. But it was too late</p>
                <p>Life was almost extinct, and he was transported to the hospital, where he died
                    yesterday morning. The cabman has had to renounce his work for the time being,
                    owing to terrible burns. The French Consulate opened an in "quest in conjunction
                    with the police and they came to the conclusion that an overturned lamp wm the
                    cause of the accident.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EZBEKIEH
                        GARDENS.</head>
                    <p>The band of the Kings Own Boottish Borderers will play the following
                        programme of Music (by kind permission of Colonel D. A. Macfarlane D.8.0.
                        and Officers) in the Ezbekieh Gardens tomorrow from 9 to 11 p.m. March-Ann
                        Behonen Strand der Elbe-Vollstedt. Entr'Acte Romande Schubert Reminiscence
                        Pre -Godfrey Two ty gety Phil-kaye Rarepta ta wert thou in the cold blast
                        (h) The</p>
                    <p>Maybelle and the down-Mendelssohe. Grand Selectie-Tanphonser Wagner. Valse -
                        bile Polaire - Waldteufel Gap-San -Nin. Regimental. March-Khedivial
                        Anthe</p>
                    <p>God Save the King</p>
                    <p>A.J. WILON, Bandmaster</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>EGYPT IN
                        PARLIAMENT.</head>
                    <p>KAARTOUM GIRL'S SCHOOLS.</p>
                    <p>CONCLUDED. On the 22nd inst. Mr. John Robertson, asked the Secretary of State
                        for Foreign Affairs, whether he is yet in a position to give the House any
                        information as to schools for girls at Khartoum, appropriation of land there
                        by the Soudan Government, and the possible</p>
                    <p>application of Wakf property to purposes of education.</p>
                    <p>Secretary Sir Edward Grey.-- With regard y to the first Question.</p>
                    <p>The facts were stated in Lord Cromer's last annual Report. They are as
                        follows.</p>
                    <p>A petition for the establishment of a Government school for girls was
                        received by the Governor General of the Soudan in October last. The matter
                        was fully considered and it was decided in March last that a girls' school
                        Ishonla bed , sufficient funds having</p>
                    <p>or the purpose. A beginning de with the erection of a</p>
                    <p>the petitioners were in nose refer the missionary school authorities.</p>
                    <p>as explained by Lord Cromer, snch Moslem girls as attend missionary schools
                        in Khartoum receive seenlar education only unless at the express wish of
                        their parents or guardians</p>
                    <p>With regard to the second Question.</p>
                    <p>The Soudan Government expropriated for public purposes an area of 1,202
                        feddans of land at the Blue and White Niles. The land</p>
                    <p>was expropriated under the Land Acquisition e Ordinance, 1903, a copy of
                        which is enclosed.</p>
                    <p>The prices were fixed by a Commission of three at members, consisting of the
                        sub-Governor and</p>
                    <p>two official members, and were based on the</p>
                    <p>prices given at the private sales which had it been affected from time to
                        time of various parts of the land.</p>
                    <p>The whole of the land expropriated, except a narrow bank on the Blue Nile,
                        consists of a low-lying flat which is flooded at times of high Nile. The
                        bank on the Blue Nile is being</p>
                    <p>rapidly washed away. The expropriation was made with a view to building a
                        protective e masonry embankment along the Blue Nile to b protect the bank,
                        and of construction works to</p>
                    <p>reclaim the remainder. The scheme is intimately connected with proposals for
                        connecting Khartoum and Omdurman with a railway and a bridge, and with the
                        eventual erection of quays along the White Nile.</p>
                    <p>With regard to the second part of this Question, the Egyptian Government have
                        on</p>
                    <p>two or three occasions expropriated land 'at e Khartoum North (Halfaya) No
                        association of el the name of the "Model Farming Association,"</p>
                    <p>or any similar name, is known. In 1905 a piece of uncultivated land was
                        expropriated for a Government experimental farm, and the price paid to
                        expropriate private rights over part</p>
                    <p>of such land was at the rate of LE, 2 a feddan, it but the average price was
                        considerably higher.</p>
                    <p>No part of this land has been sold. With regard to the third Question.</p>
                    <p>The Egyptian Government have not confiscated any Wakf property. They have
                        certain Wakf lands in their hands which are at present mainly unproductive,
                        but some of which have a considerable value as building land. The</p>
                    <p>proceeds are applicable for purposes recognised as charitable by Mohammedan
                        Law, such as</p>
                    <p>the upkeep of mosques, the payment of</p>
                    <p>mosque officials, education (especially relief regions edition), alms,
                        etc.</p>
                    <p>It would not be in accordance with the d wishes of the inhabitants of Egypt
                        so restrict ne the application of Wakf property to education.</p>
                    <p>additional purposes. COMPANY -PROMOTION RESTRICTIONS</p>
                    <p>In the House of Commons on Monday last, Mr. Rees asked the Secretary of State
                        for is Foreign Affairs whether Lord Cromer prescribed certain restrictions
                        upon company promo to tion in Egypt, with a view to the protection of b) the
                        investing public ; and, if the answer be in</p>
                    <p>the affirmative, whether he would inform the</p>
                    <p>House what such restrictions were. Fol Mr. Runciman, who replied, said his
                        right e hon. friend could only refer the hon.</p>
                    <p>member to the heading "Mining Concession" ngin Lord Cromer's Report for 1903,
                        page 29.</p>
                </div>
            
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SHOUBRA
                        ENGLISH SCHOOL. The Shoubra English School closed on the 26th of June, after
                        a very satisfactory and happy year's work, in the course of which the</head>
                    <p>pupils increased from 17 to 49. Good progress He was made both in English and
                        French, the</p>
                    <p>latter, throughout the school, being under the</p>
                    <p>able tuition of Mme Léchant y some difficulties occurred in the way of be
                        providing accommodation for the school, says le "Au SaintsChurch Magazine"
                        but these were</p>
                    <p>overcome, and may be looked upon as blessings</p>
                    <p>in disguise, inasmuch as they result in hasten ding the building of our own
                        school house. This</p>
                    <p>will be opened at the beginning of the new school year, when we hope to warm
                        the class rooms with a good tes and games for our children.</p>
                    <p>Great improvements are hoped for in the coming year, when many new books and
                        maps will be brought out from England...</p>
                    <p>Alf being well, the annual Prize Giving will he be held in December. Mrs.
                        Foote's prizes of m. 258. and. 158. for general progress, have been</p>
                    <p>won by George Aitken and Robert McPhee.</p>
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. Burns leave Church House on 8ptember 2nd. Their address in
                        future will We - The Dean's Building, Sharia Guesiret Badrane. To find the
                        house go down the Sharia Guesiret Badrone from the Sharia Shoubra, and take
                        the turning between the houses numbered 22 and 24. The Dean's Building is on
                        the left, 200 yards from the Guesiret. Badrane.</p>
                    <!-- NEW COLUMN -->
                    
                
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SULTAN'S
                        ACCESSION FETES.</head> <p> Most of the buildings of Alexandria flew the Ottoman flag
                        yesterday in celebration of the accession of Sultan Abdul Hamid to the
                        throne of Turkey and at night several of them were illuminated, the
                        illuminations of the Ottoman bank being especially attractive. In the
                        evening, a banquet was given at Ras el-Tin palace by the Regent, Fakhry
                        Pasha, which was attended by the notables of Alexandria. The dinner was
                        followed by a display of fireworks.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE
                        VALLEY'S CO'S OPERATIONS Kl </head> <p>Messrs. Lake and Currie, the company's
                    engineers, report as follows:- Daring the month of July the company's
                        operations have been confined to stopping and milling, no further
                        development work having been carried out. Stopping - The ore stopped during
                        the month was as follows:-Blook BN. 2.128.5 tons ; block. B.O.. 116.0 tons;
                        block B.8.1, 248.2 tons; block c.0., 13.0 tons; block C.N.1,30.0 tons, block
                        C.8.1, 181,8 tons ; block C.8. 2, 183.5 tons; blook D.N.I, 168.2 tons;
                        total, 1,019.2 tons. Milling-During the month the</p>
                    <p>10 stamp mill man for 6,130 stamp hours, treating 1,023 tons of ore, which
                        yielded 288.005</p>
                    <p>oza fine gold, exclusive of 1.75 tons of concentrates of an assay value of
                        40.5 dwts per ton.</p>
                    <p>The ore crushed was obtained as follows: Stopes, 973 tons ; dumps, 50 tons ;
                        total, 1,023 tons. The manager is now preparing to restart driving the level
                        at 400 ft</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CORPORATION
                        OF WESTERN EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The Corporation of Westera Egypt, Limitled, have received formal notification
                        from the secretary of the Share and Loan Depart. ment of the London Stock
                        Exchange that a quotation of the shares of the corporation has been granted
                        in the Stock Exchange Daily Official List.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE DEAN'S
                        BUILDING</head>
                    <p>9</p>
                    <p>This building, which at present consita of school premises and two small
                        flats, one for the head mistress and the oth for the assistant chaplain, is
                        now completed. On the first floor there are three school-rooms, of which
                        one, measuring 40ft. by 25, is designed to be also used on Sundays, in the
                        afternoon for Sunday School, and later for an Evening Service. There are,
                        besides the school-rooms, library for the children (to be used also as a
                        common room for the teachers) and an office for the head mistress. The
                        sanitary accommodation, provided in buildings quite separate from the
                        school, is arranged on the most approved system. The school is capable of
                        accomodating one hundred children, which is just double the number of the
                        highest attendance during the past school year. The head mistress is due in
                        Cairo about the 25th of September, and she is bringing from England a fresh
                        supply of maps, books, ete. 1. The height of the room on the ground floor
                        slis 4 metres; the school entrance is from the</p>
                    <p>South, although there are three other exits. T, entrance to the flats is on
                        the north side, by means of a staircase outside the building. The - whole
                        presents a very pleasing appearance, and</p>
                    <p>I promises to be exceedingly convenient in every way. At the entrance of the
                        school front in marble tablet has been let into the wall bearing the
                        following inscription :</p>
                    <p>The Dean's BUILDING.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>IN MEMORY OF
                        CHARLES HENRY BUTCHER, D.D.</head>
                    <p>Ye are' God'Building.-1 Cor. III., 9. Reminding us of him to whose effort, in
                        the first instance, the school owes its existence.</p>
                    <p>The total cost of the land and building has been L.E. 3,661.340.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MERCHANT
                        SHIP ASHORE The SS. "Olive Moor" belonging to Messrs W. Ranciman &amp;</head> <p> Son,
                        London, and bound for Alexandria with a general cargo went ashore last
                    evening about 8 o'clock, when trying to make of Alexandria. She is badly
                        ashore on the rocks</p>
                    <p>about 4 miles 8.W. of Agami. The Coast Guard steamer "Abdel Moneim" returning
                        to Alex</p>
                    <p>andria sighted the steamer at daylight and n has been attempting to tow her
                        off, but up to is one o'clock she was unsuccessful.</p>
                    <p>The steamer is making water in No. 1 hold, but after she is dry. We
                        understand the Ports are and Lights túg will leave this afternoon to</p>
                    <p>render further assistance and that labourers ne are being despatched to
                        lighten the cargo for</p>
                    <p>ward. The sen is very unfavourable at present</p>
                    <p>and, unless immediate assistance is rendered, all there will be very little
                        chance of saving the steemer.</p>
                </div>
                
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CASINO SAN
                        STEFANO</head>
                    <p>se</p>
                    <p>Les concerts se suivent toujours avec entrain étant Casino. La grande
                        terrasse était de nou</p>
                    <p>veau comble d'une foule très élégante, pour le concert du matin ainsi que
                        l'après midi. Nous</p>
                    <p>aurons le plaisir de publier noue peu l'is programme du grand concert de
                        dimanche et prochain de Beethoven. Rappelons pour ven</p>
                    <p>'dredi le grand bal masqué pour enfants</p>
                </div>
                <!-- NEW COLUMN -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TR, MONDAY,
                        SEPTEMBER 4, 1907.
                    NOTES FROM CYPRUS
                    EGYPTIAN VISITORS</head>
                    <p>(FROM OUR OWN CORRESPONDENT.)</p>
                    <p>NG</p>
                    <p>Larnaca, August 29. A decided change of weather took place last week over the
                        whole Island, and an unwanted touch of freshness in the air made itself felt
                        even in the plains, In the higher localities the fall in the temperature was
                        more marked and was almost extreme. Visitors returning from Troodos
                        complained that for some days the cold was excessive two nights the
                        thermometer having fallen to 36° and 30 Fahrenheit respectively. Warmer
                        weather has now returned, but tempered with an unusual lightness and
                        buoyancy in the air, which is as welcome as it is unexpected | peeted in the
                        month of Angast. There is</p>
                    <p>belief current among the Cypriots that all change to colder conditions takes
                        place from the 15th August, but this rule is more honoured in the breach
                        than in the observance As both August and September are frequently among the
                        hottest and most trying months of the year.</p>
                    <p>A good number of visitors from Egypt and elsewhere have passed through
                        Limassol during the last few weeks on their way to Troodos. Among them may
                        be mentioned Capt. and Mrs. Swift ; Lieut. Grogan, R. N. and Mrs. Grogan;
                        Borton Bey (Postmaster-General of Egypt) and Mrs. Borton; Mr. Adams; Mr. W.
                        V. Vogell, of Beyrouth; Revd. and Mrs. Thomas, of Cairo, and Major and Mrs.
                        Wilding.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Laurence King-Harman, eldest son of the High Commissioner, left last mail
                        for England, on the termination of his summer vacation. Mr. J.A.S. Buoknill,
                        King's Advocate, crossed over to Egypt by the same boat in order to meet his
                        wife and bring her to Cyprus.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Clarence Wodehouse, who for twelve years has been Commissioner of Paphos
                        is about to be transferred, as Commissioner, to Larnaca, in succession to
                        Mr. C. D. Cobham, C.M.G. retired. Mr. Wodehouse has done much valuable work
                        in the Paphos District, where he has identified himself in an exceptional
                        manner with the interests of the people, and has long been regarded by them
                        as a "guide, philosopher and friend." The personal equation counts for much
                        in the administration of a district, and the departure of Mr. Wodehouse and
                        his family cannot fail to be regarded by the large majority of the Paphitis
                        in the light of a personal loss.</p>
                    <p>The seaward view from our "Marina' has been animated this week. Besides the
                        presence of tour, and occasionally five, steamers e the roadstead has been
                        harbouring a large n number of sailing craft, which has been ang</p>
                    <p>mented by a small flotilla of sponge fishing</p>
                    <p>boats from the Greek Islands, which have been n fishing off the Egy tian
                        coast and came over</p>
                    <p>here for quarantine purposes. 'Blessed are the</p>
                    <p>uses of adversity! The quarantine dues are o quite a considerable item. These
                        spongers e report having discovered a rich bed of sponges</p>
                    <p>which they have been working. Some of our</p>
                    <p>Cyprus sponge boats were also here for a few days a week or so ago. El The
                        erection of the new block of houses d along the front, between the Royal
                        Hotel or and the Pier, is steadily continuing, and 'get along we may see a
                        hotel, and a café restaurant à l'Européenne, in full swing of business
                        at</p>
                    <p>this prominent and popular corner. The building of the new and imposing
                        premises of the</p>
                    <p>Imperial Ottoman Bank, adjoining the English Club, is progressing apace.</p>
                    <p>Large quantities of grain are at present being e shipped from this port. y
                        There have been several forest fires of late e in different parts of the
                        Island. They seem be da chronicevil, and a not inconsiderable amount</p>
                    <p>of damage is done annually and may be doubt aless attributed as much to the
                        carelessness as &amp; to the malice of the villagers.</p>
                    <p>The annual report of the Government Analyst on the working of the Food and
                        Drugs Law, during the half-year ended 30th June last is officially
                        published.</p>
                    <p>The total number of samples received from the different districts was 828, of
                        which 489 were found pare and 84 were found adulterated.</p>
                    <p>The Government Analyst states: "I have examined a number of tins of food and
                        have found several of them to be unfit for consumption. This food has been
                        tinned years aggregate and should not have been exposed for</p>
                    <p>sale. The examination of tinned food is having steamy careful attention.</p>
                    <p>"The number of examples received has greatly increased during the last six
                        months, but I am glad to report that the percentage of pure samples has
                        increased considerably in amused."</p>
                    <p>The total number of samples of food and Drugs analysed from all sources
                        during the period under report was.</p>
                    <p>247 Adulterated</p>
                    <p>Total 835</p>
                    <p>Pure</p>
                    <p>1 A comparison with previous figures would lead to the belief that this
                        useful law must be</p>
                    <p>having a beneficial effect upon the health of the people.</p>
                    <p>A successful concert was given on 27th</p>
                    <p>instant by the officers of the Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers on Mount.
                        Troodos. It was held in the</p>
                    <p>mens' Recreation Room, and was filled with le an enthusiastic audience who
                        had accepted</p>
                    <p>the invitation of the Colonel and officers of le the Regiment. Much musical
                        talent was disthe played and the performance was eminently - satisfactory
                        and appears to have given much</p>
                    <p>pleasure to all concerned..</p>
                </div>
                <!-- NEW COLUMN -->
                <div type="item">
                    <head>
                        
                    LITERARY TREASURE IN ANCIENT EGYPT</head>
                    <p>(Continued.) It was not however only beneath a statue that ancient writings
                        were placed for preservation, but also in the foundation walls of sacred
                        buildings, for a note added to another version of the 64th chapter of the
                        "Book of the Dead” than the more common recension says of it, "This chapter
                        was found in the foundations of Amihanna by the overseer of the men who
                        built a wall in the time of King Usasphais, its figures are mysterious,
                        nobody has seen them nor looked at them." This rubrie bears every aspect of
                        truth; the discovery is attributed not to any important personage but merely
                        to an overseer, doubtless superintending some additions or repairs to the
                        temple. Strange to say, however, the lost chapter was found under a king of
                        what has always, up to the present, been considered the first dynasty. Yet
                        this chapter, which has been said is shorter than its commoner duplicate
                        which is called the chapter of "going out of the day," is entitled the
                        "chapter of knowing the chapters of going out of the day in one chapter." It
                        is therefore a condensation in predynastic times of several chapters of the
                        same objective import, which must have been selected from an earlier
                        edition, or collection, forming the "Book of the Dead' than any we have ever
                        known.</p>
                    <p>The longer and more common chapter is probably one of these primitive ones
                        which were supposed in their intrinsic essence to have been contained in the
                        short version buried in the foundation wall. Such seribal scholia attached
                        to these papyri, or documents, perhaps upon leather or stone, however lead
                        to important inferences. Was this pre-Nilotie dynasty "Book for the Dead"
                        composed in Egypt at all t or was it produced by the so called "followers of
                        Horus," who are supposed to have been invaders of the country, coming from
                        Nobis or Abyssinia and bringing with them a western Asiatie culture ? If it
                        was composed in Egypt and that so long before the first dynasty that some of
                        its chapters were lost and forgotten, then the predynastic period must have
                        been lengthy indeed. More over this missing chapter, it has been pointed out
                        when it was well known and deposited in the wall was a shorter recension of
                        several other chapters, inferring a still further antiquity for them. Some
                        may decline to accept the state. ment of the rubrie that the missing chapter
                        was found under Usafis, but the statement is always found with the short
                        chapter, and a papyrus as old as the 11th dynasty makes the assertion. There
                        is no reason to doubt that had we copies of the "Book of the Dead"
                        containing this version of the chapter earlier than those of the 11th
                        dynasty the usual rubio as to its discovery after having been long lost
                        would also be found in thein. Also Usaphais, according to Egyptian
                        tradition, had something specially to do with the composition of the "Book
                        for the Dead" and it would be reasonable to suppose that the recovery of
                        this chapter during his reign was the incentive inducing him to search for
                        other missing texts and have the work re edited.</p>
                    <p>Finally the name of the edifice where it was found is of great antiquity;
                        Amihannu "The god inhabiting Hunnn" refers to a site not found in late
                        texts. M. Naville shews it refers either to Heliopolis or Memphis, both of
                        them very old cities; the god Sokaris was also sometimes called Hunnu, that
                        may be because he possessed a temple there.</p>
                    <p>Before these memoranda upon the depositing of documents in ancient Egyptian
                        sacred edifices are complete, reference must be made to a third instance of
                        such a enstom which is to be found inscribed upon the temple at Dendera of
                        as late a date as Ptolemy XIII. There is however ample reason to believe
                        that most of the writings on this late sanctuary are careful copies from
                        those upon an earlier building which the more splendid one replaced. As this
                        extract is connected with the ancient ritual of the Hathor worship there,
                        many copies among the temple archives must have been in possession of the
                        hierarchy of the goddess, enabling them to supply the architectural
                        sculptures with the correct version.</p>
                    <p>Upon the walls of one of the temple scripts which are covered with texts
                        relating to religious festivals we read concerning one of these called "In
                        the coming forth of this goddess a rds Edfou when she celebrates the "suval
                        of the navigation" a great offering is made. All the prescribed ceremonies
                        are performed to her during a four days' festival. The King of upper and
                        lower Egypt, Thotmes, made his monuments to his mother, Hathor, lady of
                        Denderah when he had found the great rule of Denderah in writings written
                        upon the skin of a goat in the time of the followers of Horus. It was found
                        inside a wall of bricks of the southern house of the time of the king of
                        upper and lower Egypt Meri Ra-Pepi." .</p>
                    <p>The record is quite clear, it is a copy of a notice from Thothmes III that
                        when he was renewing a wall of bricks, probably changing them for stone, as
                        we know from other inscriptions of his he liked to do elsewhere, his workmen
                        found old writings engrossed upon leather concealed in a brick wall erected
                        by Meri Ra Pepi. For the document itself we know from an inscription in
                        another part of the temple crypt dated from the time of Khofu. This text
                        reading "This is the great rule (ie ritual of temple ceremonies) of Denders.
                        The reconstruction of the buildings was made by the lord of diadema Thothmes
                        .after it was found in old writings of the time of King Khufu."</p>
                    <p>The first memorandum explains that the text found written at the time of
                        Khufu</p>
                    <p>"This extenet is much condensed for ways of space but the essential
                        statements are given.</p>
                </div>
                <!-- NEW COLUMN -->
                <div type="item">
                    <p>was a copy
                        of the temple role dating from the end of the followers of Horus, that is
                        before Menes. These Horus invaders M. Naville in his lectures two years ago
                        at Paris, considers to have come from Asia by way of Arabia and the
                        Sudan.</p>
                    <p>If in the greatly dilapidated remains of only a few of the many stately
                        temples of Ancient Egypt we have already discovered records of three
                        instances of old writings placed in the edifices for safe keeping there must
                        have been many other similar cases.</p>
                   
                    <p>The conclusion is inevitable that the religious and what may be termed
                        masonic literature of old Egypt goes back for and away before the first
                        dynasty inaugurated by Menes. This car ries back the age of some sort of
                        civilization in Egypt many centuries. No surprise need now be felt at this
                        for the discoveries in Babylonia and Elam are Similarly projecting into
                        far-reaching antiquity the history of these countries, whilst the finding of
                        numerous cave drawings and even paintings of animals long extinct in Europe
                        in the valleys of southern France and northern Spain compels us to accept
                        the residence of the human race endowed with artistic instincts for many
                        thousands of years in We stern Europe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND
                        SOCIAL</head>
                    <p>The President of the Royal Drawing 80 the society, H.R.H. The Princess
                        Louise, Duchess of Argyll, announces that King Edward has become Patron of
                        the Society.</p>
                    <p>Captain Hugh R. Hendlam, who is the son of the Manchester Stipendiary
                        Magistrate, has been granted the Imperial Ottoman Order of the Medjidie
                        (Fourth Clans) by the Sultan of Turkey for services rendered to the Khedive
                        of Egypt. Captain Headlam, who completes ten years service in the York and
                        Lancaster Regiment next month, has been attached to the Egyptian Army since
                        1908, and has been mentioned in despatches by the Sirdar.</p>
                    <p>It is announced that Lieut. Col. Sir John Harrington, who has been British
                        Minister in Abyssinians for the past four years has become engaged to Miss
                        Amy MoMillan, an American lady.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ROWING CLUBS
                        REGATTA.</head> <p>The finals of the regatta organised by the four rowing clubs of
                        Alexandria, the Alex andria Rowing Club, Deutscher Sportverein, Club
                        Nautique Français, and Club Internazionale Canottieri, which took place on
                        the 28th alto., were rowed yesterday in the harbour. At 8.30 am. the skiff
                        race was won by Mr. Seeger of the Deutscher Sportverein, and at half past
                        five in the afternoon the four oared race was rowed and won by the Club
                        Nautique Français. The emps offered by the four clubs were won by the
                        following -</p>
                    <p>Club Nautique Français - Four-cared outrigger race Crew - Merr Porzinette
                        (stroke), Verny, Greedy, Lorion, Barbaza (cox.)</p>
                    <p>Club Nautique Français :-Four on red yawl race. Crew :-Messrs. Gayot
                        (stroke), Lemaitre, Ingott, Metager, Barbara (cox).</p>
                    <p>Alexandria Rowing Club : -Two oared yawl race. Crew Messrs. Chakour (stoke)
                        Vasiliadi, Jules Chini (cox). Skiff Race Mr. Seeger.</p>
                    <p>The distribution of prizes took place last night at eight o'clock in the hall
                        of the Club Nautique Français, and tents to the various clubs were drunk in
                        copious draughts of champagne. A most enjoyable evening was spent and the
                        party broke up in the best of spirits, highly delighted with the success of
                        the afternoon's sport.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>• STEAMER
                        MOVEMENTS. </head> <p>The SS. "Highland Prince" lett London the 31st August; and is due
                        to arrive at Alexandria on or about the 16th inst.,</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>L'AFFAIRE
                        COMMENTS </head> <p>On sait que M. Coumes, propriétaire des journaux Cairotes
                        "Vosporos" et "Bosphore", accusé de diffamation contre MM. Tambaco. poulos
                        et Frangiscatos, a été condamné par le</p>
                    <p>Tribunal Consulaire de Grèce à 25 jours de e prison et aux frais. Nous
                        extrayons d'un ar</p>
                    <p>ticle du "Bosphore" à ce sujet, signé Guémard,</p>
                    <p>les passages suivants : - Après cet arrêt contre un journal hellene</p>
                    <p>faisant suite à un verdier analogue contre trois familles indigènes, qu'il me
                        soit permis de me demander avec mélancolie si la liberté de la presse n'est
                        pas quelque peu méconnue en Egypte… </p>
                    <p>Mais quel a donc été le crime de Monsieur Jean Coumenos ? Il avait écrit que,
                        d'une sous éruption publique, destinée à secourir les victims d'une
                        catastrophe, des fonds avaient été détournés. Au moment de l'éruption de la
                        Montagne Pelée, à la Martinique, des secours furent expédiés de même aux
                        malheureux ministres. Or, plusieurs journaux français prétendaient qu'une
                        bonne partie des sommes te cueillies avait fonda entre les mains du comité
                        Ce fut un scandale épouvantable. Les journaux accusateurs eurent-ils à
                        prouver leurs dies devant les tribunaux Pas le moins da monde. Bien qu'il y
                        et diffamation caractérisée, ageun ne fut poursuivi. D'ailleurs même une
                        condamnation n'serait pas modifié l'opinion publiqne.</p>
                    <p>Mais passons. Je ne réoriminerai pas contre la décision de l'augusto Arcopage
                        d'Alexandrie, je pourrais, mois aussi, être traîné devant barre et jeté sans
                        pitié dans une oubliette inconfortable ! Je me contenterai d'aviser noe
                        lecteurs que dorénavant nous apprendrons à exprimer notre pénale d'une
                        manière moins franche, à la voiler sons des réticences habiles À peser
                        jusqu'à nos virgule et surtout a ne I pas confier trois lignes de notre
                        écriture aux</p>
                    <p>typographes sans avoir consulté le Code Pénal Lou lieu du Larousse</p>
                </div>
                
                
            </div>
            
            <pb n="4"/>
            <div type="page" n="4"> 
                
            </div>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <div type="page" n="5"> 
                
            </div>
            <pb n="6"/>
            <div type="page" n="6"> 
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
