<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2015-10-21">October 2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-11">11 July 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, JULY 11, 1905.</head>
                <div type="section" scope="international" source="wire">
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>NATIONAL DEFENCE. A DEBATE IN UPPER HOUSE. MR. BALFOUR CRITICISED.
                            LORD “BOBS” AND CONSCRIPTION.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline> London, July 10. </dateline>
                            <p> During the debate on National Defence in the House of Lords Mr.
                                Balfour’s statement of the 11th of May was severely criticised. Lord
                                Roberts said that the lessons of the South African war were already^
                                forgotten. He had no hesitation in saying that the army is as
                                absolutely unfitted and unprepared for war now as it was then. The
                                nation must choose between conscription and universal training.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div type="subsection">
                        <head>THE “ENTENTE CORDIALE.” BRITISH FLEET AT BREST.</head>
                        <div type="item">
                            <dateline>Brest, July 10. 4,</dateline>
                            <p>The preparations for the reception of the British fleet, which will
                                arrive to-day, have just been completed. The rejoicings promise to
                                constitute a record in international naval courtesies. The programme
                                of official and private festivities is so huge that there will
                                hardly be an hour during the whole week that will not be accounted
                                for. </p>
                            <p>There are evidences on every side that the visit is most popular.
                                (Reuter.) </p>

                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Brest, July 10.</dateline>
                                <p>The British squadron has arrived in order to assist at the fêtes
                                    given in its honor. Its arrival was cheered by those on shore.
                                    (Havas.) </p>
                            </div>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Brest, July 10.</dateline>
                                <p>The British fleet arrived this afternoon. There was a remarkable
                                    demonstration of welcome by immense crowds ashore and
                                    afloat.(R.)</p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>FRANCE AND GERMANY. AGREEMENT CONFIRMED.</head>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline> Paris, July 10.</dateline>
                                <p>Chamber of Deputies. — M. Rouvier announced that France has
                                    accepted the Morocco Conference and that Germany recognised
                                    French rights and interests. M. Rouvier’s words were greeted
                                    with unanimous applause. (Havas.)</p>
                            </div>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline> Paris, July 10.</dateline>
                                <p>M. Rouvier announced in the Chamber that France and Germany have
                                    agreed to an international conference on the lines mentioned
                                    yesterday. He stated that the missions at Fes will be recalled
                                    when the conference meets. Germany has not raised the question
                                    of the Anglo-French nor the Franco-Spanish agreements, which are
                                    not mentioned in the negotiations. (Reuter.) </p>
                            </div>
                            <div type="item">
                                <dateline>Berlin, July 10.</dateline>
                                <p>The Socialist organ “Vorwaerts” has publishd M. Jaures's lecture
                                    textually. The tone is moderate and most friendly to Germany. </p>
                                <p> There is a notable warmth the reference to the Anglo-French
                                    entente, declaring that “we shall resist to our last breath any
                                    attempt to entangle us in hostile action with Great Britain.”
                                    (Reuter.) </p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>THE PEACE COMMISSION. PLACE OF MEETING.</head>
                            <dateline>Washington, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>The peace plenipotentiaries will meet at Portsmouth in the State of
                                New Hampshire. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>JAPANESE LOAN ISSUED.</head>
                            <dateline>London, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>The Japanese loan has been issued.(R )</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>JAPANESE ESPIONAGE CASE.</head>
                            <dateline>Tokio, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>M. Bougouin, mentioned in despatches of the 10th of May, has been
                                sentenced to 10 4 years’ hard labour, and the interpreter Maki to 8.
                                (Reuter) </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>CORRUPTION IN WASHINGTON. LEAKAGE OF COTTON REPORTS.</head>
                            <dateline>Washington, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>Owing to constant complaints of the leakage of cotton reports to
                                brokers, the Government has instituted an enquiry which has resulted
                                in the dismissal of the leading statistician at the Department of
                                Agriculture. (Reuter)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>FRENCH SUBMARINE DISASTER.</head>
                            <dateline>Bizerta, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>It is not believed that it will be possible to raise the submarine
                                before some days. The Minister of Marine has arrived and has gone
                                for a long submarine trip in a vessel of the same type.
                                (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="subsection">
                            <head>THE CANADIAN NAVY.</head>
                            <dateline>Halifax, July 10.</dateline>
                            <p>The disorders mentioned on the 8th inst. have been settled. A new
                                Crew has been embarked. (Reuter.)</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL.</head>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Rains</head><p> in the Kassala to be late.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The New Anti-Rabic Institute,</head>
                        <p>it is expected, will be completed by the end of the year. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Agricultural Shows</head>
                        <p> are to be held in the Fayoum and at Mansourah in September and October
                            next. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Little Girl Drowned.</head>
                        <p> A child, named Um el Saâd, four years of age, was accidentally drowned
                            in a masraf at Boghos Pasha’s ezbeh. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Stray and Ownerless Dogs</head>
                        <p> found in the Saida Zeynab quarter of Cairo during the night of Wednesday
                            and at daylight on Thurs day will be poisoned by the police. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Defrauding the Revenue.</head>
                        <p> A man named Antonio Carabot was arrested yesterday with a quantity of
                            silk thread in his possession which he was attempting to smuggle. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>P. W. D.</head>
                        <p> Sir Wm. Garstin’s Report for 1904 on the Public Works Department is in
                            the hands of the printer, and will be published in October next. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suez Canal.</head>
                        <p> 10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 7th inst., 8 of which were
                            British, 1 French, 1 German. The day’s receipts were frs. 293,573.11,
                            making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 2,126,168.89. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>The Plague</head>
                        <p> Yesterday’s bulletin records a fatal case at Alexandria, the victim
                            being a native fisherman who was found dead at his house at Khattabieh.
                            A fatal case is reported from Ashmoun, a death from Damanhour, and a
                            recovery from Menouf. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Theatre Regulations.</head>
                        <p> The Ministry of the Interior has sent the new regulations for theatres
                            to the Ministry of Justice in order to be submitted to the Mixed Court
                            of Appeal for its approval, which cannot be given till after the
                            vacation. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Mosque for Paris</head>
                        <p> M. Lion Lambeir, a French merchant, has decided to construct a mosque in
                            Paris, and has asked the French Government to grant him a site for the
                            purpose. A fatwa has been signed by the rector of El Azhar University
                            approving the project. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>An Absconding Clerk.</head>
                        <p> M. Leonardo Golisti, advocate, has informed the Attarin police that his
                            clerk, named Abdulla Hozalli el Shami, to whom he had entrusted a cheque
                            of £50 in order to pay costs in a law case at the Mixed Tribunal, has
                            absconded with the money. _ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Another Case of Embezzlement.</head>
                        <p> The Attarin police have also received notice from M. George Maisokis,
                            director of the Kafr-el-Zayat Cotton Co., that a man named Ahmed Mursi
                            had cashed a cheque for L.E. 61 with the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, and had
                            absconded with the money. _ </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Suspicious Death.</head>
                        <p> The Alexandria Gouvernorat has been informed by the Minet el Bassal
                            police that a man named Moh. El Said Rizk, who had died in his house,
                            was found, by the medical officer who was called in, to have a severe
                            wound on the forehead. His relatives, when questioned, said that the
                            deceased suffered from hysteria, which caused the injuries that resulted
                            in his death. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="section" scope="social">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <div type="article" scope="social" source="local">
                        <p> The Earl of Cromer was one of the guests at a dinner party given on
                            Saturday week by the Prince of Wales in honor of Prince Arisugawa of
                            Japan.</p>
                        <p> Sir Wm. Garstin left Cairo this morning for Port Said, where he will
                            embark on the P.&amp; O. S.S. Britannia.</p>
                        <p> Mr. E. B. Gould I.S.O., H.B.M’s Consul- General at Alexandria, and Mrs.
                            Gould are leaving for Europe on Saturday next. </p>
                        <p> Mr. A. D. Alban, H.B.M’s Consul in Cairo, and Mrs. Alban leave for
                            Europe by the French steamer on Friday. </p>
                        <p> Two marriages of local interest take place to-morrow in London, one at
                            St. Peter’s, Eaton square, where Major D. K. E. Hall, A.S.C. (Egyptian
                            Army), will be married to Mrs. R. Howe Davis, of Sandy Hill, Crafton,
                            California; and the other at St. George’s, Hanover square, where Captain
                            C. W. Maclean, Lancashire Fusiliers, will wed Miss Gladys Royle,
                            daughter of Mr. and Mrs. George Royle, of Ghezifeh, Cairo. On the 18th,
                            Mr. Horace Rumbold, second secretary at the British Agency, eldest son
                            of Sir Horace Rumbold, formerly British Ambassador to Austria, marries
                            Miss Etheldred Fane, daughter of the late Sir Edmund Fane, British
                            Minister to Denmark.</p>
                        <p> Halil Hamada Pasha, Director of Customs at Alexandria, who has been
                            staying at Constantinople, has now left for Western Europe. </p>
                        <p> We are glad to hear that Mr. G. de Beaupuis, manager of the Banco di
                            Roma in Alex andria, is making very satisfactory progress and hopes to
                            return to Egypt at the end of the month.</p>
                        <p> Mr. H. W. Tite, chief inspector of the International Sleeping Car
                            Company, arrived in Cairo yesterday from Paris. He will shortly leave
                            for Cyprus, where Mrs. Tite is passing the summer. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb/>
                <div type="section" scope="local">
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>STATE RAILWAY CONTRACTS. AN OFFICIAL DEMENTI.</head>
                        <p> Statements having appeared in certain newspapers to the effect that the
                            German Diplomatic Agent in Egypt had protested against an alleged change
                            in the system of placing railway contracts by international competition,
                            we are authorised to state that the German Diplomatic Agent has informed
                            the authorities concerned that no complaints whatever have been made to
                            him. </p>
                        <p> We are further authorised to state that no change of policy has
                            occurred, but exceptions to the rule are now, as they were formerly,
                            committed when it is clearly to the public’s advantage to dispense with
                            competition, and owing to the very rapid increase of traffic within the
                            last twelve months, the number of exceptional eases which have recently
                            occurred has been large. This has no doubt given rise to the rumours
                            alluded to. w </p>
                        <p> The exceptional cases mentioned have as a rule taken the form of giving
                            orders in extension of their contract to firms who have been successful
                            in previous competitions, in order to avoid the delay necessitated by a
                            fresh competition.</p>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head>THE GRAND MUFTI.</head>
                            <p> We regret to learn this morning that the condition of the Grand
                                Mufti has taken another turn for the worse. Little hope is now
                                entertained of his recovery. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head>ESNEH BARRAGE.</head>
                            <p> The Public Works Department expect to commence the construction of
                                the Esneh Barrage next year. Tenders will be invited in October
                                next. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head> AMERICAN COTTON.</head>
                            <p> The following telegram has been received m Mr. Price of New York by
                                Mr. G. L. Sursock:— “Market possibly entitled to some reaction, bat
                                doubtful ; it is on its certain way to twelve cents in my opinion.”
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head>DEAR CEREALS.</head>
                            <p> The country is suffering considerably this year from the high price
                                of cereals. Durrah and beans, which form the principal ingredient in
                                the diet of the fellah, have reached the price of P,T. 9 to 10 per
                                keila. In spite of the excellent barley crop in the Mariout
                                district, for which the abundant rains of last winter are
                                responsible, the price of barley has risen to from P.T. 63 to 65 per
                                ardeb, against an average of P.T. 45 per ardeb in 1904, when the
                                rain crop was to all intents and purposes non-existent The English
                                and Con­tinental breweries have bought up a very large proportion of
                                this year’s crop, and the barley from the rain belt is evidently in
                                as high request among brewers as ever. The present price of these
                                cereals makes the feeding of horses and cattle a very costly affair.
                                The bersim is over and the poorer owners of cattle and horses are
                                sometimes obliged to give their beasts half rations. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head> MORTGAGES IN EGYPT.</head>
                            <p> It is stated that the Land Bank of Egypt has announced that it will
                                issue no further loans on mortgages till the end of September. This
                                bank has already placed upwards of £1,300,000 on similar loans since
                                its founda­tion six months ago. The other mortgage-banks are only
                                accepting on an average about 5 per cent, of the transactions
                                proposed. The natural result of this action on their part is the
                                growth of a certain uneasiness among land-owners, who find great
                                difficulty in obtaining the money required for the exploitation of
                                their lands. The Agricultural Bank, of course, con­fines its
                                operations to the small cultivator. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head>PORT OF ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                            <p> During the half-year ended June 30 the number of vessels of all
                                nationalities which entered the port of Alexandria was 856, of which
                                number 367 were British. Other nationalities were represented as
                                follows: — Italian 92, Greek 81, Austrian 77, French 59, German 54,
                                Ottoman 49, Russian 48, Belgian 12, Swedish 8, Norwegian 2, Spanish
                                2, American 2, Dutch 2, Danish 1. </p>
                            <p> Of the 367 vessels which flew the British flag it is interesting to
                                note that 54 belonged to the Khedivial Mail Line, 48 to Bell’s Asia
                                Minor Company, 40 to the Prince Line, 36 to the Ellerman Lines, 20
                                to the Moss Line, 12 to the Westcott and Lawrence Line, and 5 to the
                                P. and O. Company. Of the 92 Italian steamers, 65 belonged to the
                                Florio-Rubattino Company. 51 of the 59 French vessels belonged to
                                the Messageries Maritimes, 68 of the 77 Austrian to the Austrian
                                Lloyd Company, 30 of the German to the Deutsche Levantie Line and 23
                                to the Norddeutsoher Lloyd. During the six months four men-of-war
                                (two British, one German, and one Italian) paid a visit to this
                                port. </p>
                        </div>
                        <div type="article">
                            <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                            <p> The S.S. Scottish Prince arrived in Man­chester from Alexandria on
                                Saturday last. </p>
                            <p> The S.S. Avon (Ellerman Line) arrived at Liverpool from Alexandria
                                on Tuesday.</p>
                            <p> The S.S. Bulgarian (Ellerman Line) will sail hence for Liverpool on
                                Wednesday.</p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <cb/>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>BRITISH TRADE IN EGYPT. MR. FREEMAN’S REPORT.</head>
                        <p>In his report on the trade of Alexandria for 1904 Mr. Vice-Consul Freeman
                            remarks ;— The answer to the question why the United Kingdom is, or at
                            any rate seems to be, grad­ually losing the largest share in respect of
                            the total imports is perhaps to be found in the wonderfully prosperous
                            condition of the country.i, the greater attention that it consequently,
                            attracts among Continental manufacturers and merchants, and in the
                            keener desire aroused on 9 their part to enter so tempting a market. The
                            contributions of countries other than those specified in the table have
                            more than doubled in the space of four years. Postal parcels and the
                            various goods included under the heading of “Other imports” have
                            likewise doubled in four years. The expansion is spread over all
                            categories and almost all items, and the stock inquiry : “Where are
                            there openings for British trade ?” can best be answered with the one
                            word “everywhere.” But at the same time I can only repeat the 8took
                            advice to manufacturers, jointly or singly, to have agents on the spot
                            and to send more travellers. As the representative of a group of British
                            firms remarked to me, the native tastes may not change, the same class
                            of goods may be in demand for years, but nevertheless local requirements
                            should be studied at the outset, and regular, periodical visits are
                            necessary to ensure a hold on the market. The agents at Alexandria of a
                            British firm dealing in carpenters’ and blacksmiths’ tools and also in
                            Sheffield goods in general wrote to this Con­sulate as follows:—“The
                            difficulty with our principals arises from the fact that the native does
                            not use the same tools as the British workman. Many modifications and
                            additions have consequently to be made so as to adapt the tools to what
                            is required on our markets. If it were a question of a few articles
                            only, the difficulty could easily be overcome by sending home samples ;
                            but as there are a thousand and probably more lines that have to be
                            attended to you will easily understand how impossible it is for an agent
                            who is neither a carpenter nor a blacksmith to give them all the
                            particulars they want. We there­fore suggested that they should send out
                            either one of the partners in their firm or a competent traveller, who,
                            with our help, might secure the first orders. What we have to complain
                            of most in the firms at home is that, although oar markets are invaded
                            by an army 'of foreign travellers, they (the British firms) do not take
                            the trouble or care to incur the expense of sending out competent men to
                            see What others are doing. We may give you as an instance the case of
                            Messrs whose turnover with us was very small until they decided to send
                            out one of the partners of the firm. They are now doing many more
                            thousands than they did hundreds.” </p>
                        <p>Another British commercial traveller told me that his quotation for
                            certain goods was 18s. per cwt. (If. 16s. per 100 kilos.) with three
                            months’ credit, while the German quotation, thanks partly to the
                            drawback in Germany, was 25 fr. (1/.) per 100 kilos., with six months’
                            credit. The British article was of course better, and some people
                            preferred it, but it was not, as the priced would seem to show, worth
                            nearly twice as much as the German article. With such competition as
                            this to face, merchandise, however excellent in itself, can scarcely be
                            left to speak for itself with any prospect of success. I hear of
                            machinery being bought in the United Kingdom by German firms and sold at
                            Alex­andria more cheaply than if it were imported direct. Here again
                            there is surely scope for the energies of a British traveller. </p>
                        <p> Inquiries of all kinds are received at this Consulate in ever increasing
                            numbers, and it is becoming almost impossible to answer them all. The
                            prospects and possibilities of this trade and of that trader the
                            restrictions and regulations to which they are subject, a description of
                            the articles already in the market, —such inquiries cannot be usefully
                            answered except after long and careful study of the conditions affecting
                            each particular trade, and this study a Consul has no time to undertake.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="article">
                        <head>FRENCH FETE.</head>
                        <p> Preparations for the celebration in Cairo of the French fête on Friday
                            next are almost completed. A large and well-decorated triumphal arch has
                            been erected at the Boulac entrance of the Esbekieh Gardens, and this
                            will be illuminated on the night of the 14th. A wooden pavilion has been
                            erected in the gardens for the official receptions and a stage has also
                            b3en erected for a variety entertainment which will be given by the
                            troupe of the “Nouveautés.” The gardens are gaily decorated with flags
                            and promise to look most effective when lit up by the numerous Chinese
                            lanterns and electric globes which are hung in every direction. The
                            bands of the 2nd Royal lnniskilling Fusiliers and the Egyptian Cavalry
                            will perform alternately throughout the even­ing, and there will also be
                            a grand display of fireworks. </p>
                        <p>All entrances to the gardens except the Boulac one will be closed and
                            this will be opened at 9 p.m. The officers of the Egyptian Army and the
                            Army of Ocupation have accepted the invitation of the committee to
                            assist at the festivities. </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                    <p>BECK &amp; CO’S PILSENER BEER BREMEN. MASS HO HOHWT COMPETITION FOB QUALITY.
                        N.B.—Inferior Brands now bring offwad to Mao* agar of certain good writs.
                        Beware el svflly Higessd eemgetltow rawing</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <cb/>
            <div type="section" scope="local">
                <div type="article">
                    <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN. FEVER ON THE INCREASE.</head>
                    <byline>(From our Correspondent.)</byline>
                    <dateline>Suakin, July 5.</dateline>
                    <p>The weather is becoming more oppressive than ever, owing to the hot khamseen
                        winds. Fever is daily on the increase, both among the natives and Europeans,
                        especially among the railway people. The latest victim in hospital is Mr. W.
                        H. Bailey, Inspector of Bridges, Suakin-Atbara Line, who is, however,
                        pro­gressing favorably towards recovery. </p>
                    <p> The following passengers are leaving by the S.S. Dakahlieh to-day, viz., Mr.
                        Smart, chief storekeeper, Suakin Railway, who is being invalided home to
                        England, Mr. Fulton and Mr. Finlay, also of the Suakin-Atbara Rail­ways, who
                        are likewise returning to England invalided as unfit for Suakin. </p>
                    <p> Mr. Ward, chief engineer of the Sudan Government steamer Hawk, having
                        resigned his appointment with the Sudan Government, also leaves to-day by
                        the Dakahlieh. </p>
                    <p> Dr. Crispin, senior medical officer, Suakin Moudirieh, is also a passenger
                        by the S.S. Dakahlieh. He is going on three months’ leave of absence, which
                        he will spend in England. Daring the absence of Dr. Crispin, Dr. Ibra­him
                        Effendy Fahmy will act as S.M.O. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="article">
                    <head>EGYPTIAN LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>
                    <p>The report of the Egyptian Land and General Trust, Ltd., submitted to the
                        statutory meeting on the 6th instant, states that with a view to spreading
                        the company’s investments over as wide a field as possible, the directors
                        are acquiring a large building area in the heart of Cairo, and their
                        agent-general in Egypt, Mr. Hooker, who has recently been to London to
                        confer with the board, has just left for Egypt to complete the arrangements,
                        subject to the titles of the property proving satisfactory. If this business
                        is concluded the directors have no hesitation in saying that it will be a
                        most satis­factory investment for the company. The direc­tors are also on
                        the point of completing the purchase of some very valuable budding land in
                        Alexandria which has been strongly recommended to them by their local
                        advisers. The directors feel that when these transactions are concluded the
                        shareholders will have a considerable interest in the heart of the two most
                        important cities in Egypt—namely, Cairo and Alexandria, which cannot fail to
                        give most satisfactory results. In view of the growing importance of the
                        Egyptian Mining industry, the directors are supporting on favorable terms
                        the issue of the Egyptian Gold and Emerald Company, Ltd. In this they are
                        acting in conjunction with the United African Explo­rations, Ltd. The
                        Egyptian Gold and Emerald Company, Ltd., is formed to acquire what appears
                        to be one of the most important mineral concessions in Egypt The concession
                        comprises an area of some 3,000 square miles, and it is reported upon by
                        responsible engineers as being rich in gold, silver, lead, copper and
                        emerald mines. The directors have also before them various proposals, which
                        are-likely to materialise shortly, for the development of sound and
                        profitable business in other direc­tions. The Board have elected Mr. Charles
                        H. Rigg as a director to represent his substantial financial interest in the
                        company. </p>
                    <p>July 5 was fixed by the committee of the London Stock Exchange as a special
                        settling day in Egyptian Land and General Trust, Limited, 200,000 shares of
                        £1 each, 5s paid (Nos. 1 to 200,000). </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="section" scope="sporting">
                <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB, REGATTA. The following is the handicap for the month of
                        July:— Class I.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> A. S. C.</head>
                    <p> The following programme of music will be played at the Skye Meeting on the
                        A. S C. grounds on Saturday next:— 1 March—On guard o’er the Empire—Myd- 2
                        Overture—Juanita—Suppe [dleton 3 SoDg (Cornet Solo)—The Silver Path -Be van.
                        4 Piccolo Solo - Playful Kittens—Young 5 Selection—The Belle of New
                        York—Kerker 6 Serenade— —Leoncavallo 7 Valse—Tout Paris—Waldtenfel 8 Ein
                        Albumblattr—Wagner 9 Selection—Die Puppen fee—Bayer 10 Danoe—The Coon s
                        Holiday—Barns 9 Khedivial Anthem—God Save the King S. Dobs, Bandmaster, 2nd
                        Royal Berkshire Regiment, </p>
                </div>
            </div>

            <cb/>
            <div type="section" scope="letters" source="local">
                <head>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.</head>
                <p>We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our
                    correspondants, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to all, to permit—within
                    certain necessary limits—free discussion.</p>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCE.</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>
                    <p>Sir,—I should be greatly obliged if you would, through your columns, call the
                        atten­tion of the Cairo police to another street nuisance which exists. At
                        most of the junctions of two streets cabstands exist, and the cabmen appear
                        to think that they have a right to stand in such a manner that the passage
                        of pede­strians is entirely obstructed. The cabmen naturally wish to look
                        for fares along both roads, and draw up their cabs accordingly, the general
                        public have to go round them in the middle of the road, which has pos­sibly
                        been recently watered. The stand opposite the Cafe Chicha is perhaps one of
                        the worst cases in point There is always a policeman on duty at this place,
                        but he does nothing to ameliorate the nuisance, and when complained to it is
                        with the greatest difficulty that one can drive into his head that the
                        cabman is in any way out of order. Personally, I invariably insist on the
                        cab being removed. Sometimes I am met with abuse or stolid resistance, but,
                        being fluent in the language, I finally get my way. Frequently the cabman
                        returns to his former position immediately I have passed, and remains there.
                        It surely would be an easy matter to explain to the policemen, either
                        individually or collectively when on parade, the rights of pedestrians, or
                        simpler still, to pat a red paint mark on the footpath indicating the limits
                        of the cabstand. Apologising for troubling you,—I am, etc., </p>
                    <byline>An Old Resident.</byline>
                    <dateline>Cairo, July 8.</dateline>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>REVOLTING CRUELTY AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette</p>
                    <p>Dear Sir,—At the hotels in Egypt collecting cards for the S. P. C. A. are in
                        evidence for support, bat at Port Said at least they are not likely to get
                        much as long as the dis­gusting scenes occur while cattle are being landed.
                        The poor beasts are slung by the feet or horns, kept for hours without
                        water, most likely from the port at which they embark, and on landing try to
                        drink from the sea. </p>
                    <p>On Tuesday the passengers on a ship in quarantine (therefore unable to take
                        steps) were entertained by the following exhibition of cruelty. A cow ran
                        away from the herd and was chased out on the breakwater by three or four
                        savages, her tail was twisted, she was stoned on the head and body with
                        rocks of about 20 lbs., beaten unmercifully with battens 3 inches thick,
                        sticks were thrust into her anus and vagina, she was thrown off the
                        breakwater into the sea, a fall of 12 feet, dragged over the rocks that cut
                        her hide, hauled up again in a most brutal fashion, her horns torn off and
                        blood was streaming from her nostrils. This performance took about two
                        hours. We are used to seeing acts of cruelty, but not such refined brutality
                        as this. If the S. P. C. A. has a representative, he should be on the spot
                        where these things happen or else he is not much use.—I am, etc., </p>
                    <byline>A Lover of Animals.</byline>
                    <dateline>Port Said, July 8.</dateline>
                </div>

            </div>
            <div type="section" scope="financial">
                <head>CHRONIQUE F1NANCIERE</head>
                <dateline>(1er-10 Juillet)</dateline>
                <p>Encore sous l’influence de la liquidation de fin du mois, notre marché a débuté
                    calme et insignifiant On s’attendait même à ce que cet état de marasme durut
                    toute la semaine, lorsque l’heureuse issue des négociations franco-allemandes et
                    la nomination définitive de ministres plénipotentiaires russo-japonais en vue de
                    la paix ont remis à flot les bourses européennes ; ce qui a été d’autant plus
                    facile que le capital abonde en Europe. </p>
                <p>A tons ces motifs de hausse est encore venu s’ajouter un facteur important: la
                    reprise soudaine et considérable des cotons à la suite du rapport du Bureau
                    d’Agriculture de Washington sur les prévisions de la prochaine récolte. Sur
                    notre place, pourtant, la spéculation continue à négliger les sociétés nouvelles
                    pour concentrer toute son attention sur les anciennes, dites à tranche dorée. On
                    a pu remarquer cette tendance chez un grand nombre de maisons financières de
                    notre ville qui estiment sans doute que ces valeurs ont été trop dépréciées à
                    l’occasion des derniers lancements de compagnies.</p>
                <p>La valeur qui a donné lieu au plus fort mouvement est l’Agricole en raison de
                    l’ouverture de la souscription des nouveaux titres à partir du 10 juillet
                    jusqu’au 2 octobre. Ce fait a de suite attiré des acheteurs. Certains
                    spéculateurs même, pensant que les nouveaux titres ne seraient livrés qu’au 2
                    octobre, c’est-à dire avec un trimestre de crédit, eurent bientôt fait de les
                    pousser jusqu’à 9 13/16, tandis que l’ancienne émission ne dépassait pas 13 7/8
                    ; mais, à peine surent-ils que des certificats provisoires au porteur seraient
                    mis en circulation dans un délai maximum d’un mois, qu’ils devinrent plus
                    réservés : la nouvelle émission baissait du coup d’un quart de livre, tandis que
                    l’ancienne avec droit montait de 1/16 à 1/8. L’ancienne avait débuté à 13 9/16
                    et touché un moment 14 1/16, elle clôture à 1315/16; la nouvelle finit à 9
                    9/16.</p>
                <p>La Fondateur Agricole débute à 912 pour clôturer à 960 acheteurs.</p>
                <p>Tout-à-fait calme d’abord à 28, la Daïra monte graduellement jusqu'à 28 1/2, pour
                    réactionner aujourd’hui à 28 e/8. L’assemblée du Crédit Foncier Egyptien réunie
                    au Caire samedi pour la liquidation de la Daïra a décidé, paraît-il, de payer à
                    celle-ci la somme de</p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
